all righty all right everybody ready
that sounds like yes okay so all right
I'm Richard Steenburgen from GTT
previously in lair and today we're going
to talk about optical networking so the
purpose of this talk why do we want to
talk about networking basically as an
industry a lot of guys spend a lot of
time dealing with optical but not many
router jockeys out there actually have
enough exposure to it there's tons of
people that know how to move traffic
they don't know anything about what
happens when they plug in their fiber
it's a wide variety of issues confusion
out there so the purpose of this talk is
just to try and get everyone familiar
with every little little thing it's not
gonna make you an optical engineer can
you hear okay it sounds like it's doing
something okay
yes some so is it better no okay
testing testing oh okay better all right
so this talk will probably not make you
an optical engineer but the point is to
get everyone familiar with just the
basic concepts everything from
theoretical to practical from really
useful to really mundane stuff the goal
just to give everyone just a really
basic understanding and talk about a
little bit of everything so first off
the basics how this optical fiber
actually work so optical fiber obviously
is a very thin strand of glass which
just act as acts as a waveguide over
over distances for light keeps it in
whatever guides the waves what do you
want so it works on a principle called
total internal reflection and that means
when when light tries to pass between
two different media so in this example
air to water you've you've seen if
you've been underwater or you've looked
through water you've seen that light
bends at certain angles it bends and at
certain angles it will actually reflect
back in at the same angle that it
entered so you see in this example that
if you are past a certain critical angle
it bounces back in that's how fibre
works so fibre is actually composed of
two different layers of glass the core
which is what actually carries the
actual signal and then the cladding
which is a different type of glass
around the outside of the core and that
causes the reflection back in so the we
have what's called index refractive
index which is I'm just a measure of how
quickly light passes through the the
fiber so the the cladding has a lower
refractive index and that causes the
total internal reflection inside so
here's a gratuitous pretty picture from
Wikipedia
showing someone shining a laser pointer
into a piece of plastic or something and
you can see that it just bounces around
inside and keeps propagating forward so
the inside of a single-mode fiber cable
you've got your ear core which is nine
microns
you've got your cladding which is
usually 125 microns you've got a buffer
which is just a
around the fiber to keep it from being
damaged and then inside of that you'll
have strain relief members you'll have
them be possibly multiple fibers and
then you'll have the the big jacket
around it which is what keeps it from
for me actually being damaged and what
do we actually transmit over the fiber
well we encode digital signals into
analog pulses of light essentially
you're just modulating using a technique
called non-return-to-zero so it's not
quite on off on off but it's a very
simple modulation really really fast and
obviously most fibers working duplex
pairs if you ever work with any fiber
you typically what you'll do is use one
to transmit and one to receive so
opposite directions but you can't
actually send it over one strand and
talk about that later
so the basic fibers basic types and uses
two main types single mode fiber and
multimode fiber the difference is really
the size of the core so multimode has a
much wider core you know not quite 10x
but much significantly wider so that
multiple modes basically a mode of light
is light whether it will follow the same
transmission path or not so if you you
have a core that is small enough it will
only allow one mode of light it will
only propagate in one way if you have a
big enough core it will obviously
multimode that's the name
so SMF nine microns and there's
advantages and disadvantages to each one
so multimode specifically designed to be
used with cheap light sources so you
have a really wide cord that lets you
send an incoherent signal you don't have
to buy as nice expensive of an optic so
you can use LEDs you can use VC
effective axles which are vertical
cavity surface emitting lasers you can
you can use cheaper stuff and you don't
have to have as tight of a tolerance for
any of your connections so it just makes
things cheaper basically what you're
paying for by making it cheaper is you
no longer have long reach what happens
is you get you get multiplied multiple
modes of light and the fiber and you get
distortion to talk about that a minute
but basically your look
distances anywhere between 22 and max
500 meters depending on the type of
signal and an exact type of fiber
there's also recently a laser optimized
multimode which uses aqua colored cables
and that's designed to let you do 10
gigs up to 300 meters before you had
that you might do 10 gigs on multimode
to 20 meters there's the thing along
those lines single mode fiber is what
you use in any type of long reach
application so the core is small enough
that you can only have one mode of light
inside it and that lets you get several
thousand kilometres without without
completely regenerating the signal
obviously you still have to amplify and
dispersion compensation things that
we'll talk about later but you can
actually get really long distances with
single mode but obviously it's more
expensive you need tighter tolerances
you need lasers that are that are
specifically aimed things like that so
classic single mode fiber is called SM
f28
which you'll hear a lot that's actually
a product name from Corning but just
it's become kind of the de facto
standard for classic single mode fiber
there's actually a bunch of other types
out there there's low water peak fiber
there's dispersion shifted fiber there's
nonzero dispersion shifted fiber there's
things that we'll talk about in a bit
but single mode classically it just the
original stuff was SM f28 there's a
bunch of standardized color codes that
you will use when working with fiber so
orange is going to be like the the
jacket on the actual fiber orange is
going to be your basic 62 point 5 or 50
micron multimode fiber yellow is going
to be your standard single-mode fiber
aqua is going to be your 10 gig
optimized multimode and it's rare but
sometimes you'll see it blue is
polarization maintaining single mode
fiber talk a little more later so here's
kind of a little diagram showing what
happens inside the fiber when the core
is so wide in multimode and and even
inside a multimode there's two different
types of fiber there's what's called
step index and graded index it's not
really important to talk about that but
you can see that there's different types
of reflections that happen inside
whereas the single mode because it's
narrow though
enough that it can only propagate one
mode it just goes straight those there's
only one path the light can travel so
big question that lots of people ask is
what happens when you mix fiber types so
if you take a optic that's meant for
multimode fiber and you plug it to a
single mode fiber what happens you've
got a really wide signal that's now
hitting a really narrow core you're
gonna lose most of your light you're
just gonna go a couple of feet you're
gonna lose all your attenuation and your
lights go on you're not really gonna be
able to do anything with it if you take
an SMF optic which is a very narrow
signal and you put it into multimode
it'll work but it'll start to bounce
around inside the fiber and that's gonna
listen limit you by distance but you can
you can actually take an S a something
that's designed for single-mode put it
into multimode and you will get the
exact same distance that you would have
gotten if it was a multimode signal and
then there's a special type of cable
called a mode conditioning cable which
is basically just a precise fusion
splicing
single mode and multimode that lets you
get a little bit better distance so it
kind of sets the angle right and aims a
little bit better you'll typically see
this in older stuff where you're trying
to get maximum distance out of a
multimode fiber plant somewhere but
that's what happens it bounces around
there so talking about fiber optic
transceivers they have talked about this
before there's two links to
presentations there was a one gig
presentation there was a 10 gig
presentation a few years ago that I did
basically the the latest and greatest
updates looking at it five years later
SFP+ is now common there are long reach
optics that didn't exist before so you
can you can very easily do your 10 and
40 kilometer reach optics you've got
lots of hundred gig tuned b2b diem out
there 80 kilometer systems are out there
in some way some vendors are shipping
them some vendors are not quite shipping
them there's there's definitely some
minor magnitude questions on heat and
power drawn things like that but give it
a little bit more time you'll see ATS be
very common sfp+ is
definitely the format of choice for
anything enterprise anything
high-density anything the top of rack
type stuff but XFP is still the winner
if you want to do anything fancy so if
you want to do very narrow DWDM channels
if you want to do very long reach
systems and a great effect in any things
and we'll talk about a lot of this stuff
later but it's still where you have to
go if you want the good stuff so now we
get into just optical networking terms
and concepts so first off we talked
about optical power what is optical
power it's just the brightness the
intensity of the light so obviously as
light travels through the fiber you're
going to lose some of it it's either
going to be absorbed by the glass
particles or scattered you know physics
you're going to lose lose intensity and
it's going to turn into heat as it hits
particles the loss of intensity over
distance is called attenuation so what
we we measure that in is decibels the
same as a sound and a decibel is 1/10 of
a bell it's a logarithmic scale unit
that expresses the relationship between
two values that means it doesn't
actually measure anything on its own it
you have to measure relative to
something all it does is compare two
values so for example 0 DB is is no
change 3 DB is double - 3 DB is 1/2 plus
10 DB is 100x it's a logarithmic scale
so an optical networking if you want to
talk about what an actual value you have
to compare it to something and that's
called a DBM which is in decibels
relative to 1 milliwatts
so 0 DBM would be 1 milliwatt 3 DBM
would be 2 minus 3 would be 1/2 same
concept so if you completely lose your
signal you are negative infinity DBM
that's how you actually measure it but
it's actually very common for people to
confuse DB and DB especially if they're
they're out there working with a light
meter they'll they'll put it in a
relative mode that's designed to look at
testing off a test set somewhere and
they'll they'll get a completely wrong
value so you have to understand there's
two ways to measure it one is an actual
value relative to some
thing so you can say there's this much
light and one is this much change of
light so loss over over distance things
like that so why would we want to
measure it in decibels because light
just like sound follows what's called
the inverse square law so that means
that over distance the loss is
proportionately squared so for example
if you travel distance X you're going to
lose half your intensity you travel
distance X again you're going to lose
another half so at 2 X you're down to
25% it's a logarithmic scale at 3 extra
down to 12.5%
so using decibels basically cancels this
out it lets us do simple math when we're
working with it so you can say a 3 DB
change every time and and for every unit
X you can say well another 3 D another 3
DB 3 6 9 you don't have to do a
logarithm for math that's basically the
point so I threw in a little table that
just kind of shows the the DB and what
it actually is
so you can see you get 250 DB and you
get to one one hundred thousandth of the
original power it doesn't take much
towards me in there to have to
absolutely no signal at all another
concept that we talk about is called
dispersion so dispersion just means to
spread out and what happens in optical
networking is that will degrade your
signal there's basically two types of
dispersion that we care about dealing
with one is chromatic dispersion and
that just means different frequencies of
light will travel at different speeds
through a non vacuum so even a signal
that is is very optimized to be one
specific frequency
it still has a high point in a low point
and over distance that will cause it to
spread out and then you end up with a
smeared signal that you can't read and
the other one that that's less of a deal
but still out there is called
polarization mode dispersion and that's
caused by the fiber not being perfectly
cylindrical imperfections in the fiber
just moving it around you're going to
have if you know polarization of light
sunglasses where you turn it one way or
the other and you're seeing half the
signal you're going to have one type of
polarization traveling faster than
another if the fiber is not perfectly
shaved and what this causes is you get a
smeared out signal and now you're
sitting on the receiver side you can't
actually figure out what it is there's a
couple of transmission bands that we
talked about actually sending signals
into the first one is called the first
window 850 nanometer today we really
only use that for very short reach stuff
lots of multimode typically but that was
the very first window that people
figured out how to actually use descent
signal over the next one was the 1310
window it was the the point of zero
dispersion on classic single mode fiber
but it has pretty high attenuation so
today we typically use that for medium
reach stuff and then the third window
it's called the the C band which stands
for conventional band
it covers fifteen twenty five to fifteen
sixty five nanometers that has the
lowest rate of attenuation so if you're
trying to get long distances that's the
one that you want to use and it has
another benefit and that you can amplify
it with what's called an and erbium
doped fiber amplifier which we'll talk
about later but the very specific
properties of physics that allow this
one frequent frequency of light to be
amplified it's another reason that we
use it and then there's a fourth man out
there that's relatively uncommon except
for things like under undersea systems
and things like that called the L band
and that's just up in higher frequencies
so here's kind of a little chart showing
why the frequencies exist what you see
here is the loss relative to the wave
lengths what happens is there's there's
molecules of water that get trapped in
the glass and water absorbs light at
certain frequencies so you can see
there's these big Peaks where the signal
is completely unusable that's called the
water peak
so the original fiber a lot of a lot of
fiber that was deployed early has these
huge huge areas that are completely
unusable and obviously it's gotten a
little bit better over time now you see
modern fiber is it is not nearly as bad
but there's still these areas that you
don't want to use because you're going
to lose a lot more signal it's
frequency's there's a technique called
forward error correction what this does
is it adds a little bit of extra
information in the transmission so the
receiver can recover from small errors
basically you can you can think of it
like raid 5 for your wavelengths so for
example you might take a 10 gig signal a
10 point 3 to 5 gig signal which is what
a 10 gig Ethernet is and you turn it
into an 11 gig signal you put just a
little bit more overhead on it but now
you've got a lot more protection against
loss you can recover from from errors
and that's implemented using something
called called G 709 which is a digital
wrapper talked about a little bit more a
bit the benefits are you can take what
would be your loss over over losing
signal and recover from it much better
so lets you get really long distances
you might take a was previously an 80
kilometer optic optically and turn it
into 120 kilometer just by adding a
little bit of software to it there's a
technique out there called digital
rappers G 709 it's also called ot M
stands for optical transport network
basically it's a set of protocols that
let you work with wavelengths
generically so you can go between
vendors and not have to if you ever
bought a wavelength 5 10 years ago you
had a problem where everything had to
come back the sonnet and then that you
needed sonnet in order to work with
anything so OTN lets you take any signal
and still work with it so now I can go
to a carrier get a 10 gig Ethernet wave
and not be dependent on Ethernet scrappy
troubleshooting abilities they can
actually troubleshoot it in their
network by looking at it as OTN so it's
just a technique that a lot of people
use now we talk about wave division
multiplexing so we've division
multiplexing WDM we know that light
comes in lots of different colors what
you can do is take all those different
colors and put them down one strand and
have them not interfere with each other
you get ships in the night so you you
have a unit called a MUX that takes any
number
wavelengths and you end up with just
carrying all of the the signal on the
same fiber completely independent of
each other so there's a bunch of
different types out there the most
common or dense and coarse so here's
kind of an example of the different
channel spacings out there how wide they
are relative to anything so that's a
CWDM channel the huge one which is very
wide and then you've got a bunch of
smaller ones so that's a 200 gigahertz
that's a relatively old technology DWDM
modern stuff is is usually half that or
even less and there's more examples of
it later so CWDM is basically used to
mean anything that that's not DWDM
there's there's a popular version of it
which is eight channels like 1470
fourteen nine fifteen ten things like
that if you've got low water peak fiber
you can get more you can you can get
into eighteen channels of lower and
stuff you can also use it to mean just a
1310 1550 splitter you can take those
two very common signals put them on the
same fiber and have them not interfere
with each other sometimes it's called
GWT and ghetto wave division
multiplexing so DWDM is a much more
tightly packed system that's what you're
going to see in any type of commercial
long haul system you're gonna see that
based around this the c-band
obviously for for distance and it's it
uses what's called a standardized ITU
grid so that when you say channel 37 you
know that your channel 37 is someone
else's 37 or they're going to talk to
each other there's a bunch of different
grids out there depending on the spacing
so your your 200 gigahertz stuff that
was what you were seeing around 2000 era
these days you're not gonna see anything
less than 100 gigahertz which will give
you 40 channels in the c-band
most commercial systems at this point
are going to be in the 25 anything that
was deployed a few years ago might be in
the 50 but depending on how much money
you're paying you're gonna be in that
and the 25 s right now so that can give
you 160 channels in the c-band
on one piece of fiber the advantages
obviously CD BDM it's cheaper you need
less precise lasers you don't have to
too
worried about the the signal wandering
what actually happens it's not that the
signal itself is any wider it's that
it's free to move about you don't have
to have a precise ly manufactured lasers
you don't have to have the the cooling
be quite as nice if you've got a pretty
big window that you can send your signal
in DWDM you get a lot more channels but
you've got to you know deal with all
those those things and by staying
completely in the c-band you're going to
get the lowest attenuation so you're
gonna get the best distances and you're
going to be able to amplify the signal
which is any type of real network you're
gonna be building something like that so
here's a relative size comparison of the
different channels so that's a CWDM
channel is the whole thing and then
there's a there's a 200 to 150 Hertz
that show you how many channels you can
kind of put in and one thing there's a
bunch of other use places where WMS used
non-standard stuff so for example
there's a type of optic 410 gig called
the LX 4 and what this does is take for
non-standard channels and and put them
over the same fiber so you might have a
10 gig pluggable like as in pack and
what it's actually doing is sending four
different 2.5 gig waves across the the
fiber that lets you get longer distances
over multimode it had some advantages
for certain technology like xenpak which
actually talks the the router talks to
the optical via four four lanes anyway
so it's really easy for the Box to take
those four things turn into four
different signals put it in little tiny
muffs it's actually integrated into the
pluggable these days you're going to
start to see that for a hundred gig
hundred gig optical peer optical just
doesn't exist or it exists in the lab
it's not practical you can't do any
distance with it so what you you see out
there is a lot of four by 25 or ten by
ten things like that and obviously you
can use it for a 1310 1550 simple MUX is
just two channels there's a lot of
people that make optics that integrate
this so what happens is you you have an
optic and it only has a plug for one
thing what it's doing is it's got a
really tiny MUX integrated into the opt
that lets you send and receive over two
different colors of light on one strand
so for someone who knows nothing about
optical networking they can just buy
this one SFP plug it into their router
and just take one strand of their fiber
and then use the other one for something
else just instant doubling of capacity
so now we talked about a bunch of
optical networking components first off
for WDM you've got the MUX and the D MUX
short for multiplexer some people call
it a prism you can you can kind of think
of it like that that's not how it
actually works I'll talk about how it
actually works but you can think of it
as a prism where you send one piece of
light in and it splits it out into a lot
of different colors it's a very simple
device typically what you'll see is one
common port and a whole bunch of
individual channels it's completely
passive it doesn't require any power if
you're working with a commercial system
where you don't see any of this the
exact same component exists inside that
system they just hide it they put it on
a card that that powers up so you can
feel good about it but it's it's a
completely passive system and it doesn't
do anything other than split the light
most MUX is you're gonna see a duplicate
you're gonna see the exact same thing
twice for returns bit and receive most
modern stuff it's actually the exact
same thing it can work in the other
direction so you just put it into into
one unit the next thing is called an OEM
an optical add-drop multiplexer what
this lets you do is pass some channels
through while dropping others so you
might have fibre going across and you
might have this device here and you say
you want to pass 30 channels and
unmolested right through but you want to
drop 10 that you want to actually work
with so be able to talk to the a side
talk to the B side you you could you
could do this with a MUX and you would
just have to sit there take two muxes
and just do a bunch of short patch
cables and that would be silly so by
doing this you get a lot less loss and
and you can just for convenience factor
so
everything there's a modern device
called a Rotom which is a reconfigurable
om basically what this is is something
that you can log into the device and
reconfigure what channels you drop and
you can even do fancy things like multi
degree you don't have to have only one
side out on this side out you could have
three different directions that you can
add and drop stuff so let you design
really complex optical technologies
start apologies and things purely at an
optical layer they're relatively
expensive optical amplifiers let you
increase the intensity of the signal
there's a bunch of different types it
depends on the frequencies of light you
know different physics are required the
most common thing that most people deal
with is an edge via and erbium doped
fiber amplifier what that means is is a
piece of fiber that's doped with erbium
and you can by injecting
a laser of a completely different
frequency cause the stimulation of light
and these other frequencies you can make
the light get brighter so you have a
pump laser across this fiber and it
causes the the light to get excited and
amplified you have optical switches
which lets you do purely optical
interconnection without converting from
optical to electrical back to optical so
basically you've just got a little tiny
array of mirrors you've got these
microscopic mirrors that are controlled
by software so you can you can say link
of these two ports together and if you
want to change it you can you can aim it
to another port you'll see these used
for optical protection systems for
optical cross connect systems they're
relatively expensive but they're they're
really nice you can have have things
where if you detect the signal drops you
can just instantly switch which port you
talk to you can you can change to a
different fibre and probably do it so
fast that the protocols don't even know
anything happened basically these are
used inside of rotom's to implement
those sometimes called a W SSO
wavelength selectable switch so how does
a MUX and an OID I'm actually work
you have what's called an optical
bandpass filter there's these different
types of filters but what happens is
though there will be a filter that
reflects a certain frequency and passes
another frequency so you you send to a
bragg grating filter you send a signal
and it's going to pass through most of
it and reflect back another part of it
and use that in combination with what's
called a circulator you probably never
run across a circulator outside of
building a DWDM system but that's how
muxes are made so what it does is it's a
three port system and when something
goes in one port it when goes in port
one it comes out for two when it goes in
port two it goes out port three so let's
you kind of get a double pass at things
so here you see two circulators paired
up with a with a Bragg grating filter
and that's how you actually implement a
no idiom you'll also see it used for
dispersion compensation it lets you take
the same piece of fiber and run the
signal over it twice there's splitters
and optical taps so optical splitters do
exactly what they sound like they do if
they split the signal there's a bunch of
common things but the most common ones
are just like a 50-50 split err one area
where you might see that used is if
you've got very simple optical
protection say you've got two diverse
dark fibers and you want to use be able
to use both of them but you don't want
to actually pay all the investment
necessary to fully light these things
both ways what you can do is split the
signal in half send it down both and
then on the other side you've got a
device that purely looks at optical over
sea level and if it loses the light
because of a fiber cut or something it
switches to receiving the other one so
for a 3 DB hit you've now got instant
protection you can use a very cheap
system to protect hundreds thousands of
channels you know potentially millions
of dollars worth of stuff very simply
another common uses is a 9091 splitter
which you'll see for optical performance
monitoring so basically you're just
going to pull out one percent of the
signal and send it over to a monitor and
now this thing can by knowing that it's
one percent it multiplies
and it knows what's going over this
fiber what's happening on all the
different different frequencies so
there's actually a bunch of different
types of single mode optical fiber that
we talked about so we already discussed
that single mode is used for anything
that's long reach but all the different
types out there you've got your standard
SMF your classic SMF which is called us
an f28
you've got your low-water peak fiber
dispersion shifted fiber low loss fiber
nonzero dispersion shifted fiber bend
insensitive fiber we'll talk about a lot
of days so your standard classic SMF
like I said is actually a product name
for Corning it was actually optimized
for 1310 because that's where the lowest
rate of dispersion
yes dispersion occurs so the attenuation
is lower at 1550 but if for original
systems that were very concerned about
this version they didn't know how to
deal with it that was the the driving
issue low water peak fiber is modern
fiber that's been designed to reduce the
the water molecules that get into the
fiber so you see that we were talking
about before that that water peak where
you had a spectrum that was completely
unusable now you can start to use it
again dispersion shifted fiber was an
attempt to improve the dispersion at
1550 because that's where the longest
reaches it capable so what happens is
the the rate of which chromatic
dispersion occurs changes for different
frequencies of light and if you use
specially engineered the the fiber a
certain way you can shift the point
where that occurs to be centered around
1550 it turned out this was actually a
really bad thing people didn't know this
at the time but when you started running
DWDM over just straight dispersion
shifted fiber I mean you get the non
dispersion point you started causing a
bunch of nonlinear interactions what
would happen is you would take three
wavelengths that are supposed to be
ships in the night not talking to each
other and they would interact with each
other and produce a fourth phantom
wavelength bunch of physics this way
over my head but it just turned out to
be a huge hassle so everyone backed away
from this very quickly and moved to
something called non zero dispersion
shifted fiber
so you're you're still shifting to get
lower dispersion but you're putting it
just outside the signal you're actually
using you're not actually going to use
this this point that causes causes all
these nonlinear interactions and what
you end up doing is you engineer the the
fiber in two ways one your normal
transmission fiber it will will happen
it will disperse in a certain way and
then the engineer certain types of fiber
that will actually disperse the other
direction and you use that I'll talk
about this later for a dispersion
compensation
so after you've you've transmitted
eighty kilometers over the real fiber
then you take it and you run it through
a spool and you kind of compress it back
the other way so you you restore your
signal the other fiber types out there
you've got your your low attenuation
fiber at the expense of dispersion so
you'll see those and undersea systems
and things where you really really
really care about
attenuation you've got your Bend
insensitive fiber stuff you you use in
office buildings and things where people
can play with the fiber and not break it
it's it's not as good for transmitting
but it's you know you can you can
actually play with it
modern fibers usually like the specs
that we're talking about here the the
modern fibers that you can actually go
out and buy right now they're very good
a lot you should got to remember that a
lot of what's in the ground is old stuff
so you have to know what you're you're
working with so here's some examples of
different different types of fibers and
kind of how the dispersion and their
slopes classic SMF standards called g65
- and then you've got three different
three different types of very common
stuff you'll find a lot of true way of
leaf and terra light fiber out there
from corning and various people and you
see they have different slopes of
dispersion so now we talk about how you
actually engineer an optical network so
first off you have insertion loss even
the best connectors and splices aren't
perfect every time you plug two fibers
together you're not getting a perfect
perfect alignment you're going to get
some loss typical budgetary figures
somewhere around half a DB for a
connector but it actually depends
entirely on the type of connector and
and the the phrase insertion loss is
also used when you connect to a MUX
basically the penalty that you pay just
for inserting the fiber you're paying
something real life example you if you
plug it into a 16 channel DBM system
you're gonna see maybe 7 DB of loss
going through this DWDM just going
through internally all the components
that it uses and here you can see 3
different types of insertion losses that
you see when connecting cables 1
mismatched core size which we talked
about before but it can actually happen
in between even single mode fiber some
fibers will be 8 micron some will be 9
if there's any type of distance
difference you'll have mismatch course
you can have misaligned course or the
things don't quite meet up perfectly and
you can have an air gap between the
fibers just you don't fully insert the
fiber it'll still work but you've got
that that air in the middle and that'll
start to lose a lot of signal so when
you're building an optical network you
need to have an optical budget basically
when you look at something and it says
40 kilometers that doesn't really mean
anything that's that's a guideline you
can either do much better or much worse
depending on what you actually do with
the fiber and it's smart to leave some
margin in but it's gonna happen over
time
say there's a fiber cut and then someone
comes along and fixes it now you've
added a new splice say someone starts
moving patch cables around someone's up
in in a cable tray and starts start
shifting your fiber there's all kinds of
things that happen in real life that
changed the signal even over time the
transmitters will actually start to cool
off you'll you'll start to send less and
less signal as they age so what started
out as a really high emergent system
might go down over time but here's just
kind of a little diagram showing fiber
loss over distance the connector losses
the splice loss and you're trying to do
a little planning and make sure that you
stay within that budget here's just a
table of some of the common types of
losses typically the the real loss is a
lot better than the worst case loss but
it can happen factory-made connectors
field connectors fusion splice
connectors are going to have different
different things if you for example
you're out at a coal
like in a clinics and they they
terminate a fiber for you what they're
doing is a field terminated connector
and so that's going to have some loss on
it compared to buying a perfect pre-made
patch cable out of factory where it's
being done with a machine it's going to
do it perfectly you're gonna see
different rates of loss at different
frequencies so here's kind of just a
little table that you can look at you
can see that there's obviously a lot
more loss at 1310 than at 1550 and
what's called DB over kilometers when
you're actually working with amplifiers
you need to balance the power so when
you're working with amplifiers the the
game is not always consistent across all
wavelengths you might have one portion
of the spectrum that is amplified more
than another and you you there's a bunch
of consequences that happen if you don't
take care of this you caused a lot of
signal noise issues what happens is the
the total power and the system can only
be so much the amplifier can only do so
much and so when you've got ten channels
and now you you add five more channels
that changes the individual the
amplification that happens to each
individual channel and you need to to
flatten this out so you'll have a lot of
gain flattening amplifiers this what I
was talking about they have limits on
the the total power that they can put
into the system so just think a single
DWDM channel at 10 DB is only one
milliwatt that you put 40 channels in
there even though I've got four
milliwatts so that's gonna affect how
much you can actually amplify each
channel and you've got to remember that
this will change over time so for
example if you if you had just have a
standard um amplifier that's passing 40
signals and all of a sudden you lose
power in Iraq and and 20 of these
signals drop off it's going to change
instantly the total power in the system
so you need a good outfit that can
actually look at what you're trying to
achieve and kind of adjust the gain
dynamically to deal with dispersion you
have a dispersion compensation unit
which is basically just a big spool of
fiber with this slope in the opposite
direction so like I said you you run it
80 kilometers over
transmission fibre and then you run it
through one of these spools and you kind
of shift it back together the other
direction and you might throw a
circulator in there too so you get get
double the use over the same fiber
modern stuff is actually doing a lot
with electronic dispersion compensation
you that's basically what allows a lot
of 10-gig technology right now and
40-gig things like that you're doing a
lot of electronic compensation one thing
to keep in mind is that in the sfp+ spec
this was actually moved out it used to
be in an XFP the electronic dispersion
compensation happens on the optic and so
you can go out many years after you buy
your router and go buy whatever the
current state-of-the-art pluggable is
and have it be able to do maximum
distance if you've got an SP plus system
the electronic dispersion compensation
happens on the router itself and so you
you're tied to the quality of whatever
that box is for doing these long reach
things so a lot of people went out and
bought a lot of SP plus systems back
when they didn't have any long reach at
all and then found out that oh this
particular device isn't actually good at
working with no matter what optic I put
in there isn't actually capable of doing
the dispersion compensation but
dispersion is is a much bigger issue at
40 and 100 gigs so it plays a critical
role in actually making these things
possible optically you got the three RS
reamp Liffe Iying reshaping and retiming
with repeaters so 1r is reeling this
basically you just taking the signal and
you're making it brighter so you you get
a very low signal and you're now making
it bright enough that the receiver can
see it
the 2r is reshaping you're restoring the
original pole shape so you you know you
you need to actually be able to
distinguish the pulse to see if it
wasn't one or zero so you restore that
shape but you don't need to completely
decode the thing and then 3r is retiming
you're actually readjusting the spacing
of the the pulses at this point you're
usually just going electrical optical to
electrical and back to optical again to
get the full 3r regeneration
sometimes you'll see eye diagrams out
there basically this is just an
oscilloscope display of what is actually
happening so every time the signal
crosses it's a one or zero and this is
kind of what it looks like after it's
after it's gone through a fiber with
with a lot of impairments dispersion
things you end up with this big mess and
you can't tell what you actually got we
talked about bit error rates so what
happens is as you get impairments as you
get noise distortion dispersion loss of
signal you don't you don't just
completely die what happens you just
start taking errors they might even not
be noticeable at first you might just
have a very small percent of packet loss
and then as it gets worse and worse and
where should get more and more packet
loss and all of a sudden people start
complaining but the link is still up
still passing light that's passing
signal typically you try to target for a
bit error rate which is better than 10
to the thumb behind this 12 but as you
started to get down the end you you're
literally 1 DB of loss will cause a
tenfold increase and in theirs and then
all of a sudden you end up with a very
very arid length that if it's right on
the edge you might not even notice it at
first and then someone bends a cable and
all of a sudden it goes over the edge so
there's a bunch of tools of the trade
when you're working with fiber the first
is the optical power meter the light
meter is just going to measure the
brightness of the signal like I said
there's going to be on most fiber meters
two modes one which is absolute it says
I have this much light and that's going
to be DBM if you does not say DBM you're
in the wrong mode the other is a
relative mode so when you're testing
fiber you might have a known light
source that puts out some ount of signal
and you go to the other end of it and
you're in DB mode and you say well I've
lost this much over the span that's just
for testing fiber that's not for
measuring how much am I actually putting
out from my device so you need to make
sure that you're talking in the correct
unit literally if I had a nickel for
every time someone told me they just
measured 70 DB in my and my fiber
because they're in the wrong
it happens all the time so just want to
point that out make sure you're in their
correct mode you've got an OTDR an
optical time-domain reflectometer what
this does it lets you characterize the
fiber it sends pulses of light down and
it looks for reflections every time you
have a splice point or connector or
something that's not completely perfect
you're actually going to get reflected
light back you're gonna you're going to
hit an edge and something's going to
bounce back and you're actually going to
be able to characterize this and and see
exactly how far out these things occur
so here's a little diagram showing what
happens like you can you can see the
splice points you can see the the rate
of loss over distance so you'll
typically see this used when you when
you order a dark fiber or when you're
when you're testing something and you
want to know if the the spices are good
and the whole thing is engineered well
now we get to a bunch of fun questions
can't really blind myself by looking
into the fiber beware of big scary
lasers do not look into being with
remaining.i I actually I printed this up
on a t-shirt and I wore it when I got my
LASIK done the doctor loved it so lasers
are grouped into four main classes for
safety class one is completely harmless
there's nothing you can do short of
poking yourself in the eye with it
physically that can actually hurt you in
any way
it's either low powered or you can't
look at it so for example your your DVD
or blu-ray player has a high-powered
laser but it's sealed in a box and you
can't get at it when the thing is
running so it's a class 1 class tubes
are only harmful if you actually
intentionally stare at them you're crazy
and you're like I really want to want to
hurt myself class so laser pointers your
common laser pointers or class 2 is
things like that it's actually bright
enough to hurt you if you if you've sat
there and looked into it but don't do
that
class 3 shouldn't be viewed directly so
class 3 is broken up into into two
different things there's there's a new
system in an old system it used to be
called 3a and 3b now there's its 3r and
3b but basically the the difference is
whether you have a reflex to look away
so if it's a certain frequency of light
that you
I can't see you don't have that reflux -
ah I'm not gonna look at that
that typically get you into into a 3b
system and then class for burn smells
thing starts fires destroys altar on
anything in that category so so the
lasers that we work with and networking
are all in the infrared spectrum the
human eye stops seeing above about 600
animators so even 850 you're deep into
into infrared there's actually two
categories of infrared called
near-infrared and far infrared the
difference being what the eye will
filter to you know because your eye is
not meant to see an infrared it's
actually does a very good job the cornea
just blocks it so the the near-infrared
is actually worse because your eye
doesn't do as good a job of blocking it
so the long distance stuff the the 1550
systems your eye actually does a really
good job of blocking that it's what's
called IRB but the the the near-infrared
systems have a potential to get in
basically if you look at any router out
there there's not a single router out
there that you can go to pull pull a
pluggable gbics impact XFP whatever that
is not a class one laser these things
put out power at most in the in the one
to 2 milligrams its it does nothing
optical amplifiers are where you start
to cross into the point of actually
putting out enough power that you could
potentially damage your eye so if you
throw something into a very powerful
amplifier that's when you'll you'll
start to cross into the the 3 B range or
a 3 ro 3 B and D do BDM systems in
general if you if you take 40 channels
and you put them all together on one
fibre you've now got a 40 X signal that
can actually start to cross into the the
point that you actually care so the
question is should I wear my goggles to
the Colo probably not generally speaking
everything that you're gonna see on a
router directly is going to be a class
one just doesn't matter you don't you
most of the time you don't see anything
anyway so there's not much point in
looking at it but you don't need to
freak out over having dust caps on
everything it's not a real issue
even on dbvm systems as soon as the the
signal hits the air you're not taking
the fiber and holding it right up to
your eye you're gonna start to lose
signal rapidly and like I said anything
above 1,400 is gonna fall into the IRB
category and I just going to filter it
so why even look into the fiber at all
you can't you can't actually see the
signal so there's there's no real
benefit to it when you look at an 1815
850 signal and you see red what you're
actually seeing is a sideband you're
seeing the thus the very edge of red
that's out of what you're actually
trying to transmit but the the generator
is not perfect one cool trick is that
digital cameras actually can't see
infrared so here's a picture of a
digital camera photographing a TV remote
control and you can you can very easily
see the infrared signal so you can take
your phone put it in camera mode hold it
up the fiber and see if you've got light
on a bunch of different panels it's a
quick trick next question I get a lot is
can optical transceivers be damaged by
overpowered transmitters yes and no it's
not actually the transmitter that does
it it turns out that all transmitters
basically transmit about the same signal
the the difference between a ten
kilometer and 80 kilometer optic the
transmitter might only be 3 DB and it
might not even be that much the way that
Longreach optics get better is they have
more sensitive receivers and that's the
part that you actually care about
damaging not the the overpowered
transmitter so there's two different
thresholds out there there's what's
called the saturation point it's the
point where the signal is so bright that
you you just can't read anymore so you
start taking errors and then there's the
the point where you actually hit damage
these differ depending on the exact make
of the optic you can look it up it's in
the spec sheet but generally speaking
speaking only 80 kilometer stuff has
this issue so here's kind of a little
diagram showing what the you know you
can't read this very clearly but showing
what the the transmit and receive
windows are so you see that like a 10
kilometer optic you can't do any of the
above you nothing that you send or
receive is going to fall into damage or
blindness threshold with with a 40
kilometer optic you have the potential
if you take a 40 kilometer optic and you
run it through six inches of fiber
you're going to be so bright that you
can't decode the signal but you're not
going to damage anything with an 80
kilometer optic if you take to 80
kilometer optics back to back and you
run it through six inches of fiber
you're crossing the point where he
actually calls them damage to the optic
so that's where people say plan this
accordingly use an attenuator use
something don't just use any type of
optic without without worrying about it
big question that I get asked a lot is
do I actually need to be concerned about
Bend radius yes you do because remember
that fiber has to enter at a certain
critical angle in order to propagate one
cool thing out there is you can actually
check the signal on a fiber with a
little clamp four meter like this you
can actually just clamp it onto the
fiber and it'll bend it a certain way
and it can actually see the light
leaking out through the cladding and
through through this so you can get a
light meter and see what's actually on
there it's called a macro Bend there are
bent and sensitive fibers out there you
won't see them in data center use
because they're they're not as good for
for optical signal so just don't tell
your fiber up into knots big question I
get asked a lot can you make these two
transmitters on different wavelengths to
talk to each other more or less yes
basically what happens is all optical
receivers or wideband so if you're in
the laser category you're going to be
able to decode anything between 1260 to
1620 nanometers
you're not going to be able to make an
LED or an SX 850 talk to a NLR but
you're going to be able to make a 1310
and a 1550 talk to each other absolutely
mini DB to be dim systems are actually
built around this you don't need two
strands of fiber for transmitting
receive you can put them on two
different frequencies on the same fiber
and receive on anything
the only gotcha here is that when you
use an optical power meter it actually
has to be calibrated to the frequency
that you're using so if you've got the
power meter set to 1310 you're expecting
a 1310 signal and you go to 1550 it's
going to be wrong by a few DB so you
need to know what you're doing to have
power meter work correctly but otherwise
it works perfectly well here's obscure
optical networking trick you don't
actually need your a pair of long reach
optics to get over the same distance
what happens is say you you want to go
some good distance and you've got an L R
Nene or you got a 1310 that does ten
kilometres and you've got a 1550 that
does forty kilometres what happens is
the 1550 signal will have a lower
attenuation because it's in the right
frequency and the 1310 signal will be
landing on the the optic that has a more
sensitive receiver and it'll just work
you'll probably be able to get 30-plus
kilometers maybe in 40 out of
mismatching an L R and an ER it works
perfectly well obviously plan your
system check you check your power plan
if you're going to use this but it works
very well another common question is do
I really need to clean the fiber to have
it work right the reason you need to
clean it is not typically for
attenuation it's for reflections if you
get dust or or things in there you'll
calls reflections in a way that you
won't necessarily see on a power meter
but that will disrupt your signal so yes
any fiber is is good and I throw in a
link to lots of detailed documentation
on that other miscellaneous fiber
information people only know how fast is
the light actually travel in fiber it's
very simple to do the math on this so
the speed of light is about 300 300
million meters per second and you can
actually go look up the refractive index
of the course so like an SM f28 has a
refractive index of one point four six
eight that means that light travels at
you know the speed of light divided by
one point four six eight it's about two
hundred two hundred thousand kilometers
per second do a little math you can see
that it's about 126 miles per
millisecond and remember that when
you're doing a traceroute
you're actually looking at round-trip
time so cut that in half again about a
hundred hundred kilometres per
millisecond is what you're going to see
based purely on distance this is going
to cause your latency Xin ping and
traceroute why do I see a much higher
value in real life remember the Phi
there's never late in a straight line
it's it's late in rings it's late in
ways that try to go to hit population
centers or or run through tons of patch
panels so there's always a lot of
overhead you'll in the long distance
systems you'll have dispersion
compensation spools so you're adding
you're adding distance they're a little
bit about the future of optical
networking technology right now most
systems use what's called energy
non-return-to-zero it's a very simple
system but there's actually more
efficient modulations out there
everything from dual binary to dpsk to
dqpsk
you're starting to see clam stuff being
being looked at it doesn't really matter
much outside of these technologies we'll
let you be more spectrally efficient so
here's kind of a diagram showing that
within the the same 25 gigahertz signal
at nrz you might be able to send 11 gigs
I'd do a binary you can now send 22 at
dqpsk you can now send 44 that's
basically the basis of anything above 10
gig technology at this point optically
where we're at 40 gig is the max there
there's no optical hundred gig in any
kind of practical sense so to make 40
gig work and actually get good distance
you need to use techniques like this in
there so they're starting to become more
and more common another concept that
people talk about is alien wavelengths
so normally when you run a DDM system
it's run by one person but what happens
if I want to so right now if I go out
and sell a wavelength my customer
doesn't doesn't know about the color
they don't know about the DD medium
system they get handed that was called a
gray uncoloured and what that means I'm
now paying for conversion on both ends
as well as the optics to talk to the
customer and the optics and talk to
myself internally what would happen if I
could just go to the customer and say
hey you get this frequency you send your
own color light that's called alien
wavelengths it has an advantage in cost
obviously the disadvantage is if you're
working with an amplified system you
need to know what is being transmitted
in that or someone
well customer whoo out and and replug
something else in the wrong way and it
will screw up the amplification but if
you're just doing a very simple
unamplified system you can absolutely do
this and there's people starting to to
look at it as a product and that's
basically it
questions anybody biggest challenges
with deploying WDM in a production
environment mostly just a matter of big
challenges it's relatively simple when
you when you know what you're doing the
big challenges are if you've got to
amplify the system you you get into
something that's very quickly very
difficult to maintain if you've got
complex rings OEM things like that
happening it becomes a lot more
complicated than just a simple
point-to-point system most people can
figure out a point-to-point system very
quickly and most of the time it actually
works out very well but when you when
you start getting into OEMs when you
start getting into amplifying maintain
the network correctly to do that that's
when he gets tricky yeah
a margin for just budget it depends you
can you can go look up there there's all
kinds of guides out there that to kind
of show you what you should plan for I
would typically it entirely depends on
the system I would typically want to do
something at least like like five DB to
deal with people in in the in the cable
trays it happens all the time you you're
a third party Colo and you you order a
new cross connect and they get up there
start running the cable and they they
jostle it and you if you've ever graphed
the the transmit power you can see when
when they do that when they start
bending fiber and things you can see
some variance so you just have to keep
that in mind and set a value that you're
comfortable with but there's lots of
guides out there where you can figure
out exactly how to do that to your your
goals to go beyond 80 kilometer
basically nothing so 80 kilometer is
about the most that you get out of a
single transmitter without doing
something like amplifying fact is is the
technique that you use to get past 80
kilometer but you're doing that with a
software trick so there's people that
are making optics that integrate the
feck encoders and receivers actually in
the optics so your host box doesn't need
to know about it other times there's
vendors like Cisco and ASR nine case
makes a line card that will actually
send a signal so that lets you take it
from 80 kilometer to go to 120 but
really what you hit is a point where
there's only so much signal you can put
down if you send it any brighter you get
noise or you get something that's
outside of the power spec of what you
can actually do especially with sfp+
you've got a look at 1.5 mil awhat draw
cap on these things so there's only so
much you can do pass that point so
you're never going to see too
kilometer maybe you will but you're not
going to see it with anything other than
techniques like feck things like that
yeah or just very improved receiver
sensitivity or protocol stuff so there's
a lot of I've seen 200 kilometer one
Giga optics because we're now at the
point where one gig is so easy to to
work with that we can we can have very
very very sensitive receivers that can
decode that because it's not modulating
nearly as fast but things get
exponentially harder as you as you get
faster so really what you're what you're
seeing right now the future is figuring
out how to send 40 and 100 gig signals
over long distance so that 100 gig
becomes something more than a fancy
cable management solution it's it's a
different type of amplification so
typically you'll see that under on
undersea systems different frequencies
of light use a different type of
amplifier that's that's really the
difference it's not it's not a different
technique or anything like that
significantly Oh Raman amplification
anybody else yeah
not my area of expertise but what people
are working with a multi motor right now
is doing lrm is very popular so if you
want to get any any type of distance in
the 200 300 meter range you're still
going to need some type of fiber but lrm
is a very enterprise solution the
interesting thing is that single mode is
actually cheaper to manufacture than
multimode so what you're what you're
doing is to be cheap is not in the fiber
it's in the optics it's in the the
components these days the cost of of lr4
SFP+ is so cheap that most people in
large production environments say it's a
lot easier to standardize on single mode
everywhere than it is to try and save
twenty bucks by doing some LR and some
SR anybody else yeah
on what not something I'm super familiar
with but there's a lot of safety
techniques out there and that's one for
if you've got a fiber cut you don't want
a extremely powerful amplified signal
going out and so systems will detect a
cut and turn off the laser it's a good
safety feature but it's not something
that you'll typically encounter outside
of a very commercial very long haul type
system you're not going to see this on
any routers or anything like that
nope so it's it's not like load
balancing at layer two or layer three
it's completely layer one it happens at
the bit level where you see these
systems used so getting into 10-gig
certainly if you wanted to do anything
over over multimode at the time before
lrm came out you definitely needed
something like LX for you needed to not
be doing a 10-gauge signal but to be
doing for 2.5 gig signals the same thing
at 100 gig you need to be doing a 25 gig
signal because an actual hundred gig
modulation is just too difficult right
now to do commercially but no it doesn't
it doesn't channelize it in any way it
just does it purely an optical layer so
looking back at the looks for for
example between your router and your
xenpak it actually happens over four
data channels already anyways when you
move to XFP and exit p+ that was the
first time that it actually moved into
happening at a at a pure 10 gig signal
so this this type of stuff happens on
the interconnection between components
on the circuit boards all the time
already anyways in that case it actually
made it easier because you didn't need
the sterilizer you didn't either surges
anybody else all right thank you very
much