later on we'll have you log into a
virtual machine running on Amazon Web
Services and to know which machine
you're gonna log into you're gonna use
your row number in this roster page you
also are probably gonna want to watch
the slides on your own laptop you might
want to cut and paste the commands later
on during the hands-on and so this the
second link should give you you should
take you to the slide deck
so I'm going to wait a couple more
minutes and then kind of just repeat
what I just said and and get started
yep I'm good thank you
so again we're gonna we're gonna have
some hands-on exercises probably about
halfway 2/3 the way into this tutorial
and if you want to participate in that
part you need to go to this first URL
and put your name in the spreadsheet and
make a record of the row number in that
spreadsheet because you're going to use
that to determine which VM to log into
so my name is Steve Wallace and I'm the
acting executive director of something
called in center in Center is located at
Indiana University and we do education
in translational research and networking
focusing mostly on Software Defined
Networking Chris small is one of the
researchers within center and Chris set
up some of the virtual technology that
we're going to use to walk through the
tutorial ask questions at any time we
the more questions the better this
workshop usually is a full-day workshop
and so I've kind of hacked at it to make
something that's gonna fit ninety
minutes and I've not done it in this
format before in this time period for
those of you who've just walked in part
of the tutorial will be hands-on and if
you would like to participate in that
you should go to the URL on the screen
and take take you to a Google Doc
spreadsheet put your name and email
address you want to be anonymous you can
put a fake name and email address but
it's important that put something in
there so that you have a row number and
you remember that row number as you'll
use that row number to select the VM
that you're gonna log into for the
hands-on exercises
okay we'll go ahead and get started
anybody trying to get on the roster
spreadsheet and isn't able to for those
walking in we're gonna say hands-on
exercises during part of this tutorial
if you want to participate you need to
log into this the first URL on the
screen which is just tinyurl.com
slash name nano at 57 - roster and
besides collecting marketing information
from you the purpose of that spreadsheet
is to assign you a unique number so we
can tell you which PM to login to okay
we're calling this open flow in 90
minutes we'll see if that works again
I'm the acting executive director of
something called in center at Indiana
University and easiest way to explain in
center is its I call the research arm of
the globalnoc which is located at IU
there is a demo of open flow software
and hardware next door I think that's
going on most of the day today and
tomorrow they're hours posted on the
sheet but you can go in there and
actually see this stuff working Indiana
University has developed a service that
runs on a nationwide research network
called Internet - it's a production
service and they have a really cool
orange box over there that that actually
goes to the Arctic with computer gear in
it normally
we got some more people coming in I'm
just gonna I'll do this just this this
will be the last time we're gonna have
some hands-on component of this later
and if you want to participate in that
please go to the URL at the top of the
screen and just tinyurl.com
nano in 57 - roster you'll need to know
what row your name is associated with in
the spreadsheet to select the correct VM
to log in to tell you what will come
back to the slide right before we start
the hands-on stuff again my name is
Steve Wallace you're welcome to send me
e-mail just SSW at iu and this is for
small he's CH small a little bit about
the tools we'll be using today when we
get to the hands-on exercises we're
gonna use Amazon Web Services we're
gonna fire up VM instances in their ec2
service we've created an Amazon machine
image that contains all the stuff you
might want to play with if you're gonna
play around with OpenFlow and we've made
it public so after this tutorial should
you want to play some more with the same
tools you should be able to do that
pretty easily for those of you not
familiar with Amazon Web Services you
create an account on AWS and get a fair
number of hours I forget how many hours
but hundreds of hours free on their
micro instances when you first get your
account so you'd be able to set this up
and use these tools for free
the other tool that we're gonna another
tool that we're gonna be using is
something called open V switch so open V
switch is one of the items on the Amazon
machine image that we'll be using today
open V switch among other things can act
as an open flow switch and it also comes
with some utilities to make that are
good at debugging open flow switches and
it also has a component that can act as
an open flow controller we're gonna be
using us a network sniffer called
Wireshark you probably many of you
probably familiar with Wireshark I
believe it's the case that that the
default distribution of Wireshark does
not include the open flow dissector and
so you have to build a special version
and the Amazon machine image that will
be using has that version of Wireshark
and we're gonna be using in something
called mini net which is an open source
virtual network - all you can
essentially design networks with
arbitrary topology on your laptop and it
can the the switching components in
those networks can be under open flow
control so you can play around with the
network of any kind of topology it
supports open flow and in fact I
mentioned earlier next door they're
demoing some software that's used in a
production network to provide
essentially circuits unto me and their
bandwidth on demand using open flow and
when they develop that software they use
mini net as their test environment
so one of the one of the difficulties
with explaining open flow is it's sort
of like talking about HTML and trying to
get across to folks early in the day
that you know HTML actually will change
every our entire life but we're gonna
start with these tiny components these
just tags so OpenFlow itself is pretty
simple
it's pretty basic but I think it has
potential to change the way we do
networking certainly software-defined
networking does and it open flows an
interesting example of that we're gonna
talk most about today mostly about this
sort of the low-level stuff and we're
not gonna really show any polished open
flow applications but we'll talk about
some innovative uses of open flow okay
so logistics here if you want to do some
of the hands-on exercises participate in
hands-on exercises later in today's
session you need to go to this tiny URL
and put your name in a spreadsheet how
many people do we have so about 27 have
you have done that so far
and we'll be using you'll be using the
row number on that spreadsheet to
connect to some virtual machines running
on Amazon Web Services to do the
exercises and although we'll do that a
little bit later when we want to go
ahead and get you started down that
directions so if you want to fully
participate in hands-on part and the
hands-on part will be useful even if
you're not doing it hands-on we'll be
talking through most of it but if you
want to do it you're gonna go ahead and
want to open up two terminal sessions
and you should open up those terminal
sessions username open flow at VM and X
and X gets replaced with a row number in
that spreadsheet so don't pick a random
X actually use the row number in the
spreadsheet
so so SSH you know open flow @vm
whatever the number is in the
spreadsheet training dot in Center which
is spelled awkwardly I ANSI n TR e dot
org and the password is open flow you
can also point your browser you'll need
to also do this so you're gonna do two
terminal sessions and then we used to
have folks use X and X server on their
laptop to you to work with Wireshark but
apparently most people have just gotten
over X and and when we have a class it's
too difficult to work through getting X
installed for everybody so we have
Wireshark available via something called
guacamole so if you point your web
browser to VM X X being the number again
from that row number in the spreadsheet
dot training dot in Center spelled that
weird way dot org port 80 90 / Baca moly
you should get an html5 rendering of an
Ambu - desktop running Wireshark and
we'll get to the problem you're gonna
have with this in more detail later but
Wireshark when it's running this
configuration spits up an error dialog
box and you have to find that dialog box
on the screen and dismiss it before you
can use it so I'm gonna leave this up
here for just a few more seconds so
people can get it the salient point is
you need to go to the roster spreadsheet
tinyurl nanog 57 - roster sign-in put
your name email you can put a fake name
and fake email if you want to remain
anonymous but that's gonna get you a
unique row number and you're gonna use
that row number to determine what VM you
login to and where you point your web
browser
how many people are gonna do the
hands-on stuff okay anybody having
problems getting to the Google Doc or
SSH again when you go to the
registration page when you when you go
to the registration spreadsheet one
purpose of putting your name in the
spreadsheet is to reserve a number and
the number is the row in which you put
your name so if you look to the left of
spreadsheet there'll be a number you
know the first one will be two because
I've you know the headings take up one
and and so forth okay so I'm gonna I'm
gonna go to the next page okay normally
when we give this talk it's a full-day
talk and we go into a lot of detail and
please stop me if things are not making
sense because we've really stripped us
down and we have a test of it I can
share our test what is open flow so open
open flow is is both a protocol and an
API for controlling the forwarding
behavior of Ethernet switches in
something called the software-defined
Network now that you can have
software-defined networks that have
nothing to do with open flow but open
flow is a nice open standard that we can
use to talk about a specific kind of
software-defined network and open flow
initially was released by the clean
slate program at Stanford University it
came out of some security work basically
some PhD students wanted to design a
network that by default had no
connectivity so today you know we
connect to the wireless network here and
you've got global connectivity well you
could imagine certain agencies of the
federal government would be interested
in a network where you
connected and you could get to nothing
without making a request it's being
authenticated and that request being
authorized and then the network itself
actually setting up connectivity to just
what you're requesting and and what
you're authorized for and so they wanted
to do this on a pretty granular network
control plane scale and they want so
essentially they want to be able to do
this per TCP flow and so they needed
some way of signaling to the network how
to forward things as small as individual
TCP flows and what came out of that was
this open flow thing so that's kind of
work I started so initially Stanford
released the protocol and
did I do something wrong okay
sort of like the Super Bowl only not for
30 minutes
so initially Stanford released the open
flows back but then industry got real
interested and Industry sort of spun up
this thing called the open networking
forum excuse me
the open networking foundation that
should not say forum the open networking
foundation is is kind of a new kind of
standards body has board of directors
and on the board are companies like
Google Microsoft Goldman Sachs which
telecom Verizon interesting none of
those companies make hardware or at
least make hardware that they would
actually sell they're very much
interested in this standard taking off
so there is an ecosystem over use that
word like everyone an ecosystem of
products and services that conformed it
us back because they need to be able to
use that stuff and so then the more
folks that are making a making equipment
that supports staffs back and truly
interoperate the better the Verizon's of
the world can take over the world it
offer all sorts of communications and
sorry if there any Verizon people in the
room I don't mean that badly most of the
material we're gonna talk about today is
based on open flow 1.0 1.0 is kind of an
interesting version of the spec it's the
first version of the spec that you could
get software and hardware that claim to
conform to it it's fairly limited and
but being limited vendors were able to
take existing equipment you can kind of
upgrade firmware and be able to do some
open flow 1.0 kinds of things open flow
has evolved quite a bit in the last year
and we're now up to open flow 1.3
which is way different than 1.0 and
there was a big jump at 1.1 and we'll
talk about that in a bit a couple couple
more things that are important to point
out so the open networking foundation is
not like the I Triple E it's not like
the ITU it's not like the ITF so it's
currently they have I think 90 members
members pay 30 grand a year to be a
member of the Oana those members agree
that if they contribute intellectual
property if they help contributes
additions to the specification they
require intellectual property that they
own to implement or its implement
efficiently that they'll share it under
reasonable terms with the other members
of the onf they also are those 90
members are the folks that are working
in the working groups to expand the
specification so not quite as open but
the board members have an interest in
making this happen and there was a is
anybody here from Google so you can
correct me if I if I say something wrong
last I think it was in in so there's a
meeting called the open networking
summit and the last one I attended there
were 900 people there and the one
previous to that I think there were 300
so this is a rapidly growing group of
folks and Google did one of the
plenaries and they talked about their
transition to open flow so Google has
basically two networks they have their
network that faces the public that we
use when we type google.com and then
they have the network that interconnects
their data centers they have a dozen or
more data centers throughout the world
and they started on a project to convert
the control of the devices that switch
data among the data centers to open flow
and there at this meeting saying that
we've done it not that we're planning to
do it not that we're in the process of
converting that Network to open flow
that vote but that we have already done
it so the network that cares more
traffic the network that carries all the
flows among those data centers the
forwarding the packets is determined by
open flow capable switches they also
showed a picture of the switch they
built which I found fascinating because
you know you've been reading the trade
press and you know somebody finds a
little Google switch in Kansas and it
gets all kinds of press everybody's
curious about what they're really
building and they're pretty tight-lipped
about it some analysts figured out a few
years ago that there were more ports
being made than being shipped by the
known switch manufacturers so it's
pretty clear that people like Google
were building switches and large numbers
of them because there was this missing
port problem so during this presentation
Google shows a picture of his switch and
you know it's the big it's has a lot of
ports on it switch they built and during
the Q&A a guy comes up from the audience
this is can you tell us more about your
switch and Google says there's nothing
really special about the switch and we
don't want to make any more of them and
there are a lot of vendors in the room
and I almost felt that was a setup I
mean I think Google was signaling we've
moved our entire network at least inner
datacenter networks you open flow we had
to build our own switches but we don't
want to keep doing that hint hint
so that would you know so this stuff is
real certainly real in the datacenter
okay so let's talk a little bit about
today today we typically buy these
appliances and an Ethernet switch would
be a simple example of an appliance but
we buy routers and firewalls and all
these things they typically come in the
form of an appliance and they have a
high-speed data plane where there's some
specialized hardware that makes that
does that's able to forward packets at
high speed and then there's sort of a
control plane that provides the features
that sit upon that and typically the
interaction between the data plane and
the control plane is that the the data
plane Hardware is table driven and the
control plane populates those tables so
you the data plane usually have has
hardware features like cams or T cams
and then the control plane will populate
the memory that drives the behavior of
those t cams and network processors and
you and you know when you buy a Cisco or
an HP or whatever you are brocade the
features you get are usually implemented
in this embedded operating system that's
part of the control plane that's part of
the appliance and and that is in some
ways much of the value that you're
getting from a particular vendor is the
set of features the reliability of those
features and so forth sits in that
embedded operating system in the in the
appliance in a software-defined network
model you separate out the control plane
from the data plane and the data plane
continues to look very similar it has
this high-speed hardware but if that's a
table driven data plane the formation
and the maintenance that table instead
of being done by software that's running
on the appliance like the switch is
actually outside of the device and we
call that a controller in in open flow
parlance we call that the Oklahoma flow
troller so you have a protocol that the
open flow controller uses to manage this
table in the in the high speed
forwarding device and you also have an
abstraction of that table that in an API
for manipulating that abstraction and so
basically you develop software running
on this controller to implement the
features of the slash and this has a lot
of advantages in its difference and
there probably some downsides but now I
have a regular server running a
operating system and able to easily
throw lots of CPU cores and memory and
have developers work and in a
well-understood environment to develop
those features so I can write code on my
Linux box that is going to implement
features in my network even features
that require very high speed because the
control is centralized it can be
coordinated better when Google talked
about the advantages to switching of
this model for their inter data center
network the specific advantage is that
they were seeing immediately we're - one
is they described their ability to more
easily simulate and understand what
happens under different failure
scenarios so you've got a bunch of boxes
talking different routing protocols in a
link fails or box fails these are all
distributed systems that are healing and
understanding what their state will be
under any particular failure condition
is somewhat fuzzy depending on how
complicated it is you have timing issues
and they're all acting as autonomous
system is trying to understand what the
network looks like and how they should
behave in this new configuration so
Google said one of the nice things was
if you have central control that problem
is easier to solve that you you are
centrally forcing the behavior of all
these distributed devices
they're not communicating back and forth
to each other and doing it autonomously
so understanding what things will happen
for any particular failure is much
easier this led them to be able to run
links of higher utilization so what they
said was now that we better understood
how things will fail we're able to run
our links of higher levels of
utilization because we have a higher
degree of certainty and understanding
what won't happen when any particular
failure takes place so there's this
advantage of having sort of this central
control over your network domain in that
you have the full view right there
it's consistent now yeah it may vary
between that central view and what's
really happening in all your devices but
you have this you have this view that's
self consistent its central you're
developing features on a real operating
system with normal software developer
tools and and that puts you in a
different place it enables you to adapt
more quickly to adding features and it
gives you some other advantages as well
doesn't come without some pain and when
somebody says what is Software Defined
Networking the core of Software Defined
Networking is the separation of the
control and data plane and the
centralization of
great question so the question was if
you are doing the features in the
controller that how do you get the line
rate out of the device and if you think
about it today when we look at these
appliances you have this embedded
operating system and control plane that
can't do anything at line rate and
basically that control plane is setting
up tables whether they're fibs and
routers or whether they're forwarding
tables with ACLs and T cams as a part of
layer 2 equipment that control plane is
basically maintaining those tables and
then the high speed hardware is using
what's in those tables to determine how
to do things at line rate and so what
you're moving off of the appliance is
the maintenance of the tables not the
high speed forwarding capability you
know there are corner cases where things
don't work well but and I'll show some
more specific examples of that so again
in a software-defined network and open
flow networks specifically you have this
centralized device the controller and
you might think of the features and the
value-add is being there rather than in
the switches and you could think well
that might be kind of disruptive for
some of the companies I deal with you
might for example buy a particular
controller based on the set of features
it supports and have some flexibility in
which switches you buy as long as they
have enough capability to work with that
controller the way this appears to be
working out is is there are incumbents
hardware manufacturers that are making
their own controllers they're making
their own OpenFlow controllers and their
software companies making their own you
know startup software companies nasira
was one that was purchased by VMware for
1.2 billion not too long ago there's
another startup called big switch
and these thoughts are just making the
controller so they're making features
for networks but they're not actually
making any hardware they're just making
this software and the controller you can
think of it as sort of your network
operating system and that's running on
top of Linux probably but you think of
the controllers the network operating
system and it has some built-in features
the controller manufacturers has put a
bunch of features in that will compel
you to buy their controller but in
addition to that they have it's a
platform for applications to be
developed upon so you have the
controller excuse me the controller
vendors features and then they're
exposing an API that can run
applications written by third parties or
maybe the customer maybe you have a
particular thing that you need to do to
comply with lawful intercept or some
legacy bridge stuff that you need to do
and you write an application that runs
on the big switch controller or maybe
there's a company that specializes in
payment card industry security
compliance and maybe they write an
application that runs with the big
switch controller and so you start to
have this application platform the
network operating system and a
programmable network and it can change
the way you look about how you would
address features you know there's a new
buzz about Network function function
virtualization you know why don't you
take this to another step and be able to
put network functions in these devices
like firewalls and when accelerators and
that kind of thing and open flow can be
used
you know in a way that supports that
kind of evolution as well by by enabling
you to finally tune where things go in
the network and do that from a central
location
okay so one of the more important
abstractions in an open flow environment
is something called the flow table now
unfortunately
okay for those of you who have the
slides up but I'll try to be very
descriptive one of the most important
abstractions for open flow is the flow
table and unfortunately the open flow
spec the 1.0 spec labels some of the
items in the flow table differently than
the 1.1 SPAC so you have this flow table
it's basically a 2-dimensional table and
you have columns and one of the columns
are it's called header fields and these
are things that are used to identify a
network packet that you want to affect
it's a tiny tiny URL / Nanog 57
lowercased - slides and we
okay so this important two-dimensional
thing it's called the flow table at a
high level what's going on is you're
using the open protocol to maintain
what's in this so this is controlling
the actions we can do things let me go
back here and then once you identify a
packet is is when you want to do
something - there are actions that you
can do that packet and the actions are
pretty straightforward you know you can
forward the packet and when you forward
a packet you can forward it out all the
ports you can forward it through the
controller
that's called a packet in event
you can tell the packet to take the
normal path of the device so some open
flow devices can have kind of a split
personality where they're running up and
flowing in one context and something
else maybe a firewall in another context
and within open flow you can say take
this packet outside the open flow
context and you can modify the packet so
some of the actions include modifying
the packet you can essentially modify
the same fields that you use as header
fields to identify the packet and then
there are a bunch of counters so here's
some more specific examples
so in this make-belief flow table I
might have something that says if the if
the ingress report was - if packet came
in on core - then I want to drop the
packet simple role I might say if the IP
address is 129 79 1 1 maybe I want to
rewrite that IP address because I'm
doing a network address translation
gateway and forward that packet out port
3 I might say if the ethernet address
has a certain value and by the way with
the IP addresses and Ethernet addresses
you can mask those about those matching
values I might say if it has a
particular value I want to add it add a
VLAN ID and send that out port to do
things I can perform more than one
action at a time I can say if the
ingress report equals 4 for that packet
stop port 5 & 6
I can have any number of actions
well the protocol and the spec allows
that it's implementation dependent as to
how much a switch will support
but I can have multiple actions that I
can apply to a packet that matches the
header fields and there's also something
called priority which allows the switch
to
determine the appropriate action when it
when a package Mancha's more than one
flow table entry so for example I might
have a rule that says that the ether
type is r4 the packet to the controller
and by the way that literally means that
packet gets encapsulated in a TCP stream
and sent to the controller which could
be very useful and very dangerous the
ether type is our then forward normally
as the normal context of the device
would do now notice if I had a packet
that managed the last rule it would also
match the next the last rule but it will
the action will be applied by the rule
with the highest priority highest number
priority 40000 would be what is applied
I said you could forward to a port you
could forward to multiple ports and then
there are special ports you can forward
to the controller again that's called a
packet in normal send packets to the non
open flow function of the device flight
do whatever that device thinks is
appropriate for plug and local doesn't
get used much
there are also timers in the flow table
their timers and each flow entry can
have no timers which really means timers
with zero value or they can have an idle
timer or a hard time out timer or both
and this simply says if the open flow
controller puts one of these table
entries in a switch it can say this
table entry is only going to stay there
for so many seconds or it's only going
to stay there for so many seconds since
the last packet actually matched that
entry switch itself not the controller
so they're kind of two different ways to
think about how you might maintain this
table in the open flow swish and these
are not exclusive but you can have a
proactive model and if you go to the
demo in the room next door they're happy
to show you an application where you go
to a webpage and you essentially draw a
point-to-point circuit and you press a
button and software behind the scenes
use this open flow to configure the
switches along that path to implement
that point-to-point circuit that's
proactive so before any data flows over
that point-to-point circuit the rules
are being put in the switches along the
way as to what to do with the data
reactive is responding to data that's
hitting the switch for which there is no
rule so in in the default condition
under open flow 1.0 and it's all more
complicated
starting with 1.1 but if you send a
packet to a port on an open flow switch
and there no is no rule that matches
that packet then that packet will be
automatically forward to the controller
and in a normal application the
controller will look at that packet
figure out what kind of rule needs to
exist in the switch to process that
packet it will update the table in that
switch to process that type of packet
and then it will send the packet back to
the switch now there's some tricks to
make that more efficient the switch can
buffer the packet and the controller can
say remember the packet in buffer to go
ahead and reprocess it because I put a
rule in that will match on that packet
so proactive is when you put the rules
in the switch before the traffic hits
the switch and reactive is when you have
the switch sending the controller
traffic and the controller
is writing new rules in the switch to
handle those new flows they're going
through yes so if you have if you're
doing a lot of reactive stuff one of the
things you have to design for is how
much traffic would be going to the
controller
generally speaking reactive is bad
especially in a wide area network but
there are cases where it's not as bad
like in a data center so in the case of
the application that they have across
the hallway it's purely proactive so no
traffic I believe that's true
no traffic is actually being sent to the
controller for the controller to set up
a rule in the switch the controller
based upon a web portal and user demand
is pre configuring the network for those
services in the hands-on exercises we're
gonna actually do proactive and reactive
examples that works okay normally a this
is how this normally works you you have
an open flow device you can put in your
network and you give us some basic
information maybe you give it an IP
address default gateway subnet mask and
the address of its open flow controller
now there's some security stuff too it's
it can be a TLS connection so you can
have keys and all that stuff but
basically you take a device you give us
some basic information you turn it on
and it connects to an open flow
controller the way this is is typically
designed especially a wiring network is
there some sort of network that exists
exclusively for the purpose of
supporting this traffic from the switch
to the controller so you plug the switch
in maybe there's a management port you
plug into some management network switch
contacts the controller and then the
controller from that
four can maintain this table in the
switch which is controlling its behavior
now there it's not part of the SPAC but
most open flow devices support kind of
an alternate way to talk to them and you
can configure most up in flow devices to
listen for an open flow connection on a
particular TCP port so you able to
actually connect to them your so
something outside well some other device
can initiate a connection to an open
flow device if they have one of these
things listening and they're still
talking open flow over this channel
there's no real difference in how the
channels work it's just who initiates
them and many switches support both at
the same time and this can be really
useful maybe you have a switch that is
configured to connect to a controller
and it's part of your network and that
controller implements all these features
but maybe you have a network engineer
who's trying to figure out what's going
on and they would like to connect to the
switch using open flow and interrogate
the switch directly to see what's going
on and so it will do that and some of
the examples will actually have a switch
that's talking to the controller but at
the same time you're able to connect to
the switch and using some command line
utilities use the OpenFlow protocol to
interrogate the switch
okay I want to give you just a real
quick example of how some of this stuff
works let's say that we're talking about
an enterprise let's say campus I come
from University so let's say campus
you've got some big open flow network
that is all over campus and you've got
in a network engineer installing a new
device and they've given this open flow
device the basic stuff its IP address
the address of its default gateway
subnet mask and most importantly the
address of the open flow controller and
in the network engineer and you know
these are really skilled network
engineers that put these devices in the
phone closets on campus they can walk
mote most most of them can drive they
put the they put the switch in the phone
closet they put some wires on it and
they leave well wouldn't it be great if
there was some standard way
vendor-independent way to determine how
that new thing got wired into the
network what does the topology look like
now that this new device is in the open
flow network and this is just an example
this isn't exactly how it's done
but here's an example of how you can do
it in an open flow environment and it
gives you some sense of how all this
stuff works so you give the switch its
minimum configuration switch it connects
to the controller the controller will
say you know what kind of open flow
version do you run how many ports do you
have what kind of ports are they so
forth and then the switch excuse me the
controller will put a rule in this new
switch now it's also put this rule in
every other switch that's connected to
us so all the switches have this rule
but it's gonna put a rule on this switch
that says if a packet if a packet comes
in with an ether type of lldp send that
packet to the controller so it's new
device it puts this one rule in
then the controller very creatively
creates an lldp packet piece of software
creates a packet like that and I'll by
the way the controller can send packets
to the switches and tell them to forward
out ports so the controller sends an ala
DP packet down to the switch a unique
lldp packet has something unique payload
and it says you know send this out port
one and it waits to hear from any other
switch if they receive that packet and
if there's a switch connected to port
one that other switch will send a note
to the controller saying hey I just saw
this lldp packet and here's the packet
and it came in on my port five okay now
the controller knows port 1 of this new
switch is connected to port 5 of this
existing switch and the controller can
create unique packets for each port on
the switch send them all out so you
really come back and all of a sudden the
controller now has this kind of
real-time updated topology view of how
these switches are interconnected in and
it's actually not very hard ok so I said
most of stuff we're going to talk today
about is open flow 1.0 the hands-on
stuff I'm gonna talk about what happened
between 100 and one one no one is doing
one one but the big change took place at
one one now in one oh we had a flow
table in a head fields like header
fields counters actions priorities there
are some other things like timers
starting in one one header fields become
match field so it actually changed the
terminology they have priorities and
counters but then they have something
called instructions
and they also support multiple tables
and in in the old way in 1.0 it was
really simple if a packet matched the
thing in the header field then the
action whatever was in the action field
happened to the packet done you know if
you had stuff that was any priorities
were used to break ties you know if a
packet matches more than one table entry
but really simple done in 1.1 it gets
more complicated and you need to think
about a new abstraction and that is sort
of this data structure that's moving
through the pipeline of the switch in
this data structure has a couple of
things with it it has a blob of metadata
just 32 bits there are instructions that
I'll talk about this more in a minute
they can set and test those bits
you've got the packet itself that's
moving through the pipeline and then
you've got what's called an action side
and an action set is essentially where
you can't accumulate things you need to
do to the packet when you're finished
processing the packet in 1.1 there is a
new table introduced called the group
table and a group table you can have
sort of an instruction in the in the
regular flow table entry that says
process this using a group table entry
so for example if you had a lot of
packets that were going to a common next
hop they might need common encapsulation
and a common forwarding but you might
want to have a whole bunch of different
table entries that identify packets
going to the next hop and so what so if
the next hop changes rather than
changing a whole bunch entries that are
identifying all
traffic that goes the next time you just
want to change the behavior of that
quickly and so the group table gives you
a level of indirection on what you do to
a packet that allows you to have that
kind of efficiency group tables also are
where you get features that allow you to
do things like balance traffic cross
bonded links so again in 1.0 does the
packet match the flow table on entry if
so perform the action and 1.1 and
forward including 1.2 and 1.3 does the
packet make mat match the flow table
entry if so look at the instructions we
Lim actions anymore we have instructions
instructions may be immediate actions
that kind of like the actions were in
1.0 but they can also be things that
tell it to do something in the packet
later on so the instructions can set
things in that action set remember I
said there's this new blog this new data
structure moving through the switch and
part of it is collecting things that
need to happen to the packet before the
packet leaves a switch and so these
instructions can essentially populate
things in that data structure telling it
to do things to the packet for example
push this VLAN ID on it rewrite the IP
address change just sort of code points
something like that collecting things to
do to that packet before it's left the
switch so you start to keep a list of
things to do and this exists because on
one point one you can have more than one
flow table so you can have a packet come
in and match an entry in flow table 0
and the instruction might be okay
ultimately I rewrite the diffserv code
point and then jump to Table three
packet goes to Table three and it sees
if there's a match there and a Table
three you might add another
okay rewrite the destination MAC address
and output port - so you need a way of
collects that you have multiple tables
in the packet can be processed by more
than one table you need to have a data
structure that's keeping track of what
each matching entry in a table wants
done before the packet leaves the device
now in addition to that I remember yeah
so that are the instructions bound to
each bit stuff before dynamics so the
instructions are the controller using
the OpenFlow protocol creates a flow
table entry and that entry has
instructions and they're they're fixed
so it's not like it's a Turing machine
so those those are fixed and you and
they won't depend on what's in the
packet there is a there's a part of the
switch then that presents this
abstraction table which may be different
than the Hardware table underneath and
there's some opcode that means do this
thing and it's the same across all
switches that that support open flow and
then there's some software on that
switch that translates that into
whatever it needs to be for that
particular piece of hardware and I'm not
sure I'm answering your question close
enough okay you can have instructions
can say to jump to a higher number table
they can't say jump to a lower number
table so you don't have this you can't
have things back up essentially the puc
the pipeline only moves forward in this
switch and i think i was starting to say
one of the things is in in this data
structure that's now moving with the
packet through the switch remember the
32 bits of nothingness at the beginning
an instruction might say
set bit 20 and then in a future table an
instruction might say if bit or a match
might say if bit 20 sets do something so
you can you can start to not only
collect actions that need to take place
on the packet in the action sets but you
can also flag the packet so it will
match specific table entries further
down the pipeline so you can see it got
a lot more complicated okay again 1.1
introduced multiple flow tables and true
paint introduced the group table with
multiple group table types instructions
can jump to other tables but only in a
positive direction open flow quality
services so in open flow 1.0 there was
some really primitive quality of service
things there was an optional action
member nax is doing something like
output a packet there was an optional
action which was in queue so you could
in key took this specific port excuse me
specific queue on a port so outside of
open flow maybe the manufacturer of the
switch gives you the ability to define
queues and those queues have different
queueing mechanisms maybe rate limiting
or whatever within open flow there's an
optional action which lets you in the
you know if I match on this packet the
action is and queue this packet to a
particular queue on a port so you get
that functionality pretty primitive
you can also match on and mess with the
header fields which could include VLAN
priority IP tossed bits so you can do
some you know you can do some marking or
you can make decisions based on marks
but just on the marks so it's it's not
particularly useful we'll jump to open
flow 1.3 for quality of service it has
the stuff we just talked about the
primitive stuff from 1.0
but it adds a new table type so we've
gone from in window having just the flow
table to now having one or more flow
tables a group table and now in 1.3 a
meter table the meter table is is a lot
of QoS rope essentially a meter table
has an entry in a meter table has a
meter table identifier just a number it
has a list of meter bands
that's essentially traffic thresholds
and what to do for that threshold and
then it has some counters so in open
flow 1.3 you can have an instruction
that says associate this thing I just
match the traffic is hitting my match
filled with meter number three and maybe
a meter number three there are two meter
bands and the first one what is a
hundred bits per second two to a hundred
thousand bits per second to 200,000
visitors second and the next one is two
hundred thousand bits to five hundred
thousand votes so all of the you might
have a bunch of different match fields
all pointing to the may same mean or
identifier so these traffic this traffic
is being aggregated into one meter
identifier and based on which threshold
or band that aggregate traffic hits
different things can be applied to that
traffic and the only things that can be
applied to that traffic at least right
now the only there are only two band
types one is drop the packet the other
is remark that is sort of code point so
if you had a bunch of traffic pointing
to one meter table entry and the
aggregate of that traffic never hit the
first threshold it's just going to be
processed normally but if the aggregate
of that traffic is enough to hit
the first meter band but not the second
it'll do whatever the first meter band
is and the only kinds of things that can
be done or either drop the traffic or
remarket so actually quite a bit of rope
here kind of complicated but this is the
the QoS mechanism in 1.3 the key
paragraph in the spec which I copied the
Meanor applies to meter band with the
highest configured rate that is lower
than the current measured rate is a
complex way of saying these things are
thresholds that you had I know we're
going through this fast okay so we're
gonna do a couple of hands-on exercises
how many people okay so so 50 of you
have gone to the registration page and
and thank you we fund these events
through selling your email addresses so
that's so just a quick overview you know
open flow is actually really simple
it's about this common abstraction of
this table these tables aren't exists in
these devices but this just normalizes
them to a common abstraction and what's
in this table controls how the device is
forward packet a try rates and we're
taking the piece of software that
maintain that table and removing it
outside the device to central controller
normally an open flow device connects to
the controller but it's like I spoke
earlier usually you can set up an
optional port to listen TCP port that
they can listen on
and you can talk OpenFlow to that port
and you could do both at the same time
and that's really good for debugging
okay we're gonna use something called
mini nets I'm just curious how many of
you heard of mini yet before a few okay
mini net will create simulated Network
environment on the VM that you're gonna
log into and it uses up in V switch you
know it's based on Linux containers it's
kind of cool if you're interested you
can look up old stuff on the web we're
gonna be used making very basic use of
many net when we run mini net it'll
create apology and then you can do some
really simple things like ping things so
the arc apology will have a couple hosts
on it and if we want it to ping host
three from host to the syntax looks like
this the mini net prompt you'd say h2s
saying I want to run the screen on h2
ping space h3
okay so how many I'm gonna zip what back
in the slides and we give you guys all
the login information because we need
you to do this on the memes
okay so what you should have done is
once you've got in the registrations in
the roster spreadsheet you looked at
your row number on the left just what
row you your name ended up in and you
need to open two terminal windows to a
VM and the username is OpenFlow password
is open flow so typically this would be
ssh space open flow apps and it's vm and
then that row number training in center
spelled weirdly i n CN TR e dot org
password open flow all lowercase and
then you also need to point your web
browser to VM your row number training
in center or port 80 90 slash slash
guacamole now let me show you what
you're gonna see when you do that when
you point your browser you're gonna see
this login screen and you're gonna type
open flow and open flow by the way
guacamole is like ultra cool you guys
should you have questions about how many
of you know about guacamole oh you
should there should be a guacamole here
basically it is an html5 it turns your
desktop into html5 dynamic html5 so
you're gonna when you when you go to
that web page you're gonna see this
Wireshark but you're probably going to
notice that you can't get any of the
menu items to work on Wireshark and that
is because there is an error message
that is carefully hidden from you that
you need to dismiss
it's on the bottom lower left okay okay
okay so let me just tell you what you
have to do you you're gonna have to and
I apologize we this isn't something we
can easily solve oh there it is see that
see that air dialogue that's carefully
hidden underneath you have to dismiss
that before you can use Wireshark okay
so you guys are gonna need to do that
let me go back to my slides you guys
like Google Docs for this this is
working out pretty okay don't work ahead
okay
so in one of your terminal windows you
need to do s you do space MN for mini
net - - Mac space - - switch base OBS k
space that special controllers face
remote and hit a return and you should
get a o if you get asked for the
password it's open flow right yeah open
flow lowercase and your you're going to
create a topology that's going to look
like this
there's some people are okay now I want
you to configure your wire shark
you know dismiss that error error
message in Wireshark and in the filter
field in Wireshark put o F for open flow
lower case and also tell Wireshark to
capture on the loopback interface and so
what we're gonna do is we're gonna watch
the OpenFlow protocol between the open
flow controller and the switch and we're
gonna see how this works
okay we're gonna use a tool called Oso
fctl this comes with the OVS switch
common distribution this is actually a
really useful tool so if you actually
want to play with open flow this is
command line tool which is gonna let you
look at the flow table in the switch
without going through the controller and
we'll be doing that here and this is in
fact how you would debug something so
we're setting up a situation here where
we puttin Wireshark along the channel
between the controller and the switch so
we can look at the open flow
conversation between the controller and
the switch and we're also going to use
OBS ofc tol to look directly at the
switch so if you had an application that
just wasn't working you could see what
the controller was saying to the switch
and then you could look in the switch
and see what the switch is really doing
in terms of what ifs flow table looks
like okay so in in one of your windows
in the other window the one that wasn't
the mini net1 you should run s you do
space OVS - ofc TL show DP 0 you're
doing show DP 0 because we needed to do
this with a named device normally you
would the show the DP 0 would be
replaced with the IP address of the
switch you were connecting to so this is
you know this will tell you that there's
actually a port listening on the switch
you're trying to look at directly it'll
show you some basic stuff about the
switch now type superuser duo via OBS -
ofc TL dump flows DP 0 and what you'll
see are you know there's this flow table
in the switch and dump flows will show
you what that table looks like in the
switch and there should be virtually
nothing there hopefully
let's get they had just a bit okay so in
your mini net window I'm sorry but I'm
running out fun in the mini net window I
want you to try to ping so H two space
ping H 3 and what happens doesn't work
right hee hee thing doesn't work open
flow switches don't do anything until
you tell them to write it's not like an
Ethernet switch where you just have
connectivity by connecting to it this
will work that way
so this switch periodically is trying to
connect to a controller but you're not
running to controllers so let's start a
controller
- controller
PTC PE that starts up a really basic
controller that comes with the OBS
distribution if you don't tell that
controller anything else you will try to
make the switch behave like a regular
Ethernet learning switch
thank you sorry we were never gonna get
here if I went through them so when you
did the pings before he ran the
controller
they'll just fail hopefully once you run
the controller the pigs will work now
this is where it gets really kind of
interesting
your Wireshark window should have just
filled up with open flow salad at this
point so you are now running the
learning switch so we took this switch
that didn't do anything and we thought
oh there's this feature learning switch
kind of a basic feature actually it
turns out to be one of the harder things
to do controller and you're seeing it
operate right now now one you know do
those things every now and then and run
this command again again this is the
command you would run if you were
debugging something and this is directly
to the switch and show me the flow show
me the flows and now you're gonna see
those flow table entries that the
controller is putting in the switch to
make that switch behave as a learning
switch and it's going to be pretty
dynamic run this a couple times it's
gonna look different maybe every time
okay so we got 13 minutes left here's
what I'd like to do because there's
there's one other thing I want to talk
about you can do this exercise at home
all you have to do and everyone who put
their name and real email address in the
roster we will send a pointer to where
the Amazon machine image is the public
one we made that has these tools and
some cryptic instructions for how to
spin this up under your own AWS account
which should be for free if you I can't
promise that but when you get a new AWS
account you get so many hours of the
micro instance and I think this will run
on the micro instance what you should do
if you want to see what's going on is
look at the Wireshark output open up all
the tabs and follow what's going on for
just a learning switch because that will
really give you a sense of how this
works and we were gonna do that on the
screen but there's not enough time to do
that so I would really encourage you to
do this it's not rocket science but it's
pretty interesting to watch what's
happening this is what I call a reactive
application so traffic comes in if it
doesn't match a flow table entry it gets
punted to the controller the controller
updates the switch a lot of traffic
going to the controller you know this is
useful useful simple way to do a
learning switch this might work in a
data center or a campus environment
would not work in a win so go ahead in
the window you were running the
controller and hit control C if you if
you back rounded it hit a foreground and
hit control C and kill that controller
I'm gonna talk through exercise to we're
not gonna really do it
in exercise 2 so in this case we had a
controller running and we have the
controller emulate a learning switch and
exercise 2 we have you manually put in
some of those flow table entries so we
don't learn a controller we use this
command line utility that talks directly
to the switch normally used for
debugging and we have you put in some
really simple rules to turn this turn a
couple ports on that switch into into
repeater pours packet comes in one port
they go out the other port we have you
put in rules that are based on ports and
then we have you put in rules that are
based on the IP address and we ask you
to give the IP address ones higher
priority and that is so that you can see
how the counters change and how priority
is used to determine when a packet
matches more than one rule how
priorities use to determine which which
action it is selected and you could you
guys can do this on your own there's
also something we didn't even try to
include and that is using something
called flowvisor
to virtualize all this stuff there's a
way to put a device between the
controller and the switches
it speaks open flow in both directions
it's essentially a proxy in both
directions it's called a flow visor and
it has a set of rules that you set and
the result is you can virtualize access
to an open flow environment but I can't
do that so you you can do these these on
your own because I want to talk you
about one less thing is anybody from
juniper
I cannot remember who at juniper but but
there's somebody who was who is or was a
Juniper who described a term floor
floorplan entropy which I thought was a
really cool term maybe in a multi-tenant
datacenter in a big multi-tenant
datacenter you've got this this problem
that you have let's say you have a
million VM data center and maybe you
have customer a and they need two racks
worth of servers to run their
application and smoke most of the data
stand in those two racks but these are
dynamic services so maybe on Tuesday
they only really need a rack and a
quarter so they D allocate a bunch of
stock and customer B comes in and takes
that second rack and maybe some more and
then customer a comes back and says well
no I need to ramp back up but now what's
free is across the datacenter and so you
have this dis fragmentation problem in a
multi-tenant data center so I don't know
exactly how Amazon solves this for
example but you know they have to deal
with it so they over time if you've got
these tenants growing and shrinking
their resource requirements in either
Amazon is going to set up a huge extra
amount of resources or they're gonna
migrate things around in real time to
try to balance things out which they may
do both but the other problem is is
fundamentally they're gonna have to
support high bisection bandwidth
throughout the entire data center
because you just don't know where things
are gonna be it's okay
you don't can't predict what these
tenants are gonna do so you know that
could be an expensive and complicated
problem to solve and if you want to
solve it with layer 2 devices and
building that free networks based on
inexpensive devices that that's cool
that will work except if you have a
million
vn data center we can't or it's too
expensive to buy layer 2 devices that
will support a million cam interests and
when I say million I'm not making that
up I mean a million VM Data Center is
kind of in the order of magnitude that
you can expect in large data centers now
really large ones so you there's a
simple layer two way to solve this but
then you get into hardware that's
expensive and power-hungry and an
awkward and all those things here's how
fundamental fundamentally differently
you can approach something if you have
open flow there's a there's a protocol
called Portland and there's a link to
Portland in here and what I'm going to
describe is not exactly Portland because
that would take too long but it give you
a sense of how you can use open flow to
completely change the way Ethernet
behaves to solve a real problem so let's
say we were going to mess with the
ethernet address just the destination
Ethernet address and in this data center
when it when a VM armed to talk to
another VM that we had an ARP server and
that ARP server would give that kind of
a fake Ethernet address and that fake
Ethernet address would have some
structure to it and maybe the first two
bits not of Ethernet address get left
alone but maybe a few bits are used to
describe from a topology perspective
what corner of the data center that
destination is in and maybe a few more
bits describe what row you know if it's
in the northwest corner what row and
maybe another one says which rack and
another one says which server and the
rack and then you got some bits to say
which VM it really belongs to now you
can have switches that are configured in
a factory network interconnecting this
entire data center and their rules are
tiny right it's like
so you've highly aggregated these rules
because you you flipped Ethernet on its
head you said the destination address is
not some unique thing bound to the VM
with no other meaning you're actually
they're actually getting destination
Ethernet addresses from the ARP server
that provide a route to get to that VM
and so the switches that are
interconnecting all this can have a
really small table now
when the packet gets right next to the
VM it's heading to you've got to do one
other thing you've got to rewrite that
MAC address to be the MAC address that's
expecting now what's cool is if your VM
environment is using something like open
V switch you can write those rules with
open flow and if the physical switches
in the room support open flow you can
have orchestration software networking
software an ARP server is set up to do
this and it's not that complicated and
it gives you a way to solve a problem in
a completely different way you know it's
like I don't know if you guys read and I
don't know all the details
google recently solve e you know you you
can't have a widely distributed database
that is fully consistent all the time
you in Fast those those things cannot be
all you know it's it's but good cheap
and fast or something you can't have all
those and Google's said well actually
you can we'll introduce a common clock
precise clock and all this and we have a
scheme that lets you break the rules
well open flow is a way to really change
the way you think about forwarding
packets and fundamentally what it means
is is all those fields that have fixed
meanings at the beginning of the packet
you can use whatever however you want to
use them and in vm environments where
you have as the last top in the first
top v switches you can fix the packets
back up so there's no in system change
the VM software doesn't change you just
put the packet back in some form at once
see it in right before it gets there so
time questions
you guys can send me email if you yeah
so an open flow 1.2 so an open flow 1.1
they changed the way they encode the
match header fields or match fields to
be type type TLD type length effect
thank you
tackling type length value in 1.1 they
made that change would be easier to
incorporate things like v6 and 1.2 they
support v6 so the question is well then
what Devender supply and I should
probably say a few words about this a
bunch of vendors did 1.0 because 1.0 was
simple enough that they could update
their firmware and get their existing
devices to do it
my understanding is most vendors are
talking about serious products designed
for open flow D to support 1.2 or 1.3
nobody's doing 1.1 and they're focusing
on 1 2 and 1/3 the other problem so the
lab the lab where I work
does it's a narrow operability lab and
also a conformance lab and the open flow
spec is unfortunately a bit vague in
terms of what's required and what's
optional and today if you go out and buy
switch one of the things that and is
what the vendor actually so a vendor
might say yeah I do open flow and you
have to say what parts of open flow and
what are the limitations you know can I
do layer 3 and layer 2 matching at the
same time can I you know what's the
table size limit how many table entries
per second can I update you know that's
all brand new and scary space because
most of the products out there you know
they weren't built for this they were
adapted to it soon we're gonna see stuff
built for it
so the open floor the open source
ecosystem a controller side some so the
original the first controller was
something called knocks it came from
Sanford Knox was a Python and see
franken thing and that effort has I
believe forked into a newer Knox which
is which is mostly see and pox which is
all Python there's also a Java
implementation called beacon which was
forked and then mix which developed into
floodlight which is still open source
I'm not sure if they're commercial
product is just add-ons to it or how
that works but and then there's a
framework for building controllers
called trauma that comes from folks in
Japan and there are I think on the order
of ten open-source controllers and I
didn't name them all there are a lot out
there and then there are big companies
both the incumbents building their own
controllers and software companies just
building controllers anything else thank
you for coming hopefully the people did
the hands-on it worked and we will send
you some email that says how you can get
to the the image
at the end of the slides there is a
description of exactly how to spin it up
in AWS or in your own