and we will continue guests also they
come from the west part of the United
States Atlanta and from the east part of
the United States California their names
are for shiver and mic'd ambrosia their
collaborative effort to share thread
data in a valid member community
this session will introduce the aPWG
and its Clearing House approach to
sharing electronic crime data there
Ekrem exchange is a platform designed to
provide threat data between the aPWG
member community the ACX repository
provides real-time information for
blocking malicious URLs and other data
be a restful happy to help protect the
users and organizations from criminal
and fraudulent entities so I hope you
enjoyed this afternoon with Foy and Mike
please give a big applause to for
Schieber and mike D'Ambrosio thank you
yes thank you very much good afternoon
and thanks for joining us this afternoon
go talk a little bit about I'm gonna
start out just to open and talk about
who and what a little bit of what aPWG
is and the clicker there we go
push the other button that worked the
ante phishing working group was founded
in 2003 originally we strictly focused
on fishing there was about four or five
of us got together just to look at this
new phenomenon that was taken over the
industry we saw with the pH and phishing
and I'm from there we built together a
collaborative group of interested
parties so our membership has grown now
to include different financial
institutions ISPs a lot of you
technology companies law enforcement
agencies including a lot of your
research groups like universities the
different communities
yeah computer emergency response teams
around the world we work with those guys
different treaty organizations just
interested folks that are working in
cybercrime specifically over the years
as we've been working we've expanded so
as crime and fraud have evolved through
the years the anti-phishing working
group has grown and evolved to cover
other areas so some of the areas we look
at now is we get involved a lot in cyber
policy we work with ICANN the EU
government the US government Asian
governments as well to talk and advise
on different aspects of fighting
electronic crime we do a lot of work in
education and user awareness we have a
global program called stop think connect
that we use to help what I like to say
is upgrade our users a little bit to
make them more aware of the threats that
are out there and how to work and
operate safely on the Internet
over the years from the beginning we
also have been tracking trends so we do
quarterly reports and annual reports
where we look at statistics and the
phenomenons phenomenons in that are of
malicious activity the actors that are
out there what are they doing what are
the threats that we see coming down the
road we report those out we've been
doing that for 1213 years now so you can
see a evolution of what's going on out
there in the electronic crime field the
two areas we're going to talk to mainly
today I'm going to talk to you a little
bit our bure about our research programs
and then mine's going to get a little
more into the threat data sharing and
more the technology side of what we do
from a research side and this is what I
think will be interesting to a lot of
the attendees here is we run an annual
program called our symposium on
electronic crime research this is a peer
reviewed process where we review the
papers the accepted papers are then
published we run two tracks so the first
track is for theoretical cybercrime
academic research so these are
the actual you know our students our
university favor we're working on their
PhDs have some research they need to get
published if you want to get a PhD you
need to publish your papers this is one
of the things we focus on and these
papers are all revolving around
electronic crime to date we've published
over a hundred and twenty papers through
the I Triple E as well those papers that
we accept we then fly one author from
each paper into our annual event our
next event will be in San Diego next May
and so they get to present their work to
the industry in this process you get
introduced to a lot of organizations
like Microsoft Google Symantec IBM blah
blah blah all the big security companies
in the industry and quite a few people
end up getting uh employment through it
so I highly encourage you if you're
working on some research that you get
your papers in we also run a second
track for industry one of the things we
found there's not a lot of facility if
you're working in industry and you're
doing some research we try to help you
get those papers published as well if
you're working in industry and you
publish your paper we kind of expect you
to pay your own way to come to the event
and present your work since you do have
a job and the students do not owe and
also we do offer a cash award for the
two best players each year so uh a
little money in your pocket never hurts
or anything outside of that we also have
a European foundation that we set up in
2013 now the European foundation does
its own research and awareness projects
and those are currently running
primarily funded through their horizon
2020 programs and in that program we've
got three going on right now the V vet
program is creating educational
materials for vocational studies to help
students the true sec is creating a
program through the EU for a security
seal
so educational programs and different
organizations that are working in cyber
can get a kind of like what we would
call in the States a Good Housekeeping
Seal of Approval I don't know if we have
a similar program in the EU like that
but just a program to evaluate and say
these programs are valid you should look
into them good education process and
then we're also developing through the
EU foundation a cyber volunteer network
so this will be a program basically
you'll have apps that you could install
and users are our cyber volunteers will
have the opportunity to get certified
and become part of the network so let's
say I'm a teacher you know and I want to
help educate my students I could use
this network to help schedule and find
someone to come in and talk to my
students
and help raise their awareness again so
just some programs we've got going on
there to raise the awareness throughout
Europe specifically focused within the
European Union beyond that now to get to
more of the technical side is going to
talk to you a little bit about the AP
wgz crime exchange in our data sharing
program push button right great hi
everybody I'm Mike D Ambrosia and as Phi
was saying I am the technical guy and
what I'm going to show you today is just
a real brief we've only got a limited
amount of time there's quite a bit of
depth to this but what I'm going to do
is just give you some surface level
information on how we share data and
what our experience has been as Floyd
was talking about the programs earlier
the ECX that I'm exchange which we refer
to as the ECX as a free service for aPWG
member so there's no additional cost to
be able to use the data sharing side of
the aPWG so the mission for what we're
trying to accomplish here is just to be
a best-in-class data sharing framework
where high performance framework things
happen quickly we're trying to limit the
access into the system to people that we
know are known good actors
we handled we handle sharing of really
any type of threat data and I'm going to
show you I'm going to talk a little bit
about some of the workgroup features and
we make data available nearly instantly
to everybody that comes in we turn it
around fast we bring it in scrub it up
get it right back out and back into you
so that people can use it to protect the
public Ori for your research or academic
or whatever it is that you're doing with
it one of the big goals is we want to
try and drive data towards users and we
use an alerting system when data comes
into the system we scan it we look for
matches for patterns where people have
said show me when TLD comes in that I'm
interested in we can send you an email
alert and get that information out to
you right away
one of the big things is is I don't know
how many of you out here are already
using existing threat platforms and tool
kits but what we didn't want to do was
create yet another platform that you had
to log in to scan the data that way we
wanted to do is give you a robust API
behind the scenes I'm going to talk a
little bit about that and finally we've
been doing this for a while
his appointment me sorry buddies wait so
this started back in 2003 just a brief
history our chairman Dave Jevons went to
an industry dinner in San Francisco
where he met with some other banking
people everybody over the dinner was
complaining about the fact that they
were all facing the same threats but
they were not talking to each other
about what was going on and so the idea
spawned at that point in time let's
share data of all these banking entities
some large banking entities in the
States along with some emerging
electronic banking such as PayPal were
all there in attendance Dave went home
in his living room basically crafted up
a system of servers and networks email
started coming in from all the banks we
collated all that information and this
started distributing it back out kind of
similar to what the pallet off the
network I was talking about if you saw
that presentation where they share data
with Symantec and some of their other
competitors these banks as well we're
sharing data amongst themselves it was
an email based system it didn't scale
very well
but there was a very small sharing group
and so that lives on until today
there you go so ECX is built into two
sides there's the web interface where
you can come in and enroll take a look
at data it's a very sort of thin
interface and then the real power behind
the scenes is the API and we use a REST
API gentleman before us that was
speaking was talking about the REST API
that comes with Azur we do a similar
sort of thing as well exposing some of
the technology that we've got that we've
built on we use a lambda style lamp
stack and what lambda means or is in use
these days is that you have hot data and
warm data so we have data that we make
available instantly and then we have
data that we curate bomb from behind the
scenes metadata and then we bring that
in that takes a little while longer
eventually everything syncs up so we use
PHP we're a PHP shop we do behind the
scenes messaging where we send messages
out for jobs just to spawn and go out
and find additional data we use RabbitMQ
for that MySQL is used this is the
repository of truth that's where we keep
all of our data in but it's heavily
indexed and elastic we use log stash
Cabana we've tracked files that we have
on the system through file beats and we
use an alerting system called the last
alert which is done by Yelp we've added
that in as well and then we have a
legacy indexing system Spink search that
we're trying to get rid of memcache
helps us with speed and then we're very
distributed because we run on AWS and
that helps us be able to deploy new
instances quickly and be able to respond
to additional workload that comes up so
quickly on the side one we've said that
there were two sides to this on side one
the web user interface we store data and
we make it visible in either modules or
workgroups and the differences is that
modules are data that we gather curate
bring into the system normalize and
we're responsible for that work groups
allow users to be able to come in create
their own data schema basically hold any
sort of data that you've got out there
you create the schema sort of think of
it as Excel where you name each column
whatever it is you want to put in that
column we do a similar sort of thing we
allow you to create ad hoc sharing
groups so you can bring your data in and
and store it within that and then figure
out who you want to share it with
inside the web interface we provide a
little bit of filtering I'll show you
some examples of that and some
screenshots that we've got and it just
gives you an easy way just to go in and
kind of do some ad hoc searching so you
can kind of see what's going on with the
data that you're interested in it is a
close community as I've said you must be
an aPWG member to use it and this allows
us to know that people that we're
sharing data with are vetted so that
takes the original concept of those
original banks and extends it out maybe
another layer so we don't want to do is
provide it off to the public because
then we don't have real control over the
data we don't know where it's coming in
from this way we know who's who I
mentioned that we've got data that gets
driven out with the alerts we provide
all sorts of API documentation we use a
documentation tool built for API is
called swagger and in github there are a
ton of tools to be able to work with
swagger Docs where you can build clients
and change your documentation around as
far as the presentation style goes lots
of stuff you can do with it it's very
flexible and so the concept that we've
got here is is that things are really
complex back behind the scenes but using
this web interface it kind of keeps
things simple for you so this is really
where the meat of the matter lies which
is with the high performance REST API
everybody uses an API before so I'm good
we use basically two main operations I
get which gathers the data out that
where you put in a command it returns
data back to you a post is where you
send us data a patch is where you would
change data and options just it's a way
that the API tells you what's available
as far as services go we use one
interface for the entire ECX application
is to make it simple and easy and then
we use different endpoints to represent
different buckets of data as we keep all
of the fish data in one bucket that's
represented by the fish endpoint we have
a malicious IP which contains scanners
botnet activity login attempts and that
comes from PayPal actually it's the only
place where that data comes from or were
the only people that end up having that
data
we do user validation through a token
and we have a pretty robust set of query
parameters to allow you to be able to
dig in find the data that you're really
interested in and dig it back out
quickly we allow you to paginate through
the data so that the results that
actually shows you your on page 1 of 50
odd pages and then it gives you the
links to be able to surf through the
next couple of pages so you have
complete control over the results that
with that fast that's the big thing we
wanted something that that's scaled
really well where we could continue to
add more and more users as it as the
aPWG grows so we can return we take your
query again we parse it out we figure
out what data you want we gather the
data we put it in together in a packet
and we send it back out to you and that
happens in under two hundred
milliseconds we provide our testing
sandbox for you so you can come in and
play around a little bit with it we pick
up the last I don't know maybe four
hours of live production data so you've
actually got some real data to work with
and kind of test your queries against
and then oh I should have started with
this to begin with if you want to take a
look at the way that we output the data
the URL at the bottom of the screen here
is a zip file I put together last night
that shows the output and I'll move out
of the way so those of you with cameras
can can take a look so the zip file
contain a cut of the fish endpoint the
malicious IP endpoint and we have a sort
of a honeypot of email if you're
interested in email analysis and looking
for trends and email scams and phishing
we have a honeypot that we bring in at
report fishing at aPWG org all those
emails go in there also available
through the API I'll show you that in a
web interface as well so sending as data
is easy really easy we take four fields
that's it the date that the whatever
information you're sending us isn't in
the way a fish is foreseen the brand
that the fish is trying to attack the
URL of the fish and a confidence this
happens to how confident you are that
this is
actually fish and we use three three
consistent values a hundred percent
means that you've seen this with your
own eyes that you know for sure that
this is a fish and ninety is that this
is a machine process as identified this
as fish and you're sending it to us that
way fifty I don't know it could be maybe
maybe not
and we've used the same format since the
original days of 2003 when this was put
together within that banking dinner we
validate the data we accept it we
normalize it we turn it back around and
the insert happens in less than 75
milliseconds so again we're really
interested in speed here in tuning and
then we have a complete set of robust
result code so that when you perform
your operation the API tells you through
these result codes was it successful was
there an error if so what was the air to
help you programmatically put your
scripts together so I'm going to run
through a couple of screenshots of the
application this is the web interface
and so what you see here this is the
main page when you log in so you get a
little graphing and charting that kind
of gives you the general state of the
nation as we see it and then as I
mentioned we have full documentation for
the API so up on the top there you see
you've got your API key you've got the
base URL to get to the API and then
you've got down below if you scroll the
screen down you see all the
documentation for each module that's
within here one of the cool things about
swagger as I mentioned using that as a
documentation platform is it'll auto
generate API clients for you so if you
work in go you work in Python you work
in Java all of those using the swagger
documentation you can fast track and
build a base API client that you can
then extend out it's what we try and do
is get you going really quickly through
this and inside of that auto-generated
in the green circle there are a series
of about seven different clients that
are available for you to download it
right away so going quickly through the
modules you can see right there that
we've got the fish the malicious IP
which is the PayPal feed and then the
report phishing which is the emails
those are all located under modulus this
is data that we support maintain and
then you've got in parentheses you've
got the endpoint that you would use in
order to get through that data through
the API this is an example screen
showing the phishing data it's hard to
see from right here
so date discovered the brand the
confidence level in the URL those are
the four fields that we've got right
there the status indicates whether or
not the fish is still active or if it's
been knocked down and taken care of if
it's still a threat or not and then you
can edit the information from inside of
here using the blue button on the far
right hand side one of the nice things
about using this data table presentation
here is we've got column filtering at
the very bottom of the data table so you
can put in whatever you want to know you
want to put in a substring for you're
only looking for URLs that have a
particular string and you can put that
in the bottom there a data table will
filter that down and only show you those
results so in the next slide you're
gonna see I've taken the very last entry
on the list there with the MAS lrg club
URL and filtered it down to just that
they've found one results in the system
it's a quick way to kind of get a handle
visually on what's going on within the
data that you might be interested in
this is the malicious IP data this is a
series of as I said scanners BOTS login
attacks and so on it shows the IP where
this information was generated from and
PayPal sends this to us we get a good
feed in here we've got about 10 million
entries in this in this data set and
this is the report fishing data set
again all of the interface through each
of the modules here uses the same data
table so you've got the same pagination
column filtering ability to take a look
at the data scroll up and down and
change your results that's in addition
with this one this was kind of
interesting because on the right hand
side here we actually show you the
source that's inside of the email so
what I've done here is I've clicked on
the show button for the headers and for
those of you interested in email
information you can see the header
information right here already so then
you can set up your queries in the API
and begin to bring this out work groups
is a real powerful feature that we like
it's deep it's kind of technical I'm not
going to get into it today but the
overarching concept is you can set up
your own container that holds your
specific type of data you can store
basically any sort of data in there and
using the same API that we use for our
modules you can use that for your data
and then figure out who you want to
share that with same you can add and
take data out of that repository and
then you have member control over who
has access to it so these are the first
ones that we've got in here right now
we've got a Bitcoin data exchange with a
bunch of Bitcoin information a little
bit of ransomware oriented type stuff in
there the IRS is the United States
taxing entity Authority there are people
calling around right now saying you owe
the IRS money send us a gift card with a
payment at this at this address we track
SMS fish and then malicious domains and
then finally this is the alerts section
would be would be located in here which
I've talked briefly about it where when
data comes into the system the system
checks it in real time
looks for a pattern match that you've
set up already a particular domain name
a TLD of brands if there's a match made
there it'll send you an email we also
hook into slack channels for those of
you that use slack and then this is just
your peers your standard profile
demographic information phone change
password and so on so since this is sort
of a research and a learning conference
I wanted to kind of just finish up here
with some best practices that we see
first of all a lot of people don't read
the documentation we've got a really
robust set of documentation available
for you spend some time read it figure
out what the options are we get our logs
messed up bad with people which I'm
gonna figure it out on the fly an API is
designed to be beat on use it use it a
lot we like to see people making a
request about one per second or so in
the past we've had people that only make
a request one time for per day and
that's 24 hours or what 23 hours and 59
minutes of exposure where there's data
available to you that you could be using
in there so work with the API query it a
lot in order to do that you're gonna
want to keep track of the last time that
you query we have a highest ID parameter
that comes back so you can say this was
the last ID that I got give me
everything from that point forward and
you can do the same thing with with the
date modified and then know your data
set use the UI use the
web frontend in order to be able to poke
around in there and figure out the data
that you're interested in what would
that pattern be how would I query that
inside of the API what would I be
looking for and as we all know bad
actors changed up their their game off
and in order to be able to maintain
their attacks and and be effective it's
a good word so what you're going to be
looking for it's going to change over
time so as those threats begin to get
knocked down the bad actors are going to
change the way they do business they're
gonna come back in with new threats so
you need to go back in and check every
once in a while to make sure that what
you've actually think you're looking for
is actually in the data set and if they
haven't changed that and so this is real
quickly how to run an API so the very
top entry would return all the fish that
we have on file as of right now working
in descending order the next one you can
specify fields so if there's fields I
know in the EU there's some sensitivity
around information some of the stuff you
don't want you don't want to have in
your possession you can figure out using
the fields parameter which fields you
want to get back so you can avoid the
things that you might not want to get
you can look for specific brands and
then you can do wildcard searches so I
threw this search actually in there last
night with the model gap
wildcard is to see and it found 75
entries in our data set for it and then
you can mix and match wild cards or I'm
sorry query parameters within that so
you can you can run multiple query
parameters at the same time so the other
thing I thought I'd share with you or
what are the obstacles and problems that
we've got with data sharing data sharing
should be important right the more data
we share the more effective we are as an
industry so I broke it down into three
sections technology legal in business
but within the technology section and
this one that really surprises me we use
the REST API we've get feedback that
people find it difficult for some reason
there's this technology that's been
around for over 12 almost 13 years and
it's very well established yet people in
this industry don't seem to use it very
easily we get a little bit of pushback
on it so it started originally with
Flickr and Facebook and Twitter back in
2002 2003 those were the first releases
of rest api s
the other problem that we see is when we
start training people up we get high
industry turnover as everybody's
mentioned this morning if you sat in on
some of the other presentations that
there's a real need for engineers in
this space right now battling cybercrime
and so people when they come in they
tend to move along and they move up and
they get promoted and they move around a
lot so the person we trained today could
be gone next week someone new comes in
to take the place they're not very well
trained so we need to continue to train
people constantly yeah this is an
interesting one it's ones that kind of
surprises us at least in the states is
that we're not seeing a lot of people
coming into a job knowing how to use
api's and technology like this we're not
kind of surprising we see people just
wanting to can't you just send me by
email a CSV file that's got all the data
and it was like no this is much better
way to go about doing things and then we
still see a lot of people wanting to use
that email CSV file sharing standard and
it just doesn't work it's got its
riddled with latency this is a much
better solution from the legal side and
this is facetious obviously the first
thing to do is we're gonna kill all the
lawyers there is quite a bit of
uncertainty in the legal community right
now around how to share data what data
is available to share do I want to share
data is it a good thing to share data
what's our exposure for for sharing data
if say for instance a domain name has an
IP address in the domain name is that
personal information can that be shared
I don't know talk to five lawyers you're
gonna get six different opinions and
then on the business side companies are
understaffed right now that's the whole
reason why this conference exists in a
sense is to get people into the industry
and so we've got processes that were
established a long time ago in order to
be able to get data in and out of
systems and they're very reluctant to be
able to go in and change these things
because they don't have the staff to one
make the change monitor the changes
release the changes and then take care
of it afterwards so people are companies
and businesses are somewhat reluctant to
be adding new new new changes to their
existing business processes in the
States we have a small animal
mmm about the size of a squirrel maybe
lives underground and it pops out every
once in a while it comes up out of its
burrow and pops up and looks around and
then it grabs whatever nut so that's
right back down into its hole and I use
this term to describe some of the action
that we see from companies that are just
interested in consuming the data
companies will pop up they'll grab all
the data and then they'll go back down
in their hole and we don't really see
them again for a while what we're
interested in having is people sharing
data and the prairie-dogging doesn't
help us move in that direction a lot of
companies don't know that they can share
data with us or that they should be
sharing data with us or why it is that
that's a good thing to be able to do and
as I mentioned that a lot of companies
are understaffed right now there's just
not a lot of development cycles in order
to be able to building tools you're up
yeah thanks Mike just in closing to
cover a couple of quick points on how to
get involved with aPWG
so there's there's generally two main
areas here when we look at our
researchers and and the universities so
as a University researcher you want to
get your stuff published we can help you
do that you know like I said we do
publish these papers to the I Triple E
there's very few places that you really
want to get published as a researcher
but that's one of them
and we do offer special membership for
research organizations so aPWG is a
nonprofit organization everything we get
goes back into the community so and
that's where we maintain a membership
program so all of our corporate entities
we ask them to pay an annual membership
fee we use that money to keep the lights
on keep the systems up and running keep
our developers paid you know although we
try to think of ourselves as we're doing
the good fight we still have to pay our
bills so we kind of depend on those
groups to keep that money coming in we
get some grant money through the e trip
through the EU and some other
organizations but it's a small portion
of what it takes to keep the
organization as a whole up and running
but generally as a university if you
want to get access you just need to
a short abstract on what type of
researcher doing what other researchers
are you're working with and what
corporate entities you may be working
with and then we do have a data sharing
agreement everybody signs the same
agreement for the corporation side we do
have different levels depending on what
kind of data how you want to work with
the system the sponsoring level is for
full access then we have other levels
like a lot of the banking institutions
and and some of the other entities they
don't necessarily want the data they're
already working with somebody that has
access they just want to help keep the
group running so we have less or you
know a lower level for them to join and
we have an introductory you know if
you're an organization and you want to
play with the data a little bit to see
is this something I can use is it going
to help my company we do a 10-day trial
so you can sign up and get access and
get in there and play around a little
bit the emails are right there for me
Mike and support if you have questions
about the he crime exchange itself drop
us a note
we'll get you involved and see how we
can work together and like you say you
know our ultimate goal is try to make it
a safer place out there and see how we
can get this threat data and help our
researchers to get out there and
hopefully save people from losing their
money in the end of the day and I think
that's got it for us if there's any
questions we're here thank you very much
I think you
you