[Music]
okay so hi everyone welcome to the first
talk of the second main track today
today we are talking about
reusability in coreboot and a bit of a
tale about it so please give a big round
of applause and enjoy thank you good
afternoon everyone my name is firkin
Shaikh and I'm here to narrate a tale of
reusability in code boot a little about
myself I work for Google in the Chrome
OS firmware team I actually started out
in this team as an intern and I have
been working on code boot and Chrome OS
for the past 5 years now so this is a
quick overview of the topics that I have
planned to cover today please feel free
to ask me questions at any point okay so
at the I believe some of you here are
familiar with what Chrome OS is but for
those who are not I would define it as a
single collection of mostly open-source
software running on a variety of
hardware we have shipped Chromebooks
with Intel x86 arm 32 arm 64 associates
including the ones from Nvidia mediatek
and ROK ship so all the Chromebooks
except a few early ones use coreboot as
their machine initialization routine and
rest of the software stack includes
libraries like verified boot library
third-party firmware like arm trusted
firmware some blobs FSP depth-charge
which is the OS loader and finally the
Linux kernel Chromebooks have actually
gained a lot of popularity in the audio
segment in us and with devices like
Google pixel book HP Chromebook x2 the
focus is expanding towards consumer
segments as well so the combination of
software and hardware that we saw is
actually just one of the components that
goes into building an entire Chrome OS
platform
and it is referred to as the application
processor apart from the application
processor there are a number of
different controllers like the embedded
controller t CP CP mech and a variety of
peripherals like keyboard touchscreen
trackpad and more this might actually
look familiar to some of you since it is
similar to any typical computing
platform the model that Chrome OS
follows for all of its platforms looks
something like this the Chrome OS team
at Google designs a reference platform
using the components that we saw before
then one of the OEMs is chosen as the
lead om and they copy the reference
platform as is and ship a device with it
next multiple OMS come onboard and they
add their own tweaks on top of the
reference platform and ship multiple
follower devices now even though there
is a single block shown for each OM
device there could be multiple SKUs here
like convertible versus clamshell SKU
that screen versus non touchscreen mid
friend memory SKUs or different storage
skills one example of this model is
GLaDOS so the reference platform GLaDOS
was designed using Intel skylake SOC the
lead om Shiva
using GLaDOS and different OEMs ship
devices like Caroline and Cave a better
example of this model is actually Reif
the reference platform reef was designed
using Intel Apollo Lake SOC the lead OMF
asses and various OM Slater shipped on
follower devices like nasha pyros san
and snappy another example of this model
is coral but coral was special in a
number of ways one of the unique things
about coral was that since it was a
refresh device based on Intel Apollo
Lake SOC it derived from the same
reference platform reef and coral itself
was never shipped but instead multiple
follower OM devices were shipped like
astronaut
Robo national etc the other unique thing
about coral is that all the OEM devices
ship with a single unified firmware
image that is a single a firmware image
was used on all the OEM devices from
this family now this approach had its
own advantages and disadvantages and
we'll take a look at that later finally
the most recent platform is octopus here
we have to reference platforms you're an
PIP which allows the OEMs to have a
wider selection of components and
multiple OM devices like phaser me leaks
and boba but you must be wondering that
this story was supposed to be about code
boot and all have been doing is talking
to you about Chrome OS actually it is
important to know the background here in
order to understand the decisions that
were taken within code boot so let's
rewind back and first take a look at the
objectives that we are trying to achieve
the first objective is faster
time-to-market so audience would like to
ship devices as soon as possible they
would like to have more flexibility with
respect to component selection obviously
we would like to avoid duplication of
work within the software stack this kind
of ties in with the first example of
being able to ship devices as soon as
possible so anytime a new device has to
be added to the same family you would
want to make use of the existing
infrastructure next is making the whole
process manageable for everyone this
includes the electrical engineers who
are designing the hardware software
engineers who are designing the firmware
and the OS for the OEMs and ODMs to
actually ship devices and even for the
test team to be able to validate these
devices and finally making the whole
process scalable so that way you're able
to ship more and more devices each and
every year so let's see how these
objectives are being achieved using the
same platforms that we saw before the
first example was GLaDOS on the left is
the hardware view of the platform and on
the right is the software or firmware
view
my firm when I basically mean the BIOS
or more specifically cold boot in this
case here each om device got its own
firmware now as you see on the hardware
side there is a clear hierarchy or like
reusability since all the different
devices are based on the same reference
platform GLaDOS but on the formal side
apart from the common block one which is
the arch SOC library code there was no
sharing at the mainboard level even
though they were all derived from the
same reference platform one of the files
that was very commonly duplicated across
different boats was the mainboard ASL
file member dot ASL basically allowed
you to do like describe different
devices that are present on a platform
like that screen device trackpad device
TPM device so here's an example of manbo
dot ASL file from GLaDOS shell and
Caroline respectively it specifically
highlights the touchscreen device node
so if you observe closely the entire
device node or most of the device node
looks similar across the different ports
and there are just a very few
differences like the head which is
actually used by the kernel driver to
identify the device the device
descriptor the i2c address for the
device and the touch screen irq
basically the ones highlighted in red
and this duplication was present not
just for the touch screen node but for
all the other devices as well and it's
not restrict it was not restricted to
GLaDOS we had a number of ports which
did the same thing in order to fix this
duplication SSDD generation was added to
code boot
so ssed generation basically allows a
runtime edition of device notes to a CPI
SSD T based on the device tree
properties it basically relieves the
developers from hectic task of having to
define all these device nodes in a CPI
source language ASL is not that
difficult to learn but for a newcomer it
could take some time so the underlying
idea here is that a driver in RAM stage
would be responsible for generation of
these nodes a truant
you can find some examples under eye to
see generic spy ACPI or generate GPIO
keys but these generators are not
limited to just drivers you can also use
them for like CP or no generation PCI
device generation and mocha a good way
to locate these generators is by doing a
grep for a CPI fill SS DT generator in
Co both sources it is basically the
callback that is used for the table
generation now using this SS DT
generation the same touchscreen device
node can be described using the block on
the right now you just have to indicate
what driver is to be used in this case
the drivers eye to see generic and the
same properties that were different
among different devices like the head
descriptor the irq and the i2c this SSD
T generation has since been used on all
the older as well as new platforms that
are being added to code boot next
example is the reef platform again on
the left is the hardware view and on the
pic is the firmware view similar to
GLaDOS each device in the reef family
got its own firmware so similar to
GLaDOS we have a common block one which
is the arch SOC library code but apart
from that there is a common block to
across all these different devices and a
block 3 which is different among these
devices the reason why we see a common
block 2 on grief is because it
introduced the concept of baseboard and
variant structures so unlike GLaDOS
which basically added a new directory
under mainboard for each device from the
GLaDOS family we followed a completely
different hierarchy the underlying idea
here is that the different devices that
belong to the same family requires
similar initialization and device logic
so all of this common code can be placed
under a baseboard directory and only the
things that differ across these
different devices can go under variant
specific directories so we have a single
directory reef under mainboard Google
and under variants we have a baseboard
which would be most of the common code
and then different directories for the
different variants this actually takes
us a step closer to a data-driven
approach where common code is doing all
the work for you and the variant
specific variant specific code or data
is providing just the information that
is required by the common code to do its
work so because of this we have the
common block two that we saw earlier was
the baseboard specific code that is
common across all the different devices
in this family and the block 3 is the
variant specific code end data let's see
how much code had to be added to support
each new variant in brief so as expected
majority of the code went into mainboard
googled reef and the baseboard directory
if we look at the variants reef and
Nashua pretty lightweight they almost
had no new code in them it's basically
consists of header files and those
header files essentially just pointed
back to the baseboard directory but if
you look at sand pyro and snappy they
still look pretty bulky and one of the
reasons is the device tree dot CB file
it's the one that is highlighted in red
it kind of occupies more than 50% of the
lines that are added I understand that
lines of code might not be a very good
metric here but it's just being used as
a reference for comparison so apart from
the device so ok let's keep the device I
understand that the device tree had a
lot of duplication in it and there was a
lot of scope for optimization but we'll
get back to that later so apart from the
device tree file the differences that we
see are in the DPT F dot SL which is
basically the thermal table and this has
to be different based on the different
device devices the other differences are
mainly in like memory dot C or GPIO
configuration so the differences that we
are seeing here were the actual
differences that were present in
hardware and so they required some
amount of firmware code so if you ignore
the device tree for a while
the variant and baseboard structure
actually allowed us to save a lot of
duplicate code within kaput
the baseboard in variant structure has
since been used for all the new
platforms that are being added and also
some of the older platforms have been
migrated to this structure a next
platform is coral as I mentioned before
coral was special in a number of ways
and one of the unique things about coral
was that it shipped using a single
unified firmware image that is all the
devices had the same firmware image so
what we see here is the devices from
this family have common block one two
and three so there's no difference among
this approach obviously have its own
positives and negatives positives
because it reduced the amount of work
that was required on the firmware
development front obviously we could use
OEM IDs and SKU IDs to distinguish
between these devices at runtime but it
also had its own disadvantages
disadvantages for the oils because it
restricted them to the number of
components or the components that they
could actually use on the own device and
to the test team because anytime a new
firmware had to be released for any one
device it had to be validated on the
entire pool of devices this is actually
a very good example which shows us that
reusability might not always be
beneficial or it might actually not help
us achieve the objectives that we saw
earlier so we need to find a fine line
between achieving the objective of
reusability and reducing the effort or
achieving the other objectives so based
on the learnings from other platforms
here is the most recent platform octopus
octopus moved back to using a different
firmware image for each om device so you
see that there's a common block one -
but block three is different among these
devices here we have to reference
platforms your end bit which allows the
OEMs to have a wider selection of
components they can do a mix and match
of different components from
reference platform it also uses all the
features that we saw earlier like SS DT
generation and the baseboard and variant
structure if you notice carefully the
block 2 on octopus is slightly bigger or
larger than the block that we saw on
reef and one of the reasons for this is
the same problem that we identified
earlier regarding device tree
duplication so let's go back to the
brief example and look at what the
problem with device trace was so these
are the same three variants and pyro and
snappy and on the right on the left you
can see that even though the files were
like more than 200 lines the actual
differences between these device trees
was less than 35 percent or even less
than 10 percent in some cases so in case
of sand even though the file was like
230 lines the actual difference was just
16 lines in order to fix this issue of
duplication s config utility which is
used to basically generate the static
dot C files from device trees was
updated to allow variants to specify an
override tree what this does is it
basically applies the variant specific
overrides on top of the properties that
are already provided by the base device
tree obviously there are certain rules
that need to be used for overriding
so if a property is present in both the
base tree and over.i tree then the one
from the override tree gets precedence
if it is present in only one tree then
that's the one that's used if a device
is present in the override tree then it
gets added to the appropriate parent in
the base tree if the base parent already
had some children then this new device
gets added as a sibling of those
children an evening of this override
device tree is as simple as basically
just setting the override device tree
config to point to the variants tree and
setting the required properties and
device info which is specific to this
variant in that tree the S config
utility will basically walk through the
base tree and the over I tree in
lockstep fashion applying the properties
and device nodes as appropriate a good
example of how device trees can be used
can be found under octopus so that is
the reason why we basically have a
bigger common block to where we are able
to use more common code across these
different variants from the same family
so to summarize we started with glados
where we did not have any sharing at the
mainboard level between different
variants even though there was clearly
reused at the hardware level then we
moved on to reef where we added the
concept of the baseboard and variant
structures thus introducing the common
block to on corals we went with complete
reusability using the same firmware on
all the different variants but we
learned that having a lot of reusability
might not actually be beneficial and
finally the recent platform octopus
where we were able to use override
device trees to have more more sharing
across the different variants so what's
next I'd like to highlight one of the
challenges that we current have which is
GPIO config table duplication so similar
to device trays here the base board
basically provides one set of GPIO
configurations the variant has two
options either it can go with the one
that is provided by the base port or it
can define its own configuration if the
variant basically share same GPIO
routing as the base board then it is
okay to just use the one provided by the
base board but if there is even one GPIO
that is different for the way for the
variant then we have to make an entire
copy of the base board GPIO config
change that one entry and add it to the
variants directory
or we might be able to do the variant
configuration after the baseboard
configuration is done to let the variant
configurations stay but none of these
solutions seem optimal in order to work
around this issue GPIO configure pads
with override was added to code boot it
basically allows the base board to
provides its own GPIO config table and
the variant provides an override table
with only those GPIO s that differ from
the baseboard and GPIO configure pads
with override basically loops through
all the GPIO s that are present in the
base table and it checks if there is an
override present for that GPIO if it
finds an override then the override
configuration is used if it doesn't find
an override it just falls back to the
one from the base table the solution
seems okay but it might not be optimal
the reason why I say this is because
GPIO configuration when you are
comparing the different variants it
requires some amount of human effort to
identify the differences between the
base board and the variant GPIO s and
considering the fact that there might be
hundreds of GPIO s that are configured
per port there is a lot of probability
for human error especially as the number
of variants go on increasing it might
become really difficult to track the
differences so I mean like I said this
is one of the challenges and the
solution for this problem might actually
go beyond code boot as well like we saw
that reusability might not always be the
best solution we also need to think
about the human effort or how easy it is
for managing the whole process so we I
mean there might be a solution where if
we have an automated tool which can look
through the different schematics and
identify the GPIO s for that board and
compare it with the different variants
it might be able to minimize the effort
or a human effort that is required we
can even go a step ahead and actually
generate code using these differences so
that code boot or human actually doesn't
have to do anything and just those
tables generated by the tool
can be integrated into code boot so I'd
like to leave you with this thought and
open it up for questions yeah
with understanding your last model
wished which was this octopus and I
fully agree on it's not always optimal
to have a common frame where I want to
highlight that the difference here seems
to be very small which is then only the
variant specific coned which remind me
of whatever you then change in the in
the 1 and in the 2 means the baseball
code you still have to go through all
validation and testing I think I didn't
get you your concern was that you on the
previous version where you had the
filler for all the same you need to test
it then on all boards right ok so here
you're not in the need of doing that but
only if you change something in the
variant specific code right but if you
change it in the base board code then
you have to go through the testing
anyhow right that is was the effect at
all or correct that is always been true
like if there is something which affects
all the boats like if you if you have to
make a change of just going into the
baseball or any kind of common directory
then it is going to affect all the boats
but I mean consider this case where
device a has certain bug and we had to
fix something with specifically for that
device that won't affect any other
device but in case of a single unified
firmware image even that change or
unrelated changes particular device
would also affect all the other devices
from that same family
understood ok thanks thank you
more questions even going further with
all these nicknames then so can you put
numbers on how many different vendors
and variants and products your team
supports in a year just to kind of give
us a better idea of the scale of how
this reusability helps ship Chromebooks
so if you consider so is this like poor
platform that you're considering so for
every single platform we might have
anywhere between like four to seven OMS
and there could be like at least three
to four platforms shipping every year so
at least in development every year so
four into and your multiple SOC is
multiple volumes multiple ODMs
so all of that just keeps on multiplying
okay I guess that's it thank you thank
you again
[Applause]
[Music]