[Music]
first up Vincent simmer and we will
talking about how Intel is harnessing
this great community give it up okay
thank you thanks everyone for showing up
today I'll try not to be preachy but in
an environment like this I have to fight
the impulse but uh yeah I'm really
honored to UM been invited a lot of
community here we've worked with in a
lot of new faces and really what I want
to talk about today is you know sort of
set the mood for the event but also some
of the things Intel's doing to try to
help this community be more make it
easier to do open source development
done all use examples of some of the
things we're doing within Intel since we
want to try to catch folks up I'm gonna
stop at the half hour and maybe catch
questions in the hallway or afterward if
that's ok with people so I wanted to
sort of start with my beginning you know
one of sometimes I give this talk and I
remember I once gave of it I had a
picture of Rodney Dangerfield and I said
something about you know firmwares
the Rodney Dangerfield of the industry
you know Hardware people think you know
we're software folks application
software people think we're hardware
folks but you know you know sort of
didn't really want to denigrate the
great stuff we do really want to sort of
talk about you know what motivates me
why I'm passionate about trying to open
things up and my beginning so you know
for me doing firmware was I think was
the 80-85 my father given me a board and
I thought the time it was great you know
had schematics could wire-wrap different
chips but was excited me the most was
there was a book which had the source
code of the monitor so we had the EE
proms and actually had all the source
code and what other way to get excited
about development actually being able to
touch see how things work and that
spirit of openness and transparency over
as the years have gone on and products
have become more you know integrated
it's kind of been lost and so one of the
things that really again gets me excited
about working with open source for more
communities is how can we sort of
realize this again get the data sheets
get the source code out there so people
can innovate open up the software and
there's some you know business and other
reasons why but that's sort of again
what sort of is the fire in my belly for
some of this stuff so but as I mentioned
though I'm gonna sort of talk about some
of the things Intel's trying to do here
too with respect to open this and
there's sort of three pillars simplicity
openness and then security so really
it's not just you know is the is the
code out there it's really is our things
easy to use are we transparent open to
work with and then a security top of
mind is everything we do so simplicity
you know we build complex code bases
within Intel and we build a code base
want to validate all the features of a
chip sort of you know we validate our
hardware it's sort of like this you know
very rich block but when you go to the
market people want less if you're
building a cloud server and appliance an
embedded system you don't need all the
features but some of the ways today
we've been delivering our code is sort
of like the Jenga stack and when you try
to take features out or drivers out or
recompose it's you know the stack may
fall over some of those blocks may not
be you know well documented so how can
we make it easier for customers to use
our code make it simpler and so some of
the activities I'm going to talk about
are really responsive to that and then
openness you know openness is not just
sort of a philosophical concern it's
really thinking of what customers need
you know some customers you know don't
want to be stuck with having to use you
know us the supply chain may have their
own innovation they want to do and so
really giving them the pieces such that
they can do what they need to do and
don't presume you know what the end
customers need to do building that fold
jiangha stackin assuming everyone will
use it a quote I remember from Bill joy
is you know all the smartest people
don't work at your company huge amount
of you know you know horsepower out in
the industry so how can you empower
people given the information they need
in the pieces and not give them this
sort of full full stack that's kind of
opaque and they can't really change and
then security from both design and
development so saying we have security
features is great but if people can't
assess them whether it's putting the
documentation out there having all the
source code really making it such that
we work with the ecosystem that it's
easy to deploy fixes and patches
security is now you know top of mind in
all of our for all of us and so some of
the work we do with the community here
has security definitely in mind and then
what I'm going to do for the next couple
pages here has just sort of highlight
some of the activities we're doing this
is not meant to say these are all the
open-source activities going on in the
industry this is sort of just a small
view of some of the activities within
Intel or we're trying to act upon some
of these precepts so like simplicity you
guys are probably familiar with what
we've been doing with the FSB so trying
to make it such that for code we can't
put an open-source make it very easy to
ingest in the open-source communities
well-defined interfaces you know easy to
easy to integrate and then on the actual
platform implementation itself later in
the week you're going to hear from some
Intel my Intel colleagues about this a
project called Intel slim bootloader an
alternative way to build your boot code
it leverages some of the IDI k2 source
code uses FSP but again for certain
markets some of the embedded IOT an
alternate way to help engage that
community and say hey can we can we can
we do better
and then something we call the min
platform so when you saw that big Jenga
block and when it was pieces were taken
out it wasn't very clear often when we
have a large code base what subset you
need to build
the basic platform so what we've been
doing now is creating essentially the
subset of the platform code you actually
need to boot lock down some of the
interfaces have that code reusable
across some generations something we're
calling them in platform we have a few
examples I've mentioned and we're even
trying to drive that concept of a min
platform even to some of our core so a
subset of code what's the minimum you
need and it has to be open source so
everything other than FSB you can drop
on top with the min platform and then in
the spirit of that and that min platform
again openness it's nice to have a
design but if you don't have instances
of it then it really is not worth the
paper it's printed on so having
embodiments of the platform so we've
created a new project called edk two
platforms where we have we're vying to
have examples of our client our IOT and
servers where we build them in platform
have the associated FSP and have a
consistent recipe that folks can look at
so if we're talking about security and
we have a security ingredient show us
sort of a full stack implementation I
mean the host firmware is in everything
so you're gonna hear about the sound
firmware some of the SOC firmware
Intel's opening up and then micro Python
so tools on top of the firmware things
you can do testing and development and
then micro Python these sort of this
environment allows us then to have tools
like chip sack which we'll hear later in
the week also to do assessments of your
platform and this is again another
community-based project where we'll have
a tool where when new when new exploits
come out we can have a test to say hey
is your platform armored against it or
if you just want to do some general
Assurance work like fuzzing a certain
interface you have chip sack and then
capsule update so capsules are there are
a few things about capsules one is the
host interface
so within upstream Linux we have L VFS
we have Windows Update a way to send the
capsule but then the actual payload
which is well defined way to deliver
updates so
be a hackathon later in the week and
again capsules really emblematic of us
wanting work the community on how to get
updates out there whether that mechanism
whether how we work on security fixes so
again you know it's a journey argue
we're not there be great if you know FSP
was all in the sort of the open source
column but we're trying to make things
easier and so these were some of the
precepts driving us and some of the
activities sort of on that on that
journey and there are a lot of options
in firmware so you know if this was ten
years ago you'd see an EFI guy saying
EFI or bust and really our view is if
you're using Intel hardware we want it
to be easy to use and there are a lot of
options and I think they're great
options rich communities like the
coreboot community you boo
and Tiano core and really want them all
to be successful and not have I can't
figure out how to make it work on your
hardware the impediment so how do we
sort of engage with all these
communities as you know it's the market
knows firmware is kind of important you
know the host firmware is pretty pretty
privileged if you have your trust zone
or SMM you can cloudburst through it if
you have device firmware that's opaque
to the host and has privileges and so
really being open here not just the host
firmware but actually in the SOC the
embedded controller I think the stuff
Google's doing with its open with its
open EC then you see our 50 I think
Facebook's going to talk about BMC's I
think it's imperative to take these
precepts not just to the host firmware
we sort of fetishize and talk about host
firmware a lot because it's quote been
in the way but you know I think there
was one talkie on Maj gave and said the
pixel book has 16 updatable firmware
elements it's not just your bios or your
host firmware so we care about it all
we're just trying to sort of get over
that host firmware hump and make it a
little easier for folks and we do
believe in openness to something Stephan
myself Mark Jones when we wrote some
stuff down a couple years ago really I
think the market is really spoken about
open and I think I saw some analysts
that if you don't have an open-source
strategy you don't
a business strategy so I think this
openness isn't just a nice to have but
really as part of doing business and the
in the 21st century here so I gave you
the sort of the three pillars open
simple secure what are some of the
things we're doing now we have an open
source core coreboot has a great open
source core Tiano core does so I think
it's imperative that the core code
maximize its open
you know blobs and including that code
is horrible but our core is big there's
like two million lines of open source
code and so some of the things we're
looking at is subsetting some of the
open source packages and looking at
profiles what does it take to build a
cloud server what does it take to build
in IOT what does it take to build slim
boot can we have a simpler view into the
core there's some public mock-ups we
have that I talked to you guys about
offline I'm and then the platform code
we talked about the mint platform right
what's the Minimum Viable Product just a
boot but hey what if you still have
advanced features you want to snap in so
have well-defined packages to snap in
advanced features preferably open source
and one that we recently open source was
the Thunderbolt code so if you use a
discreet Thunder boat controller on
Intel or AMD or other vendor and you use
et k2 you can take them in platform you
can add Thunderbolt and then close
source if a vendor chooses but
well-defined interfaces on how to snap
them in if you have to do binary blobs
have a well-defined interface the
original FSP it sort of was modified for
each project that used it it didn't have
a well-defined interface we cleaved with
the FS p11 and now to a well-defined
interface so you can write class like
code in coreboot or e dk2 and then for
silicon specific or platform specific
and integration guide so if you're going
to do blobs lock down the interfaces
make them easy to ingest and then the
build tools you know if you have a lot
of platform code core code a binary blob
but you can't finalize your ROM image
you're sort of not done so get the tools
out there and then the last point is
standards you know again ten years ago
this talk would have had the EFI logo
and the nice line
of the H but really standards are
valuable for interoperability to
shrink-wrap os's
but they kind of move slow and so this
internet age waiting two years for a
standard so we're really trying to move
to if we do standards sort of a code
first do this the protocol the
interfaces work with the community and
then if it sticks and it has value
donate it to a standard later then of
course the facto standards interfaces
that are there in communities embrace
them so I want to I'll pick up the pace
because I want to give a 9:30 hand off
to the exciting security talk so again
here's sort of an action what I've been
talking about here you know again FSP
where we can accommodate these many
communities having this well-defined
interface this min platform where we
open sourced the platform code and if
you have coreboot UDK to full stack
Intel slim bootloader you boot a nice
way to sort of snap it in and then again
sort of our evolution here have the
binary blobs at the bottom open source
platform code and then on the FSP the
one thing I wanted to share is we're
trying to make it such that FSP is easy
to use but both the e decays to solution
and the coreboot so coreboot folks use
the FSP api is we call it api mode but
for the e dk2 there's a lot of sort of
wrappers that have to be written to use
those api's so we're evolving FSP for
something we call dispatch mode where it
just looks like a firmware volume so we
really won't have to make this strong
distinction between FS PS used by some
community firm or volumes by others I
know the Linux boot folks are using the
P IFE let's make it a first-class
citizens that you can just use FES and
one mode of an EFI can be FSB but you
can use FES also for these alternatives
so we're trying to sort of make it such
that you don't have to say FSP or binary
Effie's
they're one in the same and to that end
we've been working with a lot of you
folks in Open Compute listening so
there's an open system firmware so a lot
of the things we've done we've sort of
you know within Intel we have one view
you know we build that stack we validate
our hardware but we don't build a lot of
end products at scale and so OSF is a
great place to work with Ron Trammell
SCI and others from the cloud vendors
security companies and really listen to
some priorities and some views on what
we could do better so I think events
like this are great would love to have
similar discussions but we're really
trying to reach out to these venues
where not so much where we can sort of
sell what we're doing but sort of listen
such that are we making the right
investments in our time and energy and
then we have the FSP binaries the open
source code etc and want to give a
couple of examples in the market so you
know one of the big areas we're openness
it's been a little tough are sort of our
xeon core base servers so last march we
did open up a one of these men platforms
on mount olympus and on that we're
really not claiming we have the ultimate
you know cloud solution but we now have
a baseline out there that we can iterate
you know open up more of the binary
provide more of the more platform ports
and then the other thing we've
definitely listened to this community is
difficulties with using FSB so a lot of
folks today and sort of the existing PC
ecosystem get a lot of this code you
know directly and they don't really
complain about issues because they get
the full stack but if you're community
based development and you don't sign the
50 NDA's using FSP wasn't so easy so we
moved away working with a lot of our
teams at Intel from click click-throughs
2 licenses next to the file but then we
heard you know some of the terms the
license were pretty tough so we opened
the license up so it's really you can do
what you want with it you can take the
blobs and put it in your own repo and I
really want to thank this community and
the feedback you've given Intel
that was really helped us make the case
that this had value and again this
didn't really you know change the world
you know as the phoronix article said at
the end it's not as good as open-source
but it does show that we're listening
and we're trying to get there and with
that trying to get there our challenge
is you know freeing up some of the tools
our silicon code we've heard the message
loud and clear on documentation
you know chatted with Trammell a little
that it would have been great at the end
of my talk I could say here's a github
link where all these Doc's you're asking
for don't have them it's it takes a
while but we're listening debug if we
give you a binary it needs to be easy to
use
or else again we're not hitting that
precept of simplicity and then the rest
of the platform don't say if we even get
everything open on the host firmware and
the journeys not done so really looking
at all of the reprogrammable microbes in
the platform and trying to have this
precept of openness simplicity and
security top of mind so it's on our
radar on the on the books there's that
whole matrix of urgent and important I
think all of these are important but I'd
really like to hear from folks this week
on what's urgent I what's blocking your
your getting your job done and will take
the action item as we say it Intel or
action requests AR but you can give me
an AR here and sort of tine it up again
this isn't an EFI talk this is really a
community talk and I think all of these
are first-class citizens and we want if
you're in my perspective as an Intel
employee want it to be easy to use Intel
I think all these are great and have
business value and so again want to work
with you folks and openness
you know if to me it's an arc I sort of
put this page in there a lot to remind
me this is we're trying to go and
haven't quite got there yet and again
keep it simple be open and sort of
broaden our approach for security but I
didn't really spend so much time on
security because I think we have sort of
one of the world's experts here to give
the second half of the keynote
and on that point I'd really like to my
honor to introduce Trammell Hudson was
going to talk about firmware security
and do that topic more justice than I
could have ever hoped and with that I'd
like to thank you folks
[Applause]
[Music]