[Music]
good morning everyone welcome to the
security track down here today we will
hear a lot about different platforms
different architectures are starting
with arm and Sandrine give a big round
of applause for her she will be speaking
about secure partitions thank you
hi everyone thank you for joining me
today so I'm Sandrine Bayou I work at
our most specifically in the trusted
from my 80 and today I would like to
talk about secure partitions but before
I do that I'd like to give you a brief
overview of what the project is so the
the aim of the project is really to
provide a reference human implementation
of a firmware for the um v88 platforms
yeah so as I was saying the traces from
where a project is a about providing
reference code for the firmware on a v8
platforms so on the right you've got a
picture of how typical software stack
might look like on on on an arm v88
platforms so this is showing a device
that will have the trust loom technology
where the world is divided into two
parts you've got the normal world that
on the left which is running or your
normal applications your operating
system like Linux and potentially your
hypervisor and on the other side side
you have the trusted world where you run
all your secure payload so you might
have some trusted applications running
on top of trusted OS and at the very
bottom we have trusted my a which is
running at ef3 that's the most prevalent
the highest level of privileged on on a
on an arm v8 platform and so the DM is
ready to provide a foundation for people
to for people
to build such a trusted execution
environment the project the code is
designed as much as possible to be to be
reused and to be easily ported to new
platforms it's an open-source project
otherwise wouldn't be there
it's available on on github and
distributed under BSD three closed
license and the project was created
about five years ago I believe it's the
anniversary this month and so over the
years it's got some some tracks options
from partners we've got about 30
platform ports available today in the
upstream so I wanted to list some of the
main features of the 34 my eighth so
obviously being the most the first piece
of software that runs on your platform
in the trusted world it has to boot
everything and to initialize your secure
devices it's got a modular boot flow
where the form is divided into several
images the ROM from where I'm from a
persistent ramp firmware that provides
some some runtime services so you don't
have to use all of these images you can
pick some of them only and potentially
replace others by your own
implementation if you have different
needs
it supports trusted boot where every
firmware image authenticates the next
one before executing it so you build a
chain of trust from the very first piece
of firmware also it's since we have this
concept of normal world and secure world
sometimes you've got to do some
transition between the two so that's
that's the trusted family handling this
world switch you can integrate the
trusted families with a trusted West
with support a number of popular ones
this is done by implementing a piece of
code in the in the form where you
basically intercept all the requests
that are targeted to this trust us and
and forward them and to the trusted OS
it supports a recovery mode in case your
device is braked and you need to
updated firmware and also much like UEFI
it provides some runtime services so
it's it stays in in memory at one time
once your OS is booted and the US can
make some calls into the firmware one of
these services is for example power
management so I said that the code is
available on github I wanted to take
this opportunity to introduce Tracy from
on that org which is which in a couple
of months will be the place where the
code will be available just about where
the code is available it's a kind of a
new era for us because the project is is
will become soon a leaner Oh community
project that will host both the trusted
for my a but also its counterpart for
m-class devices the trusted former Emma
the m-class devices our microcontroller
space and this project will be operated
independently from the main in our
organization there will be a board of
members so any one religion join the the
the board and whether they are Allen
arrow member or not and the benefits to
being a member is that you'll be able to
piggyback on the infrastructure provided
by the narrow for example to you to get
your board integrated into their boat
farm so that it's so that the firmware
is continuously tested against
regulation and and potentially also
influence the direction of the projects
or the new features and everything so if
you want to know more about that please
go to transfer mode at all or contacts a
board
trusted from analog so now let's delve
into the the heart of the subject so
what I want to talk about is very much
related to the challenges that people
face today into the trusted world before
I start just before I start just as a
disclaimer this is kind of a hot topic
it's something we are currently working
on that we've been working on for some
time so it's still nothing is that set
in stone yet things might evolve
both on the specification side of it and
also in on the implementation side of it
but hopefully I can give you an overview
of the concepts and why we are doing
that and how we are going to do it so
one of the challenges that people face
today in the trusted world stack is that
the UM v8 architecture I mentioned
trusts own that provides you the
separation between normal world and
trusted world and the concept is really
that the software running in normal
world cannot cannot interfere with the
the software in interested world so it
cannot force Apple it cannot access
secure memory secure devices so there is
a nice separation there but beyond that
we don't really get any isolation in
particular so here on this diagram we
see the Tracie drama a running at the
highest privilege in l3 and the trusted
OS is typically running at Sakura l1 and
there is no proper isolation between
year three and secured one between the
firmware and between the the trusted OS
so that means that year three and Sakura
one both have basically the same level
of access to the memory memory space
they can access any memory they want and
they also get direct access to the
physical interrupts so as a consequence
you have the these orange arrows that I
drawn is the interactions that can
happen so the farmer in year three is
not is named never really isolated from
the trusted OS if you've got several
components inside your firmware they are
not isolated from each other and the
also the normal world cannot be
protected from the trusted OS insecure
one and there have been some attacks in
the past where people would leverage
some bug in some trusted OS
implementation in order to access the
normal world and do some privilege
escalation attacks so that is a real
primer
second channel and that the software
stack is very much fragmented so here
the we have a picture again of the same
software stack I've just put some colors
to identify who provides the code and
the dependencies so let's start first
with the green boxes so these are these
are all the trusted OS specific things
so unfortunately the when you have a
user particular platform that some
dependencies on other software
components although there are some some
some standardization at the application
level to communicate with the operating
system the standardization doesn't go
beyond that so if you have if you've got
a particular trusted OS you've got to
have the corresponding trusted OS driver
in your operating system and potentially
in your hypervisor as well if you have
one in order to be able to communicate
with this trusted OS and the same goes
also in the USB firmware you've got to
have some kind of dispatcher that will
basically
interest-rate all the requests for this
particular seed OS and forward them in a
trusted OS specific manner to secure l1
so so yeah the the other thing is that
the code is coming from different
vendors so obviously there's the trusted
OS vendor like I just explained but
potentially there is also some code
provided by the silicon vendor if if you
need to access to some particular Traci
the hardware resources
you must most probably will need some
driver into the el3 firmware and into
the trusted OS and the fact that there
is no proper isolation between the
trusted OS and the firmware and that and
that it's provided by different vendors
means that these people have to trust
each other
these software images has to
right to some degree and that's an issue
so the solution that I'm proposes is to
introduce virtualization in the trusted
world so maybe you've heard that there's
a new version of the architecture coming
MV 8.4 and that will give us secure
virtualization extensions with a new
exception level which is secure
l2 and that will allow us to run some
firmware code at this exception level
and it will be very similar to the
counterpart I mean the EO 2 in the
normal world where you people use a
hypervisor at the moment so that means
that the hypervisor will I mean sorry
the security l2 firmware will be able to
restrain access to the physical memory
for the trace addresses because Tracy
devices will no longer access directly
to physical memory instead they will
access to intermediate physical
addresses that are then translated by a
second stage of the MMU by the security
or to Farmer so you've got two stages
like that and and so the secure yacht's
who firmware can control like that
exactly what physical memory is accessed
by the trusted OS and the same for the
physical interrupts they will be routed
to secure your - instead of the security
l1 so that means that the situation for
my controls them and if it deems that
it's it's a it's a in interrupt that it
would that it need to forward to the
trusted OS it can reenact it as a
virtual interrupt into the trusted OS so
these are all the hardware feature that
we'll get with MV 8.4 but of course we
also need a software architecture to
leverage all of this and that's where
the secure partitions would would would
play a role so a secure partition in
this context is a software sandbox that
friends interested world so it's a
sandbox that means that its isolated
from
other secure partitions in the system
and from from all other software
entities and it's iterance at the low
privileged exception level under the
control of higher privilege software and
the aim is really to for a secure
partition to provide secure services so
just to illustrate give you a better
idea what a secure service is you may
think about platform specific services
think about Russ or O'Hanlon so that
when you you've got a hardware error
like a memory corruption something it
might be fatal
you might not be able to recover from
this from this error but you might at
least be able to read some platform
specific register that will give you a
bit more information about how this
error occurred in what circumstances and
build a narrow report a report so that's
something you could do you could
implement in a secure service you could
also have device specific services if
you if you've got some cryptographic
Hardware on your platform you might want
to have a dedicated secure service that
controls this cryptographic Hardware and
although the rest of the software type
would have to interface with the secure
service to access the cryptographic
Hardware behind it so there are two
examples of quite Hardware related the
secure services but you can also have of
some higher level services to implement
protocols like secure storage secure
payment or secure firmware on the
updates and all of these secure services
and secure partitions are meant to be
independent of any operating system
because remember one of the challenges
in the Transvaal is really that we have
this dependency on the trusted OS
so by standardizing the communication
interfaces between the city of partition
and the rest of the world we we would
remove this this dependency now so this
is how the world would look like we
sit your partitions so in the greenboxes
you've got two example of secure
partitions so the first one is let's say
it's a simple one that would run both in
security l0 and secure l1 but you can
also have more complex
secure partition that encapsulate a
whole trusted OS and it's trusted
applications so and you may have as many
secure partitions as you want in your
system so obviously you need some kind
of entity that manages all of them so
that's the in the yellow box the secure
partition manager so that's the bit of
code that would run at secure l2 and
conceptually it's very similar to a
hypervisor that would manage its guest
operating systems and the secure
partition manager is provided by the
trusted for my a project and the project
will continue to ship the year 3
firmware as well obviously now this is
so unfortunately I'm here Todd for is
not there yet so for the time being we
don't have any security l2 we don't have
any secure virtualization so that's
that's how the software side currently
looks like
so we since there is no secure to the
city of partition manager currently runs
at l3 and it's part of the really the
same binary as the trace the rest of the
trace is from 1a and the secure
partition run at secure Year Zero
because as I say there is no proper
isolation between year 3 and secure year
1 so we don't want to put secure
partition that secure l1 other way that
kind of defeat the purpose of set your
partitions so and we just have a bit of
glue code a disorder yellow box it's
just because architectural II it's not
possible for secure zero code to call
directly into year 3 code the way you do
that usually is by executing an SMC
instruction secure monitor call
that's that's an undefined instruction
for security zero so we've just got a
bit of glue cut that relay as we seize
that sorry secure your zero code can
make a supervisor call in to secure one
so we just have a bit of glue code that
we relay as visas into SMC's and that
that software architecture enables that
to start implementing SPM with the
current architecture now I just wanted
to give a bit more detail about some of
the implementation details of secure
partition mostly around their runtime
model so obviously a secure partition
provides some secure services so we need
a way for the other pieces of software
to request these services so we need
some kind of communication model so
we've implemented a client-server model
where in this context the server is a
secure service and the client can be
either running in the normal world so it
could be your bootloader or your
operating system but it can also be
another secure service in case you have
some dependencies between secure
partition earlier I was talking about a
secure service that food tried your
cryptographic Hardware in this case that
will probably that may involve a
dependency on another secure partition
that would like to implement a secure
storage pit for example and so in terms
of implementation a secure service
service is really just a passive bit of
code that waits for something to do so
it's just a loop that waits for some
input and when it receives some some
some work to do it just processes it and
and then Tessa forever and for every
communication between a client and a
secure partition everything goes through
the secure partition manager and one
important thing also is that we want we
we want as much as possible that the
normal world software stays in charge of
scheduling what I mean by that is that
we we don't want the teacher service for
execute to execute for a very long
period of time because that would result
in a blackout from the point of view of
the offshore Linux kernel for example so
if you've got your scheduler in Linux
that he trained to take the best
decisions you know on what what
applications to schedule having the
secure box then in all the sikhism sorry
having the trusted world stealing all
the cpu cycles like that would mess up
everything
so it's really for the if the normal
world thinks that some service is taking
too long to to complete it can always
interrupt it that might not be the case
in all it's not the only model that we
will support but that we see that as the
the main one so as I said at the
beginning one of the issue is really one
of the issues in the trusted world is
really that we don't have any standard
so the one of our aims is to standardize
all these communication interfaces so
arm is introducing two new
specifications which one for the clients
to request some services so that's the
secure partition client interface or SPC
I and for an another standard a standard
is for secure partitions to actually
handle the requests they receive from
clients so that would be standard ID by
standardized by the secure partition
runtime or SPRT so this specification
are still under development at the
moment and the aim is for the trusted
former project to provide a reference
movement ation of this of these
standards and this is still under
development as well
so the the s PCI is really just a
collection of a B is for clients to to
to discover the secure services that are
available on your platform each service
basically has a unique ID so the clients
that's how they refer to as secure
service the secure partition manager
basically keeps a kind of registry or a
database of all the city of partition
IDs in the system and in which partition
this is implemented so that it can
forward the request to the right
partition the especia also obviously
allow clients to establish a
communication channel with a given
secure service when it's been identified
and eastern messages with the secure
service and if there is a kind of big
payload to attach to this request there
is a possibility to share some memory
between the client and the secure
partition to put the payload inside and
on the other hand the SPRT is a again a
collection of a B is for the design
provided to secure partitions that's
implemented by the SPM again and it
allows secure partitions to retrieve
client request to send responses back to
them and to receive to receive any
interrupts that would be targeted to
this secure partition either some-some
interrupts potentially you might have a
secure service that handles the device
so it would own all the interrupts of
this device or it can also be some inter
process communication between those
secure partitions if they want to send
interest to each other and the the SPRT
this runtime model is really there to
provide a frame for people to to
implement secure services on top so it
is the development of secure services
and it also improves the robustness and
security of secure services since people
don't have to reinvent the wheel from
the beginning every time so remove some
of the usual mistake that they could
made make in the implementation
so hopefully this gives you an idea of
why we are working on that and what we
are trying to achieve and how we are
going going to implement that I put a
few links to have a look at your leisure
me to the Tracy from our a code and also
the last link is a white paper from from
arm that basically talks about what I
just presented in more details so if you
want to know more I invite you to have a
look at this one
do you have any questions hi so my main
question about this architecture is
tension with the securio to is
essentially why don't you just have the
Secours because there's already a
separation between secure ear 0 and the
other one right so why can't you just
only have the secure services in year 0
and have a common implementation of
secure year one that could be part of
trusted firm you could be another arm
project and then have your common ABI
between 0 and the other one and then you
would like right now you essentially
have two layers of isolation where I
think you only want one right right yeah
so the main issue is that yeah I should
have said it so people were at the
moment so I should correct one of the
diagrams just to illustrate that so at
the moment
oops this one yeah most of the time
people only put one trusted OS into
their software stack because it is
possible to have multiple trusted oasis
but it's kind of difficult they they
have to cooperate with each other and so
if you if if we were to implement it the
way you said basically so we would need
to have some one of the if you have two
trusted oasis you will
need to have one of them that implement
the the standard for for the for the
rest and so it wouldn't be very scalable
because it will again introduce the this
this prime of of standardization so yeah
this is DM is ready to have a more
scalable software stack in the trusted
world where you can have multiple
trusted oasis sitting alongside secure
partition that that do not have anything
to do with trusted oasis so that's why
you have to kind of have something at a
higher exception privilege that manages
everyone basically just but sorry so
right now is there anything you actually
gain from having more than one trusted
OS because couldn't you just have one
trusted assets maybe develop from arm
that all vendors could use so um don't
develop any interest us and we will not
that yeah I mean people want to be able
to have several trusted devices on the
same platforms I mean I mean they've
said it to us it's mainly for audience
when they integrate all the software on
they start on their stack they may be
interested in having several devices
I thanks for the talk I have two
questions like first is can you tell
like what are the top business cases for
having multiple trusted devices or top
cases for trust leads and last year
Google zero project announced problems
with revocation of trust LEDs can you
let us know what would be the procedure
for revocation in new cases and how it
works
from our perspective right so for the
first part of the question about having
multiple trusted devices to be honest I
don't I don't very I don't know because
I would imagine that different trusted
oases provide different services but
I've never really looked at what kind of
services I know that trusty devices are
mainly used on mobile devices it's not
so much to target it towards the server
market for example so yeah so trust us
that so do you mean trust application
rain is running on right so about
relocating that is like you mean if one
of them is a has a vulnerability inside
it right but in this case as long as you
don't have any variety in your trusted
OS if you've got one in the trusted
application that shouldn't do much
damage right I mean if they they because
the trusted OS controls all the
resources that every application can can
access so I I'm not too sure about the
yeah okay so if the trusted OS is where
I will yeah that that's another issue so
so we stick Uriel to again we would have
a higher privilege exception level that
can control that but again you can have
a bug insecure a little bit but then you
can make a case for of that for for for
every piece of software
so which have to cooperate with Vargas
justices so so still the question is
open like how you revoke applications
which are inside phone and and in the
field like we have like millions forms
there and what's them so I think it's
more of them this is an issue I would
say that the trusted OS itself would
have to handle in any case it's really
implementation specific I guess I'm just
giving you my I mean I don't know for
sure okay
I'm just extrapolating I think that if
you if you want to be able to revoke
your applications you need to implement
some kind of of signature in your
application and perhaps having a
resister registering your trusted ways
of what application you trust and which
one you don't and and you can always
revoke applications there but I don't
think it's a it's something that
concerns secure your two or three former
I think it would be handle I'd hire
stacks inventors of of trust addresses
just don't have the path for that hmm so
that's the case and that's what Google
zero project pointed like July 2017 okay
yes you can replace it yeah absolutely i
mean it's it's loaded anyway by by the
by the firmware so yeah you can always
have a to have the firmware enter some
recovery mode where it would
update the the the trusted OS on secure
storage yeah
so you were talking about scheduling
blackouts before can explain maybe if it
does take too much time how that works
actually for instance if you do want to
appear a secure partition from a guest
OS on a non secure site mm-hmm and it's
time slice runs out how does that get
scheduled out and back on again because
it's kind of inverted from the from the
normal scheduling case so the idea is
for is that secure partitions are
interruptible by normal world in terms
so you can have you can have your
operating system programming some kind
of timer interrupts and which make sure
that it fires every every fixed amount
of time so if if if secure service is
taking too long to run it would just get
interrupted by the timer and that would
that would I mean the interrupt would be
targeted to your operating system which
would then choose or not to choose
resuming the request of the secure
service or if it doesn't want to then it
doesn't have to Joe's so the hypervisor
reschedules it doesn't mean that the
call from the secure petition has to
return first then it gets rescheduled
and then the call is like restarted or
well so the so the your secure service
would be running okay and at this time
you've got a timer interrupt that fires
automatically because we've configured
the right routing model inside the the
general general interrupt controller the
geek
this interrup would automatically stop
execution of the secure service and and
then because the interrupt is targeted
towards the operating system that's
where it would be delivered and you
would basically enter your vector
interrupts in inside your sick yoram
operating system so then the operating
system can figure out that the it had
made a request to to secure service and
it can figure out that has been
interrupted and so it is free then to
resumed this request later on or do some
urgent work first and and and do it much
later just answer your question so you
don't actually contacts which the state
inside the secure partition so you don't
have reentrant calls into the secure
partition you know we don't have any
real interest see but we would still I
mean yeah there's a step that I forgot
yeah y'all ready you've got to at least
save the the state of the secure
partition you know enable to resume it
that would be done by the er3 farmer
just before forwarding the interrupts
the no more yeah if you run a septic
correctly that requires new hardware
features mm-hmm what in what will they
be available so it will be in the in the
core arm v8 architecture so all course
but I the only thing I'm not sure about
is whether these Hardware extensions
will be optional or not they probably
will you know in the Army I texted sure
so we we often have new revisions and
every time they introduce new features
and some of them are mandatory to
implement so if you want to have a v8
point for architecture then that means
you implement these features and that
gives some some guarantee to the
software that they are here
and some of them are optional so I'm
provide some guidance about how to
implement them but people don't have to
actually implement them to claim that
they are v 8.4 so I'm not entirely sure
whether the situation are mandatory or
optional but in any case that would
concern any mv8 core so all the cortex a
that that our army 8.4 compliant cortex
a 72 is not 8.4 whatever
yeah so when we have an eight point four
ah okay core from arm okay so the
extensions I mean the MV 8.4
specification so I mean the the document
published by arm that should be
available sometime around October but
then um doesn't deployment any emulated
core um v 8.4 course itself
some people might in the future but I
don't know exactly yeah a dot for design
about secure partition manager which is
running secure year one where does just
trust you device is turning to so I can
just go back to this for you yeah yeah
young this one so whether whether is
your trusty device is sitting on right
yeah so in in this model you can't
really have any Tracy device that's the
thing I'm recommendation is to not have
been interested OS on the current
context a well if you want you cannot
have in in the current active
architectures or you cannot have
partitions running at secure years your
alongside with some trusted OS because
you you don't have the T isolation like
I said between secure one and yes we so
that's I mean it's possible but then you
you don't have a it's kind of a fake
right because
because you cannot defeat the purpose so
yeah that's why there is no truth us
there yeah but yeah with the 8.4 just to
you all of that becomes a person quick
question about I'm Tracy I'm a dog
you mentioned the card we move to to the
website mm-hmm
that it means it will I don't get have
anymore so I believe the plan is really
yeah that it won't be available on
github anymore
moment we've got the main code on github
and we've already got a mirror of that
entre stood firm on that so you can
already go there and there's the cod
both for the receiver my a and the
trustee for my m but in the in the
coming month every single the plan is
ready to move everything there the
review the code everything that the
having our build infrastructure open as
well yeah but to be as open source as
now yeah
um just as with just this oh sorry as we
just discussed
um b84 is quite some time to go we are
currently at armed v8 - that are they
are implementations out you started out
at the first slide of your old slide
deck talk and also including our v7 mom
is trusted firmware a only about um v8
or is there a version or kind of somehow
copilot for arm v7 II yeah it also it's
also it also supports mv7 platform yeah
it does yeah I mean he talked about a v8
MV 8 platforms because that that is our
main focus but there was some traction
from from people to have it for MV 7 as
well so yeah yeah it is yeah yeah
all right so uh thanks Undine
[Applause]
[Music]