[Music]
so let's get started next up is Paul
Kolakowski and he will tell us about a
way he's been figuring out how to make
installing firmware I'm selling open
source firmware on your computer to make
that as easy as installing it like Linux
distribution like a Bunter or Fedora so
give a round of applause for Paul
Korsakoff C ok hi everyone so during
this presentation I'm going to provide
some insight about what the fine wire
and boot software situation is like for
hobbyists and for people who are
technical users well interested in
actually getting involved in the
technology you know into to a larger
extent and just using it and so I will
present some of the issues that arise
when trying to do that and what are the
points of complexity and what I've tried
to do to mitigate these issues and to
kind of move forward on these topics so
first off I'll focus on digital
technology and end users on a kind of
broad sense and I will stop by telling
you a bit about how digital technology
is made and what impact it has on end
users so if we look at the proprietary
industry there are some observations
that we can make and generally the end
users are treated like consumers and not
just clients but consumers and this
means something kind of nearly political
it means that the consumers are passive
and they're just going to try to use the
technology and nothing more than music
they're not going to be interested in
understanding how it works or in
changing it or in owning it in any way
and so the expectation from that is that
while the technology the technology
should just work and it should always do
the right thing and it should always
serve the user interest but of course
this approach is
really not neutral because if we
consider these these assumptions this
the technology that is developed this
way is made in a way that only the
developers have the exclusivity of the
knowledge and actually when you have the
exclusivity of how something works then
you're the only person can have
effective control over that so it means
that there is sort of a world garden and
only a few people in society are in that
garden and have the access to the
knowledge to the control and in the end
to the power to really act upon the
technology and to decide how the
technology works and what it does and
what it doesn't do and so this is really
a fundamental question of what do we
want technology to be in that sort of
walled garden at the society scale or do
we want it to be something accessible to
everyone who basically wants to get
involved at sort of technical levels and
when we have this situation the
hierarchy of interests may not be the
one that is in the best interest of
users of course when it's groups of
developers and especially companies that
decide how the software is made they're
going to do it with their own interests
first and that's natural the people who
do the work do it in their interest and
those interests don't always align with
the interest of end-users and nothing to
match this we can have technology that
will refuse to to cooperate with users
and that will refuse to do what the user
wants them to do and so that's the
example from 2001 Space Odyssey well the
Machine says well I'm sorry I can do
that you asked me to do something but
I'm a machine and I'm refusing so we
have a problem here and if if we look at
if we look at it on a very broad scale
digital technology nowadays is
everywhere in our lives it's in our
communications it's in the way we
interact with other people so you know
in
everything social all the information we
access and we use devices that have very
extensive input and output so there is a
lot of data collection going on the
devices know where we are going what we
do who we talk to and and basically
everything about us and all that data we
sent to some infrastructure and well
what data do we send and to whom and
under what conditions and to do what
with it
and so really digital technology affects
every end-users life and because of that
the way it's done is going to have
consequences about these users life very
directly and if we take a step back and
look in literature how this problem was
perceived it starts with Frankenstein's
monster complex the idea that a
scientist will build a piece of
technology while Frankenstein's monster
is kind of technology that will
eventually repel against its creator and
do something that is not in its interest
and because of that Asimov thought of
the thriller of Robotics that would be
ways to prevent the machines from
harming their creators and and this kind
of the this takes the assumption that
the machines are independent from humans
but we all know that they're not
independent the machines just do what
the people who build them build them to
do and so this is shown with a Wells
telescreen in 1984 where it's very clear
that the technology is just a way for
the power to impose restrictions or to
have active civilians on the population
so this is not really something new and
and this problem has been known in
literature for a while except that first
off we thought it was separate creatures
that eventually turned into robots that
were still independent and nowadays it's
clear that it's really computers that do
not necessarily obey users but obey the
people who program them
and this is why I believe we need to
embed grantees in technology that's
allowed to revoke developers privileges
meaning that they are not the only
people in that wall garden that can
control the technology but that all of
society can do it if they want to so it
doesn't mean that everyone has to be a
developer but it means that if everyone
wants to become a developer which they
should be allowed to do it and they
basically users should be allowed to own
the technology this way and this is not
just about individual ownership it's
also about society scale ownership and
basically being able to ask a
contracting or anyone to well look at
this piece of technology and make this
or that change or ensure that it's doing
this and that and not this other thing
and that other thing that you don't want
and basically this is formalized by free
software's for freedom the freedom to
use the software for any purpose the
freedom to modify the software and the
freedoms to distribute it either in its
original form or modified and the
implications are of this are well
individual and collective control that
as I said any member of society can
decide to take control over the
technology it also means that users get
to decide who they trust if there is if
they have choice between different
software and if they're not locked down
with just one software that they can run
then they can decide well that I have
different choices different options and
I can choose based on my own values and
to make that effective the distinction
between hardware and software is key
it's basically the nature of technology
that both both aspects are distant and
so there is just no good reason why one
piece of software should be tied to one
piece of sort of hardware and vice versa
it should always be possible to replace
one aspect of technology if you have
just hardware that is supposed to run
any software you program it with then
that should be the case in practice it
shouldn't just be the software made but
the manufacturer of the hardware that is
allowed to run
and that means that we need access to
knowledge and when we have access to
knowledge then users no longer have to
be passive of course they can stay
passive if they want to that's not a
problem but the point is they should
have the choice so the bottom line is
freedom empowers user and it also allows
to sanitize digital technology on a
society-wide scale but if we look at it
the way that the software of the
technology especially the software is
developed it's not always on the same
grounds so first off we have upstream so
upstream is the idea that the code that
is made will be will be made in common
so it's not just someone who's taking
that code and developing it in the
corner of the world and and that's it
and then they're not touching it anymore
it's rather the idea that we're going to
do something together and that the code
base will be common so that all the
different features all the different use
case are integrated into one tree and
and then the it's much easier for for
maintenance because that way you don't
have ten ten million different versions
that everyone modifying in a subtly
different way you just have one piece of
one piece of code that you have to
maintain so for security there is a huge
benefit because the improvements that
are brought by one person to that
codebase will benefit all other users
and so this brings the focus on the long
term rather than then shortened and on
the other hand we have so downstream
whether the code is done in a quick and
dirty way where the modification are
specific and the updates are often not
provided and this is driven by shortened
focus so usually time to market meaning
that we have to get a product out as
fast as possible and so we don't have
time to do things in the long run we
don't have time to actually commit the
the code to
repository to have it reviewed by peers
and things like that
but thankfully some companies still
manage to meet the time to market goals
and also to upstream so that that's
that's a really really nice thing to
have
so upstream we can say that it stays
relevant across across time while
downstream is really fatally outdated so
if you get a piece of software that's
downstream that doesn't get updates it's
going to be useless after a period of
time and there's just no way around that
so in with this consideration we can we
can say that the deprecated software is
really considered harmful especially for
security reasons because bringing
updates to software is just a natural
and very desirable thing to do and not
updating software is actually abnormal
and like different types of technology
like hardware where you do it once and
you expect it to work
software is something that should be
perpetually evolving it's a bit like if
you were driving a car and and you would
never ever have any technical checkup at
any point in using it then for how long
would you use it I mean the longer you
use it and the longer you use it and the
craziest it get the more dangerous it
gets because you have no guarantee that
there's no problem with the technology
you're using so that's all forgive the
Oracle it's not very practical and well
those ideas are maybe interesting but
for end-users what what does it really
mean so if we look at its digital
technology as I mentioned comes in
different different things you have so
the circuit board the integrated
circuits then so logic configuration
which is what you find an FPGA is like
this and then in the end software that
are the instructions and so some of
those can be reprogrammed and some of
those effects so the hardware aspects
are always fixed and integrated so sorry
software and logic configuration you can
actually
you reprogram so what is the state of
free software on digital devices so
nowadays we have lots of systems and
applications that work and those are
divided in two categories you have those
that are generic like the user
interfaces and all the the the
applications and those don't depend on
the hardware but on the other hand you
have all the hardware specific support
which is what we people usually work on
so that that's for the system part so
how does this which support is usually
in the kernel and nowadays support in
the Linux kernel is pretty good for a
wide range of devices but what about
boot software and fibers well the
situation is that most of the time they
come pre-installed with the device so it
means that it's not actually expected
that this will get updated so of course
there are exceptions like the
Chromebooks for instance where the
firmware updates is all part of the the
update process and it was really thought
through but on the the widest variety of
hardware that you can find in shops the
the boot software and fibers are just
installed once and they expect it to
work and to never be updated and so
that's a problem and this makes this
situation rather complicated for for for
free free software and if we look at it
boot software is really critical for
freedom privacy and security
especially because boot software is also
the root of trust it's the first kind of
software piece that runs on the device
so if that software is compromised then
the the whole chain that follows it
cannot be trusted any longer so for
security there are especially huge
implications so in the free software
world we have we have significant boot
software so we have I mention core boots
and new boots Co boots covers lots of
Intel x86 devices also a few arm and
MIPS ones and also we
five is upcoming and on the other hand
we have you boots
that really is about embedded devices so
that might be single board computers as
well as phones or tablets and mobile
devices and with those two we can
already cover a good span of devices
that that's many many many types there
are also other projects that are less
known but also quite interesting
sometimes have technical advantages over
others
so that's bear box and little kernel and
on top of that you have payloads that
are sometimes sometimes called boot
loaders although the distinction can be
a bit blurry you have see buyers Diana
called Robin depth-charge so those are
all payloads four core boots you boots
usually has its own kind of interfaces
to to boot up and these also provide the
user interfaces in the end for for for
the users but we also have the privilege
execution mode which is something that
came up rather recently I would say so
I'm toasted fine where is the reference
free implementation on arm there is also
something called up T which is not
actually at the same level as on trusted
framework so up C is rather on the the
privileged execution mode it's a system
kind of equivalent and in this privilege
execution modes the software that runs
has the highest level well as the name
indicates of privileges so it means that
it can have access at all the hardware
it can forbid the main operating system
from accessing some of the hardware it
can yeah forbid operations like this so
it's also really critical for privacy
and security because if in that in that
privilege execution mode you have
non-free software running then you
basically cannot trust what the main
operating system is doing and that stuff
is all always it keeps running on the
side of
the main operating system so
implications are high now for end-users
hobbyists and people who would like to
actually replace the boot software with
free projects and also the farmers like
they do with the system and with the
system it's it's actually not so hard
that there are installation guides and
they apply to lots of different systems
and it's usually something that people
can do and although not everyone has the
ability to install their own the
operating system on the machine it's not
hard to find people who can do this and
they are usually installed parties and
things like this where people gather
together and they help those who don't
have the technical knowledge to do it
and the point is that those people who
can actually replace the system don't
have to be developers because there are
enough instructions and the process is
simple enough but if we look at the the
fine wire and boot projects then becomes
a lot harder and finding people who
actually know how to replace the these
pieces of software with with free ones
is very complicated and there are also
additional limitations in addition to
the sheer technical complexity so the
main problem we have is and false
signature verifications so the idea that
the boot software will be sign with a
cropped Agra cryptographic key and that
is fused in the hardware itself so the
public key is fused in the hardware
itself and it will be used to verify
that the boot software that was
installed matches that key so there is a
signature and if it didn't match then
what's going to happen is the device
will be turned into a brick because the
device can no longer boots and it the
device will just refuse to work and that
is a very clear indication that these
devices and platforms are fatally flawed
if they're not if they're not able to do
what the users tell them to do then
there's a big problem going on
and it's really the idea that in those
models that are often presented as
security but it's security always
depends on the threat model and on who
it serves so in that case it's security
but security for the manufacturer and
not for the user the user is actually
considered to be a threat because
they're not allowed to change the
software by themselves they have to
trust the manufacturer and maybe the
manufacturer is just not in in the the
trust model of the user maybe for
whatever reason the user decides not to
stress the manufacturer and they should
be able to do it because again the
hardware and the software are two
distinct aspects that should not be
intrigued one with the other so for this
reason the the platforms that have and
the devices that have this limitations I
consider to be fatally flawed and really
not not very interesting for the cause
of liberating devices and empowering
users and of course even when we have a
hardware that is somewhat cooperative
the free project don't always have the
full extent of hardware support so it
really all depends on the project and it
all depends on the platform and the
devices the device that is used and most
of the time this this status is not very
clear to people from the outside we
would like to start using these projects
very often the people who do the
development are aware of the current
status but it's rarely formalized and so
the next step for a technical user would
like to replace the the farmers and and
boot software with free ones is
integration so how do you get images to
install with with systems it's easy you
just you just install software with the
package manager right and you find live
CDs that you can just boot and that's it
but with with boot and fine wire it's
rare to find pre-built images
and the system distributions don't
include the farmers and the boot
software it's all taken out of the scope
and it's assumed to be in that state
where it's already installed and working
and we don't have to care about it
so that makes that makes it even harder
for for end-users and again the
documentation for the the process of
building the images like what conflict
to choose and how to which options are
right to select is is not always very
obvious so it requires heavy lifting to
go through the whole process from
finding the configuration to building to
packing the image in the right format
and finally installing it to the medium
and so that requires knowledge and
skills which are kind of above the scope
of just replacing the software for the
the the the system components the users
don't always have to to find out you can
figure out how to build it it all comes
prepackaged it's integrated and it's
easy and so why is Boonton and fine work
so very different also one of the
downsides is that the the the procedure
might be very specific to the device or
to the platform because it often
requires more than just installing
something from one place to another you
might have to actually open the hardware
and mess with some like you might have
to connect an external flash or probe to
to access the storage whether the the
farmer lives so the situation now is
that it kind of requires developer
skills so the people who do this know
how to to set it up and how to get it
going but for others it's it's pretty
hard so this is when the origami paper
comes in so globally it's a project that
provides means to install sorry to ease
the development and preparation and
installation of free software and logic
configuration projects related to
hardware supports so that is pretty
Brod but really the underlying the
underlying mission is to abstract these
technical steps and to provide some
entry points some interface that is not
as complex as it is for the developers
so this this means providing tested
revisions and configs
so making sure that everything that is
integrated actually works that it was
tested because it's also hard to know
when you just download the the source
tree flood project what is the state of
things now and what works and what
doesn't work so it's also about tying
projects together because there are some
dependencies once you want to for
instance run a specific specific boot
software with the specific payload then
you have to kind of integrate the two
correctly and that may not be obvious to
users as well also the the steps for
each device have to be documented and so
the idea here is to provide all of that
and in one place so it's kind of like a
distribution but not a system
distribution and rather I if I my
distribution and the focus of this is to
only well only care about the devices
that are relevant for freedom so it
means not the devices that are fatally
flawed with the signature verification
problem but instead focusing on on the
devices where you can replace it and
whether the status in the support status
in the project is sufficient to actually
do something useful with it and the
focus is also put on upstream projects
and in cases where there are non free
components required then we just remove
those components and the the supported
devices will be able to still function
to some extent without these blobs so
that's how it's done so the first
component here is the build system so
it's written in bash with lots of
helpers and the idea is to provide
simple actions like build
to download build to do one step of the
process but in just one call and
eventually the idea will be to have
releases for the images and the tools
they are also set up scripts that help
actually install the stuff on the device
that can use directly the build the
builds images or releases and it looks
like this so the idea is you just have
one single command line so paper build
you boot for the cubieboard - and that's
all it is and it will build all the
dependencies and everything that's
required it will use the right country
and in the end you have one image that
you can install with the scripts and
that just works so paper deploy is an
attempt to kind of tie together the
build part and image preparation backing
with the installation so in that case
you don't have to use the scripts in a
second step but it's all done in one
step so it has to be configured like
this you just provide the device you
want to use the boot medium where to
install it and the pass to the build
system then just paper deploy you boot
and it's going to do the same thing
install it to the SD card and then you
can just take it out put it on the
device boot and that's done so the idea
is ready to do it in one go and so
that's all some of the issues that I've
mentioned but there is still the the
problem of knowing what features work
and what doesn't work so to solve that
I've studied a some sort of a static
database where there is basically pair
hardware features status so the status
looks kind of like this so you have the
the different things like g-ronn okay on
the cubieboard 2 and new boots is it
supported yes it's supported and so you
have that for every hardware feature and
it gives visibility and makes it very
clear that well what can be done what
can be used with that and there is also
a special criteria about missing when a
future depends on non-free software its
concern
to be missing because we only care about
the the free the the extent of support
that goes up to free software and not
anything beyond that so the current
status of the project is that a few old
wiener devices are supported but also
many chromium OS devices especially the
arm Chromebooks so that's Tegra k1 and
the two generations of rock chip on v7
and on v8 and those components are some
some of those are actually already
usable paper and paper deploy I've been
using for months and years paper
supports and documentation per device is
still in progress so I'm working on that
I'm also working on a website mailing
list and source code hosting and
everything so far is available on my
personal jet so it can be tried out
already and in the future we want to
integrate more platforms especially so
some on devices again because those do
pretty well when it comes to free
software and also have reproducible
builds would be something very nice and
eventually distributing the binaries and
the source and in the end integrating
that in free systems like parabola or
Debian or whatever so that you can just
install that from your package manager
and that would make things a lot easier
and in the longer term I'd like to have
a graphical UI for these command-line
tools so that is just buttons to click
and it gets really really easy this way
so there is a workshop organized Friday
at 9:00 the idea will be to help porting
the gem 45 Intel laptop which also
worked very well with free software and
without blobs so we'll try to integrate
these in an origami paper and that's it
for this talk so thank you and if you
have questions that'll be with pleasure
thank you so much
so are there any questions I can't see
any Oh over there first of all I want to
say I think this is a pretty cool thing
you're doing this is really I think
addressing one of the things that aren't
really addressed well yet in the open
source form over the sole footing all
the different things together but I'm
curious about how serious you are about
the no blobs rule because as we all know
it's sort of an unfortunate truth that
there's hardly any completely blob free
devices so are you going to completely
never allow any blob devices in this
yeah yeah that's right so it's
drastically reduces the scope of devices
we can support but it's also intentional
because it shows that hey look only a
very small number of devices can be
supported by this so in a way it's also
kind of to create incentive and to say
well if you want mobile devices
supported then it would be good that the
situation changes and yeah so it's not a
very strong incentive of course but it's
also less work for me
so yeah I mean I think the problem I'm
seeing is it would be cool something
like this could take off as the firmware
building mechanism that we all use but I
think you might have a hard time like
gaining traction yeah
well it's also supposed to be something
for a very specific vision and in news
case so it's for people who want to run
maybe I didn't put the emphasis on that
too much but it's for people who really
want to run fully free stuff and that's
kind of why I've done that it's not so
much - yeah to support as many devices
as possible and also it's for those
divide those two devices that I'm really
interested in and that
I want to provide tight integration for
physically okay I have actually
questioned and earlier you told me that
origami paper mostly consists of scripts
that's its collection of scripts but
later a new talk you said that you're
planning a binary distribution so how
much of your code is like what does your
code base consist up at the moment
so so yeah collection of scripts is not
a bad description the idea is it's well
yeah mostly mostly bash bash scripts
tied together that provide this level of
integration so I think that the
interesting part about the project is
not so much the technical part of it
because that's and that's just yeah just
scripting and things like this it's
really what it's useful so - yeah
provide images in the end so I'm not
sure that really answers your question
yes it does okay
so you mentioned that basically the fact
that firma for instance is signed with
manufacturers key doesn't provide
security to anybody but the manufacturer
right so isn't there a contradiction so
if if there is a device which doesn't
require any verification for booting and
somebody owns it then unbeknownst to the
owner this could be replaced and could
become infected with all kind of stuff
how what do you think about this yeah so
yeah maybe I saying that it's only that
that's signatures only covered and
manufacturers security issues is maybe
yeah going saying too much but yeah if
the question is is it better to have a
security model that is tailored for the
manufacturer or no security at all I
think it's a very personal question to
answer it depends on the threat model if
the threat model directly involves the
manufacturer then it's probably better
to have no security at all because that
way you can still run the code you want
and you still have better guarantees
than money just one binary that's signed
by the manufacturer and that you don't
know anything about so I think it's
really a matter of personal choice and
security I don't believe security is
something you can answer in objective
terms it depends on the situation it
depends on what you want to protect
yourself against there's no just
security it's security versus some
threats so it depends on the threats and
of course for many people it might be
fine to to to agree that the security
model will be the manufacturer security
model even if it includes the user other
threats that might be fine for some
users but I know lots of people who
fought for for whom that's just not
workable that just doesn't fit the bill
so that's my point
and again this project is for end-users
but also people who want to regain full
control over their devices so in that
sense with that scope it might make more
sense to have no
signature verification at all than to
have signature verification imposed by
the manufacturer I'm not saying this is
a case for everyone or this is a general
statement I'm saying that there are
eustacia's it's relevant and currently
no one is interested in these use cases
at all so that's kind of why I'm also
providing that
[Applause]
so our microcode blobs blobs yeah I
think so yeah okay so no no updates for
Spectre or anything but this is mostly
for arm stuff and on many of those
there's no predictive execution so no
spectral anyway but that's a side point
so in a real early days of Linux BIOS we
had a web page it was like the Rama
Matic web page and you need to come in
and do a couple drop-down boxes and they
would give you a button in it don't you
download your image and it didn't work
because for a given name of a board the
vendors kept tweaking things so that for
a given model like even the very long
you know product part number they still
tweak things and buried the differences
in the firmware that does that happen in
the boards that you're targeting do you
think are they all kind of always be
wired the same way yeah there is kind of
this expectation and it's a problem yeah
I agree that's providing fixed
configuration kind of assumes that the
devices are all the same and this may
not be the case in practice so yeah
there is a problem I'm not too sure how
to tackle that maybe yeah making
different different device names in the
build system that each match one of the
configuration that's not ideal and I
don't have really a good solution to
that you may need to have a serial
number believe it or not is yeah yeah
yeah it's gonna be awful probably but in
many cases though you can the dis
approach still kind of applies like
full full ya various types of devices
it's just always the same so yeah I got
asked from work so the really neat thing
would be if you were able with something
like that to get in the early stages of
design cycles in other words a vendor
designed a board to work with this
mmm-hmm so I don't know it's just a
thought I don't know if that's even
possible but yeah maybe some kind of
runtime involvement could work like you
run a first piece that detects the like
the specificities of the device and then
you fit that back through the build
system and those so it cooks kind of the
right image so literally that there'd be
a product from a company that said works
with origami you know what I mean
so they when they laid out their PC
board they would have it in mind that
they're doing a product designed to work
with this thing you're doing so you get
actually into the then into a no DM at
like the very early stages of the
process of design okay so just a slide
all right yeah are there any more
questions are the dependencies on online
resources
how many differences are there
dependencies on online resources like
talk about something that's something I
didn't mention but I would also very
much like this to be kind of contained
so that you could put all the required
stuff on like a USB stick and you
wouldn't need to download anything extra
to get everything to build and to set it
up you know yeah I'm thinking more and
more but like people in Cuba who don't
who have very expensive access to the
Internet well if we can still get stuff
like USB media and things like that and
these people also deserve to have access
to free software so yeah I would very
much like and I will try to make it so
that this this project can be kind of
contained and you can have a release
that's just sufficient to rebuild the
image so also be able to modify it right
not just binaries but to have all the
sufficient source code to rebuild images
yeah that's very desirable I agree
although what I saw what would be
important for for at least a long time
stuff it's that any online resources
that they would be archived in any way
maybe archive.org or something yeah so
often serve locations maybe for for very
specific devices the web pages have a
dropped and so you're just lost because
you need a tool a or PE or something and
it's not accessible anymore so my idea
would be to to have everything to build
some some specific firmware to have it
archived or in parallel archived maybe
one of the archive reports so the the
solution I would have to that is so in
the releases I mentioned I want to be
doing releases at some point it's not
just binary releases it's also sauce
releases and so you can mirror that and
you can make it so that it spread all
over the world and that eventually the
knowledge doesn't disappear because
indeed that's that's a pretty serious
problem any more questions okay thank
you give another round of applause for
Holocaust you have ski
[Applause]
[Music]