[Music]
so next up will be Simon glass and he'll
be talking about a hacking project that
will bring heute back to be working with
Chrome OS and he also will tell us about
how to do firmware packaging probably
please give it up for Simon glass hello
everyone so let me jump straight into it
this is what I'm going to talk about
first of all you boot verified boot and
limitations and how we might do it in
Chrome OS that's the most part of this
talk I do a little demo and then I'm
going to talk about firmware packaging
depending on how the time goes thing
called Ben man so this is a bit about me
everything you wanted to know about me
I've mostly been interested in ARM chips
and electronics and the next and that
sort of thing I got into you boot seven
years ago now in chroma when I was in
Chrome OS the first time and I ended up
up streaming things and then after that
I dabbled in a fear different bits and
pieces because basically my day job was
kind of like a Java programmer I suppose
except I didn't do we even do this very
much of that so I used to go home in the
evenings and federal wood boards and
that sort of thing so I did quite a lot
of stuff to keep my sanity while I was
doing that at the moment I just maintain
a I'm custodian of driver model in
device tree in new boot so I don't do
you need to be like as much as I used to
and I'm particularly interested in
runtime configuration and firmware which
is something that perhaps is
traditionally not done in film with that
I think it has a lot of benefits so I
guess if you've heard a viewboot you
were here it's a very hidden bootloader
isn't very seldom do you see a you boot
logo on the outside of the device but a
large number of devices that we use day
to day lives have do use you boot under
the hood you boot is a very flexible
bootloader something which could almost
be a fault there's a large number of
features that you can enable you know
most of the major file systems and
networking and all this sort of thing
so it all says a test framework based
around a thing called sandbox which is
basically the ability to run you boot on
Linux this is a Linux program which
makes it much more convenient to develop
your software because developing it on a
I don't know a Raspberry Pi where you
put a slot the SD card back in and out
there's a serious pain so at the moment
you boot supports to verify boot
implementations the first one is users
first the flat image tree which is
basically lets you select configurations
like kernel ram disk whatever and assign
them when you sign those they cannot be
mixed and matched or anything like that
and the public key in a read-only memory
or some protected memory is used to
verify it so you boot can boot through
to the kernel and verify any images that
you happen to load if PGA's or whatever
it might be so that that implementation
is a few years old it was it's used the
talk last night about open BMC which is
sort of data center system that uses
that technology and it's built into you
boot as a court as a core feature well
recently reboot picked up Android
verified boot which is sort of like
Chrome OS
this does things it's got an a/b boot
and you can do one try the other a few
fail sort of thing let's use with the
Android things but it doesn't you boot
doesn't actually support Chrome OS
verified boot he used to but it it
doesn't because basically the supporters
atrophied so I thought what would it
take to get it running 2018 and what
would it look like he's very different
from the way it was years ago why would
I want to do this I have a day job it
does involve embedded now so I'm not
spinning anything like as much time on
this stuff in my spare time but
essentially I think Chrome OS verified
boot Metz very well onto embedded
devices it's it's actually reasonably
small as it's a fairly efficient
implementation that actually runs on the
device it has some nice features like
the firmware screens maybe you've never
seen them but if something goes horribly
wrong with your Chromebook it'll come up
with a recovery screen and you can
insert an SD card and recover the device
and get it running again
it's got auto update and rollback
support which is actually very robust
and it's got a good security record I've
mentioned you boot already and the other
thing is that the Chrome OS build system
is a pretty big commitment for someone
to digitally to to do you know if
they're trying to build I just want a
bootloader and I just want to have
verified boot I don't want to bring in
Chrome OS and you know all that sort of
stuff just to get there there is a
bootloader what's not really a
bootloader a sort of a program I suppose
you'd say that runs and a core boot
called depth charge which you know it's
what Chrome OS uses these days but it's
not really it's not really widely
adopted
so my goal is just really to look at how
it could be done and can we have it so
that we can just say okay an able
criminal is boot on it's a Raspberry Pi
and it will just do it that's all you
have to do and everything all kind of
work that would be that would be ideal
for me and I will say this is work in
progress so I'm not I haven't got there
yet this is just something that it's a
starting point I think so here are some
of the things that I think we want to
use in a verified boot implementation in
2018 you vote so first thing I mentioned
is sandbox so actually the original
verified boot the implementation and you
boot was written using sandbox it was
entirely written on a laptop with no
devices anywhere inside you can you can
write your algorithms you can run your
debugger you can do all of that sort of
stuff without any any embedded hardware
and and you know develop everything and
then when you get it working you can try
it out on a device but it should work
there's things like device drivers and
so on but anything to do with an
algorithm it's it's pretty much how I
develop stuff I can in my little
beautiful thing I push here for it
builds it takes a couple of seconds and
then it you know it can run it or I can
manually run it on the command line if I
want to use that in gdb I can do that so
it's a nice environment
I don't really develop anything major on
an actual device the next thing is
driver model driver model is something
that's been a new boot about four years
it's pretty much the means by which we
get devices up a new boot so we say
we've essentially we have a device tree
which describes all the devices and the
drivers that are needed through the
compatible strings and then we you boot
at startup will go off and bind all
those drivers and then when they get
used they get probed so they so
obviously you boot it's a lazy probing
we don't probe anything and this week
so that's a little bit different from
Linux we just have that probe step when
you start when it boots up you boot has
this extra buy and step because we
really don't want to probe every USB and
everything else you've got then we may
as well run UEFI so it's very much
trying to just be a lazy init system I
mentioned device tree
I believe half of you hate it and half
of you love it is that correct this
seems to be the this story for those of
you who don't know what a device tree is
think of it like a CPI or something like
there be maybe more familiar with it's a
little bit simpler the device for
implementation you boot is fairly
efficient uses roughly three K bytes of
memory on thumb to to get the basic
library in place so it doesn't there's
no huge overhead and there are other
features as well and a final one has
been man which I'm gonna talk about
later on assuming we get time which is
the firmware packaging one of the things
about verified boot is the packaging
does become more complicated no longer
are you just you know getting a SPL and
a new boot or something like that in an
image now you have to sign things
particularly areas are signed and the
signatures have to go somewhere and
maybe you've got some images you want to
display on the screen as well they have
to go in the firmware image and so the
firmware Packer becomes a little more a
little less trivial then press just you
know using DD you're getting two images
together at the moment you've got users
been meant for I think Tegra and x86
maybe son X I as well okay so talk a
little bit about sandbox I just want to
show you I'll show you it later actually
but essentially it allows people to run
on Linux
it supports most subsystems so you can
you know you can for example type USB
start the command line it'll go and scan
and find a fake flash stick with I think
1k of space on it and will go and you
can read it and that sort of thing so
there's quite a lot of functionality in
there and a lot all of the testing on
your new boot relies on sandbox it
actually does run on any other board as
well but the one that runs on Travis CI
and so on is is basically using sandbox
well in a bit of qemu most of the core
features at least in driver model have a
good set of tests it also supports TPL
and SPL
have any of you heard of those things
yeah one of you okay
so briefly we use TPL to load SPL DPL is
often very small a few k and then we use
SPL to load you boot because SPL sets up
their memory until we have memory we
can't load you boot in because it's too
big and so some systems you don't have
them some systems you only have SPL and
a few systems you also have TPL but
Sembach supports those and it's you it's
you run those things it also lets you
save state overruns so let's say you
have a TPM driver which has some
rollback information you can run sandbox
you you can then run it again later
we're going to see protests later on and
it'll read in that state and carry on
we're left off it even lets you persist
the drm over across runs which is
actually useful for testing because you
want to set up a case and then run it
multiple times perhaps so my obvious
plan was to use sandbox to bring that
verified boot Chrome OS verified boot
and that's what I've done so
[Music]
driver model is pretty much based around
the concept of a new class which is a
like a real-time clock or USB controller
or scuzzy or whatever each of those
things has its own API and each of them
each of these things have device tree
bindings taken from Linux
essentially to provide properties to
those devices
I mentioned it supports lazy in it it
also supports the command line you can
see the devices at the command
so on is a talk down there that you
might want to look at just or just
search for you boo driver model if you
want to know more about that device tree
actually this is cool
you won't bear to hear it I'm told but
device so it was no point in doing this
we're gonna do it anyway device tree has
a song do you know that oh my god
it's C that's the only configuration
language with its own song it's sort of
like to the tune of the Flintstones
you need to look that up later on and
it's basically just about runtime
configuration you put all your
configuration in one file in one place
and then everything goes from there
rather than having to put you know with
a different configuration all different
files and write and C code and that kind
of thing
the idea is that maybe you can run
exactly the same you boots on ten
different types of hardware and just put
the device tree and for each one and
there are some various other random
things and you it seems a long time ago
that you boot doesn't used to have K
config so I think you know define Chrome
OS actually should spell it correctly
when I do that to enable the features
automatically there's a logging system
now which would be useful to use just so
that you can log against different new
classes and that kind of thing that just
makes you say okay I'm debugging the TPM
now show me all the TPM logging that
kind of thing I'll mention the phases
have you boot in a minute and in terms
of being able to boot other stuff you've
sort of already does that so it can run
a lot of stuff in fact to talk after
this I think it might be in the other
room
is you boot see your thigh features so
the ability to run efi apps and they
grab and things like that which is so
does the other stuff if you like very
well
there's also boot stage which is the
timestamp duration system
okay so let's just talk about the boot
stages this is a specific to Chrome OS
so it probably looks a little confusing
but let's just look at this bit over
here this is the TPL the tertiary
program loader this is what we first
execute when the machine starts up now
what we want to figure out here is do we
want to do a would we want to do be one
of them is going to work one of them may
be broken one of them might be the new
version one other might be the old
version this is how we do upgrades we
upgrade one and then boot into it so the
firmware solution happens here that's
actually we're a large chunk of verified
boots going on once you do once you've
done that you go into SPL you see that
we were sdram because remember you it's
not start it's not you not ready on
startup why do we do the SDRAM after we
do the film with selection anyone know
you want to tell you anyway well the
problem is the DRM setup code might be
buggy we might have to upgrade it down
the track which I could tell you a
horrible story about that because it
actually happened and we had ended up
writing our code to checksum and correct
the memory after resume because of that
so listen listen that we learned once
you see that the SDRAM you then go to
you boot itself you bit proper again you
have two of em an A and a B this is
where the real coders as loads of code
here you know we've got full UI and
maybe we've got it you know anti-aliased
outline fonts and images and all sorts
of stuff we can go to town here I mean
finally we vote until the next I or be
again if things go horribly wrong in
either of these systems neither of these
things will verify and work or we die or
crash along the way we end up in
recovery and that's where we have a
screw a recovery screen and we try and
show people what's wrong and let them
put a USB stick in or an SD card and
recover the system so we have to have
that as well well we have to have that
and effectively read-only memory so that
we can never broke the device these are
some of the things that I wouldn't
bother implementing and I don't intend
to with the scrim OS thing you boot has
a lot of other things that can be handy
scripting and file systems Network
booting for factory and that sort of
thing but that's already there so just
leave it alone so this bit of it this
bit of the talk is just going through
driver model and how it's used it just
shows you what what I think is a fairly
elegant way to put the system together
with the device tree configuring it the
code selecting what's done and so on so
I'm this these are just fragments
don't don't don't try and type this code
and it's not going to work just
fragments to show you how things work so
the first thing is dessert there's au
class and you boot called block the
block device and lots of things have a
block device so if you've got an
immensely controller it's got a block
device same with USB and insajder and so
on so this is effectively the driver
model free it's a tree of devices and
you can see at the bottom we've got a
hole every one of these things has a
block device the one that's out on its
own over the year is actually the
sandbox one sandbox has a block device
but it doesn't have a parent now we can
iterate through those block devices we
can just say give me all my block
devices probe the each one and 0 USB
scissors
is there a file system available that I
could recover from so for recovery we
just simply go through and iterate those
block devices and find find anything
that's plugged in whether it's USB stick
or it's D or whatever else there's also
a reset u class and this this one just
lets you reset the system
find out why I reset last time this is
the driver it's pretty much the entire
driver for x86 sori set you can see down
here the driver you can see the
compatible string which matches the
compatible string and the device tree
over here and you can see some methods
including this one which is request to
reset depending on the reset type you
send out a value about some special x86
port to make this thing reset so it's a
reset driver Chrome OS needs to reset so
we'll just have it define that driver
and pretty much any platform should be
able to define a driver like that and
then it sort of separated out from the
core code the next one's a little bit
strange but essentially we want to be
able to read from the firmware and I
mentioned that the film wears
complicated the firmware images is very
complicated actually I'm not going to
bore you with the details but here we
have we've actually invented our own new
class and this new class is called a
firmware store all it supports is
readwrite and checking with a software
ripe with a rye protectors enabled those
are the three operations are supports so
you could imagine implementing those
operations very easily with a spy flash
device or maybe with an MMC device or
something like that so there's a level
of abstraction you know between that and
what you how you actually implement it
here we've got you we can show that it's
implemented by spy there's a
configuration node up here that's saying
ok my firmware storage is this thing and
you follow that link to here it's a spy
flash and so we're gonna we're going to
have a driver which which knows
basically is a firmware store driver
that knows how to talk to flies expire
flash I haven't shown you any of the
other code that implements this but
essentially it means that when you start
up what you do is you say give me my
firmware store and you can start reading
from it you don't have to worry how
that's provided how their comes about
the driver model takes care of that for
you
similar to that is non-volatile data so
one thing you have to do was Chrome
obviously you have to have rollback
information but you also have things
like did I do I want to go into recovery
this time
did something happen on my did I crash
last time that kind of thing so we have
a couple of different things we we
actually use the EC there's an embedded
controller or a little cortex in three
micro on on Chromebooks and we have we
can send out a message and say please go
and write some data for us 16 bytes of
data or please bring it back that kind
of thing and it stays around over a
reset of the AP the maintain the main
CPU it stays around because the EC
doesn't get reset in that case so we
have a driver here which basically
implements this is this is a function
within the driver it says you know read
this data in this size and we just go
off and find our parent parent device
which is where this thing here this in
here so our parent is up of the year
it'll be in this could be a real-time
clock or it could be a Chrome OS e see
if it's a Chrome OS EC we just go off
and make that call so we can implement
well the way I've done this is
implemented three different in v8 as one
as using the real-time clock because
some devices just use the CMOS frame for
they're using the TPM because some data
is what's called secure data we don't
what we need it to be protected we can't
have it disappear and we have to know
that it's valid so we put that in the
TPM and the third thing is with the EC
so we can we can say okay please give me
the data and I haven't shown you exactly
how it works but give me the secure data
please and one of the drivers will put
its hand up and say I've got secure data
here it is the other two will say no I
don't know how to do that so we walk
through we walk through the available
drivers until we find one that puts us
hand up and says yeah I've got that data
for you so again it's a fairly elegant
way to do it it's entirely configured in
the device tree so we simply put in
there RTC node we've got an envy data
now here we can put a need
we put the envy data as parent as the
thing that it talks to to get it so it's
again it's configured through the device
tree it run it run time and in a single
place the boot flag is a little bit
similar we can you know hold we can go
into recovery mode we have different
weather the lid is open or not whether
the power as you know the power button
is pressed and so on so these are all
just configured in different ways so
this is a GPIO the lid open is a GPIO so
we specify the which GPIO it is the
power off button and sandbox is just a
key that you hold down when you when you
want to when you want to power off so
it's just the key number that means a
bit random but the developer flaggers
just always on constant one so you can
hack around with this configuration and
change the way the system works and that
information effectively gets down into
all these different drivers that you
have here this one here is basically
walking through all the device all the
reboot flag drivers that I can find and
it's trying to find the flag that you've
asked for the FET driver supports it
they will call that driver to get their
value global configuration is pretty
simple we have just basically two ways
one is using K config which you for we
familiar with just defining K config and
then check if it's enabled and do
something and the other is to actually
put properties in the device tree so you
can say okay the EC takes a long time to
update and then at runtime you say if
it's a slow update see the flow to put
up a big up a scary update screen
turning a user to wait it's this it's a
way to make configuration work notice
that neither of these is changing the
build I can use that exactly the same
you boot image here just put on a
different device tree to make it make it
behave differently I won't go into why
it's useful to have smaller number of
builds probably figure it out for
yourself and probably many of you have
had this problem as every time you have
something new you have to test it
so what's the current status with all
this messing about
well sandbox boots to the colonel and
kind of everything works reasonably well
as you might expect because that's the
way that's what I used to do it
phobia maple I've been fiddling with
this laptop here which sort of works and
I'll show you in a minute
it's basically say x86 it's the
Chromebook pixel - and then with Corbeau
there is actually a you boot target that
is designed to run on top of coreboot
for x86 platforms about Evan and that's
actually what the support used to use
but I haven't actually resurrected it's
pretty it's pretty straightforward to
think I think to be able to do that and
then I've got a video game console at
home that runs a Raspberry Pi 3 so I'd
like that around Chrome OS for a
five-day I think they'll be cool so no
we don't get to that but we'll see
current status is this is kind of
working this is well it's dimmable and
then these two not so much speaking of
which now I'm going to try and do a demo
please hold your laughter to the end and
see if I can do this so here I am at a
prompt which I hope you can see and I
can run I can runs you boot basically so
that's running you boot in obviously
under Linux but it looks the same as it
would on a board if you actually used it
on a board that's pretty much what it
would say and you know you've got your
commands and you can do various things
like reset to quit and so on but it is
basically you boot if I type DM tree you
can see all the devices that are in the
system using the driver model to have a
look at what's available
so that's sandbox so let's just run the
new boot
this thing this is basically the command
line I'm going to run which I'm going to
explain briefly so I'm running you boots
TPL which is if you remember the very
first stage before SPL and before your
big proper okay so this is just a
program that you run that will in turn
run SPL which will in turn run you be
proper right I'm telling it please use
this device tree this is something that
been man has produced this is just a
logging level this is the command I want
to run I want to bind this big path
which is a chromosome it receipts you
that I built and then I want to say V
boot go Auto which just means V boot
however you want to be verified boot
just do it for do the correct thing for
whatever stage for at this basically
what I'm going to run so let's do that
and we get a whole lot of stuff so let
me just take you up a little bit so you
can see this so the first thing is that
we are starting up here where are we
there's quite a lot of stuff
unfortunately with with we're starting
up in TPL UV t PL here and we we first
of all run this version this init stage
which we're trying to verify that
everything is ok we read the flesh to
figure out what's in the flesh we've
found these things in the flesh
and now we're going to go and duel the
initial verification and this basically
ends up with us saying ok we're going to
we're going to boot from slot a we
decided that's what we want to be from
and once we decide that we figure out
where it is we hash the firmware and
check that the hash verifies as it
should we have some unimplemented ec
commands as an emulation of a khromov
sec a new boot i doesn't do everything
but it probably should
I don't know what those commands do
hopefully they're not important and then
we have a thing called a blob list which
is relatively new it's not really in
mainline yet and that one that
essentially lets you pass information
between the stages is TPL SPL and so on
we then go into SPL all that really does
is set up SDM which doesn't happen in
sandbox and then she jumps into you boot
and then we do a similar sort of stuff
again and then we end up in this loop
where we're pretty much gonna try and
boot the kernel and in fact it does as
you can see boot the kernel on sandbox
all it does is find the kernel and exit
that on a real system that would
actually boot it if we if we run it with
the LCD on you can actually see what's
going on this is obviously the the
recovery was sorry it's a developer mode
screen you can change your language and
you can you can go out of you can decide
that you want to go to new verification
on and that sort of thing so all the
screens work you sandbox has a pretty
good pretty good system for displaying
this off so that's basically a demo of
it running and I'll just show you a demo
on this device which is going to be
interesting to see if how I can do this
but let's just try it so this is a ghena
traning and I just wanted to show you
the lazy init thing that I was talking
about one of the problems in
criminalists primeras has is that when
you start up you don't normally want the
display on in firmware it takes about a
second turn the display on run the boot
ROM and everything else on this device
so we don't want to do it most of the
time so the way you bit works is that if
you if you don't need it then it doesn't
get doesn't get an owner said but if I
type a command then it will actually you
can't really see it but there's a little
cursor now it's init of the display all
they did was tell it please see your
standard out to the vid console and that
caused that to probe oh yeah I need the
video console okay no problem now I need
to run the PCI boot ROM it's sorry Oprah
option ROM and all that sort of stuff
happens laser
so the end result is that when I when I
boot the machine it it has to normally
wouldn't do it but if it sees that it
has to it will go off in another display
automatically so that's a nice thing
about driver model if you want to see
that better you can perhaps you're
welcome to come up at the end so that's
my demo and then I just want to talk a
little bit about what what the plan is a
lot of the stuff will land in the next
two releases and when I say stuff I mean
the non Chrome OS stuff access to the
Chrome OS stuff itself I'm not sure
there's a smudge code I'm not too sure
what the best thing to do is we'll just
have to see and how much interest there
is in that sort of thing but I'll take
it that far okay so by my count I've got
two minutes left and so I'm not going to
go into this in any great detail but let
me just let me just go through this
quickly and talk a little bit about then
men I didn't I don't mind if we don't
talk about it at all but I just mention
it at least so this is my motivation
obviously firmware packaging is becoming
more and more complicated bin man does
all of these things essentially you
create an image with a lot of list of
entries it packs them together it does
whatever needs to be done to them and
then you end up with a final image and
the image that I was running in sandbox
before and on this device they were
produced by Ben men here's an example of
an image we have SPL here we have some
padding 232 K and then we have you boot
very very simple image here's what how
you described it and Ben man you say
okay here's my image size here's my pad
by I want SPL then I want that's you
boot at this episode associate will
automatically put padding on that kind
so that's it it's very simple to put
things together unless you're on x86
where it's a total disaster because
there are so many binary blobs and so
many bits and pieces that have to go in
there in fact the way it works is this
only a single x86 file which does
everything and you can see that's why
it's got these if it is if we've got an
E and an entire leaf is P then we shove
it in here if we don't then we don't I'm
being told to go to the end here so
basically my objection main teaching was
been managed to make it be able to build
a Chrome OS image which it can but I
think it needs a little more work and
there's a little few lengths there to
tube in man if you want to read the
documentation and the entry types it's
pretty easy to extend in heck if you
want to try it out and I won't play this
video
and unfortunately I'm very sad I wanted
to play the video but there's no sound
there's no point please buy your family
Chromebooks helps keep me employed thank
you any questions thanks give her an
applause
whoo I'm so glad I don't have to tackle
you tackle me promise to tackle anyone
whom x-max all the time so you just
happy I didn't take 10 minutes no it's
fine
so yeah any questions oh oh they're okay
so doing your sandbox demo I saw some
line scrolling by that said something
about CV GFX did you host hi stannie
code from the payload until you go to
support the graphics so how does that
come from
oh yes it should be on the to-do list
the graphics so all gubec provides is a
frame buffer anybody in a convent it was
called a text console which has you know
nice fonts and things but no actual
graphics so yes that code is simply
brought in and needs to be removed or
something because it's but there is no
u-boot equivalent I don't think at the
moment you can draw bitmaps and you boot
but I think I think it's does scaling of
bitmaps as well it does at the moment
yes good well so you're not considering
putting that over or sorry are you
considering actually putting that over
to you boot or just replacing it with
something else
ah I don't know it's hard to say yeah
this is one of the weird things about
Chrome OS it has all these features and
sometimes you know you boot is a
bootloader right I suspect is that
there's value in it actually because
anything that has a display you probably
want to be able to show something on the
display and say yeah I can't boot or
whatever okay cool
we'll see any more questions
to quickly piggyback on a graphic stuff
we were sort of having a same question
about particularly ER and alex graph be
here because it's presenting downstairs
in five minutes
mentioned there is a library here you
might want to look at so I talked to
Alex maybe say something out there that
he says is interesting regard we got in
your talk I will thank you first and I
noticed you took some liberties with the
device tree I took some liberties with
how you put things in the device tree oh
absolutely
and I used on the matter I assume you
have no intent to get that through any
binding document to what through any of
the binding definition process there is
an open question and it's something I
think is worth some of us thinking about
is this whole concept of having those
pillar devices in me that I effectively
use as a way to group various lot of
functionalities into a virtual so the
device and in some cases you've been
sticking things in your slash commerce
in some cases you have been putting
things as children of the device
providing the apparent functionality
back and forth do you have any
particular reason why you prefer one way
or another so there is a way to say
here's a device tree that I want you to
merge with my normal one the the x86
tree has a you boot DT si and that just
gets attached to any x86 thing so you
can put overrides and things like that
in a separate place so it's not like we
have to pollute the you know pristine
Linux kernel device tree or anything
like that
necessarily so I don't have a
particularly strong point of view the
advantage of having it in a conflict
block as you saw is by an example it's
all in one place and you can go here's
my pee handle to this
no but when you're writing a driver it's
a pain to go and find all that stuff the
driver just once it's easier for the
driver to just say where's my parent my
parent is my parent if my parent is
spied in I know it's fire I can talk to
it so I think I probably prefer the
latter but I don't know I will point out
on the device tree side you vote doesn't
have user space you know Linux has
attitude as well you know you put all
your information in all your product all
your decisions and so on a common user
space you boot doesn't actually have a
user space so that's one justification
for putting config and device tree
unfortunately that's all for questions
now so thank you very much give a round
of applause
[Applause]
[Music]