so this is actually refreshing because
this is the first presentation i've done
live in front of an audience in two
years which means i don't get the whole
cheating of actually looking at my notes
into a zoom screen anymore so if i
forget where i am if i drew that's why
out of practice so what we're going to
do today is we're going to talk through
um the evolution of modern ransomware
and how we kind of got to this point
over time so we'll go through the
tactics techniques and procedures that
these different groups use we'll talk
about how you can understand that to use
it to defend against them but most of
all i want to under let you understand
how we got to where we are today and
where it's likely to go next
so we'll start off with this this is a
really important slide this is the aids
ransomware trojan and the reason why
it's important is it shows up in just
about every damn ransomware presentation
where somebody will normally show you a
picture of a five and a quarter inch
floppy disk and tell you that ransomware
all started back in 1989 with this thing
it didn't
um it's true that malware that could
encrypt devices and um you know networks
and so on did exist back then but this
trojan has about as much in common with
today's modern ransomware as a cart
pulled by a half-blind donkey called
dave has with a high-end tesla it's
utterly irrelevant
so what we're going to talk about
instead is ransomware as service so what
is ransomware as a service and how did
we get to kind of where we are well
we'll fast we'll go back in time a bit
to about the 2000s first of all to tell
you what was kind of before this and
that was theft based um
cybercrime models so by and large
whether it was banking trojans credit
card stealing password dealing doesn't
matter all of the ransomware or sorry
all of the malware back then was focused
on stealing information and then
monetizing it by selling it in some way
shape or form right and that was highly
successful for a long time or at least
it was successful by those standards
it's nothing compared to what ransomware
um does today
fast forward a bit later and we
notice that a whole service industry
spins up in the kind of malware
infrastructure so whether this was the
case of the the kind of emerging cloud
industry that was out at the time and
people seen how successful that was or
maybe some cyber criminals got a jeff
bezos biography for christmas i'm not
entirely sure but either way everything
started to become services so you want
to send um phishing emails you want to
um compromise networks you want to do
money laundering you want to any of that
stuff there's a service first so if you
want to think of an analogy
imagine spam imagine you want to get
your malware out to as many people
around the world as you possibly want to
so instead of having to code all that
yourself which would have been the the
previous way of doing things you'd
simply go and find a service provider
who will send the spam for you and they
will guarantee you know a million spam
per day and they will get it delivered
to certain countries and so on and the
nice part of the service model is you
don't need to understand how that
actually works right you just trust that
there is a good reputation and they'll
do what they said they would so whether
they're doing it through a whole bot net
of machines they're using for spamming
or they've compromised mail servers
around the world doesn't really matter
not your problem just like when you spin
up a ec2 instance in a cloud and amazon
you don't really need to know how it
works under the
hood as long as it works everything's
good and everything's happy days
the other advantage of this service
model is it makes things incredibly
scalable for criminals so now when you
want to run a criminal business you just
need to come up with the idea the
business model essentially stitch
together all the different services you
need to make that happen and then you do
a quick calculation that if the money
you're paying out for those services is
less than the amount of money that you
will make and it will be then you have a
profitable criminal business and it's
just a case of running that and it's
really really scalable
the other thing that evolved over this
time period was ransomware itself
so i mentioned that before kind of
ransomware became as big as it is today
we had mostly theft based models right
theft is the crime that actually it all
boils down to banking trojans whatever
it doesn't matter the core crime was
theft of information
there's a problem though with theft of
information so as our information got
bigger and bigger the theft of it
actually is hard to monetize so if you
can imagine i had my laptop my work
laptop in front of me here and somebody
in the audience actually compromises the
work laptop and they have access now to
gigabytes of trend micro software
projects i'm working on my email
folder with star wars fan fiction if you
really want that one
all that sort of stuff
that's great but i want you to think
like criminals for a minute and think
how do you monetize that so first of all
who would you sell that to and how much
would you charge for it right there is
an underground community of star wars
reylo fans who will pay good money for
some of the stuff i've written but good
luck finding those people right so
instead they thought well this is bad
enough when we have just bob's laptop
what about we have a thousand people's
computers to go through on a daily basis
so they did instead is they came up at a
different model and that is quite simply
extortion instead of theft right
fundamentally different type of crime
the idea here is they know the data on
the compromised machine is valuable but
they don't know to who it's actually
valuable right but there's one person
that absolutely definitely thinks that
information is valuable that's you
because it's your data right so simply
denying you access to that data and then
charging you for it back means they've
got a guaranteed customer in these cases
and that and then led to this emergence
of extortion based crime so
fundamentally different as i said from
the theft based crime that went before
and as we see it actually can be a lot
more profitable
so what i'm going to do next is i want
to take us through an evolution a bit
over time that's a high level view but
like how did we kind of evolve through
the different stages of ransomware to
this point
well first of all if we have to start
out the very start of ransomware we
start with no no i'm missing we're not
going to go through this right not this
skipping ahead the early days of
ransomware were about 2010 ish
approximately and back then what
ransomware looked like might look
completely different to what you see
with ransomware today so i assume
everybody knows how ransomware generally
works you deploy malware on a machine it
encrypts files that are important to
that person and then it charges a ransom
through some note of some description
and says pay this money and you get your
files back simple out right
so back in about 2010 how this worked
was it was primarily targeting home
users and the ransom amounts were kind
of in the hundreds or maybe thousands
and part of the limiting factor there
was how they had to get paid so
a lot of the payment uh ransomware if
you see back then was actually paid over
like sms not like just a straight up sms
but some countries have systems where
you can send funds uh up to hundreds or
thousands over sms so for example in
russia and some of the russian-speaking
countries has happened
the downside to that is it was good
money by the time but it also is limited
by geography right so if you have a
russian number and your ransomware is
only going to work for them it's not
going to work in ireland you have to
find a you know equivalent service to
make it work over here and so on so it
doesn't scale particularly well
fast forward a bit
and we have the start of much more mass
ransomware so the big differentiator
here was bitcoin so with bitcoin
emerging you now had a way that anybody
in the world who could essentially buy
bitcoin for some local exchange can now
transfer money to the criminal right and
even nicer there's a whole anonymizing
nature that comes with bitcoin as well
so it makes it even even nicer for them
so
this then led to the spread of mass
ransomware on a global scale where they
could get paid and in the process this
was kind of when we moved from a
targeting home users to it also hitting
companies it didn't really so much
target companies as the fact that it was
just hitting everything and that was
also affecting customer or companies as
well
fast forward a little bit further and we
get to the start of what's kind of
modern ransomware um at the moment so
the key differentiator was in a couple
of years after ransomware went and
exploded all the different security
vendors basically upgraded their
solutions taught about it figured out
how to stop it and generally speaking if
you have a modern kind of security
solution that does things like can
detect encryption when it's happening
right do any method protect certain
folders from being even accessed you
know has decent backups all of those
type of things make a really big dent in
stopping ransomware as we know it unless
of course you know some scenario where
the attackers had compromised the
network so completely that they had full
admin access of the network and they've
disabled all of those security solutions
in which case you're screwed right but
that's not going to really happen turns
out that's exactly what happens so
because these security solutions were
getting better the criminals needed a
way to get around that and the easiest
way to do that was moving from a more
mass ransomware type approach then to a
heavily targeted approach where there
would be actually humans on the network
disabling security software working
their way around and so on and obviously
to make that whole model uh work you
have to charge more money for it or make
more money out of every single victim
and that brings us up to what we kind of
see today with the kind of modern double
extortion ransomware which i'll get into
in just a minute so it's much more
targeted it's no longer the kind of
volume business we saw in the past but
the ransoms can be exceptionally high
making instant millionaires in some
cases
so before we dive more into this trend
and we'll talk about where it's going to
go next i want to just backtrack for a
minute
and look into it from the criminal's
point of view because seeing this
evolution from a criminal point of view
sometimes really helps you to think how
do i defend against um all of this
so we're going to take an example that
ultimately leads up to a troj or to a
ransomware called nephilim and we're
going to start off with this individual
which is a js worm in early 2019
so two things to point out before we go
any further first of all all the
original posts here were written in
russian text which we've machine
translated for you you're welcome that's
also why some of the text doesn't make
sense and secondly obviously the
author's name is not really js worm
nobody's parents hate them that much
this is just one of the various handles
that they actually use
at the time so js worm started out their
career with a remote administration
trojan or a rat called rav c rat right
very common for criminals to start out
this way and by
um by rat standards it's pretty decent
nothing wrong with it it does all the
kind of things you'd expect from a rash
or a key logger it gives you you know
remote reverse proxies you know file
manager key loggers back door capability
all that kind of stuff does all of those
things
and key loggers and rats are very common
entry point for criminals because
they're not hard to code there's a lot
of source code out there you can just
take adapt and modify a little bit but
it's also not terribly profitable right
you might sell a key log or a rat for a
couple of hundred dollars um and it
doesn't it's not people don't return
back to you that often to keep buying
from you right so as a business model
not terribly profitable so this
particular actor js worm is quite the
entrepreneur and kind of moves on
over time and sees this ongoing trend of
the mass ransomware that was happening
at the time so created their own version
called js worm ransomer which no prizes
for originality on the naming um there
and when we look from a technical point
of view it's well written it's not in
groundbreaking but ransomware doesn't
really have to be it just has to encrypt
files right you can technically throw
everything into a password-protected zip
file and it's a ransomware rights is not
a particularly good one but it still
kind of works
so in their case what was more
interesting was the amount of ways this
got onto a system so when you looked at
it js worm ransomware has been spread
over email who's been spread through
drive-by downloads through direct
infections rdp connections literally any
sort of infection method you can think
of this thing was being spread by so how
is that happening how is it this
widespread well the reason is this
widespread
is down to this line here so it mentions
that they have a 70 30 split between an
affiliate and themselves how does that
work so what they essentially were doing
the business model here is that they
partner with
um affiliates or like kind of pen tester
initial infection type people
they break into the network they deploy
um their back doors and things around it
until they have complete control of the
network and finally they drop the
ransomware component for you and to make
that um work for everybody the affiliate
takes 70 percent of the overall ransomer
profits and 30 goes to the actual
ransomware author right so it doesn't
have to do half as much work for the
effort so that's why they're not getting
paid as much money and that's also why
you see so many different um infection
vectors here because there's different
affiliates in every case doing this it's
also why if you're an ior company and
you're looking at a ransomware incident
it can be really hard to put together
the kill chain because there isn't one
killjet there's like two or three kill
chains all overlapping that you're
trying to detangle from each other
so fast forward a bit further
click and
in about the end of 2019 js worm changes
and brings out a new ransomware called
nimty now nimty operates using the exact
same kind of split an affiliate model
that um js worm had it's of 70 30. the
file itself isn't massively different
from what came before so the question
would be why why bother rebranding this
right
and if you look into details it kind of
does a lot of the same stuff and gives
details before but the 70 30 split so
the answer is we don't 100 know why they
would have done this and kind of rebrand
it but if i had to guess i would guess
it's down to they wanted to cut out some
of the affiliates that they were working
with up to that point so if you can
imagine for a minute imagine being a
startup and going into a frat house in
california and saying hands up who wants
to join a tech startup you will get some
really talented people who will jump on
board and you'll get a bunch of wasters
in the process right so fast forwarded
like six months of doing this and there
was probably some affiliates that they
worked with that just did their head in
and were not particularly useful and not
particularly profitable and they wanted
to get rid of so when they were
advertised and empty they actually
limited to only 25 affiliates they would
work with and they would even offer up
to 90 10 split for really good
affiliates who could get them onto a lot
of good networks right so this is just a
case of them kind of trimming the fat
off their business if you like
moving forward in a bit again and around
the end of 2019 start of 2020 was when
this whole new world of double extortion
ransomware was starting up and i haven't
already explained double extortion
ransomware yet but i will in just a
minute
and js worm everyday entrepreneur jumped
on this bandwagon with a new trojan our
sorry new ransomware which they called
nephilim it was actually originally
called an empty revenue edition um which
is uh what they've marketed as
originally so what's the difference
between this and the others well it's
the whole
double extortion model so if you don't
know the double extortion model the idea
is the affiliates get on the network
they go around and they're going to
deploy the ransomware but before they
actually do that they hoover up any
files they can from anywhere in the
network that they think would be
sensitive right so obviously your source
code your like sales details the star
wars fan fiction i mentioned earlier all
of that gets zipped up in one file like
a couple of gigabytes in size and then
exfiltrate it off the network to some
other location under the attacker's
control and then once all that is done
they deployed a ransomware and all the
endpoints and at that point the board
realizes they're in they're actually
under attack
so this has
two things the board have to kind of
consider at this point one they're
dealing with the fact their systems are
mostly offline so they can't work they
can't do whatever it is the business is
actually doing that's the ransomware
component and the second part is they
have this looming kind of possible gdpr
breach that they have to deal with um on
the back end which is a very powerful
kind of card that the attacker can bring
in mid negotiation to kind of put extra
pressure on whenever they need to use
that at that point
a couple of other things to know about
this this model one is it's technically
not double extortion everybody calls it
double extortion but it's actually
extortion with a blackmail chaser but
that's hard to explain double extortion
looks catcher in a headline so that's
what everybody goes with
the second is when you look at a leak
site like this which is where all this
stuff gets posted up on
it's um only the people who have not
paid normally go up on these sites so
that's not all their victims that's just
the ones who've refused to pay and i had
their data breached as a result and
another thing to consider is if you're a
board on the receiving end of something
like this by the time you notice the
ransomware is deployed the real crime
which is the complete compromise of your
network and theft of all that data
happened maybe a week ago or weeks
depending on the actual um case so
you're already far more more damaged
than you think you're actually in at
this point
so
we took the actual victims of nephilim
and we kind of broke them down to see
what did the victim profiles look like
and if you look at the actual the
countries that the different uh uh
people on the league side came from we
can see they're heavily targeted north
america south america be about second
biggest but they also hit targets in
europe uh asia oceana as well right so
but it was clearly that they were
targeting north america when they could
uh when they had preference to do so
what's more interesting though is we
look at the actual breakdown of the
victims
and nephilim strangely enough in terms
of the number of victims they're about
middle of the pack so they're not
terribly interesting compared to some of
the others also in terms of the volume
of data just the sheer gigabytes
uploaded again they're middle of the
road um although they're still one
terabyte of data is not to be laughed at
right and at this stage where they're
most definitely not middle of the pack
though is in the revenue of the people
they targeted so on average the revenue
of those companies was 890 million um
plus and even on the advertisements when
they're reaching out to affiliates so we
see in criminal forums they specifically
say they only want companies that are
200 million plus in revenue and ideally
in the billion dollar ranges so this is
what their kind of market is they're
going to and if you think of that from
the business strategy it means that
those people that they in fact are going
to be much harder to actually ransom
they're going to have better security
software infosec teams all of those type
of things so they're harder nuts to
crack but if you crack them any one of
those is a massive payday potentially
right because they have much more money
on the books than the middle of the road
so this is just a kind of business
strategy if you like if you think of it
like in security terms nephilim target
enterprise customers right or customers
to them or victims right but they target
them where somebody like conti is more
like middle of the road smb type people
so likewise
nephilim are going to keep going in a
negotiation a lot longer because they've
invested so much into it where someone
like conti will bail out of a
negotiation if it's not going well
faster because they just move on to the
next one right so you can kind of tell
from these things
so if we look from a technical level at
the actual kill chain of these groups
so everybody here is familiar with the
kind of the kill chain but as you notice
with these ransomware groups and this
isn't just nephilim it's all of them the
kill chains get very murky very quickly
uh when we start looking into these
so
if we start with the kill chain you
normally traditionally look at the
reconnaissance and weaponization phase
that's the phase we actually have the
least details on for any of these
ransomware groups because that's the
part you don't see in your network that
all kind of happens on the attacker side
and actually interestingly none of that
has anything to do with the actual
ransomware itself
so the reason behind that is the kind of
affiliate model split i mentioned before
so if you think about it the affiliate
is um the affiliate is taking care of
this kind of part the first part of the
kill chain and interior the ransomware
gets deployed at the very end and does
the other part of the kill chain
but it actually gets a little bit
trickier than this as you see as we go
on here so if we flick ahead into the
kind of delivery and exploitation phase
which is where you would see the first
kind of signs of them actually on your
network there's a couple of methods that
nephilim themselves favored so nephilim
would regularly use microsoft rdp and
they would either use stolen credentials
that they'd gotten somewhere else or
just brute force to gain access they
also liked using network vulnerabilities
in their case their favorite was the
citrix net scalar vulnerability other
ransomware groups use different network
vulnerabilities but similar approaches
to this so this kind of is generic if
you like
once they'd used that for the initial
beachhead they would set about actually
establishing kind of stronger control of
the machine so the way they would do
this is to use tools like process hacker
to delete or disable the security
software on the machine itself which
then means they can kind of run around
without any of those pesky ransomware
and stuff or anti-ransomware stopping
them
they'd use powershell which has really
sped up their deployment so in the past
a lot of this was manual now they've
kind of scripted up their playbook they
just run scripts the script ripped
through the network at very very fast
speed and do all the kind of standard
things they would do
and of course they make use of uh the
big tobacco of the legitimate software
industry which is cobalt strike um
everybody has hacked cobalt strike and
they use this for back doors to control
the machines to laterally move around um
dump admin credentials and so on and as
the actual command and control to
actually control the overall attack and
that's interesting because you would
think the command and control happens at
the end of the kill chain so it's on the
ransomware side but this shows you how
this gets kind of murky right the a lot
of the ransomware don't have command and
controls because they don't need one
right it's just deployed manually by the
affiliate as they actually get onto the
network itself but it does make all this
more murky to try and pick apart who did
one
so then once they've done that they need
to escalate privileges a bit and move
laterally around the network and
mimikatz is a favorite tool for that for
taking the credentials they've dumped
and trying them in other machines also
they would use certain like privileged
escalation vulnerabilities that exist at
a time just to get more you know admin
rights in the machines that they have
and tools like adfind which help them
map the whole active directory network
and that's for two reasons one so they
know where they want to go and target um
but also they quite often don't know who
they just infected right so they have to
figure out what is this network how big
is it and then who am i going to sell
this network to so for example if they
found out it's like 50 seats they might
say okay nephilim are never going to pay
for that i'll go sell this to klopp or
conti or somebody like that whereas if
it's like a fortune 500 company to have
nephilim would probably pay them more
money for that than anybody else would
and then the next stage just before the
ransomware is deployed is exfiltrating
all that data off the network normally
they bring it to one server internally
first and then pull it all out if
they're either using something like ftp
or mega sync and others use or clone and
some other things to do this
with the same idea
and then finally to deploy the actual
ransomware component itself right and
the ransomware isn't terribly
interesting in terms of its technical
capabilities it uses a mixture between
private and public keys aes for
encryption and it just encrypts the
files as you kind of expect it to do
quite quickly one important thing to
point out here is everybody when they
get ransomed the first thing they do is
they google and they go name of ransom
decrypter and they pray and it is
pointless because any modern ransomware
will not have a decrypter think about it
from the affiliates point of view would
you partner with a ransomware group that
you put all this effort into and it gets
wasted at the end because somebody just
downloaded an executable off the
internet ran it and they're back to
being fine again just doesn't happen
right in today's case unfortunately
so what does happen with these
ransomwares was they constantly evolved
their code to get faster or add features
and so on because their customers want
in the case of nephilim they keep adding
different extensions to the end which is
this kind of word cloud that you see
here and what's interesting is if we
take all those different variants and we
just map them out
we actually use uh this is a dendogram
which is like a family tree if you like
and we use a tlsh fuzzy hashing to do
this but essentially if you think of
this like a family tree where the common
ancestor is all the way on the left and
then the more you get to the right the
closer they are to each other right so
the green stuff at the top was the
original version of nephilim was coded
in c plus plus and then they changed to
using the go language after that and as
you can see the important thing here is
just the constant iterations right
there's constant evolution over time of
the actual trojan showing that they're
really evolving this this thing
so if we put that all together on a
miter map like this one here it looks
very complex
in fact if you
took this miter map and i showed it to
you with no context whatsoever a couple
of years ago and didn't tell you was
ransomware you'd be forgiven for
thinking this is probably an apt attack
because that's what a lot of these
actually look like because criminals
read apt reports too right and they take
ideas from them like that's really smart
we should do that and unlike an apt
attack where it's probably more stealthy
and they're trying to try and stay in
the background the network and not
really damage you directly apart from
the information theft with ransomware
it's going to be very visual and do
damage because that's how it works right
it's going to be visual and in your face
so we've put all we've wrapped all of
this up into our report i'm just
highlighting here at 3. anyone can
download it it's 96 pages long so i
can't go through all of this
um but if you google double extortion
and trend micro you'll find it very
easily what i do want to highlight from
the report is there's a ton of
recommendations in it and it's a big
long section but i'm going to call out
the ones i think make the most
difference when you're defending
and those are first of all don't ever
expose rdp on the internet for any
reason ever it always ends badly and it
like it will always embody the second
one is patching i know patching is a
pain i know all the issues with patching
and there's very good reasons why it's
hard but at the end of the day some of
these vulnerabilities are four years old
right they have patches that would make
a big difference in stopping these move
around
also any of those like dual use tools
like adfind or powershell or ps exec and
so on really limit which machines in the
network are allowed to use them maybe
the admin really needs them but nowhere
else in the network needs them and that
will really help and finally and most
importantly from defenses make sure
you're defending against the affiliates
not the ransomware if you uh if you put
all your money into defending the
ransomware component but the attacker
has completely controlled the machine
and turns off your fancy new shiny
securities offer it's useless instead
put all the energy or as much energy you
can into the initial access and stopping
your affiliates if they never get in the
network they never deploy to ransomware
and you have much better chance of
defending
so what comes next to just wrap up with
two or three slides um before i get
killed by the ipad in the front um so
we've talked about double extortion and
a lot of people think that because of
all this data leak part of double
extortion the logical thing to do is to
move away from ransomware and actually
be completely based on the data leakage
itself and actually in reality that's a
really poor strategy while the data
leaking gets a lot of the media
attention it's kind of the weakest part
of the whole chain because at the end of
the day you're just relying on a
criminal keeping the word that the pinky
promise swear that they will delete all
your data after they've taken it off the
site which they won't right
and also it means that um
these leak sites very few people
download that data in the start when
there's only a few of these groups
people would download and look for data
now there's leaks every single day no
media has time to go through all of them
and they're all on tour sites i don't
know if anybody's tried to download 100
gigabytes of data over tor yet but if
you did and you started last year it's
still running on your machine right now
right so nobody actually looks at them
unless it's a really like political
victim or something that is high profile
instead uh we are seeing some
experimentation conti for example
started experiment by trying to sell the
access to the data so instead of like
just dumping in the data site they're
saying is there anybody out there who's
a specialist in like finance data if so
we'll sell the data to you we don't know
exactly how the split of this would go
whether it's a one-time sale or to take
a percentage of the profits but that's
one model that's been tried in the last
couple of weeks but they've since
stopped this so i don't know how
successful it was
then there's the triple extortion idea
this is simply adding ddos on top so if
you think about when they're negotiating
if they have the ability to hit you with
a ddos attack to put extra pressure on
you it's quite easy to do ddos is very
scalable very cheap to do so a lot of
groups are going to adopt this and it
just makes sense and then more
importantly quadruple extortion which is
the um
not marketing bingo i promise
but yeah um but what quadruple extortion
is essentially they take the data leak
that they have they essentially scan
through it for emails of all your
customers and they email them and
basically say you did company x got
ransomed we're going to leak all your
data from them unless you get onto the
ceo by the way here's their email
and tell them to pay the ransom now and
that puts the board in an impossible
position where everybody knows knows
they're on the ransom and if they don't
pay it their customers will blame them
for their data going on the internet and
to finalize up the last thing that we
expect to change we talked about how to
kill chains kind of look like this to
this point that makes perfect sense when
you are maybe selling or doing a ransom
for ten thousand but if you're doing a
ransom for a hundred thousand or a
million that is a ton of money to give
away for no good reason so what a lot of
these groups are doing is bringing this
in-house they're maybe giving 20 30 to
the initial finder like a finder's fee
and then they're actually the lateral
movement part they're just putting pen
testers on salaries which is saving them
a ton of money in the process and
basically increasing your margins so
almost every group will adapt this
approach going forward so that's it for
me i want to wrap up saying we did a
whole there's a whole bunch more we
could talk about in ransomware we
haven't talked about things like the
effects of the colonial pipeline or the
hse breach um or hd taxes say on um the
underground or a whole bunch of other
things we could get into there's a load
of other ransomware team talks today so
you can get to see some of that there
but i would be unforgivable if i didn't
cover one last part of ransomware which
is critically important that you
understand and that is of course
reminding you of how all this started
back in 1989
thank you very much everybody