thank you very much and uh before i
start i'd like to thank brian and the
team you know for organizing the event
for having us it's great to be here
great to have a real audience and so i'm
really looking forward to you know
giving my little speech and view on the
cyber crime
landscape and you know i wanted to ask
this question this is really a question
for me but also a question for you are
we doing the right thing but before i
start i'm going to share a little secret
with you you know i'm a risk taker i
like to live
dangerously
and what i'll do is i will ever so
slightly
disagree with the grand great
bob mcardle you know i can do that
that's a teaser he's a good friend he's
a good partner
but the two points i'd like to sort of
you know challenge a little bit from
from our side but you know without
further ado just going into into
my presentation and just to tell you
what we do how we work
obviously as as europol we are the eu's
law enforcement agency we support the 27
member states we support
non-eu partners but we don't start our
own investigations we don't you know we
don't have policing powers but so what
we are we're really law enforcement as a
service you know we provide key
expertise to our member states so none
of your partners we provide you know
aggregated intelligence packages
uh we provide um you know tools and
services
and then we have a whole networks of a
network of liaison officers that are
actually physically sitting in the
building that's not just from the 27
member states but from all the countries
with whom we have none of your countries
with whom we have an operation agreement
so for instance the us is currently
present with 11 different agencies
now
in so we were established in 2013 where
part of europol
really with the idea being that we need
to have a dedicated center to deal with
cyber crime to support our member states
in dealing with the problem
but then we realized and that was
something you know similar to a startup
in 2014 when we still had you know we're
able to go to a bar at europa you've
ever come to europe we have our own bar
you know the blue bottle like you would
know that well brian you as well
definitely right and uh so on the back
on
on in a little piece of paper we came up
with the idea of saying what we need to
have a network of cyber crime
investigators so we established that
done in 2014 at the end of 2014 you know
against a lot of pushback and a lot of
countries being very critical because
they thought well that's a duplication
we already have but the problem is you
know a lot of those liaison officers are
not cyber crime experts now you know a
few
years later we have a platform and we
host a platform which is
member state let it it's well member
let's it's intelligence led and it's
very operational
this is now a platform where we have you
know 20 different law enforcement
agencies from 17 different countries
including seven
non-um eu countries and if you look you
know the the us just joined with a third
agency this is to show how much
importance they
they um attached to that platform and
with belgium as one of the last
countries to join us and interesting
enough they were quite critical in the
in the beginning so this is now a unique
operational platform globally this does
not exist there's not a second platform
like the jcat and all of our operations
everything we've been done doing over
the last you know since 2014 has been
coordinated prioritized uh through
deconflicted through through the jk so
that's a you know this is what we do
one of the one of the services key
services that we provide to member
states and uh none of your partners to
combat cybercrime
but when we were established uh it was
already clear that we need to have those
different networks you know as they say
you can't
fight cybercrime on your own you know
can't do it as an organization you can't
do it as law enforcement you can't do it
at a national level you need to have
that international network of partners
and you need to work with industry you
need to work with academia you need to
work with the c cert community you know
we need to all come together uh to
create that network and you know we have
currently
three different advisory groups with 80
experts and you know a lot of those
companies that support us are actually
in the room thank you thank you for that
thank you for your continued support
um and it's been hard to get where we
are right now uh to see eye to eye you
know to respect each other it's it's a
huge effort as you know you know build
the trust have your personal
relationships but those 80 experts from
those three different areas they're
hugely important for our work and what
we do actually we have annual work plans
where we agree on what we want to
achieve what we you know what we want to
deliver at the interview and we measure
our cooperation based on that i think
it's a really successful model but like
i said it's it's hard work i need to
continue investing into that from both
sides and what you see here is despite
the pandemic what we've achieved in 2020
i think it's a huge success so thank you
again for your help thank you for your
continued support you see it's not just
strategic and tactical but also a lot of
operational activities that have been
supported with the help from our advisor
group members
now
before i go into the key threats and
trends so that's one of our key services
obviously you know is to provide an
overview of what where what are the
threats what are the trends what
happened you know during the last 12
months
what's the future going to look like but
before i do that you know i just wanted
to you know credit that to vic baines
she is the mother of the iocta i think
it was 2013 wasn't it
the first that you drafted the first
iocta
or even 2011
there you go
so ever since you know we've kept your
legacy alive and
this is now the key strategic product
when it comes to assessing the
cybercrime landscape in the eu
we have obviously input from a law
enforcement colleagues but also from
industry and academia now i won't dive
into you know the details here because
we've heard all of that what you see
here really should reflect what you're
seeing as well there might be some
differences because obviously as law
enforcement we tend to see the end of
the attack chain whereas as industry you
often see you know the initial attack
vectors the iocs but i think in in
overall you know terms it's it's a very
comprehensive document every by the way
all the documents i'm going to mention
here you can download from my website
but you know see crime muscle service
ransomware as a service
you know huge problem mobile malware
huge increase obviously reflecting how
we use our phones linked to things like
sim swapping
you know to bypass two-factor
authentication and whatnot but
at the last point obviously you know the
continued challenge that we have as law
enforcement which is linked to the
chrome abuse of encryption criminal
abuse of cryptocurrencies criminal abuse
of privacy enhancing technology so just
diving into some of the key findings
again you know we heard about ransom
where we heard about you know triple
quadruple
attacks that's we can certainly confirm
that you know we see a lot of
ddos attacks for ransom coming up again
you know in in combination with
ransomware attacks uh just maybe a point
and um
brian i think you can hopefully confirm
that gdpr
if you become a rans a victim of
ransomware
even if you decide not to report this to
law enforcement even if you're able to
you know fix this on your own you still
have to report it on the gdpr it's a
data controller linked to the data
controller function so there is an
obligation to report under the gdpr if
you you know if your data has been has
been encrypted
now one of the years we also look into
is is combating child sex abuse online
unfortunately a huge increase during the
pandemic um much more at least based on
the data that we've seen much more
child sexual abuse material that has
been produced and circulated
um
we see a move to peer-to-peer networks
well that that's has been there but it's
still there huge problem and you know
what makes it even harder to combat that
that form of criminality is the fact
that we see more and more self-generated
explicit material that is being
exchanged
amongst young people
dark web still one of the main platforms
no surprises there
in the area of online fraud i think what
we've seen there is you know how quickly
criminals have adapted to you know
adopted
to the the the kovit 19 narrative
use that to improve their
their fishing and and fishing campaigns
and and you know certain fraud schemes
and what's also important and we see
this a lot is also in terms of damages
yes ransomware is the dominant threat
but
um it's actually also business email
compromise that we still see as a huge
problem
and then the dark web interesting there
creating criminal activity what we see
is now move away from also based because
of you know successful law enforcement
actions you know that always has an
impact replacement you know strategy or
or reaction to that we said we now see a
move to
distributed uh
encrypted communication platforms such
as
telegram and wicker and also a tendency
to use more privacy enhanced
cryptocurrencies
now
i mentioned you know i i didn't get to
the point so that's the first
ever so slightly pushback you know
because uh bob he did mention you know
ransomware first sort of you know
ransomware attack now it's true
obviously this is light years away from
what we're seeing right now but the
point is and this is sort of link what
vic has had said what brian has said you
know eugene has said
there are no sort of black swans or very
rarely and brian you actually had this
as a screen very rarely would we see
those black swans the you know curveball
that's like oh my god nobody ever
thought about this
so that's why it is important to look
back and say well 1989 there was the
first attempt you know to encrypt data
of course it's very very different from
what we're seeing right now just like
with artificial intelligence you know it
was 1940 that the first ai systems were
programmed and and guess what i mean you
know the the basic principles are still
the same now of course we have the
computing power we have the we have the
data so now we can actually use it we
have that convergence the same with you
know i don't know quantum computing you
know introduced conceptually in 1980 so
all these concepts have been around so
there are no black swans in that sense
there's a real evolution and what you
see here is something that we actually
i'm reusing this in in our 2015 iota we
had that in there and we call it the
cyber crime trichotomy we tried to sort
of you know have one infographic that
explains you know based on our
understanding how cyber crime works you
know you have sort of the you know the
cyber criminals and you know at the
bottom you have the unskilled ones that
use you know the tools and services to
attack a large number of potential
victims so you know if they're
successful
you know typically their profit is very
small but as we move up they become more
skilled more sophisticated even and and
a lot of times you know at the top they
won't even share the tools and they
those are the ones that have the
targeted attacks if they're successful
big game hunting you know they have the
huge successes why is this important
this is linked to you know what we've
heard before if you look at the bottom
we cannot we do not have the resources
to investigate that you know high volume
low volume low high volume low value
criminality we just simply do not have
the resources we can't investigate
investigate ourselves out of this which
means all these principles we've heard
you know security by design security by
default privacy by design privacy by
default cyber resilience whatever we're
going to call you know those basic
principles the things that i've been you
know discussing for years now again this
is not news you know we know what the
basic cyber security controls are we
know what we need to do network
segregation um you know monitor your
admin accounts two-factor multi-factor
authentication you know test your
backup plans all the things that we know
we should be doing
a lot of times unfortunately we don't do
because if we get that right if we
collectively manage to increase the
cyber security baseline increase cyber
resilience with this idea being that
there is no you know full security no
100 security so eventually we'll all be
you know a victim of a cyber crime
attack we need to be prepared we need to
be ready you know we need to have a
incident response plan plans not just in
you know sort of prepare but also test
it
because if that's working if we if we
manage to do that again collectively
we can focus as law enforcement together
with industry obviously csert you know
all the partners to focus on the top
criminals and the ones that you know
really cause the biggest damage not just
financially if you look at ransomware
but also now obviously having a
situation where we go way beyond
the financial
impact
all of that very difficult you know
explained in very difficult terms this
is actually what i'm trying to say
it is
the basics you know of course i'm
simplifying but it is a lot of times the
basics and if we get them right
we can already fend off a lot of those
cyber attacks
so
oh
so if we are successful you know you
could say well what's the gold standard
for us the gold standard is if you
actually have successful operations you
know we take down infrastructure we go
after the bad guys you know we seize
their assets and i think one of the best
examples recent examples is the takedown
of emote in january
this year
an operation that took more than three
years
many international partners not just law
enforcement but also industry academia
working to their coming together
very early start on a day in january you
know four o'clock waiting for one of the
the um the suspects you know to to get
to the office and then it kicked off
three different teams one just focusing
on the infrastructure one focusing
on
the the financial aspects among just
focusing obviously on on the criminals
and we were able to use new legislation
in the netherlands to
that would allow them to actually hack
into some of the cmc2 servers and we
used legislation in germany to and it
was also a novel approach to
uh seize the actual malware and replace
it with um you know modified code that
would still report to the sinkhole so we
would still get the ping but obviously
would be without
without the malicious part
and if you think about it emoted you
know for years one of the key threats in
2019 it was estimated that about 61
globally of all emails with a malicious
attachment were coming through emo ted
we i think we started i think it was
2018 probably or 17.
it was the first time we you know we saw
emoteet at the time it was a small piece
of malware
and then it developed into i think a
perfect example of the crime as a
service model right because that was
rented out to other criminals and used
it for instance to distribute
ransomware so huge
success and then of course we had that
you know expectation versus reality i
thought that was quite interesting you
know on the left we said well surely you
know this this is the command control
center of of emote you know such a large
network you know causing all this you
know hundreds of millions of uh damages
you know being used by that many
criminals you know
responsible for all these attacks but as
you probably know that was the reality
and it's quite interesting first of all
you see the difference you know because
on the left hand side that's what we
have to do that's our suck right this is
that's 24 7. you know top experts
monitoring the threats
what they need to do is on the right
hand side and just put something
together you know obviously knowing what
they're doing
but being able to control such a large
network through that equipment you see
there
of course no time to rest and i'm not
going to go into great detail but those
as many other examples um like we heard
already you know we've been like very
lucky that we've been able to go after
some ransomware groups and had some
successes there and that's ongoing
we've had some good successes against
the
dark web vendors and sellers that was a
follow-up activity but then also in the
area of
criminals abusing encrypted
communication networks we actually had
three successes in a row we had anchor
chat with sky cc and then adam which i
thought was the most innovative approach
where you know the fbi with some
partners actually developed the app and
you know
um offered that to to the criminals
you know take anchor chat
we are very lucky that we have some of
the top experts in certain areas such as
encrypted data at rest or
cryptocurrencies that was a situation
where we've been able to provide key
service to to the member states to make
that investigation happen
well emoted is it down
nope
right it's coming back
up again
now
it's frustrating of course it's
frustrating because we've invested so
much time and energy in taking it down
but it was to be expected you know i
discussed this with one of my colleagues
and his you know responses well the race
goes on you know i would just continue
with that you know game but it just goes
to show you and i mean it's very hard to
eradicate also actually the um you know
the the software the infrastructure
because there is a huge incentive for
cyberknife to get into that space
because it's typically low risk high
high
profit a high profit
uh business
now this is not the second time where we
ever so slightly disagree
or push back whatever you want to call
with bob and you know this is really
meant as a joke
now when it comes to public private
partnership and actually trying to
prevent a cybercrime cybercriminality
from happening that to us is
the platinum standard if you will
and first of all it's a platform
standard for those like we i mentioned
before you know this um you know the the
high volume
criminality that is very hard to
investigate or we simply don't have the
resources to do that but in general
especially also when it comes to
ransomware if we can help victims and we
can help to prevent or to you know
mitigate the attack that's where you
know that's the sweet spot
and the normal ransom initiative and who
in this room is actually aware of the
normal ransom initiative you probably
are
good good good that's good and thank you
for all of you who are supporting it
because we have about 170 different
partners
now it's true of course i mean the
latest ransomware it's
let's let's put it you know frankly it's
going to be unlikely they're going to
find you know immediately a key to
decrypt that but there have been cases
we've been you know able to very in a
very timely manner to provide
um the
decryption keys decryption tools for
even very you know new ransomware
families this was established about five
years ago but more than five years ago
with kaspersky
mcafee i don't know if kaspersky is
still in the room
and and um the dutch police and the idea
was about we need to have a platform but
we can where we can you know provide
victims with uh with the solutions and
then you know fast forward five years
later we have a platform available in 37
different languages like i said more
than 170 different partners but most
importantly 120 different tools that are
currently decrypt 150 different
ransomware families
in july we had the fifth anniversary
we've been able and this is a very
conservative estimate we've been able to
help 6.2 million victims and that's just
in individuals this is whole
organizations and we've been able to
prevent more than 900 million us dollars
um friends from our payments going into
the hand of criminals i think that's a
huge success of course it's you know
it's challenging we need to adapt but i
think you know if you come together for
the greater good this is what we can
achieve
and all of you you can actually become
you know a law enforcement officer you
can start helping us and that's another
area where we try to sort of you know be
innovative and that's our stop child
abuse the trace and object initiative
this is an era where you know all the
experienced
investigators you know they look at the
child sexual material they can't even
place the image they don't know where
the video was taken but the image was
taken you know so we started um
with that initiative and we we extracted
certain parts of the image like you know
a t-shirt a shoe
you know the background
and put this online
and to me
the the left two numbers are the most
important ones you know we've been able
to you know identify five project
because most importantly we've been able
to rescue 23 children those are the
latest figures just we have a pr oh
thank you that's you also yeah
well that's for all of us thank you very
much you know we've received more than
27 000 tips
this is the latest press release days
it's out today
and think about it those 23 children we
we've not been able to rescue without
the help of the public
and we have another a lot of other you
know prevention arrest materials so the
left of boom idea all of that is
available on our website in different
languages you know this idea to actually
you know educate young people educate
you know the general public how you can
protect yourself what are the threats in
in simple terms in their language so for
us that's hugely important and we
wouldn't be able to do this without our
help with the input from industry from
academia to understand how we can best
design those things
so just looking ahead you know we do a
lot of forward-looking analysis
all these reports again are available on
our website so the idea is again to
understand you know what's coming our
way in terms of new technology what are
the challenges what are the
opportunities
so if you're interested um that report i
think is quite good because it has sort
of five main categories where we talk
about loss of data loss of location
international cooperation cross-border
corporation legislation challenges in
that regard so you see sort of the main
categories and what you know the the
various different
detailed um
challenges are in that in that regard
we have now for the third time published
our observatory function report on
encryption
anything you want to know about you know
the latest developments such as
oblivious dns over https
uh homomorphic encryption using ai to
crack encryption or improve encryption
quantum encryption it's there it's
explained in terms that you can
understand it and again we're looking at
the threats the potential abuse but also
the opportunities again you can download
us that from our website this is
something i i co-authored with professor
mary aiken and there it's a position
paper where we said well you know
there's the blue line the concept of a
blue line and we said well how do we who
decides where to draw the blue line in
cyberspace you know where is safety and
security um you know who's responsible
for that and basically the message it's
a collective discussion that is that we
need to have so i invite you also to
look at that and participate in the
discussion then as a last example this
is something we
we
drafted together with uh it was actually
bob and his team and unicre on the
malicious users and abuses of artificial
intelligence which was a very innocent
question i got about one and a half
years ago from a journalist and i said i
have no idea so we looked at it and i
think it's quite interesting it's a
little bit gloomy but we have a number
of recommendations because the basic uh
message is that and i think that goes
for my inter entire presentation is yes
there's a lot of risks there's a lot of
bad things happening but
there's so much potential in cyberspace
right and artificial intelligence for
good there's so much potential we just
need to know the risks we need to build
systems that are robust
that are ethical that are unbiased so we
need to understand what the risks are
and how criminals are using ai and will
be attacking ai systems to build those
systems and of course you know they do
we have 2019 um the first case where
somebody used a publicly available tool
to emulate the voice of a ceo to have a
successful co attack about two weeks ago
um i had i had um you know attended a
meeting i was sitting next to a board
member and we're talking about this and
said yeah happened to me two weeks ago
they spoofed my number and then called
two of our partners here in spain and in
the u.s so it's happening this is not
sci-fi this is happening as we speak we
had the case where you know some mp's
thought it was speaking to the chief of
staff from navalny but apparently that
was a deep deep fake so this is you know
if you look at this i you probably know
that website but i love it you know
where you see
thanks where you know you can see those
two faces one of them is completely
synthetical you know created from
scratch i'll give you a second to look
at those two faces
which one do you think is real
yeah true so it's the yeah the right one
uh but you know if you think about that
that means in terms of you know
identity management know your customer
i've seen um proof of concepts where in
in real time they've been able to
manipulate videos so a lot of those
standards that we have you know in this
space for instance for banks when you
create online accounts you know
we need to come up with new ways of
testing those images and videos to spot
whether those are deep fakes or not so
this really gets me to the end you know
where the question was so are we doing
it right
honestly from where i stand i think
we've come a very long way we're doing
it right because we're working together
we're coming together but having said
that i think we need to become even
better
we need to become more innovative and by
the way you know we do a lot of
innovation it's just in the interest of
time we didn't want to dive into that
we've done a lot of interesting work in
that space we need to work with academia
to become more innovative even
we need to improve our communication our
collaboration it's challenging you know
somebody wants that you know cooperation
and sharing information is the thoughts
and prayers of the cyber security
industry and it's true we've been
discussing this again it's not a new
concept
but i think we've come a long way and i
would like to thank you because a lot of
you in the room are working closely with
us and together we have you know an
opportunity to make cyberspace safer and
more secure and with that i'll thank you
[Applause]
three thumbs time for questions
two wins okay
is bob still here
i think those are you know resonate is
operational work so uh whatever we do is
mostly focusing on supporting operations
so strategic tactician and operationally
i would say about 20 20
and of course we have the problem like
everyone else you know what's the how do
you measure the impact of your of your
of your prevention awareness work but
what we typically do is that we work
with operations so whenever there's a
large for instance money mule actions we
have regular manual actions last one
support but more than a thousand
different
banks you know not just within we then
have a prevention campaign following the
operational activity in the various
different languages so we also try to
really link it to the operation
activities but i would say about 20
of work this dedicated to prevention
awareness
yeah so i mean that's certainly um
obviously and bob said that you know i
mean definitely cryptocurrencies where
where game change when it comes to it
comes around somewhere
i think the volume still is is a
challenge also for criminals because
eventually they want to turn their
cryptocurrencies into fiat
uh money and that's where it's becoming
a little bit easier if the volume is
higher but then the ways to split this
up use mixers and tumblers and like i
said you know go from bitcoin to monero
see cash in the back and you know it's
it's challenging to follow the money but
certainly the volume is is i would say
then a challenge for cyber chronicles
because again they need to get this out
of the system and that's sometimes
helpful for us
exactly
oh please
you mean that they allegedly had the key
and were given that today
um
so the question is but maybe i'm missing
yeah i think that's
you know that's a challenge in general
and i think that's one of the reasons
why normal ransom is not as popular as
it could be because there's obviously a
whole business model uh out there in
terms of ransomware mitigation and
that's where trust comes into play and
that's typically you know a lot of times
we have that problem for instance when
it comes to releasing press releases you
know they have some countries saying
well we're so excited you know we're
going to release that and we're like oh
you know we actually decided to do the
tomorrow or whatever so um
you know a lot of times it helps them to
have jcat and other platforms to
deconflict and coordinate that but we
can't control this uh all the time it's
it is what it is i guess
one more question
wrap up now yeah i'm
totally wrapped up
so over time oh my god thank you very
much