good afternoon so as bob said this is
still very weird being in the room full
of
hundreds of people
so i'm still using my you know cheat
code but this time around on my phone so
if you see me looking down i'm probably
looking at my notes
um so
yeah we're talking about supply chain
attack interestingly enough i was going
to talk about around somewhere but then
i mean the room is full of ransomware
talk so
let's do something else um
we you know we all knew about what
happened with solarwinds because i have
vsa you know and i'm guessing most of
you have a question
what is supply chain
you know why am i talking about supply
chain
so i like this photo and that's the
reason why it's in this slide and i just
wanted everyone else to see it so
what a supply chain um
supply chain is a system of resources
that
needs to make either a product or a
service and in this you know in this
topic in this in this day we're going to
be talking about supply chain from cyber
security
so what is a supply chain attack a
supply chain attack is the type of
attack that targets organizations
um cyber criminals target organizations
weakest link so it's not just targeting
cyber cyber and cyber organizations or
i.t organizations but it's the weakest
link within these organizations
and
in this case your weakest link is your
third party vendor or supplier
so how does this happen
the purpose of this attack is to
compromise trusted service
again solarwinds very popular one um
and from there they are able to gain
access into more resources into
sensitive data into credentials
i'm going to be talking through the
three common types of supply chain
attack we have the malicious code
injection into private code base
we have the open source supply chain
attacks and in open source supply chain
attacks there are three different types
of attack vector typos quoting
dependency confusion malicious code
injection again and vendor email
compromise so we're going to be looking
at each of these types of attacks
so malicious code injection what is this
what happens here
the purpose of this is
an attacker scans
your network your company's network and
they're looking for a vulnerability
right so they find this vulnerability
and what do they want to do they want to
find a way to get in so they introduce
a malicious code into your vendor source
code
this is still the similar thing that
happened in solarwinds where 29 lines of
codes were you know added to solarwinds
on code and this was then you know sent
to their customers
so during the build process
the
legitimate code and the malicious code
then
automates into the update server thereby
pushing malware to
multiple customers i mean think of
trying to update one applications to a
hundred or a thousand endpoints think of
the damage that that could cost
so you as a customer you get this update
or patch as we called it um from your
vendor your trusted vendor your trusted
supplier and you then update the server
when you update your server you're
indirectly
initiating a communication with the
attacker
unknowingly of course because this was a
trusted supplier
and then you know sometimes behind the
scenes it could either be apt or it
could be a command and control server
from a you know a random hacker sitting
down in their
backyard
we have open source supply chain attack
um i think joe talked about security by
default um you know we like to call it
industry watch security by design
um i think the the concept of security
by design being essential to a company's
network and infrastructure
is a conversation that should be had
between devops team and senior
management
um it's not enough to build code to
solve a problem you need to build secure
code you need to build secure products
so
you're a software engineer right um
taking calls from the internet is
probably
might be your day job
might not be your day job
um i mean if the code exists and it's
ready for use why reinvent the real
right just use it from the internet
but
there is a downside to that because
most of the codes
online
are infiltrated malware different things
the attackers will you know infiltrate
public libraries adding adding different
types of malicious or malware codes and
you just go to the internet and you grab
that because it's an easy fix right so
let's look at the different types of
attack vectors in open source or
software supply chain attack
dependency confusion
very very interesting name
this is
a technique that involves tricking
software installer scripts to pull in
malicious packages from public
repository how is this done
so
when the attacker scans your network
because this can your network for
information all of this is around
reconnaissance so they scan your network
and they see that you have
a package a legitimate package called
acme node 1.2 right so they're like okay
well
you get
they might or might not know that you
get codes from online
so they then publish
a much higher version that you might
need at some point for your products
to the internet
and then
when automated software tools within
your organization then tries to
update their dependencies they might or
might not go through external or
internal you know public or
repositories or libraries and then when
they go external in this case they
automatically download malaysia's code
without knowing once again it's an easy
fix right so
you have established a connection
between
your network and the attacker
type of squatting we all make typos i
still make typos thank god for
autocorrect
um here
the attacker
pegs on human mistakes very very common
mistakes which is you know mixing a word
writing
one word before the other when it
shouldn't be that case
the attacker scans for a legitimate
public package so this this is
focused on the public repository the
public libraries that we would get
different quotes from
when the attacker scans for this they
then rename the package with a typo
multiple types of you know random typos
that we might use
and then
you as a devops engineer software
engineer you go to the internet and you
make similar mistakes it's possible
let's not say oh i don't make mistakes
we all make mistakes
so you then make this typo and then you
download the malicious
package from the internet down to your
network server again
the attacker has tricked you using human
mind using you know the mistakes that
human beings would make
so
what do we do
we try and review our
our letters we try and review whatever
we've written same way when you're
typing a message so fast you try and
read it before you send
and
it's not an easy fix but this is
something that is very possible to you
know it's a very easy mistake to make
when you're on the internet trying to
get codes
malicious code injection explained this
before but it's still similar and very
very common where
we would go to the internet software
teams devops teams looking for easy fix
trying to pull
data um you know from the internet and
or the attacker themselves trying to
infiltrate your code and trying to find
out okay what's happening how can i
infiltrate this network and get
information
vendor email compromise
it's a very popular one some people
might know it as business email
compromise
a lot of us you know different years of
experience would have probably heard one
or two stories about this it's very easy
but at the same time there's a lot of
financial loss when it comes to
attacks like this
here the attacker sends a phishing email
it could be you know related to kovid
the pandemic the vaccine
anything even related to work as well
and you as a recipient you get this
email it could be really good i've
failed fishing test as well before so
you know
everyone could be a victim um so
you go and click on this link and it's
like oh yeah you know update your
microsoft account or update your email
account and then you put in the
credentials
into this phishing site
and thereby
allowing the attacker still your
information you're not aware of this of
course but behind the scenes your email
address your passwords have been stolen
and then the attacker then monitors your
email they don't kick you out of your
email because they need you to establish
the communication they need you to lead
them to where
information or sensitive data or money
is
so
let's say they are able to get into a
financial
um you know accounts and then there's
invoices payments there's procurements
it's just so many conversations going on
and then what does the attacker do they
monitor the inbox
when it's time for payment
they then
reassign
the actual account that you or support
you as a client was supposed to pay your
vendor
and then you then
take this fake invoice and you're paying
the money and then maybe two weeks later
your vendor comes back to you to say oh
yeah i'm still waiting for that money
you know for the job that we've done and
it's like i paid you you know weeks ago
and it's like oh no you didn't pay me um
i can tell you for one that um i've
worked in a place where this happened
and it was huge financial loss for the
company
so why should you care
i mean i'm just probably standing here
blabbing right
um
it affects everyone um whether you're a
client you're a company or business
owner you're an employee or you're just
an individual it does affect everyone
um
you know it's there's a whole ecosystem
of communications of people of
connections
and it's a ripple effect take for
example if slag goes down um companies
are not able to communicate a lot of
companies depend on slack if amazon goes
down um your company could be you know
running or amazon goes down in a country
where your services have been hosted you
know you have a data center there you're
not able to communicate so maybe you
service different clients that's the
financial loss for yourself but this is
as a result of amazon's database going
down not your network just amazon
so you should care because any of us
really in this room could be victims you
could have your data stolen
from you know maybe an insurer that you
give your details to and someone is
impersonating you somewhere in china
and maybe stealing your your money as
well
so
what can we do to manage this threat
so many things we can we can do um i'm
just going to be focusing on three key
things that i think is important to
share to you third party risk management
because we're talking about supply chain
so supply chain is not just about you
it's about the people that you work with
your organization supply chain who is
connected to your network who offers
different services to you who who
provides you know even if it's the
cafeteria for example that's a supply
chain because you know they have access
to your building
do they provide you know
um pppe materials for you that's the
supply chain whether or not you don't
you know service the medical area
so third party risk management
example of a third party risk management
framework companies need to establish a
risk management framework
because
it's important
you need to develop
a framework within your organization to
assess
the risk for your vendors for your
suppliers
senior management must understand the
high risk that comes with dealing with
different third parties and what the
organizations are exposed to
regardless of your organization's risk
profile establishing a third party risk
management process is very important
and there are different ways to go about
it let's take for example analysis what
do you do there
you make an inventory of the third party
providers that you want to work with who
are they what do they do
where are they located what kind of
information are they going to have
into your network
why do you want to work with them it's
very important
because before onboarding a third party
you have to identify this risk
it's not enough whether they're best or
highly recommended or you know some
other company that uses them it's not
enough
so you develop a security rating based
on the engagement and the impacts
from these vendors into your network the
rating could go from low to high to even
critical
the purpose of this rating is to
understand where whether this third
party vendor meets your organization's
risk appetite because first you have to
have a risk appetite you have to
understand how much you're willing to
lose
or if you're willing to lose at all
and then you bring in contributions from
subject matter experts it's not enough
for the procurement team to carry out
the financial risk around this third
party it has to be from a cyber air
aspect as well it has to be from an
operational aspect so you're bringing in
delivery managers you're bringing senior
managers and different people from
different teams to understand
how should we
approach onboarding or how should we
approach bringing on this client or this
third party vendor into our network what
are the risks are there any risk what
kind of questions should we be asking
them and then this goes to engagement
and approval
so let's say you've carried out due
diligence right
everything is okay ticked all the boxes
how do you then engage this third party
if the vendor security you know matches
your risk appetite if you're okay with
it the next step is then to have them
complete a security questionnaire most
of you are probably very familiar with
security questionnaires with vendors
most of your vendors here as well
so
why do they need to complete this
risk um questionnaire or what the
security question here it's important
because
the questions give you insights into the
third party's security controls that are
not visible to the outside eyes they
might not actually have had that
communication with you during the first
process
so by giving them this questionnaire to
fill in you're getting more insight into
their network you're getting more
insight into their business operations
you're getting more insights into what's
important to them when it comes to cyber
security how are they going to manage
your data how are they going to you know
access your data are they storing your
data if they're storing your data where
are they storing your data if they're
storing your data in for example the u.s
and you're based in europe is that okay
is gdpr permitting that these are
questions that arise from the security
questionnaire that you give your vendor
during the engagement and approval stage
um denise sp800 171 gives you an example
of the kind of questions that you should
ask your third-party vendor very
important
so let's say you've you know again
checked all the boxes
you're on boarding your security uh
sorry you're on boarding your your
third-party vendor
what happens then
they've received the approval right
it's important to configure your
third-party vendor with zero trust in
mind
i know this sounds again like a buzzword
but we'll come to it with zero trust in
mind it's important because
your third-party vendor should not have
more access than they need
it's not enough again because maybe they
have access to
they're managing your your your server
maybe one server and they're like okay
well let me just give them access to all
my servers because they could manage my
server no you need to restrict access
and configure access again with zero
trust giving them just access to what
they need and also making sure
that the server or whatever systems that
you're giving them access to
is restricted so they shouldn't be able
to do more than they are doing they
shouldn't be able to do more that they
need to do and they shouldn't be able to
creep around because
as we all know it only takes one
credentials to leak and then there's an
escalation of privileges when it comes
to supply chain attacks
so then we go to
performance and monitoring
it's
more important to
even more more important now that this
client or this vendor has been of you
know onboarded to your network to
monitor them
and monitoring them doesn't just mean
checking when they log in and checking
when they log out it's more than that
it's checking the changes that they make
when they log in
is checking the times that they log in
it's checking
the the actions that are taken during
the times when they're logging whether
it's the right time whether it's not the
right time um i think jorgen mentioned
the thing about the domain account and
checking the 10 minutes and 20 minutes
of the domain accounts lockout those
times are very important
so if anything
when monitoring them
make sure that you're monitoring them
for the right reasons because now they
have access to sensitive data they have
access to your
i don't know your logs they have access
to your your systems you know your your
business your business
network it's it's just you're as exposed
as
they are to the internet
so
you do that and this is where continuous
security monitoring comes into play
under performance and monitoring
and
see at css csm is a threat intelligence
approach that automates monitoring of
information security controls
vulnerabilities for clients
the last one exits from the contract so
let's say this client or this
third-party vendor has fulfilled its
purpose and maybe you want to move on
you need to make sure you need to verify
that the access that they had they are
off-boarded properly so you've onboarded
them and it's time to off-board them
it's very important to make sure that
the right the access the data that they
have
is all returned or deleted during due
diligence
so
examples of potential risk that
companies faces
reputational risk
we could mention the thousand clients or
customers in this or companies in this
place that have faced reputational risk
in the last 12 to 24 months
operational risk
cyber security risk
the an answer here talks about 66
percent of the attacks
focused on suppliers code again very
important to know what you're testing to
know what you're installing to know what
you're patching to know what you're
updating also
62 percent of this attacks
exploit comes from the trust of the
companies and the customers of their
suppliers so again zero trust in mind
financial risk we talked about the
vendor
email compromise where you pay money
into the wrong person you pay money into
the wrong account
this happens all well too too much in
the industry
implementing a zero trust model
i like that diagram
um
it's you know it's very important to
to look at these things from a realism
point of view because
these cyber criminals are
they that they're trying to use our
minds our our human nature you know the
trust where you bring in a third party a
trusted third party so not just any
third party trusted third party like
solarwinds into your network
thousands of companies over 18 000
customers are using you know solo wins
and then what do they do
they infiltrate your trusted suppliers
access network into your network just to
gain information it's terrible
by implementing a zero trust model
organizations are able to control access
to their data and their infrastructure
by enabling this privilege again giving
them access to only what they need and
not what they wanted to to have
and this verification process is one of
the aspects that xero trust talks about
where
take for example you have a contractor
that has access to one of your server
and then the contractor you know might
need access to a different server
it's not enough to say oh yeah i know
that person or we already give that
person access to this server so let's
just give him access you have to
re-verify
re-verification
doesn't stop within your network
especially when you're dealing with
contractors third-party vendors
third-party suppliers when you're
dealing with people that have access to
sensitive data re-verification is very
important
pen testing
another popular one testing testing
testing
a lot of companies set up dev
environments and say oh yeah we run the
patch you know we we we run this patch
on the dev environment it was fine
nothing went down so it's time to move
to production
but you're not treating your development
environment as your production what are
the security controls are you checking
for abnormalities are you checking for
you know different changes in in code
lines for example solarwinds again 29
lines of codes that's a lot of code in
my opinion but that went unnoticed to a
lot of customers even solarwinds
themselves
so testing your environment for
abnormalities testing your environments
for back doors testing your environment
for any sort of change that isn't usual
is very important
so
what are my final thoughts
coming to the end of this feel sad now
[Laughter]
[Music]
the nationals institute of standards and
technology states in their software
supply chain
attack information sheets that encode
software supply chain are particularly
bothersome and insidious because they
violate the basic and assume trust
between software provider
and consumer
they also predict that these attacks
soft supply chain attacks
are gonna grow more and more
and we would have
almost no resources almost no
plans to control them
defenders and those who manage corporate
risk
must focus on where trust is being
granted
trust again
because well we trust these people in
our network we give them access it's
like opening your door to a friend
and
if the trust is abused what do we do
if you give access to your third-party
vendor and they are compromised and as a
result you're compromised what do you do
what does your company do
in your
third-party risk management
do you have plans for when your vendor
is compromised
do you have any
business continuity plan for what you do
when this happens
we need to shift from a model of trust
to a model of trust and verify
re-verification again of access
of rights
of who has
you know access to your servers to your
network to your firewall all of those
and if we can focus on building
safeguards around our most trusted
assets again knowing your inventory
it will provide the redundancy that we
need to mitigate
if not even prevent supply chain attacks
thank you
[Applause]
sweetheart my timer has been asking me
to stop talking
does anyone have any questions
yes please
[Music]
that's a good one
during my research i did come across
even fifth and sixth parties
i think
we have to start with who has you know
access first to our networks and you
know when it comes to
the tm
the the or the trm the the risk
management profile
by having your vendor
carry out the risk questionnaire you're
aware you're informed of who has access
to their data and thereby having access
to your data
so
first is awareness because sometimes you
know companies onboard third parties
for a service and those third parties
then outsource the service
to another third party
so that's where the fourth and the fifth
party comes into place so if you
understand the business model of your
third party you would then have you know
the information that you need to know if
this this service that i'm outsourcing
now is it going to be re-outsourced and
if it is am i okay with it do i want to
work for this client and i'm not saying
that that's a bad thing in general
it's just understanding and carrying out
due internal audit due diligence around
who has access to your data and the
person that has access the client the
company the customer that has access to
your data who has access to their data
so it's just all about audits and i mean
i'm not giving you a quick fix here
because there's none and we always have
to just
check these things you know you have to
check them you have to make sure that
you take
not just the boxes but make sure that
you're taking the right boxes as to
you know
where's your data being stored and who's
going to access your data
so um i've been asked to get off the
stage so
i think i'm going to go now and i'm
around to the end so if anyone else has
any questions i'm very happy to have a
conversation with you thank you