i can try to figure out what to do if
you need some help i'm sitting here
okay yes so for the moment we are
controlling the slides
okay so if
yeah
okay so if you agree let's
maybe start
okay
hello
so uh welcome to the meeting of the six
low working group
uh if we can see the previous slide
okay thank you
so
my name is carlos gomez yeah the chair
is srita bandari
our responsible ali is eric klein
who is also today sitting at the table
thank you eric
and
we have
made a takers dominique has volunteered
so thank you very much dominique once
again for helping
taking minutes
is there perhaps anyone else who would
like to volunteer to take minutes
yes
okay
someone
said something in the room
do we have a volunteer
okay
anyway recall that we are taking minutes
by using hedge dock so this is a
collaborative process and everyone is
welcome to join and contribute to the
process of taking minutes
and thank you in advance
and also we might need a jabber or
perhaps today a zulip scribe
as well so if anyone would like to
volunteer please let us know
okay
and also on the agenda you can find a
couple of pointers one is the link to
the online agenda and the other one is
the link to the hedge doc that we are
using today for taking minutes
so
next please
so this is the second itf meeting that
has an in-person component since the
start of the copied endemic
so there are a few
meeting tips to keep in mind
so basically they are the same as for
the last itf for in-person participants
please make sure to sign into the
session by using meet echo for example
you may use the on-site tool which is
available from the data tracker agenda
and the very important point is that
actually we're going to use miteco
to manage the cube so if you want to
join the queue please do that through
miteco as there is a single unified q
handle in this way
and also blue sheets are automatically
generated from miteco so please if you
are in the room uh please make sure that
you join me technically
and for remote participants just keep in
mind that you need to keep your audio
video off unless you are presenting
next please
so this is the notewell
this is a reminder of idf policies on
various important topics just patents
code of conduct and so on
so if you are not familiar with it
please make sure that you have read it
next please
and this is the agenda proposed for
today
so the first presentation is the usual
chess introduction that's currently in
progress
this will be followed by a presentation
on the status update of the six low use
cases draft by young
[Music]
that will be followed by
the presentation on the nd multicast
address listener registration draft by
pascal
and a discussion on the next steps for
the draft
then
the next will be the presentation on the
transmission of chip compressed packets
over 15.4 networks and this will be
followed by a set of two presentations
that focus on the native short address
scheme
the first one is the presentation on the
base document and the second one is a
companion document focusing on
reliability considerations that is
presented for the first time both will
be given by rudy yandone
so as you can see
the total schedule time is 60 minutes so
we have a packed agenda also we would
like to kindly ask
request the presenters to try to stick
to the allocated time
and well is there any comment any
question on the agenda
okay so if there are no comments
then
yeah let's proceed to the
report of the working group document
status
so the first document that we have on
the table is
again the ipv6 over nfc draft
which as you may recall was evaluated by
the asg
then it was updated after that
and now it has been stuck for two years
now
so perhaps uh eric if you can
uh let us know about details about the
next steps any plans for that
yeah this is this is my fault i have not
been able to
prioritize this but uh but i know that i
need to
i had some discussion with lars i think
and some others and
i think we can just
we can demonstrate that everybody who
had access to this who needed to have
access to the spec uh had access to it
and also that those that did not it's
not terribly different from other
wireless standards
and certainly not from an ipv6 interface
definition so
i think
there's a small
there's some clarifying text to the
security considerations we might we
might make
uh and uh probably the right thing to do
is to maybe bring it back to the isg
thank you so uh one clarifying question
uh regarding the point of anyone uh who
might like to have access to the
specification does it mean that if
any folks approach the authors who i
understand at least then they have a
copy of the specification uh is that
enough or should there be some sort of
announcement or wider broadcast of
uh
how to access the specification
i think the former is probably enough i
think um
uh
i i don't think
it's uh
terribly contentious enough or so
terribly uh there's enough uh
interest to warrant
uh
worrying about spreading the information
and i also don't want to violate any
sort of
the
nfc
sdo their their
standard distribution
uh orders
yeah or recommendations so
okay
uh for those who feel it's necessary for
review they should be able to review the
essential components i feel that's
fair okay
thank you
so the next document is ipv6 over plc
uh you may recall that uh all the
discussed ballots have been cleared the
authors updated the draft after that
incorporating the last remaining set of
comments as well
so
however if i understand it correctly
eric
there has been some changes in isg
membership so new isg members need to
provide also some ballots right
that's correct we lost some ballot
positions during the changeover and i
failed to advance it prior to that
and so i've sent email uh to their
remaining uh and to the to the new into
the uh to those with no record ballot to
ask uh if we could get uh two more
reviews i think we only need two more at
this point and then uh or two more no
objection or yes ballots
uh there are discuss points we'll have
to take care of that but i think we've
already dealt with uh difficult
discussion issues so i'm i'm not
anticipating any particular difficulty
if we get to our uh so i'm beating the
bushes trying to get two more reviews
and after that we can send it off to the
rfc editor
great thank you
then the next one is six low use cases
draft
it has been evaluated by the security
area directorate and the general area
and it has been updated
as a result and there will be a
presentation later today on this draft
and uh well perhaps i don't know the
next step maybe but after that it will
be ready for telechat
um
anyway
yeah eric
yes i think
i
passed last call i just need to issue
the ballot and bring it to telechat
which i should be able to do by the end
of august
great thank you
and finally the multicast address
listener registration document has been
updated several times since the last atf
uh thanks to michael richardson and
rahul yan have for reviewing the draft
thanks a lot
and also there has been an update after
an ayanna review so this will be
presented and discussed later today
so any other point any comment
okay so if there are no
questions then we can proceed to the
next presentation on the use cases draft
okay nice to meet you uh my name is hong
i'll present the sixth row of
ability and the use case document
next page please
okay thank you yes this is history and
status
of
2018 the first vocabulary score and the
second working group last call was
2720 october
and this year february
ed submitted to isg and this is the
certain revision okay
please
yeah
so
after our last meeting we got two a
comment from
security director robert spark and the
other is to peter e or general art i
sincerely thanks to to uh robert sparks
and peter e
uh the comment from the robert sparky us
uh
has he said he has some issue so i'll
talk about in more detail and document
from peterby uh he said already with the
issue so he is
his comment was uh mainly for the minor
issue okay let's space please
okay
i talked about the comment from robot
spark the first one is the security
consideration
originally
this document is the usual document so
if you see the section 7 security
construction
there is all
two sentences security construction are
not directly applicable to the document
for the use cases the security
requirement describes in the protocol
section of line
but he says that
the text of this draft has several plays
that rightly call out like the
implication of privacy privileges to
become a shared issue and assumption is
that l2 security must be present
so he recommends to add a word on
sentence for the security construction
so
uh if you see the the blue box i add the
newly added that is the six row stack
use the ipv6 address model and it is
required to consider the implication for
privacy with l2 address drive ipv6
addresses
in a typical six row use cases with the
operator of secure data
it is also required to provide secure
data transmission even though the
six-row stack do not address curate at
the network layer it is required to
provide l2 level security and the
application level security is highly
desirable
but after a submission of this division
of document
i got a response from robert spark but
he does not satisfy so i need to enhance
more in the next revision
okay next page please
yeah and another is also
security so if you thought uh table
two
or there are some the law for which is
regarding to security requirement for
because which
g-wave period security msdp and nfc and
plc but he suggests that
on content is not clear so i think that
it is better to remove the
role itself so in the update revision i
treated this part
next page please
yeah uh
the third comment from robert spark is
that
uh appendix a uh in
previous revision there is appendix a it
is the design space dimension for sixth
row deployment
on kuju next space please
yeah in appendix a on design speed
dimension for six rupee deployment there
are some descriptions of deployment
photo strapping topology l2 mesh
wireless remesh multilingual survey data
radar
blah blah blah so this is not directly
related to uh
sixth row while sixth row open
technology but it is helpful to
understand and help people to design
for the network so
yes uh could you back to
one page please
oh sorry
a back one
yeah
so
he says that appendix a is neither
introduced nor reference from the body
of the document yes it is true
so
you know in itf
106 meeting
they recommend that this document is a
little too long so it must be
short and
it narrow down and focus something
so reflect the command the
uh this section was originally
section 5.1 but it was moved to appendix
a
but now uh
the relationship from the
main body is not exist so
i would like to ask how to handle the
appendix say my personal opinion is to
remove this appendix a if it is not
important
okay next page please
okay next page
yeah
the final comment from robert spark is
that
this document has some misuse of canal
description and marketing words for
example superior range so he suggests to
change to better than or goes further so
i agree that
because this trap has some parts which
are recognized at the marketing world
because we invited some expert for
example
double
threat or electricity or white sun etc
so
there are some
use of the marketing world so i try to
change the marketing words to technology
words in this revision
okay next page please
this is the comment from p3 uh she says
that there are no the major issue and
there are some minor issues
two or three
items so i try to update to reflect all
minor issues in this revision
okay next page please
yeah that's sure thank you
okay so
one comment by the way as author of the
document regarding appendix
there is a paragraph
introduction which says that the
document covers design dimensions and so
on
so uh
removing the appendix maybe one approach
but another approach is to to add a
forward reference from the last
paragraph to this appendix a and also if
i'm not
[Music]
mistaken i think that there's a
comparison table where each row in the
table is based on the different design
space dimensions
so we can discuss maybe
or well later
how to proceed but another approach is
keeping the appendix and maybe adding
some forward reference but we can
discuss
okay thank you
yeah
um
i do agree with carlos i i do apologize
i didn't read the appendix but i don't
think that just removing it without just
for an editorial issue makes sense the
first question is
is there any information that is useful
if yes then the solution of cardless is
the best way forward in my opinion
i'll insert myself in the queue here and
say on the security considerations stuff
um there's
there's plenty of text that we can point
to from rfc 8200 security section
and 8200 has links to other
security documents for ipv6 neighbor
discovery security considerations so i
don't know
uh if that would satisfy robert's
concern but
we could certainly point to all the
other security sections and all the
other things it's basically
because i
there's nothing
there are no new conservative security
considerations per se right i mean all
the security considerations
are things that affect all the sub-ip
layers for all of ipv6 yeah so there's
we can just point to a bunch of existing
text i think
i'll uh i'll send some mail about uh
okay so
if there are no other comments on the
draft next we proceed
to the
multicast address listener registration
presentation by pascal
locales can you hear me okay
yes perfect
so
sorry not to be here with you guys
so yes we are we are uh now
deep into the the process of the
multicast registration document so this
document was stimulated by work which
happened effectively in
uh an alliance in three alliance called
white sand that was just mentioned
where they
use
six low and raw
uh
rfcs to be on the solution for mostly
for the smart grid over i2.15 for
so
um
the multicast registration came from
the realization that
they
still had to do a lot of multi of
link layer multi link multicast
uh to support mld even if we managed to
avoid it for nd
so
that was the question i mean how could
we do the equivalent of mld but
uh in a way that is
a pull from the device as opposed to to
from the router basically the the or
push call it the push from the device as
opposed to a pull from the router so the
device would not have to be listening to
paradigm ld
reports
so
next slide please
so we
we started with this
and we ended up uh also looking at the
way the multicast is distributed in
ripple
and since as you know most of the
iot cases of repo are using non-storing
mode we figured that
there was a need as well to enable the
multicast across the non-storing mode
network
and so we
we did that as well so the draft
actually ends up doing work for six law
but also work for raw
so in in this new uh update and since
well basically there were two or three
updates since atf 113
uh it was mostly clarification it's not
like well there is one thing i will show
you in the next slide but most of the
rest is clarification so we clarified
that uh effectively it's a push from the
device when the device wakes a support
as opposed to a pull from mld which
would require the device to stay awake
um a clarification that this tid you
know the sequence number that's that is
in the air option
and in ripple as well um is not used for
freshness assertions since
any cast and multicast come from
different sources that are not
necessarily synchronized for setting the
tid
so we clarified that the tid is not
checked and so the state actually
disappears
with a lifetime timeout so that's why
it's important that the lifetime is
chosen correctly
um
and
we the the big change is basically a
command i think it was from newcastle
i'm not too sure anymore but the
basically the question was
how you know if the writer reboots
how do we know that uh it needs to
to fetch
some state
and so we did two things
the first thing which really addresses
the low power devices
is a
multicast
arrow status that can be sent a
synchronous line and the name sh any
cast or multicast which will basically
say hey any state that i would have had
i could have lost and so please refresh
and since this is a pull by the router
again it's something that the low power
devices might miss
uh it actually shoots the the the lower
layer that
ysan for instance has because they
effectively has a multicast
periodic
window so they can use that
but for other iot devices or iot
networks where there is not such a
periodic multigas window
then it might be that this
n a is missed by the devices so we also
introduced something for the array which
is the node uptime option it's going to
be next slide
and
finally
i had some comments some only comments
by amanda barber uh about the ayada
section so
i cleaned you know the wording of the
irs section to to make it fit the way
i now wants it written so that's already
done that will save us time on the
publication process
now what is this new node uptime option
it is something that was needed in
rfc8505
that was not there because at the time
we we didn't really care
uh about
going to a network where
um
that there would not be enough
reliability on the routers basically
and so
uh now we figured that it was actually a
mess it was a command that we got a
number of times and so we kind of
leveraged this specification and the
particular discussion we had
uh on dna um with this new status to
effectively add the option in arrays
so it's it is um something that will
require um six-man uh visibility so now
i'm talking to eric since
i see you here
we are proposing a new option in the
array
to basically tell
well for the array to say how long this
router has been up
it's basically um
the sequence and a um a time
and so the the time i is split in two
fields one is an exponent and then there
is mantissa this allows to express very
short and very long times depending on
what the exponent is
with two bytes
so we we kept it short because you know
there are many things in arrays and uh
so that's why we compressed the
value this basically says in the
agnostic fashion you know this router
has been up for this time and so if you
registered if the node uses that to
register at the registered
um
or in
longer before basically the beginning of
the new life of this router
then the device can figure that the
router is not aware of the registration
status of this device and this device
should re-register
so this is basically another way for
advertising
uh that the the device is
uh has reboot
so the router has reboot then again the
array itself can be a multicast and then
again the device might not be listening
to it but it can also be stimulated by
by the device sending an rs if it fails
to connect or something or just
um sends an rs to the old routers is
still available and with this rs the the
router will reply with another type
option and the host will basically see
that the router has not been up for so
long
so this is this is the second way
basically that we propose
to uh enable the the host to discover
that the router has been down and has
lost registration state
next slide please
so that's basically it i mean
effectively the
document has been stable apart from this
addition this last time edition about
you know
awareness of the
of the router status and how long the
writer has been available
so
i understand that
you know that this is a cross area
discussion we have
uh some work uh
which interests
roles which which interests role someone
which which interests six law we decided
to package that together to have a
consistent story so people would see
exactly what's going on for multicast
and with this i will leave you know for
questions and then if um the chairs want
to say something about next steps
okay
so if if there are no questions
basically we discussed with the raw
chairs
and we informed our respective ads about
the plan so the plan would be that if
there is no significant issue raised
in this meeting
then we plan to launch a coordinated
working glass call which will happen in
both six low and role working groups
and well on the other hand
sixth law will remain as the home
working group
regarding shepherding making decisions
and so on but anyway the process will be
coordinated with growth
and then there is this new option right
at the
uptime for which we need to to
coordinate with six men i mean either
six-man
opposes in which case we can retract it
from the document
or if like a six man in which case we
can leave it
so basically there's always this risk
do you plan to present uh the draft in
six months this week
i would like to present the option at
six man at the the next uh
but but if it could be discussed on oh
ultimately yeah
tim since you reviewed the other
documents
for six men
because yeah
i think you could tim winners qa cafe i
think you could send it to six million
but i also was wondering about a
multicast group
should maybe look at this one because
it's got a lot of multicast
i don't think the whole organ group
needs to look at it but i think you
probably want to check in i'm guessing
pin is the last or m bone would be
either one of those would be popped into
my brain is just having them look at
this and
from a multicast perspective but yeah
six man
i don't think it's on the agenda but i
think you should run it by the working
group for sure because of the options
yeah that that's interesting we are
effectively the team we actually got
that
remark long ago at the beginning of this
document about multicast and as it goes
what you need to see is there is no
there is multicast in the original repo
using the preferred parent tree inside
the ripple but that's for storing mode
and here this is kind of specific we are
doing non-story
so what happens is the root of the
ripple
graph will basically do ingress
replication and tunnel
so there is
even though it's it's it's a multicast
registration
there is no
real multicast operation inside the
graph it's it's just ingress replication
of our uh tunnels to the edge routers
so so
yeah it's it's a
neutral for multicast
okay
so so eric what would be your suggestion
for the
the array option
how should we move forward with this one
i admit that i don't fully understand
what its intended use case is
uh anything that goes in the ra
you know
in normal nd semantics means it's
only
all the information in the ra must be
consumable by all multicast percent
volume by by all nodes recipients right
yeah and this is why it's very abstract
can you go down come on go back one
slide or two please
yeah this one so so it's the oath no
back yeah this one so the easy option it
the only thing it says really is is how
long this router has been up
because you know when the router goes
away it can send a final array but
and some people might miss it and and
the router reboots
and if
they have done whatever and it's
completely agnostic to what they have
done with this router
uh might maybe they will be interested
in knowing that the router has rebooted
and has been alive for this long but the
only thing that the option says
basically says the router has been up
for this long
and so it in our case uh we use it to
presume that the router has lost state
and that's valid for any kind of state
that the hope that the router could form
does this um
could this i mean that that sounds like
the thing that could have some
applicability to multiple
considerations uh can it be a a document
on its own just just about this option
yeah i
could do that too i guess if if that's
what the group prefers
now the only thing is
will this document be blocked or
is that why yeah i guess we can write it
such a way that it augments this one
without amending it right
so if if we take it separately
i'm willing to do that yes
then i would just take up the reference
to that document
publish again to that option publish
again
without it and then make it a separate
draft and a separate draft would say oh
it can be used for instance for for this
draft
is that the way you would
yeah i mean i i can see where this could
be useful
for
just for detecting reboots and possibly
some of the slack renumbering
concerns there were similar
i think nothing written but there were
some real similar
discussions about having some kind of a
generation number or a generation id uh
which is which is the ssi probably yeah
um
but uh i can't recall if there's any any
draft actually written about that but
um okay so your suggestion is take it on
a separate draft right make it a very
short simple draft for six men
yeah and the thing is you're gonna have
to decide
um how much you want to attempt fate in
that draft by listing various
conceivable use cases given that they
might all be picked apart by
people to say whether it is or is not
useful
uh it might be better to just say to
just to assert that it is
or it could be used
but yeah so i can basically take this
document we can progress this document
and and
use it as one reference that this thing
is useful
because you're gonna yes i think you're
also gonna need um yeah it's going to
have to have an accompanying operational
guidance section right that readers must
reset
uh i guess there is but i can take all
that text of this document i mean
it's it's more of a you know almost
last-minute edition
and
you know the requirement that i you know
we we make this rfc with a certain set
of requirements in mind and we for the
sort of requirements that we have in
mind there is effectively your multicast
channels and in most of the iot networks
i'm aware of they have a multicast
channel they don't want it's not fat
right you can't use it often but it
exists
and so we can use dna
with the new status
and that's enough for instance for y sub
um
so it's okay for me to remove that
option and put it in a separate document
we still have a consistent solution but
we only have dna we don't have the array
the array was
you know for the use case m and were off
it was nice to have
yeah i don't know i haven't um i don't
know how the document stands with this
piece uh removed um so
i wouldn't well it was it worked like
that all the time it's it's a very
recent addition
so i i guess it would still i mean we
want this option it's more like
uh this was a way to avoid doing yet
another rfc
but if your recommendation is
effectively to do yet another rfc then
then
just to keep things separate
then we do it we kind of package the
full soyuz in one rfc in this case we
have six low we have raw and so we would
have had a little bit of six men as well
um but if that's not the proper way for
six men then we can take that off
make it separate
uh yeah let me you can uh
maybe we should talk to the six-man
chairs see what they think about a
separate document how that might be
received uh
whether that's useful if you're if
you're if you're up for it
i mean i'm open i mean the
the document can move without it
uh i needed a vector
to carry it so that was
one way
if you tell me there is a better way
i'll take the better way
uh i don't know exactly what th what a
better way might be just yet but yeah we
should we can talk about it offline yeah
yeah with eric and the six-man chairs
i'm completely open
so
yeah and i will update the document
based on that conclusion
and then we can launch the work group
let's go on buff
sites i guess we can do the one goodness
calls with the current document but if
the chess prefer uh i can
take it off
just let you know
yeah maybe
once every uh has a response from the
six-man chairs they're probably
maybe cleaner to
to launch the weather call uh with a
separate part uh i don't know if that's
whatever they conclude right so if if
they decide that they should remove that
section make it separate
then they'll do it and then we can
launch work up let's go if they say it's
okay let's just circulate it by six man
then we'll we'll do that as well so so
basically we will be holding
that's how i understand right we'll be
holding the word group let's go
till eric gives us the green light and
and the the action to be taken
have i understood that correctly uh
you're going to wait for me to send
email
and ccu and the chairs
to talk about
yeah
basically we we we we will be waiting
for recommendations by you eric wink
uh six many ladies and six-man shares
i'm sorry about making it separate or or
circulating it through six-man scs
yeah i can start that email thread and
then we can we can see where it goes
nice
but
that's that's it on my side that's
that's where we are
thank you very much guys
okay thank you thank you pascal
so i guess
yeah uh okay i'll try to make it fast
so i'm going to present uh the update of
the crafting title transmission
compressed package over 15.4 networks my
co-author is anna miraburo from mcleod
next please
so basically here there are some numbers
this is about the motivation for the
draft the idea is that with chic
in some cases we are able to achieve
greater heavy compression
ratio than with traditional six low pan
header compression
especially if we consider also
compression of application layer
protocols like co-op
so this expectation is this should lead
to some significant performance
improvement next please
sorry
oh we've lost the
slides yeah i think shweta is offline at
the moment so i don't know if eric
is it possible
uh yes i could try i don't know how to
share from here
i tried to make myself yes a delegate
so but i have to be the first time i've
ever tried to do that
let's see here
uh
nope that just opens this up
okay maybe i can open the materials
i don't know how to share them
okay maybe
here we go okay
this one
share
yeah so i'm seeing them on the screen
now
so if you can go to slide number three
please
no
no i guess it's you who is now
can you control the those lights yes
yes yes
take me away to several
okay
thank you so basically i'm presenting
revision03
of the document which tries to enable
the transmission of sheet compressed
package over 15.4 networks
next please
so yeah on the updates in the draft
you may recall that there was a problem
with how
we are
going to compress ipv6 addresses and udp
ports by using chic
so
sheik uses dev and up terms
in its specification that corresponds to
a constraint device on the left in the
figure app corresponds to a
network site infrastructure not
constrained on the right
and the shift specification this rfc
um
defines that compression of ipv6
addresses and udp ports
is performed uh
expressing
who is dead and who is up and not in
terms of what is the source or the
destination
in of these fields
so
here the point is that because an entity
knows in advance whether it corresponds
to debian
in chic then this allows some
optimization because a single
compression rule allows it to be usable
in both directions as expressed in terms
of level
however
well the point is that in some 15.4
scenarios we can still use this
optimization as is for example in star
topology networks
however if you go to slide number five
next slide please
there are some other scenarios in 15.4
where
we cannot just use the same approach as
this because for example two peers
within a mesh topology
uh might be candidates to be considered
depth so then who is that who is up
so this is the problem the consensus so
far has been trying to to stick to the
developed terms because they are very
much at the core of sheik and they still
allow this optimization of using a
single rule for compression in both
directions
and in version 0 3
we now state that the chic compression
decompression entity needs to know uh
which is the role developed for each one
of the rules that are going to be used
in communication and actually this needs
to be known in advance before
communication happens
and well knowing the role in advance
makes sense because the rules also need
to be written beforehand in advance
before communication happens
also now in zero three we reference the
lp1 architecture draft
um
so this has some additions it will be
discussed by the way the architecture
draft
in the lp1 working group later this
this week and
the idea is that it
starts to provide a solution on this
problem of who is that who is that
in environments which are outside or
beyond the original lp1 architecture
next please
so we've added a new section of title
multi-hop communication where we explain
that
we can use routeover
which means that routing is performed at
the ip layer there is one
straightforward approach that may be
used to transmit compressed packets in
this case
which however requires all nodes to
store all the rules in using the network
so this presents some challenges in
terms of scalability in terms of network
size memory and so on so an alternative
is that if ripple is used as the routing
protocol then as suggested by pascal
we can exploit ripple on story mode and
use rfc 138 to make it efficient
and in this case an endpoint must only
store the rules for the communications
it is involved in
so
this is some idea that we plan to
develop and elaborate in subsequent
versions of the draft and then we can
also use mesh handler
in this case there is no particular
challenge uh to enable the transmission
of g-compress packets here
again in this case an endpoint just will
not need to store the rules for the
communications it is involved in and as
a sort of optimization for reducing
further the header
we state that the rule id may be reused
across disjoint pairs of endpoints
however this means greater complexity so
this is just some idea at the moment
let's go
yes sorry for the gory details but
in uh non-stop we can use non-stirring
mode uh in ripple even if the main diode
is storing mode and we do that for uh
low power devices which are not ripple
aware and we can expect that a device
that needs chic
is probably not ripple aware it's
probably one of those low power devices
so it makes a lot of sense
to to not contribute to not that
straight to ripple
use the ripple underwear leaf mode in
which case it's always reported on story
so when it's reborn on storing there is
a tunnel
between
the first router and the um
the the root so basically the root would
have to know the rules for everybody
and the leaf would just need their own
set of rules
so so it's not with every communication
i mean the wording is not entirely crisp
it's not the communication between twin
points it's every end point
communicating to the root the root will
decapsulate the encapsulate may
will decompress
may recompress if the destination inside
the dag or it will just send to
to whatever up there but basically the
compression would happen over the ripple
network
over the
device to to root tunnel
and yeah we
we need basically the 6lr we would need
to spend some time explaining exactly
how it works but that's that's what
would happen basically the session would
be
oriented you know the hub would be the
roots there is enough discussion on lp1
uh specification that when there is a
habit spokes the hub is effectively the
node that has rule for every spark
and it is the it is up
basically
it is the upside
so yes kind of lines
yes
maybe the same comment as possible if
you use ripple then you have up and down
so it's
so it's very very close
we use it who is it it is the app and
the doubt it's completely consistent
with the architecture it's just that the
question was who has to have the rules
and the route must have the rules to
every uh ripple number nice
right because there will be a tunnel
between the reaper and the wall if and
the rule the route
um but the reaper and valiant just need
its own set of fruit of rules and it
doesn't need the set of rules of anybody
else because the root will
decompress and recompress if needed
it's just the interaction between the
the the loop ripper now if in the the
first xlr
if if we want to already send chic
compressed packets there
so
or if we want the first xlr to do the
compression on behalf of the reaper and
the relief which is another possibility
okay thank you so i guess we'll
elaborate on the details and
if we go quickly because we're running
out of time to the next slide
so
yeah basically we are recommending
that in the case of router
virtual reassembly buffer should be used
so i guess we should stop here due to
the lack of time
and we can continue discussing on the
list
and i guess that we can proceed with the
next presentations on nsa by ouija
hello so i
in principle i can control the slides
from my
mobile phone
i send the request
the church i guess should
allow me to do it
wonderful
here is the one
okay
so i have
shrinked my presentation from 20 minutes
to to 10 less than 10. the first
presentation is a very quick update on
the nsa the native short addressing
um
so
we did an update in june fixing the the
last uh
concerns that were licensed okay um
we did again as usual the the typos
hunting um
with the one main change is about
reliability and i will come back to this
in a couple of slides uh
we added the clarification about the
checksum calculation for the transport
layer that was important and
minor changes
we need one new painting because we had
an exchange with carlos which
yes make sense to update a reference and
clarify another point
uh
one thing that we did pascal actually
raised the the issue about reliability
very important thing
and uh we actually discussed for a while
how to approach this part and what we
decided is actually to have a separate
document because this reliability can be
guaranteed in different ways
and there is no one that is
at the end really special specific about
the nsa
so we took out uh an old section that
was called benefits of native short
addressing
which anyway was partially talking about
the reliability
and we added a small reliability
consideration section
where what we do basically
we discuss our routing versus stateless
for welding because at the end of the
day what we do with nsa is
is stateless forwarding we we structure
the addressing space in such a way that
we we have an idea where to send the
packet
a few words about the fact that the
reliability is a multi-faceted problem
and obviously we reference the
the new document
um
so
this is what
the status on 113 so we had a few things
to update
okay to incorporate the this has been
done
um
we said we're gonna issue
revision three after one one three we
did okay again we have these small uh
things to be added but it's very minor
note so we think really that the
the document is pretty stable
and uh unless there are
main concerns that someone has
we think we
we can go uh forward for uh working
group adoption i mean uh we we were
kind of hinting on this on the 113 but
we had some some
work to do now is done and we we
consider that is relatively stable the
document
and that's it for this one
three
minutes so unless there are questions i
guess
um
this goes to the chairs about how do
they want to proceed about the working
group adoption call
yes so uh perhaps it may be good to have
at least the first sense of the room
on
adoption
so i will use the show hands tool
so
in using the
show of hands tool
please raise your hand if you have read
any version of the draft
okay so
at the moment at least nine people have
read at least a version of the draft
then
so this is to get some sense of the room
we are not
making a decision at the moment
okay
and
yeah so
then the idea will be to to
move to the mailing list
uh we we're going to to discuss
and um
yeah
issuing a working group um sorry i call
for working group adoption
will happen on on the mailing list
so next okay
if you want to use the last remaining
minutes for the presentation on
reliability
uh
i can go very quickly on the just to
show the main approaches that we have
there um yeah
sure also also usually the room is
closed five minutes past the official
time so maybe let's use some additional
extra time from there
i will try to stay in the four minutes
remaining
[Laughter]
it's a challenge
[Music]
but
i still see this who has read any
version of the draft on the screen
um
i think it is up to you carlos to take
it out somehow
yes now it should be out
yeah i have permission already
this is the right set of slides
this is the chest
okay okay so this is now new draft that
we
um
we build in order to
to tackle this issue about reliability
this is very important so the main
the main point is that there are several
solution uh classes of solution that we
can use uh
the most important one let me go is the
fact that obviously we need uh
some prerequisites so the fact that
actually we have redundant links now the
question then is you can build multiple
topology
using multiple addresses or you you
just
decide
which link do you use you use one single
address
address for each node and you try to
remember which link is active which one
is not
used okay
so
basically in the multiple addresses uh
solution what you do is
you build several topologies which means
basically if you remember nsa is based
on a tree uh
topology so you have a second route and
you uh add a secondary address
uh
for the nodes so by doing so you have
two completely orthogonal topologies and
you one you use it as a primary topology
and then you have to decide when to
switch to the second one when there is a
failure now here there is such an
example where that cross obviously is a
failure what happens is a node can can
uh send through an the secondary
topology an icmp message to the main
route to say look this branch of the
tree
subtree is not reachable anymore because
i i see a failure okay and
this way the root can can store this
this information and redirected the
traffic when needed same thing when we
have a link that is broken you have to
do the same thing from both sides so
that you redirect in the right
in the right way okay so that you still
have a rich ability all the time
pascal you have a question already
yes if if uh for instance you have the
breakage that you show here but it's the
the guy in the bottom left it's not
aware of that breakage is it
[Music]
1000 yes it's not a word what happens if
if
he sends traffic upward is 100 that
redirects the traffic doesn't need to be
the there is just one thing
is meaningful what you said is
you can consider optional to send i say
an icmp downwards and you say you may
consider to use your secondary address
in order to bypass or all of this okay
you have no choice because 100 will not
get the traffic i mean you would have
one would have to figure out that along
the path
there is a breakage and then it needs to
take the bypass and instead of
my bottom line is you're starting to
doing to do a routing protocol as soon
as you start doing this your
your
you put your your hands on europe and
the pandora box after writing protocol
sorry for me your voice was not clear
can you repeat the point oh i'm sorry
again
doing all those things you're opening
the pandora box of a routing protocol so
the whole deal was
you're
you you don't need a routing protocol
and now you're starting to do one
so this is things we discussed a little
bit in the draft but we need to clarify
more the point is
if you have few
few failures you have a few
very small state
and few redirections
and everything works fine
uh but as long as you have something
that's more unstable more failures more
dynamicity
this goes back to routing
indeed
and in a certain way
so the other solution
goes along what you are saying because
we use still um redundant links but we
use just one single addressing space so
so we we every node has one single
address but he has to store
alternate um
neighbors like an alternate patent a
parent
different childs and so to make a
decision
when there is a a failure
let me go maybe to the final slide
here the point is
with what we discussed in this document
is if you use multiple addresses the the
the in the root you have
very low state because this really
depends how how many failures do you
have
okay and also the the state that you put
into the nodes is pretty low
uh
but because everything is done locally
in a certain way and there is no
coordination at all the more failures
you you have
i mean the more messy you you you end up
and there is less guarantee that
there is a feasible path okay when the
single address solution okay in the root
in a certain way it has to have a a good
knowledge of the topology hold the
topology so the the state is higher okay
uh on the single node
we we still have low state because it's
basically neighborhood okay
and but the robustness is higher just
because you you concentrate the uh
knowledge in the roots so
there is more coordination and more
failures that you can keep up with so
but
your rider is there are trade-offs and
then at some point if you consider that
your network is not as stable and
reliable as you think
certainly
you have to think whether or not to put
routing
okay
adnan
hello adnan we cannot hear you
yes uh can you hear me now
no yes
yes luigi uh have you tested the failure
scenarios of the
multi with multiple classes
mean if you are saying is not reliable
so alan is not reliable actually
their nature is actually like this
so
so i think uh uh can you tell me the
failure scenarios
you guys have tested
okay
with sorry to interrupt
um i guess in
some seconds we are going to get the
room closed not
[Music]
and available
so
let's hope that
we can see each other in london
and
yeah perhaps we should also ask for a
longer session
okay so have a nice itf week thank you
thank you everyone
wait a minute
um