that's why i wear sandals
and a skirt but i guess that's not
really an option but um
could be
as if i don't
so we need a volunteer note taker
my normal suspect is probably running
his own meeting
who was that
that was me aaron gable
oh there you go
we'll take it
um i've
put the agenda in it you can just plop
the notes wherever you want in that mess
we'll fix it
all right you think we can go y'all
every time we try to
unmute myself
the
mitako warns me that i'm local and that
it might be causing the feedback
okay
welcome all to the acme meeting at ipf
see that only i'm wearing an acme shirt
right
but let's get on with it so this is a
notewheel
i'm sure you've all seen it plenty of
times
so we'll not
dwell on that too much
specifically for itf 114
in-person participants make sure to sign
the session using the meet echo you take
a light that's
easy to do by scanning the qr code at
the
door
and use mitecho to join the my
microphone queue
and keep audio and video off if you're
not using on-site version
and wear masks unless you're actively
splitting at the microphone
and this is something regardless of how
we feel about it this is something we
all agreed when we signed up for this
meeting so
wear your masks
and make sure audio and video are off
unless you're sharing or presenting and
use the headset is strongly recommended
for remote participants yeah like i am
okay
so
agenda got the metacall
so this is our own specific agenda we'll
do the note well already done
technical difficulties we so far haven't
needed to
do that and then you miss trivia
we already got to note taker
and we'll do the document status then
we'll talk about uh current work items
which are
um detailing node id and
ari which is not really a current torque
item because we haven't adopted it yet
but we'll talk about that as well
and then
there's potential new work from brandon
weeks
and the agenda bashing before we
continue
good
so
document status we don't have any new
rfcs since vienna
um acme authority token
has a discuss from ben k deck since
november of
new version zero eight from this month
and what do we do then kadak is no
longer an ad
do you want to do that one and the one
on the next slide at the same time
john's here
all right
so
okay acme client we have a new version
zero five from april
very light discussion on the mailing
list and that's
kind of par for the course
and then we have um
tnothlist current version is from
26th of march 2021 which i think is
right from vienna
there are three outstanding discusses
and revised id needed
and
so sorry
march 2021 which is over a year before
vienna
and
then dtn node id is current version is
from just before itf 113
waiting for write-up external parties
since march of 2022 and we have a
presentation today
yes so we have john we have john at the
mic
how's it going yeah so we did try at
least to deal with the discuss on the
first of these documents on the the
original authority token doc i know we
have not gotten to the token t not list
i'm not actually the editor of that one
but like hopefully with this new zero
eight version it's like better um
i tried to fix what seemed to be the
major discusses that were out there and
even to address the majority of ben's
comments
so we still have work to do obviously on
tnoth list and you know ben it's a very
thorough reader we have like a ton to
say about that doc that we need to get
to and i will help the editors uh the
editor of that to get that done
so can i ask you who the editor of that
is i think it's either chris or mary i'm
not actually sure who last had the xml
for it but yeah chris or mary all right
so we know who to chase now for that one
yeah um because it's not you
well i mean i can obviously do some work
but i need like the source yeah yeah you
know it was i mean it's really uh
honestly it's probably more responding
to ben's mail in particular that is the
long pole in that tent because there's
just a ton
there's a ton of comments honestly when
i looked at it some of it does spill
over between the documents even a bit so
like yeah there's there's actual work
that needs to be done it's hard to get
people to do actual work is it worth
bringing this the document that you or
the editor for back into the working
group to get it reviewed because we
don't have ben anymore
um i mean i think the authority token
document should be cool like in terms of
what the
it's the other ones the tnothlest one
right you know if if we're in trouble
i don't know if we need to bring it back
to the working group and honestly it
just is a matter of getting the cycles
to do it
and like definitely a revised idea is
needed there's there's no no but
somebody needs to review the updated 08
version right
it's true i mean i assume the isg would
review it at this point
or
yeah like in theory paul hoffman
inherited these discusses but um
yeah so
a couple of observations first i think
that
i would be reticent to bring
to do a different progression on the
documents separately they're clearly you
know intertwined and if something comes
up and we advance one too far forward
we're going to be in a pickle so i want
to move them in in lockstep so even if
we clear on the other one and we haven't
cleared on this one like i'd want to
hold it so i think part of it is i would
need to revisit where we are but it
looked like substantial changes were
needed on the tf office based on based
on the feedback so typically what we do
when we have substantial changes we want
to reconfirm consensus on the solution
so what we don't want to do is reiterate
in the isg because we still need to
check with the working group that
they're good with the big changes and
then there's a judgment call there
whether we got to go back to the
community so my recommendation would be
given that we're anticipating big
changes on that the easiest way to do
the consensus check and have a formal
process to know where we are where we
are instead of you know doing this kind
of side consultation would be to bring
it back to the working
i mean sure obviously the working group
should read it i think we want to bring
the attention working group to the
changes that have already been made to
the authority token document and ask if
everyone here is cool with what's in the
zero eight of that
i think that is something that's
probably worth doing at this point
i i definitely agree we should move
these together that it doesn't make
sense to advance the authority token
document without tnothlist or vice versa
and so i guess
you know the question is do we want to
start that process of just sending the
list and saying like hey is everybody's
still cool with what's an authority
token now as of zero eight
like or do we want to wait until
tenochlis is also iterated and then ask
the working group are both of those
documents jointly cool but we i think
that kind of can occur in parallel with
the ihg's ongoing review that's right i
what i don't want is for these things to
literally be like you know go through a
new pub wrath and a new like you know
gen art and everything when they've
already been to the isg
well we actually do that all the time uh
and i stare at it i guess um i i just
don't know where the energy is so we're
15 months from the last version of that
document
so that gives me great applause i guess
and given that i didn't hear kind of
firm dates we're gonna we're committed
to
to hammering it kind of here you know at
a particular time we are we sure about
the editors we're not like maybe we'll
track them down i'm concerned that we
can close it it's been 15 months
and that's the consensus check on
primarily after i mean when it's been 15
months since we did it we have big kind
of problems uh i i mean i'm kind of
what i was hoping here is a lot of
energy to kind of move forward because
my gut is i'm not sure and that's why i
want to bring it back
so why don't i take an action to go back
to the tnoth list authors and find out
who the editor is who has the pen who
has the pen and and give them and make
them tell me how long it's going to take
them for them to
update the document once they update the
document and reissue right then we drop
them back down to the working group for
a short period of time just to review
them both in parallel
and at that point we pop them if they're
fine we just ship them up and and we're
done right
because we should clear the discussions
on tn off and there are no there's
nothing to clear on the other document
the one that has all the ben comments on
it yeah and so there's like one
francesca thing or something that there
is something from francesca but i don't
remember what document that's on yeah on
the token authority well she's not
reviewing anything
because
yeah in terms of process
just to make sure we have the names
right uh the others are comments uh
these are the blocking discusses and
paul did uh take up ben's position so
paul can help us
right
this results yeah uh mister
well you know yeah right uh former chair
uh sorry deb um president
the tn stuff was
def came to you know
hope john correct me if i got a
character if my memory is faulty but it
came from the stir stuff and it wasn't
really
i mean the domain expertise is for the
most part over there right so if it
landed for more than a year um it was
probably not
purely the working acme working groups
issue or concern and they might have
fallen through the cracks because some
of the people got
busy and other stuff in stir i mean i'm
happy to involve stir if we need to
involve stir like i don't think that's a
problem right
john again i won't put myself back in
the queue but yeah i mean part of the
issue is right that we ended up using
some of this but not all of it in the
way that we practically do certificate
issuing here in the united states right
first or shaken and like so yes and
searching has become this whole thing
it's like really huge and we're all
super busy with it and so this this was
is not front burner because we we need
the token format and that's already
written into some like addis documents
under standards bodies things like it
but we haven't seen a lot of uptake on
actually using acne for this bluntly no
i i'm not thrilled about that in the
sense of we have like a short lived
certificate story that we're building
for stir that really should rely on acme
for it to work and it would be a shame
if we can't get that to work because
it's one of the best solutions that you
know we could really have to some of the
more difficult
um non-carrier stir shaken cases
so it's like yeah because that the
energy around it is sporadic right like
i mean i'm not gonna you know try to
sweep that under the rug it hasn't been
critical path for us to get this done
but
you know in light of some more recent
things that has injected some energy
back into it especially because of the
potential for doing short-lived which we
need for something that i know chris
feels pretty strongly about and i mean
if you put me on the spot i'm pretty
sure chris is the one that is supposed
to or at least has the latest version of
the source for this tnothless document
so like i believe the energy exists to
do it
um again i can't i don't think i can
make promises for when but like
you know that's the situation so i mean
we're happy to do the right thing for
the
for the situation right we just need to
we need to get it going
we need to get it going and that that's
how i summoned the energy to do the
document that i did right because i see
this coming down the pike and i'm like
okay this gotta get done and i had
cycles to do that but not to intervene
on this and do this one too
and like if necessary i'll do this one
too right at the end of the day
um
we could share the load to somebody else
i mean there's like four authors on all
these things and there's like no reason
for one person to be doing all the work
i know
so all right so let's let's stick with
unless sean's got a comment because
sean's at the mic
hello sean turner i will volunteer to
review these drafts when you rest the
xml from chris's hands and get it fixed
oh you're the best
so i think the plan is to to contact the
authors of tnoth and find out or
whatever we're calling that thing
um figure out when we can get an update
to that we'll bring them all both of
them back to the working group for a
two-week last call
and we'll review it
with the
number of reviewers that we normally get
in this working group
um
which is
three
possibly more than the number of authors
of the document but i wouldn't count on
that there's like four or five of those
and then um push it back up again
do you agree
i'm looking at you off he doesn't know
i'm looking at him though
what do you think yeah that sounds good
enough i mean one outcome is that the
group has lost interest interest and we
buried the documents i mean that's also
a possible outcome if really there's no
energy to write them i mean
if this was really important for people
then
the original office not having energy
would mean that somebody else takes the
pen
i don't see anybody else rushing to take
the pen either so
um well
i guess it all depends on the current
authors getting uh
getting the energy to
uh revise when we make that
when we make that working glute last
call we'll cc stir too
while we're at it because that might get
us a few more reviews
right okay
does that sound like a plan
yeah okay
good because we'd like to get this done
right it needs to be
yeah right it doesn't you don't need
hanging over your head for the rest of
your life right
just saying
okay
so um
two more things uh integrations went
through working group last call not a
lot of discussion uh question is are we
ready to go ahead and sub domains just
finished uh working with last call
i think integration's had a handful of
reviews
um it's got some tie-ups with lamps
in that there's a
is my purchase in here no
oh look at that um
he's got a draft in lamps that needs to
get adopted
but i mean i guess that's
not our problem right
right
okay so i say we push both of those
okay
and okay and then there was ari which we
um
had a
adoption call
and well when it was presented in vienna
and uh the previous uh
meeting uh there was a lot of enthusiasm
in the room a virtual room at least
and
then we called for adoption and uh
heard pretty much nothing from on the
mailing list
so
yeah how do we deal with that well
anyway we do have a presentation so
we might uh want to
delay the
that discussion until
today's presentation
okay and
with that
it's time for acme detail nowadays
right
so there's brian
yes hello oh you get this already
we can hear you i mean you're just going
to drive your sleds for you
okay
all two of them
very short yes
uh so go ahead to the
next the real slide yeah yeah
uh
so
the good news is that there has not been
any further changes
since the last ietf these are really the
same notes as before summarizing the
last changes in the document
the bad
news is that there hasn't been any
feedback or real
progress so far on this
um
the
uh
the cose document is still in in off 48
which isn't a huge hold up um and the i
don't have it on this slide but the the
corresponding
dtn document to add a missing iana
registry that's needed here
um
is still
being requested for working group
adoption but it's also not a
controversial thing
uh any other working group
so if you go to the next slide
there is no next slide oh i'm sorry
well
uh
the
the last uh ietf uh ended up with this
uh requesting
uh a last call since
there were
changes in function changes in on the
wire encoding on
on this behavior
for the uh
the um algorithm agility
uh
but i have not seen anything since then
so we asked for a last call right
are we asked for a review what are we
doing here
roman
yeah i'm just pulling up the way i
yeah so we went to itf last call a bunch
of
things were kind of requested we made
breaking changes in the protocol and i
think the call on the list was can we
confirm that people put eyes on those
changes and we're good to go it's i
think it's like a consensus recheck
question because adam last call we did
to make breaking changes like separating
separating the bundle
so i think what would help us here is a
couple eyes on it and say
we're all okay with it and i will give
it another look and then we can ship it
and the main actual benefit of these
last changes was to bring this behavior
more into conformance
with the rfc 8823 behavior so so this
behavior
logically
um is
that same workflow
for those that don't the roman did it
for those that don't track
rfc numbers it's the email challenge to
make it more consistent
okay
any comments
in person we need reviewers
we always need reviewers
okay yes aaron
i know that i'm one of the commenters
who requested
the changes to bring it more in line
with the email validation and i'm 99
sure that i've looked at it again since
then and it looked good but i will make
sure that i take another look at it and
send an email to the list as
thank you thank you
okay i don't have anything further then
okay so we'll reiterate the request for
review
and
look and see how many reviews you
already had i think you had a couple
right
um
and we'll see if we can't push this
along
great thank
you thank you
okay aaron
uh
yeah next slide
um not a
yeah hi aaron gable uh
this is the re ari uh acme revocation
information draft uh it is currently at
version zero three
uh so one new version since last acme uh
next slide
um
most of the changes here are pretty
small a few people spotted some minor
typos and we got those cleaned up uh
there's some good discussion on the
mailing list about
why other solutions aren't
viable solutions to the set of problems
that this draft solves and so i updated
some of the text in the introduction to
better address those questions
uh and
clarified the suggested renewal
algorithm uh next slide
so this is just the one thing that is
like actually slightly substantive uh
the there's text in the draft that
describes
what a client should do with the
information about its requested renewal
window uh and previously it was phrased
that the client
must perform a specific set of
calculations and then simply
should renew at the time resulting from
that set of calculations and some people
i think rightfully pointed out that
that's a kind of weird way to phrase it
and so instead i've changed it to
exactly the text that is on this slide
which is that they
must attempt renewal at a time based on
the suggested window
and we really recommend a specific
algorithm for determining a time within
that window
um
obviously i would like people to take a
look at this slightly changed text
provide feedback about it uh let me know
if it makes sense if it seems like a
reasonable way to standardize this etc
but i think all of that will be part of
just the the current round of document
review
um next slide
um yeah so next steps uh
i just slightly updated the draft so i
need to go back and update the current
implementation uh to match the the very
latest version but that's
not hard at this point
um
and
after the last ietf
deb sent out an email
asking for
a call for adoption review and feedback
and support for call for adoption there
was
a small amount of discussion on the list
uh and i have addressed all of the
feedback received from that discussion
so far uh but i think the next big step
is
whatever the chairs want to do with the
discussion that's happened so far
that's all i've got
so i think we need more review on this
right when it does need when we ask for
the call for adoption we need people to
pop up and say whether they think it
should be adoption adopted or not
um so i think we're going to redo the
call for adoption again and hopefully
we'll get more people popping up and
saying yeah we want this um
um
we had a bunch of people saying they
thought this was worthy of adoption and
when we made the call on the list there
was like crickets
yeah i think there was made one of the
polls here i'm sure we would get uh like
uh
10 people or
20 people saying yeah we should adopt
this but then when you ask them the list
nothing
right
i mean to be frank
20 people on anything on this working
group so
i would be happy for five
honestly and there's 30 people in the
room
i
really
yeah
there is currently uh support for
adoption from two people uh melinda
shore and peter thomason
um and that's that's it on the list so
far
yeah
all right
all right so we'll remake that call for
adoption hopefully we'll
get a little more pick up this time
since all the people in the room have
heard now that we're going to ask for
adoption mr saltz
saying what we're saying is that uh
don't assume that just because you said
uh yeah let's adapt it to the meeting
that it applies to the formal call for
adoption
yes rich
yeah you could call for adoption here in
the room and then post on the list if
anyone objects
can we do it that way yeah
yeah
that way
so do you think we should adopt this
draft well
yes
do we raise hands or do we do a fancy
little vote thing you do the fancy thing
yeah i found
a show off hands too
let me
did you say to do a fancy tool a fancy
little thing oh look at that
okay because these polls don't appear in
the youtube recording uh
we're running a poll now that says
should we adopt ari
and so far we've had well
i'll wait for the final results which
declare i guess there's nobody voting
against it
yeah
okay so we have more voting for it than
we've had emails
yeah so you've had 17 people raise their
hand indicating that we should adopt ari
and
zero
not raising their hand
actively not raising their head which
means that we should not trace so it's
17-0 for adopting
ari right so as rich said i mean just go
to the mailing list and say are there
any objections given what looked like
consensus from this meeting and i can
give them a week or two weeks and let it
roll okay cool that's
easier because apparently it's easier to
do it in the room than it is to do it on
the left
cool
all right there is a reason why we're
having these meetings
well yeah okay
yeah
okay so thank you aaron
any other comment
okay so
let's go on to
the new proposed stuff
yes brandon
so you can come up and stand on the
little pink
and you if you want to take off your
mask
so it's up to you whatever you want to
do
you probably have to be near the
microphone though well everyone i'm
brandon weeks i'm from google uh just to
clarify
uh i'm on our security team and
specifically our corporate security team
so i do not represent any products
whatsoever i have no influence over
product direction
next slide please
uh tldr why am i here um
this is a specification and it's
relatively simple that combines the web
authentication statement format which is
effectively a key value pair where the
key is
a attestation format that it exists in a
registry and
the value is a
format specific uh series of bytes
with acme
um
the reason i care about this is this
seems like an ideal way to issue client
certificates
for
primarily things like laptops
workstations and servers but i don't
think there's any reason
that the specifications necessarily be
restricted to that
i can someone could come up with a use
case where you want to connect to the
same server every time
and for reasons that become clear in a
later slide i'd like to call for
adoption at this meeting if possible
next slide please
so
why acme
uh there's numerous uh certificate
enrollment pro uh protocols um most of
them are ietf specs however skep remains
the standard for
operating system vendors
device management vendors
cmp est
cmc all of those specifications haven't
really seen any adoption
from operating system vendors while they
might be adopted in networking gear
um
i don't know exactly why but
they're most of them predate my
professional career and we've seen no
real adoption of them
acme is incredibly well designed i'd
like to say thank you to the authors
this draft doesn't even really extend it
that much because all of the
extension hooks were pre-envisioned by
the authors so it was relatively simple
to combine these
and acme has is really well supported
across languages across platforms
i don't believe that to be true for
cmp est et cetera it's kind of hard to
implement those in newer languages
or
depending on the libraries that you're
allowed to use at your uh
in your environment
next slide please
so
what makes this a good time to do this
um
this is
probably the first time we can say that
most of the devices that are purchased
and deployed at least in enterprise
environments actually have a way to do
a device identity at the station and the
device can
identify itself and speak for itself
without users so
on android we've had android kia station
since
7.0 which is i think over five years old
um apple introduced managed device out
to station um this wwdc so
on ios so that's kind of
the major platform that has been
blocking this from being ubiquitous
it's not available on macos yet but
hopefully it is some day
someday soon
chrome os has this
the rats eat specification
is attempting to
build a standardized way of doing
attestation uh statements that doesn't
involve having uh four different five
different uh specifications um
and i would one day like to include that
but
today we have the formats that we have
um and tpms is probably the most well
known um
and this is uh what's mostly used on
linux windows and
other operating systems that don't have
proprietary attestation schemes
next slide please
um
so
web authent is already got mindshare as
seemingly the de facto format for
encapsulating and abstracting
uh different attestation formats across
vendors
apple already adopted it in their
uh apotest which is their anonymous
attestation that is provided to app
developers
um
and they've since adopted for their
managed device at a station feature that
is their non-anonymous feature for
managed enterprise devices
i've discovered this week that there's
two other ietf drafts that were
presented at 114 that also made
independent decisions to use the same
format um there's one for including
attestation formats in tls
and there was another four
uh essentially back porting this to cmp
and est and existing
uh
like
older certificate protocols
um
and like acme web authent enjoys fairly
ubiquitous library support across
languages and across platforms um
almost like every vendor already had to
build this for their browser
so it should be pretty easy to integrate
um into other parts of their platform
next slide please
hi everyone before we jump off that uh
for anyone that was in lamps maybe
shauna rich
didn't we learn that after some
discussion
with the uh the designated experts for
the web authent registry that the
approach wasn't what we thought it was
going to be for that lamps document you
yeah
got it
you can't put what was intended in that
registry
yeah
i believe the outcome was there are the
attestation formats that are already
defined in web offend there's an
extensible registry for that exists
already for formats that would make
sense for the primary use case of web
authent and we'll likely need to create
an additional registry for formats that
don't
fit into like the actual web off and
fido
scheme
i think there's another question
hank where's hank hank's not here
am
um
he's gone okay
um so what is the the draft uh proposed
changing um it adds a new challenge and
that challenge encapsulates a web authen
uh attestation statement format yeah we
also have kathleen in the queue if you
want her yeah uh go ahead
kathleen
can you hear me now okay yes
i had asked on the list
and i'm hearing a bad echo i hope nobody
else is
nope just you
i'll power through it
i had asked on the list and
in the comments here
for the working group to
decide whether this should if adopted
be combined
with my client draft that already is
adopted
or if it should be separate
it already adds
web often as an authentication type
to be able to or a challenge rather
to
be able to get
a certificate so this is a little
different
but there could be a good bit
i'm not sure what if this
if the correct answer is a separate
draft or being included i will say that
the draft i'm proposing is fairly narrow
it only works it's for devices it's not
it doesn't touch certificates issued to
users or authenticating users uh it
doesn't touch code signing
and it
doesn't
touch devices that lack the ability to
attest their own identity
so this is a
fairly narrow focus
and
the the web offend usage in the client
certificate draft is around actually
using the full web offense spec this is
narrowly tailored to only using
datastation statement format as an
encapsulation for attestations the rest
of web authent has is has nothing to do
with this proposal
but i leave that up to the working group
chairs i think
okay hank are you back
i'm trying again is this working
yes
wonderful okay
yet another device hi
um so um i've been asked to come here so
i'm swinging by
um the lamps id says that they use
cryptographic attestation
in order to establish the provenance of
a key
that's fine
but that is not what a tpm does in
general
that's just one of the tiny things that
tpm does the gpm creates evidence about
the system characteristics that can
prove its trustworthiness
which has nothing to do with the web off
and also
it does not do that
but they're also not it's true that's
not entirely true and two
can do that optionally
um which makes me happy to hear when you
say that it's just about framing i'm
putting the evidence inside and i think
that's the term i want to hear here if
you're talking about the authenticity
of a device that's phosphory meaning it
is doing exactly what is intended to do
and nothing else um then i think you are
absolutely go okay with saying um
attestation evidence but uh please uh
differentiate between the uh
the web off and capabilities
the fact that they say over 500 times at
the station and only mean it like four
times i think between the tpm capability
and uh and the other ones so just define
are you creating assertions that are
actually believable about the
trustworthiness or are you really
talking about key provenance which are
which is part of the first but it's
absolutely not the first but it said
just highlighting that
thank you that's helpful um
tpms have
many many things it can do in lots of
options but
what the rest of the attestation schemes
actually do in reality is relatively
simple they
provide evidence that the key was
generated in hardware and they
provide
uh an identity of the device that's
associated with that um so for tpms to
kind of exist side by side of these
other attestation schemes we're really
just using key certification
um along with either the endorsement key
or the platform
or the endorsement certificate or the
platform certificate to establish the
identity of the device
i think
broader state attestation is kind of out
of scope
sorry for interrupting just state that
up so don't use the term like at the
station
just state what you're doing like you
just did and then mint the term in the
context of your work
that's fine you can call it grab it
doesn't matter
um the important thing is people
understand what you're actually talking
about and and think that's a big problem
with throwing the term attestation
around because it means nothing anymore
if it you don't can't even say it's a if
it's a procedure or a message
so um if you're at that level i think uh
really talking about the exact thing
and defining it and then naming it is a
better way around and then everybody
would be happy and then you can
tie android key to station and gpms and
apple here to take whatever i do there
and then that will make sense
thanks
how many thanks thank you for the
feedback
um
so uh
what is the actually contained in the
extension uh it specifies a new
challenge type um when this challenge
type is presented to a client the client
returns a web authentication statement
format uh in the
response payload the challenge response
payload which is
not done by any other
challenge types anymore of today but
the
high level acme specification does
have language around future
specifications may do this um
another way this could be done is
involving an external verifier um where
the acme server actually reaches out to
the verifier um but based on discussions
i've had most people seem to prefer the
simpler method of passing data station
directly to the acme server
it also uses the acme specified key
authorization
as the nonce that's passed into
the key generation methods of the
various formats um
and definitely open to feedback if this
is the
like the intended use of key
authorization um
ident i specify two identifiers um
one uses the rfc 4043 permanent
identifier
to identify the platform
um i also included
uh a hardware module uh
identifier that was specified in rfc
4108 however i've gotten feedback this
week that this may not be the best idea
uh the reason i put that there in the
first place was
if you imagine a
tpm device
uh tpm included in a device that doesn't
have an issued platform certificate
the that device is actually unable to
prove the identity of the device it's
only able to prove the identity of the
tpm which is a different assertion than
would be made if a platform shift exists
or with the other attestation schemes
which do attempt to prove the actual
identity of the entire device not just
the security chip included in it
i also added informative text around
using external account binding for
pre-authenticating requests to the ca
in my experience most enterprise
environments don't want to have
uh except unauthenticated requests on
the open internet so they're
likely would want to include this in
some form of configuration management um
that's pushed down to the device before
it um is able to
prove its identity um
next slide please do you want to take
the question yeah
ron
was just going to comment that
i did something similar in a proprietary
implementation of
a
new challenge type with a challenge
response that contained
a um
a jwt authentication token using
the
[Music]
the d-pop work
and that seemed to work quite well so
that seems like quite a sensible thing
to me
so
thank you good to hear it thank you
so existing implementation um
i created a fork of small step which is
a uh not a fork per se uh patch series
of patches a small step it's a open
source golang ca
um that
along with a client that implements this
for tpm at a station um
and he also includes a tpm simulator in
case you want to run this on a regular
laptop
the demonstration ca also later added
support for apple's managed device
at a station feature that they launched
wwc
the other major implementation of this
is apple's ios
16 betas
that uses this uses
uh encoding including an acme uh web
authentication statement in acme
as the basis of requesting a certificate
alongside skep and sending the private
key plus certificate in a p12 payload or
the other two
methods they spot on older versions
and not included on this version of the
slides
android has also
put this on their roadmap to include
alongside apple
next slide
please and uh now i have some questions
uh for everyone
um
there's been some discussions i've had
this week around
um
the the types of information that can be
reflected into the client certificate
that the ca has validated
these would include things like the
identity of the device the identity of
the
security chip
the key generation properties
key generation properties seem like a
specifically controversial
thing to identify that
has a lot of complexity about what does
harder backed mean
what are the relative trust levels of a
trust trust zone versus discrete
hardware versus hardware on diverse
hardware on a bus
um and
is this draft the place should be or is
that somewhere else because that's a
pretty hard problem it sounds like
and
the verification procedures this came up
on the mailing list someone asked okay
why would my enterprise ca trust any of
this
um each of the different attestation
formats has various levels of quality of
documentation
the documentation where it does exist
there's often
asterisks and foot guns that if
implemented improperly caused the system
not to be secure
[Music]
and
i don't believe there's any place this
is really specified i think web authent
has done the best cross attestation
scheme attempt at documenting but
i know there's issues with
um
like it's not complete with all of the
the foot guns and asterisks
does this belong in the the rats uh
working group does it belong in this
document does this document have any
does this document stand alone without
attempting to specify how you implement
verifiers for each of these schemes in a
secure and correct manner
sean
sean turner um so in full disclosure i
am writing a draft and lamps about this
kid station stuff over there so i'm
basically supportive of this approach
for the first one it seems like that is
a
hole that you could be buried in for a
long long time did we just set up a
registry and leave it alone make it
first come first serve and knock
yourself out so the mechanism is there
to be able to specify what those things
are and just
punt
completely because that would be an
option to do that because if you're
going to try to document all of them
good luck you'll come back and you'll
have a long gray beard like i do yeah um
the verification procedures you have to
put something in there right but
if it's
if it's really that complicated but
again there's a bunch of different
options i don't know how you write that
right so then you end up in this hole of
like if you do this and then you do this
and if you did this then you're gonna
use 12 other things so i'm not quite
sure how to
how to solve that one but the first one
i think just maybe make a registry and
call it a day
yeah i think it's it's fairly tractable
to document verification procedures
until you try to do it correctly and
then it
gets very complex from there
sorry
q is mine
um
so
i have a couple of comments on this um
[Music]
one
is we need to make sure that this is
actually all verifiable
if
um
the acme or the ca that's issuing the
acme certs
or the relying party that then gets the
certs
can't
be assured that the data in the cert is
correct
then
we're going the wrong way
if the ca can't tell
whether the device
i mean the device can't just say hi
i'm a tpm
without proof that he is actually a tpm
right so you have to be able to validate
that now it appears i've spent like 15
minutes reading this stuff it appears
that android and
a bunch of places have basically root
cas that
assert that these are devices that they
have built
so that's fine um
[Music]
within the realm of how trustworthy that
is seeing that's another rabbit hole
um
[Music]
so that was my my main when i first saw
this my main concern was
who's this who who gets to decide
whether this is what it really is and i
can't self-assert like self-assertion
should not be possible
oh my opinion um
so that's that's part of it there was
had another point what was it
um i think you can't when you talk about
key generation and the quality of key
generation there's no way for a ca or of
a lying party to know how well you've
done key generation and you're back to
basically self-assertion at that point
there's no way for an acme ca to know
that this tpm over there did it this way
for real right i believe there is
it's
fairly key certification is not simple
with tpms and there's again many ways to
do it incorrectly but it is possible
and can the ca tell it's been done
incorrectly yes
how
um when you generate a key the the
policy is encoded um in a string that is
signed and verifiable
so
if the key is not generated in the
expected manner so for example tpms
allow key importation and they also
allow key generation and you can
actually tell the difference whether a
key was imported or generated um it can
it provides evidence whether it was rsi
or ecdsa
and
if you if you're in an environment that
has a attestation ca or a private cca
that is willing to de-anonymize clients
as
is in an enterprise environment um
the privacy ca can pass along the
identifiers included either in the
endorsement key certificate which
identifies the gpm chip itself or the
platform certificate which identifies
the the combination of a tpm and a
platform
how do i know the tpm hasn't lied
uh the the t like the tpm has an
endorsement key certificate which is
included um you do what's called
credential activation and tcg terms to
turn a
decrypt only ek into a signing ak
attestation key and the attestation key
going forward signs
actually signs the key certification
data that is sent to acme ca so if you
trust the tpm vendor
you can trust
yeah okay so there's
um
pitfalls here i think
is probably the best way to say that i
am generally untrustworthy of these
things um so maybe i'm a little um and
this is no hats by the way
um this is just me
um
since monty is staying right behind i
will pick on the trusted computing group
a little bit um
android chrome os and apple have
implemented their attestation schemes in
a way so for example apple's managed
device attestation if it generates a key
at all and it produces an agitation
certificate that was generated in their
secure enclave processor there's no
other way to get so right so as long as
the enclave processor is working
correctly you're good
if it's failed
you're screwed right
the trust in the
the tpm
monty wiseman by the way
um the trust of the tpm is
anchored in whoever signs the ek
certificate which says who made the tpm
that's really not any different
than trusting apple to say the key and
the t2s the same is good
just in android that's really not any
different than trusting infineon to make
the tpm the only real difference is it's
portable across platforms
um
so anyway i'm gonna
go on the other
the other topic the reason i came up
here is
i think a document like this is a really
good place to put
values
you know maybe hardware i don't i'll
make the same comment i made in lamps i
think it's going to be hard with a
binary assertion of hardware versus not
hardware
um
but
the distinction
any distinctions we made about we make
about quality
should not go in here needs to go
somewhere else otherwise it becomes
exactly the same comment labs
so we're gonna have to find a way to
enumerate these somehow right to make
any value assertion between a software
tpm that's running in my process
that i have happen to have an ek signed
by something on my platform and an
affinian tpm or
something else we have to find some way
to make a distinction between those
something like this doesn't need to
worry about that we just need to
have some value that somebody else
decides not this one
yeah i tend to agree given that
there's going to be three different
documents that specify for for tls for
uh the right three at least three
documents i think i heard a fourth
that's gonna need it so yeah
yes um
aaron
yeah
uh
having having read the stock when it
first went out on the mailing list i
i think it's completely appropriate for
this document to not specify
exactly what the ca is supposed to do in
order to determine whether it trusts the
attestation that it receives because
that's a matter for like five different
documents because it is
very difficult the thing that surprised
me was that this document didn't talk
about that at all i was expecting a
paragraph that was like and when you
receive the key attestation
you
should make sure that you trust it via
informative reference to some other set
of things that might be useful instead
it was just like the ca gets the
attestation back and is good to go and i
was like i am very confused now
um so so some sort of reference to the
fact that this is a hard problem and
ca's need to do it correctly would be
very appropriate but i don't think it
should be fully specified
yeah here
totally agree i appreciate the feedback
and i'll definitely add that um i think
i ended up basically writing the
informative text out on the mailing list
anyways so i think i can just
put that in the document
hi
yeah i agree that there's a lot missing
in the document like there's no um
um
no example of the uh
um posters get with the new identifiers
but that's fine and
it's really a zero zero um version
so yes carl
carl are you still with us
i was just going to say on the second
question here um
um well i thought so maybe you don't
hear me
no we'll see you we hear you too so
you're good
there's a terrible lag so i'm just i'm
just going to speak okay um
the verification procedures have to be
in a separate document
that's all i was going to say over
okay thank you so um
so you have some open questions for us
we have an obvious question for you are
you seeking adoption
yes i am um in consideration of vendors
already beginning to support this um
i would love to get as much feedback
about bachelor encoding
of the requests as soon as possible um
i think there's been
broad interest on the mailing list for
someone to write something whether it be
an existing draft or a new draft um
it does seem like people are attempting
to use kieva station and acme and cmp
and est and tls and seems to be a very
prominent topic this year
okay so that of course we'll go on the
mailing list um
so uh thank you
so we're out of time how did we do that
it was supposed to be short yeah
we used the time exactly i mean we even
have 30 seconds for any other business
which i guess
we're all getting back okay
thank you all
right enjoy the rest of your eye
more physically in
london
yes please
thank you
both
carl wallace