a minute more
until
it's like 5 30 now i guess yep
it is
you want to start off bernie
no you you you do it go ahead
all right i'll do this one welcome
everyone philly ietf 114 this is the
dhep working group
here's the ietf notewell if you haven't
seen it by thursday you're lucky i guess
please take a look at it and please read
it if you don't recognize it and follow
all the rules in it um additionally
we ask that you uh keep your mask on
if you're not presenting or actively
drinking doing any of those things
everyone's been doing a great job this
week so
keep that up
no well blue sheets so if you're in the
room there's a there was a qr code it's
gone now but there's a qr card please um
if you're in the room physically just go
to the on-site tool click on it and mark
yourself as here that gives us accurate
counts for who's here
um
note takers bernie's agreed to start him
off and i'll be filling in when he's
presenting but additionally there's the
markdown hedge doc
notes feel free to add your own notes as
we go through we'll clean them up at the
end
and zulup is and jabber is kind of like
a merged thing now so if you're in the
meat echo tool there's a little chat bot
it shows up very nicely so
um feel free to use that and i'm tim and
bernie's remote
hanging out with us from from lovely new
hampshire
hi there
i hope everybody's doing well and i i
also want to uh welcome tim because i
think this is the first working group
meeting we've had since you've been
chair is that correct or am i
misremembering
no you're actually right this is the
first one i've chaired i didn't even
think about that it seems like an ian
ago now
it does and you know i i don't know
whether uh
tomek is around but uh you know we miss
homek and uh wish him well um and thank
him for his many years of service as a
co-chair
so with that i'll hand it back to you
awesome thanks bernie so this is our
agenda for today we've got a little bit
of the normal stuff going on the chair
slides
um we're going to talk a 8415 to
internet standard is our second bernie's
going to take that one and we've got
distributed sr6 locators by dhcp
self-registering
registering self-generated ipv6
addresses is our fourth one and then
we're going to talk a little bit about
net next steps at the end
so i'll do this one bernie since you're
going to talk a lot in a minute so
our current working group status is we
don't have any working group documents
at the moment we finally got the yang
model
through after some
trials and tribulations thanks to ian i
don't know if he's online but ian did a
lot of work for that to get that over
the
hump um but we did get it over
we have two related documents today that
we're gonna talk about both of them are
on the agenda so that's good um
milestones we currently have and
bernie's going to talk a little bit more
about this is
2023 and march of 2023 for um what to do
what we think the working group is going
to do going forward
um does anyone have anything they want
to change about any of this stuff any of
the agenda or any comments on that
seems pretty straightforward
okay
um
then bernie do you want me to share the
slides from here
sure yeah if you can do that
i can
all right the floor is yours
okay so we'll talk a little bit about
advancing uh dhcp v6 to
internet standard um
can i advance the slides no i guess
you'll do it
okay
so um the motivation for advancing
uh dhcp v6 to
enter its standard from what it
currently is which is proposed
um is really
because of the charter and the charter
that we uh did many years ago
uh we figured it was a worthwhile
endeavor to do and that was also the
reason we wrote rc 84
15 which really consolidated the base
specification from the you know three
core documents 3315 and the two others
you know the iapd
and stateless
uh plus a few others into a totally new
document
but you know we always have the choice
to uh leave it as proposed but i'm going
to go on the assumption that the working
group is interested
in doing that the work to move it to
enter its standard because we are pretty
close
so next slide
the requirements for
an internet standard
document
is
really um
four
key criteria
uh there are at least two independent
interrupting
inter-operating implementations with
widespread
deployment and successful operational
experience
there are no errata against the
specification that will cause a new
implementation to fail to interoperate
with deployed ones
there are no unused features in the
specification that greatly increase
implementation complexity
and four if the technology required to
implement the specification requires
patented or otherwise controlled
technology then the set of
implementations must demonstrate those
two independent separate and successful
uses of the licensing process
so let's go through each of those to uh
indicate where we are today
um
you know we
i think
there's no uh disagreement that we have
lots of independent
implementations that are interoperating
today
you know pretty much
we have things from cable modems to home
gateways to routers to servers to
laptops
even quite a few handheld devices you
know mobile devices and things like that
um all seem to be able to interoperate
and work
and you know do the ghp v6 standard
um you know everybo everything appears
to operate well from both the previous
usg v6 testing that was done at
um
the unh interoperability lab and
previously at cable labs uh field
deployments like comcast's broadband
service which is ipv6 based
and also uh things like the itf midi
network offers dhp v6
so i think we have quite a lot of good
implementations
and have no issue with that
we do have three reported errata
and
you know we do have some unused features
uh that
could be argued to add some complexity
complexity such as the iata
um
we have no
updated by that i could find but that
might be something to
to look through a little bit more
carefully
and obviously there's no ipr that's been
filed or that anybody has
claimed
um regarding rc 8415 or its predecessors
that i am aware of
um and has been reported to the ietf
um
you know there could be some
issues in the documentation in in the
standard uh that we might not have
had reported um you know if
anybody is aware
of any please file on rada asap
the mailing list i did do a quick sort
of scan of it does seem to have one
minor
item and that is that there was no
reference to rc 7943
which is in you know in section 13.1
which talks about
address predictability and you know
algorithms to use to select addresses
and i think that was just a timing issue
because while we were sort of you know
head down and and writing the
documentation we missed you know
updating rc 3315 and its friends to 8415
we kind of asked that this came out and
uh should have been included so that's a
pretty minor thing just add another
reference
um let's quickly go through the errata
because those are
potentially sticky items
um
one is just a typo where section six is
missing and closing parenthesis i don't
think that causes any interoperability
issues um
and depending on what we do if we do a
8415 biz
and if we drop temporary addresses the
section would disappear anyway so it
might be a non-issue to begin with
um
and we do have another type o in section
1838 which uses the word client instead
of server you know it's like
it's talking about what the server does
and it says the client
generates a packet well no it meant the
server generates a packet i think it's
easily understood to be a typo and
probably is not that um significant yes
it should be fixed and you know we'll do
that should we need to
um
then we have this errata which is a bit
more
involved um and this is an inconsistency
as to whether survey server unicast can
be used by information request
messages
um
and it it seems like the intent was that
they could
and so there are a couple sections that
have
uh some incorrect list of messages where
you know information request message
should be removed or or included
um and
um
there's also an inconsistency as to
whether server unit test option can be
used in a reconfigure message
um
so that would be another one uh to to
look at
there was some discussion on the mailing
list about this issue
and you know this
could
arguably cause some interoperability
issues although i'm not sure that it
really
has to to date but you know if a
client were to
use a server unicast
uh in an information request and the
server disallowed it then obviously the
server is going to probably send back a
malformed or dropped the packet and
therefore you know no progress
would be made by the client to to get an
answer to its information request
so this one
probably does require
a
correction and that would be done
through a biz document
um and then you know we have the this
kind of came up
during the 8415
discussions about
should we deprecate the iata
since most
clients never really use it
and you know it it kind of has
it you know
with with most
things being you know if monitoring is
being done it's probably using the
prefix the slash 64 or something like
that
and so the address itself doesn't really
matter that much when a client can
always just go ask for another address
if it wanted to
to anyway
um you know there is one subtle
distinction between an iana and iata
because an ia ta should not be put in
dns for example
so if dns updates are being performed by
a server it should not be doing an
update for an iata
so this is a discussion that we need to
have in the working group as to whether
we
should deprecate this
or or not
um you know the other question is are
there any other things in the document
that
might be considered uh to obsolete you
know we did obsolete some things from
and i don't think there's anything else
but
it is a question
next slide
so as i kind of mentioned on errata
likely
the router likely requires a document
update
um
you know we'll we'll start with the
co-authors of 8415 biz assuming that the
working group does want to proceed with
this work
um to to start putting together the 8415
biz document depending on how what the
response is or if somebody has a really
strong desire to become involved
um you know that might be something that
the the remaining co-authors consider um
in working on the biz documents and who
who would be included the the work is
fairly small to integrate the errata
um you know removing the iata temporary
addresses is likely
a bit
messy i mean it's pretty straightforward
but there's you know there's quite a few
places where
uh the text would
get some sort of changes
you know i think there's also an
opportunity to shorten the document
which might
a little bit more powerful for the iesg
you be
when they have to go review this and and
or
you know the
other
uh people within the itf that need to
review this document
um
you know we can uh
remove a lot of the motivation for the
original rfc 8415
um
you know the some of the appendices were
fairly large because we made a lot of
changes and documented all those changes
and obviously now we would just document
what is new to 8415 bids from 8415.
you know one of the goals is to be very
careful to minimize the changes though
because that will make
our job as a working group to review the
document
uh much simpler you know when you look
at the diffs you'll you'll be able to
say yeah
you know i can see that the
you know the either i were corrected and
other things were done
so this is my straw for you know a what
i think is a fairly aggressive but
doable schedule
and that would be to publish an updated
you know biz
8415 biz document a zero zero version of
it uh before the november
uh ietf deadline um
you know again it's it's not a lot of
things to do but there are a few area a
few things that we the working group
and the authors need to discuss about
what do we do
uh both for fixing the errata and for
like removing the iatas
um
you know the working group
needs to do a good job at reviewing the
document because hopefully we can
complete that
um a couple of months you know two
months later
and then um publish uh the updated
document by
the art the march itf deadline to submit
it to the isg
one other thing is that i i
you know tim is a co-author i'm a
co-author
um and so we'll likely need to find um a
shepherd as the co-chairs will be
involved with the document but i'll
leave that up to the
a.d
uh to decide and maybe one of the ads
would even be willing to to shepherd the
documents
so
the the first big question
is do we go for it do people think it's
worth
advancing this to internet standard
so i don't know if you want to take a
a straw poll
tim in the room to see and
don't we have we have a voting tool
don't we here
yeah i'm putting one up
show of hands tool
yep i'm working on it
okay
should have been doing that earlier
a pretty good response
yeah
okay so i i think that's definitely an
indication i mean obviously we're going
to go to the list with this but i think
that's a sign that people are interested
in doing this
yeah and i don't know is everybody in
the room there or is that just a online
participant
okay it's both yeah that's how it works
um we do have somebody wanting to come
to the queue
okay
hi mike ackerman my question is about
iata
and with the focus on security which
that is intended to do i think
why would it be a good idea to take that
out now
and i know you're going to say nobody's
using it
but
the folks that we use the most would be
enterprises like myself and we're not
doing anything in ipv6 yet but when we
do
this could be important so i guess
that's my question
well and and that is really the the
debate um it does add a little bit
complexity and since
you know its usage has been found to be
almost
zero
i microsoft has at one point was using
it i don't know whether they're
uh still doing so
um
so
you know i mean maybe that's uh
you know that's a discussion that the
working group should have is do we know
of implementations out there using it or
do we know of people potentially
interested
in you know now or in the future in
using it
yeah obviously
go ahead
i was going to say the case i'm making
isn't for anybody using it i'm saying
some of us might use it in the future
and i know that's not a very strong
statement but it's all i got right now
right
okay just my two cents thank you thanks
i'm going to close that poll
okay
so uh let me see
suresh
come on up
oh yeah
but that's not gonna
change
okay thank you uh so
bernie just couple of things um i think
um
one of the things i'm really worried
thanks
so one of the things is really like you
know this is like a really long process
and and uh
if you're going through with this i
think there's like some other stuff we
need to look at so there's a couple of
things that kind of caught my eye right
like you know like some of the late rfcs
right like you know seoul max rt and
stuff like that right is somebody using
it right like i think tim you would know
best like among all the people right so
maybe it also go over like a lot of the
when i say newer like probably like last
10 years right like all the stuff that
came out right like you know bulk lease
query stuff right yeah to see well so
yeah so
the vocalist query just to say is that's
a separate rfc and dot covered in the
base
8415. but things like the information um
sorry the the
solicit refresh timer and things like
that those are in there and yes we do
i i do know that there are devices out
there using that and you know they they
seem to to work
okay so yeah but yeah
i think we need to
you know i think tim um may have some
some to say about the usg v6 stuff
because some of the testing there
on the new uh dhcp v6
8415 work
uh focuses on some of that additional
testing
yeah so i'll talk a little bit about
this and kind of make a plug for my
friends at the unh iol so what we've you
know the ready logo has a new dhcp logo
we're working on we put it out for
public review
i said some notes about this on the list
the general idea there is to cover all
the new things that got included in 8415
like soul max rt
stateful issues
a couple of those things that weren't in
a 3315 standard
client or server so one thing you know
if you're interested in my call kind of
here would be is if you have an
implementation and you're interested
please talk to my friends at the iol
you know drop it off there they're just
looking for interoperability partners to
make sure that people have implemented
some of those more corner test cases
because a little bit of concern i'm
hoping by november we'll have better
we'll have better results to say yeah
we've got a bunch of people that have
done this i think we're kind of in a
state where i think some of it's been
done like soul max rt is in the home
gateways for sure
but i i don't know what it looks like
for enterprises for example so i think
some of that we're gonna have to sort
out that make sense right i think the
idea would be to kind of make it easy
for eric to kind of defend this right so
if the information is ready to go i
think it's easier for him to like defend
something that eric like to will would
say like hey like you know this is where
it's implemented and so on because like
we kind of remove the implementation
status and everything from the rfcs
right so it'll be good to kind of have
this information ready because this is a
really long process and
i i did 8200 like and it's like and and
it's like really tough on the 80 so it's
uh
it's probably good to kind of have
a good idea of like you know what is
really yeah out there like okay thanks
that's good now
yeah we probably need you know we'll
probably need to develop some kind of uh
feature
uh matrix or something to
to see you know have have these
combinations been tested especially
about some of the newer
uh non-basic sort of stuff
um
[Music]
so you know what what can you do to help
in the short term uh well for the
um
you know co-authors i need to hear from
you whether you're interested in working
on this or not
um
and you know if anybody has else has a
strong interest let me know
um you know you can send uh to dhc
chairs
um if you are interested
um that way tim's aware of it as well
and um
the other thing is you know
if you have
any
issues that you've
had with rc 8415 any typos errors
uh you know more
severe
mistakes or whatever
you know do report them um ideally it's
best if you report them as the you know
using the errata stuff but if you don't
want to do that
you can send them to dgchairs at itf.org
for now as we'll collect them we might
you know depending on how the
the dhcp uh v6 biz team wants to work we
might open up a different mailing list
as we kind of did last time but i think
this is a hopefully a
smaller effort and we won't need to do
that
um the other thing is that you know it's
it's again something in the future but
we need people to review the document
when published and do it properly
um
and you know give us updates quickly so
that we can get new versions correct
new corrected versions out as soon as
possible so that's it
awesome thanks bernie i think we got our
next steps here so we'll take some stuff
to the list for sure
all right
let's see next up is um the dhcp
sr locator and then
let's see
i'll put up the slides
all right
let's see
okay you want to go ahead
wing chun yeah so uh hello
can you hear me
yep we can hear you just fine go ahead
okay i'm gonna give you control of the
slides or you're okay if i do it
uh i can do that
okay hang on
okay
so uh
hello everyone uh i'm with sancho from
uh
channel mobile i will
present
this
slide
to
show the distributor sr6 located by ds
dhcp
and uh
okay
so
here the
figure shows the network architecture
of a telecom operators
the applications narrow here
is a
private line and vpn services for
enterprises
the cpus are located in the
customers
sites
the number
will be very large
even
more than
50 000
around the country
with a wider
geographical
distribution
some of them
may be based on 4g or 5g
with a high mobility
in order to keep the network simple
the cps
often
do not deploy
igp
so recently
[Music]
many people
many operators
have deployed
large scale as rb6 networks
the cps also begin to support
srv6
so that operators can provide
the end-to-end
srv6 vpn to customers
it's a little bit complicated to
configure
the i76
we hope to simplify the configuration
and hope the cpe can
dynamically learn
assam 6
located
subnet routines
that's why we write this
proposal
the
proposal is very simple
the basic idea is that
we treat
i-76
locate as
the ipv6 prefix
in prefix support
the key points i hear
the first one
is
the dxcp v6 server
allocates
srv6 located
as a prefix
and the second
follow the dhcp basics prefix
delegation process
and the third
after
the located prefix assigned successfully
the bus
dynamically
distribute
the locate subnet routine locally and
distributes the
local uh
located
uh
sub
subnets routines to arsenals
in the network
and the the
force when
the locator prefix
is released
the brush deletes the locate subnets
rotis
here the brass need to
enable the hcp v6
pd server
or dhcp v6 release agent service
so
before
we
introduce
the dhcp extension i would like to
share the basic information about the
srv6
seed format especially
the
comprised
assab6 seed format
which is
illustrated
the
bottom of the
slide
for the comprised seat
the locator
will be separated to two parts
the
common
part
we call that locate block
and
the
different part
we call that locate note
other field are the same with the
original
seed
which define the fc
89 86
so
about the extension
we hope to define a new srv6 locator
option
it will be
encapped and
facilitated
in the ia prefix options field
of ia prefix option
it will be used to identify
srb6 locator prefix
in ia prefix option and
carry
srv6 locator
subnet
information
the format
shows in a faker
firstly we need a
new
option code
for the
option assignment 6 locator
the second
we will have a
locate a block length
field
that indicates the
locator block
the length of the locator block
in a comprised state
if
it's not zero
it's a zero
it will indicate
an
original as a b6 seed
and
we need a
function
lens field
which
indicate
the lens of function
we need a arguments lens
field
it will
indicate
the length of the argument
that's the basic
extension
here
the
srb6 located prefix
is
filled in the ipv6 prefix field of the
ia prefix option
the
locate prefix lens
is filled
in the
prefix lens field of ia prefix option
so that
you can calculate
the
located node lens
based on
the information here
so all the
lengths of the field
for the comprised seed or for the
original seed
can be
get
generated based on the
information
in the
extension
hider
and
yeah this is the basic
relationship
for the
srv6 locator option i think it's very
simple and iapd option may contain
multiple
ia
prefix
options
at the same time
and
ia prefix option
can only have one srv6
locator option
at at most
uh this is based on
the rfc
and
let's see some
application scenarios the first one
the brass
works
as
the scp scp-v6
pd server
at this moment
the
favorite
second generate the
locate subnet routine locally
the third
distribute the
locate
subnets routine to
other ipv6 node so it's very simple
and
the second scenario
brass
works as the htcp
basics
really agent
it's also very simple
the behavior like that first
release dhcp basics pd
allocation messages
the second generate the locator
subnet routine locally the third
distribute the locate prefix
rotates to us ipv6 node
so that's
the basic behavior
for a really agent
so that's all
any questions or comments
bernie i think you beat him in line so
you can go ahead
okay
um
so
you know if so a client sends this new
option
in a request
or you know solicit
things
and a server
that's aware of this option would send
one in a reply so
you you know the client can know oh yeah
okay the server understood this
but if a server that doesn't understand
this
new option
it will respond
with a prefix because this is going to
look and say oh see i said i see a
request for a prefix oh i'm going to
assign you a pre-tax
um
and so now
what does the client do with that prefix
that it got
that
it's not
you know it
it it's not it doesn't have this your
new option in it the uh
ia
srv or whatever it was called
um yeah srv6
locator option in it so the client will
go well this isn't an srv6
thing
so is the client going to turn around
and release it
you know so i think that's something
that needs to be thought out is how does
how does a client
make sure that when it asks for one of
these things
that
it unders it knows it got one and it
that i think you've got the check on
that
but if it how does it know or how does
it what does it do how does it deal with
it if if the server didn't
know
about this srv6 locator option you know
and just assigned a prefix
from its prefix pool
so
yeah i think
this is a
very good
question so from my point of view
for the server
if
it
don't
doesn't know the option
it will
ignore the new option right
that is a basic behavior
for the server
which to handle the new option
and it just
treated as the
original prefix
allocation that that that is okay
well the server doesn't understand the
option it's going to allocate a normal
prefix right and you've
wasted a prefix
potentially because the client can't use
it for
the srv6 purposes right
yeah that may be
that that may happen but
you know this system
will
be maintained
in
one operator's
network
i think it uh it's easier to generate
some
basic policy to avoid
this kind of uh
problem
well i think for interoperability
reasons right you should
it's
i mean you can't argue this is a closed
system right people can plug things in
and stuff so
i
think you need to think about how to
deal with that you know i mean one
one thought maybe that you want a
instead of
putting it in
a standard prefix option maybe you want
to
add a new
you know ia srv6
option right which says hey this is an
srv6 locator you know so you want an ia
option
for this
yeah
that's possible i think he
we should consider
uh
the question uh later and uh
hope we can
uh handle it
thank you
yeah
and you know i'm not i'm not going to um
i i can't say whether this is a good or
bad idea because i'm not really an srv6
expert and so you know i think that
there
it will be good at some point to get
some input from
uh
some people that have more of this
experience because and and
you know i mean this is a protocol
option
probably if especially if it's an ia and
so it should be done in the dhc working
group but we are going to need some
expertise to help us
yeah maybe we can also
uh
submit the draft to spring working group
and maybe we can
also
apply some slot
in
spring working group to present it and
to see
the feedback and comments
okay
um we got 15 more minutes let's let eric
and suresh say there uh yeah eric i'm
gonna run real quick actually because i
think bernie said everything i wanted to
say i'm just gonna say
uh i think uh the dhc idiomatic way of
doing it is probably to define a new
option which bernie suggested i'm going
to go ahead and guess that the reason
that maybe you didn't propose that is
because the b-raz might not be able to
be updated
uh i don't know if that's a really
good
reason or not and secondly as uh well as
temporary delegate delegated
responsibility i was going to say it
definitely does have to have uh review
from from spring
yeah and we if if we adopt this work we
also need you know permission from our
ad
okay
okay thanks
okay i think that's everybody okay great
thank you
let's see
again i think you're up
well
i'll let you two work this out
whichever one of you wants to get up
here
there we go
doing it with my hat on the whole like a
d hut thing doesn't yeah okay
so hi everyone um
my plan was that i was going to be in
the grow working group and jen was going
to present this so i am in no way
prepared
so
i'll make this up as we go along
so this is registering self-generated
ipv6 addresses using dhcp v6
and
thank you
this is who we are the draft is actually
based on an earlier document from suresh
and rajiv and some others
um but you know it's myself
lorenzo
jen at some point
so that's us next slide
why are we doing this
because eventually asking people have
you tried turning it off and on gets
really old
so what are we trying to do what's the
problem we want to solve
so
a fairly common
thing with like it help desks and
security people
is they need to do things like find what
ip address a machine has
um with ipv4
the ceo can't print to his printer
he calls up and he's really annoyed
people look in the dhcp logs
they find the iep address based on the
mac they ping the printer
they you know things work out and
they're happy
if you're doing ipv6 with slack
the ceo calls up and says he can't print
to his printer
and you say have you tried turning it
off for none again
and he says yes and you say uh have you
tried turning it off and run again and
he says yes and then you go post your
resume on monster right if you just have
the mac address it's really hard to
figure out what ipv6 address somebody
has
um
next
one the other common use case
is security operations folk
have something where you know last
thursday at 2 43
they have some ids log
that shows that some machine uploaded
their entire source tree to stack
overflow
what they'd like to know is
which employee had this ip address at
this time
or what machine had this ip address at
with ipv4 the obvious thing is you have
the ip address you go look in the dhcp
logs you find the mac address
and then hr goes along and visits the
employee and says you did what
um with v6 what you say is uh
that's not good i have no idea who used
that address they assigned it to
themselves with slack
and then once again you post your resume
on monster.com
next slide
um so obviously you know the problem is
that a lot of people
a lot of devices
run slack and don't use dhcp for doing
address assignment
that's actually what's happening on this
network when your machine joins this
network
you do slack
and you get an address
and the network doesn't really know what
it is like the network devices do but
there's no central tracking of it
anything like that
um an option would be you know tell
everybody you should do dhcp for address
assignment
that doesn't always wind well it doesn't
look like it's going to happen
so what are we actually proposing
as i say this was um based on an earlier
draft which was suresh rajiv and i can't
remember who else wrote it
yep
which was basically doing registering
self-generated ipv6 addresses in dns
using dhcp v6
and it
went along fairly well but then it got
stuck in working group last call
and as far as i can tell almost all of
the unhappiness was about the dns part
of it so how do you take this address
and authenticate it that this client
should be able to update that dns
address
so we did is we took out all of the dns
bits
and made a few other changes
and what we're left with is
a method to inform a dhcp
v6 server that a device has a
self-generated address or a statically
configured address
what this does is it allows the dhcp
server to log this information and
ideally also stick the information in
its lisa's file so that it knows or
lisa's database
so that it knows that the address is in
use and it doesn't try and hand it out
in reality that's not likely that bigger
problem you know the chances of multiple
people choosing an address and a dhcp
server trying to assign it are fairly
low but it's still useful
this
solves the helpdesk use case when the
help desk wants to figure out what ip
address a certain mac address has it
looks in the dhcp logs
um it also solves the secops problem if
they want to know what mac address an ip
address was a while back they look in
the logs or what other
sort of tooling is around the dhcp
server
the way it does this is it's fairly
simple
there's a dhcp v6 address notification
message
which just says
hey i'm using this address please make
note of it
um
does this actually actually solve the
secops problems
well
only kind of
because of reasons what you actually get
with dhcp v6 is you get the duid yeah
and that's a whole site better than
nothing at all
often it is actually based on the mac
address but not always
if it's a device that your security
group has heard about there's a
reasonable chance they could actually
like log the duid in an asset database
and if they don't do that you know
there's also client link layer address
option in dhcp v6
which a number of
network devices implement and so that
information shows up in the log
i tested it actually with ios xe on the
ietf wi-fi network
dhcpd and microsoft seemed to support it
or there is what i think was being
discussed when i first walked in
which is a update to
uh 621
where a bunch of bngs and brasses and
similar can include you know the
the address in the
message um
i wrote these slides a long time ago yay
the next one's questions
so
i made up most of the talk on the fly
um who has questions or is this the best
idea ever
bernie do you have you were up there i
don't know is it the worst idea ever
yeah okay um
well i don't know you know is i'd have
to go back to the notes about why we
didn't like it that much in the first
place i i guess i just have
one
question and that is that
you know if if a device were to remove
itself
from the network
um you know it's not defending its
address
um and another device comes along and
registers it you're just gonna say the
dhcp server basically has no
responsibility to say hey i got a new
you know i got an updated thing it's a
totally different client but i'm going
to record it
sort of what you're expecting yep at the
moment it is purely
the client sends a message that says i'm
using this and the dhcp server logs it
if another client comes along and says
i'm using this the dhcp server logs it
um it's just a you know i get this no
useful sanity checking
so clearly there are some ways this
could be abused right like people could
say that
somebody else was using the address
um
attackers could also if they wanted
never send the message like even if it's
built into their os if they wanted to
hide who they are
when they join the network they could
suppress the message from being sent
but i still think it's a lot better than
not having
having any information um
so
sort of very perfect versus the enemy
the good good type thing
did that actually answer your question
or did i answer a completely unrelated
question oh that that's good
kathy's going to tell me why i'm wrong
wow did i really just call you kathy
that's okay my god i've known you
forever
um
so that was mostly what i was thinking
but this is just a fire forget thing
yes it sends it there's no consequence
there's no acknowledgement required i
actually i believe that you're supposed
to get back an act but you don't have to
i can't remember if we had the act in
the end and you send a couple and jen's
gonna correct me
as far as i can remember what you're
doing we saying
that you refresh it periodically and
actually draft has two conflicting
sentences currently and you have the
github issue for that
but i think we discussed the idea of arc
and decided not to because you never
know if your server actually understands
it
so and we also only require a client to
send this if there is a more bit set an
array indicating there is a dhcp server
because i definitely don't want clients
to send those messages if there is no
dhcp in the network whatever so but we
still client still has no way to know
what server actually supports so just
i'm sending kate if you're happy to log
it log it or drop it to
yeah it's stateless it's the whole idea
like client
will like really to inform server and
server willing to do whatever
it goes like if you if you're sending
career with mo you kind of indicate into
client is there is a dhcp somewhere
client sending it to all dhcp link local
multicast
so again if there is no such thing on
the
segment it will just go nowhere if there
is a relay agent it means the network
operator kind of expects something like
that
uh it times out we have some sorry i'd
actually misunderstood your question i
thought it was a
i'm using this address and the dhcp
server can say no so i misunderstood
your question i'm not really wondering
what the responsibility is of the dhcp
server the dhcp server's responsibility
is log this
um
optionally
note it in sort of your
wherever you store lease information and
so you don't try and hand it to someone
else that's optional but you just put it
in there and it stays in there you stuff
it nope it times out after an amount of
time
we the exact amount of time the authors
are still
fighting over
um
we just as long as it turns out
eventually it times out eventually it's
like does it time out in four hours or a
day
or whatever is
is that like deciding the best answer
that's a bit tricky but it times up it's
not infinitely growing it's also if for
example your disk gets full
the dhcp server is allowed to throw them
away or if it's having a bad day it's a
best use only that was exactly what i
was thinking about is you know getting
basically ddosed by a bunch of goofy
clients just sending stuff that you
don't even care about but then you have
to keep and yep yep you're allowed to
ignore them if you feel like it and yes
they will time out
um part of the thing is there's like 17
different timers that we could base the
time out on and is it like the lowest of
this one unless it's more than x versus
you know so the exact number is d
the
to be decided actually that sounds
better
any other yeah we got a couple more we
got hazel here online
hi hazel smith um
i was wondering if this had if this did
have an act then conceivably you could
if you were designing you know access
switches you could use this sort of ip
source card v6 and basically say like
um if you've actually got a lease from
the atp's v6 you can use this address or
if you've sent an announcement saying a
notification saying i'm going to use it
and the http responded
sure fine with me
then you allow it otherwise you don't
which would then give you some kind of
assurance that
if you later see packets on the network
with the ip address that they
came from the device with the mac
address that had told you it was going
to use the ip address um i've no idea if
that will be a valuable concept but
um yeah thank and thanks hazel like i
think one of the worries is that right
the dcp server doesn't support it and
you're waiting for like the dhcp server
to say it's okay that that could lead to
like you know somebody not having access
to that sorry that's the worry and
that's why it's kind of going as best
effort to
go through but i i think it's like
fairly available if you have like a
controlled system and this is something
that you know it's going to happen we
can probably like you know set up
something like regard kind of thing
right it can hook up to something like
regard and to do that but yeah but
otherwise like it's going to be
a bit tough to like lock it down too
much right this is the best effort yeah
yeah so can i quickly just follow up on
this there is a other concern we expect
the client only report preferred
addresses
which means by the time you send this
applications might already want to send
traffic so if you want to do something
like savvy it's better to use dad on
sales stations or any other form of
client willing to get an address and it
might be way too late here to do
anything based on dhcp registration
and i guess i'll add something to that
like
one of the other bits on my badge is
like knock monkey and we've been having
a lot of entertainment at this meeting
with
um
ipv6 and dad and the network devices
going oh i don't think you should really
have that on that port i mean actually
what it's doing is it's sending its
like device tracking message from
um colon colon
because of entertaining bugs so like the
whole
your switch can do
mac address learning and locking down
just as like terrifying but that's my
personal
vendors love it
okay we've got one minute left eric you
wanna
yeah uh eric can hear i just wanted to
say that doing this for
anything other than purely informational
purposes like as tempting as it is and
as fun as it is to be like hey i should
take this into account when giving out
leases like it seems like there's a huge
can of worm stop in there so here's a
centrally known place to log stuff as
like cool great have at it have fun log
as much as you feel like if it's too
much just start ignoring them
everything else starts to seem sketchier
and sketchier
thank you very much uh we have
go ahead
we've got one more person we're going to
sneak in here in the last 30 seconds go
so um have you thought about
perhaps routers or other network devices
faking these messages to get a
more populated lock
sorry to get a more watch
um to get a more populated look so
also lock clients that are not
collaborating yeah somebody suggested
that um you know a device that sees
somebody using a mac and ip could send
this i think that that sounds like a
really bad idea
um
mainly because
it seems like a lot of complexity
like a router could be like i saw this
guy using this ip and mac i'll send it
off i think that bad mojo but it could
be done okay
all right awesome i think we've got some
good stuff to talk about here on the
list
um i think that's everything we had on
the agenda
does anyone have bernie do you have any
last things you want to chat about
click the wrong thing i put the hand
instead of like no i don't have anything
else
okay awesome okay great great seeing
everyone we'll see everyone in london
again
we'll follow up in the mailing list
thanks everybody see you bonnie nice
seeing you
okay yeah good to see you guys take care
enjoy
thank you all take care
sex bye bye
hey ben
can i talk you into reviewing
15.