oh
okay
i think
that
the right time we should get started so
welcome everyone to itf week um you've
got me kirsten playing one of the
co-chairs for dispatch joining virtually
and um we've got murray sitting at the
front as a physical presence if you have
any issues on site at all and you might
notice we've got a change of co-chair so
just to say thanks to patrick mcmanus
for his great stewardship and chairship
of dispatch over the years and really
grateful for all the contributions he's
made and replacing him we have peng
shuping if you'd like to just say hi
paying introduce yourself i'll be
awesome
thank you
there we go
all right so bear with us because it's
always the first session and dispatch so
we always have a bit of fun working out
how the technology is working and how
the sessions are going to work and so
we'll just run through a couple of admin
points before we get started so i'm
really sorry not to be joining you in
person um
but while i'm here virtually let me just
remind you of the note well this is
probably the first time you've seen it
this week so it's a reminder of the ietf
policies that govern your participation
and please make sure that you've read
all of these you would have said at
registration that you would do so in
particular take note of all the kind of
patent policies and general code of
conduct and anti-harassment procedures
as well as the way the ietf works if you
have any issues contact the ombudsman
team
and just to say that these are places
for professional collaboration and
networking there are some um extensive
documentations that talk about the way
that you should be behaving at these
meetings and if you have any concerns at
all once again please talk to the
ombudsman team it's important that we uh
create a good environment so everyone
can bring their best work and bring
their best selves to these kind of
technical discussions that we're having
um so please reach out um to the
ombudsman team or anyone around you that
you trust if you experience any
difficulties or offensive behavior
so hybrid meeting participation and i
think we're all still getting used to it
perhaps you're well seasoned by now but
if not please bear with just while we
run through this because it is the first
session of the week so a lot of stuff um
might seem new or has changed since last
time so to the folks in the room and
please make sure that you've signed into
the session using the meet echo light
client there's a nice circle there to
show you exactly the button to join it's
really important to join that because
that um creates the blue sheets but also
it's how i'm going to call the queue so
if you stand in the room at the mic but
you have not joined the queue on the
meet echo light client then i will not
be calling you in to the queue so do
make sure that you have joined the mike
mq on meet echo we're asking you to keep
your audio and video off if you're a
fully remote participant or if you're on
the on-site version as well and please
use a headset
so i can see that we've um got someone
stood up at the mic but possibly not
joined on the meat echo client so
i'm about to break my own rule just as
an exception what's up
testing testing okay
what's the user user
um so i i actually can't join the meet
echo it's not joining it just gives you
an error when you try and join or log in
and says not authorized and several
people are having this problem so how
would you like to proceed
okay i can see mira is just joined to
the queue mira do you have a response
for that
i think she's just testing
i was just testing so colin if you want
to join just i can click for you i don't
know
okay well this is exactly why we have
murray at the back up in the room
so perhaps yeah in this thing
if it's helpful if someone comes up to
the mic because they can't join i'll
type it in the jabber and you can
manually manage it super yeah let's
manage it that way for now um so we'll
hopefully those issues will be resolved
by the end of the week but uh i can see
everyone joining the queue now yep um
save albana did you want to
make a comment
i can't oh yeah here we go
hello
hello yeah i'm making a comment now i'm
gonna
leave the queue
okay thanks so um i think it's if it
works for you then that would be the
ideal way to join the queue if not um
like we said just in person in the
meeting and we'll manage it by murray
and this is why we have our resilience
strategies
it should be resolved soon so anyway try
and bear in mind for the other meeting
um sessions that you have this is the
way we would like you to join the queue
thanks colin for bringing it um into the
meeting i do love having the first
meeting of the of the week it's very
enjoyable
um okay so just so you all know this
session is being recorded um it's very
important that you know that this goes
on youtube afterwards so just make sure
anything you say you're happy for it to
be recorded and published that way you
can find all the agenda for the whole
week at that link there's also meat echo
and other information if you have any
technical issues please do see the
reporting issues page and all the
meeting and notes and slides and
everything you might need will be on the
dispatch page uh there's also jabber and
tulip that you can give a go as well for
this um
this session
okay i think we've got someone else in
the queue jury did you have a comment
about the setup
uh no sorry
sorry okay no worries that's okay we're
gonna have these kind of teething issues
that's why again it's the joy of being
the first session of the week
so into the dispatch hybrid meeting
giving myself a healthy four minutes
just to run through the agenda and take
any agenda bash comments so you can see
that we've got a bit of flex time today
and but we have five presentations
flashing between either 20 minutes or 10
minutes for various items
um
and then we have the art area session
going on after that which is why murray
is at the front and has to say that this
whole session sorry murray just for the
kind of appendage bit to give updates
from the arts area
so we just paused here so there's any
agenda bashing keeping a beady eye on
the queue
in the room and on the techo
jonathan rosenberg
hello uh jonathan rosenberg five nine
uh it's not on the agenda and i don't
think we'll have time but i submitted a
draft called spin there's been a lot of
discussion on the list
if we don't get to it here i do want to
let people know there's a mimi buff
today
that's one of the
side meetings
so we'll try and do some discussion
there and i do ask if there's any time
at the end
left over anyone interested like to
discuss this topic thank you it's we do
mention it during the upcoming meeting
stuff
great thank you jonathan okay any other
comments before we dive right in
um first on
the presentation slides it's binary
application record encoding from jury
and we have got in the notes and the
links to the slides links to existing
messages and discussions
otherwise we'll just invite him to
come up and present
hello so it's up to me i think hi yeah
jerry would you like me to drive the
slides for you or would you like to do
them yourself
if you can i don't know how to do that
in each system so i'm sorry
okay no that's okay that's all
give me a second
yeah so uh hello everyone uh my name is
siri lasak and i will present binary
application record encoding or
shortcut
please next
so the first what is bare it's a
message encoding this is binary it
scores
data into the binary uh that are then
used to
store these data on or transmit these
data the original author is through the
valve
the main contributor of the updates is
victorian erwinger and i
do
connect all these uh awesome
contributions into uh together and uh
now presenting and trying to
standardize this uh this protocol
yes next please
so uh
what are the goals of parents
well first concise messages
then
the schema this is well defined and
and so the broad compatibility
programming environments well i guess
that all the encodings
are trying to do this
and the
important thing is the simplicity of
implementation
next please
so
the use cases for bare where
well
in the internet of uh services or
internet of things or these applications
the communications
the communication is really important so
you need some protocol to communicate
these
these messages there are plenty of these
communications
encodings and so on
the bare
as
we saw in the goals has concise messages
simply uh simplicity of implementation
and is used to communicate between these
web services or communicate
between the the internet of things
devices or
to store some uh some tokens uh into the
into file systems and
and uh so on so this is some use cases
of
of the bare
uh encoding
please next
yes well so this was in short
introduction what is bare
and
how it can be used
and now uh i would like to present some
some feedback
in the dispatch mailing list up to today
i haven't read the the feedback that was
sent today so i'm sorry about that
and the first uh
was
the comparison into cb or r
o r uh concise binary object
representation well
regarding this question i would like to
say that the cbor uh is based on json
which is itself the text based
uh and
the
main difference between cbor and bara in
my opinion is that cbo r contains the
schema because it has the legacy of json
format
and try trying to be compatible or json
in binary world
then these are kind of
different in this specific
things this is the main difference i
would say
the uh
there are
more differences but this one is the
domain i think
so please next
uh yeah there was another feedback about
the schema language i
don't think that i understand it
correctly and there were no replies
and replies to to
explain that so maybe this would be to
the discussion
please next
yeah well one of the feedbacks was the
request for measurements
between cbor
well i
did performed
some
tests
with the scripts that is available on
the on the link the slides
in fact it was a
kind of uh
kind of data structures that were 1000
messages
in one list that
showed or
that was corresponding
orders in
some
uh
imagina
imagined uh
shop or eshop
and uh just to come
to have some base measurement i used
json
as a un uh compressed and text based
format
then i
encapsulated or
encoded the the
whole list of messages in
using cbor and then
encoded using bare
and
the next measurement was the the same
but zipped
or
compressed form if
we can see the results in the bottom of
the slide
when we use
the the
length of the complete messages
is
comparable to the to the
row uh
raw data
when we use cbor there is some overhead
which comes
with cbor because
cbr messages contains the schema
of the messages and when we use json
there is even a greater overhead the
same apply for the for the compressed
versions
so it's like that
next please
um yeah just to say that paul hoffman
has joined the queue i don't know if you
want to take questions now or at the end
yeah and definitely
okay paul would you like to ask a
question
this is paul hoffman co-author of seabor
um
i think your previous slide in this
slide have a pretty significant error a
seaboard doesn't have a built-in schema
you can build one in if you want that
would be complete waste of overhead here
i
looking at your example here i cannot
imagine how it would be twice as big
unless you tagged
every item saying this is the name this
is this which is
pretty much
not what anyone does in seaboard so um
again seaboard was not written to be
shortest it's written to be concise
that's very different
but i think your comparisons are pretty
off uh because you're trying to force
the schema into seaborg which is
doable but not necessary thank you
yeah great uh thank you very much i am
really sorry about that i will uh
redo the experiment and update the
threat email thread uh to be honest i uh
used the the cbo
r2
python package to this and just let the
default settings
so so there may be some some problem
with that
that i haven't find out i will uh i will
make note and dig
deeper into this problem and try to
try to
do the measurement again if it's okay
oh yes so yeah next slide
great well uh the thing
uh
the another feedback in the mailing list
was the comparison with already
well-known uh
protocols used uh
for
uh
for encoding the messages the examples
are avro protobufs captain proto thrift
and flood buffers
these were mentioned mentioned in the in
the feedback so uh the first and most
important thing is that none of the
above is standardized and i think that
it makes sense to
have some standard
just because uh
these these frameworks or protocols are
widely used so so having a standard
that is
well defined
makes sense in my opinion
i would like to repeat what bara has
well concise messages without schema
which means the messages are concise
it has the octet aligned messages with
the little indian representation
when possible the encoding is ejective
and
the butter is designed with the
simplicity in mind
what i've already said so uh next slide
please please yeah this is the
comparison of the
of the types
used and available in encoding
it's
kind of uh
how to say well
i
take the the take the types which are in
the barre
so it's obvious that every types here is
in bare this is just to
show uh how the others
uh
how did others protocols
are uh compared to body so uh we can see
that for uh
integers unsigned integers integers and
flows this for numbers
there are
i'm sorry
there are some some types missing
first
you ain't and eind are variable land uh
integers or on-site integers
next slide three please
yeah this is other standard types
you can see that for example data with
fixed land are really rare to be uh to
be you used or to be available in
other protocols
next please
uh and the last are yeah lists optional
and and and
so on
yeah next
please so this is summary of the of the
comparisons
uh when i
was researching the protobufs i really
got lost with the variable and integers
i'm sorry maybe something is misleading
on the on the previous slide i did it
with
my best knowledge and
tried to do it as
uh
as best as possible
another thing is that uh standard is it
was uh
hard to find out which types are
supported
i needed some to sometimes dig deeper
into into the
documentation or
it wasn't in the supported types or
things like that
other thing is that
of course other protocols
uh
have uh
more types or different types or another
types like table types or something like
that
but
but it tries to keep uh
keeping being simple
and uh
all the other types can be built
up
on the basic types of
of the barracks so this is the reason
why some some types are omitted
yes and the last one
there is clear
distinction between
primitive and aggregate types which was
sometimes in bahrain which was sometimes
also difficult in the other other
protocols so next please
yeah
this was a question about the future
extension points but it specifies uh or
for for message uh
uh for future message consideration but
i
suggest to use
unions
where
all the available versions are defined
in union and later the precation
just means that the first
first message has manually set attack in
the union
next please
the
uh feedback was the using data
or time
well
we decided to not
use space special
data type time type in bare
because a lot can be done just by using
timestamp or unsight integer
or
using
other specifications for date times and
pairs the
the date time
next please
yes and this is
all
i wanted to say
regarding pare
uh
yeah
there
are questions regarding the progress
within
ietf which i am not
sure how this should
go and we'll be happy for her help so
great thank you thank you so much for
your presentation and so i'd invite
people to join the queue either in a
person in the room or using the client
if you're able to
just to summarize we've had some
messages on the list so far um
suggesting sibor and others suggesting
that siebel is not a competitor um and i
think richard barnes posted just this
morning saying sees that as kind of a
tls plus 10 so a small focus working
group with his suggestion so just to
remind participants keep your answers
focused on the dispatch question should
this work progress and if so in what way
should it progress so we'll just call
through the queue in the order i see it
so um rich richard barnes first
thanks christy um so yeah i i appreciate
the sentiment where this working's
coming from when we did mls we needed a
compact encoding we went with tls
encoding which is
as i said on the thread you know 90
similar to this
level like the way structure and code
actually could exactly contact us
we had extended tests a little bit
sympathetic the idea that there's um
need for attention um so
it seems like they're it's not
implausible to me that you know it would
be useful to have a spec that was that
just encapsulated the syntax as opposed
to you know if i was continuing
referencing section four of rfc 446
and to extend it a little bit to cover
you know what kind of what people expect
from a modern encoding system i agree
there's there's a bunch of other binary
encoding systems but we've had a bunch
of success with tls syntax and and
lightly extend light extensions and tls
syntax in the atf so all right my
inclination here probably to do a small
focus working group
uh if we're going to do anything in kind
of a small focus room starting to us
adding the 10 that we need here
okay thank you richard and you broke up
quite a bit during that so just to um
clarify i heard that you were supportive
of
forming a small focused working group um
if that's not correct can you please put
it in the java chat and i will correct
myself um okay eric rescaler next in the
queue
uh i think richard was saying he
supported a small working group to
standardize the tls syntax not this um
that's not actually my position so i'm
just trying to mirror it um so
um
i'm not particularly interested in
technical details i'm much more
concerned about the deployment situation
there are a giant pile of existing
things like this as you indicated
earlier and the fact that none of them
are standards i think strongly indicates
there's not a lot of interest in
standardizing this and for us to
standardize yet another one without any
evidence of real market desire it seems
like a real fail so my question to you
is
which large constituencies want to use
this technology
padan may you repeat your question
i said which large constituencies wish
to use this technology
uh well the body is uh used at least at
source hut
which is the the company of the creator
of the encoding and they use it for
for
web tokens for storing web tokens and
communication with client
so at least this is the use case which
which is
used today
sure i think we can agree that sourcehut
is rather smaller than facebook and
google
definitely
we also had the feedback in the mailing
list
of some some researcher that
that
tried to find out the the
uh
something different than json for
receiving data from the sensors
because of the measurements and this was
particular
case where yv uh allowed in the in the
standard the full compliance with i
triple e
floating
numbers for example so
okay well anyway my comment is this
should go nowhere until there's strong
evidence that people actually want to
use it and sourcehead is like not even
close to enough
uh
if uh you uh
or if if you need some some uh giant
company like google to backup this uh
specification i can't offer uh i can
offer nothing i don't have such a
company uh but uh
still i think uh there is a need for
standardization
of uh something similar to bare
uh that would be a simple
simply implemented which would be a safe
concise and uh
practically with the same uh same
properties
okay thank you
just um to say we only have a couple of
minutes left in this item so if
remaining participants can make their
comments short and i completely agree
that um implementation is an
implementation regardless of the size of
you know it doesn't have to be
anti-competitive in that kind of way of
having a certain size of implementer but
um i think the point might be more about
multiple vendors as is being discussed
in jabber um okay so next in the queue
is um cullen who's physically in the
queue i think
yes colin jennings thank you
i think it would be useful to
standardize something along these lines
at itf because we just constantly keep
repeating this and building it
individually in each protocol you know
we have a tls and then a slightly
different variant in mls and then and
then you know several of the drafts i'm
writing have a different sort of variant
so i think it would help us write drafts
to have a tool that we could pull out of
the box and use if we wanted obviously
we do sometimes use c boards sometimes
you use this sometimes other things so i
don't see any harm and i think it would
be useful to
pick uh maybe it's exactly this one
maybe it's something maybe it's the tls
one i don't really care but
to form something that we can refer to
and is standardized um and is roughly
along about the level of weight and
complexity that you're proposing here it
basically has exactly the sort of
characteristics of what you're proposing
i mean if there was no other proposals
i'd be fine with bear it looks it meets
my needs exactly um i wish it had a sink
like a half floating point thing like a
16-bit floating point too but i'm sure
we could add that
um so i think it would be worth doing
something like this i don't know if
there's a small working groups the right
way or whether we should you know have a
bake off between several of the
proposals that could be used and see
what people want to want to go forward
with uh but i'd be in favor of having
something thanks
thank you
and we just run through there's someone
in jabber agreeing with you as well and
barry you're next
this is barry lieber um
first i'll say i agree with what uh
ecker said
the overhead in the ietf to just to
standardize one of these things is high
and we really need to see that that we
need it that it it's going to be adopted
um and that there's a pressing need for
it before we get into that so i have
comments from two different roles i am
one of the co-seabor co-chairs now i
have not spoken with my co-chair but i
would support discussing this in
seaboard i think uh paul's comment kind
of raises the
issue that this should have been chatted
about in seabor
to see what it what it adds whether
cyborg can be enhanced whether
it makes sense to proceed with
body or whatever it is
so
i think we should start the discussion
there
and as the
former ad who ad sponsored seabor
i highly
recommend not ad sponsoring anything
like this ever again that this really
needs to go through some sort of working
group whether it be seabor or a new
working group that we set up for the
purpose
but i'll go back to saying that i stress
what ecker said that we really need to
make sure we have a need for it before
we go through the effort
thanks
i will thank you barry
great thank you just um to our remaining
participants if you could be extremely
speedy in your comments um otherwise
i'll cut you off because we have a full
session today okay um john clenson
you're up next
i i
agree with barry and
ecker uh but i wanted to take a slightly
different cast on this
uh which is it every additional one of
these uh channeling marshall roles is an
interoperability problem because it
scientists offer a different direction
um and uh
and i i worry about the need for this uh
i worry about the compression arguments
in a world in which we
have the kinds of bandwidth we do today
and and the cheapness of storage we do
today
although i'd be happy to hear the way
that doesn't apply here
uh but uh
but if we're going to do anything of
this type i would rather see
an irtf group or an art area
charter and study effort or design team
to bring the various advocates of these
various formats together and see if they
can agree upon something
a single standard for these for this
class of things would probably move us
forward starting that discussion in
seaboard would be fine
but uh but moving off in all different
directions with more and more of these
is is a challenge for operability
and not helpful for the internet thanks
just to clarify you think the work
should go forward in some form
possibly through
a new group
and
um davidskenazi google uh so plus one to
the
folks that said this before the reason
that we have like
17 different non-standards in this space
is that every company
builds their own to fit their specific
needs and those are slightly different
from one another and that's why google
has protobuf for example and what google
hasn't like moved to standardize it here
because we want to keep change control
and modify it if we feel like it
so if source
wants its own format that's totally fine
it can use it
but unless there is a specific need from
other vendors i don't see
any reason to progress this in the ietf
so the other vendors don't need to be
the size of google obviously but there
needs to be
market interest from outside of one
specific vendor so my
personal thought on the dispatch
question is
do not progress this unless there is
interest from multiple folks interested
in implementing
okay thank you very much
so that's the end of our review
[Music]
um but just to say that what i'm hearing
so far and what i've seen on the list is
not a good fit
um
it doesn't necessarily have to be this
specific proposal and um we need to see
more um interest from rather than just
from one single participant so um
okay we'll move on to the next item and
refresh that at the end if you disagree
if i will leave
in chapter thank you very much jerry
thank you
okay so next up we have braun and i
think sheeping you're running the slides
all right thank you
hopefully when this appears in just a
second
no
i'll try and make this one a little bit
quicker and hopefully we can catch up
some time
hi kirsty could you please continue
i have some trouble
yeah sure no problem sorry bro
that's okay
cool there we go next slide please
let's let's get through this fairly
quickly i think describing these
situations fairly easy
basically you want to send a file from
party a to party b
but neither of them are guaranteed to be
online all the time so you have to store
it somewhere in between
ideally that third party that you're
storing the file with or random large
blob of data doesn't need to see the
content of it so you would prefer to
encrypt it
but then you have the issue of how do
you tell the receiving party
how it's encrypted and how to decrypt it
next slide please
sorry this text a little bit small but
ideally party a creates and encrypts the
blob up uploads the encrypted data
somewhere
tells party b
via
the the most
easy to read and easy to to use way
here's how you decrypt this when you've
downloaded it
and then party b downloads it
so this this slide is lots of noise
which you can read later next slide
please i'll show the the
diagram of traffic flow because that's
probably the easiest here
so
the tricky bit here is you have the uri
has to contain the key when it's sent to
party b and then not contain the key
when it's sent through to the file store
as party c because in that case it's
gone over the wire it's gone in logs it
can be stored and the data can then be
decrypted and we don't want party c to
ever see
the plain text
so
the question is how to do this next
slide please
oh yeah first i put in this
obviously it'll take time to get to
something like this but i'd like it to
be something that we can work towards
over time it's better if it's
standardized obviously there's been
heaps of non-standard versions of this
every messaging protocol has something
for this
so that's why i thought this makes sense
to come to the ietf the reason i came to
it in the first place is i want to
implement
large file attachments with email which
means putting a uri
somewhere in a mime part saying download
from here what we have at the moment is
that the uri has put as a link in the
html version of the body with
little or no annotation to say this is
an attachment at all but you can click
on it you can download it in whatever
email receiving program you have
i want the same thing
but without the place you're storing it
having to be able to see the plain text
as well
and that means it needs to be at a low
enough level that it's embedded in the
libraries rather than in every single
receiving program and so you can pass
the uri around as if it's plain text
and any program can then access it using
the low-level libraries
the issue here of course is that nothing
does that yet and unless it's a standard
nothing will do it
and so we'll wind up having to wrap
every single uri in every single little
format in the same way
i think the next might be the last slide
which is an example of usage the next
slide please
on the justice league is in the queue
uh questions at the end i think
okay then we'll carry right on
so oh yeah so possibilities for design
i have no ideas um this is not my area
of expertise i'd love someone else to
take on this work
and i will help you if i can but yeah on
the last slide i have an example of yet
another place
where this would be useful that's not
the use case that i had so go to the
last slide
and this is an example of a v card that
i pulled from online and it has a link
to a photo and the photo is value type
uri
i would love to be able to replace this
with something that says link to a photo
and the server where the photos stored
can't see it
and that
to back port this into every single
format with separate encryption keys
very very difficult but if you could
just say a uri
gets downloaded and either has
it it's just plain text from the server
and downloaded plain text over https
sure so you've got
transport encryption but you don't have
encryption on the server or you have
encryption on the server and it's
downloaded as encrypted data and then
decrypted locally with a key that is
embedded in the uri then you can just
pass uris around and use either case and
that's all i've got
so questions comments
thank you thank you ron for ever showing
your work
if people in the room are able to it
would be very helpful if you could scan
the qr code event that should allow you
to register the meeting properly and
help us with our cue management and
first in the queue is ted hardy
uh thanks everyone uh
thanks ron for the work i actually got
in the queue to ask a scope question so
it's a little bit late um but uh back on
slide four uh it looks like you had a
party a a party b and a server but it
wasn't clear what happened if you also
had a party c d e f g h i j and k
were you expecting each of them to be
able to using the same decryption key
for it the v card would tend to indicate
that that was the case but in that
situation
it's sort of hard to figure out how any
of those people can't reford it
to party c to allow party c to have
access to it so if you could just
clarify this scope that would be useful
yeah i think realistically
if you get a copy of the url with the
key you are party b
if you don't get your party c there can
be one or n of each of these parties
so there's the party that has the blob
and doesn't have a copy of the key and
there's the party that has a copy of the
key and the key can be considered a
small version of the large data really
conceptually
so
if you get the key
then you can see the content if you
don't have the key you can't say the
content
okay uh so in in a situation like that i
think one of the things you've got to
consider is whether you're you're you're
actually better off
uh associating these as two uris which
have a relationship uh so you could have
like a uri that says this is the
um this is the place where you retrieve
it and a different uri like a data uri
that contains
uh the decryption key that you want to
send so that you actually then can use
multiple different paths to give the
data uri without necessarily always
including it in
the uri which is is used along uh the
path that that part ec has um but i i
think
my question for that would be how do you
pass that around in the existing
channels that
accept exactly one uri
uh so
that
you that's a
everything in in
in in computer science can can be solved
with one more layer of indirection you
create a uh yeah i love carrying them
both but the the upshot to this is i i
really feel like
what you're describing here um
doesn't have very
strong confidentiality characteristics
in the multi-party case
uh so i think you you'd really want to
write a draft for the security
considerations where you're describing
what it is you're expecting
the
the characteristics of the
um
confidentiality or or
other characteristics you're getting out
of encrypting this data would be because
i think yeah absolutely
it's
from the slides to figure out what it is
this would deliver thanks yeah now this
is very early stage and it's mostly just
working out is this something the isf
wants to do and if so where
where should it happen um
there's a lot more design work to do
ted are you able to just answer that
question
in the idea
i interest i don't think that there's
it's people to answer that question
without a draft that describes the
security properties so i would say
uh the dispatch answer would be not yet
yeah okay so my my answer to that i
guess since it's probably worth
answering is that
the confidentiality here is basically
party b can leak the key to whoever they
want to um if party b doesn't want to
leak the key we want to make it easy for
them to not accidentally leak the key to
party c that is that is the main
confidentiality requirement here rather
than really really strong
confidentiality which is the same as if
you sent them the raw file they could
leak it to whoever they want
but we don't want them to accidentally
do it easily
thank you very much bronn okay um we
have john mavine in the queue and i'd
encourage people on jabba if you have
comments or opinions on the dispatch
outcome please join the queue which
we'll be cutting shortly so john levine
over to you
yeah
um as i'm sure you know this is not a
new problem we have message external
body going back probably 20 20 years and
i think
and which
i think it was important back when email
had to be tiny and then when the email
sort of got medium-sized then people
started putting in attachments and now
we've come around again to the point
where the files have gotten bigger than
the mail servers again
and i think this actually could be
addressed
so long as you are willing to
restrict its use to places where you
have mime bodies it will be pretty
straightforward to extend message
external external body to do this but
you know basically you'd add some more
stuff to the external body with the keys
and the stuff and we already have the
syntax to have a url elsewhere in the
message that refers to the external body
if you want people they will link to it
um so i bought it i would want to try to
see if we could make that work first
because trying to invent a new york a
new uri format that is like well this is
a url but it also has passwords and
stuff in it i think that would give
heartburn to the people who worry about
um
uri syntax i i really don't want to do
it at that level because then we've got
yet another baroque custom format that's
only in one place for handling this and
every other place that you do uris needs
to the same thing so i would love to say
that whether it's
unencrypted data at the other end or
encrypted data at the other end
you can ask your system library to
please fetch this data make the
transformations required give me the
plain text
so it's basically
adding
adding a decryption key to you to a
general uri yes okay
in a way that doesn't get sent to the
server automatically
does that affect your view on the
dispatch outcome sean
um
i still think it's a problem worth
solving i do but i i do think now we we
want to
but you know but basically ted and i are
both saying like
we heard fairly different things that
ted has issues of who who can decode it
i have issues of is this is this a mime
type or is this a uri
so i think i mean
it definitely is
if there were an appropriate working
group
since it came from email i suppose it
could go to one of the email emails i
don't think an email working group is
the right place for this yeah
i really don't yeah i guess and i don't
i don't think an email working group
should even be trying to do this work
in the
my
headers necessarily i think this it's a
better place to do it inside the uri if
we possibly can but anyway
i do think it's worth it's it's worth
doing because i agree with ron that
people do people have hacky ways of
passing around files that are too big
too big to embed all the time
okay thank you so you think it's worth
doing more detail needed perhaps a draft
great um eric for schooler you're next
in the queue
yeah i think this is generally worth
doing um as an aside i think that um the
https plus blah blah blah is like don't
do that but um yeah like i said i don't
know much about this yeah sure what
happened i this gentleman we're solving
um i'm not as concerned as ted is about
the um security properties i mean like
they are what they are but that's if we
just set the thing as you say if you're
just something in the body be the same
so um so it doesn't really bend me out
of shape that much um in terms of
location i see mark donnie himself
behind me um it seems like probably
this seems pretty small so i would tend
to think http i know it's not quite a
great fit for http but we've already
kind of like done a bunch of some more
crap with like you know encrypted bodies
and stuff so it seems like it kind of
sort of belongs um
uh i suppose i suppose there's an http
it may have to be a new working group
which is like kind of heavyweight um but
mark may have a different opinion yeah
there was a comment on the mailing list
that the tigris working group might be a
place as well
yeah
if you if you if you wanted to be like
bogged down in secrets forever secret i
think tigress has got like a much like
bigger kind of remit so i mean maybe
there's some way to carve this off but i
worry it's going to get clogged onto the
bigger thing but i don't feel strongly
about it
okay thank you very much we'll cut the
key there and say nottingham you are in
the queue
that's the disembodied head hello
oh good i'm here oh good
um yeah i i um mark nottingham i
kind of feel like this is an area that
that is
prone to over engineering if we're not
careful
uh the the most you know if you don't
want
if you want to communicate a key with
the uri but you don't want to send it on
the request the most obvious way to do
those fragment identifiers as you saw
and in in
you with the uri is the fragment
identifiers defined by the format so
define a format with a fragment
identifier um as i said in in chat
uh i think the important part here to
satisfy a lot of concern is
uh to describe the security properties
of that thing in in the draft and we'll
see where where we where we get from
there um that that to me seems like the
most straightforward way possible i feel
like if we we throw this to uh other
venues or other approaches we might come
up with an over complicated solution
cool can i ask you to help me with this
one
yeah but here's the problem we live in
the same city i can i can get that
that's fine
all right let's do that when i get back
super thank you very much brown for
presenting your work i think there i was
hearing um that a bit more details
needed to understand the scope of the
problem but the problem is certainly
worth addressing and a couple of
potential avenues going forward
depending on the detail that comes from
that draft or a bit more scoping
okay if you disagree with that then
please uh do raise it in jabba and we'll
summarize at the end of the session as
always so thank you very much and
handily we've got mark nottingham here
ready to present his draft um and
sheeping is driving the site for us so
off you go mark thank you
thank you um
so this is going to be extremely short
ecker
do you have a question or
or is the video frozen
i think the video is frozen never mind i
just have this haunting image of ecker
standing at the queue waiting to speak
it's a little disconcerting okay so
uh this is gonna be very short i think
uh this is about a draft that i wrote uh
i think now a couple months ago privacy
considerations for web feed readers next
slide please
um so uh
people have have kind of
assumed that that web feed you know web
feed so rss adam that sort of thing are
dead that they're not really interesting
anymore uh in my experience and from
talking to people that's not necessarily
true next slide
um
on the consumption side there's a pretty
vibrant ecosystem of different feed
readers and different consumers uh that
have built some sort of feed reading
capacity into them
there's your standard kind of desktop
feed readers there's online feed readers
there are products that aren't
feed centric that also use them in
really interesting ways for example
the kind of top middle shell looking
logo there is devin think which is a
kind of uh
a very interesting academic tool
for aggregating information that uses
feeds extensively if you choose to use
it that i happen to use quite a bit
next slide
on the producer side i think most people
are aware that there are a lot of feeds
out there
um still
there's still a lot of sites that
produce them you know by default either
because the underlying
tools uh generate them or because they
have some constituency for that um to
get some sort of metric on that and and
just because i was interested i wrote a
little tool to scrape uh the people you
follow on twitter to see how many of
their profile urls had feeds and it
turns out that for most people that i
checked about a third of the profile
feeds of the people they followed
actually had uh sorry profile urls had
feeds which was really really
interesting to me that that you know
there's this latent kind of you know
ecosystem of feeds out there that is
just waiting to be used if people bother
to use it uh next slide
and and that to me is is kind of a bit
of a theme i think for for how i think
about this you know the feeds web feeds
are our latent platform on the internet
they're they're out there people don't
think about them a lot
but they're still used every day and
they're still available
and
next slide
you know
when i say platform i mean things like
you know what people call the web
platform so this this you know ecosystem
that you can build on top of the the
obvious you know big one out there being
the web of course uh next slide
but unlike the web feeds aren't really
advertising driven they have a lot of
really unique properties as
compared to the web the information you
get in feeds has a different tenor
because it's not able to be you know
advertising driven usually next slide
and so that makes me think what can be
done to improve and protect that
platform how can we
uh bolster it so that it's more useful
to the people who want to use it it
hasn't gotten a lot of love from the itf
for for several years now but but
what can we do to change that i guess
next slide
and so that's what led me and that's
kind of the thinking behind this draft
um it's a draft talking about what are
the privacy considerations for this
platform you know when you're you're
making requests when you're handling
content how should a a a feed reader uh
what in in http uh terms would be a user
agent how should it behave regarding
user privacy
uh next slide
and i think that that's all i have at
this point this is very very early stage
i probably could have taken this equally
easily just to the uh apps area because
sorry art area because uh i just want to
kind of give people a heads up that i'm
thinking about this and starting to talk
to people about it
um i'd love to hear any feedback people
have
from a dispatch standpoint i think it's
too early to dispatch anything like this
to another place but i would love to
talk about maybe
getting a mailing list or something like
that so i just i'm just
mostly this is just a heads up but also
i'm curious to hear if anybody has any
feedback or or any kind of comments
about it
and my video is frozen because zecker is
still just standing at the queue so i
can't see the room
i found him
okay come on i think i have to reload
the page to unfreeze the video
unfortunately that's okay um folks any
comments questions support for a mailing
list disdain a mailing list
absolute outrage at the creation of a
mailing list thank you paul hoffman and
we'll get other people joining the cube
paul hoffman off you go
paul hoffman surprised that i'm not
seeing more sport i definitely support
this um when we did adam hub you know in
the paleolithic era there was a lot of
interest a lot of stuff happened it
became invisible but as mark said is
still there
um adding privacy even talking about
privacy would be a good thing because
this is definitely part of the ecosystem
still
um it's not like we we're trying to do
an art i assume mark is not trying to
make this more important and you know
web 3.5 or whatever um but just you know
something to say we
you know we started something we should
we should keep working on it in a
privacy level so definitely interested i
think a mailing list would be a
reasonable start and um
if if it needs to be a working group i
think it can be uh you know an easily
set up with later but a mailing list for
this and talking about other
privacy issues
especially across formats would be just
fine thank you
comments
no
yes so we could go to the meeting list
for more discussions
yeah okay thank you
thank you very much
presenting mark yep so i think the
outcome there again disagree in java if
this is wrong but it sounds like we
would create a mailing list for further
discussion
um
and a couple of plus ones they're
starting a list and seeing how much
energy there is and hoping it will get
people
thinking about rss more so super
move on to our next presenter
hello welcome can everybody hear me okay
closer closer all right that's why i did
it all right thanks everybody good
even closer how about
that this is why we tested is that good
a little better right good awesome hey
thanks everybody for having me today
online i got bradley peabody with me
other co-author of this today we're
going to talk about new uuid formats
really it's new uid versions next slide
please
so one of the a couple of the problems
with rfc 4122
is that
the main timestamp based uuid suffer
poorly from database index locality
problems
the uuid version one that we call it has
a very uncommon epoch choice the
gregorian epoch which goes to a
timestamp length of 100 nanoseconds
which is pretty odd right and then to
further compound that problem they split
the epoch up into a weird a weird way
sorry get my hands out there and it just
causes all kinds of weird issues so
we've taken an examination of that and
figured out a different way to do it and
we actually found a lot of people
internet who are untangling that epoch
and just slapping a version 4 on it so
we're going to try and standardize that
as version 6. so the people who are
doing this and
want the benefit of it have a place to
do that in a standard track
we've also got some
security concerns that we want to
address such as things like mac
addresses in the uuid
and using cryptographically secure
pseudorandom generators
and then
we need some better clarifications
around uuid generation versus uuid
storage in terms of things like
databases and overall just a lot of
clarifications around little things like
big indian versus little indian stuff
that the errada's have an opened on 4122
and we've kind of tried to address as
many of these as we could in this update
to
4122 under some of our new versions and
i'll go through those real quick real
fast next slide
okay
so uui version six like i said is it's
the time based input it's the same as
uuid version one we're just not
swizzling around the bits we're taking
the timestamp as it is
that hundred nanosecond gregorian epoch
and we're laying it down and then the
rest of the uid layout is exactly the
same and this is something that many
many many
places have been doing and they either
put like a version zero on it which is
weird or they throw it as a version six
so it looks like it's a random address
but that's all we're doing with the
version six so we're just labeling what
other people are doing out there right
now and giving them a place to do it
officially we also make the subtle hint
to try and not use mac addresses but
we're not going to outright say you
can't use mac addresses because if we
want to you know have a one-to-one
conversion and people want to swap from
version one to version six they can do
that under this pretty easily
next slide please
so version seven has really been the
focus right of this we've looked at this
and we've said what can we do better if
we were going to make a time-based uuid
right now and the obvious thing is to
use a better epoch which is the
well-known unix epoch and then it comes
into
questions like how long do we make this
what precision level do we make this and
there's been a lot of back and forth and
we ended up laying down a 48-bit unix
epoch with a millisecond time stamp and
the rest of the uuid layout is random
it's entropy and you can move the slider
left and right and if we move a little
bit more time stamp we get one side of
the field who's really angry if we move
it to the other way and give it you know
less time stamp the entropy folks uh you
know
both sides are very heated we laid on
and landed on millisecond time stamp so
that it's the most ubiquitous to
implement there's lots of libraries that
can do this the timestamp is very well
known it caters 99 of the use cases
next slide
for those other one percent of the use
cases those folks that want to use a
custom epoch they want to start
something right now and start counting
up time they want to use nanosecond
level they can use uuiv version 8 which
is every bit of this except for the
version of the variant
are for you to use in anything you want
this future proofs our spec allows
very custom uuids to have a space
experimental uuids to have a space
versus slapping a version 4 on it they
can do that under version 8. if you want
to take version 7
fork it and do whatever you want with it
you can do it within the space of a uuid
version 8.
next slide
lastly this is kind of an oddball uuid
but we're just writing down and saying
that the maximum value for uuid
is being defined in the spec which is
all bit set to a one 4122 sets the nil
uuid
as all bits set to zero we're just
writing down the opposite of that so
that library generators can actually
write this down and reserve it so you
don't use it in some weird way this is
for some needle and haystack operations
there's a github thread about why you
might use this
but we kind of have a small section
about this maximum uuid
next all right so we've done a lot of
prototyping we've done a lot of data
modeling we've been working on this for
i mean
brad's been working on for about three
years i've been working on for about two
years we have taken everything we've
done with library implementers
prototypes and and put this into kind of
a swan song to the implementers out
there we've solved a lot of problems and
whether it be you using
version 7 or making your own under
version 8 we have a really nice list of
what you should do or should not do some
of these are like time stamp granularity
reliability source precision and
accuracy fuzzing altering smearing
padding or truncating right your uuids
let's say you can only generate 32-bit
unix timestamp how do you make that work
in the 48-bit
space
monaticity encounters for when things
need to be laid down in a database in an
exact order how do you do that what's
the placement that makes sorting really
nicely how do you generate those or seed
those from the beginning how do you
increment those is it a random increment
or is it a linear increment
and
other topics like distributed uuid
generation across multi
nodes that may not talk
collision resistance mechanisms local
and global uniqueness csr
unguessability through csp rng sorting
considerations opacity and introspection
database considerations we talked about
really briefly about how's the best
what's the best way to store these in a
database and then finally of course
security considerations we've gone at
great lengths to really put the last
half of this document as a
this is what you should do and this is
the best way to do it based on all of
our research
and then last slide i just want to talk
real quick about
do we have a need yes there's a lot of
energy from our community on the next
generation of uuids a lot of people like
uuid version seven and you can see that
yes column in the middle almost
everybody is implementing that i have a
lot of uuid version eights out there
that i have to find that are folks who
really liked what we had maybe in a
previous draft and we tweaked something
and they said i'll just i'll keep that
i'll put it as an eight and then they
just throw an eight on it and gives them
the space to do that there's more
implementations but those are on version
two or version one of our draft so
they're slowly being updated but you can
see there's a lot of different languages
there's a lot of different folks who
have contributed to this and there's a
lot of energy around getting that uuid
out there and standardized in a new way
and that's it i'll take questions
comments or concerns
okay folks um
thank you very much guys for your
presentation
give people time to join the queue
either in the room or virtually any
questions comments and don't forget the
dispatch question should this work go
forward and if so in what form so first
in the queue we have david scanasi
thank you davidskenazi google um thanks
for this presentation like that was
exactly what i like what we were kind of
looking to hear and so thank you clearly
there's interest in this and clearly
you've done a lot of homework uh i would
like to see this published it sounds
useful
as far as
dispatching it um
if is there if there is an ad willing to
de-sponsor this that might be the
simplest path forward but otherwise
maybe a very small tightly scoped
working group with a single deliverable
would work um i'm just trying to find
like the least resistance way of doing
this but i think this should get
published
thank you we
definitely scoped this to fix exactly
the problems we needed and took anything
else out of 41 22 and set it to the side
and said somebody else can fix those
problems this is what we want to focus
on
okay so strong support there any
other supporters any questions
comments we're going to need more
support than just one person here
you can see colin jennings in the queue
colin jennings uh
you know i i support the idea of forming
a working group to sort of deal with the
care and feeding of uu ids like if you
go and list look at all the traffic that
these guys had about the nuances of this
it's it's one of those things with a lot
of subtle complexities that sort of
break things like who would have thought
of the database and you know i mean
there's all these issues so i think
having a long-term sort of place where
uh if any of these updates come we get
the knowledge in one place that sort of
knows the history of why things are the
way the way they are and what went right
and what went wrong is probably pretty
good and there's a lot of errata on
those drafts too that just point out
like wow like we probably should be
doing a little better i'm keeping those
as
well maintained standards i believe
might be the words that come to mind uh
so i'd be in favor of doing something
that allowed this to be a
well-maintained standard
thank you thank you very much
thanks alyssa cooper so i was just
looking at the history of 4122 which
also looks like it was 80s sponsored but
i wasn't here at the time um so i don't
know ted or
very
people who remember um if that was a
good choice
but um agree with colin that
it might be that that wasn't a great
choice and that's why like we have a
pile of erada and other other things so
it's worth like learning from that
experience and
having that inform what we do next
thank you very much
and there's a comment in the chat from
lucas howdy just saying this works seems
valuable if only for uuid version 4.
um eric risk you're in the queue
yeah um so this does seem like a
reasonably compelling argument that
something needs to be done um just
looking at the body of work here i think
would be an appropriate day to sponsor
it um like does much work behind it
should be working grouping if it's a
very fast working group because
that's like how things get handled
okay then um
murray's noted that rfc four one two two
is a d sponsored by ted so it seems like
the
mood of the room is either um that the
work should go forward um and it should
go forward in the least friction full
way possible so um either a small
tightly sketched working group or an ad
sponsorship um
murray as the 80 in the room any
comments on your view or something for
us to pick offline and discuss
um
i think probably the next step that i
would like to see is who would be
willing to help develop a charter for
this
stroke
so as soon as i ask anyone to sign up
and actually do the work
um
i guess we can ask on the list for for
help developing a charter but that's
sound that's i'm hearing that's probably
the preferred way to go
and i can i can take up um
whatever the responsibility rule for
that is
yes thank you i can see um a couple of
comments in java as well where my group
sounds good or working group is the path
um and there maybe there's some
discussion to be had about whether it
should just be for this draft or if it
could be a more general long-term care
for uuids and but that would be worked
out in the charter i suppose so
i think there's no more comments no more
people in the queue so we'll just say
thank you very much kaiser i think we
have our dispatch outcome and thanks
very much for taking the time to present
to us here
and so we move on to our last agenda
items today the discarding priority of
rpp video packets there's been quite a
bit of discussion on the list about this
um
so we'll just stop sharing the slides if
that's the issue thing and i can share
the
new slides
there we go
and just hold it
can you hear me clearly yes cool
all right um my name is legendo i'm
going to present less discarding
priority rtb video packets
in this presentation i mainly want you
to
want to show you that you know the
importance of the packet payload would
decide the discarding priority of the
packets when network congestion happens
so
then i also want to discuss how to
achieve this prioritize discarding when
network congestion happens through the
dsp field and mapping next slide please
um as all we know that rtp is a protocol
dedicated for transport of real-time
video and you know audio streams and are
typically on top of udp
so there is no guarantee of packet
delivery um rtp packet formats for
different video codecs have been
specified
in ietf for you know various
codecs
and by reading those drafts i i found
out that
they are actually um
priority indicator of the packets in
those
rtp headers or say
um
they called an ar headers so i will
briefly talk about those in the next
following slides next slide please
uh so for for h.264
the coded video data is organized into
the in our units and then
the rtp packet for h.264 video inherits
the same and air unit header so it has
two bits here called an ri
field it indicates the relative
importance and transport priority of the
layer unit determined by the encoder so
the higher value of the mri shows the
higher importance of that packet or
another unit
and they have different types of
[Music]
packet payload structures for a single
on our unit so there is only one snail
unit inside
the payload and then that another field
would be associated with a single air
unit for aggregation packets
there are multiple in their units into
aggregated into a single rtp payload so
the value of the
rnri is the maximum of the old air units
carried in aggregation packets and then
for the fragmentation units
it means that a single nri
on the air unit actually is fragmented
into multiple rtp packets so
as you can imagine all fu packets will
have the stem and ri
value
um
and from quoted from this draft so
for more important
units
needs to be better protected against the
transmission loss of packet dropping
than less important than our units
let's go to the next slide um and then
yeah just on the slide change sorry um a
quick reminder time you remind her that
master oh okay okay i'll go quickly for
the next
few months
to wear a mask
oh okay to wear a mask if you're present
in the room that's part of the ietf
requirements unless you have an
exemption for it
so to put on a mask
okay do you want me to take the mask
right now no no you're fine i'm fine
okay it's for people in the room okay
all right
okay and and then for svc um
it also has this mri two bits to
indicate the relative importance and
transport priority
additionally it has three bytes in the
entire unit header
which
includes the pr id which is called
priority id which has six bits and also
did qid and tid because
svc actually supports the different
levels of scalability
next slide please
and for
h.265
because it has improved sport of
temporal scalability over h.264
includes this tid which is three bits
so it indicates the temporal layer of
that packet belongs to so the lower
temporal layer means more importance
because it's the base layer it will be
used to predict other layers
so the ti
the lower value of tid means more
important of that packet
for layer eye it is now used in h.365 go
to next slide please
and so for h.266
it has the layer id and tid similar as
h.265 however uh yeah additionally
um similar to h.265 of course the tid
indicates the relative importance
and then has addition this layer id uh
which is six bits
uh it is
further indicates how important the
layer id is um sorry further uh
indicates how important this packet is
go go to the next slide
yeah um just to let you know there's
someone in the queue would you like to
take questions now or at the end of the
presentation
i can ask it now real quick uh just a
informational
uh comment there's a name sorry
mozinati uh cisco
mozinati cisco um
there's a draft in abt core that's close
to rfc
called video frame marking
that goes over a lot of these points
and uh what it basically does is it
normalizes across all of the codecs not
just the itu codex but also alternative
codecs like vp8p98v1
and it normalizes them into
um
a common format for describing
the the dependencies and the
the priority of of the temporal and
spatial layers
and so really all that's missing is
in your draft you can instead of
referencing every single codec you could
reference an rtp header extension that
carries that same information
um the difference is that you're jumping
all the way to
mapping that directly to a dscp
uh
priority and that's a that's a step that
um
we've had a lot of argument about before
about how to how to do that mapping and
so i'd suggest you separate those two
things one is identifying
the the layers and the varieties of the
layers very specifically and there's
already rtb header extension to uh to
surface that
codec agnostically and then mapping that
to a network priority is a separate
problem that i think
is probably better in like transport
areas yeah thanks for pointing out draft
yes i'm aware of that drafts and uh
before
of course after writing uh this
particular draft yeah i will definitely
refer to the draft or extension header
you were mentioning about later for a
later version okay next slide please
um and
in those drafts all mention the media
aware network element so it is the
element which is such as you know middle
box or application layer gateway which
is able to parsing those
rtp packet payload headers and even rtp
payload to reacting to
to the network congestion
um
but due to the explicit layering in
protocol stacked upper layer data and
headers are transparent to network layer
so the intermediate routers have no
access to those information go to next
slide
even though we have the media where our
nav nodes may be deployed in at ash or
certain routers in the middle of the
network but when network congestion
happens for those routers do not have
those you know media awareness
you won't be able to react to
to the network congestion properly to
discard those less important packets
so what we can do
go to lexi
we can actually um maybe using the
dscp to indicate the importance of those
packets
um
so the nri field has two bits tidbit
field has three bits
so scp value may be able to be mapped
because you know uh
as it has six bits maybe can be used to
map according to either the
iv value or tid value as well as the
video types
so the either the radio host or the
source
or the mae at the server domain edge can
do the mapping and set up the dsp
cp value for each rtp packet
then the discarding precedence of those
rtp packs can be determined when linked
congestion happens go to the next slide
so this is just you know print
preliminary consideration how to map
uh the dsc rtp
how to map those mri values into dsp
values according to
the video types
um and we will discuss those later um
let's go to the next slide
and also we have this kind of mapping
for the tid value
go to next slide
oh cool well thank you uh kirsten for
showing this slide for me uh so uh in
the email list magnus mentioned
list rfc
7657 so if in general uh you know quoted
from this draft marking packets with
different dscps would result in
different phps being applied at nodes
may uh generate reordering issues
however
so in large draft it recommends to map a
single network five tuples
use phps from a to a single f class
which means there is only three in each
f class there is only three dropping
precedence
so it would not be possible to map to an
ri or tid to a single f class
you know one is four
uh another is eight so single f class is
only three um
values and
um on the other hand actually udp is not
sensitive to or reordering the network
so maybe
we can use different dsap screws
corresponding phps enables reordering
within a single udp tuple
so what i was thinking maybe you know
instead of just mapped to a single f
class we can map to multiple af class as
i
mentioned in the previous two slides go
to next slide please
and
and another thing is about you know you
have to um
h.266 and h.265
uh svc you have the pr id which is six
bits which provides more granular
priority information about lab packets
and also you have
h266 the layer id also is six bits um
which again providing more discarding uh
priority information so many
many dhcp values are already being used
and could be um available so are there
any other ways to achieve this packet
level dropping precedence within follow
um maybe we need to consider other
solutions
um
you know if discarding precedence as
final granularity is considered to be
supported
okay um all right go to next slide
please
we got people in the queue do you want
to take questions now
oh uh
yes yes
okay all right so
obviously uh this is maybe relevant to
avt core however abt core is specified
is you know a major scope is to specify
and maintain payload formats for use
with trtp may not consider
how you know how to actually use those
values in the network layer
and um
i think the most relevant maybe the
transport air
area and working group
yeah let's all for my presentation i
will take questions
great thank you very much for your
presentation and we do have folks in the
queue please add yourself if you have
you on the dispatch question so first up
hi this is pete uh yeah it seems pretty
straightforward that the people who can
evaluate most of this are an avt core so
i would suggest taking
the document there as the dispatch for
this
and uh someone mentioned in the chat
room that perhaps tsvwg could take on
the dcsp bits
um and i think that would be fine but
avt core has the expertise to evaluate
this so you might as well take it there
in the first place right thank you for a
suggestion yes
thank you very much pete uh marcus
westbrook
yeah magnus westland here um
i i think i think avt core is a good
next steps and there maybe you can try
to
explain your use case for this and how
it actually relates because if you have
like the
mains
exist mostly in this type of different
centralized conferencing etc
if it's not iptv i wonder because
there's as i wrote in the latest email
there's multi-stream aspect of this
which makes
doing this across
all the media streams blindly is
unoptimized in many ways and
lose you more calls than doing it in the
media where an application aware way
so i think there's a question saying
what are you really trying to accomplish
here
what are you what do you actually need
so but i think abd core is a reasonable
place to discuss in this but it comes to
rp and the usage and architectural
question here yeah um so i mainly want
to you know to
use those bits in the network layer
uh when our congestion happens just to
randomly instead of randomly discarding
packets
it may
you know now if the routers is able to
know which packet is more important for
decoding end to improve the user's end
of quality
or quality of experience maybe it's
better to yeah
what's yeah i still think you need to
explain what application is in usage
because
to me it looks like in those application
i know that uses rtp
trying to do this in this way is
probably sub-optimal
so
yeah all right okay thank you
thank you
um
the uh
if the goal is to um
make sure that uh that delivery is
optimal then i don't think you want to
restrict your
your focus to just dscps
because what we found is that um
layer two can also create a lot of
problems um when it comes to
prioritization so
if you really want to
look at the delivery to be optimized and
what should be dropped you should also
look at
things like you know wi-fi
upstream priorities and even in mobile
networks you know look at the more
complicated ways that rands can can also
prioritize things so i don't think dscp
is really going to
give a lot of
benefits to especially since it's
usually not
carried through interoperably across a
large segment of the network um so if
you really want to optimize the
prioritization you need to look at all
network layers and see where priority
lives at all those layers and give some
guidance at each layer yeah yeah thank
you for commenting i agree like dscp may
have remarking issues so it won't carry
all the weight from end to end
um yeah i will probably need to consider
if there is other fields in the
ip
protocol which can carry this kind of
information that could be leveraged by
uh network nodes
thank you
thank you very much for questions
hey there's um quite a bit of
a saying
tsv working group so if you could
express your opinion on the dispatch
question and those options as well that
would be really helpful to people in the
queue thank you it's mira
yeah hi mia could have been i agree so
the for the dispatch option um going to
avt core or to um tcp wwg would be fine
um if you go there i want to add to
magnus comment that i think it's not
only about the use case it's only about
showing data that this is actually
improvement because
um usually the the video streaming is
adaptive so like you shouldn't have long
periods of congestion it's like a few
packet loss that you try to optimize for
not sure if you actually gain much
performance by that
yeah yeah i agree like for adaptive if
the network congestion can be fed to
information fat to the source it will
cut down the rate yes and i'm talking
about for like those short time period
where congestion is not aware to the
source if the network could optimize
this kind of packet dropping
yeah but like ideally that's really like
a very short period of time just like a
few packets and then there's also ecn
you can use to avoid packet drop at all
so i'm not sure that like this is the
best solution
yeah eason is also to reflect on our
congestion yes
okay thank you very much um next we have
omir shapira
hello i'm
sorry i cannot hear you
omar shapiro apple
uh
plus one to what uh
what had been said before that uh the
this pivots probably should belong to
traffic but to transfer but
additionally uh
the concept of service classes is
not
limited to video
other transport
streams may benefit from that
and
additionally
the notion that udp is not sensitive to
reordering may be true for some
protocols running on udp
but
i find it difficult to generalize for
example quick maybe
more uh sensitive to
uh
to reordering and the router may not
know the difference between quick and
rtb thank you yes thanks for coming i'm
aware of those issues yeah
thomas eckhart future way so to miriam's
comment of whether this is uh you know
important or not
um there have been you know um good good
results from the past shown that it
obviously is
valuable because the impact of losing
even a single packet of
a reference frame like an iframe in a
video stream may cause a complete
interruption blackout of a video stream
for a whole
group of pictures which for example in
something like dish networks has been up
to five seconds whereas
a similar loss of a packet for a
non-reference
frame like a pre-frame just causes a
blip that any good setup box can
hide from you so
there is a totally different degree of
impact of even very short packet losses
and you know even with ecn we've seen
that we can't completely avoid any loss
so i think you know managing that loss
in this manner is a highly valuable
thing to do especially the more you're
getting into real-time and non-delay
thanks taurus
thank you very much and just to say that
i'm hearing that it sounds like a lot of
support from this abg core and tsb
working group once the use case and
performance gains have been clarified if
you disagree with that summary please
come up to the mic and express that if
you agree then also please come up to
the mic or put it on jabba and express
that view next in the queue is jonathan
lennox
yes jonathan lennox um
yeah
to the dispatch point as an apt court
chair i say this is i think this would
be entirely in scope of abt car i mean
again with the dsvwg doing the diffserv
parts um to the use case point i think
um
it depends the um assumption the network
assumptions you get for like set-top box
streaming versus
interactive video conferencing are quite
different
and i think that if you're looking at a
set-top box streaming type use case i
think this might be more i mean i think
this might make more sense than um the
interactive video conferencing types
cases
um where you do have um typically you
have free transmissions and you have
much more
dynamic uh
codec adjustments um so i'm not sure
what somebody i guess that gets the
point of what your use case is here
thanks
thank you
okay thank you very much we have
exhausted you so just to summarize
um update those aspects and then take it
to av
and tsp working group for the dsp cpu
and specific aspects
um so that's the end of the
part of the
meeting at the moment so just to run
through a summary of the dispatch
outcomes which we will also email to the
list and make sure the minutes fully
reflect this and the bar a dispatch
outcome there's a possible working group
or discussion forum on this topic
because it repeatedly comes up but not
necessarily this exact proposal there is
a consensus that it needs to be um more
widely applicable and implemented more
widely than only one um party therefore
that outcome is to find more supporters
and return with this proposal possibly
others for working group scoping
on bronze item transparently decrypting
uris the outcome was that the work is
worth doing there are more specifics
that need detailing so it can be
properly assessed and sent to the right
place since we were hearing differences
between s mime or http kind of
similarities so come back with a draft
work to progress
on the web feeder reader dispatch
outcome very simple create a non-working
group mailing list on this topic
for the uuid dispatch outcome there's
some weak support for a working group
performing a tightly focused or a longer
term caretaker for uuids and maintenance
of the drafts and so that will go to the
dispatch mailing list to find volunteers
to form a charter and flesh out which of
those two options it would be and then
finally discarding priority of rtp video
packets the dispatch outcome was the use
case needs clarifying gains and
performance need clearly demonstrating
and then once those aspects have been
updated to take it to abt core and tsp
working group which for the dscp
specific aspects
so that's a rundown of our um dispatch
session today thanks to everyone who
presented it's always really nice to see
new work coming to the ietf really
grateful for you bringing your time and
effort to us and at this point we'll
shift into the art area portion of the
meeting
so i'll just share the slides and then
hand over to mary
thank you
thank you uh you can go to the next one
um i'm marie kucharabi one of your two
area directors francesca couldn't be
here because she is uh on maternity
leave
i was hoping to have a photo of a
newborn to all share with you but that
has probably not happened yet
um
a quick update on some meetings of
interest coming
of interest to this area we have you can
see the list here um the ones the couple
that i want to point out um
tigris is a brand new working group
meeting this week um
mock isn't going to attempt to create a
bar uh
it's a working group creating buff
that might also be of interest to this
area and we have the usual litany at the
bottom as well mimi i think
you wanted to say something we'll give
you a slot in aob after i'm done my
little bit
next please
um so
some just some comments from us next
slide please
uh errata
people in this room may or may not know
about errata it is a service a record
keeping service provided by the rfc
editor about documents that have already
been published but they need to have
some kind of correction made to them or
on the record so that people know there
are corrections that have been recorded
that you might need to know if you're
implementing this specification
they can be also folded in later on if
there's an update document done for uh
like a best document that you've seen
coming through they're used for
editorial mistakes and
if the document as published did not
correctly capture the consensus of the
working group you don't use a naradam
for saying i think it should be
something else
we will reject those
uh next please
these have historically uh the
atom once processed is either rejected
because it's wrong or improperly used
it's verified meaning we've confirmed
that this is true this should be
properly recorded and possibly processed
later the third state is hfdu which sean
turner says hold for the death of the
universe but it's
hold for document update wait for the
next version before you actually do any
something with it um these are often
left neglected and not actually
processed what you see here is the
number of unprocessed in each of the
three areas for art and its previous
versions are
apps and rye so we have a large body of
work that hasn't been looked at yet
this is just historically something that
we haven't paid much attention to but
they do need to get processed uh sooner
or later so
some of these art ones are for current
working groups and so you can actually
go and see if there's something here you
could help us process as working group
chairs or document authors and see you
may have been notified that there's one
filed against one of your documents
i'll be starting to process these slowly
myself as much as i can we can't rely on
the current working groups to worry
about errata from working groups that
are gone or documents that were
sponsored by ads and had no working
groups but
anybody who has
in a working group
where you could help us start processing
some of these on your own it would be
great working group chairs if you have
the bandwidth to do that
um
next slide please
any questions on errata before i go on
okay i didn't think there would be too
much of that um this is the usual call
for help for various roles within the
ietf and within the art area
we need more volunteers to do the work
that is that is uh the work of the area
um it's not always working group chairs
although that's the common thing that
we're asking for but um you know if you
want to be involved in reviewing uh
requests from ayanna registries of media
types is the big favorite one um
uh ned fried is no longer with us he was
the champion of that one for many many
years uh there's we're down to two
people one of them is me and i'm not
supposed to be doing them while i'm an
area director so it would be great to
have additional help if you're
interested in uh shepherding documents
he doesn't have to
working group chairs are not the only
people allowed to shepherd documents if
you want to try to get you introduced to
the process that way
talk to your working group chair about
being willing to shepherd something
working group secretary is a role that
doesn't always appear but uh
help the chairs by recording consensus
of of your meetings
um keeping track of issues in the
trackers that sort of thing
please volunteer for that area review
teams we have art art the art area
review team
could use more people
and of course working group chairs if
you're interested in learning more about
the mechanics of how the work gets done
here you want to be more involved in it
talk to your working group chairs talk
to me talk to any experienced ietf or
and we can we can point you out ways to
get involved or if you know someone who
might fit this description
we would love the extra help and to
breed new talent
next slide please
uh the art area review team i just
mentioned uh this is an extremely useful
to the area directors uh team of
reviewers that look at documents mostly
coming from other areas that are um that
may have aspects that touch art and
should get proper consideration i don't
remember the size of the current pool of
reviewers it's you can find it online
they do they've done 28 reviews for us
in the last three months about 91 total
in the last year
i looked to see if i could see credit
one person with having done way more
than everybody else but it is a pretty
fairly even distribution everybody's
done maybe three to four this year
um thank you to those people who provide
that service it is very helpful to us at
during document reviews
to have an extra perspective
and if you're interested in
participating in this
barry is here and he's the current
coordinator of art art and
he would love to talk to you
and uh last slide
go ahead sorry
so if you wanted to make a point
on this side barry go for it
this is barry lieber
well i guess i wanted to say something
murray said about the previous
slide also actually could you
kirsty can you go back this one
it was
oh yes volunteering as a working group
chair when i was an ad i was looking for
the same thing of course
and what i want to stress is that even
if
it's not necessarily that there's a
particular working group that needs a
chair right now that you can volunteer
for although that but also just let
murray and and
francesca or whatever your area
directors are um that that you'd like to
be considered as a working group chair
in the future when the need arises
because we're always looking for a pool
of people to call on
who might be new chairs who might not
have chaired for a while and that sort
of thing
and then back to the art art thing
what i try to do is
do a little
i look at the documents quickly first
and assign only ones that um
that look like they would benefit
particularly from an art area review so
unlike security directorate for instance
that tries to review every document
going through there are a lot of
documents that
in in internet area routing area in uh
with yang models and stuff like that
that i decide we don't really need an
art review of
so it's it's a pretty
low effort
thing it you just get a review assigned
to you
infrequently and then it's pretty easy
so please let me know if you are not
already on the list and you would like
to be
um and the ads would really appreciate
the extra help
we definitely do
and last slide i think is just to catch
up on uh
we have um folded the internet excuse me
the internationalization directorate
into the art area that was announced
about 10 days ago i think
the current reviews the
i18 ender used to conduct
internationalization framework reviews
for documents that need them eai unicode
and so forth um the current chair of
the 18 i18n directorate needs to move on
to other duties so we have folded them
in that has happened just in case anyone
missed the announcement
um
there is a breakfast for the art art
team which now includes both
organizations wednesday morning it's in
the agenda if you haven't seen that
we'll try to get some remote
participation because i think actually
almost none of the internationalization
people could make it this time but we'll
at least set up a laptop in the corner
or something like that so that they can
say hello and participate in any
conversation
uh any questions for for your solo ad
this time
i could do an open mic before the
plenary
um no that's it then thanks christy
thank you mary very brave to open
yourself up for a mini plenary in um
the art area meeting but seeing no one
in the queue and
no nothing in chapel either so we can
conclude the meeting give participants
in the room and online 14 minutes back
just to say thank you
oh no okay
can i have five minutes
give a preview on spin and ask people to
come to me me buff
okay
i'll do it from here yeah so uh i
submitted a draft called spin um but let
me give a little context on the problem
uh the problem we're facing is that uh
you know ietf has been working for
decades on interoperability for voice
and video communication
uh between different providers this has
been pretty successful
in some areas but has totally failed
when it comes to app to app
interoperability meaning like can you
make a
video call between say skype and
facetime you cannot can you send
messaging from wire
to signal no right no can't do that um
what's app to webex call no no
so none of that works um
and that's mostly for
business commercial reasons
uh there's a recently a new ray of hope
that such a thing might someday happen
due to some european regulation called
the digital markets act that recently
is passed or getting passed or something
of that sort and so in response largely
to that a bunch of folks i know rowan
wrote some documents and i wrote this
document called spin
that's poking at different things that
need to happen to provide a modern
solution for
voice video and messaging
interoperability between say uh
you know facetime and a skype or
whatever so
that's the topic of the spin draft there
seems to be quite a bit of interest on
the list we're obviously not going to
discuss that here in dispatch but there
is a buff called mimi it's a side
meeting
which is you know a buff with a lesser
room i don't know but it's a side
meeting uh today what time was it ron
4 4 p.m today
in which room sorry
philadelphia south so
downstairs mezzanine level so if you're
interested in this topic
uh we'll have this buff rowan set it up
we're going to try and largely frame up
a buff for next ietf or engage interest
and i'm particularly interested the hard
part of this is getting the big players
to adopt it so if anyone's here from
google's or apples or primarily the ones
that need to be interested in this thing
to make it successful i'm super
interested to talk to you please come to
that buff that's it thank you
thank you very much
jonathan
sorry jonathan said something which i
did not hears
is there remote participation in the
side meetings
yes says rohan mahi
all right
on the mimi mailing list
and in the side meetings portion of the
wiki i am now the rowan mahi translator
how sad that is all right thanks folks
thank you very much for sharing that and
yeah that was just what i was going to
ask if there's remote participation
webex details have been sent earlier
today on those lists and in those places
so thank you very much for bringing that
and um we'll give you now 11 minutes
back of your of your time thanks so much
for coming to dispatch as always thanks
for your energy and opinions in the room
on the mailing list and from virtual
participants as well so thanks everyone
have a nice evening night day morning
wherever you are thank you very much
[Applause]
left
thank you for bearing with me
then i can just do the same thing you
have to do while you're gone
but now that they're older
[Music]
let's see
you