and on that note
you're here in the ml core
and let's get started we haven't now uh
um i initially thought we'll finish
early but i suspect there are actually
several discussions that might require a
bit of more
time so
um
i thought we'll try to stay on top of it
and kick us you know if we're not doing
it quickly enough
right with that
i'm alexi thought this
sitting next to me
i assume you all seen note well um
i think pretty much everybody here is a
long time participant but this is just a
quick refresher
not well kind of contact be nice to each
other
and again be nice to each other
um
we have no taking is braun thank you
braun
uh we only have one set of slides which
is chess lights
just a quick reminder if you're in the
room please use masks when you talk to
microphone don't take them off uh
obviously doesn't apply to remote people
lucky people
um
quick recap of the agenda um
hopefully there is no agenda bashing
there are two uh
items for smtp spec
uh the first one about four clauses kind
of smtp slash applicability statement
but
um and then uh we would like to get
closure on a registration policy
yes john
this is a
a question rather than just a certain
agenda i know
but do you want to spend a few minutes
discussing the uh
the issue which should not versus must
not with 550 codes that's been on the
email list
oh the one that brought on the mailing
list
yeah
shall we do it at the end if we have
time
okay
good point if
somebody
i i just don't want it i don't want to
twist those cracks by accident otherwise
i don't care
okay uh
can you remind us at the end
if we don't run out if there is an end i
will certainly i try to remind you
okay thank you john
so we have a fair amount of tickets for
applicability statement
actually uh while reviewing them i think
a lot of them can get close so at least
we can
see on uh on the mailing list saying
look this is now ready to be closed
please voice your opinion and um
i don't think a lot of them will take a
lot of time
obviously none of the decisions here are
final they will be brought in
to the mailing list but
would be nice to get indication on this
um
so that's the rest of the tickets and
then
um
starting on with the main body of the
work
[Music]
this is uh very quick i don't really
want to
talk much about this
uh
not free passed away in may
i think there will be something in the
plenary
tomorrow about this uh a lot of us
knew ned and
i think his council would have been very
helpful in
in this room but uh
all right
okay
so um
starting with the foreclose and receive
header fields um
i looked at the ticket i nearly closed
it i
i sent john uh you know
quick message saying well uh i think we
need to do this tweak and then he said
no no you know i think we need to talk
about this so this is four slides from
john and john you you you want to
present them
and then we'll have a discussion
um the only thing i will add is actually
um
i will for this discussion i will be as
a participant not as a chair because i
might have a stronger opinion so i will
ask thoughts to
um arbitrate and make sure that uh
judge consensus
go john
uh okay i i i posted a uh
a moderately long noted list
uh earlier in the week and a uh
an internet draft which
uh
discusses this at the same time
um
uh i i hope and assume that everybody
has read both of them
uh so this is intended more as a quick
review than i say
uh complete analysis
um the question when we start messing
with
received clauses optional z clause
including four
uh is these interests has been seriously
underdefined
since the beginning and we've been
picking at them in little ways but uh
but not necessarily getting it right or
changing them
so the question which
i was proud to ask when i started
looking at this
in the current text of 5321 disc
uh was first of all go back and look at
the question what the four clause is for
and 50 and 821 doesn't say a word about
it it provides some syntax indicates an
optional field and the syntax points to
a path which since we eliminated pads is
now basically a mailbox
uh but it just gives the mailbox name
syntax
and like all components of trace fields
and i hope this is clear enough in the
current document but if it is that we've
got another issue the primary intended
use is debugging the assumption was
never that users were going to
look at these fields unless they
had questions or got into trouble
um
so the value associated with four is
generally assuming a mailbox
of the intended recipient
um but again we don't really
say that very quickly uh and if we did
we would have trouble with what
intended recipient means which is what
the current debate is all about in a way
so it's never been clear what to do with
multiple receipt commands
uh
clause is only going to be used once per
received field
uh and uh
and as we have more recently discussed
it could easily disclose in information
intended to be private and we've talked
about pcp bcc mailboxes but that's not
actually the only choice
next slide
so
in the current text we've got a general
warning about accidental information
disclosure especially for sites and
special circumstances we're not going to
dividing special circumstances
and we advise against providing for when
there's more than one recipient address
i.e water speed command and the
particular statement there is badly
written and should be cleaned up to be
retained
and for the badly written part you can
you could flog the editor except
unfortunately revolt
um
if our goal is prevent disclosure
potentially sensitive information a
bunch of other cases having to do with
the fact that we
allow
our mpas to transit a great deal of
uh flexibility about
uncombining and recombining messages as
we suggest them on combining
um
we're very very vague about when that's
possible we don't
force it we don't prohibit it
and we may need to rethink this entirely
when it should be provided and at what
stages rather than just providing a
quick test patch
next slide
so
obvious solutions uh borrowing these
things in the order which they appear in
that internet draft
hard to conclude for it's just too
dangerous we need to get rid of it
uh allow it only a message submission
time because the
submission system including both any
submission servers in the mqa
are the only ones who really know what
the intended recipient is what should be
kept private and what shouldn't
uh or we decide we don't care about
those other these other cases fix the
bad sentence and move on
uh next slide
pause with you now
um
if we decide to stay with where we are
to fix the sentence the bad sentences
here on the screen alexis
improved version
after a few iterations is at the bottom
of the screen and that's where we are
right now
okay and i noticed you accumulated a
large queue
very
[Music]
this is barry lieber
so i think it's not sufficient to do the
multi-recipients thing because even with
a single recipient forwarding the
message can cause all sorts of exposure
uh okay todd can you back up or
whoever's controlling the slides can you
back up a slide
yeah so um i i primarily support 1.1 i
think we should deprecate it the only
concern i have
is whether that violates our minimal
changes rule
um but i think i think saying that you
should not include it in new messages
but it's still going to appear in uh in
older implementations might be
sufficient but we should at least do one
of those varieties of one either 1.1 or
1.2 that's my opinion a quick comment
the uh
the minimum changes rule
is is definitely a question
but the the answer to a different
question
is that you're explicitly allowed to
deprecate things which had which
experientially haven't worked out in
moving to both standards so it's it's
our rule it's a problem and it's not
about global warming
okay then i will say but my my vote is
for 1.1
alexi okay so um
i do have a descending opinion here and
i might be in minority we'll see we'll
see about that
uh first
um i did quick search on what existing
mtas do so i checked uh i saw their own
implementation and i checked uh
exam
um
both on emit four if there is a single
recipient
so uh which kind of
confirms my theory of how this is
supposed to work you know whether it was
how it was intended i don't know because
i wasn't around at the time but this is
my perception of how
i would like you know i think it should
work
so um
the second thing is um
we did actually have a request at work
where uh
sometimes it's useful to have indicator
whether you uh to occ recipient right so
email client shows whether you're two is
your recipient
and there is a similar request for
knowing whether
you are you're receiving it as a 2 occ
mailing list
in this case you know um
four can potentially if for uh if a
message with a single recipient goes to
a mailing list
it gets expanded it can get four mailing
list address added
and then later on you can figure out
that you actually got this because of
the mailing list so i find some utility
in this
um
the third comment is as far as i'm
concerned uh mta's i've seen
don't make the mistake of leaking
information they only emit four if there
is a single recipient
which also means if
i mean it's up to ntas to decide they
can split the message into multiple
transactions
at which point they are separate
messages
separate transactions with a single
recipient and then they can still emit
it whether they do or don't i don't know
[Music]
just to clarify alexis you've made a
very strong argument for inserting the
four at the um
descending end
um and i think that's fine but it brings
us rapidly direction of option two on
the slide
um the complicated situations all arise
in
shuffling and reshuffling as barry
pointed out forwarding
uh and uh
and as you pointed out what we do with
list expansion or
sending to a list that gets a recipient
name after a while and uh the only
option i'm opposed to here is weakening
the rule the mtas are uh are expected to
poke around in previous headers in order
to be able to do next
can i just play it so yeah um i
basically kind of leaning toward more of
two or three options
and i think your option two is actually
not sufficient i think mta should be
still allowed to do that basically
well that raises some other questions
which are beaten to death in the
internet correct uh hi uh this is uh
victor de covney uh also i guess number
two on the postfix project uh also only
adds for
when there's a single recipient
i should note that we're talking about a
trace header
uh that happens on entry into the mail
system
so
at each hop
we're recording
what we received from the
previous smtp talker
and if that smtp talker sent us one
recipient that's when we had that one
unique recipient that we received at
that hop
two is definitely just fundamentally
flawed
that's not
not a good option
strongly vote for three
also lots of use cases where
sufficiently knowledgeable users
in fact find the four information in the
in the trace headers and postmasters
likewise
find it quite useful
uh when i complain about spam i often
want to know which of my thousands of
email addresses i received the spam for
the spam does not disclose that in the
two rcc headers
but i see it in the four
and i want it there
and um in any case whatever the draft
ultimately says i predict that postsix
will make no changes uh in the space
you can shout up and down but it will be
three forever
uh uh the language can be clarified to
warn some hypothetical mta that gets
this wrong i don't know of eddie
thank you and i would like to remind
everybody in the room you still
everybody in the room still please add
themselves to the queue for
hi it's pete resnick um i am
strongly strongly encouraging us to go
for number three
i think deprecating it is a mistake for
many of the reasons that
uh that victor brought up
with a single address it's quite useful
information
the fact of the matter is this is
deployed
as number three for
almost all systems
and
given our
charter we should not be trying to make
a new deprecation at this point we want
to put something in the as about it we
want to write a new document that's fine
let's stick with number three and just
do it that way
john levine i'm actually going to agree
with victor but use different words and
my preference is what i would call three
minus minus which is this
this entire this entire discussion reeks
of hubris we have no idea all the way if
the people are going to root their email
so what i would say is simply note that
anything in the four clause like the
rest of the received header is visible
to any some any subsequent party that
handles or receives the message and if
that's a
and that's a security issue you should
you should keep it in mind before adding
the clause and stop there because i
don't know what else i can say that
wouldn't it wouldn't have
endless exceptions
barry lee but again i wanted to respond
to mostly alexei but also some of the
rest that
there's no doubt that it's that it's
useful for some people
if it's there uh i want to remind people
that it's often not there you you cannot
rely on it
um
so given what other people have said
about three i'm okay if we decide in
three that that in 53 21 bits we go with
three
but we also put something in the as
saying um that we're basically
basically deprecating it or advising
against using it because of all of the
exposures
i find that the privacy implications are
more or are stronger to me than the
usefulness of it and i would rather be
very strong about avoiding using it for
that reason thanks
i'm going to limit discussion on this to
two more minutes braun europe and then
pete
and then daniel
yeah i'm going to say that as someone
who works
reading email headers a lot it's very
useful to me it might not be useful to
you barry but for a lot of people it
really is useful
for things um and if you're scrubbing
mail to remove things being forwarded on
you have to scrub lots of places anyway
it can also be a
received four header there's lots of
other things can one are being added at
each hop if you want to be really clean
against stuff being seen through you're
gonna have to filter out a lot more than
just this header
um i also am very much in favor of three
make the text clear that it can leak if
it gets forwarded on and think about it
and that's it
and this is pete i honestly don't
understand the serious privacy
implications of the single
recipient
introduction of the four
if it was
sent to me i received it and i forward
it what i forward is my decision it is
now out of smtp's hands
and if i need to clean up a message then
i need to clean up a message
that's not a protocol privacy issue and
i don't think it belongs in this
document
daniel van gilmer i'll be quick uh also
speaking in favor of three i believe um
i
uh so
i think that there are multiple people
in this room who have strong opinions
about how one should scrub email and i
think that was worth doing as a separate
project
uh in terms of removing uh potentially
leaking
things and that would be worth noting
that here i also wanted to note that
when we just talk about deprecating it i
don't think that's actually particularly
useful because there's deprecating
reliance on it and there's deprecating
inclusion of it and those are two
distinct things and i think it's a
mistake to just randomly say we
deprecate this without being clear which
side we're talking about deprecating i
think the simplest thing is to say here
are the risks
and work actively on a scrubbing draft
separately
thank you
i believe in the room here we've landed
on consensus on three
any dispute on that
no all right move on
it raises a separate question
which is the difference but as you tell
me you go off and fix text which is the
difference between three and three minus
minus
uh under three we
tune the existing language a little bit
and then go forward
uh
under three minus minus for which i have
some sympathy
we
don't address we tear the bad sentence
out and replace it with nothing because
there's already language in the document
the employers see the
uh see that id
uh that talks a little bit about this
and
language about whether or not people
should rely on it and whether whether
they should and whether or not it should
be provided with their edge cases
probably belongs to the as
so the three minus minus option is even
to tear some of this some of this stuff
which we put in back out and i'm
actually more comfortable with that
option than i am with uh with with three
by itself or uh
uh
especially we decided not to do the
others and uh and i could clarify what
deprecated number one means it's
probably not worth the effort
okay um
shall we take it to the main list
uh or maybe are you happy with trying to
do the fix
on the next slide i propose
and then have a quick discussion about
whether we want to move the stacks to
ass or where they should stay
does it work for you
i i think as far as far as five three
two one is concerned
i and several people spoke and very
included
uh are uh
are
are closer to three minus minus than two
three
and that would argue against choosing
either of the options on that spot
so i i think we're bound for the mailing
list but i hope that this time people
will actually
participate on the mailing list and
respond in
in soon time rather than in november
okay quickly
so victor said suggestion is fine
yeah this is pete i i think it would be
a mistake to completely yank the
sentence i think the suggested
replacement is fine
but i i think making believe that this
document can get away with
not discussing it at all is probably a
mistake we should try just fix the
sentence i think that's a good fix and
move on and better notes as well so
pete have you read the idea and noticed
that there are other places documents
where this is discussed
yeah i i suppose that's true um i i i
guess i don't feel exceedingly strongly
about it but there it is in this section
um it's been there i i
i would my inclination is to fix a
mistake
which that person you know the the
existing sentence is it's just a mess
rather than just ditch it i wouldn't uh
uh throw myself on my sword to keep it
um but i i think the fix is fine
i'm not throwing myself on any swords
either but um
but i know that this is not 5221 text
that we're
talking about bad sentences and it's
actually put in uh a meteor two ago
uh so this is this is recent text and
it's still on the target list i don't
feel nearly strongly about this as i
probably sound
but i think we need to make a uh a
careful and considered decision here
rather than saying rather than shutting
our shoulders and moving on
and and i think the text which isn't
documented most of which is from five
three three two one is very much part of
this picture uh one of the problems with
five three two one and this document and
two eight two one is this altogether too
much redundant text which talks in
almost the same way about almost the
same things and that's a danger in
itself
can i still suggest you try to apply the
text and then we'll have a
review on the mailing list of the whole
document of the sole issue
are you okay with that
um
since since i have no immediate
instructions the way when i'm going to
do a new version
uh i'm i'm okay with that but it's
almost meaningless as far as what
anybody else sees
applying to do taxes obviously
okay
well i'm just trying to suggest a way of
getting closure on the document this is
pretty much one of the two issues
remaining um
uh and and i would argue that especially
assistance is a full standard and based
upon the number of people
attending this meeting interests seem to
be waiting and we should really get it
right
all right let's take the mailing list
and and and and i guess to answer your
question i am as happy
putting in your text and then arguably
you should be taken out as i am leaving
the old text and that argument should be
taken out
let's just
do revision to the list right with the
text
that's where we want to go
i i don't i don't feel like we're going
to solve this but this problem in the 35
minutes we have remaining we've got
other tickets to get to so let's let's
get let's move the discussion on to the
list and keep going with it
i think
some flavor of option three whether it's
three or three minus minus is where
we're going with this we have some
proposed text on the slide here
or discussion the text on the slide here
so let's
see we can hammer out on the list and
move forward on this
john i i i think there will be a slight
uh definition of compromise i think
everybody is equally unhappy so let's
let's move on
all right
okay
my favorite issue i love to hate
hopefully uh so um i i read the mailing
list on this uh topic um and uh i
thought it would be actually more
controversial than i thought you know
i expected it to be more controversial
but it looks like
very proposed text
john the other john did a tweak to it
and people said yeah
i can live with this
dave clocker did it a tweak and they
said he can live with it and john you
you said you can live with it
um
with that in mind
oh
hold on
um
my proposal is
to kind of if we can quickly agree that
we cannot live with this
um
the other
uh suggestion is
if we can live with it
well
i think we should just try expert review
and see how it works and if we really
hate it then we can do it week later on
but i think
whatever is on the table is already
better than what we have in the document
but i want to ask a question i've tried
asking several times i've never gotten
an answer
do we have real world cases
in which someone has proposed an
extension
for other than private use in a small
community and has found the
current situation
or two burdens
i know there's no general problem with
the registrations
and as i've said in other places i'm uh
i'm very very concerned about those
but i'm still haunted by marshall's
uh argument about sparsity
and um uh
am wondering whether we have real world
pieces which justify worrying about this
or whether it is
it's just a theoretical problem
um
my
okay some of it probably wasn't said on
the mailing list but my interpretation
of comments received from one proponent
is actually that specification required
would be sufficient
even though the person went into more
details saying you know all the troubles
that he got into and though that there
was no champion it wasn't the same issue
so
i think with the
one or more experts which uh
trying to be helpful and friendly
i think that's not going to be a problem
at least that's that's my interpretation
of of the proposal
and and again that's the comments
did not seem to be about a real world
problem which was a problem
it seemed uh
much more about a
more theoretical set of questions but
maybe i didn't understand it
okay quickly victor
uh expert review sounds uh excellent
i'll in fact be an early user of it at
some point before too long
okay
mary
so this is barry um
the the reason i wanted to get to this
slide before i said anything is i want
to make sure that we agree
that this slide has
the right
uh
the right guidance for the designated
expert
um this is what
i proposed that john tweaked and dave
tweaked and i think
the three of us are probably good with
this is everybody else good with this
so
um as a participant and as somebody who
didn't like first come first serve i'm
happy with this
and a thumbs up from braun is anybody
and a thumbs up from murray and thumbs
ups from everybody i see in the room
okay this is all cool i i think we're
done with this now
and i think we spent collectively way
too much time on it so let's move on
okay
we declare victory i was so depressed
last time i have to say
okay
all right do you want to
or they want me to talk
okay so uh we are moving on to the
applicability statement
issues um
some of these um
there is too much text to really show in
the room or to live edit um i think this
particular issue is we had
uh two rounds of discussions uh chaired
by todd then
um i think ken incorporated it in the
latest revision uh and
this is just a reminder for people to
have a look at this i think the text is
baked
i personally propose just to do a small
tweak to the text which i can send to
the mailing list
but i think this is good enough and
hopefully ready to be closed
final call final call for final call so
we'll take it to the main list to double
check
that people are happy with this
and unless there are strong objection on
the maining list i think this will one
will be closed
okay
um
this one is actually new i don't think
we discussed it
pete
i'm so sorry this is your ticket that's
why i can't yeah
um there was basically a suggestion
saying that
maybe something should be said about
this in applicability statement
we have no proposal so far i think what
what do you want to do
my proposal is always make me write less
text and move it to the applicability
statement
um no we can still make you write taxes
we are going to end up in your documents
you don't have to do it now
okay uh
do
do you remember what you meant by this
there i think there was someone either
posted narada or something else about
the 78 question
and whether the it should have said 77
with the fold or what have you
um
so last time i checked i think your
document is fine and very clear
um
i i think
you know we may want to give examples in
the as to explain that there are going
to be times with headers that
you're not going to have a nice fold
point and so you may need to do
something different
and john has a comment and maybe he can
come up with what the heck we were
talking about
my only question here pete before you
sit down
uh is the use of the word always in that
first clause
because that's always absent sntp
extensions and various other kinds of
weird stuff
say it again sorry it's always plus or
minus
uh mine
stops so all so so if you're gonna do so
if it says always you may need to think
a little bit about that choice of words
right
i
don't think there's a problem here
that's even worth messing and messing
with in the as
uh i'm not yep sure what was proposed to
be honest
what was proposed was move the ticket to
the aas instead of leaving it on 53 22
best it's already done it's already for
aos but the question is what do you want
in ais to be said about this uh
who who is
is todd ostensibly the author
no that's something behind you the
person behind me is ostensibly the
author will work offline on some text
i'll propose some text to him and he can
put it in and he can and he will bug me
okay so can you do it this week please
he will get me to get the text done
as ostensibly one of the other authors
please include me
okay yes not a problem all right three
of you uh
will discuss some texts and bring it to
the mailing list thank you
right um
ticket number 35 erratum 3135 about
quarter string definition
basically this is the current text in a
s that talks about
funky use of empty quotes in left-hand
side and how it is likely to cause
problems in real world
i think suggestion is to close this
ticket as done
if
people have
any objections
in the room and we'll double check this
on the mining list
going once going twice
okay
okay ticket 51 is about uh
format elements
in web forms this was actually raised by
ned freed i think
the issue is that many web forms are
being too strict they don't even allow
pluses and various other things
uh so this is about adding some text
saying that
based on abnf you should really be
accepting these funky characters like
probably forward slashes equal signs and
pluses
at least
well in addition to dots and
alphanumeric stuff
obviously there is no text but you know
this is kind of deciding which direction
we want to go on this
buddy
this is barry lieber what about
internationalized email addresses
do we want to go there in the
applicability statement
good point probably a separate ticket
okay because this is talking about forms
not accepting uh
book standard us key addresses
which would be otherwise valid right the
question is whether we should also talk
about forms accepting non-ascii okay can
we have it as in in a minute as a
thing to discuss as well thank you
excellent
okay
right
i guess my question is do we expect this
to have any effect
putting it in this document
um
is there is there any point in telling
web forms what they should do and do you
think they would listen
um i think there would be in a sense but
there is actually uh
you really have to be uh a bnf expert to
figure it out from
the base pack uh this is a common enough
problem so maybe at least you know if
it's written down then you can point
people to say look it says there that
you should do it
cool
that's kind of the point of it
okay john john clemson
and something to point to that is
written in
uh relatively plain english rather than
uh a bnf or uh or whatever language five
three two one or five three people were
written in which is not english uh will
it by itself anybody if they know but
have your clear pointers useful and i
say this as somebody who has this
problem a couple times a week and uh and
needs to need something to avoid it too
and that's more or less the argument
that they've made
okay
all right thank you
hans york hi uh this is hansard hubble
um i think this is a very useful thing
so um i mean i see uh bronze concerns
that obviously that might not change
things immediately somehow but um
i think this is really something in my
personal experience even even i
experience on a weekly basis that's our
ill-defined
validation algorithms and also
when we do migration projects we see
many different systems to accept many
different standards and many of that is
basically i think done in libraries
so actually if we can point library
developers to this um that might be
great
and that might even have an impact in
the long term um i'm not sure about the
abn f if it's easily so easy what i
think would be really helpful in
addition is maybe to have a
repository a list of example data which
is
which can be tested for those library
developments or something okay
okay uh
can so
we can probably
collaborate and we can find other people
to help you with this john
if i may throw a spanner in the works
the html living standard has an email
address validation
pattern which
vast numbers of libraries and web
applications actually use
and if we can't persuade them to make
their pattern match our pattern we are
completely wasting our time and their
pattern specifically says we know this
is only a subset of what this of what
the mail spec says
but we think it matches what male actual
male systems accept and it's not
terrible
but my guess is we're not thrilled about
it so i would like talk to him
mark naughty hammer somebody but
basically if we can't get we can't get
their pattern on our pattern in
in sync like we'll just confuse people
and we're not going to improve things
okay apropos uh the question about i
think that's fair let's minute this that
we need to double check whether
how restrictive it is yeah yeah and also
i don't think they're hostile to having
stuff
they're hostile to updating it i think
they just
there have been a lot of pranks and
particularly back when there was a fork
between the w3c and what wig w3c said oh
we're going to make it we're going to
we're going to do eai so all unicode
characters are valid which of course is
stupid right right yeah and yeah apropos
unicode
um i don't want to go there simply
because having done if there are a
number of experiments with with eai mail
systems i see no pattern whatsoever in
what character sets ea addresses
actually allow so i wouldn't know what
to say
okay
well at least we kind of declared this
separate ticket so we'll figure it out
when we get to it
real quick as an attempt to take the
path of least resistance would it be
sufficient for the aes just to reference
the document john just mentioned
and say that
web forms do have a restricted set
consult this spec to see what's allowed
um
to be honest when i look at regular
expressions my my brain still hurts i
kind of feel like i didn't play in
english
apropos that their pattern is not
horrible but it could be better i think
if we could engage with them
constructively and say hey we're the
male experts and here's a pattern that
we think will work they might want to
say oh thank you
yes yes i mean we shouldn't rule out uh
ability to actually do do changes if
they are well um
argued from output all right
john
i think we need to understand really
what you're designing to say that there
is an
active pew going on between w3c and wg
over some of these issues
and the last thing we want to do is to
point to one of the other of their
documents
one of the other of their
incomprehensible documents and say pay
attention to that incomprehensible
document rather than the other
incomprehensible document or our
incomprehensible document uh clear
english language would be a good idea
okay
victor you've figured out
uh yes the interface has lost
um i can volunteer to write uh fairly
advanced regular expressions if people
want that i've uh i don't get scared by
them okay that's not actually what
no but if we want to could you know you
said
you know we know but okay
i think if people want to do regular
expression it's kind of a separate topic
in a sense of and there was actually a
sample proposal uh a draft at the time
i would like this written in plain
english first
okay and then we can figure out whether
we
want to include regular expression and
we can do a call on the main list okay
all right thank you for volunteering
dkg very quickly yeah um
i definitely think that we should exert
what uh influence we have on the other
standards bodies to
produce something that is regularly
usable
and that does mean some amount of
functional material which is like a
regular expression i'm fine if that goes
alongside english text
but
the
i think the um
the test suite that you're describing is
really the key thing to say here's a
bunch of things this one is valid here's
why it's valid here's why it's not right
but we that that set of three things is
really what you want if you want people
to take it seriously as
implementers
test suites specific
regular expressions and an english
overview
okay point taken
all right uh ken i think you have enough
direction for initial version and then
we'll see what happens
okay trying to speed up a little bit
oh yeah the new ticket that
that people wanted to discuss so
the current ais basically has a stub
version in the mime section and i think
some people want to change that
let's have a chat
[Music]
uh this is barry
ken and i talked about this the other
day and i um i think the answer to this
is that we should say a fairly minimal
amount about uh mime there
uh because what's likely to happen is
when we're finished with
53 21 and 53 22 bisses
we will consider adding mime as our next
pass
and at that point we will probably
revise the applicability statement for
that
but right now all we should say is that
mime is a widely implemented and very
important
extension to the internet message format
go there and look at it and we will talk
more about this later and that's
probably all we should say
okay
p peters is saying plus one plus two
plus ten
okay
so so real quick a barry pete are we
looking for
like normative text like we recommend
you support this you should support this
are we going to dig into it and say
these parts of the spec
have never been used avoid them
you're really thinking
with respect to mine yes not now i mean
i think all we should do now is say
if this is widely deployed and there and
it's documented here
and
further advice will come later and
that's that's that's that's all i would
want to say now
right
yeah it it doesn't actually i think it
doesn't have to be normative
and pete is quite good at phrasing
things which are normative but without
using shoots a must
pretty much you know
okay
okay that was actually quicker than i
expected sounds good um
i'm going to uh so there are three more
slides on issues which i built um
i think should be closed again subject
to mailing list verification etc etc
um if people want to object
[Music]
i think you probably should take
discussion to the maining list
realistically but if people want to
okay everybody says yes
yes to take it to the mailing list now
to
just close the ticket
john
it started was not about
one of the places where this started was
not about the domain names just
addresses but about the use of ip
addresses
yeah there is a separate ticket about
this hold on okay if there's a separate
ticket about that that's fine
it's the next slide actually
okay addresses in the hello
that i have no problem with closing the
previous one and
we should deal with this if you need to
okay and the proposal is to close this
one as well
so
since i've still got a video on i will
record
record by holding my nose
sounds good
um and the last one
do you want to just quickly
i know that the proposal was to close
this ticket because that's what it said
in the ticket documentation itself so
let me just find out real quick
oh yeah this was about
there's there are timeout specifications
that are in 5321 and probably previous
issue or previous versions
and there had been some discussion about
whether or not to revisit them because
they seem really freaking long for
modern networks versus when 8 21 was
first written
um
as we've discussed it over the months
there's been a whole lot of
might as well leave them there's been no
but they're also like iot networks where
it's still relevant right so there's
been no no call to change them
whatsoever so
the proposal is just to close the ticket
okay
we john
if people wanted to i i'm not
necessarily in favor of it
put a little bit of text in the ais
which points out that under many
circumstances those timeouts
in the modern world those timeouts may
be a little bit long
but uh i don't know at the moment how to
write that text and uh and would prefer
we didn't but uh but we should be sure
we
don't eliminate that possibility without
thinking about it if we thought about it
we should move on
okay so um
we're actually at the end of the slides
the only thing i
i propose maybe we will look at
outstanding
tickets for smtp spec and i'll just
quickly talk about
oh yeah uh john do you want to talk
about your i think first to do or shall
we look at tickets first
uh let's talk about that briefly very
briefly
because i think that it's uh
i think we're having an argument that
borders
let's go say words like silly but sorry
um
it's it it's it's clear to at least many
of us that uh that we cannot promote
that to a bus not for operational
reasons i don't understand the
correspondence of the list
because i think that the person who is
advocating changing into a must turn
around and explain why it should be
assured so i'm confused i just did not
want to let this
go past this meeting without at least
some minimal discussion and awareness of
what's going on if we have to continue
arguing with them on the list i guess
that's our danger
mrs barry i completely agree with john
the only the only thing that needs to
change is the knot needs to be
capitalized as well capital should lower
case not is not a
bcp14 keyword
otherwise it's fine
if the stupid editor made that mistake a
stupid editor will correct it
okay
okay can you see the list of issues
yes
uh
i think so
[Music]
let's do this first
okay
uh we do have five minutes uh
right so
we have some way forward towards seeking
55 the foreclose received we
i think pretty much closed iron
registration policy
there are two tickets 61 and 12 about
mailing lists and improved definition of
mailing lists so um
a few months ago ned proposed to write a
document this is not going to happen now
i tend to think that
we probably don't have energy for this
so i suggest we just do nothing
should people
in slow time write a document on the
topic we can
revise it some future day date
uh
and
the only other ticket is nullimax and i
think
discussion was that the current text is
okayish and so i should close this one
john any comments
are you happy with this
and at the risk of sounding like teeth
making it go away so i don't have to do
anything is fine
fine okay so
because pete asked
um
i think there was one ticket asking for
enhancement which we are not going to do
yeah
this is barry so does that mean that
after john posts the next revision for
5321 this we're ready for working group
last call absolutely yes
so
yes this was
kind of a ticket basically why is this
so uh
email address is so complicated and it's
like um
oh it's your your democrat
i was just gonna i'm just gonna say that
looks like something somebody would have
written on the dmarc list and it was
that somebody
right
[Music]
okay so
yeah i don't think we'll deal with this
are you happy with this pete
you know we we try that over at d mark
and he just keep coming back so um try
to ignore him but it doesn't
work this is public
also too much conversation off mike so
uh
all right so
um
and if we look at list of issues for
applicability statement it actually
doesn't look too bad
so
we'll have some text about the first one
we're about to close the second number
54.
we talked about 51.
i think we're about to close uh
number 40 recommended smtp extensions
but i'll bring it to the main list
there will be some suggestion about 38
close 35
close 19
close 16.
uh
close number one right number eight
this is actually kind of important yes
um
[Music]
this started about a year ago and there
was a long discussion about an extra
registry
going through the main english
discussion i realized there was no
consensus so i i suggest we just drop it
and ned was a big
motivator and part of the discussion and
i think he sort of initiated it but at
the end he he didn't like doing it
either so i think
closing it with
do nothing is probably the best way
so
hopefully the plan is john will update
the document
uh which will go to last call um knowing
that next month is august it's probably
going to be september just to make sure
that people are paying attention
and then
we do have some work to do on ais but
um
i think we will very closely uh very
soon will have a call on opening new
issues so i think it's actually getting
pretty big now
um
[Music]
so if people think that there is a major
thing which is unclear or missing
now it's a good time to actually bring
it up
look at the mic but you know on the menu
list
this is barry is our plan to send 53 21
and 53 22 bits to the isg together yes
and then to send as to the iesg sometime
later
maybe soon later but not yes with them
uh
i think it sort of depends you know if
if we uh feel that ais is
so nearly done you know like can be done
within a month after that then we can i
just said okay
right i know that i hope ties
i'm just thinking of the
burden on the iesg and i would prefer to
get
21 and 22 taken care of before the iasg
sees the ais oh yeah yeah absolutely
look at that later it will be before yes
it's just a question if you send as nine
months later people forget what they
want to document maybe you know a month
or two later
okay yeah okay i'm good with that
cool john
i bought the deck too for the same
reasons but uh
but if we're gonna send the
5321 best 53
22 risk to the uh to the iasg without
waiting for the gas we better be very
very careful with the ais
it doesn't say anything which seems to
contradict the two-way documents
um and the good news is that if we get
53 21 finished
next month or in september i will be
able to pay more attention to the ass
sounds good i mean
fantastic
just actually a question for murray but
from the mic so but we all hear it
yeah are are you okay with
running the two through
where
you're we're gonna have to deal with the
as
we'll need to be watched to make sure it
doesn't contradict and all that
the isg is happy not dealing with it
um
no i think that's fine i think we could
even i could even warn them that you
know this is coming these are related
but they're going to be separated by a
little bit
try to remember
i can help this out okay
and i was about to ask if you have
anything else to say but i think you
just said what you wanted to say so
um thank you for the progress and this
is great that's all i have to say
okay
thank you all
um this was quite a productive meeting
and
um see you next time maybe we even
return the next time you never know
oh
[Music]