yes
questions
guys
um
uh
sorry
i'm not meant to laugh at you
yeah seems awesome
oh
all right
we're going to get started in just a
minute uh this is the newcomers overview
for ihf 114 so if you just
um
if you have not done this you need to uh
screen the qr code
um this is the way we keep track of
attendance in each meeting and you'll
get practice for it we have these we
used to have these things called blue
sheets which is the way we
uh kept track of who was in the room and
that's important for a number of reasons
actually
and because we are a standards process
we we need to do that so um you'll see
this
at the entrance to every meeting this
week and on the boards and things so and
that way uh you are recorded as having
been in the room for this particular
discussion
and when you think about app and open
standards it's important to know who's
in the room for the discussion
and one of the joys about being the
first session
is there's always
last-minute technical things
and as we go through this uh feel free
to go to the microphone if you have any
questions any of you that are remote
you can feel free to um
put yourself in the virtual queue i
guess we should practice the q
methodology while we're here as well so
you need to use your phone
to put yourself in the queue
and this will give us two advantages
during the week one
we won't have everybody lined up all
crowded around the microphone for
coveted reasons
and then the second one is it puts the
physical attendees that are here in
person on the same footing with the
remote attendees everybody gets their
their chance
their choice in line so
are we good now
we're good
great thanks
um
so there's one other thing um and i
meant to review it and stick a slide in
the slides and i didn't get it done and
that is uh the covet policy which is
which is posted everywhere so we do ask
everybody when you're in meeting rooms
to please wear a mask uh well when we're
speaking we're going to take it off to
make it a little bit clearer but we're
pretty far away from you uh and then
we'll put it back on so um
so with that
we'll go ahead and get started
um
so i welcome you to the newcomers
overview uh i am karen o'donoghue i have
been participating in the ietf for a
number of years i have been an ihf chair
and i've been involved in the education
mentoring and outreach activities for a
number of years as well uh the
um
i think i don't think we have yeah next
slide i don't know that we have a
clicker yeah okay so next slide uh so
this is the overview of the presentation
we have it divided into four parts uh we
have a uh these parts online as well
that's a little bit outdated and we're
revising it
and we're going to pull out the meeting
specific information so that the videos
online will be
you can see them in advance
but the four parts are here we're going
to talk really quickly sort of a high
level overview and an introduction to
the newcomers activities then we're
going to talk about the structure of the
ietf and then we're going to talk about
the meeting week and then we're going to
talk about additional resources that
would be helpful
so i introduced myself i actually wanted
to also introduce my co-presenter
rich who can introduce himself actually
sure hi
i assume that works um my name is rich
sals i've been also involved in the itf
for a really long time
uh and
i have had a couple of different work
group chairs got involved in the
what's now emo der education mentoring
and outreach
a few years ago have been giving the
co-presenting this
tutorial
for several years
the last couple have obviously all been
virtual
so it's nice to see people you can only
see half the face but thank you
yes so um also
if anybody is interested in helping with
the emo directivities we're we'll ask
again at the end but any feedback you
have on information that you might have
missed or things that would help you uh
sort of find your way around the ietf uh
please be sure because that all helps us
make those activities
uh next slide
oh they're right there i don't know why
i'm looking backwards so anyway the
scope of this presentation is
specifically to help uh you prepare for
this meeting and to make this meeting uh
or you know your general introduction to
the ihf uh the most effective
this presentation does not include
things like the history of the ihf or
how to write a standard
or even how it touches on how to bring
new work to the ietf but there's a lot
more information
obviously we really just wanted to give
you a snapshot to get you started and
give you some pointers as to where to go
and then hopefully from there you'll
find the information that you need
next slide
there we go
uh so the first thing that uh you will
have seen this when you registered
actually even so the this uh the
notewell is the general set of policies
and rules that the ietf follows if you
have you need to at some point read
through these and if you go to the next
slide
it's this plus the list of policies that
are referenced
i should probably begin to
anticipate when i'm going to change and
give you a heads up
we lost the connection
do you have a network
oh no momento
[Music]
okay
i can tell you there's a list of bcps on
this next thing and it covers things
like our anti-harassment policy
our intellectual property intellectual
property processes
this is not loud
all right
let me do it
okay hold on one second
no
it's not
that's not their problem
before i did
okay
okay so now we return you to where we
were this is the list of best current
practices or bcps uh that we have it
includes the things like the stan oh
sorry go ahead you can ask the dumb
question if you could define vcp for us
best current practice
so
just as a slight tangent if you look at
the
ietf
types of documents we have standards
track we have informational we have
experimental and sometimes a draft will
be labeled as a best current practice it
might be a best current practice about a
technology or it might be a best current
practice for
how the ietf operates
so
anyhow so that's our list of uh policies
if you go the next slide
so these specifically are the newcomer
activities uh for this ietf uh this is
the newcomers overview tutorial which
you are currently
attending
the uh
there is a quick connections today at
four o'clock uh there is a sign up
process for that we strongly encourage
you to attend that it's it's
it's sort of like a quick meeting with a
bunch of iutfer so you walk around a
room
and you spend a few minutes talking to
some experienced ietfers and then you
move on to another group
we've had pretty good success with that
tomorrow evening we have a newcomers
dinner that's also a sign up you should
have gotten an email about that if
you're not getting the newcomers emails
i strongly encourage you to see the lady
in purple at the front of the room she
didn't know i was going to point her out
but there she is
she's going to be helping with some of
the newcomer activities going forward
and so if you're not getting the
newcomer emails please see michelle
uh there is a remote newcomers coffee
break one of the things that we're
really struggling with as are a lot of
uh activities is how to incorporate how
to blend our in-person and our remote
attendees and how to make the experience
beneficial for both of them
and i will have to admit i think we're
struggling a bit with the remote we
really aren't quite exactly sure how to
best serve the remote newcomers
um so we do plan to have a coffee break
for them and for you all for those of
you who are remote um
in gather i know there's more details in
that in the newcomers email that you
should have received
we're going to do an oncom
on-site newcomers feedback session on
thursday morning
there will be a little bit of food there
so
you can come for that
and then we're going to do a remote
newcomers feedback session and it's not
just for remote people but we're just
going to do a follow-up session that's
going to be online strictly online
and we'll do that in the next couple
weeks and we'll get that scheduled and
sent out next slide
so with that i'm going to hand over to
rich and he's going to talk about the
structure of the ietf
okay take a breath thanks
next
all right so the mission of the ietf we
have a mission statement like everybody
does these days
we want to make the internet work better
and what that means is we're going to
produce we want to produce high quality
technically relevant documents that
means if somebody technically relevant
means if somebody has an idea on how to
get more effective use of car braking
systems that's probably not relevant to
the itf
but it does cover a fairly wide area
for example there's a recent flurry of
activity about drones
you know the little flying things that
people record the videos on
because the faa is interested in
identifying them securely
being able to control them keep them
away from sensitive areas like airports
and so on so people in the itf are
working on
drip
drone remote identification protocol
it involves some interesting
cryptography challenges how you fit a
signature into a small packet that can
be sent over radio things like that
and we want to influence the way people
design use and manage the internet uh in
the past that was more of a selling job
but now there are people
other organizations recognize that if
you want to do something
internet related and it's a technical
protocol
this is the place to be
so
newcomers welcome
next slide
so we are in what's called an sdo with
standards development organization
we're different than many many other
sdos
lots of them for example iso
or osi depending on how you want to
abbreviate it
there's membership is based on your
country of origin
and it's paid membership
the itf anybody can join all you have to
do is sign up on this website called the
data tracker
datatracker.ietf.org or dt.iatf.org
everyone here if you registered you
already had an account
you already created an account
self-selected membership is based on
individuals so you don't see things like
when the c plus standard is reviewed the
vote tallies are china says yes u.s says
yes russia says
abstains and so on it's by individuals
we also don't vote and we'll talk about
that a little later well we do have um
consensus our goal is rough consensus
which means
that we want to make sure that
everyone's had a chance to say but not
that everyone's
you know everyone's voice has been heard
but not that everyone gets to
veto every single decision
um the real the primary driver yeah
yeah please
um
a couple of ways the one let's see lee
the woman in white um
the membership fee here there's some
membership fees right you you join the
ietf by subscribing to mailing lists of
the groups you're interested in the
conference fees pay for a lot of pay for
some of it we get significant grants
from the internet society
because the internet society knows that
without the itf the internet is much
less of the thing
and now the iatf also the itif is a
legal entity underneath the internet
society but a separate legal entity in
terms of tax um
and lee is in the development leads is
the development organization which is
responsible for you know seeking grants
if you look on the
um
banners they're hanging up around the
place you'll see several companies
recognized oracle uh
contributes money to help fund
sustainability my company and i forget
the other one uh
diversity and inclusion
so if you have onsite we have on-site
child care which is funded out of that
so it's corporate contributions on the
global sponsors are people who've signed
up for significant contributions to host
the ietf meetings which are three times
around the world uh per year uh made
significant contributions to fund that
answer your question
great um
the one thing i would just point uh
mention
is um
not about funding actually but about
process um
and this this
i almost hate to do this but uh for the
rest of the meetings this week if you
have any questions if you can go to the
queue and put yourself in the queue in
this room and this is this is a friendly
group a friendly uh
introduction to newcomers event but the
the way the other meetings will work is
you'll need to get in the queue in order
to ask any questions
so um
i i hesitated to do that
but
uh i think you're smiling behind your
mask
yeah okay um yeah when so
the the video system we use is called is
we call it meat echo it's by a company
called meat echo
it's very well integrated into the itf
processes and even
so remote that's what you use it's a
browser-based application
online there's the online what is it in
person version which is meat echo light
it doesn't bother doing the video and
the audio because you're here in the
room but in the upper left hand corner
there's like a raise your hand icon and
so if you want to speak at any of the
other sessions
um you click on the raise your hand and
the chairs up front here will manage the
cube because that same cue is also for
people who are watching it remotely
okay uh next slide please
so the big picture
the iesg
you may have heard that term also the
term int area directors
these are the people responsible for
steering the technical direction of the
ietf as in what the different working
groups do and work on
creating new working groups and so on
that process
they also
approve the decisions
for where we meet
the irsg related to the
internet tech task force ietf there's
the internet engineering
internet research task force and they
have similar kinds of meetings um
they're all co-located here if you
register and attend an ietf meeting you
can attend any of the irtf sessions
and so there are things there about
privacy
uh how you measure the global
consumption of the you know global use
of the internet and things like that
the internet architecture board is sort
of an
oversight committee
they held handle the liaison program so
there are lots of organizations that
liaison with the ietf
iso itu has uh interactions you know
they define new signature schemes uh
working with nist post quantum that
stuff all has particular liaisons uh
many of the ietf protocols don't use you
know we've grown outgrown ascii so now
we use unicode and so there's a
particular person associated who
liaisons with the unicode consortium to
make sure that what we're doing is okay
and so on and we just lost the net again
one of the other things ea iab does is
they organize workshops um they've
announced two
uh one that's coming up uh will be
announced soon is on sustainability and
the applicability
of you know
what happens you know
sustainability within the itf in the
internet uh how do things change when we
all are doing zoom rather than flying
all around the world to attend places
i'm glad it's not just me
well i'm not glad but you know yeah
that's right
again sorry
all right i'll
mention the list i'll mention the areas
while we get back up
the technical side of the ietf is
divided is divided into
seven main areas
one two three four five six seven
next slide
okay so
the um
every working group which is where the
bulk of the which is where the bulk of
the technical work happens
falls under a particular area very very
rarely a working group will be respond
will be the responsibility of two areas
but the
largest
parceling of working groups
are is in areas and these are the
seven of them um i won't
read the list
that's why the network crashed um i
won't read the list this is
not that bad but we would call this an
eye chart right because you got to sit
there and try to make out little things
but
if you go to the data tracker site you
can find the list of areas
next slide
itef and
consensus so we work by consensus rough
consensus and running code that's one of
the aphorisms that the iatf likes to use
to describe itself
as i mentioned before rough consensus
doesn't mean that every objection has
been
mollified but that every objection has
been heard
rough consensus all the disease
addressed
dissenting opinions are heard but not
controlling
and we do what we do humming
like every other thing in the ietf it's
documented in our in an rfc
rfcs originally stood for re request for
comments
dates back 30 years back when the
department us department of defense was
doing things and some grad students said
well here's the way the computer will
talk to the gateways would we call it
let's put it out as a request for
comments
and so we like to still keep that sense
of history
humming is the way we do it uh so
we can do a sort of a practice hum here
so you can see how it works when it's
all remote
there's a tool in the medico thing that
lets you you know hum yes or no but the
humming has its advantages um you can't
tell who's humming generally especially
not with people are masked
you can't control
the sound but you know it's really hard
to hum very loud
um
and you can you typically the chairs
will ask you know a quad three-part
question
do you think we should adopt this
document do you not think we should
adopt this document are you unable to
decide
so
for example we can say
uh well that will do a three-part hum
you know
do you like karen more than me do you
like me more than karen or are you not
ready to decide yet
so home now if you prefer karen to me
okay
hum now if you prefer me to karen
i'm crushed i'm
hum now if you can't decide
all right so we can all hear that in the
room that was clearly the consensus by
the end of the meeting maybe we'll do it
again okay next
okay next slide
i'll just point out i have candy
okay so let's talk about the week um
yeah i'm not above it
my suitcase upstairs
but um okay so the week um
we're still obviously feeling our way
through a lot of this stuff
um this is the second time we've had
both in-person and remote attendance we
call it obviously everyone like everyone
we call it a hybrid meeting so there's
probably still a little rough edges um
but the core of the the meeting this
week
and most of the work starts monday
through
late afternoon friday
are working group sessions the itf is
divided into working groups there's
about 130 of them
every one grouped into an area
my particular focus is on security for
example
there are also what's called birds of a
feather sessions boss
they are like well let's get together
and see and maybe if there's enough
interest we'll propose a new working
group in a particular area sometimes it
happens uh sometimes it doesn't happen i
think you're leaving above right on jose
on
signatures in in
json-based signatures i forget the thing
but that's that's close enough you can
find them they're all listed in the
agenda um sometimes it doesn't we had a
buff that was like let's discuss
internet file systems think things like
dropbox google drive and so on and
the conclusion at the end of that was
well we don't have anything to
contribute and none of the people like
dropbox and google drive are here so we
could do a spec but nobody would use it
and that goes against one of our core
tenants which is the best specifications
of those that are used
there are area-wide sessions the biggest
area being
the plenary latin word meeting all of us
that's for administrative stuff the
different groups that i mentioned at the
beginning the
iesg the iab will present about what's
new the corporate parent
the ietf
limited liability corporation called the
llc will present on the
finances
nominating committee of which i am the
chair will say hey
you should try out for these positions
and things like that um sometimes
there's a technical presentation
uh not this time there are also there's
a social event
that is it the
barnes museum world's largest collection
of renoir cesan i forgot it's both the
same
tickets are available when you
registered if you don't have one you can
post on the mailing list saying anybody
got a special social ticket
common use of the attendees list
um
the irtf meets those are
research focused things on private
things like privacy
uh cryptographic research
what do we do about post-quantum crypto
a lot of cryptographers are involved in
the itf
uh there's a hackathon which was mainly
yesterday and is winding down today so
next time around consider coming earlier
if you have code that implements
some of the itf specs
bring it work with your colleagues
competitors and make sure everything
interoperates it's a it's a great event
it's free
with your ietf registration
you get a second t-shirt
it's cool
um
tutorials deep dives there's uh
i forget when it is but there is a
technical presentation by our host on
tuesday tuesday
hot rfc in this case
deliberate but rfc stands for request
for conversation
uh the host of that is remote people
have videotaped a 10-minute presentation
that says
i think we should
figure out how to do signatures so cars
can talk to each other so they don't
crash
so pretty they'll present for a few
minutes if you're interested you go out
and follow up with them afterwards it's
very kind of neat there's side meetings
which are after the regular sessions
where anybody can sign up
in the mailings if you look there's a
wiki
where people can sign up and say i want
to have a side meeting to talk about
whatever it is that might be of interest
it's sort of like a informal buff but
not really
um then there's open time between the
sessions
uh
there's you know we serve the breakfast
i'm disappointed it's more than just
starchy old pastries but during
breakfast what's called the hallway
track right you can bump in and meet
people and talk to them and that's a
very important part and beneficial part
of the face-to-face meetings next
the working group sessions this is a
picture from the before times right
we can see the back of everyone's head
but nowadays everyone is masked
most work is done on mailing lists every
working group
like i said there's over 100 of them has
its own mailing list just join
read for a while
if you go to the data tracker site
dt.ietf.org is the shorthand name you
can search for a working group and see
what documents they're working on
you can subscribe to the mailing list
you can
search the mailing list and find
comments that people have made once
you're caught up to speed
and and feel comfortable talking about
something because you read the documents
or you read previous drafts
feel free to you know speak up
using the the meet echo tool or
or post on the mailing list okay
no problem
most of the work is done on the mailing
list and what's different about ietf
meetings
working group meetings uh from many
other standards organizations is someone
will stand up
and their slides which will be
just a bullet list but without the
picture
because it's all just text
you know here's what changed since the
last time
here's the issue that we still have to
resolve four or five bullets or two or
three bullets
if you don't know what happened last
time then you're going to be lost
so one good way an important way to
prepare for the working groups that
you're interested in is look through the
documents scan them
skim the ones that you're most
interested in so that when somebody
stands up
and speaks in some cases at a very very
rapid clip unfortunately
okay so what we did last time is we
changed the packet size from 128 to 256
okay
uh yeah sure but anyhow um it's a
presentation of the diffs of what
happened what changed and the things
that are now open issues that the
working group has to decide about
the sessions are all streamed and
recorded using the meat echo tool
in addition they are also available on
our youtube channel after the fact and
it takes a couple days to upload
everything
the working group what the working group
works on is called the charter
and that is
negotiated with the relevant area
director and the working group chairs
next
birds of a feather session
person's not masked but
uh
usually a working group has a baf first
and they will say things like working
group forming buff or non-working group
forming buff there's probably discussion
of the proposed charter what's
interesting let's see who shows up at
that meeting and they're scheduled
during the regular ietf sessions
just to see who's interested and if it's
worth trying to progress and it's up to
the area directors
approved by the iesg
to make those decisions
bath meets once
irtf
the folks here the young men here uh
one
one of the things the irtf does is give
out a prize for the best networking
oriented paper
um so there's one on
coming up on fingerprinting i think this
year how you can tell what a site is
doing by looking at the order in which
the records appear in tls as i recall
another is on looking at the various
costs
cpu costs of encrypting dns protocols
they meet irtf meets during part of the
regular ietf session the irtf open
session is where
the
best research papers are presented and
they get
you know accommodations to come and a
stipend
and usually it's graduate students right
working and so a thousand bucks means a
lot to them
there is a primer
rfc 7418
that explains what the irtf does but you
can sort of
catch it up by context next
can can i just
can i just interject one thing here um
when you're looking at the ie at the
schedule uh you'll see the research
groups this week you will also see anrw
which is the advanced network and
research workshop
the and that those uh have been papers
that have been selected to come so it's
a parallel activity to the ietf that's
generally done once a year and it's on
the agenda this week it's also done
in conjunction with the irtf
so
i would look for both of those for
potential research topics um and i just
wanted to be sure that that was great
yeah and
the anrw is actually an acm workshop so
it's got you know real credentials and
presumably it's a lot harder to get
papers though right and the uh anrp the
prize where they present their work
that's paper papers that have already
been published in other venues
uh that are then nominated as a topic
that might be of interest to the ietf
um and i don't remember when the call
for that is but every year there's a
call
and a set of nominations i think we have
an anrp
presenter in here for this so
um
but anyway so the uh if you if you are
an academic um in addition to
using the anrw as a means to present
your work to publish your work you can
also present work that you've published
elsewhere through the anrp
a r yeah anrp right a rp a rw the ietf
loves its
tlas
flies okay
um
birds no wrong correction okay the
area-wide sessions so almost many areas
have um
pardon me a session
for
all of the groups to come
within their area uh they will and
there's two kinds there is the general
area session so they'll be like
transport
here's where each of the working groups
gives a two sentence summary of what's
happened or what will be happening at
their thing
and then there's also dispatch
there might be an invited speaker
sometimes
then there's also dispatch
there's various dispatch groups where
somebody comes up and says
this is something in the
transport area i have a new version of
how gateways talk to each other
where should i go with it um and the
dispatch the people who go to dispatch
the transport dispatch or the art
applications dispatch or the sec
dispatch for security will figure out
and they can make a couple of decisions
one an area director should just support
it we should consider creating a whole
new work group or oh well you're new to
the ietf with new work and you probably
didn't realize that this group over here
is working on gateway interactions so
you
go to them and see if they want to work
on you know adopt your draft
um
plenary as i said is
the whole group it meets a lot of
administrative stuff
um
a lot of you know interest here's the
financial breakdown here are here's the
corp the country breakdown of attendees
here's how it compares to the previous
time you know lots of interesting
administrative administrivia i guess is
the term
um invited lunch talks there's a
part of the emo door has a working group
chair lunch for all of the working group
chairs to
get together and talk and say well you
know this is a problem one thing the
ietf has done for example in the past
couple of years is much more embracing
of github
the open source platform and so there's
often discussion about how to handle
that there is no as you might expect an
rfc on how to use github but
you know github is one of the places
where developers congregate so we want
to be where the developers are to to get
their feedback and so on
next
hackathons so this
was
again pre-pandemic picture it's also
they also do it remote during the week
but it's a place to work on new
protocols
quick a secure transport protocol they
had several hackathons where they people
were working on different versions of
the draft and they want to make sure by
the time the rfc is done
that
a it's possible to implement this thing
b it's not crazy stupid and doesn't
require all of your cpu to just ship a
packet
and see that it works across a whole
bunch of different implementations
tls did the same thing dns is doing the
same thing so there's a lot
right now there's a research project
going on about how you do multicast
where you know you can do point-to-point
or you can do broadcast everybody on the
net but
over the general internet you want to be
able to do multicast let me send one
for example let me send one copy
of the packets for this movie to an
entire apartment building because
they're all watching it or a major
sporting event the premier league the us
super bowl uh because everybody's
watching it so it's much more efficient
for me to just send it once
next
uh the hackathon uh anyone can attend
you get free food another free t-shirt
um the idea is to flush out things and
everybody brings what they do back to
their respective working groups um and
there's often a mini presentation within
the working group that says hey here's
what happened in the past few days
um it we do get developers we get many
people who come only for the hackathon
because it's zero cost
we get a lot of academics
or student you know and or students
it's a mix of people veterans newcomers
and so on it's a really good time
uh and until the weekend you know
yesterday and today so too late but next
time
and there's an rfc coming out that
describes how to run one of these things
you might expect social events uh on the
left side the big blue was held at the
singapore national aquarium
it was kind of cool you know
there was no sushi serve but there are
plenty of fish to look at
um on the right is
i
i really wanted to do stand up no
on the right is the the sisters event uh
for you know women at the ietf
um
a local community no a community of
people uh of women uh support because of
you know as you can tell obviously in
tech
they're not not as well supported
there's more um side meetings we haven't
figured out quite the agenda
they're not
official ietf meetings but they should
follow the same rules they're not stream
video unless someone opens up their
laptop and does their own uses their own
zoom meet google me discord
blue jeans webex i think i can name them
all all the ones i know about all the
ones that are on my machine
but they're not officially part of the
ietf multimedia experience
there is a deep dive on quick
tuesday morning i guess before breakfast
is served
and then there's a blog post that talks
about new topics that are new to the
ietf this time
and so on
i think i'm done oh meeting etiquette
okay
it really helps to read the documents of
the groups you're interested in you can
also just sit back and listen and maybe
you'll be lost sometimes
integrated with meat echo is the zulu
chat system
it's a test text
instant messaging system like
jabber or slack
but you know different and better
um we want to be respectful and tolerant
of everybody
uh we don't want to you know we want to
make sure everyone feels welcome and
able to contribute or judge solely based
on you know your technical contributions
have a good time it's a real pain to
walk around
mast all the time go out get some fresh
air
and then realize whoa it's way too hot
out there and come back inside
okay um
yeah so the online version you can't
quite see it but
there
is a raise your hand so in any of the
other sessions if you want to talk
you can ask questions while someone's
presenting generally people will present
there's an agenda with you know time
limits
then there will be a time for general
question and answer or things like hey
did you consider that you know
motorcycles need to be able to avoid
cars too
um
you know going back to hyper effective
example
the local version turns off the audio
and video
uh
remote you know use headsets sort of all
of the standard video conferencing
things that we've gotten too tired of uh
comments and questions are welcome
um don't say you know
i couldn't hear you with the mask you
know try to speak slowly
state your name uh when you speak and
you'll come up to the mic when the chair
recognizes you um
because
people taking the minutes uh don't know
everybody's name it's especially hard to
hear with them see some recognize
somebody with the mask on
there's an integrated chat
that's also gateway to and from the
zulip chat system
so that there's text messaging available
sometimes it's a snarky back channel
sometimes it's a really good place to
ask clarifying questions of the room
it all depends on the on the working
group
briefly how to bring new work uh
there um
[Music]
before you have a baff even before you
know you can just go to someone hey i'm
really concerned about this um it might
be worth
writing up something a draft every
document in the itf starts out and we
call it an internet draft
id or generally a draft
drafts
are the product of working groups
you can submit an individual draft all
done through the data tracker
if you go to the
authors.ihf.org website
there is some tutorial information on
how to format your document and the
tooling available to sort of get it all
nice and pretty and make the html look
good or the pdf or what have you
there's a tutorial online
you can see it
there
on the links these slides will be
available
and also you can find out
how
we have a question
is that what that means
it means that carl is in the queue is
carl clear or remote come on join the
queue yeah
excellent i was hoping somebody would
demonstrate this right
yeah i
hi karl klatsky i partially just wanted
to try it make sure it worked for the
real meetings
but my other quick question is is there
anyone around uh for in-person help on
the data tracker account
apparently i had an account from a few
years back and had ids linked to it but
then my email changed and i got the
right message sure
a little bit later in there there's an
email address support at iatf.org
you send an email to that it addresses a
bunch of issues like things like your
account
uh and if that doesn't solve it then
there's a separate data tracker bug but
what you're talking about it's not
really a bug it's an authentication
issue yeah so all meeting issues go to
support at ietf.org
yeah
okay
and now we know the queue works and well
yeah thank you
thanks carl
next oh wait i'm on the rocks hold on a
second
oh so that's me okay
so i'm doing the fourth part of this
which is um
the basically a whole bunch of resources
and information uh pointers to groups of
people that would be useful and you're
going to have to advance my slides
um
so uh go backwards one
so first of all just a short word about
ietf participants and culture it's a
very passionate vocal culture
but don't be shy be sure to ask
questions
because we are all here to help
technical excellence is highly valued
you know so if you're working in a field
and you see some issues be sure to speak
up
you know a number of us as you've
already figured out it's uh informal
dress code
so it's not a definitely not a coat and
tie place and a lot of people here have
been working with each other for a long
time and you'll notice that over time
people
who participate in the ietf will move
companies but they'll still maintain
their ietf participation as they're
moving from company to company
so it's a culture that we're fairly
proud of it's also a culture that we are
trying to improve by being sure that we
are as inclusive and
positive as we can be because sometimes
the world is
a negative place
next slide
so
with that
caveat we do have an ombuds team which
i'm going to talk about in a little bit
later we do have an anti-harassment
policy
if you are at all concerned about any
behavior that you witness or experience
in the ietf uh there's sort of like
four levels that you can go through uh
the first one is you can speak to the
working group chairs in the working
group that you speak that you are
concerned about
or you can go to the area directors
and then lars eggert is the general
chair of the ietf
and then beyond that we have the ombuds
team if you go to the next slide
um
the exact i really should put the ombuds
team is later in here and i really
should move it so it's right after that
slide
this is what happens when you look at
the slides but you don't actually
present them so jay daley is the
executive director of the ihf so he's
responsible for all the administrative
side of the house and keeping everything
in operations next slide
the ietf secretariat
they are the
staff that are the event planners and do
all the basic logistics and keep us all
um in cookies and in t-shirts and in
rooms with all of the things that they
do
there will be a registration desk that's
staffed all week that'll have people
there they can ask
any questions of they are super helpful
and um
and they are also they're always there
for
a
friendly smile if you need one which
sometimes one does need next slide
uh
there i'm i did not double check to make
sure and in the pre-pandemic times there
were two tables one would be the rfc
editor staff and one would be the iana
staff and they would be down somewhere
in the general area of the registration
desk these are two functions that are
key to the work of the ietf the rfc
editor obviously
publishes all of our documents so if
you're trying to get a document through
and you need to talk to somebody about
some issue that you're having you can go
up to their desk and ask them
and then also the iana staff manages all
of your protocol number assignments so
you know if you want to register a
number you're going to have to go
through ayanna you have to have an iana
consideration section in any rfc that
you might be writing and so you would go
and speak to the iana staff
you can also contact them on email but
sometimes if you're here and in person
just walking up and talking to somebody
at least putting a face to a name for
the staff would be really helpful
they will have office hours thank you
both groups will have office hours so
you can you'll find their tables
downstairs um and i should have double
checked that
next slide
uh so this is the ombuds team is the
slide which i will move up in the
presentation uh so these are long-term
three long-term ietf participants uh and
and they're sort of your uh
your your final arbiters to go to to
uh
to uh report any uh behavior that you're
not happy with or in any way in which
you feel like
you're witnessing or experiencing
harassment in the ietf
um
and even if you just want to talk to
them about you know i'm i'm not sure how
to deal with this you're not it's not a
it's not necessarily a formal complaints
process it's it's a
a set of it's a set of resources to go
and talk to
uh to see about uh how you might improve
something
next slide
so the ietf sisters
this got mentioned before this is a
group
for
women and people that identify as women
or non-binary
and
the website is there it's it's really a
very informal group of people uh we do
get together during the ietf and have
lunch and i think we have a sister's
networking event this week which is also
on the calendar
and there's a mailing list
so the number of us
have been
participating for a long time
and it's it's just a friendly group of
people to as a resource to go to
next slide
uh data tracker you've heard rich
mentioned data tracker a lot this week
if there's one thing that you need to
learn
one place you need to get to for the
ietf it's the data tracker because it
has
all of the resources associated with the
working group it has all of the meetings
uh it has all the materials and i put
the tls working group up here and you
you can't really see it in there but if
you look at the tab across the top you
know right underneath the transport
layer security it says about and then
documents and meetings
and uh something i can't read and photos
and email and the list archive so it has
all of the artifacts associated with the
working group
um if you go to the about tab it'll give
you who the chairs are what the charter
is any additional resources that they
might have identified
so
and
this tool has evolved quite a bit in the
last few years
and in fact the code sprint portion of
the ietf is the tools team basically all
getting together and doing some extra
work on the data tracker
it's getting much better it's highly
tailored to the work of the ietf
there is a bug reporting system and and
there is a tools team so you can even
follow along in the work that they're
doing if you're interested in that but
if you really want to get into the work
of the ietf you need to spend a little
bit of time getting familiar with the
data tracker
next slide
increasing people on the queue i don't
know
oh i think you can you can take people
to the
i guess we
we'll just go ahead and assume you're
yeah are you i'm john oh hi john yeah i
was just wondering if the tools team has
office hours or if we can ask them
questions because the tools are
yeah i don't know if they have office
hours but um
wait somebody
is that an it
oh
oh that's a really good idea yeah
they're at the hackathon
under the sign that says i think it says
code sprint right it says code sprint
that's the tools team
excellent um
robert
oh i'm sorry lena i'm sorry i just
looked at the second yellow box
excellent hi i'm lena uh you mentioned
this sister's organization and the
networking event on tuesday is it
something that you have to join and
pre-register for or you can just show up
and uh
attend the the event
um
you know we have historically had a sign
up but i haven't seen one this time but
i do know there's a sister's lunch so i
think there's two on the agenda so i
would say just show up
but i would join the mailing list
right and isn't there's a lunch on
thursday right
yeah there's a lunch on thursday that's
the one i always remember
uh so i would show up this week
if it is a sign up we can always put one
one more person in it's just for um
catering purposes so
uh
robert
yes thank you um
when i was preparing i found an ios app
called ietfers
and i downloaded a bit it seems to be
pointing back at an older meeting is it
a newer version
i don't know the the mobile stuff is is
taking a hiatus let's say so yeah
yeah i think it's working okay
okay thank you
okay so
apparently it is working on
ios but
us android users are out of luck yeah i
i think you need she's
uh she's right i believe you have to
select the new meeting i'll have to
admit i haven't actually looked this
time i usually have it up by now but
i haven't done it this time um
i thought there was somebody else in the
queue but cube
so the next person is the next slide is
meat echo so all of the we as
you know ihf really we really like our
custom tools and so the next custom tool
that we have is the the conferencing
system that we have
it is web-based
and it is
run by a small team of gentlemen that
are in the knock
there is a
an additional page that gives you lots
of information about meat echo for those
of you on site you're you're not really
going to be using the full meat echo
you're going to be using the version on
your phone that just checks you in and
puts you in the queue
and there are also practice sessions for
any of you that are remote that you can
use if you go to the next slide
uh the ietf network you've probably also
seen like i don't know i mean there
might be eight or nine ssids that we
have now we do have our own network here
that we run
we deploy
wireless for all of the meeting rooms
and then we
provide
we don't provide we don't we don't
substitute out the aps that are in the
hotel but what we do do
is we get the hotel to add our
ssid on there and then it uses our
uplink
so we do have a full network team here
there is a printer along with the help
desk that is usually staffed by one or
two of the knock guys one floor down
so if you need to print anything or if
you have any network or technical
questions related to the network
you can stop and see them
and that was a picture of them right
before their morning meeting this
morning
next slide
so there's some additional resources
you've already probably in the newcomers
email that you received gotten the link
to all of the newcomer information
there's also a towel of the ietf which
goes on has a ton of ton of information
there's uh all of the main meeting
mailing lists are there there's a
one-stop shop for all of the links and i
mentioned this one that the person asked
earlier but if you have any meeting
issues
the email is support ietf.org it's a
ticketing system and it'll get sent to
whoever needs it whether it's an
authentication issue or a
you know whatever kind of issue you
might have uh next slide
i think i'm done above all i hope you
enjoy the meeting if you have any
questions be sure to ask
and then go to the next slide
and
questions or feedback what did we miss
come to our feedback sessions or send us
email
because you know our objective here is
to make your entry into the ietf as
seamless as possible
and with that
if there are no more questions thank you
all for attending
and we finished with one minute to spare
thanks
[Applause]
you can't tell we've done this before
apparently
[Music]
yes
i actually tried to do that like
walking two different sessions one more
time
nope can't do that yeah
your browser was getting slower and
slower
came back
i think i got most of the links
updated okay