yes
oh
okay hello everyone
can everyone hear me
those of you in the back is it good is
it way too loud or is it good
it's good awesome okay
all right we're gonna get uh get things
started here so if you can you know find
a seat and uh
uh make it easy for everyone to to hear
and see that'd be great
um
so let me start by welcoming all of you
to the uh to the hackathon it's great
great to be back here and to be able to
meet in person again
uh
we met for the first time in person
after not meeting for a couple years
right in vienna
and we had i think about 100 or so
people there i think where it looks like
we're going to have about double that
here
so that's fantastic to see i'm super
excited about it i hope you are too
um
just wanted to get a quick show of hands
for how many of you this is your first
time at an ietf hackathon
okay
i i thought there were a lot of faces i
didn't recognize and uh part of it i
thought was because of mass and covid
but uh but yeah we actually do have a
lot of new people so so welcome i i hope
this is a great experience for you i
hope you really enjoy it i
we're we're a great group of uh people
here at the hackathon so feel free to
reach out to those around you and and
those of you who saw another newcomer
here you know
maybe just go that little extra step to
introduce yourself and and help make
sure that uh that everyone gets involved
in a project uh that'd be great
um
and then so how many of you this is your
first time to ever be in any type of
ietf event
it's oh almost the same yeah okay
well uh i think you came to the right
place i'm a little biased because i've
been running the hackathon for a while
now but but i think it's a great
introduction into the ietf and a great
way to
you know really start getting involved
right away around around code that's
implementing the standards we're doing
that's a big part of the hackathon so
um so i think you made a great choice
and i'm glad you're here
and then
you know
kovit things are getting better every
day still fortunately some up and downs
but uh i'm wondering how many of you
this is your first time at an in-person
event since
uh coveted
so we have a number of that too so
uh
you know i'm glad you're here um for for
those of you who have had a little bit
more experience with this think back to
the first time you were at an in-person
event um since covet started and so you
know we all have different comfort
levels with with kovid
and
you know the ietf meeting we have some
pretty strict rules that are a little
stricter than what you may be used to at
conferences um
it it's okay to not wear a mask when
you're presenting uh it's like when i'm
presenting today or tomorrow when we do
the presentations it's okay to not wear
a mask obviously when you're eating or
drinking
but uh but we have been asked to wear
masks otherwise so when you're in this
room when you're working try to keep
your mask on unless you're eating or
drinking when you leave the room
and go out into the hallway please make
sure you have a mask on we're trying to
keep mass you know within the ietf venue
as much as possible so just to keep us
all safe since there there will uh
thankfully be a large number of us here
so well you know let's do what we can to
follow those rules and especially for
those people who uh this is their first
event since cove would make it a little
bit easier for them too but but really
easier for all of us
so
you know the reason we're here is i
mentioned this a little bit at the
beginning this is really we want to
advance the pace and relevance of all
the work we do in the ietf
you know we do a lot of great work with
standards i think our standards
fortunately get get implemented and
deployed and run the internet that's
fantastic but by by working on them by
implementing them at the same time that
we're we're writing them and improving
them you know we really get the best of
both worlds and we make you know we
create some code that people can use to
help them in their deployment um so
that's really fantastic so i'm glad
you're here and also another big part of
the hackathon is to to extend the ietf
community and to to welcome new people
into it and and i think you saw with the
show of hands we're we're doing well in
that regard as well
um
lars are you here
yeah lars um i'd like to
welcome the itf chair uh lars up he's
a huge supporter and participator in the
hackathon and uh
mike is yours
thank you hi i'm lars eckerda charity
iatf and thanks charles and thanks all
of you for being here um i don't quite
remember how long we've been doing
hackathons but must be well over 10
years now and i think
2015 so not it feels like 10 years but
but not quite uh but they've certainly
sort of become
like really one of the best events i
think around the itf in my opinion
because this is sort of what it's all
about right it's like actually getting
stuff
done and shipped and deployed and
interoperable and while we do that
during the week as well right there we
care mostly about the technical
standards and then you know writing
english that's correct and easy to
implement but here we actually write
code which is a little bit closer to um
what we all want to do i think rather in
writing specs writing code feels like
more fulfilling um
i also want to say that we have had a
sort of separate event for a while
called the itf tools code sprint
which has been in a different room up
until now sort of as an experiment this
time we sort of
relocated that here so it's the table
over there that i'm also hanging out
those are the people that work on the
tools that make the itf work the data
tracker xml to rfc mail archive and so
on so if you have an interest in that
come say hi and and if they have bugs
file them and we'll hopefully get them
fixed for you um
the other thing i want to mention is
that uh there was a noisy piece of
equipment in that corner the door got
closed so there's a group up here that's
doing l4s which is a new congestion
control thing for the internet that
originated
on the research side a couple years ago
and it's now sort of getting close to
deployment so there's people from
comcast who are also sponsoring the
meeting
i think there's some operators involved
i think bt
as well there's um i think apple and
meta and google and some other um people
who have end systems and then they're
going to try and actually get this into
operate so if that's of interest to you
come and say hi um take a look at the
rack it's pretty impressive if you want
to bring equipment you can so this was a
good example
just let us know ahead of time like
these guys did and then we'll figure out
how to make that work for you
otherwise enjoy the day keep your mess
on please we already had a corona case
this morning reported so it's a thing
it's for your safety it's for other
people's safety we want to keep the
number down
in vienna we had i think around five
people over the course of the week which
is
a unfortunately high number but it's
actually a low number compared to what
the corona people in vienna were
expecting to see so i'm hoping that we
can leave philadelphia and also have the
absolute minimum number of exposures
that we can manage for meeting this size
um enjoy today
enjoy the company write some code and
then i'll see you during the week thank
you
all right
thank you lars
okay so um
you know just a reminder especially for
those of you who are new to
ietf but really for everything for
everyone everything we do in ietf falls
under the the note well it's good to if
you haven't already made yourself
familiar with this it's uh
good to familiarize yourself with it it
you know
it talks about the
rules and procedures of the ietf what it
means to participate in the ietf so um
you know good to take a look at that one
thing that it doesn't really uh that is
a little different though is is uh
around code because what you present in
an ietf meeting that's all an ietf
contribution but the code that you work
on is a little bit different in that
there's
usually hopefully a license associated
with it and so you also need to be aware
of the the rules and the requirements
and the obligations that you have when
using that code base and extending that
code base so so be sure to pay attention
to the the license of the code that
you're working on because that code base
is not actually an
ietf contribution it's it's governed by
the the license of the code that you're
working on but the presentations that
that we do and that i'm doing now that
you'll do uh tomorrow hopefully you know
that that does fall under the normal
ietf rules and is an ietf contribution
so if you're not familiar with the note
well i i
recommend you do that
uh now project so we have a lot of great
projects you heard about one that i'm
super excited a couple actually that i'm
really excited to have here the code
sprint and the l4s project
but we have a lot of other great
projects too
they are all listed on the wiki if you
haven't taken a look at all those
projects or figured out which one you
want to work on
i suggest you do that now take a look at
the wiki we had we have over 20 projects
and uh the the name of the champion and
kind of what the project is about is
there and then you can just go find that
table and and talk with those people
if you are having a hard time finding a
project we have a a
a wiki page called the lost and found
and that's kind of to serve a couple
purposes one is if you're
if you're looking for people with partic
particular expertise to join your
project you can advertise that there if
you're looking to help a project and you
have like some some uh things that
you're interested in or skills you can
offer
you can put that there as well so it's
that it's to help match uh people the
projects
okay the agenda we are running uh pretty
much on time and uh you can see where we
are on the agenda we're doing a quick uh
kickoff here
and then
um you know really this first part of
the morning is uh take some extra time
to make sure that we get our teams
formed
that um
and if you haven't found a team you can
come and you need some help you can come
talk to me but really talk to those
around you
and uh and let's try to make sure that
everyone finds a team that they are
comfortable in that they feel they can
contribute to
because uh you know that's the best way
to make the
the best use of this weekend if um if
you're have if you're struggling with
that don't just you know stay quiet
about it reach out and ask for some help
there's many of us here who are familiar
with a lot of the people in a lot of the
projects and can help you get situated
in order to make it easy for you to
continue to work on your projects
throughout the day lunch will be served
out where you saw the snacks this
morning uh we'll have lunch brought in
so
uh we welcome and encourage you to stay
here and have lunch with all of us
continue to work on your projects
there'll be some some food it breaks and
then we will have dinner too for those
of you who are
available to stay and don't already have
other plans we'd love to have you stay
and continue to
to work and network during the evening
to have dinner here
and then the room will close at nine and
we'll be pretty strict about that you're
welcome to continue to work on your
project outside you can use the ietf
network and all that but we just need to
close this room and let the hotel staff
like shut it down and so so they can
have their uh
you know their evening wrapped up as
well
the next morning uh tomorrow that the
doors open same time they did today
around 9 30
and
you can come in lunch will be provided
again tomorrow
the main thing i want to call your
attention to is that we will be doing
these project presentations
starting at 2 o'clock where you can give
a brief um overview of what you did and
what you accomplished and what you
learned
those will start at two o'clock so keep
that in mind that a little bit before
two
or maybe a while before two you wanna be
starting to put together a a short
presentation um those are short just
like four minutes i'll talk about those
a little bit in a minute but just in
terms of the the timing i wanted to
point that out
and then at four o'clock we we want to
be done here with all those
presentations because there's other
activities like newcomers
uh events and uh
and the
the welcome reception we want to make
sure everyone has time to get to those
yeah if you did have some equipment that
you brought in
and you've set it up in here
you can leave it overnight if you're
comfortable doing that but we do ask
that by five o'clock you have it out of
here so this room can be turned over and
into the next uh kind of setup that it's
going to have
any questions about the agenda
okay
so
uh as we started using gather um as a
way to interact especially with people
who aren't here in person but even for
those who are here in person
um we have the the
the gather space that you can go to and
there's kind of the virtual ietf in
there what i'm showing here is from 113
but it'll look very similar for 114.
uh just don't have the updated slides
for that
um there is you'll see uh some arrows
here i lit up in red pointing to where
the hackathon room is there's a virtual
hackathon room if you
move over there with your little
character you can go into the hackathon
room the hackathon room looks a little
similar to this and has tables
especially if you're working where you
have some remote participants in your
team
you um
you may want to and i welcome you to go
ahead and
you know pick out one of these tables
and you can kind of assign you know you
can say hey table a is going to be for
us
and whatever your team name is and you
can so you can use that as a virtual
meeting space where the people here in
the room and and the people who are
working online can can have a
you know a space to meet and you can
share documents within there you can
share notes there's some nice
capabilities within it to help you
collaborate with you know especially
with remote participants
and i think i forgot to mention it but
there is a let me go back to the agenda
there is this team schedule
um and you can put down in that team
schedule it's another wiki page and
especially if you have remote
participants it's good to say well these
particular hours this is when we're
going to have sort of a meeting between
the virtual and the people in the room
or for the people who are working
virtually this is the way to communicate
with the people in the room you can use
whatever you want you can use gather and
i just you know showed that and you can
pick a table you can say we're at table
a or you can set up a zoom session you
can you know use webex you can do
whatever you're comfortable with
just uh this
team schedule is a way to capture that
and share that
so going forward again we talked about
gather
hacknet that's another cool capability
we have this lets you connect
especially for people who are remote to
connect into
a virtual ietf network but even for
those of you who are here if you want
something special um it effectively is a
layer 2 network and we can offer some
some interesting capabilities beyond
what you would typically get when you
you just sign in via wi-fi to the ietf
network and we can allocate that that
out to you so if you have special
requirements for your project which some
of you have because you're working on
networking protocols
you can make requests
to get that set up and we can get that
set up for you
i mentioned the results presentations so
these are very short presentations where
you just give a high level of what you
tried to do what you actually
accomplished what you learned
that type of thing and it's a great way
to share just briefly with the ietf
community so they we have a little bit
better understanding of of your project
and because we we're probably going to
have a lot of these and we want to get
through them all
we we keep them to four minutes and we
will be pretty strict on that
we'll start a timer and so
you know when you're putting these
presentations together just i'm giving
you a heads up now do keep them short
less than four minutes is great
um but definitely no more than four
minutes so just to give us a high level
idea of what you accomplished and i'll
talk in a minute about a way you can
give like a more extended presentation
but this is kind of the quick one just
to introduce people to your project and
and kind of get you know ongoing
communication going
okay since we are working on code
perhaps you need a place to to keep uh
to kind of host the software you're
working on
if you do need a space for your project
and you don't already you've not already
figured out like a place on github or
elsewhere to to host it we can create a
repo for you within the ietf hackathon
github organization we're happy to do
that if you want that you can just
come see me or send a message to
the hackathon chairs list and barry and
i will take care of that
we have a
a repo set up specifically for the
project presentations though so if you
are interested in presenting your
project this is where you will upload uh
that project presentation so that we
have all of them available at two
o'clock tomorrow when it comes time to
do those
if you go into that repo you'll find a
couple things one is
a couple templates which you're welcome
to use one is a html template the other
is a powerpoint template you can use
those as just a template to help you
put together your project presentation
um
a lot of people have found those useful
in the past and i i recommend you take a
look because it it kind of just gives
you an idea of sort of the high level
format and type of information we're
looking for
the other thing that's in there is this
readme file
and you should always read readme files
and what this one will tell you was
it'll give you a bit more information
about the templates but it's also going
to tell you that
in in order to make things simple rather
than do the normal github thing of
sending a pull request and having
someone review it and then approve it
we want to make give all of you access
to to be committers
so all of you can upload your own
presentations in order to make that work
you need to become a member of the ietf
hackathon organization within github
so you can request that membership
barry and i probably barry he's been
quick to respond to those
can get you added to that group and if
you think you're going to be presenting
if you aren't already in the ietf github
organization make that request sooner
rather than later so we can get you
added now and you just get your access
set up and out of the way because if you
wait until two o'clock tomorrow
things are going to get busy and
uh something might fall off the table we
won't get you set up right
there's also some rules there like we
want to make sure we know who everyone
is so if you can as part of your github
account if you haven't already make sure
you put down the name that that you want
that you go by
so that we'll know who's who
and also enable two-factor
authentication just so that we don't you
know we get a little bit more security
as to who we're giving right access to
the the ietf hackathon org
and if you have any questions about that
you can come see me you can come see
barry
one other thing i want to point out is
we're we're really trying to make uh
advance the pace of the work we're doing
right and so by a lot of this is about
code and many of you thankfully for your
projects you have links to
uh the code where to find the code
associated with your project on the ietf
hackathon wiki and that's fantastic but
for those who who aren't here those who
are going to go and read the drafts and
the rfcs we want them to be able to find
that code too so this related
implementations this is something great
that actually the
the the tools team and i forget if it
came out of a code sprint last time but
it got implemented by some of the same
folks
they enabled this functionality and
that's where you can make use of this
additional resources if you go to the
data tracker you'll see something called
additional resources and and i've used
that before to associate um to tell you
where my
uh that my draft is in github but now
there's a new thing called related
implementations and you can do use this
to indicate where code related to that
draft is associated and you can put one
or more of these depending on if you
have more than one code project
but
if you click on edit it'll bring you to
a page like this and sorry it's a little
small but you can download these uh
these slides and see it a little bit
better
and you can you can add in one of these
related implementations and then uh the
the address of where the code is in a
little text description so it's really
handy it helps people find code related
to the draft that you're working on
i think this is great functionality i
would really recommend and ask that you
make use of it and hopefully we get
people more accustomed to this idea of
there being running code associated with
drafts and with rfcs i think that would
be fantastic
okay just a couple more things
i mentioned the hackathon ends it you
know tomorrow afternoon
and we have these really short
presentations well if you want to give a
more extended presentation if you want
time for like engaging with the entire
ietf community not just those in this
room and you want more time we have this
thing called hack demo happy hour and
that will be monday
evening from 5 30 to 6 30. you can sign
up um it's actually in this same room
this is liberty a it'll be in this room
we'll have tables set up you can um have
demos of your project and you can really
engage one-on-one with people for longer
periods of time right so you can have
that more in-depth conversation that you
weren't able to have during the
four-minute presentation so i i
recommend you take advantage of that
if you are interested in doing that just
let us know
anytime starting now until uh noon
monday so that we make sure we have
enough tables set up to accommodate
everyone
and then one more thing also in this
same room all week you are welcome to
come down here and work on your projects
there'll be
there'll be some tables set up they
might be in a different arrangement than
they are here
but you're welcome to come there'll be
power there'll be you know this setup so
you can all gather around the table and
work on your projects there's a schedule
so you can
not just reserve a table but more to
advertise to people hey we're going to
be in this room at 12 o'clock from this
time to this time so that they know they
can come and meet you here and that's a
really handy thing to be able to do too
so it's not like when the hackathon ends
you can't work on your projects anymore
and then i definitely want to thank our
our sponsor uh cnn nick
obviously it takes some financial
resources to put these things on the
food the space
and we thank cnn nick for for helping us
the t-shirts cost money to produce too
so so we have we have a lot of costs and
uh so thank you to cnn nick and i would
encourage others if you have the ability
to talk with those within your
organization we're always happy to have
more sponsors and looking for more
sponsors
and with that uh any any questions
you can of course come see me anytime
i'll cause i'll be floating around here
but if you had any questions or anything
you wanted to share with the group
before we get started we do have a
microphone there
okay well then thank you all for your
attention i really appreciate it i know
you want to
talk to everyone and get working on your
projects but uh
thanks for for helping me get through
all that and i hope you have a great
hackathon and a great ietf meeting
[Applause]
oh sure let me put this back on