okay
tell me to go yup just a minute
all right we're going to get started in
about one minute
and it seems like we've got folks uh
online as well so hopefully you can hear
the audio okay
you can't hear me right now
you can okay
all right thanks everybody for joining
today i'd like to introduce introduce
ilad nafshi
elad serves as our chief network officer
and he's an executive vice president at
comcast
he's in charge of our unified core and
access network so basically the entire
network end-to-end that supports all of
our products
so it's a huge technical organization
and he's got tons of experience and
energy but i'll let him continue from
there and begin his talk thank you for
joining us a lot thank you so much for
having me jason thank you everyone for
being here uh both in person and
virtually it is so good to see people
again uh and it's so good to uh you know
to be able to interact in these forums
uh and i really appreciate um everyone
both virtually and um especially here in
the room for taking the time and joining
us um i'm gonna be describing our path
to what we call 10ge which is really the
continuous progression on the network uh
as we continue to uh uh to work and grow
our um connectivity business okay
um i will have time uh for questions at
the end
so you know feel free to
ask away uh and in the meantime let's
just get right into it
and uh a lot as you speak bring the mic
a little closer sorry for the stream
is it better now it is excellent well
first and foremost welcome
welcome to philadelphia
um welcome
after uh you know very long pandemic
where we all spend way too much on
looking at video screens
um
comcast is proud and happy to uh to be
sponsoring this event i want to thank
jason livigood uh who's really been
absolutely instrumental uh in in
everything that we do here and in outer
forms um and it's super exciting and and
candidly an honor and a privilege uh to
be able to to host this you know great
event um i also want to thank everyone
each and every one of you for all the
hard work over the years in making
internet delivery what it has been right
if you really take a step back and think
about this march 13th which was a friday
of 2020 we all went home
okay and the network in a day needed to
adapt to a scenario that none of us
really expected right who would have
thought that in our lifetimes we all
would go home jump on teams and zooms
and you know what whatever other video
communication
um that you're using
and stay there for two years straight
and really be able to adapt and grow and
add additional subscribers to the
network while we were doing this uh
truly unprecedented uh and it really
speaks to the robustness of the
engineering work and and
and work that we've done together as an
industry and i mean industry in the
broader sense of the world uh in order
to uh harden the internet delivery to
the point where in this country uh we
were one of the um the only countries in
the world where we did not need to go to
netflix to ask them to downgrade their
video delivery
europe other parts of the world not here
and i take
quite a bit of pride in that i really do
is having the opportunity to lead the
team uh as we've uh done that uh and i
had a great discussion earlier with
stuart at apple who commented about the
uh improvements that we've done in
latency throughout all of this uh and
that i think again that speaks volume to
the technical leadership uh that you
know comes from this organization and
many thanks for that
okay
let's start talking about our actual uh
roadmap so
first and foremost for the folks who are
not familiar with comcast or you know
maybe familiar but don't quite
understand how big our network is it's
really big
it's really really big uh when you
really look at the network end-to-end
over a million
miles of fiber and co-ox plant spread
across the entire us
uh 39 states uh in the district of
columbia um where we service our
customers uh throughout that footprint
in terms of the delivery
how many transactions are we actually
carrying through and i think that that
is uh such i'm trying to you know
balance between all these screens uh so
that you could still see the screen and
i could uh you know not uh you know get
out of uh view for the lens
um
1.3 trillion dns lookups every day
1.3 trillion
uh capacity literally doubling on the
access network every two and a half
years so think about it this way comcast
has been in the high-speed uh uh
business since uh late uh the late 90s
right and every two and a half years we
need to double what it took us to build
30 years
pretty pretty amazing
and
when you look at
the
investment that we continuously put into
the network in 2021 alone and i'll talk
about the stats of 2021 and one of the
next slides we've invested over four
billion dollars into the network uh and
over 20 billion dollars over the uh you
know the uh the horizon since uh 2017
and this year we're continuously um in
uh continuing with our investment in the
network uh because capacity continues to
grow our customer needs continue to
evolve
and my team's job is to make sure that
the network will always be infinitely
scalable and will be able to never
endure business growth
okay
so let's go into uh
what 2021 was and it's funny to
summarize 2021 were
almost uh in august of uh 2022.
uh but it's i thought it would be
interesting to kind of take a step back
and look at you know where we come from
before we talk about where we head into
as
much as we saw
internet growth in 2020 and we saw
explosive internet growth and added
millions of subscribers to our network
which we're very happy to do
um
in 2021 we continue to grow
usage
okay both downstream and upstream so
downstream continued to increase at peak
at 11
upstream increase by 5
um what's really interesting in all of
that is that while
capacity continues to grow
the customer needs are still very much
asymmetrical
okay there's a lot of
buzz around symmetry this and symmetry
dot right but the reality of it is that
at the height of kovid
um and you see it you know here uh in
terms of the uh uh the the ratios at the
height of kovid we saw downstream to
upstream ratio be at 12.4
okay
in the second half of 21 as we kind of
all were coming out of our uh sheltering
in place that went back up to over 14 to
one which is where it was prior to the
pandemic okay and so the reality of it
is that the network is still
very much
a downstream delivery network
okay it's not to say that upstream is
not important it is
um and we've seen some pretty
significant obviously traffic increases
on the upstream driven by video
telecommunications
but
it's still very much driven by
downstream consumption primarily
entertainment services that's not a
surprise
right and as you see those ott services
continue to proliferate um i just so uh
a research note today tivo is saying
that the average consumer has nine
different
streaming services
uh unfortunately there's only 24 hours
in a day right so you know you just you
know there's a you know you've reached a
substitutive effect in terms of what
they actually watch uh but those are the
growth rate that we uh you know we we
needed to accommodate and continue to
accommodate from a subscriber's
standpoint
um and then you know last but not least
um while video conferencing share of
peak network traffic
um um literally doubled during the
pandemic
okay doubled one day uh it's still only
five percent actually less than five
percent of the total bits carried on the
network
okay now if this guy has anything to do
with it you know they'll uh you know
they'll uh you know we'll all be
broadcasting at 8k out of our home
but you know the reality is that you
know for the uh you know for the uh
current uh subscriber um trajectory it's
you just put that into a perspective
okay
let's talk about you know what it means
to the network and what i try to show
here is both kind of the physical
topology but also the spectral topology
of what the comcast network uh uh
represents so 60 million homes the vast
majority of the network which i'll start
you know down below is rated at 750
megahertz of of spectral capacity okay
of which
the small part of which you see down
below on the left-hand side
uh between 5 and 42 megahertz is
dedicated to upstream
everything else is dedicated to
downstream and is really shared by the
various formats of docsis over cable
delivery
um
and traditional video channel deliveries
while all of our lineup does is carried
in ip we still deliver uh uh
channels two traditional set of boxes
are quan based
okay
um in terms of uh the physical plant you
know what what it looks like for
high-speed data delivery uh
traditionally we relied on separate pipe
delivery the cmts or the cable modem
termination system uh that delivers the
doxa signals uh to our high-speed data
subscribers and then all t the uh the
optical
equivalent of a cmts um that you know
delivers uh services to our fiber to the
home subscribers okay
the vast majority of delivery is over
docsis but we do have parts of the
network that are fed with fiber
and what you see here
is a typical cable architecture
which relies on analog fiber
from the cmts which resides in a local
data center
typically closer to the subscriber
because of the analog optics limitations
feeding an analog node
the reason for that is historical it's
the technology that existed when uh the
two-way cable plant was built
and then we used amplifiers to basically
amplify and extend the rf reach all the
way down to the home
what you're seeing here in cable lingo
is something called n plus five the node
plus five
uh amplifiers and this cascade
okay and this is kind of a
what a traditional cable network um
looks like uh not just for comcast but
you know among our other cable brethrens
and the challenge with this is really
twofold right number one is notice that
while the network is asymmetric uh
there's obviously a very small sliver of
capacity that is available to be sent
upstream
those are not easy
things to fix because they're really
limited by
rated devices in the network that are
able to pass or not pass frequencies in
order to change the number of lanes that
are dedicated uh to uh uh to upstream
and downstream delivery okay
um we've spent a lot of time in and
great innovation led by dan rice who is
sitting right here on a platform called
octave which was rushed to market during
the pandemic and is really the first
time where we've implemented ai and ml
in live in real time across our network
in order to optimize the bit delivery to
the individual customers right because
network conditions vary across the board
uh the signal down to my house may be
impaired by lte interference so maybe
have you know i have a connector that
needs to be tightened up which sending
noise upstream and that may be impacting
the efficiency of the bits that i may be
able to deliver to home and so octave
which is the platform that we built is
able to make those decisions in real
time with real-time polling and so the
bit delivery down to dan rice's home may
be better than it is for me but we both
are getting the service that is
optimized to the then current network
conditions
okay
um and and what we've done is we've
taken a smart network and we made it
brilliant and by doing that we were able
to generate another 45 percent of
capacity at the time that we needed it
the most by reliant on pure software
innovation
so really exciting times even doing
pandemic okay
now the challenge that we have is analog
optics
in a world of you know everything
digital
a cmts which is an appliance-based um
architecture in a world that is all web
scale and web speed how do we evolve uh
the architecture uh to uh to be able to
authorize the network challenge and
about five years ago i got this amazing
opportunity to really take this on at
comcast and lead this virtualization
transition
across the board so why don't we go to
the next slide please
and what you're seeing here is the
continuous
evolution and innovation on the access
network and i'm going to start with the
spectrum and you'll see that
uh what we're doing is we're doing two
things number one is we're increasing
the size of the pipe okay to either one
gigahertz or 1.2 gigahertz
why are we doing this because the
customer needs continue to evolve right
you know how do we continue to have the
pipe that is there whether the capacity
is needed today or whether it's going to
be needed 10 years from now right
those are very large lengthy upgrades
that we we need to go through the second
piece is that notice that we're
increasing the amount of capacity that
is dedicated to upstream by executing on
something called mid-split okay
there's an another split called high
split which extends the upstream
frequencies all the way up to 204
megahertz the reason why we chose a
mid-split is you see that guard band
that white space uh in between uh it's
there you know so that we could continue
to deliver video services to cable cards
and other retail devices uninterrupted
okay
um and it's really important for us that
as the network progresses we're not
interrupting uh or disrupting the
customer delivery uh from a service
standpoint even on legacy video quant
video not just legacy
um what we're also doing is that we're
virtualizing the entire delivery system
and so we have launched several years
ago what we call our virtual cmps
by disaggregating and separating the
hardware from the software we're able to
innovate in web scale and web speeds uh
we're running on intel-based platforms
instead of proprietary
appliances um you know put that in
perspective we're on our second
generation of that platform about to
transition to the third generation of
that platform um all riding on intel's
moore's law coattail um you know with uh
effectively
enabling to double the density and
capacity uh writing moore's law rather
than you know reliant on proprietary
chipset applications
um we're
transitioning to brand new digital um
fiber capabilities which enable us to
extend the distance um you know on the
physical plant which enables us to
invest
more
into what we call the critical
infrastructure
how do we make sure that we have backup
power backup cooling back up everything
uh in a uh in a world where the power
grid uh is suffering from uh the weather
events that we uh you know we all
experience every day uh if you walked
outside you know today or yesterday
rather you understand what i'm talking
about
and then
the
amplifiers on the network are upgraded
in order to pass these additional
upstream capabilities to fully take
advantage of these speeds this is
something that we're doing
across our network right now
and working very hard because one it
enables us to literally triple the
amount of upstream capacity that we're
able to deliver
significantly increase
speeds on the upstream uh and really
drive a lot more usage uh if and when
customers are gonna demand those uh
additional upstream services uh driven
by gaming or you know vr or whatever it
is that uh you know will come
okay
um if we go to the next slide please
uh we're not done
right and when we say we're not done is
uh that's really a stepping stone into
evolving our network into what we call
the axis 4.0 uh in this case it's the
full duplex uh version of docsis 4.0
there's an extended spectrum
optionality to the docsis 4.0 spec uh
and what docsis 4.0 enables us to do is
deliver multiple gigabit symmetrical
services
on the same crossover network that we're
putting in place
with our you know um our network rebuild
okay
and what's really exciting about this is
you know take a step back for the first
time we talked about the asymmetry and
the frequency dedication
or separation rather between upstream
and downstream and how much of the plant
is dedicated to downstream
what fdx
doxy4.fdx enables us to do
is with advancement in compute we're
able to overlay
i need you to mute
it's the story of my life the muting
you're mute
there you go um
so what uh
nope
no you're not a mute
[Laughter]
it's okay no problem
um
it's uh it's it's it's the story of our
lives really over the last two and a
half years but that's why it's so great
to be here with you we kid that we can
control that um so what docsis4.ofdx
does is enables to overlay
upstream and downstream frequencies
right on top of the other uh with uh
echo cancellation innovation which we're
working to uh develop and build into the
plant uh and be able to service those
multiple gigabit symmetrical services on
this
while still maintaining and you see it
you know down below all of the
subscribers that have equipment that is
not compatible with access 4.0 okay so
the mid-split modems will continue to
function the legacy video delivery will
continue to function and all of that
we'll be able to do on our coaxial cable
i had the privilege of demoing this
technology at cablelabs back in april
we were able to demonstrate nine
gigabits down and five gigabits up
uh on this uh under service uh and
what's really cool about this is with
the virtualization innovation uh that uh
you know we've uh worked on for the past
four or five years uh we're able to do
this is a software download on the
virtualized platform
okay
uh electronic upgrades to the nodes and
the amps
and now you have a coaxial cable plant
where we're able to deliver multiple
gigabit symmetrical services without
needing to dig up everyone's front uh
yards and everyone's sidewalks and an
eight-hour fiber installation and
everything else that
some of our fiber veterans are dealing
with
that's the innovation that is the
comcast commitment
uh to continuous
investment in the network in our
technology and into products and
services that our customers continue to
demand of us as technology continues to
evolve
super exciting to see it happening but
we're not done there uh let's go to the
next slide please
i talked earlier about
the low latency delivery and what we do
what we've done in terms of active queue
management during the height of the
pandemic and how and again then rice's
team here
really helped us to uh optimize the cmps
delivery configurations so that we don't
just take care of capacity and we don't
just take care of speed yes we deliver
gigabit services to more customers than
anyone else
but speed is one element
the actual effectiveness of the bit
delivery is as critical
and we have some pretty pioneering work
that is already underway uh in terms of
docsis 3.1 low latency implementation
both on the network and on the wi-fi
side of things so that we could deliver
end-to-end
low-latency
uh docsis delivery sub 10 milliseconds
across our entire network uh and be able
to do that uh in in great scale
so pretty exciting uh innovative work
still ahead of us i haven't even talked
about how the same virtualized platform
uh effectively
abstracts the wired delivery and so i
mentioned earlier the fiber to the home
delivery that we have
and we with the virtualized platform and
the distributed access architecture that
we put in place we're able to deliver
those multiple gigabit symmetrical
services on whether the fiber is coaxial
or whether the fiber is fiber or whether
the wires fiber
because again the customers don't care
whether there's clocks in the black
wire or whether there is um a glass in
the black wire they want to make sure
that the products and services that they
rely on uh they continue to uh to deploy
uh with the virtualized architecture
with the digital connection
uh what i
um emotionally excited about
is the real-time visibility
and the real-time traceability that we
have to the service end-to-end it's a
digital connection
it's now doesn't rely on polling
technology anymore it actually streams
the real-time customer experience
across this network uh in real time so
that we could
act on it you know i mentioned the
octave um
ai engine that we built
for bit optimization
imagine if you will the same thing for
fiber connectivity imagine the same
thing for rf impairments on the network
that may or may not be disrupting
customers
imagine if you will service
interruptions where we're able to detect
in five seconds
instead of you know polling technology
which is ultimately limited by the cpu
on the appliance and so on and so forth
and so
this architecture beyond the fact that
it's going to be faster beyond the fact
that it's going to deliver low latency
like no other uh is truly extensive it's
truly broadly deployed uh you know we
don't dig this side of the street or
that side of the street all of our
customers are able to experience gigabit
speeds today and they'll be able to
experience even better in the future
so
that's my uh my story for the uh for the
path of 10g
um and i'll pause here and i'm happy to
take any questions that you uh you may
have whether it's uh here in a room and
let me start in a room uh and then you
know we could uh you know jump in and
take any virtual questions and stuart go
ahead
okay that's better
i don't have a question i just came up
to thank you
for your presentation
to thank comcast
for its ongoing support of the ietf
to thank all the comcast engineers like
jason living good and others that i work
with for
the amazing work you do
being on the forefront
of creating new technology and i'm not
going to name other names but there are
other isps and operators who are not
here
who are very clearly playing catch up
and five years from now they'll be
finally figuring out what you're doing
and realizing why they're falling behind
so wonderful work that you're doing well
it means a lot coming from you
personally um it means a lot you know
for me
uh is having the opportunity to lead
this team through this transition
because
this is not easy
okay this is not uh and when you're in
the typical sphere of technology you
know guess what you know the first year
and a half of working through the the
virtualized platform
we did not sleep honestly
um because uh because you know it looks
great on powerpoint
right but when you try and put this in
front of paying subscribers you run into
you know any possible corner case you
may run into and obstructing hardware
from software uh you know really um is
uh
is easy to say on powerpoint it's not
easy to do in practice
uh but with all the lessons learned um
i'm so proud to see what the team was
able to accomplish
um and you see that with the millions of
subscribers that are on this uh platform
right now so it really means the world
to us it really does thank you
thank you and i just realized poor
microphone etiquette i didn't say who i
am uh this is stuart cheshire from apple
thank you thank you
[Music]
and we have one uh in the queue uh
yoshido asks if we are providing ipv6 to
customers yet
and if so um what sort of size prefix
length do we provide that that's a shoe
in for you because you know you've
launched ipv6
the answer is yes we do and uh generally
uh 56 or 60 uh yeah
and and and i would say what's really
what really makes the comcast network
unique is not only are we providing ipv6
we're providing ipv6 multicast on the
video side which uh you know um it's
quite the complication from a delivery
standpoint
uh it is a very very unique uh comcast
case
uh because uh
you know when you look at uh some of the
third-party applications you know at the
the nos level it's uh it's not a
requirement that is uh
very broadly adopted uh you know across
the uh the industry at large
we had to do it because of the way our
video delivery pipeline is
any other questions
my name is amir jandy so sorry go right
up to the mic so the stream can hear you
uh can you hear me perfect yeah so amir
virginia so um i so you actually did a
very good like interesting job and like
you know congratulations are you looking
to expand this sort of work like you
know to other parts of the network
because this is one small i mean it's
not a small section but it's one part of
the network so
wow
small
i i heard it
so
the short answer is yes but let me give
you the long answer too okay
we don't do technology for the sake of
technology
we don't right you know as much as you
know engineers like to do that that is
not uh that is a means to an end in the
end here is a customer experience it's
reliability it's the scalability or
continuous scalability and continuous
growth of the network okay
when you look at the
other side of the network
um
the smaller side of the network uh the
core network
is uh i'm just joking um the the
uh
when you look at the core delivery right
the core delivery today
uh very much uh
relies on appliances uh up and down uh
the delivery
for various historical reasons right uh
you know this is being a a vendor-led
vendor-driven um industry that had very
little incentive to innovate
disrupt
okay um and you know it it served
extraordinarily well and continues to
serve extraordinarily well uh but i look
at some of the work that for example att
has done uh in terms of of uh uh
virtualizing their core network
um and driving uh both asic and nos
diversity onto the core network i look
at the progressions uh in photonics
across the transport layer
and when you see innovations like zero
optics and and others you begin to uh to
come in and how those get paired with
the aggregation routers
um and
you know
the two coming together i think that
there's tremendous opportunity in the
core network
we are actively looking at you know what
the right
technology decisions are for us
but again to me
beyond the technology choices and beyond
the hardware and software abstraction
to me it's the real-time visibility uh
and how for example we rely on gnmi in
great scale right not just at the access
layer not just at the you know close to
the customer but really up and down uh
and be able to rely on on real-time
streaming real-time alarming and
real-time telemetry to start to really
drive ai at a grand scale across all of
that and that's something that we are
looking into and a lot more to come so
can i add the second question yeah yeah
yeah go so um first of all i didn't mean
to say so i just said like one portion
of the network maybe that would be hurt
my feelings it's too much i'm sorry
just allocate that english as a second
language so um
but uh so you actually bring a very good
point of like you know ai so industry is
talking about self-healing networks for
a while all that stuff that comes into
picture is that something that
do you think would
eventually i mean and everyone's talking
about it for the last like you know six
seven years so where do you see in your
opinion where that would do you think
the self-healing network would we will
see that in the next couple of years or
it's a ten-year
so i so i will tell you uh that again
with the octave example as it is right
now right we are uh effectively
modulating around network impairments as
we speak millions of times a day today
okay um and that's on the uh you know
the access network uh without going into
too many details uh at this point
we have a platform that we call netiq
uh which uh you know operates uh you
could
check it out online we actually have a
you know a couple postings or not that
does that on the core but we're just
getting started the real power here is
how do you connect all of them together
because
you know picture if you will you know
the following
um
i have four boys uh two were in college
doing the pandemic and came back home
because
you know that they closed it and then
two are still in school
uh and 15 seconds after the internet
goes offline
one of them at a minimum is in my home
office by letting me know that the
internet is down
they're like internet probes it's great
okay
um
and and now the real question becomes
where in the network is the impairment
where in the one point you know
something million
miles of cable okay fiber or clocks the
impairment is
okay
and the problem is you're dealing with
kind of you know vertical appliances is
that they don't care across very well
right but if for example the issue was i
had a big um local metro area fiber cut
okay
um if you everyone i'm sure has called
their cable company to try and get
service and the first thing the unhold
message tells you is reboot your modem
okay well you could reboot your model a
thousand times if there's a fiber cut to
your area that's not going to help
right and so how do we de-duplicate the
alarms because think about the alarms
that when it just went off in our
network the cable modems were streaming
that they lost connection okay the smart
network the amplifiers the nodes
and the vcmts said
we're not getting traffic it's not
coming through okay
the local network said well i lost
something northbound
and now it's how do you shoot the fiber
in order with an otdr in order to
pinpoint exactly where the fiber
disconnect is and that's what we're
working on right now how do you tie all
of these indicators together
into a coherent
alarm that only pinpoints where the
breakage point is
but also then
has the intelligence to message to our
customers
what their expectations are
okay and so it's not just about the
self-healingness of this is what do you
tell the end customer okay don't reboot
your modem there's a fiber cut in your
area
fiber crews are aware of the issue and
are working to restore service the eta
is four hours
and that ultimately is is what the
network goal is
right because that's what our customers
expect of us
and that's what we're working on thank
you so much
any other
questions i got that one already yeah
next question yeah yeah please
uh hello i'm robert jackson so i have a
question do you have numbers of your tcp
versus udp traffic percentages lately
and is it affecting your
engineering of the network in any way
i don't think we uh
yeah i don't think we've uh shared any
of those stats but yeah we're watching
closely you know what's happening with
the quick and uh all these kinds of
things i don't think yet it's changed
the way that we do engineering yeah
all ip
that's exactly right
okay any uh any other questions from
anyone
any other questions online
i don't see any more online is there
another one on there yeah oh sorry i i
don't see the same screen
uh maybe the person that's online can uh
we lost the meat echo here
maybe the person online can ask your
question go off mute
sharon
yes hi this is sharon
i'm thinking of a
very large upstream application with
connected cars
hitting
a
access network
wall
with cellular
is there any thought of
combining docsis with wireless lan in
order to
uh free up this jam
any plans any thought about it
thank you
um
so uh sean it's a it's a good question
um let me let me answer it this way okay
comcast is not a wireless company we do
offer cellular services but they're
through an nvno with verizon we do have
a very very large wi-fi um
network uh in fact it's the largest in
the u.s uh which we use for you know
both you know customer benefits but also
as a way to offload um
solar minutes um and uh you know help
with the economics of the nvnl
um
as such and really driven by that
obviously
you know what's right for the comcast
network you know may be different than
companies like uh rogers that is
actually a wireless carrier uh and has
you know a tighter integration and so
sean i really think that the answer to
your question is probably but it really
depends on the actual um operator
and the the unique services that they
provide
okay
any other questions
yes
last one and then uh
and then we'll wrap up yeah we'll wrap
up sorry not a question about a comment
uh jason tucker from comcast uh
following up on the ipv6 question from
earlier
not only are we delivering ipv6 to
customers but we were doing it at a
large scale like 10 years ago so ipv6 is
it's really integral to what we do at a
lot of levels yeah totally and has been
and and you're 100 right um and jason
thank you
um
i would say you know last comment on
this uh on the ipv6 uh pieces
um
it's so ingrained to everything that we
do from a network standpoint we could
not scale at some point we were the
largest consumer of ipv4 addresses uh
and and we literally hit a wall so you
know this has been a uh
instrumental for us you know to your
point for many many years yes last one
and then
they kicked me out hi paul curtis sienna
um
in talking about the monitoring and
troubleshooting you mentioned gnmi i
guess i'm curious to the extent you're
using gnmi just for monitoring also for
all network management and if there's
anything you can say about your progress
there where you guys are at and rolling
that out
yeah so
um
i'm trying to think what i could say i
could say that um i could say this um
we're very excited about the fact that
it is a common standard uh even though
every vendor siena has a you know
different implementation of gnmi right
um you know same for the nokia person
you know back there and so on and so
forth okay and so part of an operator
challenge is what pieces of it can you
take that you could fairly standardize
that you could then feed across you know
this average ecosystem that you could
actually act and and operationalize
because at the end of the day you know
think about the the ops people that at
2am need to get an alarm and do
something with it okay
and that's where you know the challenge
has been i want to say that uh in parts
of the network we're further along in
some parts of the network we have um you
know we're just big in the beginning
stages of this um but again it's
exciting uh to be able to uh to leverage
a uh you know a common spec across these
as we're maturing the actual delivery
does that make sense
thank you
okay great well thank you very much alad
appreciate it thank you for having me
thank you for coming here
and again thank you for uh for your uh
thought and technology leadership we we
could not have done any of this without
the great work that you're doing across
the industry so thank you
thank you so much