okay
so
so this is um
sorry
oh good good
your voice is very faint guys
sure
so
the top of the hour so i guess we can
get started
good morning everyone
welcome to the interior working group
meeting
uh with me today uh my co-chair juan
carlos is joining us remotely and
carlos bernardo is going to be
with me here
so let's get started with the chair
slide go ahead jesse
welcome everyone to the interior uh at
itf 114
um
this is an ietf official meeting so the
usual not well goes
therefore we have this reminder that
ietf policies on topics of patents and
code of conduct
how to present yourself and address your
colleagues
are in effect
by participating you agreed to do you
agree to the ietf poli processes and
policies uh and of course if you're
aware of any contribution covered by
patents please uh
speak up or send us a note to the
to the
chairs
also for your information everything
here is going to be
written audible uh written audio and
video and photo will may be made public
and the personal information that you
provide to the atf will be handled
accordingly to the
idf privacy statement if you have any
questions you have the references there
to the
different pcps
so
please make sure that you sign into the
session using the mythical
uh
we will ask you to use mythico to join
the queue so that we can control
local and remote participants and the
order of questions
um keep audio and video off if you are
not
using the on-site version
we ask you guys
locally to wear masks
unless actively speaking out of the mic
if that makes your voice clearer you you
may be able to remove your mask at the
mic
and uh
for the remote participants please make
sure that your own video are off unless
you're cheering or presenting the
decision
these are the links to the agenda
mythical and other information and
if you have any issues please report it
back
so once again the minutes are taken and
we will need you guys to
log into mitico as a blue sheet for the
data tracker
for the scribes there is a note for int
area
and there's a chat room uh both on the
mythico and on the zulip tool
at this moment i guess we can ask
for a note taker
can someone help us with the notes
ladies and gentlemen we need please an
outtake of any volunteer
please
uh
i can offer my help as the last time
you're offline i mean i will prepare it
is that fine
for the chairs yes
thank you
thanks luigi it wasn't
very clear but i guess you're offering
to to take the notes and uh and we can
help of course
also when you're presenting
thanks
so by the way when you guys speak to the
to the queue mike uh
don't get too too close it's going to be
clear for the ones that we are remote
so with that we can move on to the
agenda uh we have a compact but dense
agenda
starting with a few updates that we're
going to give followed by threads
presentation on the ip parcels together
with some
other drafts
then we have the internet addressing
considerations follow-up from luigi
ayana considerations from don
eastlake and
service routing and multi-access edge
computing
from zongping
are there any questions or comments
regarding this agenda
okay hearing none
we can move on to the quick uh working
group updates
so the first one is we had this call for
uh working group adoption of draft
templin
interior parcels
we had a heavy discussion on the main
list but so far we're not seeing any
consensus to to adopt the draft
so
our plan is to continue this call for
adoption until the end of this meeting
since fred is going to present now
so we're going to be hearing uh one more
round of comments and
and then by the end of this week we can
close the call for adoption
and this presentation is following
uh it's going to be the first one so
that discussion can be
uh both at this meeting and over the
mailing list
the other update is
the internet addressing considerations
draft from luigi
it's been moved out of inter area
this was draft gi into area
internet addressing gap analysis and now
it's uh draft
internet addressing considerations
so same thing we are going to have luigi
presenting and
giving us an update about his draft
but these are pretty much the the
working group update so far
okay thanks for listening
thanks
um we're gonna start with the first
presenter fred please
you want me to give you
control friend
um
we'll do it from here
that's all right you can do it from
there yeah
okay
okay so this is about
arrow and omni and and ip parcels
next chart
the internet was originally intended as
a network of networks
i'm standing on the x
like that
okay
the internet was intended as a network
of networks beginning in the 1970s the
arpanet grew to to become what we know
today as the global public internet one
of the first nodes on the arpanet was
the srivan the mobile node
sorry today's public internet
um sorry it's on the remote now it's a
little too loud it's uh it was actually
not bad before
is that better
yeah that here is perfect
so today's public internet is a single
monolithic grounding and addressing
domain instead of network of networks
it's because there's incomplete
architectural layering private intranets
connect to the internet via security
devices like firewalls proxies and ads
but they use address translation so that
there's no true end-to-end global
addressing
and internet working between private
internets is problem problematic due to
addressing the security
incompatibilities
and this complicates global mobile
internet working
but the early pioneers envisioned a true
end-to-end communications over a global
scale network of networks and they even
had a name for it they called it the cat
net name model for internet working
and i believe we're at a unique point in
history where the end to end can be
restored
next chart
so here's the cabinet model for internet
networking the figure that you see on
the right is the one originally drawn by
spin surf in 1978
it was documented in 48 which was the
precursor to the rfc series
i incorporated still earlier concepts
from leopos on beginning in 1974
and it envisioned a true network of
networks
they knew at that time that gateways
were required to interconnect diverse
internetworks but they did not know how
to traverse them
and they knew that end systems also
required a local gateway to support the
end to end
what they did not know at that time is
that they needed a new architectural
layer and that we called the adaptation
layer arrow and omni now provide an
adaptation layer for the internet
next chart
so here we have four
disjoint
internetworks
they might be for example large
corporate enterprise networks
uh
service provider networks
uh one could be the global public
internet itself the global ipv4 internet
another could be the global ipv6
internet
but they're in disjoint partitions
so next chart
so if we deploy gateways that operate at
the adaptation layer
we can now span these
disjoint partitions
next chart
and thereby have end-to-end
communications both within the same
partition and across partition
boundaries by using adaptation layer
forwarding over the gateways and over
partitions
next chart
so that what happens is an original ipv6
packet ending starting down in the
bottom left
becomes encapsulated in the adaptation
layer which is that orange encapsulation
that you see
then fragmented if necessary
and then encapsulated again as carrier
packets is what you see in this green
layer
the green carries the packets across the
individual segments
the orange carries the packets across
the adaptation layer gateways
and at the very far upper right you see
that the original packet then comes out
at the other end after
decapsulation and reassembly
next chart
so the omni adaptation layer uh it and
or near end systems configure an omni
interface which is essentially the same
thing as what the catnip model called
the local gateway
the omni adaptation layer source uses
ipv6 encapsulation fragmentation to
produce oil packets
and then uses l2 encapsulation to
produce carrier packets
the carrier packets transfers through oa
to the destination which reassembles and
decapsulates
and the source can tune its packet sizes
without loss to achieve the best
performance
it's very similar to atm adaptation
layer 5.
next chart
so in terms of multi-net traversal we
have these things in the middle called
ol gateways
here again the original source and final
destination are in different internet
segments
the ol source produces packets and
fragments and the old destination
reassembles
and the aol gate
gateways forward the ayl packets at a
layer below ip but all above the link
layer you can see where that bend in the
green graph there
happens at the adaptation layer and
below ip but above layer
two and the carry packets transport oil
for packets or fragments across
first top segments then undergo
re-encapsulation and re-transmission at
each next top segment
and this provides us the opportunity for
true end-to-end in the spirit of the
cabinet
next chart
so now let's talk about
aero omni and the six m's of modern
mobile internet working
the adaptation layer naturally
eliminates many challenges that
complicate diverse mobile internet and
service models incremental deployment on
existing networks there's no need for a
flag day
security is addressed at all layers in
the architecture including end-to-end
it naturally supports dtn
and the 6ms that i'm talking about are
multi-link multi-net mobility
multicast multi-hop and mtu assurance
and all six of them deserve a 30-minute
time slide in their own but i'm not
going to talk about all six today
just understand that they're very
important
but what i am going to talk about is mtu
assurance the ability for mobile nodes
to send packets of diverse sizes without
loss
and to dynamically tune packet sizes for
best performance
and it's inspired a new construct that's
known as the ip parcel
next chart
ip packets of both of ipv6 forward ipv6
contain a unit of data that becomes the
re-transmission unit in case of loss
upper layer protocols such as tcp quick
udp ltp udp
exchange segments
and with a single segment per ip packet
but i p parcels permit a single packet
to carry multiple upper layer protocol
segments
as a packet of packets
but the segment is still the lost
transmission unit
the goal is to support larger packets
for better performance
flexible packaging repackaging for more
efficient handling and to encourage more
diverse maximum transmission units in
the internet
next chart
so as an analogy when a consumer orders
50 small items from a major online
retailer the retailer doesn't ship them
in 50 small separate small boxes
instead they put as many of the small
items as possible into one or a few
larger boxes or parcels
and then they place the parcels on a
semi truck or an airplane the parcels
arrive at a regional distribution center
where they may be further redistributed
into different size parcels that are
finally delivered to the consumer
but most often the consumer will only
find one or a few parcels at their
doorstep and not 15 individual boxes
and this greatly reduces handling
overhead for both the retailer and the
consumer
next chart
ip parcels are formed
by
putting together segments that come from
the same upper layer protocol 5 tuple
being the source address destination
address source port destination port and
protocol
to produce buffers with up to 64
segments all concatenated together
all segments except the final segment
must be equal length they can be up to
65k octets 64k octets minus the length
of the headers
the final segment may be smaller
and the upper layer protocol
delivers the data buffer and non-final
segment size to the ip layer
and from there the ip layer forms
parcels by appending jumbo a jumbo
payload option
uh it's the same jumbo payload option
that appears in rsc 2675.
next
chart
so ip parcels are based on ip jumbograms
ip parcels use the jumbo payload option
with a non-zero total payload length
whereas true jumbos use zero for that
field
the total payload length encodes the
length of the first segment only
and the jumbo payload length includes
the length of the entire parcel
ip parcels are defined for both ipv6 and
ipv4
for ipv4
we're proposing to reuse the obsoleted
rfc 1063 ipv4 probe mtu option
and the maximum ip parcel size therefore
is a little bit less than 64k times 64
times 64k or or 4
megabytes
next chart
so
here's what they look like ip parcel
structure
it supports both tcp and transports over
udp
they include up to 64 upper layer
protocol segments but only one tcp or
udp ip header
and the tcp udp checksum covers only the
headers
with an individual trailer for each
segment
all set all checksums are calculated in
a single pass over the
data for tcp only each non-first segment
is appreciated for by a four octet
sequence number header
and udp transports encode their own star
delimiter in each segment therefore they
don't need the sequence number header
and these sequence number headers and
checksum trailers can be thought of as a
compressed tcp or udp header only have
to include that much information that
would normally appear in the tcp header
and then you can put all these items
together as a single parcel
next chart
a transmission of ip parcels
ip parcels travel traverse parcel
capable links with sufficient mtu the
same as packets partial capable physical
links are not yet available but omni
virtual links can forward ip parcels
using the adaptation layer today
the omni adaptation layer uses
encapsulation and fragmentation to break
large parcels into smaller sub-parcels
if necessary
since the largest that can undergo ip
fragmentation is 64k
in the first pass we have parcel
fragmentation which is accompanied by
loose reassembly with opportunistic
merging
in the second pass we have ip
fragmentation which has strict
reassembly with fragment retransmission
but the goal is to forward the fewest
and largest ip parcels possible over the
network to the final destination
to minimize segment reordering due to
parts reparcel if possible although
that's not critical
we leverage ip fragmentation reassemble
if necessary
and the lost unit is a single segment
instead of the entire parcel
so
before we start sending parcels we have
to qualify the path to see if the path
is capable of supporting them
so we have this partial path
qualification procedure
we have a partial probe from sources
test consecutive hops up to the
destination or a router with a nine
parcel capable next op
and this is done by using a hot buy hops
option that's processed at each hop
and then the destination or the router
informs the source that some of the all
of the forward path is possible capable
by sending a partial reply
and for this we use udpip encapsulated
icmp messages that are processed only at
the source
but after a partial path qualification
parcels from source traverse partially
capable past the same as ordinary ip
packets up to the destination router
destinations that receive parcels can
effectively deliver them to upper layers
and router routers that terminate
partial capable paths open the parcels
and forward individual ip packets to the
destination
uh now this goes a long way of saying
why are we wanting to do this
i p partial integrity but
with link layer integrity checks like
crc 32 they can miss errors in packets
larger than about 9 kb
but ip parcels are often much larger
than that
ip parcels include separate integrity
checks for each upper layer protocol
segment
the parcels improve integrity compared
to same size packets or jumbograms which
only include a single upper layer
protocol segment integrity check
only segments with correct integrity are
accepted individual segments and not the
entire parcel is the last free
transmission unit and this is very
important because if you send a parcel
it has 50 items in it and only two are
corrupted you still get to accept all
the 48 other ones
so ip parcels now encourage new link
types with larger and more diverse mtus
plus improved integrity resulting in
major internet and performance
improvements and that's why the why of
doing ip parcels
and now we come to the question ip
parcels is ready for adoption as an
interior working group document
aero and omni are also ready for
adoption as interior working group
documents
can we adopt ip parcels
and can we adopt their own army
that's my chance
thank you fred
just a reminder
the area working group
initiated a call for adoption on june 22
and so far as jc mentioned
we haven't seen enough support to adopt
the draft
we have some time for questions
thanks fred it's ducard
um wondering wondering if you have
looked uh oh well affiliation in this
case critical technologies um
i wonder if you have looked at the
potential interactions of this with the
various tcp options the one that i care
about most is skips options
with tcp options they would appear only
in the tcp header of the first parcel
if it gets broken out into multiple
parcels they would still only appear in
the first parcel the other parcels
wouldn't carry the option and it's the
same thing same with the tcp act flag
the tcp act would only apply appear in
the first parcel not in all partial
subparcels after partialization
okay
no more questions
okay thank you fred
luigi please
i'm smaller than fred
okay um let's start so this is an
apparent update about the discussion
about internet addressing
uh we had two drafts in the in the past
named problem statement and gap analysis
now
as has being mentioned by sean carlos
the new update
she
changed the name to consideration
explain why next
so let me
put a little bit of context in the next
couple of slides to to recap what this
is all about next
so
this slide comes from actually itf 113
when we presented the update on both
documents the problem statement he
provides basically a scenario
that we have today in the internet um
where the the addressing model that we
have uh it can be a potential entrance
so
maybe sometimes
things can be done in a different way
then there was the second document the
gap analysis that
investigated a little bit more
uh about these scenarios and actually
also looking
what kind of extensions in in some areas
have been introduced in order to to go
beyond what was
looking like like uh
some limitations or shortcomings okay
um
we had a huge discussion on the mailing
list various mailing lists but mainly on
interior
uh started from a side meeting that we
did in ietf
112 okay and yeah we we we try to
capture all the input that we received
from the community
next
so i i think the animation that i put
don't work now but so you will see some
awkward bubble in
sometimes but so the conclusion uh
this is the last slide that we we showed
in 113
uh was the fact that we were uh
asking basically to have a
adoption working group adoption
because we we felt that
while not finished this is a good
community effort and we also suggested
the fact that maybe we should start to
things
think
what's next i mean we we have some
considerations
so what should we do
with this okay
next
and
people listen
what was great in the sense that uh
the interior chairs were ready to issue
the the working group adoption okay but
in the meantime the iab and the isg
organized a retreat
they have usually to discuss various
things
okay but one of the discussion items in
their agenda and there is a snapshot
here was exactly about internet
addressing okay if you
did you if you go on the wiki of the iab
ist you can find the agenda and then
even the link to the slides okay
which i um
took the liberty to use a few of them
since they were public
i must have
handled this in a different way maybe i
apologize if i didn't
directly ask
isg to do that so but the blame is
completely me
and
next
so
uh in the next few slides you will see
this
except the hogwart bubbles
the slides can come from the iab ist
there is the link on each and every
slide
stating the source
and i would like to to ask eric to help
me to
set the context of each slides okay
thank you reggie so my name is eric
vince i'm the internet area director
and indeed those slides were prepared by
colleen perkins it's maybe in the on the
meeting right now
basically because we were seeing a
couple of drafts about this we sometimes
kind of hey colleen
nice that you were able to join us
we were wondering basically where what
was the intent
of uvg at this point of time so we reuse
basically the
the retreat to say those two documents
and that's what i wrote on the right
there are multiple authors
a little bit too much right too many
but it's okay including academic and you
are also ex-academic there
and there were basically multiple gaps
in those addresses it was a quick
summary of your draft basically on about
the length sometimes about the semantics
the confusion between locator and
anti-fire
which i think everyone will agree with
you
on this one except for the name of gaps
that's the reason why
i put there because it works right the
internet works and basically you were
the authors
were making this statement
and i don't disagree with and proposing
nothing
right to do and it was kind of puzzling
for us that's the context of this slide
exactly and um no i i
agree totally what you said it's cool
that you see that uh there are several
outers uh
yes
the use of caps maybe is not the right
working wording will come this is the
reason actually why there is a a change
of naming in the document and we'll talk
about this uh
i think in the next slide
no solution proposed this was absolutely
important
as we say in the
uh problem statement the document is
really
um
not about proposing specific solution
but as i put it in the awkward bubble is
i'm that stimulating discussion
okay so there was no intention to to
to go into the solution space or at
least not yet okay next
um
so coming back to the fact that the the
gap analysis um
uh
it's true that uh the feedback basically
as eric says that you use the word gap
looks like there is a real issue
and
you use a gap to to describe something
missing between
two things one is the current state the
other is the
proposed solution but we don't have the
second one so there is no gap uh
in that sense
um
and
we
while we did some effort not to to
present like there is an issue in the ip
addressing
or maybe we still use too much the word
in the issue in the previous version of
the document so
after discussion with eric and the
chairs we agreed that on the mailing
list that the the word consistent
sounds better okay and so that is why
there is the drafty and non-internet
addressing uh consideration okay
next
i mean um
would we tell us to go in all the
details in the changes that we did to
this document what you see here is just
the diff
uh between the old document and the new
the type of content already
shows that the word issue issues
disappeared
okay the point is not to to
and it has never been to say ipad
dressing is bad
it's good it it works perfectly
there are there are some scenarios where
um
some solutions have been developed to
overcome some limitation now the
question is can we do it in one
coherent way okay instead of have point
solution here and there that sometimes
may be incompatible and sometimes can
end up being introduced some kind of of
fragility okay
next
so
we
i asked eric to come back so that's
another slide from the retreat as luigi
kindly indicated at the below we were
really wondering
um what to do with those drafts or what
the best suggestions to move forward
with your work or there was about
creating a research group
making an ieb workshop just on this
topic
possibly creating a new working group or
keeping an interior
we were posing the questions there i got
some feedback from the iab and the isg
and uh
basically it was the third point that
was kind of selected or suggested as the
best way forward
okay so from from our perspective
i i mean i
we we we are these documents are not is
not about research pure research so we
don't feel that there is a place
uh uh
or better
we don't need to bring completely this
work
into irtf if there are uh research
aspects
related to this work certainly we can go
discuss to the various rg that cover
the topic obviously
ib workshop is up to iab would be
welcome obviously
so what i what we focused on is the the
the last two
possibilities next
but there is suresh on the queue
suresh
yeah thank you suresh krishnan so
uh keep in interior i i'm not really for
it right so interior is supposed to do
one of things right i mean i ask you to
make this comment after this the next
two slides because i'm tackling exactly
these points and
i'll call you back to the mic thanks
thanks you thanks suresh so
eric if you want to say anything on this
slide this is just the specific two
point new word yeah
exactly it is what basically what i
wrote as the benefit and
at first sight right the benefit and the
drawback of get creating a new working
group to work on this okay it is just
one detail is that they that are
mentioned
and arena i i suppose you guys discussed
also this uh
but uh yeah
other than that i mean this is the the
the
let's say
what should be done in order to go for a
new working group i mean uh there are we
know the procedure that there is we know
there is much work to be done and the
community has to be there
okay this is a community decision
and something which is you were right so
sagan and raina
uh different topics are not really
related to this but we put in a retreat
in the same bucket so forget because it
was not linked to your draft
and
the incremental move is really what will
be important for the next step right we
don't want to invent a pv10 right
yes absolutely
so
um
the documents so far are not exhaustive
but cover
i think all the main areas
doesn't mean necessarily
that we we we
have to find a solution from each and
every area i mean this is something also
to be discussed and decided as a
community and
and uh to decide whether or not
something should exactly be done in the
different areas so
i mean as has been marketed let's not
boil the ocean let's focus on something
that makes sense okay
next
eric you want to say something this is
just the other slide on the in the area
is a
is an except of the the chartered but
which rightfully says
what should be done here is something
that doesn't fit in any working group in
the
internet area but is not
uh
let's say enough to
or was it to create a new
working group so
i think that if we go to the next slide
yeah this open the question whether or
not we consider that the discussion
about internet dressing
should be considered as
uh walls to be discussed in a larger
scope beyond the interior and so
considering if there is sufficient
energy and willingness
to explore the possibility of a working
group or the community feels that the
two documents that we have are a good
snapshot of the situation but there is
no willingness to go further at this
point in time
so
we are happy to have any possible
feedback we also set up a aside meeting
tomorrow early morning 8 o'clock
you are very welcome to
stop by and express your opinion because
yeah
we we need to have consensus to en
energy to move forward and suresh please
if you can come back
uh thank you luigi so i think um you
kind of got to my point of view so like
it's uh the interior is like as i said
like you know it's like chatted for
smaller work items right like you know
one-off things
and this seems to be like a large body
of work potentially so i think if you go
for a new working group or new rg like i
think that might be better and i say new
rg or like you know existing rg as well
as possible like you know for
like maybe
i don't know right like you know it
might be a home for it
the reason i'm waffling a little bit is
because it's not clear if the problem's
all understood and agreed upon right
like so it might take a little bit of
time before we get to a working group
and that's probably why
i think colin might be online so the
idea might be to kind of like solidify
the set of issues that need to get done
and the only concern i have is like is
to
kind of make this incrementally
deployable so like one thing we don't
want to do is like come up with another
clean slate solution and as long as
that's there like you know you're not
going to see me coming and
screaming at you so thanks
thank you sir i totally agree with you
in the sense that uh what
whatever will end up doing this must be
incrementally deployable and
also there is a work to be done on the
scope on what we want to do it's not
just oh let's let's revise the the
addressing model it's not that is
where
why where what are the areas where if we
do something
we get real benefits and how do we do it
in order to
be incrementally deployable that's the
the question so there is some some
refinement work to be done on the scope
and then solution space to be explored
andrew camping um this might be a
question for eric i guess which is uh if
if the purpose of the iab is to provide
long-term technical direction uh on
the development of the internet i'm
struggling to see why this wouldn't be a
good subject for a future iab workshop
as a way to flesh this out somewhat
no
i am on thecube oh yeah i know
you were painting to me andrew
ib workshops are managed by iab right
clearly
uh
an outcome the site meeting i mean
everything is in flux because honestly
the problem is not well scoped right
there's a reason why the assad meetings
may be both later or maybe ib workshop
so yeah everything is possibly open
i understand it's not the answer you
wanted but it is the case
i might be do wrong but the the two
things are not incompatible right if if
there are side meetings and discussion
doesn't prevent the iab to organize a
workshop am i wrong
joel halpern from erickson
luigi i appreciate the goals and you've
gotten in writing into this document you
and i have talked about it yes
but i can't figure out how to use this
document as it currently lives as a
basis for any discussion for what to do
next
the document mixes things that are done
with things that have been proposed it
mixes things which are done but work
badly with things that are done and work
well
it mixes
ideas that have been proposed that
probably make sense and go in ip with
things that are application layer and
don't belong anywhere near this
um i don't know how one would even put
together either a charter or further
discussions in this group without
significantly more clarity in what it is
we are actually talking about
i mean if you want to publish it as a
survey paper in sitcom
hey
you do good work but
that's not what we do here at the ietf
so
thank you very much joel you have good
points let me uh answer that um
two things one is uh especially then the
consideration
document
as we discussed by email
could be better reorganized i and some
some thoughts that are there are not
clearly spelled so there is quite some
work to be done uh but it's i i did
really appreciate your review
so this is one thing now on the fact
that i cannot use these documents to to
explore a solution to a chart or
whatever
so
but because they were not written with
that purpose in mind as i said in a in a
few slides before the the point was to
trigger discussion
which is the reason i'm here right now
if we do agree that there's something to
be seen now
we need to work in in
in another direction and go exactly
where you said uh try to transform these
documents in something that can be used
to structure
a charter a discussion or something like
that so there is work to be done in that
direction i completely agree
i think you have another question from
colin
for comments
i have with the
these drafts i think are very similar to
the issue the issues joel just raised in
that um
that they seem incredibly
broad
um and there are some aspects of these
drafts that that um
we have had research groups in yrtf
discussing related topics for several
years now uh there are some aspects
which are
very straightforward um engineering
extensions to existing protocols uh and
there's the they cover the whole range
in between them
um and given the
the breadth of the drafts it is very
difficult to know where the work should
go because the work doesn't seem to have
a focus
it doesn't seem to be
so much research but you know or clearly
research because it's covering about
three or four different research groups
it doesn't seem so much to be
engineering
it's not sure where it's going
so i i would echo the previous comments
if if if you can focus the work and you
know decide whether you wish to do
research if you wish to do engineering
uh and focus it down on a specific topic
i think you will find it easier to make
progress
or at least it's a definitive answer
where progress should or shouldn't
happen
sure thank you uh thank you colleen
that's a good
comment
is on the lines like joel said i
i do agree that is broad
again uh the reason is very simple we we
try to to
let's call it a bibliography as charles
said we we went broad to see what what
is going on doesn't mean we need to
tackle each and every
uh different area or different scenario
etc etc so certainly there is a big work
to be done in order to scope
the the things and in which direction we
want to go and
might this change the venue um
maybe maybe the the point at the
beginning really was to
trigger discussion not to to drive
discussions that is why we went broad so
that and everyone can have a say on this
and we will continue to do in this way
so and try to to
set the priorities
according to what the community feels
are the priorities or the most promising
direction to to explore so
i uh what can i say i do agree there is
a lot of clarity that is why we need
more discussion as a my personal opinion
thank you stu card and this time i'll
say my affiliation is with ax enterprise
so
on the one hand i think this work is
fundamentally important
and i believe that having a venue in
which these various issues can all be
discussed at the same time in the same
room is important
because trying to tackle them one at a
time
um
i don't think leads to the kind of
solution that we ultimately will need
um the sec the uh your section two in
your draft lists eight different areas
where issues exist and in the drone
remote identification protocol working
group we confront clearly at least four
of those eight and arguably more of
those
so there is work in ietf going on that
addresses you know some of them for a
particular application area but so now
coming to my question you probably
covered this in your slides but i
somehow missed it
why i etf rather than i
rtf
so we documented all engineering efforts
to to to to um to extend the addressing
model and uh
as colin pointed out and you can check
it on the documents there are not that
many research paper as a reference so we
don't feel like that that
there must
we don't feel but
again it's it's not been to decide we
don't feel that uh
building a new rg is worth it also
because
part of the the the things we cover in
the documents are covered by existing
research group also that we can discuss
specific research aspects in in the
existing uh research groups i think
so that is the reason
actually dino dino was first
this is dino um
so discussion is good i agree it's
helpful especially face to face but you
know at some point discuss you can
discuss the depth and there's no
progress
what i would suggest in the discussions
is
maybe
we see without out of the list of
problems or potential problems let's see
what people think about what's the most
important single problem to solve
like what address
like what address problem what's wrong
with ip addressing and everybody has
their favorite
problems wrong
we can provide ex extensions there is
nothing wrong with ip addressing it's
just that in some scenarios we can
provide extensions that are meaningful
well all right somebody could say i love
ip addressing but the way we do proxy
aggregation in bgp is a problem maybe we
should work on this problem because we
think it's going to help service
providers so that's what i would suggest
is pick one problem and then we could
focus and then it's succinct and it's
described
and then we then we could then explore
exclu solutions that either change
something or extend it i know changes uh
you know and like you said an important
requirement is compatibility so how much
can you change to get a benefit and
still keep it compatible in transition
to it easy
thank you you are making the points i i
was willing to open tomorrow
unless i'm making excellent thank you
very much dina
actually i think dino uh probably
articulated it better than i could but
but when focusing or if focusing on
particular issues i really want to see
more about what problems you're trying
to solve specifically right so that's
something that's quite um
quite weak in the document it's kind of
all over the place but a lot of people
have said that already the other thing i
would just say is um just a sort of
caution about thinking
about developing things that are too
complex going forward so we're seeing
quite a lot of protocol developments
that are quite wide ranging at the
moment and i would say you know if
you're thinking about these specific
solutions really have a one problem and
one solution kind of thing
um so that's just my feedback thank you
please state your name
oh sorry dominique lizansky and i work
for lastpass legal thank you
thank you
yeah i do agree with the comment what
can i say uh there is one thing i
personally want to add i mean
um
there is nothing that is going to break
we see that just there are in several
places extensions that are developed in
a kind of independent way the point is
that just can we have something more
coherent and bring it together so we
have we have time to discuss and we have
time to make the right
choices i mean we don't are in a hurry
so yes scope the problem what we want to
solve we don't want to solve
and
how can we do it incrementally
deployable etc etc so this is all part
of of
what is in front of us if we take the
path of yeah discuss for for
larger effort
than just two documents in the interior
one more question dino go ahead
this is dino i don't want to be
redundant but
it's funny how if you just choose one
specific problem that's well defined and
try to solve it it ends up taking a life
of its own and then it sprawls out into
other things
that then could be solved because you
have a firm problem statement and a
solution
and so you know
i mean i i always use rsvp as an example
we needed a reservation protocol on the
internet right and so rsvp was developed
it was done in research in university
and it did solve the problem it had
limited deployment but then it turns out
that sometime later people said hey
rsvp might be a good protocol to do
label binding in mpls and there's more
deployment of
than there is for the original problem
statement so you see just going down the
path of just picking one succinct
problem and trying to solve it may
develop into a solution that somebody
says ah this is going to be good for you
know holographic video in the future or
whatever you know
so you are basically saying we will
develop something that will go beyond
our expectations
wonderful it's always the case right
[Laughter]
thanks dude
okay thank you luigi thank you and feel
free to continue the discussion on the
interior mailing list for now okay thank
you um our third presenter i don't see
donald in the room
so maybe we'll
we'll jump to the force is zonk bank
[Music]
yes we can
we
we'll just give you control
okay
go ahead
hello everyone i'm tong hando from china
mobile
and it's a the version one for this
service routine in time you see
the draft
and uh
next page please
and this this page is about the
modifications we add some sections that
briefly analysis the service routine
mechanism in mbc
it's in including
section 4 of the analysis requirement of
service routing network notes
including the following nodes in imc and
the client and the server
uh
in the section file uh i'll be
announcing the hash complex problem
uh and in the section six we announced
it's the service routine for
the fixed clients and we make some other
corrections
next period
and
the we will
reveal the mechanisms uh we think that
traditionally
uh the dns procedure will be needed when
a ue user equipment access the local
service in the uh mec
in this document we introduce a
mechanism that can access the local
services
in diamonds directly without the dns
procedure by using a special
special address
in the picture we can see that
when the ue want to access the local
service they it will send since two
attempt time one is a normal dns square
to get the service id such as the
www point local weather point
com
and the second attempt is to
make a destination of ap address itself
by hashing the domain name
bypass the dns procedure
if this attempt to succeed
uh success uh the uee can access the
service directly inside the ipc we think
it will uh
see
it will be quick than the attempt one
if if
the time to success
next page
and then
we here uh
that is the service routine ip address
we have several we think we have several
options for the service loading ap
address
uh in the first option uh
we we can assume that the uee can
receive uh mec prefix for the service
routine in the procedure of establishing
the session between the oe and the upf
in the mic
then
they can use the first
uh for example 64
64 for the mec prefix and
64 for the hash domain name and in the
second option we can use the uh
your unique local address
for the
service routine ip address and also
the first 64 for the prefix and
the
last 64 for the
hashed domain name
the procedure is similar to the first
option
and
the imec
ui prefix contains a special subnet id
in the last option
we can also use all the
128 bits as a hash domain name
and the finger shows
next page please
please thank you uh
this is uh
about the section four we analysis the
requirement of service routine next
workouts in the mec the network need
need to support forwarding of the
services routine ip
and in the content server they should
support the binding of the service
routing ib under the traditional
destination address ip we think that the
value of service routing exists mainly
in the period or establishing the
connection
and after the connection is as
established we can use
the normal ip
normal destination address app instead
next page please
we also analysis the hash conflicts
people and services
we think that at the beginning we do not
think that
we were
gonna have too many essential services
that are requiring
uh requires this uh ultimate yoga
experience
uh but if the mechanism is adapted badly
and the completely
exists between the hash domain names
in diameter we can enable uh the
mechanism that only on the most
essential service
or we can change the harsh algorithm
that occur that is running on the client
and the servers to make a better harsh
redoubt
uh
we also
think about several uh several solutions
for this but it is open for discussion
next page please
this is the service routine for fixed
accounts
mmc can also support accessing
fixed clients in this situation we also
have a
gateway
the broadband network getaway at the
gateway or client that can
work similarly
to the upf
uh but uh we can see that a tunnel
between the png and the imec may be
needed because uh the upf uh
pipes uh the the png is not in the imac
and the i mean thc prefix can be
obtained in the procedure or
authentication of the client by the png
we also think about that uh perhaps
several mic may connect with the bngs so
ability to make a decision about which
i'm easy to connect
in this situation they will also think
uh
the client will also send two
attempts
and if the time to success it will
get access to a service more quickly
and next page please
oh that's all thank you uh thanks for
listening and welcome for comments and
contributions
uh any questions
thank you
i think
uh
as an ntd as individual contributor
honestly on this one
i wonder why you post this draft
interior for something which is more for
me like
v6 ops
uh
i
i can also
[Music]
uh share it
in other group i think but i think uh
it it
is also related to this
entire
working group
uh i'm personally i'm not really sure
that it's interior is the best place to
discuss this
uh we can continue discussion for sure
okay thank you
okay
thank you
eric again
you have suggested a mechanism for mac
and as far as i know mac is not
developed in the atf
but i guess in 3gpp
so this should rather be directed to
3gpp because it's no impact
for us here
thank you
but i think we have used a different ip
address
it should
be some agreement in itaf to use the
address that way
okay
thank you i think
donald is here now so we're waiting for
you
on time
number three
thank you
okay
hi i'm donald eastlake with uh future
way technologies
i'm going to talk about
revision to rsc 7042
which talks about iana considerations
ietf protocol and documentation usage
for ieee 802 parameters next slide
please
so it's this is part of a series of uh
bcps have been two or three before
and basically there's enough changes in
the document
seems to be generally better to replace
it rather than try to do a bunch of
updates that people have to correlate
so it mostly concentrates on the ana
considerations for these parameters
particularly the
parameters that are assigned by iana
underneath the eno ui
and i'll explain a bit what an oui is
and from other blocks that have been uh
allocated to iana by
the ieee registration authority it's got
some miscellaneous related information
of one kind or another and
just generally sort of explains to some
extent what these 802 parameters are
next slide
so it uh includes
uh sort of from previous versions and
updates
specs concerning assignment of mac
addresses
so the yana oui is zero zero zero zero
five e hex
so by virtue of having that
organizationally unique identifier iana
has the right to assign
mac addresses
that begin with that either with or
without the multicast bid on which is
the bottom bit of the first byte the way
ietf writes things
so those are the ranges that are shown
here on this this slide
uh they're both 48 and 64-bit mac
addresses if you're wondering what uses
64-bit mac addresses the three uses i'm
aware of are
802.154 which is zigbee
firewires ieee 1394
and infiniband
uh
just a for information di tripoli
will sell you an oui if you need these
blocks of addresses and under the ieee
rules these sort of
global
mac addresses are only supposed to be
used for hardware interfaces that is to
say the concept is you'd be a nick
manufacturer or something like that
but the ieee will also sell you a for
less money a longer prefix so that you
have a smaller block of
mac addresses because the number of bits
you'd have available to assign is
shorter at the end
yana can also assign uh extended ether
types they're called so the ether type
88b7 hex is a magic ether type which
means that it's
to be followed by an oui and then you
have two bytes
so anybody with an oui can
create up to uh to the 16th extended
ether types
and there's about half a dozen or so
currently available
currently assigned rather under the no
ui indiana could assign more of them
this document also mentions
the address family numbers
and the dns rr types that have been
assigned for mac addresses next slide
this version of the abyss
terminal 42 bis adds a specification of
cbor tags for mac addresses and ethernet
protocol
identifiers and adds information on the
structured local address plan which i'll
get
give more details on and company ids
she'll also give more details on and it
has pointers to some other blocks of
things that iana can assign there's
continuity fault management code points
that were allocated to yana and
those are assigned as specified in rse
and the registry is set up for what's
called vendor specifically
organizationally specific
link local discovery protocol code
points lldp is actually 802.1 a b
and uh the rc 8520
set up that registry and allocated one
code point and uh there's
uh a draft uh personal graph listed
there which supposed to allocate a
second code point
and uh this uh seven to four two bits
actually make some minor changes to
bring that sort of in conformance to the
way that
rfc 7042 suggested that vendor-specific
registries for code points under the
anna oui should be structured
and this this version also includes the
iesg statement on requesting ether types
it used to be that any etf working group
could ask for an ether type from the
ieee registration authority those
requests have to go through the iesg now
i'm not sure if the ieg would want their
statement in this
document but when came when it goes
through the iesc i guess we'll find out
uh or it'll be
found out next slide please
so uh
there's a allocation procedure in here
which is a little different uh mac
addresses are pretty cheap we've got
lots of them if you want one or two or
four or something like that mac
addresses unless it's a pretty bad use
you probably ought to get it because
you know we've got lots of them however
it sometimes makes sense to allocate
very large blocks of mac addresses
example ipv4 multicast uses half of all
of the
available multicast 48-bit mac addresses
under the iana oui
and mpls multicast uses 1 8 of them so
anyway for a small to medium-sized
blocks there's this designated expert
actually has two couple of them
i'm the primary and there's a secondary
uh that can disapprove or disapprove it
if you want a really big block then the
isg gets involved to
eradify approval if the designated
expert approves it the way it's
currently written if you want a large
block and the designated expert says no
that's that's the end of it but if the
designated expert approves it then it
still has to get ratified by the iesg
because of the impact on the available
mac addresses next slide
so what's this structured local address
plan
this is a 48-bit mac address shown here
in the with the ietf uh bit ordering
ieee tends to use the opposite bit
ordering because of the
physical order that bits are sent out on
the the wire for uh ethernet
so the the m bit there is the multicast
bit and that's uh still
unchanged from before if it's zero it's
unicast if it's one it's multicast and
it's also one of course if it's
broadcast which is all bits on there's
this x bit which is formerly the local
bit and if it was zero it meant uh
it's a global unique
address which is still true and it used
to be it was a one it meant just meant
local and means the local network
administrator had control over things
but it's been renamed x and there's a
couple more bits that now have effect
because for various reasons i'll get
into they decided that the local address
space should be divided into four
quadrants with
and this is actually an optional split
right now but it's the way things are
going so i think it'll become somewhat
less optional in the future
next slide
so here we go this is what the four
quadrants are with the x bit of one
uh
the next two bits above that are zero
zero it's just like current local up to
the network local network administrator
uh zero one is uh assigned to a cid
holder i'll explain that in a sec one
zero just sort of reserved obviously
local network administrator can use that
but you who knows they sort of reserve
the right to assign some other
use for that quadrant and one one is
standard assigned which is intended to
be assigned by a local dynamic mac
address allocation protocol
and this is basically to answer the need
because of virtual machines and because
of uh internet of things devices both of
which can be
quite numerous and dynamic uh
it's a violation of the rules to use
these globally unique mac addresses for
that sort of thing so you just wanted
some protocol to
assign them locally and dynamically so i
there's no reason for any this to be
exclusively uh any particular protocol
from any particular organization ieee
has 82.1 cq there's a couple rfcs on how
to do this
so uh
looking back at what what exactly is
this oui so uis are represent
organizations they're 24 bits they have
the m bit 0 and the x bit 0. so that's
great and if you have an oui you
automatically have the right to assign
uh
a bunch of unicast and multicast
globally unique mac addresses
so there are people who need a company
identification but they don't really
need necessarily this block of globally
unique mac addresses so that was the
idea of the cid so it has the
local the x bit a one and the y bit of
one z bit of zero and that basically
indicates that it's the top 24 bits are
a company identifier and if
this structured local address plan is in
use on the local network then you also
have
mac addresses you can allocate
locally this is somewhat similar to the
ietf
thing
that used to be in rfc 2153 for ppp
where there was a block of things which
were called
cf series ouis
although
i think this was somewhat the ietf
stepping on the ieee's toes
only about a half dozen i think were
ever assigned in this series so those
have
all these m x y and z bits of one and
the multicast bit is meaningless for the
use that it was originally intended for
uh so that's use that that's been
deprecated
um
and the only other funny thing is
interesting is that ipv6 multicast
has always been defined to use mac
addresses with the top byte being 33
which actually falls into this
administratively assigned quadrant and
it's interesting i if i mention this to
some people in 802 who have never heard
of this they say that's terrible you
know this is camping on stuff that
belongs to us and the ietf should fix
that of course it's built baked into
hardware and has been for many many
years and i talked to other people who
say oh yeah we knew about that we talked
to them at the time it's okay
so
anyway uh next slide
so there's also some stuff in here it
adds some documentation an example code
points where there weren't before the
two rfc sites cited there are just rfcs
that explain why it's a good idea to
have documentation an example uh code
points and there's you know it's just
it's a the various clarifications in in
the document and some minor changes from
before that i didn't get to here i
recommend you take a look at it if
you're interested in this sort of thing
so you can you can see what's there
next slide
so what should be done with this
document uh i'm fine with it going
through the interior working group
or it could be ad sponsored
thank you donald
any question comment
otherwise
go ahead j.c
thanks wassim um
yeah i think uh this document makes a
lot of sense uh and uh don i think you
did a great job at uh
encompassing and compiling all these
latest events uh definitely you're you
you participate very well and and i i
triple eight or two and then you're well
aware of all the latest and greatest
um i i
personally think that this makes sense
to to be adopted in interior so that we
can have some some more discussions and
and perhaps add some more
uh references if need be and then and
have the group discussion
so
i think it would make sense to to get it
adopted in interior
thank you uh if anybody has any
suggestions for additions or corrections
or whatever happy to hear them
carlos bernardos uc3m just a comment
that we have rfc
8948 that
basically are extensions for dhcp to
assign
mac addresses considering the slap
quadrants
just for for you maybe it's uh i think i
mentioned it here and i i don't remember
whether it's mentioned in the draft
right now or not okay i haven't checked
the draft
apologies but just as a potential
reference that you may consider that's
it that's my only question it's
something that should be mentioned in
the draft
okay thank you we'll do a call for
adoption thank you
okay
thank you all this was our last
presentation
so thank you for your time and
see you in london
thanks everyone
still
yes
thank you for the support
how this will go
i prefer to do it back in the area
okay
right