[Music]
so
okay it looks like people are still
coming in
um i see some tuna
in the room
so
you
okay
actually
um
okay i could have a few minutes now so
you should probably get started it's uh
i don't know
there
so you want to come up and get ready for
the microphone
while i do the introductory slides
[Music]
okay so sure can you do an audio check i
see you're there now
it's taking a little camera to work
okay um
i will assume that you can hear me in
the room uh if that's not true please
enter the chat
um so um
so uh welcome everybody this is the iota
open meeting uh at uh ipf4104 uh i'm
colin perkins i'm the irtf chair
hopefully you can all see and hear me
in the room and i'm remote
so uh i would like to
begin with the um
the usual note well slides
echo but hopefully it's not too bad
so uh this is the irtf open meeting the
irtf follows the
itf's intellectual property rights
disclosure rules uh and a reminder that
by participating in this meeting and by
commenting on the presentations that you
you agree to follow the irtf
processes and procedures including
disclosing any intellectual property uh
relating to the contributions that you
make
uh i'm sure most of you have seen these
slides before the the details are in the
documents linked but
essentially if if you have ipr on the
documents you're talking about you you
need to disclose that if you're
commenting a microphone
in addition a reminder that
the irtf routinely makes recordings of
these meetings uh available both the the
online and the in-person person meetings
uh including this one uh and this
meeting is being streamed uh
live on uh youtube as well as via the
usual meat ecosystem
um if you're participating in person and
you are not wearing one of the red uh do
not photograph lanyards then you consent
to appear in these recordings and if you
speak at the microphones um
then again your consenting to being
recorded and as i say the recording is
being made available on youtube
equally uh if you're participating
online and you turn on your camera or
your microphone and make a contribution
then
that that is being recorded and you can
consent being recorded
um and also the chat is also being
recorded and will be made available in
the the usual jabber archives
as a participant in the irtf um
as i say you uh acknowledge that
recordings of the meeting may be made
available and that the previous that any
personal information you provide will be
handled in accordance with the privacy
policy
um and you also agree to work
respectfully with the other participants
in the ietf and the irtf and if you have
any uh
issues or
concerns about that speak to me or speak
with the ombuds team
and the the itf's code of conduct and
anti-harassment procedures uh
linked on the slide also apply to the
irtf
um for those of you participating in
person um please sign in using the the
mobile meet echo the meet echo light
tool uh we're running the queue
electronically so if you have questions
then we're using the electronic queue
that's accessed by via the meet echo
tool
and keep the audio and video off if
you're using the on-site version that
the meet echo light tool
remote participants please leave your
audio and video off and unless you're
you're presenting
or asking a question uh just to avoid
feedback in the comment section
also a reminder for those of you who are
attending the meeting in person uh as a
covet safety measure um the itf is
requiring those those of you in
attending the meeting in person to wear
an
ffp2 and 95 mask
or its equivalent
and the only exception for that is the
the chairs and the presenters who are
actively speaking
uh in particular participants who are
making comments or asking questions from
the floor microphones are expected to
wear a mask at all times including while
they're asking the
those questions as i said the only
exception for that is
the active presenter at the front of the
room
okay so uh as i say this is the the irtf
open meeting uh the goals of the irtf uh
are to complement the standards work
being done in the ietf by focusing on
some of the longer term research issues
the iitf is very much a research
organization it's not a standards
development organization
and while it can publish rfcs and and we
do publish both experimental and
informational documents on the rfc
series that the primary output of the
irtf is his research is understanding
his research papers
the irtf is organized as a series of
research groups um
hopefully you can see them on the slide
here the the crypto forum group and the
uh privacy enhanced enhancements and
assessments groups met earlier today
um the the other groups meant uh sort of
highlighted in dark blue on the slider
meeting later in this week uh so please
do um look out for those groups uh this
week and try and attend the sessions if
you're interested in those topics
a little bit of research group news uh
i'd like to welcome curtis heimerl
who's uh recently joined as co-chair of
the gaia group the global access to the
internet for all research group
um curtis will be joining uh leandro
navarro who is um planning on stepping
down from
from chairing that group after this
meeting and jane coffin who is uh
continuing
so i'd like to welcome uh curtis
and um thank uh him for his service and
thankfully andrew for his his many years
of service to the group
and i very much appreciate the efforts
the android has put into chairing the
group and i look forward to working with
curtis going forward
so
thank you both
as i say the irtf is primarily a
research organization we tend not to
publish many rfcs we've had one rfc
published since the last meeting um from
the information-centric networking group
uh looking at uh architectural
considerations for um using an ic and
main resolution service
um but primarily the the iitf tends not
to publish much in the rfc series and
the output is more in form of
interesting presentations and
understanding and research papers
to support that
we run
the applied networking research prize
and the the goal of this prize is to
recognize that some of the best recent
results in applied networking research
uh is to to um recognize some
interesting new ideas uh which are
potentially relevant to the internet
standards community going forward is to
recognize up and coming people who are
likely to have an impact on the internet
standards process and internet
technologies
uh we're very grateful to the internet
society to comcast and mbc universal for
their sponsorship
of the a rp that
allows us to make these awards
bring different people to give these
thoughts
and uh
what uh what we're doing today is uh
the goal of this session is to to to
make some of these awards so i'd like to
congratulate uh tasha swami
and sam kumar who will be giving
their award talks
on this session today
um
tasha will be talking first in a couple
of minutes uh talking about uh his work
on data plane architectures what's the
line right in for insurance um and sam
will be following uh later in the
session talking about tcp
low power
uh we have two really really good talks
coming so
please do
please do stick around pay attention to
those again congratulations to
tasha and to sex
going forward um
look out for a little bit more of more
wood talks uh goten akiwati uh korean
cat and daniel wagner will be giving the
talks of atf-115
and the nominations for the um
nominations for the 2023 awards will be
opening in september 2022 so to look out
for those uh
um look out for the nominations opening
in online
okay did the audio improve
trade muting and restarting hopefully
you can hear me
okay
okay hopefully that's better as i was
saying look out for the uh nominations
for the 2023 a rp um in september this
year
uh and um congratulations to tasha and
to sam who will be giving their very nrp
talks today
in uh addition to the applied networking
research prize we also host the uh
applied networking research workshop
which we organize in conjunction with
acm sitcom
um this workshop is taking place
tomorrow it's co-locating with the itf
in philadelphia
so thank you to tj chung and marwan fire
to the chairs this year and who've been
organizing that workshop
um we've got um a program of uh i think
that there are four four really nice
research papers uh a keynote and some
invited talks on novel approaches to
protocol specification
as i say that the workshop's happening
tomorrow um if you're there in in person
then
please do consider attending if you're
attending remotely then you can register
and attend um
registration is free for anyone who's uh
also registered with the itf although we
do ask you to to register separately so
we know who's attending the workshop
um and the a rw next year will be uh
again co-locating with the the itf in
july 2023 which is planned to be in san
francisco
and to finish up before we get to the
talks uh i'd just like to
um note that we we are very pleased to
offer a number of travel grants for
these meetings um
both to support early career academics
and phd students from underrepresented
groups to to attend the irtf research
groups
and a number of travel grants for the uh
applied networking research workshop
um thank you very much to
the travel ground sponsors to akamai
comcast cloudflare and netflix uh for
supporting that um
if you'll you know please see the the
travel grants page uh linked from the
website um
for details of that um and if if you're
interested in sponsoring uh
the travel grants in future or if you're
interested in applying for a travel
grant uh see that webpage or contact me
for for details of those sponsorship
opportunities and again thank you very
much for the sponsors
so that's uh essentially all i have to
say today um
the agenda for the remainder of the day
um we have the the two a rp award talks
uh
tasha swami will be first uh talking
about taurus a data plane architecture
for per packet machine learning and that
will be followed by some sam kumar's
talk on performance tcp for for low
power wireless networks
okay um i will at this point switch over
to
uh tasha can you
check the microphone when i get the
slides up
yes it's okay
uh yeah i can hear you remotely
is it working in the room
awesome should i get started
yes just one one second if you have a
phone i can pass you control so you can
control the slides yourself if you have
the meat echo light if not then
shout when you want to go to the next
slide
okay so i should have control over that
um
while uh tasha is checking to see if
that works uh i'd just like to say that
uh
the that as i say the first talk today
is uh
he'll be talking about taurus at data
plane architecture for per packet ml
tasha is a phd candidate in the
electrical engineering department at
stanford
his research is focusing on the
intersection of machine learning
networking and architecture and he works
on the hardware software stack for data
plane based machine learning
infrastructure and applications
uh tasha is due to graduate this year i
understand he's on the job market so uh
if if you like this work then please do
uh talk to him he'll be
around at the itf all week and if you
find this talk interesting i believe
he's also going to be presenting in the
coin rg session later this week
um tasha over to you
awesome thanks colin
uh cool so
um i'm gonna be talking about taurus
which is a project that uh me and my
colleagues have been working on and so
taurus is essentially a data plane
architecture for per packet machine
learning and
go into a little bit of what
that means all right so
this here is a quote from a 2015 google
blog
and at that time uh
google was already dealing with uh over
one petabit per second of total
bisection bandwidth um and it's only
grown larger and harder to scale since
so what we're essentially dealing with
here is a situation where networks
require more and more complex management
with higher and higher performance
um and so it's
uh the time is ripe for finding new
solutions here
and
one of the promising solutions in this
area is machine learning so machine
learning can allow us to
essentially take in data from the
network and make progressively better
and better decisions as we train our
models
and
these machine learning algorithms can
approximate network functions based on
the data they see
and
they're also going to customize their
operation to the data that they're
training on which in turn means that
these machine learning algorithms are
actually customizing their models to the
network itself
and so we're sort of uh doing elements
of this already with handwritten
heuristics in the network so something
like an active queue management
algorithm or
hashing and load balancing and playing
with operator tuned parameters so
all machine learning
uh is doing here is taking the next step
by automating the um
the
search for these kind of parameters that
allow to work well within your network
so
uh if we're okay with using machine
learning we now need to examine where
exactly in the network it has to happen
so i'm sure many of you already familiar
with software-defined networks
essentially the control plane and the
data plane are split and the control
plane is responsible for policy creation
um essentially in the form of flow rules
which are installed into a data plane
where that's where you're going to find
your switches and they're doing packet
forwarding via match action
so
right off the bat there are two good
candidates for where we should operate
with machine learning
and
uh on the left here i have a diagram of
the same typical define software defined
network
but on the right uh i have a software
defined network with the taurus
worldview
and so
what we've actually done here is we've
split the machine learning operation
into training which is going to happen
in the control plane and then inference
which is going to happen in the data
plane so in the control plane policy
creation is going to take the form of
flow rules plus ml training and when
installing this information into the
data plane it's going to be sending flow
rules as usual but also the ml model
weights
and in the data plane we're going to be
doing our typical match action packet
forwarding but we're also going to be
doing decision making with ml inference
and so that brings me to one of the core
tenets of taurus and that's essentially
the ml inference should happen per
packet in the data plane
um and so the the intuition here is
relatively straightforward you want to
be able to do per packet operation
because that is the finest granularity
of traffic essentially operating on a
packet scale now not every application
may need per packet
level operation but
the there are applications that need it
and so the platform should be able to
support per packet operation and then
the data plane that's where the packets
are so if we're going to be doing
decisions on packets it should happen in
the data plane
oh
i think uh powerpoint animations don't
play well with the pdf um
so
that's okay uh
what what's basically happening in here
is that um if we were to do just a rough
off the uh off the cuff math here so you
have traffic at one giga packet per
second moving through your data plane
now in the time it takes you to send a
packet digest from the data plane up to
the control plane
calculate flow rules and then install it
back in the data plane in this case
we've assumed
half a millisecond for each step so
we've now missed
1.5 million packets
in our traffic stream by the time
uh we had flow rules installed into the
data plane so
in the example here we're doing anomaly
detection so we're trying to find out if
incoming packets are malicious or benign
and maybe if we find that it's malicious
we're going to install some rule to say
block that ip
um
and
by the so we've missed 1.5 million
packets during this flow rule
installation time by the time we block
that ip we've already let a ton of uh
potentially malicious traffic into the
network so
the whole takeaway here is really just
to
um show you why
we can't let
our operation for these kind of this
level of application happen in the
control plane and if we're committing to
using machine learning we can't have
inference happen in the control plane
so
fundamentally the conclusion here is
that the robustness and performance of
your network are going to be determined
by the quality of your reaction and the
speed of your reaction
so
in the machine learning world view the
quality of the reaction is going to be
determined by your training data so how
much do you have what kind of cases does
it cover how well is it cleaned
but also your speed of reaction so in
the case of the anomaly detection
you want to act on a malicious packet
the moment you see it you don't want to
have to go to the control plane and come
back and install any sort of flow rules
and
this is essentially the per-packet
operation in the data plane
so
zooming in on
uh
the control plane let's talk a little
bit about the actual implementation of
how you do this
so i mentioned before that we're going
to split our machine learning uh into
training in the control plane and
inference in the data plane and so the
key here is that training is off the
critical path if packet forward is
packet forwarding is happening in the
data plane
then
the control plane is not
uh responsible for making uh per packet
level decisions which means that we can
do our machine learning training there
at leisure and um
essentially we can we can put in
whatever the latest and greatest ml
accelerators are whatever your favorite
ml framework is um install it in a
control plane server and have it
training models offline
the trickier part
comes in the next step where
now uh we need to deal with the actual
critical path basically
um tackling packets as they come so
machine learning inference here
is going to happen in the data plane
like i mentioned and the the final
outstanding question here then is if
we're okay with doing
uh training in the control plane we can
use whatever existing hardware we want
and then what do we do about the data
plane do we have
say a switch that can do inference um at
line rate per packet operation
and
so this is really the the crux of taurus
and that's what it needs to do so taurus
is an architecture for per packet
machine learning inference in the data
plane
so
let's jump into the actual hardware
and how we enable this kind of machine
learning inference at line rate so i
have a picture here of a piece of
pipeline a protocol independent switch
architecture so this is
the typical uh
programmable structures you'll find in
these kind of uh switches so
some sort of programmable packet parser
match action tables that allow you to
encode your network functions and then
maybe a programmable traffic manager
so
we're going to actually keep most of
these elements
and just make a modification of
additional hardware that'll allow us to
do our machine learning inference
but the natural question is
if we're if we're committing to adding
hardware into the switch pipeline um
what does that look like and more
specifically what is the abstraction
here
with which we're going to create our
programmable machine learning
fabric
and so in taurus we use the mapreduce
abstraction so mapreduce is really
useful for machine learning because it
supports a lot of the common linear
algebra operations that you need for
your ml algorithm so this covers
everything from
neural networks support vector machines
k-means
all these different kinds of
applications and just as an example i
have here in the picture
um an example of a single neuron from a
deep neural network so you can see
exactly how map and reducer applied here
in this case in the blue box
we are doing an element-wise
multiplication that's our map with
multiplication with inputs and weights
and then we're applying a reduction and
so this is going to
essentially add all the values together
and
you're going to produce
a scalar value from your vector of
inputs
and then finally we're going to apply an
activation function and so that suffices
for a single neuron but you can
mix and match this pattern ad nauseam uh
to create a full neural network so by
stacking extra
of these blocks
um in parallel you'll be creating a
layer of neurons and then stacking them
sequentially you'll be creating multiple
layers and so that's how you can create
say a deep neural network
so the other advantage of the mapreduce
pattern is uh comes from the kind of
performance that it enables primarily
it's a from the the cmd parallelism that
same instruction multiple data so we can
get a lot of performance out of the
parallelism with minimal logic
and this is as opposed to what you might
find in a say like a
a typical like tofino pipeline where
they have vliw pipelines
which give you much more flexibility but
the cost here is that there's a lot of
logic that's needed for the
communication hardware and um
that ends up taking up a lot of the the
overall on-chip area
and uh in addition
simply parallelism gives us the ability
to
um unroll
the loops in our um
uh in our algorithms so the the idea of
unrolling here if we take the example of
um say a single layer of a neural
network and say you have four neurons in
your network you can either
execute them sequentially you're doing
one neuron after the other or if you
have the resources you can instantiate
all four of them in parallel
and so the trade-off here is that
more on rolling is going to give you
better performance essentially doing all
four of those neurons at once
while less enrolling means you only need
the hardware
for one single neurons worth of
operations but it's going to take you
four times as long so it's less resource
intensive but it's also uh
much less
a much higher latency and
but we get this kind of control with the
cmd pattern by um essentially on
adjusting unrolling factors
so
we went ahead and we
essentially adjusted the switch pipeline
with a mapreduce unit that
implements the patterns that i just
described so
the
the we still have our typical
programmable elements we have a
programmable packet parser match action
tables and traffic manager but you can
see in the center we have this mapreduce
unit and that's essentially what's going
to do our machine learning inference and
so there are a couple uh little
idiosyncrasies about the um the
arrangement of the pipeline that i want
to point out and uh and that's how we
use these different elements
for machine learning context even if
they're typically uh network elements so
a packet parser is normally for pulling
out your headers from your packets
and doing whatever you want with your
match action rules in this case packet
parsing is also pulling out the features
for our machine learning
inference and then we have match action
tables before and after the mapreduce
unit and so these are doing
different types of rule-based pre and
post-processing on our machine learning
inputs and outputs so uh the
match action tables before mapreduce can
be doing some sort of cleaning on the
features and then the match action
tables on the output
on the right side of the mapreduce unit
can be doing some sort of interpretation
of the results
and
so
when we actually went to design this
mapreduce unit um
there's a couple of things that came up
it turns out you can't really just stick
an accelerator into the switch pipeline
so
uh what we did was we kind of
established what were the the points
that we wanted our mapreduce block to
fit
and so most of all we wanted it to be
reconfigurable so essentially you should
be able to program it it can't be a an
asic for a single type of machine
learning application you should be able
to put in whatever or program whatever
application you want oops
and
it has some meat line rate with the
fixed clock so
this essentially uh rules out an fpga
makes an fpga will give you a variable
clock
we want it to be deterministic um
and of course line rate is our
performance requirement
and then minimal area and power overhead
we don't want to blow up the entire chip
area adding in
like a a map reduced block it should be
something that is
small but gives you access to a whole
class of applications
and so finally the
one little thing to note here that's
kind of interesting is that
most of these ml accelerators are built
to do
batch processing in an effort to get
high throughput but in the network
pipeline you're actually
processing packets as they're coming
which means that you're operating on a
batch size of one
which is uh turns out
puts a lot of different performance
demands on the hardware than a typical
accelerator would see
uh
yeah so um
i have a quick example here just to make
this a little more concrete going back
to anomaly detection
um
so you can you can uh imagine say a
packet coming into the switch pipeline
and we want to see essentially whether
it's malicious or benign
so the packet hits the first stage and
that's where we're going to um do our
packet parsing so we're going to read
local features
say our ip
whatever information we can extract from
the packet itself
the packet is going to move to the
second stage which are the match action
tables
and from there maybe we're going to do
some sort of uh retrieval of
out-of-network events so these would be
different kinds of uh elements of
metadata that the control plane may have
installed into the match action tables
so something like the failed logins per
ip
the packet then moves to the the center
block the mapreduce unit that's where
we're going to apply our learned anomaly
detection so you can imagine this is
maybe a binary neural network and it
gives it a a score from zero to one on
how anomalous it is so one is definitely
anomalous zero is benign
and
finally the match action or the the
packet will move to the post-processing
match action tables and that's where we
do our interpretation so say we got a
score of 0.8 so it's pretty anomalous
and
now we want to drop it or quarantine it
this is where the match action table
will set a rule for that such that when
the packet now moves to the traffic
manager it's going to go to the
appropriate destination
so uh
in the
paper we actually did a full um asic
analysis
of uh this taurus hardware and how we
can uh
we wanted to show essentially that it
has minimal overhead and it's feasible
to to build something like this
and so we based our evaluation platform
on a coarse grain reconfigurable
architecture called plasticine
and we programmed our applications in
the spatial hardware description
language and so spatial is just an hdl
that lets you um use these kind of uh
parallel patterns like map and reduce to
uh program your
um
your your reconfigurable architectures
uh at the loop level and so the the
basic architecture of the mapreduce unit
here is really just a grid of compute
and memory tiles so easily scalable and
very very straightforward
in the compute units we have cindy lanes
that are operating in parallel and a
reduction network that allows us to
implement the reduce operation and the
memory units are just um blocks of
banked sram
so
uh we're doing
severe pipelining within the compute
unit but then we're also doing
pipelining one level higher between the
compute and memory units so the idea
here is cindy parallelism everywhere
uh and then pipeline parallelism
everywhere and that's how you get your
performance really
so
uh
we went through a set of real world
applications
and um programmed them onto our asic and
we ended up using a 12x10 grid to
support all of them
and
we compared it to state-of-the-art
switches with four uh pipelines
and um
our reference which was 500 square
millimeters and
we found that our grid which could
support these different applications was
only adding a 3.8 percent overhead or
4.8 millimeters per pipeline
so um again before uh earlier i said we
want minimal area overhead so 3.8 is
pretty low given that you're now getting
an entire class of machine learning
applications
and jumping into one of these uh
applications i've been using anomaly
detection as a recurring example here um
we tried out two different types of
anomaly detection with support vector
machines and a deep neural network
and so uh
for both models you can see in the
throughput it's one gigabyte per second
which is the line rate for um
high end uh switch pipelines like your
tofinos and broadcoms uh the latency
that we added was in the um hundreds of
nanoseconds or less
so in this case you would choose your
application you can see here that the
bsvm requires 83 nanoseconds while the
dnn requires 221 nanoseconds so
depending on your slos and what kind of
requirements you have to meet you can
choose your algorithm to reduce latency
um
and then in both cases the area and
power overhead required for the hardware
to implement just these applications
is um
single digits or uh or less of 0.6
power overhead 0.5 area overhead or
point eight and point uh and 1.0
respectively
again
if you don't need um
say the full suite of benchmarks you
only want a reconfigurable fabric that
will let you do anomaly detection you
can do it with um
minimal overhead here and so
in the paper there's a
several more applications if people are
are interested such as
a congestion control network and a
traffic classification network
so
uh
we went through this whole process of
doing an asic analysis to prove that it
could be done um but as far as research
goes we don't really want anyone waiting
for some sort of mass-produced taurus
asic so we've put out an open source
fpga based test bed um and so this is
just a rough diagram of what it looks
like um at the control plane we're using
um your typical network os like onos um
we're using a tofino switch to to mimic
the
piece of pipeline elements like your
programmable packet parsers match action
tables and traffic managers and then
we're using an fpga to um
to mimic the mapreduce unit so we set it
up in this bump in the wire
configuration
um and so
uh
because of the limits of an fpga you're
not going to be able to hit the same
performance as you're going to get with
the asic
uh core screen reconfigurable
architecture
but it's there to serve
as a proof of concept for the
functionality
so just a quick demonstration of this
testbed
we did an example
essentially the example i mentioned
earlier about anomaly detection where
we're trying to do
uh detection of anomalous packets in the
control plane
or we're trying to use taurus and do an
uh anomaly detection in the data plane
and so with the testbed that i just
showed you you can do um
you can do either so you so in the case
of taurus we'd be uh placing our anomaly
detection application on the fpga
while if we're trying to do control
plane based anomaly detection we would
run it at the uh the controller on the
cpu
so
uh the takeaway here is is the same sort
of message on
um why you really can't
use the control plane for efficient um
machine learning just based uh decision
making
and um if you take a look at the very
last two columns the f1 score
um now this is the f1 score
for
the model when it was implemented on the
baseline which is a control plane or
taurus which was in the data plane and
in software
in tensorflow uh the f1 score is 71.1 so
you can see that taurus on the far right
side of the uh
the uh the table
is achieving an f1 score of 71.1 so it's
faithfully recreating the model as it
was in software and um we're processing
packets as they're coming in
whereas in the control plane we actually
had to
sample packets from the network and um
run it through the control plane and run
it through an ml framework and try to
install flow rules and what ends up
happening is that you miss so many
packets while doing this operation that
your effective f1 score uh drops pretty
heavily so you can see on the far right
column the f1 score for the baseline
ranges from 1.5 to almost almost zero
so
you're effectively throwing away your
model because of the added latency
so that's just uh one example of what
you know what we did with our fpga
testbed um
there's of course lots of other things
you can do but the just to reinforce the
point why you have to operate in the
data plane
cool so
yeah so that's mostly it uh for me um i
have my contact information here and i
have at the bottom the git lab link for
the fpga testbed we hope people wanna
can uh try it out and there's the link
to the full paper in this easy to
memorize url
so
uh
yeah i'm happy to take any questions
okay uh thank you very much
the excellent talk um
since we we have a some people remote
some in the room i think if if we can
manage the queue using meet echo uh me
take a queueing tool i think that would
be helpful
uh i do see i guess it's barry at the
microphone there
okay actually i'm being uh dave or am
right now um dave iran asks i assume the
class of anomalies you can detect are
those that can be detected by header
fields within the width of the alu of
the switch
things in the packet data beyond the
headers won't be seen is that correct um
so the in the case of anomaly detection
we used
the kde nsl data set which had a a
record of different um
attacks that were calculated from like
you said either header fields or
um
you can also actually calculate
aggregate fields from across headers so
you can um
say create like a histogram using the
matte checking tables across different
packets um
and
the the packets the
the packet
headers um are going to be limited by
the packet header vector size that's
moving between stages in the switch
pipeline but you don't necessarily need
to be limited to features in the header
because the control plane can install
different types of metadata into the
imagination tables and you can do your
own um processing in the match action
tables um over time or whatever other
kind of calculations you want to do on
your headers so the headers are just the
starting point for the the features here
hi
is this working yeah
george michaelson can i say
can i sneak two questions in is that
okay yeah
so the first one and this is the naive
attendee question i suspect the paper is
very important for interpreting that
last table
it was really quite opaque how to
understand the meaning of the columns
and their impact on a comparison to the
baseline i think there's a lot of
implicit knowledge in your table
structure i'm sure the paper explains it
the slideway it was just a bit of
produce to a naive reader
so at the start of your talk that was
the first point you made a
case to say that the delay between doing
a packet sample constructing
table match rules in the controller
injecting those rules down into the
functional plane and applying them had a
huge packet
loss and mismatch interval but it seems
to me
the delay to perform the ml operation
tune your ml have a model that is
representative of the condition you want
to model and then install that has a
similar cost
it's not to say there's no benefit of ml
i think it's huge but the component
that's about the delay cost of doing an
instantiation of rules i don't think is
the basis of doing it i think you're on
stronger ground arguing it's about the
ability to do complex match at line rate
than the static cost of doing the rule
installation
right so
um the installation you're right about
the installing the model itself so the
idea is that you could be taking
sampling uh packets from the your
network and be sending different kinds
of metadata to the control plane and
essentially be doing your training
offline and you can install model
weights or replace model weights
as uh as needed the idea is that
whatever is operating in the data plane
itself has nothing to do with the
installation of model weights yeah
completely agnostic and i thought i
thought that idea that you could do the
model training asynchronously the sample
exactly is very beneficial but if you
consider a new class of attack that you
have to understand it and do some form
of bayesian analysis and classification
which is completely unmodeled here
exactly how you do that training unknown
how long that takes it's not about the
speed of the chipset it's about your
ability to do the good bad
classification a priory to inform the
model and then download it that's quite
a high cost in time
yeah so so this is always like kind of
the uh the trouble with security rate
like if you want to do an on-the-fly
analysis of a brand new attack that's
not really uh what we're what we're
targeting at the moment here
but uh but in engineering terms your
case this is extremely fast at line
right well made i enjoyed listening to
it a lot
thank you thank you
so
excellent work to share
i have a question
doing machine learning and data blend
will consume more energy
oh sorry i can't
using machine learning in the data plane
will consume more energy
so and we would like to reduce the
energy consumption of filters and
switches
so have you looked at this issue yeah so
i think the
the
for
energy consumption needs to be looked at
maybe more holistically so while you are
increasing by some small percentage the
energy that you'd be consuming in the
the switch itself you can consider that
say if you're doing anomaly detection
you're removing
the cost of running an anomaly detection
application and software on a server
somewhere else
so with this like specialized hardware
here you're consuming less power
in the switch than you would running it
in software elsewhere so
on the whole
you're reducing power cost but for the
switch itself yeah you'd be increasing
it minimally okay thank you
okay thank you uh when i have questions
but for sure
[Music]
and i guess
while we're waiting at the
this is a an irtf
uh meeting which is which is co-locating
with the ietf um
and obviously you know since that this
communicates with the itf the question
is then you know to what extent have you
given any thought towards how that how
this might change or affect the type of
work the ietf does
are there any implications of these
types of systems so for the way
way we design standards or other types
of protocols
the itf designs or is this just a an
optimization that fits within the
existing architecture
yeah i think
so
one of the the things that uh actually
uh shamu who uh
asked a question earlier
um
brought to my attention was
that was what kind of um standardization
is needed for
packet headers if we're going to be
using them as
features or carrying model weights or
basically doing kind of this
like ml ml assist type operations um
so i think there's probably something
there as far as um
making a cleaner definition of what what
has to happen at the uh
the the packet standardization level um
to support this kind of machine learning
and make it
easier for different different types of
ml systems to
interoperate
[Music]
yeah that makes a lot of sense
presumably there's also something in
terms of the control plane and the
standardized um sort of programming
model for that in order to to
to specify the the model is that right
uh sorry very exciting
um i i i mean i'm thinking that your
traditional programmable switch uses p4
or something like that as a programming
model do do we need a similar
standardized programming model for these
types of ml switches
yeah so um
yeah so so it's like kind of a
compliment to to p4 um we went with
mapreduce so we're not necessarily
married to the idea of using
um a map produced blocker anything the
the bigger idea here is just doing
inference in the data plane um so but
yeah it could definitely help to have
some sort of standardization in the way
that p4 works but for
um the
the mapreduce element so
uh you could even consider like an extra
control block in p4 as mapreduce and we
actually we have another paper and
submission on um what the the language
level constructs here look like so yeah
there's that's definitely an area for
standardization as well
all right great thank you very much
are there any any final
okay i don't see anything screw thank
you
all right sam if you can come up while i
try and
share the slides
[Music]
all right so can you see the slides
yes we can see the slides here
okay
all right so with any luck you should
now have control of the
slide
they gone away
i see
so
that's is it working
i can see it on my oh yeah i see i had
to click share okay here we are just
took a little while yeah
okay scope
okay great all right so the second talk
today is um
focusing i think on a very different
problem domain um so in this talk sam
kumar will talk about his uh paper on
performance tcp for low power wireless
networks
uh this was originally presented at the
nsdi conference in 2020 if i don't if i
remember correctly
uh sam is a phd student at uc berkeley
uh advised by david culler and rolac
he's broadly interested in systems
security and networking and his research
focuses on rethinking systems designed
to manage the overhead uh using
cryptography uh and presumably also uh
improving the performance of tcp for
power wireless networks so um sam over
to you
[Music]
okay um thanks colin for the
introduction um as you said i'm sam and
i'm going to present my research on
performant tcp for low power wireless
networks and to join work with my
collaborators at uc berkeley and as you
mentioned it was published in 2020 at
nsdi
so
i'm going to begin by giving a brief
overview of of history of research in
low power wireless personal area
networks or lopens
to put our research in context
so low plan research began in the late
1990s and at this point in time
researchers deliberately cast away the
internet architecture based on the idea
that low panels may have to operate in
two extreme environments and two
different uh from regular networks in
order for the internet architecture to
directly apply so
many of the early protocols like s mac
dmacc and so on and the early systems
like taneos and contiki did not conform
to any particular standard or
architecture and this allowed the
researchers to nicely explore how to
tackle the challenges of low panels
without being hindered by having to
conform to an architecture
about a decade later in 2008 ip the
internet protocol was first introduced
in the space largely enabled by the six
lowpan adaptation layer standardized by
the ietf
and what happened here is that people
found ways to take the lessons that were
learned in the earlier systems and
applied them within an ip-based
architecture and this essentially caught
on
in a few years by about 2012 ib had
essentially become the standard in the
space
but surprisingly the adoption of iep did
not come with tcp
for example openthread a lowpan network
stack developed by nest and used in
in the smart home space didn't even
support tcp
and instead the community has come to
rely on protocols like coap
which are specialized low-pass protocols
based on udp
it's also worth pointing out that during
this time lopens have not yet achieved
the same kind of pervasive adoption that
we've seen
in other protocols like wi-fi at least
in the context of branding internet
access to devices
so a natural question is whether to get
that kind of pervasive adoption of
lopens we should adopt not only ip but
also the broader set of iep-based
protocols including tcp
in this context our work completes the
transition of low pans to an ip-based
architecture by showing how to make tcp
work well in low pans and a research
artifact is tcplp a performant tcp stack
for low bands
so what exactly do i mean when say
performant
well one metric is good put and that's
the amount of bandwidth that an
application is able to get when
operating over a tcp connection
now there have been a few prior attempts
to use tcp in the space uh typically
based on a simplified embedded tcp stack
like micro ip or blip
and what we can see in this graph is
that our work tcplp achieves
significantly higher good put than prior
attempts to use tcp in this space
in fact we can calculate an upper bound
on good put shown by these dashed lines
based on measurements of how fast the
radio can send out packets and how much
overhead is lost to headers and acts and
so on and our work comes quite close to
these upper bounds
i'd also like to share an update that's
happened since we published this
research which is that open thread the
low power network stack that i mentioned
that's used in the smart home space we
simply adopted tcp directly based on our
research it uses tcplp as its tcp
implementation and the research also
influenced thread the network standard
that open thread implements
so i'm delighted to have been invited to
spear help spearhead this process and i
am hopeful that that the adoption of tcp
in the space will help improve the
adoption of lopens more broadly in the
smart home space
so now i'm going to take a step back and
provide some more context as to what
exactly low pans are and what some of
the challenges are with using low pens
and i can do that by comparing low pans
to other wireless technologies that you
might be more familiar with so on the
left wi-fi provides a host with internet
access via an access point in the middle
bluetooth uh it doesn't really provide
full internet access it's more like a
cable replacement channel a wireless usb
of sorts
and then on the right we have low pans
which aim to provide internet
connectivity at the same level as wi-fi
would but to embedded devices and while
operating within the constraints of low
power for example having a transmit data
over multiple wireless hops to set up an
embedded mesh network
so lopez has been used in a variety of
applications for example scientific
applications like environmental
monitoring structural monitoring of a
bridge
and it's also been deployed in the
indoor environment in a smart grid
context
and recently there's been a push to
deploy it in a smart home and iot space
and the thread and open thread efforts i
mentioned earlier are one such attempt
but despite being useful for all these
applications it's difficult to use low
pans because they also come with a set
of challenges
the first set of challenges come from
the resource constraints the fact that
the embedded hosts have limited cpu and
memory resources
uh the second set of constraints come
from the link layer uh low pass link
clear like for example ieee 802.15.4
has a small mtu of only about 100 bytes
and has low wireless range which means
that in order to in order to get
connectivity over a large area you need
to transmit data over multiple wireless
hops
and finally energy constraints are also
an issue
you typically don't have enough energy
to keep your radio on and listening all
the time so you duty cycle your radio
what that means is that your radio is
actually in a low power sleep state for
say 99 of the time and then one percent
of the time you can turn on your radio
to send or receive packets
and in order to provide an always-on
allusion to applications despite doing
this to save power we need some careful
scheduling at the link player in order
to make sure the data is only sent to a
node when this radio is on and ready to
receive that data
so to make this more concrete uh i'm
going to tell you about the platform we
used in our research it's called
hamilton and some of the stats of this
platform
are on the slide the key point here is
that this kind of device is more
powerful than the devices we had when
low band research first got started in
the early 2000s but it's still
substantially less powerful than even a
raspberry pi
you cannot run linux in a device like
this instead you have to run a
specialized embedded operating system
and you can understand our research as
tackling the central question of how
should a device like this connect to the
internet
and the result of our research is that
we show that tcp ip works well
now as i mentioned earlier the adoption
of iep in this space did not include tcp
and that was no accident
the reason is that researchers had
doubts as to whether tcp would work well
and we expected it to not work well
given the challenges of lopens so here
are some quotes i've taken from some
research papers to show some of the
concerns that the community has had
about using tcp the first one is that
tcp is not lightweight and may not be
suitable for implementation and low-cost
sensor nodes with limiting processing
memory and energy resources
the second one is that certain features
of tcp may cause harm like for example
that the connection oriented protocol
aspect of tcp is a poor match for
wireless sensor networks where actual
data may only be in the order of a few
bytes and finally there's the wireless
tcp problem the idea that tcp may use a
single packet drop to infer that the
network is congested which can result in
extremely poor performance because
wireless links tend to exhibit
relatively high packet loss rates
so again to summarize more simply
there's concern that tcp is too heavy
that its features are necessary and that
it will perform poorly in the presence
of wireless loss
so
central to our research was
understanding tcp's performance and what
we did is we did a study where we
actually ran tcp in a low pan measured
its performance
and try to draw conclusions about how
well tcp really does or does not perform
and what we found is that out of the box
tcp indeed performs poorly but it turns
out it's not due to the expected reasons
that people had
the actual reasons were somewhat
different
okay so the actual reasons are that low
pans have a small l2 frame size
basically a small mtu and this results
in very high header overhead
the second problem is that hidden
terminals are a serious issue for tcp
when operating over multiple wireless
hops
and finally that the kind of scheduling
at the link layer needed to support a
low duty cycle and low energy
consumption interact poorly with tcp
now there's a key difference between the
issues on the left
and the issues on the right
the issues on the left if they were to
exist would be fundamental issues
there's no clear way to adapt tcp or the
link clear to eliminate those issues
but the issues on the right it turns out
are fixable within the paradigm of tcp
or a fairly straightforward techniques
so in our research we show why the
expected reasons don't actually apply
we demonstrate techniques to address the
actual issues causing poor tcp
performance and our overall conclusion
is that tcp can perform well in low pans
after all
so
that's an overview
of what i'm going to be telling you
about
and they're also by the way a set of
techniques that we propose in order to
make low pans work well which i'll go
over in the course of the talk
okay in the next part of the talk i'm
going to focus on the expected reasons
for
uh why uh or why the expected reasons
for performance don't apply
um and to go back here i'll be talking
about this technique in this part of the
talk and the reason is that this part of
the talk is more about our experiments
and our observations about the expected
reasons this technique has to do with
our implementation which is why it's
included i'll talk about the remaining
techniques in the next part of the talk
where i dive into how to affix the
actual reasons for poor performance
so our methodology is based on a
hamilton platform as i mentioned earlier
you can see the picture there this is a
hamilton platform connected to a
raspberry pi and the raspberry pi is
just there as a back channel to collect
logs and so on and measurements
uh the tcp stack was of course running
on the hamilton platform directly
our software stack is using open thread
with riot os
and we used a wireless test button
collector data where each of those
numbers is one of our hamilton nodes uh
the lines connecting them show an
example of a topology uh in reality open
third is going to generate this
dynamically this is just a snapshot of
what it might look like
and we ran tcp where one tcp endpoint is
in the wireless mesh on one of the
hamilton nodes and the other tcp
endpoint is hosted on the cloud and
amazon ec2
so um one of the first things we had to
do was to implement tcp
now as i mentioned earlier there have
been several prior attempts to use tcp
in this space based on simplified
embedded tcp stacks but we wanted to use
a full scale tcp stack in our study now
the challenge is that implementing a
full scale tcp stack is hard and in fact
there's an entire rfc devoted to all
describing all the problems that people
were seeing in full scale tcp stacks
back in 1999 even though these tcps had
matured for at least a decade by this
point
so
um our approach was not to implement a
tcp stack from scratch since we felt it
would be too error prone uh to do
instead we started with the mature
full-scale tcp implementation in freebsd
and re-engineered key parts of it so it
would work well on an embedded platform
and we call a resulting implementation
tcp lp where the lp stands for low power
so now that we have our implementation
of tcp we can concretely answer the
question of what are the resource
requirements of running tcp
so what we found is that tcp lp requires
32 kilobytes of code memory and about
half a kilobyte of data memory per
connection to store all of the tcp
connection state in a full scale tcp
implementation
while our platform has substantially
more code and data memory than that now
as an optimization we use separate
structures for active sockets that are
actually endpoints of a tcp connection
and passive sockets that are just
listening for new connections which also
save a bunch of memory as well
um but the point here is that you know
at least in terms of connection state
we're well within the bounds of the
available memory so natural question is
what about the actual buffers used to
send and receive data
so um the tcp buffers need to be the
bandwidth delay product and size in
order to be able to send at full speed
of the network
uh and we empirically determine the
bandwidth delay product has two to three
kilobytes and we can see in the graph
here how we experimentally did that you
can see two to three kilobytes of buffer
size the available could put over tcp
levels off
so
our conclusion here is that tcp
including the size of the buffers fits
comfortably in memory and in fact
there's another conclusion to be drawn
here which is that if you notice the the
size of the buffers is actually much
bigger than the connection state which
suggests that most of the overhead of
tcp doesn't come from the complexity of
the protocol is from the buffers and any
performant bulk transfer protocol would
need these buffers in order to transmit
at the bdp so in some sense the overhead
really isn't bottlenecked by tcp's
complexity at all
um there's also some we also introduced
a technique here in order to reduce the
memory used for the buffers uh and part
of this has to rely on tcp having both a
receive buffer and a reassembly buffer
to store in sequence data and auto
sequence data for reassembly
now
full scale tcp stacks like freebsd use
packet queues there's a separate queue
of packets for each of these but in the
embedded setting we don't want to use
dynamically allocated packets because if
we hold on to dynamically allocated
packets in a memory constraint setting
we may cause other memory allocations to
fail so we instead we want to use flat
arrays and the naive strategy would be
to have a separate flat array for your
receive queue and for your reassembly
queue
now to optimize this what we observe is
that there's an interesting relationship
between the advertised windows size the
number of bias we currently have and the
total size of the buffer which is that
the number of received bytes plus the
advertised windows size is equal to the
total size of a receive buffer
now the observation we make on top of
this is that all of the data we may
possibly get for reassembly has to fit
within the advertised window size that's
the contract of tcp that if you're
sending to a recipient you do not go
past their advertised window
so this allows us to actually store the
receive buffer and the reassembly queue
in a single flat array okay so the way
this works is that we have our flat
array and the yellow region with the
start and end pointers is just a
circular buffer to store our in sequence
data then as we receive auto sequence
data that needs to be reassembled we
store it in the same array past the end
of the circular buffer using a bitmap to
keep track of which of these bytes are
active corresponding to received out of
sequence data and which of them are just
empty slots on the array where new data
can be stored
okay so in this way we can significantly
reduce the memory for buffers by in some
sense not having to allocate a separate
buffer for a reassembly queue and just
sharing that with the buffer we've
allocated for the received view
okay next i'm going to talk about the
wireless tcp problem and before we talk
about that i need to tell you about the
number of implied segments is that
affects tcp's congestion control
so as i mentioned the bama's lip product
is two to three kilobytes
each segment is sized to about 250 to
500 bytes and this was chosen carefully
it's actually based on the technique
i'll tell you about later on in the talk
or coping with a small mtu of these
networks uh so we'll come back and
explain this but for now take it as a
given that our segments are 250 bytes to
500 bytes
and what this works out to is we have
four to 12 in flight tcp segments at any
one point in time
now this is different from other higher
bandwidth networks you might imagine if
you're transmitting over a higher
bandwidth network or over a longer
distance you may have hundreds or
thousands or tens of thousands of
packets in flight and in comparison 4 to
12 is is very small and that profoundly
affects how tcp's congestion control
operates
so here are some examples of how of tcp
and urena's behavior in a low pain and
for now focus on the left graph
here
our maximum segment size is 462 bytes
um and what's going on and when i say in
action segment size i'm actually
subtracting the space for tcp options so
this is how much data is sent in each
tcp packet
and our bandwidth delay product is
filled by just four tcp segments
so what ends up happening is that yeah
we're our losses are very frequent but
because we only need a connection window
of four segments in order to fill up uh
the bdp and send senate line rate tcp's
congestion control actually
is actually able to recover from losses
extremely quickly and we spend most of
our time actually sending at a full
window
despite the losses in the wireless
medium being frequent
on the right we have a more challenging
scenario where we size our mss to be
smaller and we use some active queue
management which induces some more loss
events but we still find that tcp is
able to reach a full window and operate
there most of the time despite seeing
treatment losses
so somewhat counter-intuitively we find
that because our bandwidth in these
networks is so small our bandwidth delay
product is small and as a result we can
recover to a full bdp quickly after a
loss
and this means that the wireless tcp
problem actually does not affect tcp's
performance significantly in these
networks
uh and it's much more resilient to
wireless losses in a lower pan than it
is in a higher bandwidth wireless
network so that was a surprising result
but one that works well for us because
it removes one of the obstacles we
ordinarily would have faced in getting
tcp to work
so now i've talked about the expect why
the expected reasons don't apply in the
next part of the talk i'm going to tell
you about the actual reasons for poor
performance
and going back to our slide with our
techniques on it i'll be telling you
about these three techniques now there
are a couple i didn't get to the zero
copy send buffer the link clear queue
management and that's because i don't
have the time in this talk to talk about
it but if you want to chat about it
afterwards i'll be around
or you can look in the paper to find
some details about those
so first dealing with the mtu problem
here's a graphic showing the size of the
mtu in ethernet wi-fi and i triple eeee
into the 15.4 which is an example of a
low pan link layer
and what we can see is that um tcp ip
headers are very small compared to the
ethernet and wi-fi mtus but they're
significant compared to the ieee inner
tutor 15.4 mtu
and this is going to result in large
header overhead okay normally we size
tcp segments to be as large the link
supports but no larger this is standard
this is what's used in ethernet and
wi-fi
but in the case of ieee air duty 15.4
it's only
104 bytes right our mtu is small and our
tcp ip headers can actually take up more
than half of that if you include the
cost of tcp options even if you use a
standard ip header compression that's
part of 6lowpan and what that means is
that if you're transmitting data in a
tcp connection more than half of the
data you're setting out are just these
headers and your good put is severely
affected by that
so in order to overcome this we break
this conventional wisdom and instead
allow tcp lp to have tcp segments that
span multiple link layer frames okay
what that means is that we're relying on
the six lowpan adaptation layer to
handle fragmentation and reassembly for
us
which adds some overhead but it means
that the overhead of our headers is now
amortized over multiple frames allowing
us to get some good good put
now there is a trade-off here um if we
use too much fragmentation if we set our
our mtu i mean if we set our tcp
segments to be way too large what's
going to end up happening is that we
rely on too much fragmentation and
that's bad because now if one fragment
gets lost we lose the entire packet so
what we want to do is we want to choose
our tcp segments to be as large as
possible to effectively amortize the
overhead without incurring more
fragmentation beyond that okay and this
graph was an experiment where we where
we measured the maximum segment size and
the good put that results and we found
that the gains essentially level off
around three to five frames uh so that's
what we use for our future experiments
and it shows that you know there's a
good trade-off to be made here where we
can get good good put despite the
despite the header sizes
now one thing that we didn't do but
could potentially help in a way that's
orthogonal to this is to get good tcp
header compression right because six
lupine currently standardizes udp header
compression with six low pen but not tcp
header compression and that's another
opportunity to reduce these overheads
further
okay now i'll talk about how the link
clear scheduling to support a low duty
cycle interacts poorly with tcp
so recall that these devices often don't
have enough energy to keep their radios
on listening all the time so we define
the duty cycle as the proportion of time
that the radio is listening or
transmitting basically the percent of
time where the radio is not in a low
power sleep state okay and in order to
get good energy construction we want the
duty cycle to be as close to zero as
possible
now there are several ways in order to
support this uh in the session
literature open3d uses a particular duty
cycling mechanism that's called a
receiver initiated duty cycle protocol
which i'll now explain so in open thread
you have two kinds of nodes we have
battery powered nodes where we want to
minimize the duty cycle and wall power
nodes that are plugged into a wall
outlet and have enough power to keep
their videos always on
okay
now sending a frame from b to w is easy
because w video is always on so we can
just send the frame whenever we like
more challenging is the reverse getting
a frame from w to b
okay so what has to happen is that w has
to wait
until b's radio is listening and how
does it know when b's radio is listening
well this is where the protocol comes in
what b does is that whenever it turns on
as radio to listen for a for a frame
it'll send a data request packet to w
informing it that it's now listening so
w has to wait until it guesses it a
request packet and once it does
then it can go ahead and send the frame
to b and b will listen and receive the
frame okay so what's the key point here
the key point i want to emphasize is
that these idle duty cycle is directly
related to how frequently it sends data
request frames b can choose to send data
request frames very rarely which allow
it to get very good energy consumption
but doing so would uh but by doing so
will cause more of a delay in getting
frames to it since w has to wait for the
request frame in order to send it one of
the uh one of the data frames
okay so now let me talk about what this
means for tcp operation and i'll do this
by comparing http over tcp to coap okay
and coap is a rest-based protocol
running on top of udp
and in our setup we had bsnw data
request frame every one second basically
it makes it listen for packets every one
second and that allows it to get a
really low duty cycle
now the key difference between http and
co-app here is that http requires two
round trips whereas co-app only requires
one round trip
okay so for the first round trip right
you start at a random uh phase within
the 100 million within the thousand
millisecond sleep interval so you'd
expect on average a 500 millisecond
delay and co-op is consistent with that
for http what happens is that for the
first round trip we see 500 milliseconds
but the second round trip starts right
at the beginning of the next leap
interval so the second round trip
consistently sees the worst case latency
when transmitting the packet from
b
okay and as a result http performs more
than twice as poorly as coap
on this workload now i want to point out
that there have been some recent
extensions to tcp for example tcp fast
open which you can use to eliminate the
second round trip and get performance
parity between co-app and http
but this problem also happens for bulk
transfers where the acclock nature of
tcp causes it to consistently experience
the worst case latency even for bulk
transfers so this is an important
problem to solve regardless of that
and our approach to solving it is to use
an adaptive duty cycle the idea is that
we can use the tcp and http protocol
state in order to vary how often we send
data request frames the idea being when
we expect a packet we want to send data
request frames more frequently so for
example if i'm an http server of one of
these battery-powered devices and i just
accepted a tcp connection i can be
pretty sure that that i'm going to soon
receive an http request on that
connection so i may choose to send data
request frames more frequently at that
point in time and doing this
nearly entirely eliminates the gap
between co-app and http in terms of
performance
so if we zoom out and look at the
overall network this adaptive duty cycle
technique works well for the last hop
going from a wall powered node to a
battery powered node but the overall
network still has to operate over
multiple wireless hops to even get to
that hop
and what we observed with the tcp
performs poorly over this chain of wall
powered nodes due to hidden terminals
so
let me step back and go over hidden
terminals to provide some background on
that for those who aren't familiar with
it
we can understand the wireless range of
a node is looking something like this
the unit just models the simplification
where we consider this to be in some
sort of perfect circle
in practice of course it can be more
complex depending on the exact
environment your deployment is in
uh but unit this model is is going to be
enough for us to capture the phenomena
of interest here so you'll go with that
um so imagine you have four segments in
a line i mean four four nodes in a line
with their uh with their transmission
ranges shown here and we want to
transmit data from a to d
now the nature of tcp is that uh we have
multiple segments in flight at the same
time for a single connection and that's
why we have segment one being sent from
c to d and segment two being sent from a
to b
but unfortunately this is bad because
the wireless ranges are going to overlap
at b so the two packets are going to
interfere there okay now in the context
of wi-fi we typically overcome this
using a protocol based on rts and cts
frames that allow us to mitigate the
hidden terminal problem in most cases
but in the context of lopens the small
mtu means that rtsdts typically has too
high of an overhead as a result most
uses of it don't use rts and cts packets
uh so as a result we're only relying on
csma right so at a csma can't detect uh
c's transmission
because uh it's all the way
because a is out of range of c and csma
at c can't detect a's transmission
because c is out of range of a
but both of the packets end up
interfering at b and the packet gets
lost
this also happens because of data
packets and acts going in opposite
directions so for example here
what we'll ultimately see is that
um
you get the same problem with b and d
both sending at the same time to c
because each of their csmas can't hear
the other
so to mitigate this our approach is to
add a new random back off delay between
link player rate price okay so the idea
is if you transmit a frame and it fails
which you know because you don't get a
link layer acknowledgement for it
then you wait a random amount and retry
the transmission and this is different
from csma in two respects the first
respect is that in csma
you do this randomized
delay with exponential back off if the
channel appears busy
in this case even the channel appears
clear if our transmission fails we still
do the back off so it's different in
regards of what triggers the
transmission
and second it's a much longer delay
right because in csma you can rely on
hearing a concurrent transmission you
can transmit immediately if the channel
appears clear in this new delay that
we're adding this link retry delay what
we're seeing is that we want to have a
delay that's chosen between 0 and 10
times the time to transmit a frame the
idea being even if there are two
concurrent permissions that can't hear
each other with high probability they
won't overlap in time
okay so
um the way this would work is that
uh each of these two nodes would send
its data once in order to go and they
would never collide but then when they
retry they'll transmit a second time at
hopefully different intervals and they
won't overlap in time and the
transmission will succeed okay so
um
we did a measurement study to understand
what kind of link delays would be
appropriate and what would work what we
observe is that there's a huge reduction
in packet loss
even from a small delay and as we
increase the delay too much it starts to
eat away at your good foot because now
you're beating a lot when transmitting
your packets
so we found that there's a sweet spot
here at around 40 milliseconds which is
about 10 times the time you transmit a
single frame and actually to the 15.4
so that's what we used in our study
um
and this reduced the packet loss from
six percent to one percent which was
which you consider a significant
improvement
so finally i'm going to summarize our
evaluation and and conclusions so
first i previewed this result at the
beginning we're able to achieve
significantly higher good put than prior
attempts at using tcp and we're very
close to a reasonable upper bound that
we computed based on measurements of how
fast the radio can send out packets and
the overhead loss to headers and x
we also did a measurement study to study
the energy efficiency so we used tcp and
co-app for a sentence and task and
measured the radio duty cycle over a
24-hour period and you can see the radio
duty cycle here
the key point is that tcp is not
significantly worse than co-app in fact
they perform comparably for the duration
of the experiment at about a two percent
duty cycle and we consider this a
success because tcp is able to perform
essentially on par as a protocol over
udp developed specifically for low bands
so now the tcp is a viable option what
does this mean well first we should
reconsider the use of lightweight
protocols that emulate part of tcp's
functionality
in the sense that you know if you have a
protocol that's specialized that
performs just as well as a general
protocol that's more interoperable and
used more broadly you should perhaps
prefer the one that's used more broadly
and is more interoperable
second we think that tcp may influence
the design of low-pan network systems in
the sense that you know for a long time
it's been the case that many sport home
devices that you buy on the market
require a specialized gateway to get
internet connectivity
um and tcp gives us the opportunity to
allow these devices to connect
end-to-end to any uh services externally
that they may depend on
and finally i just want to mention that
udp-based protocols i think will still
be used in lopens but just in the same
sense that they're used broadly in the
internet for applications where
specialized protocols substantially
outperform tcp
in cases where tcp performs on par with
specialized protocols using tcp is now a
viable option
so just to talk a little more about the
about the middle point about how tcp may
influence the design of low-pan network
systems when i say gateway architecture
i mean a setup like this where you have
your devices these smartphone devices
you bought on the market and in order to
allow them to communicate with an
application server and a data center
somewhere you have to install some
specific gateway in your home there is
some protocol translation and
application logic in order to bring
connectivity to those devices
uh what this means is is often the case
that some of you may have experienced
this is that if you go buy smart devices
from a new vendor
uh
now all of a sudden you need another
gateway for those new devices or even
maybe the newer versions of devices on
the same fender like for example uh for
a long time it was the case that for
life that if you have bulbs from say
lifx and bulbs from philips you would
need separate gateways for both of those
devices
um
so uh the the introduction of ip in this
space
didn't really change this in the sense
that now your application protocol on
the left is now implemented over ip but
you still need the application layer
gateway and the missing piece i think
that would allow an end-to-end
connection here would be to have a
transfer protocol that's supported on
both sides namely tcp and once you do
this your application layer gps become
regular border routers and you could
potentially consolidate these together
into a single border router
so
in conclusion
we implemented tcplp a full-scale tcp
stack for low-pan devices
uh we explained why the expected reasons
for poor tcp performance don't apply
uh we show how to address the actual
reasons for poor tcp performance and we
show that once the issues are resolved
tcp can perform comparably to low-pan
specialized protocols
that's all i have prepared i'm happy to
take any questions now
okay
thank you
sam now that's for that excellent talk
um i see we have a couple of people in
the
online queue and a couple of people at
the microphone
um should we do the uh
i guess they will do the microphone
first so
who that is but if you can go ahead and
say see your name in your question
so hi i'm matthias i'm one of the
co-founders of white great work thanks a
lot
um one remark and two questions uh
question first
so you argued that supporting tcp is
important because it's popular now quick
becomes popular did you work on any
comparison from the system point of view
um sorry i didn't quite hear what i said
becomes popular uh you said that tcp is
quite popular but quick also becomes
popular in the internet quick you know
quick so trying to quick quick yes yes
yeah yeah so did you do any comparison
uh so we didn't do a comparison against
quick but i'd like to comment on that
because that's a good point that other
transports are becoming popular many of
the issues that we addressed
aren't specific to tcp they apply
broadly to tcp and other protocols
needed for bulk transfer like for
example
um the main issues getting it to work
with hidden terminals getting it to play
well with link clear scheduling and so
on apply broadly to any protocol that's
transmitting a lot of data and wants a
significant amount of bandwidth
therefore i think that many of our
conclusions would actually apply equally
well to quickest due to tcp
okay
um
and another question i mean in your
paper you'll note that you also have an
implementation for gneic the default
networks they can write do you also plan
to submit the pierre to upstream's
implementation um
at some point we did have plans for that
but what happened is that riot os
already adopted a different tcp stack
and it seemed a bit redundant to
contribute a second one uh recently what
we have done is we have we must have
contributed our code to open thread
which now uses it as its default ecb
stack okay firstly i highly encourage
you to submit the pm
and finally remark um you said that
fragment needs to be
a packet needs to be is lost when the
fragment is lost i mean this depends a
little bit on the fragmentation screen
right if you consider for example
selective fragment recovery
um
it doesn't matter too much whether the
fragment is lost or not for the whole
packet
yeah so um my understanding about the
basic slope and work or at least the way
it was implemented in the operating
systems we looked at was indeed that if
a fragment is lost you lose the whole
packet but i do agree that there are
protocols you can use to recover a loss
for happening without losing the entire
packet and those could also help with
the problem allowing you to make the
packet bigger and amortize tcp ib
headers even better
all right hello um tommy paulie from
apple
thank you for doing this talk um very
interesting i'm
super happy to see
the use of tcp here um i just had a
couple questions from the presentation
um
way earlier and you don't have to go
back when you're talking about
the memory saving aspects and the
ability to have the flat
buffer you had the diagram there of you
know essentially here's kind of what's
in flight and then there's the out of
order bits
and there are gaps in there as well um
when you're doing this are you able to
essentially guarantee 100 of the time
that you'll never need to allocate
memory or is it like just most of the
time and then there would be a failover
case where you do need to have dynamic
allocation uh that's a great question uh
we ensure that you never have to
dynamically allocate memory cool and the
way we do it is that you store the data
there you have a bitmap to keep track of
which bits contain the out-of-order data
but the bitmap can also be sized
statically because it depends only on
the array size which is also static
got it okay cool
and then
the other question is more about kind of
what you're ending with talking about
how you can use this to get to internet
hosts and end
and i believe in your tests
you were testing against end-to-end
internet connections
for that do you need to modify anything
on the tcp implementation on the
internet servers because we were
mentioning things like timing the
re-transmit timing schedules that you
want to add randomness so you're not
colliding
um is this something that
needs tuning
on the internet hosts to make sure that
they are friendly to the low pan devices
or can you use completely unmodified
um internet hosts to talk to yeah that's
an excellent question and the short
answer is that the hosts on the linux
side were completely unmodified great um
i mean that's uh to say a little bit
more about that uh the timing that we
adjusted for like the randomized delay
was none of the tcp levels at the link
layer
so as a result the the other side
actually doesn't see any of that got it
um this is also one of the advantages to
us using a full scale tcp stack like the
one from freebsd because it's been
battle tested in the real world and it's
interoperable with all the major tcp
stacks that are out there and i just
want to say that uh interoperability is
actually a problem in the embedded space
many of the other tcp stacks you find
are have
have interoperability problems in pretty
subtle ways with the real tcp stacks
that are used and that's something we
manage a side step by using a battle
tested tcp implementation as the basis
of our study
cool thank you
[Music]
so hello this is thomas also from the
riot community thanks again for this
work thanks for using riot
there's
another encouragement using generosity
because you have a generic packet buffer
here which you could reuse that even
reduces your memory overhead even
further
just just a remark
one question about
about your
multi-hop experiments
you showed us nicely how by
jittering the the tcp forwarding how you
could avoid the hidden terminal problem
was that in a clean environment without
cross traffic with only a single tcp
connection
yeah so
uh the hidden terminal problem affects
even a single tcp connection in
isolation
um and we verify that our
randomized back off
fixes the problem in that case yeah but
only in this case i mean the normal case
is that you have background traffic
right
yeah yeah so i mean if you have
background traffic this is also why we
use randomized delays instead of fixed
delays because if you have a randomized
backup it doesn't matter the
interference is coming from the same
stream or a different stream
right in both cases you'll back up a
random amount and hopefully transmit
again without colliding
um
this is also why we did it without
because i mean there are several
particles you could use that look at tcp
state in some way
um and having it just be a randomized
delightfully the link clear gives us
some confidence that it would work
across tcp streams and regardless of the
source of traffic whether it's tcp
different tcp streams or even something
else
in this context did you also consider
experimenting with more flexible
link layer mac layers than
just a csm aca for instance the dsme
mech layer which is also supported by
riot
no we didn't experiment with that we
looked at the sme because that was the
most common one supported across all the
operating systems and networking
particles that we tried across tiny os
riot and open thread
so it's the most natural to focus on
that
okay thank you
thank
you all right thank you i think we have
a
remote question
am i unmuted finally
so uh this is following up on the
multi-hop case
uh so in these environments the uh
forwarding devices are in fact also very
low power low
uh resource devices
um did you see or could you speculate on
what you might see as to whether tcp
traffic would have more stress on the
buffers
of the forwarding multi-hop wireless
nodes
uh so that's a great question um first i
want to i mean
so first i just want to clarify that the
buffer is used at the intermediate
routers these aren't tcp layer buffers
it's just like the general packet
buffers used for forwarding because you
know an end-to-end tcp connection
there's no tcp state
sure sure sure but it may put a
different may put a different low
aggregate load
um
on those buffers than say co-app traffic
or something that's more
you know simple request response related
yeah so i mean of course it's the case
that when you're transmitting at higher
bandwidth you're going to place some
more stress on the on the buffers of the
intermediate uh of the intermediate
routers and there are a couple things
that that we do in that we actually did
in our study in order to help mitigate
that the first one is that we added some
active queue management functionality to
those intermediate routers where you
mark packets that's congested using
explicit connect using explicit
condition notification and so on in
order to prevent tcp from filling up the
entire buffer and keeping your cues
short
the primary reason we did this was to
improve fairness of different tcp flows
that are competing for buffer space of
these intermediate routers and also to
reduce the and also reduce the latency
of traffic uh but it also has a side
effect of limiting the amount of buffer
space that's being used by a single tcp
flow to address some of the concerns
that you brought up
thanks i was looking for the ac aqm
angle on that
all right uh
you have so
i have a question um
does the uh i i i very much like the
idea of the
headers multiple linked airframes
um does this put any constraints on the
link there or or does the six loop
handler
handle all of that
um
that's a great question so some of these
uh can potentially be handled at the
sixth low fan layer but others do indeed
have to do with with the uh with the
link layer directly like for example the
randomized delete that we added to avoid
hidden terminals is something that would
operate at the link layer right because
at the six little band layer
you don't have or at least you don't
naturally have the same kind of
visibility into you know when your link
clear acts are coming in and so on
whereas you would need that to determine
uh that resolution failed and how much
to back off on the retransmission and so
on so some of them do indeed affect the
link layer
yeah are the requirements that the link
layer delivers packets in order um to
avoid um damaging the headers or
or is six we're pen handling that
uh sorry i didn't understand your
question
is there a requirement that the link
layer delivers packets in order in order
because of the way you've uh sent the
headers split across multiple link their
frames um or is that all that the
reordering handled by six looper
oh yeah so the reordering and reassembly
is handled by six low pan and there's no
strict requirement that you have to
transmit the frames of a packet directly
one after the other consecutively in
fact one of the things that i skipped
because of the time limit was another
set of techniques we have
at the level of managing
how to deal with concurrent frames
basically how to schedule frames when
you're some of them are going to other
wall power devices some to battery
powered devices and in effect what we do
is if you if you receive a data request
from a battery-powered device then you
prioritize sending frames to that in
order to reduce its duty cycle and let
it go to sleep as fast as possible and
that's one case where we specifically
might interrupt another transmission and
not send its frames concurrently i mean
nuts in the streams consecutively
okay yeah that makes sense okay
gabrielle
me
hear me when
okay
um yeah thank you very much
for this work this is great stuff
um
i did have a
comment on
the comparison with co-app i think the
specification for co-app was not
entirely
based on
we can't use tcp type that thing it was
more based on we can't use http because
the justification for it was for
folks who wanted to use a restful
interface for the application layer not
every application of the year in iot
wishes to do that but there's certainly
a lot uh of a lot of incentive
to use restful so
uh when
when um the restful folks
started
to become interested in iot the only
alternative was http one one which uh
i completely agree is terrible uh it's
massager it's textual based vertical you
cannot compress it it's it's very
verbose et cetera it's it's terrible
um we subsequently had http 2 which
became a binary protocol and we actually
had a paper
uh three years ago in a in our w about
you know how to use that over something
like 6lowpan for example some just
initial scratching the surface but now
we have http 3 and quick and it's all
binary so um
i
i understand you you guys haven't had a
chance to go after the excellent work
you've done to look at those layers but
i would highly encourage you to do that
because that would that would address um
a significant portion of the
of the application layer incentives
um
to um
for iot as well
yeah so uh so thanks for
clarifying that um i do acknowledge that
co-op has has evolved quite a bit in a
few years some of those evolutions
happen after after we published this
work uh but i do want to uh to clarify
my position on co-op a little bit uh
based on what you said it's that uh
indeed i think that co-op is useful and
it has its uses and it's very flexible
it's been evolving a lot over the years
and that's great um i do i mean i have
noticed that coap has been evolving in
some sense more and more towards the
same kind of abstraction that tcp
provides right in some sense uh the
ability like for example with some of
the recent work on on streaming on
streaming block transfers and so on
all i'm seeing here is that i think that
an application that's built on coap in
these kinds of networks with all the
latest features like for example the
ability to have multiple blocks in
flight concurrently and so on would also
be wise to potentially consider using
tcp directly itself given that tcp is
also a viable option in these networks
but thanks for that comment
all right thank you
one more question uh benjamin uh salt
summit closet
i thank you so much for the presentation
i really appreciate it um i was just
wondering you talked mainly about the
applications of this in um in lans do
you see any application for longer range
networks like uh like mobile ad hoc
networks or anything of that sort
uh that's a great question so all of our
experimentation was uh was done using
ieee introduce 15.4 which is a personal
area network protocol and that was
motivated by the recent interest in
adopting some of that technology uh to
work in the smart home and iot space um
some of the i mean some of these lessons
might carry you over to the mobile and
an ad hoc network space like lp vans and
so on um i'm not sure i'll be able to
tell you any specifics given that i
don't have much experience with those
networks um but i mean
my first gut would be there's probably a
way to make tcp work well given that
it's been adapted to work on so many
different kinds of networks uh in all
kinds of different environments but
other than that i'm not sure if any of
this which of the specific techniques
would directly carry over
there thank you so much
all right uh thank you very much
excellent talk
[Applause]
uh
and thank you again to to both of the
speakers i think there were two two
really great talks there um
both uh sam and tasha will be uh around
all week uh i'm sure they'll be very
happy to talk with people more about
their work uh so
please do to find them have a chat chat
about their work make them welcome to
the the ietf and to the irtf
uh congratulations both to
uh sam and tasha for the award of the
anrp this time
um
as i said earlier look out for
more a rp award talks um at the the uh
itf one five in london in november
uh the nominations for the uh 2023 uh a
rp awards will be opening in september
so um if you know any good work please
think about nominating that work
and look out for the applied networking
research workshop which is taking place
uh co-locating with the itf in
philadelphia tomorrow
um thank you again everybody
hopefully i will see some or all of you
in london or at the end nrw tomorrow or
later this week
thanks everyone
you