so
what's happening
every one of them
is
you don't know
all right we'll be starting in two
minutes everyone
um
is
anyway maybe yeah
okay
all right
hello everyone happy tuesday
my name is david skenazi and this is
miria kuluwind
and we are internet architecture
enthusiasts and welcome to iub open
um
next slide please
so this meeting like many of the ones
you've been at and you will be this week
is covered by the note well
um
in particular
you've agreed to the note well when you
registered for this session um
some of you might have read it most of
you probably didn't read the whole thing
um
just want to point out that anything
said here or on the list or in the chat
or on github or any related to ietf is
considered an itf contribution and
triggers some legal responsibilities in
terms of disclosing patents for example
that you know about
i
generally don't think there are that
many patents when we're talking about
policy things but who knows
just be aware of such things
additionally
the
itf network covers our
code of conduct in our anti-harassment
policy
just those are incredibly important this
meeting has always been pleasant and i
just want to make sure we keep it that
way
so
yeah so
let's be happy everyone be nice
um these
are our usual meeting tips um please
make sure to join the session on meet
echo even if you are here in person
uh
that way we have a count of attendance
so you can either join the full meet
echo client on your laptop or the lite
client on your phone
both of them fill out the blue sheets
and allow you to raise your hand if you
want to talk at the microphone so
we're using the meet echo queue for
questions comments uh long speeches
so just make sure that you join that and
then walk up to the microphone so when
we call on you you're already there and
you can talk
additionally
the
want to remind everyone of the itf mask
policy
not the working group the thing that
prevents the spread of covid
everyone is required to wear masks
during session with
exceptions of people on the podium here
while they are actively speaking because
we're far from all of you
um so please keep your mask on while
you're sitting and also while you're
asking questions at this microphone over
there
um okay and uh remote participants
please stay muted and camera off unless
you're speaking and then when you're
speaking we do recommend taking turning
your camera on that way we can see how
good you look and if you don't want to
that's totally uh optional all right
next slide please
so what is ib open why are we here did
we walk into the wrong room
um
it's kind of
a session for the internet architecture
board the iab to share what we're up to
and to give the community an opportunity
to all find out and also comment and
give us feedback because at the end of
the day we're not just some crazy people
in an ivory tower where some crazy
people in an ivory tower who listen to
you
um okay next slide
and
how
should you send us feedbacks comments
rants speeches anything you'd like in
general we have this mailing list ib
ib.org that is the recommended way but
and we have some more specific ones such
as architecture discuss for
long discussions and for liaisons we
have another list but also feel free to
grab any iab member here in the hallways
we're
generally friendly
and you can recognize us by the red dots
we have on our badges
next slide
yeah so this is the boring part of the
meeting where we just give a couple of
updates so you know what we're doing um
we did manage to publish one rsc and
this one is actually important one it's
a new roc series um editor model it's
done it's implemented
where it's off our um plate so we're not
responsible anymore and like i provide
you more information
tomorrow in the plenary as well
um but then the documents we are
actually still responsible for
we have two workshop reports uh one is
in the rfc editor queue already and the
other one is in community feedback so
that's also done i guess feedback is
most um useful from people who actually
participated in the in the workshop but
anyway if you want to read it and
provide any comments um we're we are
grateful for that
um we have one technical document about
recommendations which we believe is
ready for community view um i don't
think the call went out yet but it will
very soon so so look out for that last
chance to comment on this document
um the ib thinks it's in good shape and
hopefully it's useful to the community
and
then we have one more document which is
under active discussion uh and we know
that this blockchain has provoked a lot
of discussion
um and and there will be more um time
for more discussion in the edm program
meeting which will be on thursday
that's the iab protocol maintenance
document
yeah and talking about programs
so a quick update on the electronic
dance music
or evolvability deployability and
maintainability of protocols
group
we're having an interim meeting so yeah
to a bit of context for folks the goal
is working group is to think about how
we can improve the process of making
protocols and documenting them
and we write documents aimed at
this
and we're focusing on one of those
documents which is uh draft ib protocol
maintenance
um which talks about
when
it might be a good idea to use the
robustness principle and when it might
not be and so we're having a
thursday morning meeting from 9 to 10
a.m
in the ib office on the floor below if
anyone is interested in that topic
please come and chat we had some really
good discussion on architecture discuss
and we're looking to publish this
document soon
so we're really encouraging folks to
come share opinions
um
thanks
yeah maybe one more comment so this is a
small room it's an open meeting
everybody is invited to join but like if
you if you're not actively participating
you might not fit right so it would be
nice to
to have those people in the room who
actually want to participate
okay and we have another technical
program which is the model t program or
the internet threat model program
and this we reported a couple of times
in the ib open meeting and the current
stages is that there was an interval
meeting um in april which discussed a
little bit about what are the next steps
for the program
um and since then there wasn't much
activity there was much discussion there
were like a few
small document updates
um but we're not sure what the way
forward is um and so we are actively
considering closing this program now and
that doesn't mean that like all the
problems are resolved or it doesn't mean
that the discussion is ending here but
it means that probably the program
doesn't provide the right venue for this
discussion anymore
so even if we close the program
discussion can go on on the architecture
discuss list or hopefully some of this
will actually find its way into the itf
or maybe there's also room in the irtf
but
the plan is to close the program so
we are we are still discussing this but
if you have any feedback you can provide
it to us
now i mean not now but you can send us
an email you can also provide it now but
i guess that's uh
that's yeah
okay
um then like uh again back to the more
less technical more
administrative side um
i just we just want to mention quickly
that we actually created two new groups
and this is really kind of for
um just our internal
um
support of our our functions so uh maybe
not that exciting for you but just like
for some transparency we have a new
group
for ietf and ieee coordination this is
actually not really a new group this uh
activity always existed we just like
home it now more officially on the data
tracker
so hopefully that provides more
visibility about the liaison work we're
doing there
um
and this is kind of it's uh
it's a it's a it's a closed mailing list
but it's like experts are invited on a
need basis so it's like a moving group
of people working on the coordination
and then the other new program is the
iab ice policy coordination
group
um and
this is really just to
intensify our relationship with ice hock
we have the liaison we talk to them
quite often and we thought that like
having having a group that can meet more
often and and can focus on topics and
make sure we don't miss anything
important will help us here so this is
brand new and and hopefully it will
improve our
relationship with isoc even more
okay um next is the ease on updates
since last time we added a slide on this
because we thought we want to
provide a little bit more
awareness about liaisons um to the
community
um not like a huge number of updates
this time but um at least there is uh
the rsac committee
which is in the process of of
rechartering so maybe that's information
that's interesting for some of you
and then we will have a longer update uh
from scott our laser manager to itu-t
this time
um to provide a more broader overview
what's happening in this organization so
that's also something new we're doing
right now and we go from like we start
with i2ut this time and then hopefully
the next time we we give you some more
updates about other organizations just
in general to provide more awareness and
coordination between the different
organizations
okay one more part here and that's the
more exciting part
workshops we are um just send out a call
for a workshop that we're organizing in
fall
and the workshop is on management
technics and encrypted networks
and we really want to discuss um how
management can be improved in encrypted
networks and also like how management
can be more
secure eventually and actually support
user privacy and security
so what we're looking for
is contributions about action
requirements um that are needed for
network management so things that like
are not only aspirational but like
actually can lead to changes um and
we're looking for people who are
interested in actually working on this
or provide solutions or just
explain solutions that maybe have been
provided already
so the call is out there please look at
the iab website if you there's more text
explaining more stuff
and then if you want to participate in
this workshop
you have to submit as a position paper
by email
and then the workshop is as always on
invitation
but if you submit a position paper you
have good chances to get invited but we
really want to know
what your thoughts are in advance so we
can organize a nice workshop
and then this is a little bit of heads
up we are discussing another workshop uh
on ira mental environmental impacts of
internet applications and systems this
call isn't out yet
but it's coming very soon so the ib
already decided that we want to do this
the workshop will happen in december
likely so submission will be a little
bit later in october
and we're interested to actually
understand what the impact is what are
what are the right metrics to measure it
and what are the data that we have out
there
and like what
what do we understand if you put
everything together so watch out for
this as i said the call is not out yet
but we will send it out very soon
okay
any questions on these updates
ah sorry we actually yep
um so i wish it were a question
it's it's more uh input to the iab
i hope you don't close uh the model t
program instead i hope what the iab does
is inject a little energy into it um
ib has been a little passive about that
program
there are five drafts uh there is
community interest um
but what we seem to lack there is enough
energy
to keep the program
what the iab sees as a symptom
is something that i think the ieb could
solve by generating some of the energy
the community has contributed some
drafts but we like you mentioned we had
the one interim meeting uh that doesn't
seem like enough to me so my input to uh
my input to the iap on the model t
program is don't close it and if the
conversation takes place in the iab
about closing it
make sure that you have a place to go
for those documents right that you've
you've asked the community for input
you've got contributions
and you've closed the program please
make sure that you have a concrete plan
for what to do
with the contributions that you've
already got
thanks
so i i well understand um that desire
and i understand that it's very um
not satisfying if we just close the
program and there's no follow-up but
what we see is that the
purpose of this program or the purpose
of a lot of the iab activities that we
do is to kind of trigger
a conversation in the community to uh to
point the community at gaps or topics
that think we think we need further
discussion so that's when we created the
program what we wanted to achieve and we
don't see this goal achieved so we don't
know like if keeping the program around
will achieve this goal
there are documents which have
contributed to the discussion
but i think a lot of these documents
were not um
were not considered as being
publicate public published on the iab
stream from the beginning so this might
not be the right venue anyway for these
documents
um we had a discussion today that we
needed menu for these documents
um and i understand it's very
frustrating that i just like can't
create it for you but i don't think this
when you will be in the iab
and i i can only
act in the iab i can't act in the other
part of the organization so i think it's
actually on you
to bring these documents to keep the
discussion going and bring these
documents
into its right place and one place we
discussed for example is also there are
some research groups which have
a relationship here like um prg
or hrpc
so you might want to approach um
these uh chairs in these groups or you
also want to maybe go to the sec area
and keep the discussion going there
thanks maria um
so
we we see two people in the queue that
aren't in the virtual queue we'll allow
your questions now but please in the
future everyone join the virtual queue
we want to make sure we're fair with the
remote participants
and
yeah um
why
oh yeah yari since you're the chair do
you wanna uh of the model t group are
you responding to the previous point
i mean if you're responding to the
previous point i think pl you you're
welcome to jump the cue let the queue
drain first i'll
thank you sounds good go ahead and you
can keep your mask uh when talking just
keep the microphone close it works
really well okay thanks
um so just to support what mike said but
more importantly for model please state
your name for the minute oh sorry
dominique lizanski um i'm the author of
two
drafts for model t on threat models um
and and threats
uh just to say i think just to say i
support what mark said but also just to
say i think it's not on us particularly
but on us collectively with the iab as
well the threat model has changed and my
drafts actually show that and there's
quite a lot going on in this area and i
would agree with mark and his comment on
saying that i think it needs support and
input and sort of zest i would say from
the iab as well as from the community
and i haven't let my drafts expire
because there's quite a lot there that's
changed and that's going on at the
moment and uh i just wanted to to make
that interjection that i would really
support seeing this giving it another
chance and to make sure that we actually
have a place to discuss
these threats and these threat issues
that are coming up
and let's be honest it's not just about
you know private sector as well there's
a lot going on right now that we really
need to take a look at in terms of
threat bottles so
there's this exciting one we discussed
today it's it's important to have a
place to discuss this with community but
that is not what we're doing in the
program in the program we're a small
group of people discussing it and we are
failing to bring this to the community
so we need a different way to do it and
it might not be an iab program
uh rob wilson cisco so just a quick
comment on your workshop on the network
management which i think is great um but
when advertising that you might
emphasize network monitoring and
operations more than network management
in a sense because otherwise you may
find that network management itself
isn't affected by this and actually it's
monitoring the traffic so just be clear
when it's being advertised to to pull in
the right people and make sure people
understand what's coming
you had a workshop on environmental
impact
on
whatever we do
does this include energy management and
sustainability
yari behind you can answer this question
what the person behind you can answer
this question
um
yeah so so the the um the workshop on uh
environmental impacts uh
it's under preparation we expect that to
be a virtual workshop in in december and
so everybody should be easily able to
participate
uh you'll be needing to submit the
position paper and uh
you know
submissions that are interesting from
from the point of view of the program
chromatin will uh will be accepted and
we'll have a discussion
yes it does include energy management
and sustainability
all right and i'm gonna cut the cue
after yari here go ahead yari yes i just
wanted to come to the mic and and say a
few words about uh model t so
i i don't claim that i have all the
answers like i mean i share the pain
that was expressed on the mic previously
um but um i i i i probably would have
you slightly different words than media
did uh so it's not not necessarily that
we're gonna close this and go away type
of thing it's it's more that you know
that we see some opportunity for uh
moving some documents at least forward
um for instance some of them in in the
iab documents and
um continuing the discussion
architecture discuss lists so
it's um at least for some parts it can
be an opportunity for actually
completing the work rather than
you know telling people to go away but
there are other parts that that we don't
necessarily have an answer for so we
need to work on that and we will be
discussing one of the documents by the
way today later
yeah particularly um for documents that
we want to move forward in the iab
document we are looking for
recommendations for the community right
so this is the part
um that makes most sense on the iap
stream
scott i think you have to be very brief
because i will
yes i will be as brief as i possibly can
and still transfer some information so
greetings everyone i'm the scott
mansfield from erickson i am the itu-t
liaison
manager between the ietf and the itu-t
and also from the itu-t to the ietf so i
tend to write liaisons to myself quite a
lot
so what i've provided here and this is a
presentation that's up on the website so
i'm not going to read every word on this
slide people can read
i just want to point out a few things if
there's particular information that
you're looking for
and then i'm here all week so if you
need to
discuss anything in here
a little bit more in depth just contact
me send me an email it's
scott.mansfield.erickson.com very easy
so
there are many things that we deal with
when we're talking between the itu-t and
the ietf
and so there's technical impact things
there's policy impact things there's
geopolitical impact things
so depending on what you're really
interested in
take a look at those things and then
decide if there's anything that you
might want to uh want to talk to me
about
for instance the itu-t focus there's
some topics there they they tend the
itu-t if you don't know
part of the itu
part of the un they like to look at
things from the top down so they always
have whatever the latest buzzword is
there's going to be a quantum thing or a
digital twin thing or whatever but what
that means to the itu
is different than what that kind of
thing means to the ietf so it's
important to keep that in context so you
go to the next slide so when i but i
provided in here
and there's even more now there was even
a couple more liaisons that came in this
morning even after i sent you this
particular version of it but
go to the the liaison tracker
that the online thing and you can see
all of them you can sort and so there
are several uh liaisons that we've
received a lot of them are for
information some of them are for action
i chair a joint collaboration activity
on imt 2020
and that liaison just came in this
morning so
if there's any group that has work that
they're doing
associated with 5g or the transport of
5g
those are the types of things that we
would like you to send back to the itu
so we can keep a database of all the
work that's going on
mainly so that we can avoid duplication
of work if the itu-t knows that work is
going on in a particular area they don't
have to start it all over again right
so go to the next slide
just real quick so there's another
slider liaisons
there is uh actually this isn't the
newest well that's fine
so there's a whole bunch of drafts on
trust in quantum so if you like trust if
you like quantum
the itu-t study group 13 meeting just
happened the two the first two weeks of
july
they produced quite a bit of work these
are some recent drafts so the next slide
i'm going to do this and then so the
activities there are joint collaboration
activities and focus groups and
correspondence groups and road map style
work so if you don't know what those
things are you can come and talk to me
but the groups that are very active in
study group 13 right now are identity
management autonomous networks
machine
learning data sets this is a new
correspondence group that's been created
so that you can discuss
how to how to standardize the transfer
of data set information when you're
dealing with machine learning
next slide
whole slew of new workouts and i chart
this is just study group 13. there are
11 study groups in itu-t there's a lot
to look at this is the newest work in
study group 13.
study group 20 is going on this week in
a couple weeks study group 17 which is
security is going on and then study
group 15 which is transport related is
going on in september lots of stuff
going on you can see that
these are the joint collaboration
agreement
links if you're interested in any of
these you can click on them and see what
their latest work is next slide
this is the information about quantum
information technology for networks
these are the deliverables that they've
already sent out so if you're interested
in that you might want to take a look at
that next
now from a geopolitical standpoint and
from an organization standpoint from
itu-t there are some humongous meetings
that have been going on because of covid
these meetings were supposed to take
place in 2020 and 2021
and 2022 well the meeting that was
supposed to take place in 2020 happened
a couple weeks a couple months ago and
it was called wtsa this is the one that
organizes the work for the itu-t
and so there's some hot topics there
what happened and some of the stuff that
that occurred if you're interested in
the resolutions or opinions or any of
the proceedings you can click on and
look at it there go to the next slide
wtdc was supposed to take place last
year
these are the things that uh came were
the hottest topics of discussion and
debate during the wtdc wtdc is for
itu-d
it's the development sector it's to help
connectivity across the world so you can
see
what happened there go next
upcoming is the plenty potentiary
meeting sounds very heavyweight
actually what it is it's the one that
elects the new secretary general of the
itu
so this is a big deal this meeting
happens it's three weeks it's in
budapest
no bucharest sorry
and the topics of this are
internet governance is a huge topic if
you care about policy if you want to see
what some of the stuff going on
in the world you can look at that link
there's uh the aai is going to be a big
topic things about openran and open
standards and open
stuff
there'll be more discussions about that
in high level res
high level uh resolutions coming down
the important thing that may be lost on
some people is the plenty potentially is
a treaty binding
meeting
which means
laws can come out of this thing it's
something that matters to a member
states so if you go to the next
um upcoming meetings that i've already
said those that's it
yep
thank you yeah look at the slides if you
have any uh questions follow the link or
talk to scott i think that's the easiest
way
so we're going to have a talk from yari
about data
minimization uh given that we're running
a little bit behind on the schedule
we're going to ask you to take questions
on this talk to the list and we're not
going to do them live right now
and i'd like to remember folks to please
wear their masks properly over their
nose and mouth in the session except
here right literally not here like your
exception um thank you so i'll try to be
brief um there's more to discuss but uh
let's let's do that on the list so this
is one of the drafts that has been
inspired by the model t work by the way
and there's there's more but this this
is one that we're discussing today um
and i actually believe that this is you
know potentially useful for for the iat
to adopt us as an iep document
eventually in rfc
um and that's why it's sort of i'm
asking that iab to adapt it and
talking about it here next slide please
so the context for this is that um the
iab typically doesn't like deal with
detailed protocol
issues it deals with you know broader
topics like trends in the internet or
some high level guidance for instance
rfc 8546 which talks about protocol wire
images and how they
eventually get used if you have any
information that somebody will end up
using it
and
our question was in the model t if
there's any guidance to give with
respect to data we share about users and
of course increased encryption will make
less parties
uh uh private to the information about
users
because you you know you encrypt
information flows but but you still
provide a lot of information to various
servers and services and maybe that's
too much and these services can also
share the information further either by
accident or through commercial uh
reasons what can we say about this
it's a hard problem but maybe there are
some things to say next slide please
so we came up with this
simple thing it's just called the data
minimization principle and we're trying
to use the principle of least privilege
and sort of set it in the protocol
context
um just reading out allowed that
political participants should minimize
the information they share for instance
they should
provide only the information to each
other that is necessary for the function
that they expect
to be performed by the other party
um and if they if they say more
information than that then basically
this wire image thing applies that
you know information will get used even
at the servers even if you encrypted the
whole you know tcp flow or or quick flow
um so it's really simple but perhaps it
needs to be said given that we are
sharing so much data the next slide
so you may ask how does it actually get
translated to real technical works three
examples and there's probably more we
can think of new new places to apply
this
oblivious dns oblivious https
um basically about giving full
information to any single participant so
that that's the clue there
privacy preserving measurements the ppm
working group
avoid giving a single user's data to any
party but still be able to provide
aggregate statistics for instance and
then
end-to-end message encryption between
users
so that you may use some relays servers
that relay information but you don't
tell the servers
the content of the messages
um but that's the destination where they
won't want to be relayed so pretty
simple stuff but but actually important
because we are sharing way too much
information in the internet today
so that's it and we're out of time
awesome thank you so much gary uh and so
if anyone has comments or questions
please send them on architecture on the
architecture discuss mailing list
all right
dr cabral thanks so much for coming over
to give an invited talk the floor is
yours
yeah so we we invited um dr cabral
uh he is a professor of economics and
international business at the university
of new york so it was a short drive but
it was quite spontaneously so like
really
here
um and we invited you because of the eu
digital market act which was just uh
finished i think right very recently
and this already triggered some
discussion in the itf there was the mimi
barb off yesterday evening and there was
a lot of discussion there already and so
we are really happy to have you here as
an expert and i can just encourage
everybody to take the opportunity to ask
any questions they have now during the
session is i mean we have 25 minutes
left so let's see how far we get but
also after the session you will be
around for a little bit longer so yeah
thanks thank you for having me and and
i'll try to be brief so again i was next
slide if you could move i was going to
just very briefly introduce myself
because i i'm not by any means an expert
in internet infrastructure so to be very
clear my area of expertise is the study
of competition policy
and there's a lot of it on over the
internet and so there are a lot of
things that may be relevant for you
that's the reason primarily i'm here in
particular i uh co-wrote a report to the
european union in preparation of the
digital markets act which was approved
monday of last week so this is all very
fresh
so next slide please
i'm sorry if i'm starting from the zero
but basically as i said i i don't know
anything about infrastructure and i'm
primarily talking about
commerce over the internet so issues of
ip of competition and so forth those are
the issues that i deal with and those
are the issues that the digital markets
act and also the digital services act
which is the next one that's coming up
address and which i think are relevant
also for people dealing with
infrastructure so next slide please
um now being so ignorant of issues of
instruction i decided it might not be a
bad idea for me
not to assume any knowledge on your part
on issues of competition policies so i
apologize if i'm stating the obvious to
some of you but i'm going to start with
you know antitrust 101 uh what is this
all about um by the way if you're not in
north america this is usually known as
competition policy but it's essentially
the same thing see you know a set of uh
institutions and laws that govern the
way
um commerce is done not just on internet
but more generally okay um
some key players might be the antitrust
division of the u.s department of
justice or in europe dg comp the
directorate of competition which is
probably the most powerful directorate
in the european union and then there's a
whole set of of laws
one thing that's a bit peculiar of
competition policy and this may sound a
little strange to you
and if it does it is because it's
strange it's jurisdiction
so um
strictly speak in practice i should say
every competition authority in any
country in the world has jurisdiction
over pretty much every firm in the world
it sounds a little strange but it's true
so just a few months ago the united
kingdom blocked the acquisition
of giphy by meta so we have an
acquisition of two american firms and
that acquisition was blocked by a united
kingdom regulator
how come how did he find that
jurisdiction well to the extent that
meta and gif you want to do business in
the uk
they have to follow their rules they
decide you cannot do that acquisition
and they cannot afford not to do
business in the united kingdom
then they have to follow
whatever is imposed on them so this is
so much it's very different from refined
in these meetings and
because it's not so much about
uh global cooperation it's it's a very
fragmented
next slide please
um just again
three minutes for those of you are not
aware of um competition policy has
evolved a lot in the past 30 years in
particular one thing that we've noticed
is what uh my uh colleague thomas bond
refers to as the great reversal it used
to be primarily a u.s based tradition of
being very tough on how firms compete
and so forth whereas europe did not have
a lot of that and in past 30 years there
was a complete reversal between the two
sides of the of the atlantic and now
it's the european union that's been
really the leader in trying to enforce
rules for a level play field in in
commerce in general and in particular on
internet and and i think this is
particularly important when it comes to
digital markets and that survey when i
finally i'm coming to next slide please
my point uh which is the digital markets
act
this is all very fresh as i said it was
approved on monday of last week so
we're just living through it right now
and and
the goal is to restore some level of
competition
in uh digital markets and what i mean by
that is you know the usual suspects
google and apple and amazon microsoft
meta
and then maybe other smaller platforms
which are referred to in dma as the
gatekeepers
and i think
if i had to divide the structure of the
dma i would say there are three parts
that are important to it one is defining
who are these gatekeepers because we are
first to say who are they we're going to
be regulated second the list of do's and
don'ts and i want to talk a little bit
about that and finally how does this
work in practice how do you implement
this uh one thing is to have a law in
theory the other thing is how this is
going to work in practice so what i want
to do in the next uh three slides or so
is to go over uh these uh uh different
parts in greater detail
so gatekeepers um
there's a bunch of articles that you
find that um and i'm just giving you
just a little bit of the tip of the
iceberg it's basically you know it's
basically
as i said the usual suspects and
basically come up with rules that would
essentially include them so you have to
be large you have to be uh
entrenched power you mean in other words
have dominated the market for quite some
time
um and you have to have a a core
platform service so it could be a the
google search engine could be uh um
uh social uh networks on facebook and so
forth um
and there's an article article 15 one
that says that the commissioned european
commission will
conduct market investigation to decide
whether a certain corporation should be
or should not be included as a
gatekeeper and therefore subject to the
regulations in the dma next slide please
and the core of the dma and this is
probably what you should uh probably pay
attention to um
everyone should be is chapter three
which is the list of do's and don'ts
um
let me just say that i mean if you ask
me does this have the potential for
being a big deal
and my answer is no this is the
potential being a humongous deal i mean
this really could be a watershed moment
in the history of the internet maybe i'm
exaggerating and perhaps of course you
guys have a different perspective which
is infrastructure but in terms of the
history of how google and microsoft and
and facebook and so forth
have been doing business i i feel i
think could change radically in the next
few years if this is really implemented
okay so uh it's articles five and six
there's a typewriter in there they
basically have
if i were to summarize article five
things that you really have to do or
cannot do and then things that
maybe upon further investigation we may
tell you not to do and and let me know
in the next slide please give you some
examples of what those things might be
just to give an idea how
revolutionary this could be if this is
actually implemented
no self-preferencing in ranking and in
indexing
so for example i mean of course
there's allegations we don't know that
amazon would favor its own products in
listing them on on the page
or that google there is some
evidence of that would
bring some of the
affiliated services up on the organic
search pages and so forth
that's
in the blacklist
okay
second huge this one friend which is the
idea a legal term for um
fair
and non-discriminatory
uh fair and non-discriminatory access to
click and query data this is huge
basically saying that google has has to
provide click and query data or amazon
whatever to third parties at a
reasonable price of course what does
reasonable mean you know i don't know
this for lawyers to decide largely but i
mean
never like this is an important very
important step
interoperability there's
a lot of instances where things will be
important one of them that's dealt with
in dma is for for example for messaging
services
so i may if i have a new the cabral
messenger i may ask facebook to allow me
to uh
integrate it with their own messenger
now of course the devil is going to be
in the details how that's going to be
done but at least the idea is is that
that is this should be uh
important same thing for app stores
which are basically a huge monopoly by
apple and google right now
uh no restrictions on transactions off
the platform this is getting a little
technical but for example amazon does
not allow uh sellers who sell through
amazon uh to set a lower price elsewhere
sounds a little crazy it is crazy but
but it is true it's one thing that they
ask um
and then data portability if i create
now a cabral uh selling network i can
tell um
um
amazon that if if amir for example she
had an account on amazon
i want amazon to give me that data of
her past purchases so that she can have
all of that you know recommendations
that uh uh she had on amazon i can have
on my own cabral platform again
um
no precedence of of
regulations of of this strength uh i i
don't think in the history of the
internet and that's what the dma is
asking for
um and finally uh notification
acquisitions since 2000 uh gatham the
five top firms have made close to 1 000
acquisitions and only one was blocked
that was last year and it was giphy the
acquisition of giphy by mata so these
are just some of the items that are
covered in the lists of do's and don'ts
that just went into effect on monday of
last week and as i said i mean if this
is applied this is really a what a shed
in the history of of of the internet as
far as i can tell next slide please
so um
non-compliance again this is huge the
commission has the rights of uh article
21.1 of conduct on-site inspections i
mean i think it's pretty draconic but
it's written today i i still don't know
exactly how to interpret that but i i'm
interpreting the way it's in there that
i can just walk in here affirmative and
and ask you for the data for your emails
for everything
um
and basically you know this basically
just implementation in a decade finds up
to 10 of turnover this may not seem like
a lot but
it is a lot
i mean it could be i don't know into
tens of billions of dollars of fines
so that potentially this could be it
could be big next slide please
and so it's on as of last week
okay um
i think this has a potential of being
huge
but of course the devil is in the
details
how's this going to work
and i think one very important
difference in respect to the past in the
past competition policy has been left to
lawyers
and some economists
and i think one of the reasons why this
is very revolutionary this is going to
create an enormous demand for people
like you
because i mean how on earth can the
european commission know that amazon uh
is giving preferences no i need to uh
have ways of of um
i don't know finding out whether they
are
giving access
interoperability whether they are
actually sharing the right data
and so forth i mean there are so many
ways of of not following the rules and
this is not something that a lawyer can
figure out this is something that will
require a lot of expertise and and this
to me is the biggest problem the
commission has very limited staff and in
particular very limited technical staff
and i think this will be the biggest
challenge to see whether they can
actually face up to the big giants and
and force them to to uh to to
apply the rules that are being defined
by the dma so we'll see in the next few
years and let me just say that in
addition to dma another big thing that's
coming out is the digital services act
and that covers issues like liability
free speech uh and things of that sort
so non-technical issues but nevertheless
very important issues by large digital
corporations and i think like i said
um
i think it's great that the european
union is taking the lead on that uh
traditionally the u.s was really the
country where competition rules were
more enforced and more likely enforced
but in the past few years things have
kind of been reversed uh regulators in
us
have essentially been asleep when it
comes to antitrust and so it's probably
a good thing that european union is
taking on that role
so uh thank you and i'll be happy either
now or later on perhaps uh can stay here
for a little longer and answer answer
questions you might have about the dma
again thanks for having me
thank you so much can we no actually we
have questions so stay here don't run
away
so
let's see wes kick us off
thank you very much very interesting uh
talk
and i hope you know that it actually
comes true to some extent that it
promotes interoperability at layers uh
higher than we we typically see in the
ietf these days you know everybody wants
wild guard and log lock-ins and you know
they use base http and tcp and the
layers that we know about and then it
sort of stops because they're trying to
get vendor lock in what i worry about
and what i'm curious about is
does the document which i have not read
i apologize
uh figure out a way to avoid some of the
legal loopholes right so you talk about
you know they want to mandate instant
messaging right i could very quickly see
the companies going okay we're no longer
doing instant messaging we're now doing
something different
right so they're always trying to keep
one step ahead and get you know sort of
more lock-in uh is there any sort of
protections of you know that the list is
not this fixed list that you know will
is going to be out of date in three
years so i think you're asking the right
question and i i i don't have an answer
i mean the answer is no it doesn't have
it here
and there are a lot of loopholes i mean
one is for example encryption you can
say that well i'm what's up and you know
i'm i have this technology for
encryption and and if you don't have
that i'm not going to allow you to to
interoperate with what i'm just giving
you as a possible example they're
they're mirrored ways and of course the
large corporations have a lot more
technical people who can who can who can
do those sort of tricks yes i think the
reason why i i say that the devil is in
the details whether the commission will
be able to actually
implement this in a way that it's
practical and that prevents all sorts of
loopholes and and and tricks that the
large corporations may implement to do
with that and one of the problems that
you also point out which i think is
important
i mean one possible downside of this
is that they will just stop offering a
lot of services i mean if that's how you
want to do it then i'll stop doing it
i
don't think so
but a lot of people of course i mean the
large corporations are already saying
that it was part of the lobby by the
large corporate well if you're going to
start regulating us like this we're
going to stop offering search
on google well come on
or it's like so i i don't think it's a
credible thread i'd just like to know
you really scared me when you said
companies going to start implementing
their own encryption algorithms again to
get around the interoperability problem
i i'm now quaking
hey stephen farrell thanks for having
the talk that was good um so a related
question is uh
my related question is how
so the defining interoperability is
obviously going to take a while um from
the kind of regulatory side of it how
would how how would you see that process
happening and how long might it take or
is it just nobody knows yet
so one thing that i did not mention is
that the dma does uh include the
possibility in fact
suggests that there will be a dialogue
with the corporations that are
considered gatekeepers
so as to implement that i mean i think
the commission understands that they
don't understand things and so uh the
idea is that there will be some sort of
a dialogue uh
with the gatekeepers and perhaps some
interested third parties i mean
duckduckgo for example they've been
clamoring for for ages that they want
access to
uh indexing and so forth so my guess is
that the commission will uh call google
listen we we need to do something about
this and then it will call duckduckgo as
well to tell you know you guys are the
experts tell us exactly what you need
and and then negotiate that with them so
dma does not have in detail exactly what
this means just creates a platform as it
were for this to be implemented okay
largely by means of dialogue great
thanks and as a follow-up i guess i
presume there's no mention of things
like the ietf so far in in that in those
documents um
you know i don't know it's a good
question um
i think there's a mention of third
parties who will be uh relevant i don't
know that there's ieipf is mentioned
specifically
it should be because a lot of these
things are going to amount to um
technical
interoperability details
hi phil handbaker great talk i
you know i appreciate the informed
discussion of
this stuff
uh
i want to ask about switching costs
see the thing is at the moment we're
talking about competition policy and
company a can fairly compete with
company b
i don't care about the companies
i
care about alice and bob
and alice in one world garden can talk
to bob
in another walk garden is an improvement
but the real thing for me is
alice who is in one wall garden
can get up any time she chooses and move
to another wall garden of a choice
without losing all her friends losing
all the contacts losing etc so is there
any sign of that sort of movement uh
coming on to the agenda yet
so i think that's the right the right
question and i think that's one of the
areas where the dma is very specific now
what they can get it is a different
story
but i mentioned the example of
i have my amazon account and and suppose
there's another platform that has
amazon is obliged to provide the third
party
all of the search information that he
used of me all the information they have
about me that would allow the third
party to provide exactly the same
quality of service in terms of
recommender systems
that's the law
again the devil's in the details i mean
i i can think of a hundred ways that
amazon could could could uh um you know
screw things up for the third party uh
and that's where i believe
technical support is going to be so so
important you know lawyers are not going
to be able to do this
or economists for that matter
alyssa cooper thank you for this talk
it's very helpful
um i have two questions my first
question is
about interoperability so there's
obviously like many different ways that
you can achieve interoperability and
standards are just one of those um
and so i'm curious whether
there's a sense
that you have from your perspective
about whether the european commission
has preferences about how this
interoperability is achieved obviously
in this venue we like standards a lot
and we like to do things on an internet
scale
so a sort of
one-to-one dialogue you know with each
gatekeeper where they negotiate
bilaterally how they're going to achieve
this interoperability is sub-optimal
from our perspective
and you list it out i mean there's a
number of areas where interoperability
appears to be a goal it's very explicit
with respect to messaging voice and
video but there's lots of other ones in
there around the data sharing and the
ads ecosystem and search and all of that
so i'm just curious if uh if you if you
can glean whether they actually would
prefer to see standardized solutions to
some of these things or whether they're
kind of indifferent
um and then the sort of flip side of
that second question is
there's
my understanding of other pieces of um
european union legislation where they're
much more explicit about the
standardization requirements where they
actually you know detail them and then
um and then you know delegate them to
the european um standards organizations
or for like in the the data act where
they talk in cloud switching about um
the need for standards or interfaces and
it's much more explicit at least in my
reading than it is in the dma and so i'm
wondering if that's meaningful like the
fact that there is no explicit language
in there about standardization whether
we should read something into that as
far as um you know whether it was put to
the side
because it was not viewed as a viable
option um or if that was just part of
the political process right uh two very
good questions i mean i'm probably going
to read myself a little bit in here but
the dma
was
created by a bunch of politicians
lawyers and economists who know nothing
about technical details it was largely
an exercise in reverse engineering say
here are some problems that we have
we have to deal with apple we have to
deal with google we have
what is the law that would
kind of relate to that and so um in
answer to your question i don't think
there are any preferences because they
have no idea
pardon
my
sincerity now you're on the record i
have no idea how to do it and honestly i
i i i really think that this is an error
where you could make an enormous
contribution because
um
it's the the dma it's a that's a part i
don't like is a bit of a patchwork of
things which is clearly guided by the
problems that people have not by a
general theory of how it could be but
ultimately is as one of the previous
questions said i think the goal is to
end with closed systems
the internet right now is a series of
enclosed gardens
enclosed systems that do not allow for
competition
app stores
search protocol and so forth and so the
idea is to to the best that we can try
to end that
what's the best technical way of doing
that i don't know and i think honestly i
think that the european commission would
be delighted
to have iepf or uh ib contributions in
that direction
and but i also think that probably
depends on
what type of problem you're talking
about because you know an app store is
very different from search which is very
different from
algorithm
uh
i mean there are different types of
problems on the commercial part of the
internet i don't think there's one size
fits all in terms of
regulations thank you thank you
we have christian next remotely and we
are close to time so christian and
mallory can you please keep it short and
i'm cutting the queue after mallory
thank you for the talk it was very
interesting and it's interesting to see
that people are trying to address
competition issues
i am a bit scared by
what you have mentioned about sharing
data
i mean you mentioned competition as
being a big issue in the internet and it
is
but there is another big issue which is
surveillance
which is the fact that companies are
acquiring data about you
to
either sell products or
even
steer you towards particular
goals behaviors and all that and when
you say okay
now
everybody can negotiate with google or
amazon
and get all the clicks of their users
that seems to me like a
liberalization of surveillance
in the old days only amazon and google
and a couple of big guys could do that
but in this brave new world
anybody can get all the data all the
time and that doesn't that seems scary
um
i
my answer is i agree i i have to agree
uh i think much of what you're talking
about right now will probably fall under
the digital services act which is the uh
the next uh act as it were that the
commission is putting which includes
issues of surveillance issues of
monitoring free speech issues of
you know basically uh um
liability for users actions and and and
responsibility for the user users
privacy
i
don't know much about the digital
services act
but as i said i i think your question
probably refers more and more to that i
mean regarding the example that i gave
of of amazon search data
you can think of that as
in the old days of telecommunications
number portability i mean there's kind
of similar idea i need to have a system
whereby it's very easy for me if i want
to go from a phone company to another
company i can do it tomorrow at a very
low cost
it's the same thing when it comes you
know if you switch a different browser
you would like to have a way that all of
your bookmarks could be transferred very
easily
that's the kind of thing that the dma is
asking for in here is making it easier
for the user to switch from one system
to another system and to
impose the obligation on the platform to
provide that data so this is not a
violation of privacy this is data that i
know that amazon has about me and in
fact i'm glad that amazon has about me
because they make very good
recommendations but i'm sick of amazon i
want to move to
um cabral platform
and and i want amazon to give the cabral
platform all of that data so that i can
have a seamless transfer of of of
services from one platform to the other
so i don't think
here it's so much
i don't think it's an issue of privacy
per se it's an issue of
not allowing
the firms to have
proprietary rights over user level data
hi everybody uh mallory nodal at the
center for democracy and technology um
thanks um professor cabral for coming on
such short notice it's really good to
have um this discussion here um about
the impacts um i guess my question is
really straightforward so it's short but
you know we we've seen the global data
protection regulation for example gdpr
um kind of play out for a few years now
and i think a lot of people would say
there could be some changes we've got
notes
for those regulators and i wonder then
about the dma as well i suspect that
because we're already sort of
anticipating problems that some of those
problems will play out so what are the
mechanisms to revise this how long will
it take does it have to be in the courts
would the ec be more flexible and
actually changing this because i believe
it's a directive not a regulation or
maybe you could clarify on that and um
you know what kinds of evidence or
advocacy would be useful in bringing um
you know really big red flags to uh the
commission if it does happen to play out
in ways that we think it might but
actually then do correct i mean another
great question uh yes you're quite right
in fact the dma does have provisions for
it to be revised in the next few years i
mean my guess it'll take probably a
decade before the dust settles on it um
and and i mean any interested party can
can can contribute to it uh so so uh i
mean in that regards i mean i i think
it's a good attitude that european
commission have which is one of
willingness to learn and willingness to
adapt as time goes by
i have to say that data point that he
raised which i think is a very important
point is
i mean there are risks there are
enormous risks the egdpr one risk was
and there's some evidence already that
economists have been studying that this
had a very negative impact on small
startups because uh you know if um
cookies i mean information about
consumer data is what what made many of
these startups survive and thrive and if
all of a sudden you cannot do that it
creates an enormous bear to enter for
new startups so
clearly there are risks i mean for
example in the u.s i don't know if
you're aware of that but one of the
proposals uh senator warren and other
people have been posing is to have a
complete
moratorium or complete uh
prohibition of acquisitions of startups
by large corporations like i said it's
been about a thousand since 2000
i think that would be disastrous if you
ask me because it's an entire ecosystem
that would disappear overnight
so
it's important to take into account the
risks that such draconian policies have
and i think that's one of the reasons
why this is not set in stone i mean i
was probably dramatizing it a little too
much the document was approved last
i think it was an important moment
monday of last week but this is by no
means the end of the story it will take
probably a decade until things settle
down and there will be a lot of dialogue
with all the interested parties and a
lot of adjustment in india various
articles of the dma but it's a good
start i think it's an important start
all right thank you so much we're sorry
for running a little bit over time can i
ask everyone to join me in a round of
applause for dr cabral
[Applause]
thanks so much for coming over and for
great talk because i've been hearing
about this so many times and now i feel
like i understand a little bit more and
i'm terrified
um all right this is a wrap of the ib
open session we will be back in person
at the next atf barring another pandemic
and we'll see you in the meantime on the
mailing list thanks everyone for coming
and have a great rest of your itf week
and if you want to ask dr cabral
questions he's right there