we'll need somebody else to take notes
for extra i think
all right 10 o'clock so i guess we
should probably start to be on time
uh i'm jim fenton of course this is
braun
you're in the jmap session
uh or of the of the gmap extra joint
session extra will be
following jmap
whoops
let me just do okay
yep that was the right thing
so hopefully by this time of the week
you have been well exposed to the note
well but
we will continue to do it further
if you haven't read this in detail and
read the reference documents
you need to do that because it by
participating here
uh there are all sorts of uh
uh issues with respect to uh to uh
intellectual property rights and so
forth that you're granting
and um
uh also uh we expect you to abide by the
anti-harassment procedures and so forth
and to
continue wearing your masks when you're
not eating breakfast
there is also a note really well which
we don't have in this particular slide
deck that
goes into more detail in particular on
uh
things like code of conduct
so uh please
use the the the meat echo uh tool
um you can scan the qr code at the front
if you're not there already
it looks like there's a
uh
yeah we've got pretty pretty good
turnout for the uh
for the meat echo tool at this point so
that's great um
and use that when you're going to join
the microphone queue
uh if you're not
doing uh
if you're not actively presenting please
turn off your audio and video and also
your other
uh audio noise maker sorts of devices
and continue to wear your masks
uh unless you're actively speaking at
the microphone and actually we found
that
as i'm doing right now when you're
actively speaking in the microphone
you can probably be understood even if
you keep your mask on
if you're remote please use a headset
that that really helps cut down on echo
and that sort of thing
uh and here the places to find agendas
and so forth that
you have probably already found
so let's uh
jump to the agenda
and
this is this is kind of very very top
level
um
we'll be starting with the jmap
following with extra
and any other business
and was there a more detailed one for
yeah
on next page okay
so here are the uh the the different
drafts we're going to be basically going
through the current drafts
uh and we have a couple of uh
proposed work items that we're going to
discuss
following that
and then we're going to go back over
over our milestones as we usually do
and then extra will be following a
similar format
so are the is there any
agenda bashing to be done
hearing nothing
we will go on to the first item which is
jmat blob
are the slides there now
are there blob slides yet
uh you might need to hit refresh in
fantastic
i did refresh and it worked for mine
but you might need to go refresh
separately which is i just oh i need to
yeah i just did a no no not there
unfortunately it's in the data tracker
let me just start from mine it's gonna
be easy i think
oh
they're not there again there you go i
did refresh and and they were there and
now they're not there so
let's try that again
manage slides
it's there
refresh
text ready to be shared it's not there
wow
um
okay
i'm doing great with data tracker so far
not only of with the medical thing not
only these slides not in there despite
the fact that
i did hit the refresh there you go now
they're there
um but apparently if you direct message
somebody what you write doesn't show up
in the
system anymore
hey
there's really not much to say um
since last iatf i added the digest
response by request which allows you to
the server can say which algorithms it
supports
and then
you can request
that item on whatever range you've
requested to download
and it will calculate the digest over
that range which allows you to if you
have a partial download to check that
it's correct um before requesting
additional data so that seems quite a
useful thing to do and you can also
request a digest of the entire
content of a blob
which again will be quite handy for
checking that you have the right thing
downloaded
and so
i need to add some more text around that
um advice to implementers and some
examples at which point
we'll do the third working group last
call and hopefully the final working
group last call
before shipping this thing i don't think
there's anything else we want to add to
blob
at the moment so let's just get this one
done
um any comments on that anything
i see a thumbs up
awesome i think i'm done then let's move
on
oh yeah i need to unshare you can do
that
yeah
okay so uh quotas is the next one we
have
here and uh
it's already me
okay
hello everybody
[Music]
uh okay
so regarding zakuta i'm gonna be quite
fast as well
yeah so
i mean
i i got a few extra
comments from alexay so thank you for
that
if you are here
so the
first of all the soft limit
just adding a few
examples to make it more clear
like
like you could use the soft limit for
example to uh
[Music]
to stop uh
to to block
the user to
for uh
to send outgoing events like uh
like outgoing emails outgoing uh
creating new calendar events and stuff
but you would still be able to uh get
emails even get incoming events like
emails and uh calendar events created by
somebody
else uh
the example as well i i missed uh when
we changed the result uh
from size to octet i i missed changing
it in the example so that's
that's a good catch i fixed that
and i added uh
also some more uh content to the
security consideration section
uh
[Music]
regarding the
alexa's rsc uh
what he did as well for kota's on
imap
and uh
so i didn't get some warnings and advice
on the implementation
and that's pretty much
it for me if anybody has questions or
i feel good
no i guess there's a movement in the
room and nobody's joined the queue so i
think there aren't any
okay thank you
just before you disappear uh what do you
want to do for the next step so we're
ready to work and grip last call list
uh
the next step
yeah sorry can you repeat
so do you think this document is ready
for a working group last call now
oh
alexi gave a thumbs up as well so that
sounds like yes
okay
thank you i forgot to to make a slides
for that but uh yeah thanks i would
appreciate it
cool
okay great so the next item is oh
there's jmap blob it's somewhere in the
middle of the list here
gmap s mine
which is alexi
hello next slide
how do we share the
presenter yeah just a quick reminder so
uh
this is basically for sending s mime
signed and or encrypted messages
um the two main attributes uh on email
set is s mime sinus my encrypt
this hasn't changed
next slide
um so there were couple of open issues
which i addressed uh
one is controlling
um
signing whether it's encapsulated in
application pk7 mime container or
whether it's multi-part sign because
they kind of both implemented and
we probably want to give people enough
control to generate
either
uh the default is true which is
application pks7 mime which i think is
probably
uh slightly easier to implement for
people
and similar header protection
this is a feature of s mime uh there is
a document in lamps
um about
how to do this and suggestion was to
make the default rule so the address is
all the um email header is always
protected
next slide
so
neil if you want to
comment now that's fine
um
yeah i i read the draft i think
it's looking pretty good i just had one
bit of bike shedding was related to the
previous thing uh slide which was just
the name of that header protect field
seems inconsistent with the others could
we rename it something like s mind
protect headers or something like that
like mine sign a page okay that's fine
to be honest i kind of struggled with
names here so are they i just
think
sorry send you something just send me a
quick email and i'll change yeah i'm not
i'm not really married to names so
that's fine
um so the only thing remaining is i
think it would be helpful to be able to
also automatically decrypt messages
uh for this i probably need to
talk to neil to help me out how you know
how exactly this is going to work with
probably email bars but um
i um
yeah i ran out of time to to do this
this this this round but yeah i think
that's only thing outstanding so i'll
get to it next time
um
timing i guess what when do you expect
to
to have this ready for working group
last call
um
around 1 15
maybe a bit earlier
all right
okay well i don't see anybody else in
the queue so i guess we'll go on to the
next item
which is
i i see a hand in the room
did you have a comment on this
uh you need to go to the microphone and
you should probably join the queue via
the tool if you can both the microphone
and the queue thing i was actually for
some reason i got logged out so i'm
sorry for that okay so who are you then
please yeah my name is sachin garc
i had just a quick question about the
last point that alexa mentioned about
the uh decryption of part of the s mine
thing and uh to be fair i haven't really
read the specs i mean i'm coming from
something which is zero my only point is
the decryption part should it not be
handled by the client i mean how would
the uh whatever the server would know
actually what keys to use to decrypt it
that's a sort of a
question and how this thing works
might be a slightly off topic right and
so um
basically because
that is part of the extension is to be
able to sign and encrypt there are
already keys
so if
if it has
assumption is there is some kind of
directory or storage
which is trusted by by the user
associated with jmap
so if you have the key and you receive a
message that can be decrypted it will
decrypt okay
so the user trusts the source where the
keys are stored and then the key
difference yes so the idea is
yes
um and
i mean
in my implementation we actually have
keys kind of well
csr and certificate author generated so
again you know
you can extend this to
[Music]
automatically create and install
certificates in your you know store and
then use this to sign encrypt
any other
questions comments on this
okay in that case we will move on to
gmap tasks
and yours
hi i'm yours
um
yeah so in general tasks
just a quick reminder what's the goal
that we want to have what we want to
achieve we want to make a common
standard
also for kanban boards and issue
trackers so not just for groupware
next step please
oh there's a
that's a screen
okay so um yeah so basically this is a
list of all the things
that we discussed at last itf
um
that
should now
be hopefully sufficiently worked in
so the first thing is was an error of
mine i
edit related to instead of extending
relation
which should not be fixed
with new values like depend on
then the the second one was a suggestion
of of braun about how to add colors to
categories and keywords
i
um yeah i added that to the spec
then the third one um
having estimated work
um
as
so there was a the point raised that
estimated work
isn't sufficiently
specified because i said it's just
some value
it's in addition to estimated duration
because some
systems
don't use the duration they use some
abstract value
and i tried to come up with a
more a better definition for it and i
now chose fibonacci scale that that's
like a recommendation to to use
fibonacci scale that's a common
um
common scale people use in agile to
estimate their work
um
yeah
that's that's what i came up with i'm
not perfectly happy with that but
yeah for now i don't know first
iteration it should be good
i hope um
yeah so then another thing mentioned at
last itf was that
it's a bit un it was a bit unclear why
we have impact in addition to priority
and now the text mentions that impact
is one of the things that can be used to
determine the priority later on but it's
not necessarily the same thing
basically
just to make that a bit more clear
then
yeah i threw i had this i added this
source property during the last revision
i threw that out
because we already have
prod id which we can use for exactly the
same
thing
which is something that robert mentioned
last itf which is a good thing
um yeah and there are two other bigger
things that i already bootstrapped
during last itf
which i'm gonna explain the next in the
next two slides
next slide please
so
um
the first more or less big thing is
progress tracking
there was a comment that it's it was a
bit unclear that
the pro that um
it has uh i extended the values of
progress
um and i created
a suggested mapping of progress
[Music]
and it was a bit unclear about that that
there were several values that were
not really
easily distinguished from each other
when is a
work item resolved when is it completed
when is it confirmed when is it in
process and so on
and there was also the suggestion that
some systems even allow
defining custom workflows
on a project
level um
so
in the end
it doesn't really
depend on the system
on its own it also depends on the
project
how people design their own workflows
so the thing i came up with for
extending progress
or like like extending the the spec to
have
um
yeah better tracking of a workflow
that that should also be
that should reflect what's there in in
uh
issue trackers or
kanban boards
is workflow and in two extra properties
one for the task list and one for tasks
which is workflow statuses and workflow
status
so in the task list you can define
all the
allowed values
of your
workflow
basically
so like you can already do in jira
and
there are the workflow status is then
defined which
must be a value of of those that you
defined in the task list
and it um
yeah it says which of the
status which of the work where the
workflow currently is basically
and if you use the workflow status then
obviously
progress doesn't make a lot of sense
anymore so
it must be null that's
what's now in the spec
how it's written
okay
is there yeah maybe yeah we can go on um
all right and there's uh grouping is the
next
big thing so
here again as a reminder um
the idea is that we have different use
cases
and task systems are more heterogeneous
than
typical grouper systems so the idea was
um that also
to to make it interesting for for
task systems that don't have calendars
that don't have a lot of features to
reduce the implementation overhead for
those
okay next slide please
so
i came up now i already
triggered from first discussion during
last itf
i came up now with those groups so it's
basically common recurrences assignees
alerts localizations
custom time zones so they're grouped by
the feature set basically
the methodology i used um was i i looked
at three good reasons for grouping
certain properties so first of all they
should be
uncommon in a certain type of system
then they they
then they should not belong to the
like they should not belong to the
common group if they are uncommon in
certain types of system then i moved it
to
out of the common group
they should be optional within js
calendar
so otherwise it doesn't make sense to
exclude them from a
common group
and they should uh require some
additional business logic as well so
simple key value pairs is not something
that
necessarily needs to be
in a different group than the common
group it's
yeah it's easily implementable
by vendors
so um
yeah
as it is right now each group is a
separate capability in the spec
last time we discussed about using
sub-capabilities
i decided against using sub-capabilities
because it
avoids the additional complexity we
talked about having a
not supported or set error for example
yeah and it was just for me was just
more natural and simpler this way
of course
you can leave some comments on that
yeah what i'm a bit unsure about is if
it makes some developers
unhappy that want to support all the
different use cases now because then
they need to
supply six different capabilities now
instead of a single one
um
yeah so that's
basically kind of a trade-off i don't
know or
something that i don't really like about
having
six different capabilities
yeah it's not just a question in the
room
do you still like it how it
turned out
do you have some comments on it
um
yeah
so
i'm not sure maybe we can we can go to
the next slide this should be the last
one
for grouping so basically here it's just
a list of
systems and
what kind of
groups they would need to implement
just as a
as a validation that it kind of makes
sense
that the grouping that that's now there
all right
robert
yeah this is robert stepanek um
i have a couple of other points i would
like to bring up for but for grouping
specifically um
so what's the idea of how should systems
what should systems do
if they get
a js task that includes
properties
that are in a group this
they do not support are they i'm
supposed to reject that then or
are they supposed to let just store it
um what's what's the idea here
you mean uh like if you if you have um
if you have a recurring task um but
um that we see in the list but simbra
right what should simbra do when they do
not support recurrences should they
yeah they can just um
so um
it's just the normal
capability definition as it is so if you
don't
understand the capability
as a server
um
i don't exactly remember what the spanx
is i think they would reject it then
right so okay so you would
so um one would need to send um for the
js for the js the js task in chamber for
tags along with the capabilities
that the data contains so that the
server can identify
yes if it supports all of that
yes
yeah robert like i think it's um
you know this is a client talking to a
server so it's kind of if if you
implementing it the capabilities let the
client negotiate with the server what it
supports and turn on off features
if you were importing the data from
elsewhere so it had you know you had
exported something with recurrences from
google workspace you know importing into
microsoft planner that didn't support it
then it'd be up to the import tool to
say
sorry this has
stuff in it that we don't support you
can import it and we'll strip that stuff
or maybe don't
okay
yep
yeah
um i just want to add a quick
question on this
there were more groups on the previous
page than actually being used on here so
do we have stuff that we actually no one
uses and if so is it worth actually
keeping those
right now there are more groups
because this one's got the currencies as
alerts and signees i think the only ones
on this page that are actually being
you put next to what people are doing
the previous page i think had custom
time zones and something else maybe oh
yeah
uh localizations custom time zones
yeah so those two don't appear on that
list at all so that's correct should we
actually have them at all if no one's
using them
maybe i should have looked a bit deeper
that's a good point uh
that might that might have gone lost in
my
what i looked at yeah
the simpler the better in many respects
it's it's it's somewhere but it's it's
yeah
okay
yeah i didn't i didn't look at look
deeply into those two i'm sorry yeah
that's a good point
thanks a lot
yeah
so i had a couple of things one is this
particular point about between the
client and the server if i remember in
the
internet world we have this whole
concept of be
send or be very conservative in what you
send and be very broad-minded in what
you accept so
i think that philosophy about if zimbra
doesn't if i'm getting something from
zimbra and there are alerts there i
don't support it okay fine forget it if
i'm sending some i'm i'm not sure
whether the other servers actually use
that that philosophy are built on that
philosophy that if i send them two three
different things will they just neglect
what they don't know and or how do so
that's so but i think if it's going to
be for a particular implementation it
needs to be pretty
broad-minded in what it accepts and if
it doesn't implement it fine that's
sorry it does not support it the other
thing i was at this point was when i was
when you mentioned impact versus
priority
sorry impact and priority yes
so my thinking is that impact is what
impacts me as a person who's creating a
task for you
priority is what you decide whether you
want to take it up or not
if something is an issue with me there's
a bug like for example the dhcp v6 bug
and goo android which has been pending
for a long time yeah it impacts the
entire android community which wants to
use dhcp v6 but it is not a priority for
the google developers to do it
yeah i think that is i think the key
point that we can possibly somehow make
it
yes okay you mean you mean i should
state that also like to make that a bit
more clear in the text
yeah
but yeah that's that's a good point so
that that's the point that
it's important to have both in the spec
it's not the same yeah
wow quite a lot of people
robert
letting me in um yeah in regards to uh
reject rejecting
properties you don't understand versus
you know
just being able to store any extra
properties i would rather
the server
is able to store any extra properties
because it doesn't doesn't advertise the
capability obviously it cannot do any
automation based on them or any you know
derived property or anything like that
but i think it would be better safer if
you can actually store them
i agree um
is but that's that's the thing in a
course back right that
isn't it already defined like that i
don't remember 100
so okay if it cannot be done that's fine
all right robert
i'm robert stepanek again um i have two
remarks not related to grouping so
um i i think we're done with the
grouping discussion all right okay
um so the first one is just an
uneducated remark regarding the
estimated work property yeah um
so i understood that there are
multiple scales of how to estimate work
but at the moment there's just a single
numeric value to start it would it make
sense to
define
to add an additional value to define the
scale it is done in when there are
different
estimating schemes that that can be used
okay yeah the thing is i i didn't really
find like
typically it's just a value you know it
just says
how much work is this
and this now it doesn't say that there's
an actual
unit
to it
but i try to come up with a
like the common thing that people do in
in the agile world and
the common thing that i found was the
fibonacci scale
yeah
but i i would also be happy to just say
this is just a value and
you know
even
estimated work as an abstract value it
will depend on the team
you know to say well this is a six this
is a 10.
it it's i think it's difficult to to
have like a
interoperable
unit that that you know
that different systems will
understand i don't know it's yeah that's
how i understood um the definition of
the property although i then would
rather i wouldn't understand why
even the fibonacci scale should be
mentioned if it's really yeah an
internal decision okay um although i
would i would assume that
if tasks are supposed to get shared
between systems then some
some common definition must be
must be defined at least the direction
would be handy knowing which which is
larger than the other
is the bigger number larger or the
smaller number is probably worse
all right
that's a good point
yeah
okay um the other remark is
organizational and goes more to the
chairs uh chairs which is um
[Music]
now that shame up tasks defines updates
to
js calendar tasks um but she is kind of
the test it but she is calendar is
currently
getting reworked i don't know how to
solve these dependencies
we'd probably send them through together
um that's fairly normal to cluster
documents together when they're related
to each other so
hopefully these two can go together
otherwise
we'd need to wait for js calendar to go
first
okay understood thank you
all right
this would have to go want to go at the
same time as j mccallum as well
like german task is kind of
okay yeah the
last slide is just that we
are still working on feedback gathering
feedback so we have
through the ngi
project we have
some initial feedback from the weekend
developer and
the developer from to do
also gave some feedback within the chi
connect
rounds yeah but there's still more to
come there's still more work to do
yeah there are still some next steps
before we can go to a last call
definitely
cool do you need anything from the
working group other than reviews
not right now cool
and did you capture murray's
comment murray do you want to make a
comment at the microphone or anything
because just in case people didn't see
it on the chat
yeah it's not a question for the work in
particular it's actually more directed
to the chairs in the working group as a
whole um
calex has never been something i know a
lot about in depth so as i'm reading the
charter the word tasks doesn't appear
anywhere in it and i'm starting to think
oh no you've strayed from the charter
and i didn't catch it in time but then
someone said that
tasks sort of falls under calendaring
generally so like that's fine and then
in that case the only thing missing is i
just please send me a milestone so i can
track it
except this isn't callexed
yes um calendaring in general and you
already are chartered to do calendaring
related work so that's what i was
getting at i didn't know how tasks were
related to the charter that's all yeah
yeah in in the
calyx formats tasks are a subset of
calendars so
okay
all right very good
um
there are other things in the agenda
that don't have slides we should talk
through them as well
right and yeah let's let's hit those
before we go to the uh
to the new topics
so
let's bring up the uh the agenda for
this sharing specifically which i think
are both neil
uh well calendars is robert i think
right
okay
um
yeah um so
basically calendars is waiting on
resolving um
the
uh js calendar
discussion that's happening in calyx at
the moment
particularly around identifying
who participants are corresponding
participants with who you are
um so hopefully we'll get that resolved
soon and then um
you know it was been basically done for
a while now so hopefully we'll be able
to face it off and uh sharing too
we'll probably want to publish sharing
calendars tasks kind of together they're
all
related um
if it tasks is gonna be nearly ready too
and with the js calendar even uh so
yeah um sorry there's not been a huge
amount of progress but i'm hoping once
we have this js calendar thing resolved
um we'll be pretty much there
cool thanks neil so yeah we'll basically
just wait and put them through with
tasks when tasks is ready
sure
cool
all right new work new work
oh yeah
yeah sorry i forgot to see it as well
okay it's gonna pop up
okay so uh sieve i don't have any slides
because there's not much to talk about
um the only change since since vienna
was uh tracking the changes in the blob
spec
other than that this has been kind of
idling for the last two cycles
waiting for implementation experience
with the test method
which has yet to come so
i think what i'd like to do
is pull that out of this spec
and leave it as an extension
uh it's already optional in this
particular spec and i think with
the process i met draft which will be
talked about in the
extra session
there might be
a couple additions needed for the test
method anyways so
rather than hold this up i think that's
probably the best way forward
uh we've got this running in production
at fast mail it's totally replaced our
managed implementation
and so far we haven't seen any problems
with it so unless there's
outlying concerns that haven't been
brought to my attention i think we're
probably ready for
last call after i pull the test method
out
lexi
um yeah i think uh
you brown and i had a discussion and
maybe just leave it in and
do you see a problem pulling it out and
well i mean if you want to do the work
and split it up split it off i i don't
see it it already has its own capability
so
it's it's basically just moving into a
separate draft
so this can move forward
i kind of feel it's
a bit incomplete without it you know the
for real world implementations but
and it's not a big deal i suppose as a
replacement for manage sieve test isn't
necessary at all i don't believe
okay
i don't remember
hope we can take we can take it to the
list
you know if you feel strongly about it
we'll leave it in and then no i don't
know no i don't feel strongly
about it but uh
i think maybe what uh
we should do is you want to investigate
how to extend imp action anyway for this
right
right so maybe just look at it and see
how it will extend and whether you
already have genetic
um ability to have you know stuff extra
options that that the engine can
act on which is kind of part of that yep
but understood my only fear is
that without somebody actually
implementing it and using it there may
be other missing pieces that we're
unaware of
and i hate to publish something that's
not going to work for people that need
it okay
all right
rick
yeah uh this is rick sickness the uh
as as for incompleteness with management
i can tell you it's definitely
there is no
capability that matches the civ script
jmap testing behavior in manage ziv it's
a
it's a novel thing designed to replace
an internal system at faz mail so uh
manage it has check script right it
doesn't compile and we've
we've built that into the existing civ
script behavior and uh i think it's a
great idea to split them the basic
problem being one of the reasons we
don't have an implementation to test
with our
a user-facing implementation to test at
fast mail is we've never figured out the
right way to present it to users and if
we can't find a way to say here's how to
simulate this and present it to users
it's unclear that it's technically sound
right we might realize that
uh the the testing of the input and
output can't be made useful as an actual
simulation tool but meanwhile is a
replacement for managed script manager
sieve it's
it's done the job we're done we've shut
off manchester uh so publishing
everything done now seems like it it can
replace the old facility and this new
thing is still
it's just an idea
if there's no other comments
um i will
proceed to remove this
out of the current draft and then ask
for workinggroup.com
cool thank you
all right you work
okay uh on to uh
newark
i'll start with
migration and portability i think that
was the first one on the agenda
all right just a
quick organizational note if we
if we're kind of low on time then we can
skip the
preferences part but we'll go ahead all
right
okay so um yeah i pre i prepared two
small
presentations about
our experiences or some ideas that we
have
with jmap
the first one is to use jmap
as a
protocol for data portability and
migration
so in our use case
we
want to use jmap as a generic
one time api basically
and one time api is kind of a weird word
let me try to explain so
we
in our world we have a lot of legacy
systems from
which
we want to move to a more modern system
this legacy system has typically or some
of them have no api
so what we're looking for is an api
to be
used for
the
the task of migrating away
from the old system to a new system
um
and what would be great would be to have
to point
developers
that get this task to an api
specification that they can just
they can say ah okay we have this legacy
system we can just
put this api in front of it and
be done with it basically so it's
it may it makes the job a bit easier for
developers for this specific use case
and we looked at jmap
for this use case
you can use jma for a lot of different
data types which is great
so it's it's powerful enough it has a
lot of features
um
more than enough actually than we need
so that's perfect
the thing
that we a bit we struggle a bit with
with is the ease of implementation for
server developers
so let me go to the next slide
um
so what we tried
to
use jmap for this use case
is to bend it a bit to make it more
rapid
to make it easier for
for third-party developers to implement
the jmap
api and so these are just some ideas
that we had so um
how we change the the the core api
so
so developers are actually interested in
implementing this
without
too much overhead
so the the first idea is that we
basically we focus on the key
objects and properties from the api from
the spec
which are necessary for the migration
use case so
i don't know in some cases you don't
even need query
of course it's if it's a huge data set
you need it but in some cases you don't
in some cases
you don't need specific properties of
even a get request you don't need to
implement the whole thing
so basically what we right now have is a
document stating what's important and
what's not important for our for for
this particular use case to make it easy
to implement
so
um also what we did is we skipped the
session object which is a quite a big
one in my opinion
um we can do that uh
when the username equals the the account
uh
that you use for login basically so if
you only have a single user in a single
account you don't need the whole
complexity
about mapping an account to
a lot of different user ids
um
yeah and this just reduces quite some
overhead
yeah not such a
i don't know
easy choice to do that
um also we introduced a simplified
request for this
um
can you go to the next slide for this
or yeah
so um
yeah so to make it really easy for
people
um
some people might don't want maybe don't
even want to
pass
json
in their api they just want to
give us some json that we can parse
so
we
have this way that they can choose
either implement the normal way
very simplified
get request that you can see down there
or
have a
just don't use json at all for the
request
have it all in the
url
um
yeah so we then call this simplified
request
um
yes
so can you go to the next slide
okay so that's basically the idea here
to have
a
an api for rapid development
with which we reuse existing jmap
concepts and libraries
which is good because
we can reuse parts
of jmap
other people will be more interested in
implementing jmap
i we think it can be beneficial for the
whole ecosystem
because it
might spark interests
that that's not already there
yeah
there are some related problems that we
ran into like we we could
one could also
expose certain archives
laying around on the system and a file
system for example some people have
i don't know folders with icalendar
files or vcards that you could
you could easily expose with this
um with this with the wrapper
yeah
so those are basically some thoughts
that we have some some work that we did
and i just wanted to put this out there
and the idea was that we
right now we have some internal document
that we point people to
but it would be nice to have it to some
to put it in some public place
uh it's probably not worth an rfc i
would say
but yeah i want to leave that open for a
discussion maybe we we have a document
on some website or
do you have any thoughts on that
um
yeah
i'll just pop myself in the queue here
um one thing i was thinking of
way back even was doing more of a rest
type api so rather than the the
query parameters to actually have a path
object type and then id underneath that
and if you do a query on on just the
object type you get a list of all the
ids
and then you can request each of them as
a single item so making it feel more
like a a standard rest api
that's a different way of accessing jmob
data because jmf is very neatly
separated into objects with ids so
mapping it to rest might be something
that's worthwhile as a general document
whether that's an easier way to do it
than this
it seems like a useful thing to have
okay
yeah alexi um
it looks like you're modifying or
extending things you know to make it
simple to use for certain cases so
this should be a document
whether we choose to publish it now it's
kind of a separate issue but i think
there should be a draft
yeah okay
um and you know uh bronze idea makes
sense as well
all right um
yeah would they be interested in in
having this as a draft
idea in this working group is that
per charter
fine or
yeah by the charter it's fine
all right
yeah
then
okay
sounds good i would say
cool
um
i guess publish a draft first and then
we can do a call for adoption
maybe publish is informational
yeah yeah sounds good great
okay
so the the next thing
i hope it's very quick um
yeah it's basically about preferences is
some other thing that we did some other
ideas that we have
um
i just wanted to present here just to
get some to give you some ideas what
one can do with jmap so
um grouper preferences
are
not very well standardized
everybody does his own
thing
um
yeah there are
different
ways
like
they're different dimensions
even to it so
they can be in a certain context the
preferences for example in in out of
office in a male context or
for for calendars there there are
specific preferences that one can have
but they can also be in a global context
as well
um
and
there's the second dimension here is
that preferences can be
in a
dedicated data structure
for example you have an extra object
like calendar preferences or they can
reuse other mechanisms that are already
there for example you can have some
preferences as sieve filters
then there are also the third dimension
is that there's a diff it can be a
different scope so for example
preferences can be in the user scope but
there are also some systems
where they are an admin scope is what we
call it uh for example
some civ rules might be there for a
certain user but the user actually
doesn't see them it's it's somewhere on
the system some admin
um created those rules or this is
preferences
and it's there but
hidden from the user
visible to the admin
that's just about the state right now
for grouper preferences can you go to
the next site
yeah so
um
recently we did a project or we
currently do it do it
where a vendor wants to expose certain
settings
um
for a big migration
and here they wanna wanna expose
allow lists and block lists
for this we defined
a new jmf preferences object
um
yeah just a normal i don't know normal
jmap way that you do this by
having a separate capability
the link is down there with which
contains some documentation on it
and um
we did this because
having a
jammer preferences object
is
or we we we did this for this isp
project because again
we can use jmap jmap
is something we already support
and
it's something that that we can point
others to to easily implement
and
yeah maybe there's also
it also is also beneficial for the whole
ecosystem in general
so
the way we currently did this just to
give you
um
some some example what we did or some
example how you can use jmap
is uh oh no can you go back sorry
um so we did
there's already a kind of preferences
object for example we just
have a generic preferences object in
this case because it's
about allows and block lists
is
a generic kind of thing
and
yeah because it's it was very easy for
our use case right now um
we have a separate capability for this
generic preferences object
that
you know that extends
the the general object
with
settings so for example with the general
preferences object
doesn't have a lot of things
but then the the preferences
allow list or block list
extension gives it
additional
attributes that
yeah that are specific for block lists
and allows and with that you could
extend the whole preferences object with
more and more
preferences depending on
the way it it's implemented in each
system
okay can you go to the next slide
yeah why do we do this um
yeah we want to want to stress the the
usefulness of
jmap for uh
for the data portability use case for
the the migration use case you can use
it in a lot of different contexts uh
contexts
uh it's easy to extend
uh
yeah we are we did this on our own so
we're interested in some feedback some
opinions on it
um
yeah and i think it's also good to to
have
to just to go forward
standardize a bit
what preferences should look like
um to understand them a bit better
because it's it's currently not very
well standardized
and the net the next step is for us is
also like similar to the migration use
case is to have some kind of document
that describes
what preferences are
yeah how you could standardize them but
we're not very confident of
having that as an rfc yet
but yeah that's open for discussion
yeah that's basically it just to share
some experiences to
yeah get some feedback
all right so there are already some
questions or some remarks on that
and sasha could you put on your mask
please
so
my point as i understood this particular
aspect this is largely an implementation
issue for the implementation to get to
know what certain preferences are as one
of your use cases is
adding the block list or a reject list
it's a particular mail server to
at that end to be able to understand
either what isps to use what ip
addresses to accept mail from and things
like that
so why should it be part of the j map
first say rather than being an apple
data that is known to the specific
implementation per se it may store it in
the database it may store it as a
json object it must store whatever for
properties it needs to store and however
way it wants to do it without actually
it being part of a specific
part of the jmap which is an access
protocol between the client and the
servers
this doesn't really need to if
that's what my thinking is that the jmap
server that you are having for example
your fast mail server it may have
certain contract configuration
attributes
which are dependent on how your
implement server is particularly being
implemented rather than being part of a
protocol specification
i mean based on what i understand is the
use case that's what my thought is
okay
so you're saying it's out of scope for
the protocol
but it's still
nice to have like uh
get a deeper understanding and to i
don't know describe what's out there how
it can be done
that's one way of doing it is to do it
there but i think
that my my limited understanding so
excuse me
no
makes sense i also said it's uh
probably more of a best practice
document than
part of the protocol
yeah
yeah i
i mean i i think just talking about the
previous point briefly the
you know jmat is the protocol but this
is still data and it's still something
you want to either synchronize or be
able to you know send from the client so
whatever else so that's kind of the
point of this but as you mentioned
earlier i don't think there's any kind
of
common enough subset that we could
choose to be worth kind of
publishing a standard on the data type
at least i i doubt it um but uh a best
practice document of if you're creating
a preferences
object
this is the kind of things you should
consider that sounds pretty reasonable
to me like we have a bunch of them at
fast mail kind of like the calendar
preferences one um but the actual
data types themselves the specific
properties like that's just going to be
quite service specific i suspect mostly
okay go ahead hans here
hello can you hear me hear me well
yeah yeah
yeah okay great thanks um yeah so um
i i uh
i agree which was said previously so i
think certainly it's the client service
thing because this is something that is
that some uh uis and clients do
manipulate on the server side so it's i
think certainly something that fits into
the you know client server interaction
first of all
regarding the second point neil said
i mean it's true that this is certainly
nothing which is
the same with every system but that we
see several
settings and also allow this blacklist
as a property which multiple systems
support in a similar way and as of now
what we experienced in migration is that
this is a very big problem because
there's always a big word to do the
translation
and having something like you know a
best practice reference within jmap um
would maybe help vendors to adopt a more
standardized solution and thus in the
future
um promotes portability and
interoperability with respect to those
settings that might not apply to each
and every setting but for instance for
this particular one we made as an
example here this could well be if this
needs to be an rc i don't know anyway so
it can also be a document i'm i agree
with that but i i don't i would not rule
out in general that this is something
that
might be helpful to standardize a little
bit
just regarding block list um
in you know as a specific example
i would consider that a separate data
type like each you know
item is um
a block like an email address or a
domain and that's certainly how we model
it um because that makes it any you know
more efficient to add stuff to or to
remove stuff and to you know resync it
to another client if you've added a
you know a blocked address on one client
and you want to resync another one
rather than being just like a whole blob
in your preferences object
uh maybe what
can i answer it's okay oh
are you finished
sorry
i didn't want to interrupt you sorry
i think what we can agree upon are
concluded at this point is um it might
might make sense maybe it might make
sense to um
work out some more of these settings and
discuss about them in in more detail at
a later session maybe and see if there
is some common ground for that or not
actually i wouldn't go too much into the
detail here for that particular
discussion yeah because that was not the
intent
but um i see there might be a good that
might be a good opportunity at a later
session to think about more deeply and
maybe we come with more examples which
systems use using which fashion
also gives the time right now
but thanks for the feedback
yeah
i also say thank you for the feedback
and thank you for listening
all right thank you
i think that is we're now at the point
of uh milestones or any other business
for the german working group
what's that do you think oh yeah that's
extra so i think that might be it for
jmap any other business for jmap before
we move on to milestones
all right here are our existing gem
milestones
um
i figure we may as well just edit them
directly here
rather than
putting it in the notes and having to
move it otherwise so starting with blobs
we're obviously moving that along to
august given that i need to
update the draft and send it off to my
co-chair for working group last call
and then we will hopefully submit this
finally
in august
uh submit civ document i think we agreed
likewise it will basically be ready to
go
straight after this
there we go august
jmap calendars is certainly going to be
later
so i think we should probably punt that
to
do we think we'll get tasks done i guess
by
next ietf would be the question there
because that will if we're going to
cluster this together
um is it on
yeah i don't i don't think the next one
is already it will be finished by then
maybe the afternoon
um
it's and regarding tasks it's not not
even on the milestone list yet yeah no
we'll we'll create one for that in a
second okay um
here i'm just putting each club together
let's see if it's ready and we don't
think it's going to be a problem we can
publish it but
that's him yeah i guess
i'll just move it to december for now
then
yeah
uh quotas we think is basically ready to
go so that will be
august as well
s my sender extensions
october
uh gem up address books we're not we've
got that ready to be adopted in november
so
that was four thousand
months calendars is probably done
and js contact
js contact's the biggest hold up on that
robert wins do you think they'll be
finished
we want to publish cs contact before or
the latest at next itf
yeah so adjusting it next year
yeah
cool
all right um so let's add some more
milestones
we say
submit js
general tasks
document asg and we said that is
probably going to be
early next year
well if
if addresses are ready before
if addresses are ready before um we
don't necessarily have to wait for the
next ietf to do the call for adoption we
can do that on the list so let us know
yeah
it's nice when it happens
all right so tasks i've got one ready
for that to go in there
what else did we have
that we had said so sharing that we
don't have
a milestone for sharing i'll create a
separate milestone for that
um
and i don't think we had a milestone
well yeah we've got sev
we've got tasks we've got blob we've got
quotas that might be it then
um and this other work is going to be
do we want a milestone for
the migration and portability dock or we
just do a call for adoption and then add
a milestone for it if at that point
yeah i think we let's do a call for
adoption first and then cool
all right so
sg and so to the gmap sharing document
as well and that will put in december
along with calendars
so we've got
two changed four change dates
two additional milestones
done there we go
uh
for this it is murray
all right uh jm milestones completed
thank you everybody that's the end of
the jmap section of this meeting and
we'll move on to the extra section
thanks jim
i'll unshare my screen
go back to the agenda slides
so this is our current agenda for the
extra section of this meeting
any agenda bashing before we move
straight on
you've already been noteworld keep
noting it
alexi
i've got you first i'm at partial i
think i gave you more time than you need
yes i rejected doing slides because
there is nothing new to report i think
you said it it will be sent to like to
working through plus call
yeah so sharing oh sorry i'm at partial
i will send to working group last call
straight away straight after this
meeting sounds good
does anyone have any objections comments
etc before we move on anything you want
to talk about for imac partial
it's the fastest 10 minutes in existence
thanks alexi
next on this list
process i'm it ken
not much to say on this one
um
it's in production at fast mail seems to
do
do the job
um i'm not sure how many people have
actually read it but
maybe working last call would get some
reviews
unfortunately with the passing of ned
freed we've lost one of our
big civ reviewers so we need to pick up
the slack
should you snooze at the same time
sure pretty much the same story with
snooze again
in production works
i think we've had a couple reviews on it
but as far as i'm
concerned it's fully baked and ready to
go to the last call
dale
yeah just um on the process i'm at draft
i read that um
it refers to a calendar id but there's
no
information at all about what the scope
of that is or where when we're getting
calendar id or what a calendar id is
i mean i know what we use for calendar
id but i'm saying from the draft i would
have absolutely no idea of
what this calendar id is i'm trying to
get and where to get it
yeah it's uh it's a good point it's kind
of
outside the scope though because it's
maybe but like
you need something i felt like
yeah okay
thanks jim that's fine all right i'll uh
i'll add some text to that
and uh then perhaps we go to last call
thank you
so it's uh
updated draft and then work and grip
last call
cool and for snooze did anyone have
anything to add for snooze otherwise
we'll send that to working group last
call as well
excellent
uh next on our agenda
where is our agenda just a quick comment
i mean
it looks like we're going to have like
four documents ready for last call
almost simultaneously
[Music]
i think they all should go into last
call but if you can stagger them so
there is no more than two documents at a
time ideally
or at least you know
give them an extra week you know to
start or something
yeah this is this is barry i i would say
give them extra time but put them all
out at the same time don't artificially
spread them out just give us more time
to get them done
what
yes
thankfully they're all fairly short
documents
so
that will help a
bit all right
back to the agenda
uh civ registry was the other thing that
we had
on this list alexi
i think save register is ready as well
right
i'm looking at ken who is my
creditor now
at least we couldn't think of anything
that was missing so at this point i
think we need reviews
all right i guess that's another
document for work group last call
and in a way i mean this one is slightly
weird because it's more mechanical
so if somebody can try to double check
the data
but uh
this is kenny i
i think we've covered everything uh and
just as a
point of reference
i added
in this in this news draft
i added an entry for the registry so
presumably they will either go together
or the registry goes first and then
snooze follows
cool
awesome all right we're on to the new
work so rick
see if i remember what's on my slides
okay yeah so this is uh snoozing the
imap i think uh
the idea of this feature is probably
well understood at this point uh
especially since ken was talking about
sieve
via
uh
the snooze via sieve this is if you got
a message in a mailbox and you want to
hide it away until some future time it's
present in a bunch of clients and just a
few servers next slide
so
what you see in servers and clients
implement this is you take a message and
you say i don't want to think about this
message for some period of time the
message vanishes from your view unless
you go looking for it and when that time
expires the message comes back
and i've seen this implemented in
half a dozen clients in two or three
major servers
next
so this is a basic proposed command this
command is built on top of the jmap
semantics for snooze uh which i realized
today we have never brought up but they
are implemented by fast mail
the idea is this you take a message and
you snooze it which moves the message
using move semantics into a snooze
mailbox this is a new special use
mailbox
when the message is there it's picked up
three new data items on the message and
those are the awaken to awaken flags and
awaken at
this tells you when the message stops
snoozing where will it be put how will
its flags change and when does that
happen
if you snooze it uh from any mailbox
other than snoozed it will awaken to
wherever you snooze it from and if you
snooze it from snooze you just leave it
awakening to the same place
this is
these are broad strokes of how i think
we can implement this based on what
we're already doing at fast mail what
i've seen other places but i think if we
have significant feedback on how other
people need or want this to work that's
that's why we're bringing this up next
slide
right i've covered this this is what we
do with it uh if you can't unsnooze it
to the uh predefined mailbox it goes to
inbox but hopefully that never happens
next
we also uh
yeah
cover that too yeah well okay so one
thing i'll throw in here we use flags
i'll talk about why uh when we snooze
and unsnooze these messages you just get
a list of flag changes to make when it
wakes up
this is uh
this is supposed to talk about unsnooze
i believe i think i've got some typo on
my slide here
when you unsnooze a message right you're
saying cancel the snooze i'm ready to
deal with it early what do we want to do
with the awaken flags
the semantics i put in here are we clear
them we don't add the ad flags we don't
remove the remove flags
we'll have to see what we actually want
on this next slide
the snoozed mailbox is uh it's read-only
you can't put mail in it except via
snooze you can't remove mail from it
except via unsnooze and we create it as
needed
this is not the same design we see in
every implementation there are
implementations that leave the message
in the current mailbox and we'll flag
the message with the flag or we'll give
it some other metadata to indicate that
it's been snoozed or implementations
that put the message into the snooze
mailbox to snooze it and to unsnooze it
remove it from the mailbox but if you're
using move to implement snoozing
you're losing the ability to enforce
that the metadata has been set correctly
which is why we're proposing a separate
verb rick we have some people in the
queue do you want to take them now right
now yes thanks i can't see them on the
screen i'm looking at uh yeah uh neil i
think you're up first cool
um yeah
so it didn't look like you currently
have any way of specifying the folder to
return to other than
like implicitly it's like wherever i
snoozed it from
um
we
actually do use both because in labels
mode it always snoozes um
from the inbox and returns back to the
inbox
regardless of where you choose from
that'd be great now you want to add that
here too
yeah we can add that the reason it's not
there is this started as what's the
simplest version of this we could expose
privately and as we bring it to this
room it's
what could everybody else possibly want
i'll stick that in the in the notes
i think the default you know it should
be optional if you don't split back to
the mailbox it came from makes perfect
sense
phillip yeah phil handbaker yeah uh have
you considered the interaction of this
with tasks and when i'm
when i'm using this sort of
functionality
it's really because i want to create a
task for myself later on
and
my client doesn't support that so it
might be worth thinking about the two
together
uh
yeah i mean i think the answer i can
give you on that uh thinking about this
and with respect to tasks is as a as a
individual human i have daydreamed about
how i would use that but we haven't done
any serious protocol discussion of it
and uh we can bring that up on the list
how we might do something
um yeah uh thanks rick that's
interesting but i have couple of
questions i'm not sure if some of them
might be answered in following slides so
interrupt me maybe if i'm asking
something stupid which you will explain
anyway so a very minor question is so
how does it interact with a recent flag
so because you know clients use that
already as a kind of you know to denote
uh
some message that's fresh on the server
will this reactivate reason until
unsnoozed or not
um
then what's not quite clear for me is
the client is who is doing this news
interaction so i understand that somehow
the server implements that snooze
mechanism the moving out of the smooth
states
when the date has been passed and so on
but it's actually the clients that need
to be
taking action i guess so i wonder a
little bit how that kind of it's how it
ensured that once the server moves the
message back in the unsmooth states
you know what is the client's respect
expected to do
and third question if you can still take
one is you say it's not allowed to
append messages to that news mailbox so
i wonder about what is about migration
here so if we migrate a mailbox which
has this feature we might need to
migrate messages which are the smooth
state
into a new destination system so this
would require append actually properly
okay first let me apologize the audio
quality in here is not perfect i may
have missed some of your question um as
regards to what is the client expected
to do
this does come up a bit later but the
short answer is the client is simply
expected to show the user that the
message has returned to its previous
state uh so this means number one the
message is back in its awakened to
mailbox and number two uh what we do at
fast mail with the flags is we use a
flag to indicate that a message it has
entered that mailbox by awakening from
snooze and then it uh it will display
differently i think a convention on that
would be useful but not necessary
i do think it's important to talk about
this being
a server function to awaken the message
because you would like your message to
awaken no matter whether no matter which
client you are using and you don't you
don't want your mail client to have to
awaken it if you're using a not snooze
capable client to read your mail when
you snooze it from one that can
um as for migration i don't
it's not a question i've thought about i
don't have a great answer i think the
simple one is you would migrate the
message to its awakening target and
snooze it then uh it would get the job
done even though it's a little silly
okay uh
barry
hi this is barry liba um
so i i haven't read the draft yet so
this is a question there's no draft
there's only slides okay oh okay
um
the question is about uh the use of the
special use mailbox the the user may not
move mail out of this mailbox
that's
as far as i can remember unique at this
point the special use mailboxes are like
every other mailbox except they're used
for certain other things
we don't have a case where you're not
allowed to put something in there with a
move command or a copy command or you're
not allowed to take it out with a move
or a copy command and that sort of thing
how are you planning to write this up is
that uh going to be a requirement
because i think some servers do not have
that capability in them yet that there
are mailboxes that you can't put things
into or take out of i think we have two
options um
one is to one is to eliminate the
requirement and instead to say that if
the message is moved in is that the
message is moved in there's some default
behavior which i'm not sure what it
would be and if the message is moved out
it is implicitly awoken
another option i i think in my imap
might be too poor to uh to be correct
here
is that we could require that apple
support is present and that this mailbox
must have access control that restricts
you from adding to it but i yeah i see a
thumb down yeah i i like the first one
better of that yes
but alexa is coming to respond to
this um i actually i'm not going to
fight you on this i agree with you um
magic mailboxes ideally not a good idea
so
um
and
so the other side of uh another thing i
wanted to say is
not yet fully sold on the new command
but i think it basically
we need to review
all extensions that affect
uag copy and uid move
yeah to make sure that this is handled
in exactly the same way yeah or you know
you know
module of the differences obviously so
that it kind of uh
um
i know it's more like if we can manage
that it's a to-do item we need to do
yeah but yeah
um i suspect from the reaction
from you know people in the room and
remote that
there is enough interest in this
pete resnick um so as you were
describing this
i thought what's the use of the
snooze mailbox in the first place
i understand implementation wise why
that makes it easier because now you've
got all the messages that you have to
deal with later
in one place and then you can do the
trigger off that but that seems
arbitrary
why would
why wouldn't i be able to say
snooze this set of actions on this
message wherever it may live which may
involve a move which may involve a flag
change which may involve any other
number of things like
for instance you know
cue it over to this other process
um
the move mailbox
seems like it could be removed from this
and and you could still implement it
that way
but
it seems like you could just do this as
a much more generic
protocol proposal and then leave to the
implementation whether they use a snooze
mailbox or whether they have a list of
messages you know that are waiting to be
snoozed
seems perfectly good so to make sure i
understand you pete i think what you're
suggesting is something like a defer
command where you would say here's an
action to take at some future time and
to implement exactly this you would move
the message to snooze and defer its
removal from snooze that's right yeah
and
then it's a normal mailbox um you know
you may in your ui say no can't move
anything into snooze
um that's fine
but
your ui is dealing with the idea of the
snooze mailbox and for all i care that
could be a flag not a mailbox
and in many implementations probably
would be sure so just remove the whole
idea of the mailbox and just make it a
defer command or a snooze command
whatever you like
and if it gets expunged then that goes
away so a uid move will
will wipe the old thing and the defer is
lost automatically yeah
yeah thanks yeah i will actually second
beat
on this uh it's probably implementable
with flags you you still need to store
extra metadata because you want to
substitute flags at a later date
but you can do it in place by just
defining and you keep you know one or
two more extra keywords saying this is
snoozed so basically clients when they
scan for mailbox they will just
don't show it or something i don't know
we have quite a long queue here at the
moment are all these people still
waiting in the cure have you just not
removed yourself yet
all right just yeah pop up when you're
when you're ready to talk i think it's
all good yeah so yeah
this is actually i think my what i was
pointing out for has actually been by
alex and p was about that instead of
doing the
concept of the mailbox per se we should
actually use the flags things and then
let the client decide whether they want
to implement it as a mailbox thing or
they just want to put tags or flags and
work on it that way and that way all
your flags that information for the
snooze flag would be awakened too and
all of that may come up there yeah
it was short
uh this is ken so um based on pete's
feedback
i'd like pete to review the sifs news
draft
which has similar
has similar language so
you may have an issue with that too and
i'm more than happy to change text
yeah this the civs news i mean i that's
that would be great the civ snooze draft
is much less prescriptive about what
happens with the message in the interim
so it'd be good to get looked at
yeah this is pete again and i'm glad to
review it i i have no dog in this fight
i i you know uh however you guys want to
implement this this seems like a cool
feature and and that's fine
um
just architecturally it seems like an
easier thing to
make it much more generic
so yeah i i took a quick glance through
the the
document because this came up and i
thought okay well yeah same ideas
so i i disagree about making it more
generic i think that
kind of
the point of this is
it's two things it's there's a common
paradigm that's implemented in a whole
bunch of places and they pretty much all
work the same way and so trying to
support like extra cases beyond that
makes it less likely this will be
implemented because
like for example you know if it's you
can arbitrarily do some defer command
later there's a good chance
most people won't implement that because
that's not what they're back in sports
they're back in audi sports snooze
and it's pretty they're all pretty
similar
so i think that's a downside to trying
to make it more generic um
uh
and
yeah i actually think that makes it more
complicated and i've lost whatever other
thought i had on this right now so stop
that
yeah that's uh
for the record that's my tentative
feeling also i i
defer sounds very neat and i think i
want to think about it and write about
it more but it it feels to inch a bit
towards all things to all people uh
which is
the very dangerous in a lot of designs
yeah yeah
other things so i'll just get really bit
um
it was someone mentioned oh and then the
clients could you know implement this
however they want it with the server but
that loses the point which is that this
is synchronized to the clients and they
can all provide a consistent view which
again is a reason to make it less
generic so that you're more likely to
see something consistent if you use
different clients
so this is pete again and
neil used the magic words that send my
hackles up which is because that's the
way the backing does it and this has
been the disaster of imap from the
get-go
is that you know when mark designed it
it was because that's the way his file
system worked
and that's what screwed over a lot of
clients because they didn't
deal with the world that way
and you end up with that semantic
you know ugliness between client and
server because then the client has to
figure out what the backing looked like
and if you make the the
and and generic may be the wrong word
it's that you want to take the essential
bits of this
irrelevant of what the server is
actually doing in the background and say
what can the server implement here
if the way you do this is move them to a
special mailbox
well that's one way to do it but i you
know i can imagine a zillion different
ways that a server might do this
depending on its backing
and
this would make life harder for certain
servers yeah
yeah i
i think so brian i think has been
waiting in queue for quite a while uh
sorry yeah no i popped myself in the
queue here to actually ask a more
general question which says yes we've
got this in civ
we've got this here in imap presumably
we also want to publish a jmap
version of it
do we want to do all these together and
then i guess the question is going to
come up for our area directors at some
point are we going to try and
as more things happen in both gmap and
extra in parallel what do we want to do
there but maybe this maybe it's not time
to do that this time maybe we'll wait
till
we have more area directors in art again
uh to respond really briefly to to pete
i think that something neil said that is
also relevant is
putting putting aside what the back end
server does if what we want
is for different clients
to be able to interpret the semantics of
what the server plans to do then
indicating it as this message is snoozed
until such time is easier to interpret
than
client a has indicated this message
should be
moved moved or unflagged at some future
time and client b must understand that's
the common parlance for snooze so being
able to apply a name i think has a lot
of value to it uh regardless of the back
end semantics
uh alexi
um yeah
sorry
i think i jumped in just before lexi in
the queue again i was just going to
reply
my approach is not from this is what how
back-ends have implemented it my
approach was this is how it works as a
product in various different services
it's it's you know from a user's point
of view um there's quite a lot of
consistency
um
i think there are basically two general
ways of doing this one is you know extra
imap keywords
that let the clients hide it from the
view or the server you know you know
hide it from you or whatever or there is
a magic mailbox right
well somewhat magic we're discussing
what extent ml box yes
um
i suggest maybe
once the draft is written we'll discuss
the you know the two approaches and
maybe settle on one you know i suggest
well
i suspect we're probably not going to
solve it in this room
i also suggest that chairs probably
should have a limit on how long we will
discuss and then we'll just pick one
approach along this
um
there are benefits to one another and
there are well advantages and
disadvantages to both of them so um
yeah all right
just it has to be a mailbox because
otherwise it will only work in clients
that have explicitly added support for
it whereas when it
if it's a keyword
uh look like you're just not gonna do
anything in other clients if it's a
mailbox they will sync the stuff and it
will have moved out of the inbox it will
move back into the appropriate time they
don't have to know anything about it so
it can't be a keyword has to be in the
mailbox
this is still a server functionality so
server can still hide it from the viewer
actually
so i mean there are there are variations
on you know yes it might be magic
keyboards that hide it from you know
tell the server not to show it until
later on
we can talk about yeah yeah let's take
it i mean i think i think there are
strong reasons i'd argue for one way or
the other but let's take it to the list
because i think we've taken a lot of
time my question is based off on what
pete said
uh about the
backing store and the implementation
being true
so this is very basically a concept of
what really is a mailbox in the mail
dire world or the mbox world it's a file
it's a file that recites a particular
place but if you take this whole concept
into a database sort of a bad thing then
it becomes basically
some table or something in a database
hierarchy so me so what i'm going to say
is a mailbox as a concept
versus a mailbox as a particular place
or something so a mailbox has a concept
that is implemented using tags or
mailbox that is a concept that is
implemented using a directory i think we
might need to just think a slightly more
into how it may actually happen in the
real world and excuse me if i'm speaking
something which you guys already know
because i'm very very new in this area
thank you
i think we've reached the end of the
queue
okay
let's take a next slide i think i'll try
and i think that's about it just about
uh
yeah okay there's one two more things
one is uh it's worth noting that what
fast mail does and its implementation is
we have a conventional flag that is used
to indicate a message recently awoke
that lets you see the message isn't just
back in your mailbox you didn't forget
that you ever snoozed it it is you can
see this has been deferred i think a
suggestion and a registered uh common
flag for that would be useful or
we've taken a got a bit off the rails on
exactly what happens but this function
is useful similarly the save date
extension is useful here because you can
see when the message returned to the
mailbox if in fact it has left and
returned to the mailbox as part of being
snoozed and awoken
next i think that's the last slide on
snooze
yeah but let's talk about the sieve one
well we'll do that next
okay uh
shall we move on to the next topic yeah
i think so i i like to think uh this one
is simpler but let's see uh it does call
into question what is a mailbox so
um right so a number of uh
implementations now
uh client implementations let you
visualize well they let you see mail
with labels stuck on it implemented in
one of several ways sometimes it is
using uh user flags sometimes you're
putting the message in multiple
mailboxes
gmap uh is to some extent built around
the idea that you will put an email in
multiple mailboxes and these can be
treated like labels and because you
truck with emails in terms of a single
email in multiple emails no special work
is required but if we want to expose
this in imap for clients that would like
to show the various mailboxes in which a
message appears which is to say the
various labels on the mailbox we need to
do some work
next
so uh if we want to implement
what i will call labels mode today um
you need the server to implement object
id because we're going to want to map
from emails found in a mailbox to the
mailboxes in which they are found
and then to do that mapping we're adding
a data item to the messages called
mailbox ids
mailbox ids is a list of the object ids
of the mailboxes in which this email
appears and the email here is as per the
object id capability it's it's any
message with the same email id which i
believe is defined as the same uid
validity uid and it's all the all the
non-changeable content of the message
between mailboxes every mailbox that
appears in when you fetch its mailbox
ids you will be told what the mailboxes
are you can't change this property it's
computed for you when you copy move
delete whatever else these messages
that's how you change the mailbox ids
next
the complication we've been talking
about internally and i'm sure there will
be many complications
is that
if you have this computed property on a
message in mailbox 1
and that message is also found in
mailbox 2 but you delete it from mailbox
2 you'd like the mod seek in mailbox 1
to be updated because its mailbox ids
property has been updated through action
at a distance
this is going to be either
complicated or not depending on your
implementation unfortunately it's a
little complicated for our
implementation uh your mileage may vary
next
uh yep if you want to set the mailbox
ids or the labels on a message you just
move it around it's all it should all be
able to work implicitly
uh one thing that does come up is this
leads us to want a
uh the ability to copy a message into a
mailbox only if it does not already
exist by email id this should probably
be spun off into a separate conversation
so i don't want to get too far into it
but you can imagine that if you have a
message and you say you want to add a
label which has already been added you
don't want to copy that message and have
two versions of that message with
distinct uids but the same email id in
one mailbox you're going to have a bad
time
next
that could possibly be done with uh mod
seek checks but i can't remember whether
copy and move allow you to test mod seek
store certainly does
yeah i don't know yeah
yeah great
much more prosaic concern any client
that's any good that allows you to use
labels allows you to color the labels
and we'd like to allow that for labels
mode of imap so this is registering a
piece of metadata for the mailbox where
we store the color define the way we do
everything these days as a css3 named
color or rgb code
the thing that's a bit more complicated
is that then we need to be able to get
the metadata efficiently when we select
the mail when we list the mailboxes over
imap i believe brian you're going to be
talking about that in a minute so i
won't uh but if you can't get the
metadata in the list and that's where
we've put the color you're going to have
to select every mailbox to display the
labels efficiently and that's no good
next
you've got to let me yeah sure
ah
that's a pain
okay there we go
was that it might be the last slide
there was no next there you go so uh
those changes are uh
in concept straightforward but i think
they led us to efficiently bootstrap an
imap client to display multi-mailbox uh
labels with
with color and to keep it in sync
efficiently
depending on the implementation uh we
have one person in queue sir
just thinking about this color thing is
what
makes the jmap preferences object
actually become part of the protocol in
this particular use case as i understand
because we're talking about
thunderbird on one machine on my linux
box and the thunderbird on the windows
box basically i want to have the same
interface and the best place to keep
that information is in the server so
that's where we could put something like
a preferences object
preferences for the mailbox and the
preferences object per se could be
actually opaque in terms of whatever
information you put it that may be a
part of a client specific if you can
have something like yeah so so some
place like but basically just an object
store for at the server level to store
some information that the server like
outlook does it with across they have
this whole concept now of outlook in the
cloud where you can actually store your
preferences yeah i think it's absolutely
it's absolutely plausible to talk about
jmap being useful as a sort of a generic
key value store for well-known
properties but on the other hand
um being able to say there's one
specific property which is color which
we apply to the mailbox uh gets rid of a
lot of complexity and thinking about
what else people will use a generic key
value store for fastmel's already got an
extension for the color property on
mailboxes we already implement it in
terms of metadata on the mailbox and
it's dead simple i think that's the
least complicated part of this whole
suggestion
uh that's the end of queue if there's
nothing else i will thank you and sit
down
thank you cool
i just need to pop my slides up here
because i realize i didn't upload them
yet but that will take me 10 seconds and
then i will show you very quickly the
metadata slides
upload
nobody saw that
yep
second 10 seconds don't zoom in on me
while i'm shoving my finger up at people
thanks remote person okay
slides unshare reshare
there we go
uh list return metadata this is for
anyone who's seen list return my rights
this will look very familiar to you
um it it's very similar basically you
say well you're giving me a list for
each mailbox call get metadata on that
mailbox with the following properties
and it looks like this
is that readable at that size maybe not
thanks
we we have plenty of time for that
um
i should have you i should have removed
some more things from it anyway as you
can see here if you say list return and
you say metadata and you give a list of
the metadata items you would like it to
return
after each list it then returns the get
metadata response as you can see looks
absolutely identical between
the trash line
there and the get metadata on the same
trash with the same properties
and it just says here's
the value of these things so it's very
simple
and it allows you to do a full listing
on the server and get the metadata at
the same time this is implemented in
cyrus imap has been for very many years
i can't remember whether i added an x
capability for it or not probably not um
but it would be very easy to do
so i will write a draft and ask my
co-chair to do a call for adoption on
this
and it should be pretty trivial i
imagine
any comments
this is candice one comment so this is
really the only way to get all the
information as rick was saying in one go
since
when get metadata was changed from
[Music]
annotate more i think
we removed the ability to wild card the
list of mailboxes that you want to fetch
that item on so unless we put that back
in the wild carding back in i think this
is probably the most efficient way to do
this and we already have
a handful of return options anyway so
adding this one makes sense to me
cool
in that case i think we're at the point
where we need to look at our milestones
unless there's any other business for
the extra working group
i don't see any people jumping up
let's have a look at our milestones
here we go we have adopt a document for
ai with sieve
and we have submit said document
so isg
let's have a look at
what we're going to do about that i
guess is there an option in the dates
that you can say when hell freezes over
probably not
um
yeah has anyone
even started thinking about this yet
oh there is okay yes
i'm gonna sit down
um
i think somebody from open exchange is
it was it stefan bosch he actually wrote
something
uh the difficulty is the last time ned
had a look at it and he said oh that
needs quite a bit of work
so there is a document obviously we're
not ready and not anywhere near done
with it but
um
[Music]
okay
well i do wonder whether we can just
kind of start adoption call well ask
stefan to refresh it and say
we'll adopt it you know but if obviously
you know no guarantee that it
get done i suppose but
um
i would rather adopt it and work it in
the working group even if we run out of
steam at some point and decide it's not
tractable i will
okay thank you
and
the december date is obviously yes that
one is
i'm achievable i might kick that one
down the road a bit okay
uh this is barry if he's not
willing to continue with it i'm happy to
take it over
but yeah regardless of what state it's
in i think we should just adopt it and
go from there
okay i will request a call for adoption
august will bump the delivery date out
into
next year
mid next year
we can do other things for that okay
extra milestones
uh submit what do we want to submit here
we've got a bunch of documents don't we
that we have agreed are going to go i'm
at partial process imip
snooze sounds like we may be delaying
that a little bit just because we're um
all the snow stuff will
will happen um
but sieve registry
oh yeah yeah
we're not planning to take all the
things that are ready for working group
last call and make milestones for them
right
i was going to yeah there's no need for
that i can say it's done all right fine
just we just have them ready just put
them out for last call and and go for it
we don't need milestones for them all
right so but i will put in um
adopt
a
list return
metadata draft
for august
adopt a
snooze
map
draft
or maybe september that one might have a
bit more faffing before we're ready to
adopt
anything else we need is milestones for
extra at the moment
no
my boxes as labels i think we need to
discuss but you know we can discuss on
the main list jsp meeting anyway so cool
um yeah
all right do we have any other business
in our last eight minutes
thanks everybody
look at that we've pretty much landed on
time good work
enjoy the rest of your isf
yeah yeah
i'm just wondering the google gmail has
these x labels right they use that in
lieu of the mailbox labels is that the
similar thing that you're talking about
yes it works very similarly but it uses
labels rather than well it uses the
names of the mailboxes rather than the
ids right so what google did was it it
added its own things with the x dash tag
while the my map basic thing has the
labels it but it seems outlook there's
exchange does not really sometime back
when i checked it wasn't a
supporting some sort of labels i'm i'm
just that's one of the issues the
implementation issue that
wow
all right cool
i will unshare my screen
all right thanks everybody
is
um