okay
now it's what it works
so welcome everybody to the lisp session
working group meeting
uh we have a one hour meeting
the usual note well which you are
supposed to have read it
during your registration
procedure
i know you are familiar with every
single line of this not well
few tips for if you are in the room you
join the mitiko with the local uh
uh tool okay
uh so that
in this way you can sign the blue sheets
also
okay right you can arise your hand if
you want to go to the mic uh okay
and
wear a mask
unless you you are at the mic and you
are speaking sometimes is better that
way otherwise for people that are in
remote the usual procedure with mitiga
in remote
okay
this is a
slide that we have already the last time
i think it's important the code of
conduct also
i keep it
are expected to
to treat each other with courtesy which
means also to to wear a mask because
it's protecting each other okay
we have technical discussions here not
personal discussions
okay
the the the the goal is to advance
technically the internet and nothing
else okay
be ready to contribute so
usual uh links so i'm luigi here beside
me is joel we are the coaches
padma
i don't know if she's online
yeah if somebody can help with the
minutes that would be very helpful you
have even linked
um
if you go to the agenda uh the main
agenda you have directly the link that
brings you to the
um eater part the equivalent of
just it it you want to edit it it'll ask
you to re-log in but once you've done
that you can just edit it
anybody else can help you but please
appreciate if somebody's taking points
good
for note takers that's the length you
want
and then you have to click on the pencil
icon to switch from just viewing it to
being in edit mode then it'll ask you to
log in again
just
that's it
okay
um
a quick update on the status so
um we are progressing in the last
two months that there was quite some
some work to do we have eight documents
now in the rfc editor queue
which is good news so the beast
documents basically are through
lisptec
okay that
was quite some discussions
on that one
but yeah we
we seem to to to to ready to actually
also unblock some old documents like the
the introduction document which is
stuck in the queue for uh i don't know
how long uh
anymore but now with the
the the beast document going through we
should be good
is there any uh
means you're almost done
what you've got what you've got in front
of you is when they get to it the rf rpc
the production center will do their job
when they are done they will send to you
an email that says auth48 here's what we
did to your document
please review and approve there is a
list of questions please answer them
do so promptly please
i've had authors in other contexts
that they are work by the editors but
they they have occasionally noticed wait
you said x here and why there what did
you mean
so it's mostly editorial but they're
very sharp and they they occasionally
spot other things
that's why answer the questions is
important and
god we've spent long enough on this
luigi has done more work i mean my
thanks to luigi he's done a tremendous
amount of work
so
the uh they ask is authors when we hit
off 48
please be responsive and looks like the
ad wants to chime in to add to that
you gotta find the on switch it's up on
the side of the microphone
and you gotta slide it all the way up
so hard to say something
uh
no i forgot what i was going to say
oh the documents
um
keep in mind that
we requested expedited processing for
the whole cluster
because at the request of um i
ko right
and there was no way to request
processing for just two so for the whole
cluster all seven or eight documents
so what that means is that please as
joel said
reply to the auth 48 ideally in 48 hours
i think that's what that's supposed to
mean
uh so that we can get these documents
out because all of them are
probably going to come out together in
one block
and so we need them to to get out so we
can
uh meet what uh iko wants us to do
so between luigi um
[Music]
to tell the rpc don't worry about
certain authors
who've drifted away but we'll we can
deal with that
[Music]
don't celebrate until it's published
because you'll actually get the rp
you'll actually know what the rfc number
is
before it's published yeah sure because
you'll see it in the auth 48
yes good plan
uh
we have another couple of documents that
they they passed the working group last
call um
we're working on that
okay the there is the
young model i think it was uh already
mentioned in the last time we
we should pay attention to data moving
it forward i think is
ready or
or really close to it
okay and then we have a bunch of
documents for which
um
we need to to to focus on them now that
the these documents are over or almost
over okay
that's the next next uh task i would say
uh the agenda for today we have first
the least reliable transport okay mark
uh we will
present that and then we have dino with
the satellite networks and distinguished
name encoding
unless there is any comment on the
agenda
i guess we can move
over okay
so mark
[Music]
should i run the slides for you yes yeah
okay so
um we just wanted to provide an update
on the reliable transfer draft now that
it's a working group document
i'm mark i'm presenting on behalf of
list of authors
next like this
so in terms of updates what we've done
is uh yeah we've been integrating all
the changes that we've been discussing
during the last meetings in this
document
in particular what we are doing what
we've done is
is provide further details on how do we
do the transition from udp to reliable
transport
then
also the draft now incorporates the
reliable transport bit
that
drives the understanding between the etr
and the web server that when when to use
a reliable transport
and now the document includes quick as
an alternative protocol to to use
for reliable transport and discusses a
little bit how to select the protocol
when you have multiple options
and i reserved the last part of the last
slide that you'll see for portal
locations uh all the discussion that we
had in the mailing list
let's see now next slide please
so from udp to reliable transfer uh
the the idea of that the draft defense
it's always you must always first
register with you lease udp uh once uh
successful udp registration has happened
and that's the only time that you can
switch to reliable transfer
so what we've done in address is clarify
how this works right um
in particular and
there is this concept of
as a security measure the the map server
should never accept any reliable
transport session
it should not even open the possibility
until at least
one etr has
registered with udv and has expressed
the intent to switch to reliable
transport
once an etr expresses the intent to
switch to reliable transfer that that's
the time when the map server will
put
this etr login in a
in an acceptance list and that's what
the only time that
from that moment on it will start
accepting connections from from the ctr
and
the other thing that the draft specifies
is whenever the session goes down
an etr should always switch back to udp
before attempting reliable transport
again
next slide
the second thing that the draft
documents is the
future technology speaking as
me so there's no grace where we start
uh no
yeah
yeah the idea was
to keep things a bit simpler
just to always go back you know to
whenever possible right just just
because i mean you're already
authenticated
and
um
well i don't know
no no i'll go read the first a little
bit better and ask later
no no that's a good point um
the draft now doesn't consider it but um
yeah it's a good idea to tonight the
problem is that you don't know
whether you have lost the state when
when whenever there is a problem with a
reliable transport uh
so the the simpler way that we found was
to just go back right and restart from
scratch
just real quick this is dino i didn't
understand the question so i don't know
what you're answering oh no
so the question was um he said that if
the tc position goes down
then you have to go back and
authenticate again
via udp no you're constantly setting
that registers yeah
the authentication data is in the map
register so it's a periodic
re-authentication so it's not discussion
based
maybe at the mic okay so uh okay yeah
right make sense
so
if you just
on the mailing list if you could just
say what what you mean what you're
thinking about graceful restart then
we'll understand specifically what
you're talking about
okay so
the other thing that i've now
incorporated is the reliable transfer
bit
this bit is just used
so that the etr doesn't need doesn't
need to guess whether a map server can
accept a reliable transfer establishment
or not
so the the idea is in the map register
we set this bit whenever an etr
so that the atr can express intent to
establish a reliable transport uh next
slide
and then the maps the map server in the
notified and said the corresponding
leads just to
tell back the edr okay now you can go
ahead and try to establish a reliable
transfer with me
next slide
okay so what the working group document
now incorporates is the list of
protocols that can be used to establish
the
reliable transfer then as part of this
list now incorporate quick
to the list as we discussed
in the mailing list um
one important thing that we've
incorporated and it would be good if we
can have a discussion on this but um
first thing is that for all protocols
what the draft specifies is that all the
sessions will be long lived right so
once the session established this is
what
uh there is this understanding that the
state is synchronized between dtr and
on the map server and this is what
simplifies some processes with reliable
transport
but the second part is the one that i'm
interested we are interested in hearing
back is
as of now the draft specifies that quick
and sad will use a single stream right
we know that the protocol
offers the possibility to
to
establish multiple streams between the
etr and the map server
but since we are using this for a very
specific interface and very specific
messages between
etrm observer uh for now the the draft
just reduces
this to single stream
um if you guys have different experience
and and you think we should upgrade to
to specify multiple sims we can always
do that um
okay
this
uh this part of the draw the answers uh
dino had a comment on on
okay now since we have multiple
protocols uh
how do we choose among them and and what
do we do about the
potential delay that can come from the
fact that okay i'm trying one protocol
maybe this protocol fails
next protocol comes
so
the draft now specifies an order but
just as a suggestion let's say
with a may
so if the etr can support the three
protocols this would be the suggested
order
but also
we'll introduce this node saying okay um
since we don't want um
the
information that mapping information to
be delayed while we try to establish the
reliable transport dtr should always
make sure that it's sending complete
mapping information in with udp
while waiting for for the reliable
transport to be established
okay um
observation i mean if we need a reliable
transport
i would choose at least one as
mandatory to be implemented with this
draft i mean otherwise
i mean
just choose one okay my suggestion is
tcp yeah it makes sense so when we have
now reported
that's a good one uh
about the order uh
you can suggest a note that i don't
think there is the need to to mandate an
order in any way because anyway the
choice is limited so okay
but okay another good one um
okay yeah we can make tcp mandatory
um
good
and next one
yeah this is the last one and this is
what we discussed in the mailing list
what happens with the ports now that we
have multiple transports
for dcv is easy we can reuse for 342.
one comment that we have is that
the lease constructs expired so
officially in the ayana page
for 342 is not
reserved anymore
then for quick and sap we will need to
request newport um just one minute or
not uh since we added the ayanna
considerations uh in the draft we got
these mail automated i guess from myanna
specifying a procedure to to request
these ports and they also say that the
closer we get to last call then it's
when when they will act on it
but yeah i mean i i would like to hear
uh based on past experience if
you think we need to do anything else
than this section
so i understand this is dino i
understand that we need a new udp port
for quick
but i thought
maybe you might know alvaro sctp uses
the same port number data points
as tcp and udp so we need an explicit
i don't know what an sctp port is it's
just a port
right
yeah i i i actually i went through the
ctv draft and i saw that they even have
a section specifying how how to request
the new port i mean maybe we can map it
to 4342 also but but as far as i
understood they have their own
registry
they have their own registry of course
well as far as i understood right there
yeah if we know differently
but i'm lazy to go there but
just to make a go
yeah maybe
it's just a matter to find a good
register maybe we cannot use 40c42 or
even for other protocols it's just the
lisp part let's say and then
you have different protocols that are
supported you don't need to have
different
numbers
yeah yeah the only one based on what we
discussed i think for quick we need one
right so so so that we the map server
knows that it's it's not
it's a legacy review
yeah quick maybe more trickier yeah but
but yes for the http i i think forty g42
should work
okay if it's not taken i mean yeah yeah
i can check it out
okay and that was the last slide
any further comments or questions
what no thank you
thanks man
can we do you mind if we do the
distinguished name first
okay
you can advertise this uh
agenda
okay
um i just think it'll be quicker
we have nice chairs
okay i'm going to give an update on the
dash 15 version of name and coding next
slide
okay just to give you an overview of
what it is um we can encode um
what we call distinguished names or just
character strings that can be put in an
eid record or an arlo record of any of
the list messages
um
we use the afi encoding like we do for
afi1 and 2 for ipv4 and ipv6
so it's uh
it's just basically a 2 byte afi 17
value followed by an ascii string that's
null terminated it's pretty
straightforward
and it's useful to provide
self-documenting
the mapping database records uh you
could also use it to group a bunch of
things together so
um
maybe you want to associate all eids on
a train with the name of the train so
you would have you would register to the
mapping system a name called train 154
and then you would have a list of eids
that are currently in the train it might
have some mobility benefits there
there's a lot of other
sorts of things you could do as well the
idea here is that we don't want to break
the semantics of this string with
power of two in addresses so
ddt and lisp decent those two mapping
database systems could support this
so for instance
if you did a look up on slash root slash
dino slash slide slash philly
it could match
slash fruit slash dino at the ddt route
which would be the delegation authority
for that part of the name and then the
children could then support slash slides
or flashlights billy so it looks like
it's more specific just like it would be
with a power of two um
address so rather than it wouldn't have
bit boundaries it could have arbitrary
boundaries just based on um so so the
design of the mapping system would have
to decide
if the slashes were the boundaries
because they could be variable length
um
so map
map requests lookups typically in the
use cases that i've implemented and that
are currently
written in specs do exact match but you
could also um
do partial matches as well
like if i looked up um
slash root slash dino slash
philly and slash philly wasn't
registered but slash shoot slash dino
was
you could get that returned and that
would just be a natural thing that map
sir would do with no changes
next slide
this is example of what i implemented in
my open source code is
this is a registration entry in the map
server
the eid prefix in
instance id
is called g xtr one this is just an xtr
that's sitting in google in a vm
and the arloc the rlok set um is
basically
these guys
the r loop set basically has these two
rtrs because it's going through a nat
but you could also associate a name with
the with an arloc record so it's encoded
in that our loca record this is an
encoding in the eid record this is the
encoding in the arloc record
these are the current um working group
and individual submission
drafts that are using the distinguished
name stuff
so the ecdsa authentication
is using it to store
um the hash value when you want to look
public keys up in the mapping system to
verify signatures
we use it for grouping type stuff in
predictive rloks
and we use it for encoding uh
if you if you use the lcaf
geocoordinates as an eid and you want to
map it to a name like say you have the
geo coordinates of los angeles you may
want it to map to a name which is called
character string los angeles you could
do that sort of thing
the list policy distribution guys are
using there's a lot of policy stuff that
they want to use that are going to
depend on um
on distinguished names and in all these
cases they're describing um how the
structure of the name should be and what
the collision
opportunities or or avoidance is done in
those that was a comment that was done
on the spec overlay simple nat and the
list didn't cast stuff refers to this
draft
so we started the effort the draft was
built in 2016.
there was a lot of quiet period
around here in 2020 there were some
updates and we just made an update now
this past week to reflect make it more
clear how close detection is done if
there's two different use cases using
names and how they don't clash so we
added that to the spec and that was
joel's comment and uh we think we sat
aside the comment right
okay
next
um so we addressed the collision
commentary um that joel had in slash 15.
and i requested
this past weekend to request this as a
working group document i sent that
request to lisbeth ietf.org
and
it's really it's a very small two-page
specs so it doesn't take very much to
read through it so i wanted to try to
request working group last call now but
um
it's up to you guys you really should
request adoption go through
adoption and then turn around and
request you don't even have to repost it
we can mark it as adopted using the
exact same draft and then we can turn
around and last call
and in last call that's when we switch
it to a ietf list
in the proper process and then we'll do
the last call so that
two weeks all of that before london okay
sounds good uh hi alberta wrote anything
i'm happy with the process
please rename it before
sending it to the aud
we've had people complain about the
names before and so just to avoid
complaints okay we'll make sure it gets
interesting
so you wait two weeks and to see if it's
going to should be there
you send a note
we will issue the adoption call next
week okay we give everybody the amount
of time it'll be two weeks actually we
may make it three weeks because it's
august
we'll then say it's adopted please
repost with the right name
you'll repost okay you'll then send an
email saying can we last call this
okay
we'll last call it
two weeks
if there's a problem we'll fix it and if
not
we'll hand it to alvaro and we'll pick
somebody in the working group to
shepherd it
maybe he asked for a review joel did it
already but
addition in the mean in the meantime i
mean when it is adopted
we can also ask for
early review from the
security area and all the radios
transport area etc etc so that we
we
speed up the process a little bit yeah
asking for early reviews doesn't speed
up the process
well you have to have it at some point
so yeah
and also
and they will also ask what our
intention of the spec is is it full
standard proposed standard experimental
all day and i don't know if we're ready
because those other drafts depend on you
only go ps
yeah okay it can only go yes okay okay
but there's no point in learning about
early reviews there's just not going to
be enough weeks in here to waste any
other energy okay we'll just make it go
through the process expeditiously
got it
yeah sharon is on the queue
but wait there was on
um shadow want to ask something
yeah yeah um so you know i think this is
of course a great idea and a way
for people to understand how to solve uh
problems using a routed namespace which
lisp is uniquely qualified to do
but it's hard to explain
that use of lisp without being able to
discuss use cases as part of the charter
so uh
at least select uh
use cases uh
uh
possibility to discuss should be added
to the charter for us to
really show the power of these
router name space
sorry go back to the slide with the
yellow stuff on it
one more
so all these drafts that depend on
distinguished names are in the charter
to solve problems that are in the
charter does anybody disagree with that
i mean well
i mean some of the individual
submissions like lis simplenet is just
informational type rfc of
talking about my implementation of matt
and uber laze is still in design so i
don't i don't know if those are in the
charter but
i think you you're missing vpns also
right in this way
because i looked at that giraffe and i
didn't see any reference to
distinguished names so that's the
question
so if it does use it we need to put a
reference in there okay but that okay
well case in point you made a great
point because vpn's a very important
draft because it's instant id which
everything uses yeah
is that okay sharon did we answer your
question or concern
is that we should add use cases to the
charter
yeah that's another question
yeah that's a different question in the
sense that to change the chart that we
have to recharge
which is not uh uh how to say
i mean the the charter rank now has a
a strong focus basically on the beast
documents so that to work on the
proposed standard version of lisp
which we almost done
once
we are really done with that
we can even open the discussion for our
chartering to refocus the work of the
of the working group
i guess so this is something that we we
can discuss but not today let's say
i don't know
i'm not going to suggest this question
today but what i'm going to say is that
um if everything goes to plan
we should within a month
publish the the revised specs right
so
within a month
if there's a charter
you know we can start the process right
the formal process of approving the
charter and the iesg and you know all
that stuff
disturb the process you said
start start yes so in other words you
don't have to decide on a charter today
but you know you don't have to wait till
london or anything like that we can
probably recharter between now and
london yeah right so i mean there's you
know time for you guys to discuss it
okay
any other question or comment on this
one
yeah i have two questions actually i'm
just reading the draft right now
you're not specifying how to use this
uh so what we recommended is that each
of the use case documents that you say
that you see here on the screen is
saying how to use it okay so that i'm
going to find that here somewhere okay
and the other thing is uh this uses
ascii
not utf-8 or something like that for
nationalization stuff
i made a reference in there of the
actual encoding um yeah it says ascii
it's
is the references say ascii
yep oh okay
we discussed it yeah
okay i mean that's the question that's
definitely going to come up at some
point why not use internet because the
internationalization part of it why not
is that what you mean right right
exactly okay
i mean
i don't have
i don't have an opinion either way and
we could add it at this point but
do you guys that depend on the use cases
care
because we have to we can maybe you want
to put names in kanji or something like
that right now yeah for now no yes yes
we've been asking has been enough but
but yeah also okay i'll be there either
way yeah
so i'll make that update
utf-8 is what you're
right and you know so in other places
like bgp that we've been putting strings
they've been in utf-8 and we actually
ran into a problem with one
community thing
where the space wasn't enough
because for example in cyrillic
you need a lot more characters or
something i'm sorry no there's a it
turns out there's a
big problem we can't just go to utf-8
okay
if we want to go to utf-8 we would have
to redo the in the structure completely
because you rely on zero termination
zero termination does not work for utf-8
so it's either we leave it the way it is
or we redo it completely you can't just
go to your
sounds like to me we should keep it the
way it is and if we need other types of
character stats we build a lcaf
and then it's a more flexible what do
you think just just be ready for the
question right because someone else is
going to ask that no
and will they get raised will they
accept our answer that we want to keep
it an ascii
can we put it
can we put it explicitly on the drafters
a statement that says for the use cases
or
asking coding
looks sufficient does it make sense or
not
i don't know it says it says what it
says right um but the question will come
up and whoever is shepherding it will
have to be prepared to deal with it
okay
sounds like you
don't even i mean
no we'll probably get somebody else to
do it we should be getting other people
okay whatever
luigi shepherded all those hard ones
yeah he needs a break
some location
um
any more questions or comments on this
one okay let's move to the next
satellite
okay so this draft um
is a first stab at looking at using the
satellite networks um as an underlay and
running lisp as an overlay on top of
that so it's kind of got to stand on
your head a little bit but i'll show you
in a diagram in a second
so the high level goals for this draft
is uh
we know that a lisp overlay can run over
any ip packet delivery underlay be it
ipv4 ipv6 and if the satellite network
can deliver ip packets which
existing
the the satellite networks i know that
are in operation today can do that uh we
can have lisp run as an overlay on top
of that satellite network um but
actually without touching anything in
the satellite network
and this would be just another example
of how we can run lisp
over like we do the capital i internet
where the rloks are on the ground or
3gpp network where we run lisp on the
enode b's or in the ico network the
aeronautical network where we run lisp
on the ground stations we would just run
lisp on the ground station here that
have satellite links up
um
this is not necessarily how it works but
kind of what are the benefits but
as always any lisp underlay or any
underlay network doesn't store eid state
so that would be the same with the
satellite network
the satellite network is unaware that
lisp is running over it it's just just
like it's kind of unaware of any other
applications that run over it too so
it's not it's actually ignoring the
satellite network and just using it as
uh as an ip delivery system
the overlay requires the underlay to
deliver packets to our local addresses
and the underlay uh can that the
underlay can route to so the assumption
is is when
um an itr pre-pens a packet and uses the
outer destination address we assume that
the underlay could um
forward that pack and that's what we
call a routing locator or outlook
the underlay number can transport ipv4
ipv6 packets and can be dual stack just
like it can on the terrestrial network
okay
and when path optimization is available
in the underlay just like on the capital
internet now if you're running segment
routing and you want the xtr to
influence the path of the underlay it
could prepend source routes or segment
routes in the packet this would be the
same in the satellite network as well if
we wanted to use any kind of source
routing be it relative to the satellite
network or using itf mechanisms
next
so here's a pictorial uh we see those
satellites up in space we call that the
underlay and we see those links between
satellites called
isls inner satellite links those are
typically one or more laser links that
go between um the satellites in low
earth orbit in leo
and it turns out that this is
what um
amazon is about to to deploy as well as
spacex doing with starlink okay so what
we do is that these what we have on the
ground are the overlaid nodes and the
mapping system okay so lisp an xtr will
run on the ground station that has a
satellite link that goes up
today most communications that happen is
you go up in one satellite and then down
if you go
if you can go like the quarter of the
earth you can do it with one satellite
um because of where the uh
the satellites are positioned in leo in
geosynchronous that was always the way
because it was much higher up added
delay but it can capture more of the
earth's surface here it may not do that
so if you want to go from say like san
francisco to london you might have to go
up a satellite
an isl to another satellite and then
down okay but the idea is is that list
doesn't care about this whatever this
satellite has to do to deliver a packet
from this outlook
it just does
that okay
next slide
so these are the sort of features sorry
for the busyness of the slide but we'll
go through one each
the eids can roam around ground station
xtrs
just like the mobility draft the id
mobility draft says it's no different
than
if the eids are roaming in a vm
on a top of rack switch it's the same
sort of machinery that's used so eid
mobility and even predictive our looks
can be used even in this scenario
because uh it's these are list features
and we don't care what we don't depend
on the underlay to do anything here
also the ground station xdrs can load
speed traffic across different our locks
on the satellite network or across our
locals where on our load could be up in
space and one can be terrestrial on the
ground as well
and of course all the packets can be
less crypto as well so if they go up to
space and you don't want anybody to
snoop on them even though the russians
are leaving the space stand center now
um you could um
you could encrypt the packets
and of course the gs xdrs can use
alternate paths when maybe the satellite
network is not totally connected and i
give two examples here
normally you would go
on an xtr you would go up to a satellite
and then maybe go across an isl to
another satellite and then down to
another xtr
maybe
the isls are because the satellites are
always moving the lasers are going up
and down all the time you may not have
that connectivity but of course we can
use list traffic engineering and
actually encapsulate to an rti so we
would go up from this xtr to a satellite
and then back down to an rtr that would
take off the outer header and
re-encapsulate it to that outlet and
then go up to satellite and down so
those those sort of traffic engineering
features are available by just using
regular lisp
okay
and we could use the telemetry stuff
that we proposed in that draft this
draft here to actually test the
satellite network so we know which paths
are good and we can we could actually if
if the satellite network each satellite
is an ip hop we could actually trace
route we can measure one-way latency
both forward and reverse hop counts all
that kind of stuff just like we do the
under the uh terrestrial underlay
boy it's hard to breathe and percent
present at the same time
i haven't done this yet um
ground stations xtrx can offer eid
multicast service by doing head-end
replication using any underlay multicast
service so if the satellite network's
going to provide a multicast service we
can use it otherwise you can just
unicast replicate over it we know that
works as well
uh i'm not it's not clear to me and it
hasn't been specced out if there's a
multicast service that's going to be
supported in the in the satellite
networks that are being deployed today
or are planning to be deployed that
should be interesting work like i said
this is kind of a first stab we're
learning more about what the underlay
could do and are there advantages to
make the overlay work better if we can
make
um take advantage of the underlay it's
kind of
a two-sided sword where you sometimes
want to always ignore the underlay
because you just want it to deliver
simple packets
and then you just want all the features
to be on the edge in the overlay
and of course if you have a mix of lisp
and non-list sites all the interworking
features
so if you have um
somebody an eid that's sitting behind a
ground station xtr that wants to talk to
google.com that's not a lisp site all
the machinery the list the list and that
stuff and the um
pxtr machinery can work as well
um the only thing we didn't um talk
about is do you want to put any list
nodes in on the satellite nodes and make
them routers not sure yet so if anybody
has any thoughts of on that and if it's
useful um
we could determine that i don't know if
if there's any advantage other than
maybe latency to do a decap up there
rather than down here you know so
next
um so
[Music]
i was just question should we make a
working group document i don't i don't i
don't have any preference i mean we
could work on it as an individual
submission i think the work we have left
to do is to look closer at the satellite
networks and see what's going on
and
maybe try to do some prototyping i think
my open source implementation could work
as is i just need a box with a satellite
link so i'm gonna i my plans are is to
call up spacex and say can i put some
open source code on on your uh ground
station and let's see what they what
they would do what they would say i
don't know but i'm going to try
but you know even actually even if it's
one hop away from a starling box it
might serve the same purpose because the
server could you know what i mean so we
could we can still test it though the
whole point is if we encapsulate a
packet
and the the starlink router is not doing
less but at least it knows how to route
the packet to the r look and it will go
up right so
now when it comes down the way their
service works now when it comes down it
always comes to a google data center so
um you're not you're you'll have to
deliver it to a non-eid or something
like that but we'll you know if we could
put an xtr in a vm in a google cloud or
whatever and test it that way so i'm
planning on doing some experience with
that
you guys are welcome
i think that's it is that right
yeah
it looks like a question
question and comments
um
have you given any consideration to
mobility in the draft i haven't read it
sorry but uh
um so the
the devices that are on the ground that
are moving from ground station to ground
station they'll use eid mobility
according to the draft we did itself so
what what moves is not the xtr
it's it's the
oh the xtr movie well this is an
interesting new property that we've
never seen before because
even though the xtr is stationary
normally
normally when a lisp when eids move they
get new r logs because they're landing
somewhere new right but it turns out
what's happening is now
the
xtr is actually stationary right but the
satellites are moving in and out and the
question is will the satellite network
re
um reassign the rlope to that ground
station but if it does it's just like
the eid moves so it is kind of like a
mobility event but all our machinery
will work with in that case as well
so interesting kind of cool okay we'll
see we'll see if it introduces new
problems
but i i've done this testing before
where i would run lisp at my house and i
would disconnect my cable link all the
time and every time i disconnect well i
think it was uh it was a few years ago
with att dsl every time i disconnect and
reconnected
18t would give me another address so i
was testing my air loads changing all
the time and i was trying to do that
fast and it's the same way
so this is not a new problem from our or
the overlays point of view
okay
genji
uh kinji china mobile
um
you know i'll have an arrest through
your uh your draft but from your
description and talk today
i and also you said okay so far there
are only one as a link but mate is a
link since you did not mention anything
about the dynamics about how the
rotation orbital movement no type of
things
so i don't know why is the satellite
related i think because i can give you
analogy you can put your r lock
on your car and you keep driving and
then that's it it's not saturday at all
but they still so why is satellite
it makes such a big deal for the draft
thank you
oh we're just it's just another underlay
that we can run over and if if we want
to reach rural places
um which is what starling's use case is
uh
we may want to run it's it's not the
only way you can do things i mean if
you're our loc if you're on a car if
you're driving in a car and lisp is
running in your car and your outlook is
changing because it's on a 4g or 5g
network so be it
but if if that car needs to communicate
with something that's in a you know up
in montana northern montana or something
and they don't have internet access
except for starlink
then
you run lisp on that side and then and
then they can move between ground
stations in their local area you know
the cars moving around in this urban
area and then maybe the cell phone's
moving around in this rural area you
know
of the technology i i still cannot see
the
the technical difference
like yes i understand more in order to
talk some people in mahana not some some
place nowhere you have your satellite
but still in terms of technology
but to me just like in the moving car
it's it's
have no difference from just like a
satellite movement
are you saying are you questioning that
running over satellites not useful is
that no no no because tomorrow i'm going
to have another i have a draft on my
satellite but i really try to understand
why you know uh this is satellite
suppose you try to
use some satellite technology that is
significant for the list or for your
draft
is that the
[Music]
not having the restroom so in your draft
have you talked anything about like
satellite technologies that will make
your draft more significant
oh it's just like okay you are using
some underlay network that is keep
moving
we we have a lisp draft called list
mobile network
that talks about how you support layer 3
mobility inside of 3gpp network in that
use case we say list can run on the
enode b's so when cell phones move
move from one enob to another e node b
they don't have to change their ip
address and their connection stay up
okay so that's the case because cell
phones connect to towers okay now we
have these other things called ground
station xtrs that have rf links up to
aircraft that's what the account
standard is doing
and so planes are moving around and and
um they're eid's up there and they're
connecting to ground stations and so
that's just another sub network using
that wireless network so now we have
satellite which is yet another one and
of course we have the terrestrial
internet right
that's all
okay does that make sense
yeah yeah sure
take care of coin oh sorry eric klein
eleria um forgive me for i'm not uh a
terribly well-versed lisp person uh
is there a presumption that the gs xdrs
have some terrestrial control plane
connectivity all the time or is it
possible that they may only have control
plane connectivity over the
orbital domain yeah good question and if
so does that have implications for
uh the control plane uh reliability yeah
great really good question can you go
back to the diagram
so the mapping system the assumption
we're making in the first version of the
giraffe is that the mapping system is on
the ground and that's the control plane
that we use
for this guy to find that
load but it turns out that the mapping
system ip addresses to access it the map
servers and resolvers are all in our
lock space so you arguably could put the
mapping system somewhere there assuming
that the satellite can route to that
outlook space as well so and so you
could do one or the other or you could
look this mapping system could have map
servers that are load split so we don't
we don't know yet what's the best thing
to do but i'm taking the point that
you're making that if we put it up in
the satellite network that there will be
less reliability because they're moving
the mapping system is moving now where
here it's kind of stationary well
there's also yeah even if everything's
working correctly there's just higher
latencies right yeah good point
the tcp tcp stuff will need some kind of
a pep in front of it and
right anyway yeah i definitely agree
yeah thank you
all right
i have one one last question i i mean if
you go to this slide
yeah you say
uh
across in the second bullet or across
our locks in space
if in space you have our locks it means
that the satellites have to run lisp
they have to be xtrs
right because otherwise it's just an
underlay on a way off i'll show you what
i mean i understand your question so
could you go to the uh
to the uh diagram
thank you okay so let's say
this xtr has our load that's always
reachable via the satellite this is this
xtf
this
oh
that that xtr on the right hand side
could have a terrestrial link that's
also accessible on the ground so there
there'll be two r locks that you can
load split your traffic over
oh okay
okay i see so what you're doing is your
load splitting for different flows on
the ground and going up and over okay
okay okay well this was not clear
thank you yeah i'll try to make that
more clear especially in the draft yeah
let's go mike cisco uh hey mike i was
wondering if you if you gave into
consideration that there's any mtu
limitations between the gs xdr and the
satellite because i know this like the
us military and these guys
they have
crypto devices in front they're always
struggling to get like gre and mpls in
this whole alpha thing up there yeah i
don't know yet that's a great that's a
great question and we should look at
that of course we always assume 1500 or
or or 1266 for ipv6 or whatever
so
but yeah that's a good point and and if
there are mtu issues we'll deal with
them like we do in 6831
where you know we have those three
options you know
okay
so if there are no more questions or
comments
uh there is jody
well
just this out of curiosity
um well you know the isl iesl links they
usually change between the satellites as
far as i know do you think it would make
sense converting satellite into a mobile
node at least mobile node
from a list perspective yeah
like give it an eid and let it uh let's
see yeah so they can so i mean the
mobility use case now since you have a
lot of links that are changing
continuously the satellites
so i think what you're saying is a
satellite could be a linux system that's
part of the overlay and we assign it an
eid because we want to talk to it on the
overlay
that i mean
the
point of attachment is always changing
so they have our locks yeah right so i
don't know
you want to track where what are lokes
well it's not i mean these satellites
can move around and they're probably not
going to be ip re-ip addressed so their
looks are going to stay the same but
you're not going to be able to reach
them because they're on the other side
of the earth okay yeah so yeah okay so
it's not the different ipads it's
different the
place it's unreachable right okay okay
thanks and then 40 minutes later it's
going to come around and you're going to
see it again right but of course this
guy doesn't know because he's homing to
a satellite and that satellites come in
and out he just has connectivity he
doesn't even really care what he is
remember the r look that he's sending a
packet to is on the ground and the and
the satellite is just a transit network
yeah it was like a different use case
yeah
but i mean i haven't considered what if
you want a satellite system to be an eid
node
that's part of the overlay and
and because it will go out of phase do
you want to be able to reach it on the
overlay it's a little more complex use
case
and we'd have to see a really strong
requirement why we would need that
but right now i just want to use the
satellite as it exists and see how well
it delivers ip packets right this is
something we can discuss more on the
mailing list we are uh time is up
basically
can see if you can also send your
comment on the mailing list so that
can be discussed more than clarified
that would be helpful
other than that welcome
welcome thank you for being here thank
you dino and see you again in london
[Music]
thank you
oh wow utf-8 it doesn't work
no
but um