all right
get started in just a minute here i just
want to pull up the no uh notepad
okay
chaplain
one thing i didn't do chris was copy the
agenda in it if you wanted to
uh put that up i don't know
we can do that after the status too
yeah yeah
um
yeah i can also
flip it up i think so
i think i'm ready let's let's see
chat room
all right so good morning everyone this
is the lsr working group
we've got a two-hour session
i think yeah
here's our note well you've been seeing
all week long hopefully
basically says that by participating you
agree to follow all the process and
policies
and everything else there on that slide
um oh yeah let me go back so um
also the
masking please wear your mask unless
you're talking at the mic
um
[Music]
or consuming water i guess because
you're tired
vocal cords from talking all week
i don't think that there's oh yeah and
when you if you're going to go to the
mic please oh well in any case please
sign into the on-site tool
um
that's what's going it's you can find it
on the agenda it's one of the buttons to
the right
and that will uh record your presence
instead of doing the old
signing the blue sheet thing
and in that tool you can
select the hand
icon if you want to go into the queue
so that way we can manage the remote and
local queue fairly
uh i think that that is all the
administrivia
um ac do you want to do the slides the
status now
yes
uh next slide
i'm just
well while i'm doing all of this status
i'm just going to point out the salient
uh drafts because i want to leave as
much time for the presentations and
discussions
next slide
here this is this is uh
this is uh there's been a development
here
rfc
9127 has uh will soon go
off 48 so once you know once that's
published it'll unblock the ospf and
isis yang models and once we do that i
think in the next months we're working
on
uh
resurrecting interest in the follow-on
the you know the yang models based on
this
i know
a lot of us that were working on yang
models weren't interested in doing
anything as long as we were waiting for
this
next slide
okay this is this this one's still
waiting on the flex algo we'll cover
that later next slide
these are the giraffes completed last
call we really need the flex algo done
because not only is there references to
it in a lot of the sr drafts there's
also a lot of our fault
you'll see that today a lot of the
working group documents that we have are
based on this so this is really a
foundational work that we need to get
to the isg and published
next slide
uh
uh this this extensions for srv6 this is
ready i've reviewed it once they
incorporated my comments
we're going uh if there's an
i think uh at least i'm pretty sure i
think i've heard i've heard it second
party but i've heard huawei has
implementations of this draft so we're
going to do a
last call shortly after
the
ietf114
oh and there's also uh references in
drafts and other working groups to this
draft
next slide
uh
oh no stay stay here oh all right
uh dynamic flooding for dense graphs the
working group did a lot of work on this
it's
i i say implementations proceeding this
is kind of slowed down and there's been
a lot for one reason or another the
implementations there's one
implementation of it
we talked about the offers and we're
thinking of targeting experimental and
publishing it now a lot of drafts in lsr
and this is this phenomenon is not
unique to the lsr working group but a
lot of drafts in ls and lsr nobody's
really interested in them but the offers
this was this was one of those
exceptions we had a lot of interest
across the whole working group for the
dynamic flooding and i think i think
it's a real priority at this time people
can disagree with me on the list if they
want but next slide
fast flooding is another one where we
add interest across the working group
i'm going to be
uh
talking to the or
chris and i'll be talking to the offers
and seeing when they feel that rich
ready for a working group last call i
know that bruno just did another
very incremental update
and um i will uh
uh
it would be good if people would look at
that again
next slide
i believe
those were the only ones i really wanted
to talk about
in the status next slide
next slide
okay we're targeting
interim around
september 7th
that drafts don't make
the for drafts that didn't make the
agenda now one thing about this we have
these drafts now and i've seen some
discussion on some of these drafts and
it looks like some of these rafts may be
uh unnecessary so
we're not going to have presentations
uh we're going to try and
at least read these drafts or dra or
presentations on drafts that are
definitely
uh unnecessary anyway but that's the
time we're uh
targeting
okay
i'm done
all right thanks ac
um
let me see if i can
share
no chairs
all the spots oh i gotta close the
presentation i think
there we go
um so uh just uh putting the
agenda up here in case anyone wanted to
bash it um we just went through one uh
number two is cancelled
and
we have uh
we're gonna push to get all the way
through nine
in the allotted time
uh
but we wanted to leave time for
discussion so
everything else is dependent
we might be able to get to these if we
have time
but if not this is what ac was talking
about these plus anything new like
oh
yeah look at that
was it up was it ever up
no okay
yeah
it's well
it's funny because i can see it
you can see them here we go
no i screwed up user error
so
right so here's the agenda and then
we're gonna get to nine and then
anything after if we have time otherwise
those move to the interim
and with that let's uh
let's move to the
oslo
chris i actually wanted to
ask a question
yes
go ahead les
so
if i can say this in a friendly way i
think um
we haven't progressed
any of the documents that have gone
through last call in quite a while
and um i'm just wondering if there's
you know we can get some update on that
if there's some way to get
additional
resources put on that
are you speaking of things that have
again gone to the iesg or things that
are in working group last call
i'm really speaking of things that are
in the ads hands uh sorry john
john that's the mic so that's why i was
asking
nope nope no offense taken less it's a
perfectly valid question
um so i've communicated this to the
chairs already uh but uh all the authors
deserve
some uh you know communication too
my my q is pretty severely backlogged
i'm
have taken
several steps to let me get through it
faster
it will take a while for those to
actually show up
on your dashboards and in
terms of results uh i'm
not generally a person that likes making
excuses i like showing results instead
but it will take a while for the results
to
actually start appearing um
in terms of what you can do to help
if i think of anything
i will surely let you know
um i wish i had
something more to tell you but that's
what i got i'm i'm you know i'm all ears
if if uh you know
you've got ideas uh i don't know if we
want to take up agenda time on that or
not i leave that to chris
no here here's a here's a real quick
quick one from me speaking as working
with chair
i think
that a timely review
would be that is
less extensive would be preferred
to one like
four months out
that's my uh or four to six months out
and i believe you know it's already been
through the working group we have the
people in this working group who have
implemented these protocols
uh maybe we need to if like i know i
know at least some of the drafts we
don't get everybody to review them but
that's that's just my opinion
uh that is fair um one of the things
that i try to focus on when i'm doing a
review
is hitting things that i'm fairly sure
that will you know are going to trigger
other iesg members anyway so i'd rather
they trigger me than
trigger you know a disgust from somebody
else down the line
but
yes um
quick and timely and then getting
through the discussions might be
preferable to waiting forever um i hear
you
les are you happy with that
yeah yeah i mean it's a friendly
question but i think i think
and i have a lot of respect for john and
for
how much work it takes to be an ad but
somehow
i think we we need to make some progress
okay
well
les you're on the mic
still and i think you're presenting now
so let me get rid of my screen
and then
click the little icon next to you
that's interesting do you get to pick
apparently
yeah so
pick asla or
that
that works
yup
okay
so this is an update on
the two bis drafts for
asla for iss and ospf
here's the bit of history
about a year ago
there was uh some discussion on the list
that there was some confusion
uh regarding uh
the specification of how zero length
uh abm advertisements were used there's
a pointer to
the thread
the outcome of that discussion was
an errata for each of the rfcs
in may john reviewed the errata and felt
that
it would be more appropriate to pursue
this as abyss rfc
so we published uh
the best drafts in
june
we got some additional comments from
bruno and shraddha
beyond what had been
written in the errata we've incorporated
those
this is not a complete set of diffs this
is just a quick summary of the
significant changes
we specified
we clarified that
for the srte application that this is
data point independent
it applies to srm pls and srv6
that was input from shrada
we clarified
the use of the
zero length
abms
the l bit
these are essentially things that came
out of the original errata
and we also clarified that would we have
legacy routers in the network who are
only going to be using legacy
advertisements that we must not only
continue to advertise legacy
but we must not advertise asla
because the legacy routers will not
be looking at those there was another
request from shraddha
so
next steps there's no substantive
changes here there's only clarifications
so i would really like to fast track
this and
i haven't discussed this with the
working group chairs but
this is the plan that i have in mind i'd
like to see these both bits drafts
immediately adopted
i'd like to get last call within
one ietf cycle by the next
meeting
and i know john has
graciously
volunteered to try to
speed the isg review by constraining it
just to the changes not to
reviewing the entire contents of the
original rfcs
and john i'll certainly take you up on
that
i hope we can do that
and that's it
okay um
oh goodness i was gonna ask the room a
question but now i need to do this
differently
uh
i'm gonna do a
raise hands thing to see
if anybody objects to going immediately
the adoption call in this
if i can find
thank you chair
this is why you do the thing
okay
show of hands there we go
any objection
to immediate
adoption
all right so
there we have a
go ahead and click
so raising
raising hand means you object or you
don't object
raising hands means you object
so don't raise your hand and we'll
go to immediate adoption
it will also
yeah
i don't it seemed to have ended on me
well there was 20 oh that it says
there's 21 participants and 21 didn't
raise their hand
i don't know why but it's 21 and as soon
as it hit the mat the number it just
stopped for the tool
i guess that's a consensus
yeah if any i'll give a few uh just
another moment here if anybody wants to
get in the queue if they object
yeah i'm not getting in the queue to
object i'm just getting in the queue to
say i mean you you you could do the show
of hands thing again but i think you
also
have um
discretion as chairs to just do this if
you yeah yeah yeah i i was just getting
the feel for the um
i don't i don't have i don't think that
we're going to see any objections okay
all right
thank you les
i think that we will do that then
unless we hear something in the back
channel where somebody anonymously
didn't want to talk
who knows
i can't imagine why
all right
so next up
is
chung
uh using isis multi topology okay so
who's going
first actually actually i thought we
they had one slot for the two uh
the two vtn
uh drafts
they did but they have they have two
presenters okay
you have uh
you have a control so pick the
presentation you're presenting
and run uh
yeah i will try to control the slides
can you help me to control the slice
yeah so when i you should see a list of
slides available yeah on your screen
yeah pic pick your presentation and then
you'll have control
okay
there we go
okay thank you
uh
hello everyone
this presentation about
using ssmt multi-topology for second
routing with vtn
yeah
vt is a virtual analytic network with
the required topology and results
characteristics
and it could be used only to meet the
requirements of one or
a group of weekend plus services you
know in a contest network slicing
this concept is similar to the network
resource partition defined in in this
draft
uh furthermore uh the results were said
uh replace different sites of resources
allocated
on network segments for uh packet
processing
and uh
so with srbs data plane sig can be used
to replace the both topology
instructions
and the network and the network
resources allocated by network loads to
a vtm
so this document describes the
mechanisms of applying much topology to
build sr based regions
and
it is applicable to networks
where the required number of vtn is
small
uh
isis multi topology routing is used to
create a dependent topology in my
network
so
empty-based trvas
are introduced to carry topology
specific link state information
this provides the capability of specific
specifying the customized attributes of
each topology
when each type of reaching is associated
with the dependent network topology
uh mit id uh multiple id could be used
as a identifier of vtn control planes so
i'm
um empty routing can be used with
isr-based display
you want to perform a construct-based
path computation for each beating on the
network controller of the increased
nodes the network resource attributes
and other attributes associated with
utility
can be a little bit highest
for multi topology network uh topology
specific
as a
mpsc osr
v6 location can be
advertised based on assets eisen as a
basic intentions
uh
specific link binaries advertised all
four different ratings other idt
attributes may also be advertised in
topology specific manner
since this document was adopted
last year
several
updates have been made
for the comments received we clarified
that both
uh results aware say that normal state
can be used with this mechanism to build
srbs retains
and then we also
publish the text about the forwarding
plane's operations
in the
we describe the scalability
considerations and the target network
scenarios
and also um and ethereum chain has also
been made
um
implementations
uh show that this mechanism
works well
and
the content of the document
looks stable
so we think that it is ready for working
group nascar
when the more reviews and comments are
well comes
as usual
so i'm done thank you
all right we have two people in the
queue last year up first
so
um
there was a discussion when this
draft was was up for working group
adoption
um that it didn't have really have any
significant content
uh but we adopted it anyways but
the the only way that this the content
of this draft is meaningful is if the
working group actually takes on the work
of supporting vtn or
vpn plus whatever name you want to give
it and we have not done that yet
so at a minimum this draft should not
progress
until the working group takes on
the vtn actual vtn extensions
and decides to move that forward which
we may or may not do
so i strongly object to moving this to
last call
okay ac
uh yes
ac linum cisco systems i think that uh
why would we take this to working group
glass call
when the drafts it's depended on because
this is kind of an after the fact the
resource aware sids and the tease draft
aren't
uh in working group last call
i mean i don't know why we jump this up
just because it's a very simple draft
when those aren't uh
when when when those things aren't uh
aren't done
well there's nefarious reasons to do
that kind of a thing but
i think we could just wait right
yeah that's two people have now said
that
we'll take this we'll take this
discussion to the list but i i don't see
i don't see a reason you know it's kind
of like doing uh
uh
bg pls extensions before the base
specification is done
can you hear me
yep
yeah yeah i just like to say that uh
firstly this is a informational document
and uh
as we
follow the suggestions
after the adoption we have made the
resource awareness is
optional for this document so that we
can allow both resource versus and
normalcy's to to be used within this
mechanism to build the srbs vtns so it
does not rely or depend on the
resource of our segment draft actually
and
what i want to say that
i just want to
ask maybe ac to help clarify which
document we need to wait for before this
one i i mean i'm i'm not i mean i read
the document again but what about the
work in ts to define what a btn is
is that done is that
is that is that on the editor queue or
where is that
i mean on the i on the
adq or where is the vtn the whole vtn
concept where is that document yeah that
is in the vpn class framework and we
have planned to make that one go to last
call uh maybe after this item meeting
okay yeah when that goes so call
come back
okay so these two need to move forward
together with me
yes we do we don't want to produce work
in this working group that refers to
work that isn't done you know that's
based on something that isn't done
somewhere else right
i mean it's just pretty natural to
progress things in the correct order
okay
it's not a i don't think that anybody's
saying that this wouldn't progress
normally as long as everything goes the
way it should but you know
let's do things in the right order
okay okay understand
uh okay
did you want to talk or are you
yeah uh
you can address a quick comment or
rather a suggestion to the authors
there isn't anything which changes igp
uh mechanism or protocol operations in
the draft it's only informational
there is a similar draft in spring which
covers i would say about 50 to 60
percent of the similar content
my suggestion to the authors is why
don't you just move everything from this
draft into the spring draft and then
this draft is not required anymore
uh
okay
the draft which is adopted in spring
uh you know uh you can just roll
everything from here into that
uh i'm not sure that was uh related to
igp extension or it's just a letter
it's an architect it's an architecture
it's more architecture description which
is similar to this there is just
architecture and description
just informational uh you can just roll
the sections in into that and i guess
but i mean i'll leave it to the chairs
as well but just a second yeah i mean
i mean for the igp extensions they we
really don't want to put all those
springs i mean we've kept them here
or the other sr stuff i don't think we
want to do that
anyway we can take that
so we have the next room
we have two presentations
this first one doesn't have any uh
extensions in it right so i guess that's
something it should at least be looked
at
to see if it makes sense
right i guess it doesn't have to mention
yeah this one may i i guess that's i
guess i'd be all right with that
true
uh gets a wider spread then too since
this is really about how to do things
right it's just informational okay well
let's let's there's only
six minutes left for the other one why
don't we do that one is that going to be
g is that are you presenting that
oh yes i'm the next one
we've got some odd icons
the same thing is
um
i see i have to actually cancel the
countdown timer to get access to the
okay
all right you should have uh
a list of presentations in front of you
okay
okay can i see this slide
yes
okay
so this is a update about the
draft i'm using the flash algo for the
segment routing based uh vtn i'm
presenting on behalf of the co-authors
here
first uh about the background i think
this is similar to the previous one
this document is uh describes a
mechanism of applying the flex algo to
build srvtns
okay the bad result in this draft is uh
when the hvt is associated with an
independent flash algo the flash algo id
can be reused as a identifier of the vt
in the control plane
and we can use the flex algo to describe
the topology constraints of the vtn
it can be applied to
either the default topology or it can be
applied to a multi topology
and with the same routine flash algo
extensions uh algorithm specific srcs
can be advertised
based on the rfc
8667 and as a draft for the iss srv6
extensions
here we make some minor extensions to
use flash algo together with l2 bundle
to advertise the t attributes associated
with different obtains
and we have the details in the following
slides
so
a clarifying question or you're just
getting in early to talk oh there you
are
joel halpern this is related to a
question i asked in six man
and have asked in other contexts but
it's very important here
this sorry i realized joel halpern from
erickson
the
there are two different notions that get
mixed up and i hope we can clarify which
one this is talking about
there vtn in general is a concept i
don't care there's flex algo which gives
you a topology and a forwarding path and
that's flex algo
and then there has been a discussion of
what is in tease called nrp network
resource partition
we were very careful and explicit in the
teas work
to say this does not create a separate
topology you you can have multiple
nrps within the same topology
so that things will scale because we
don't want to blow up the number of
topologies
because lots of topologies has all sorts
of cost
this seems to say
that if the vtm needs different
resources
then that will be a separate topology
and that would be painful we need to be
able to say this is the resource
behavior
a resource behavior b resource behavior
c
within the shared common topology one
i'm unclear from these slides and i did
not have time to review the draft
as to whether that is supported by this
yeah
joe maybe you can check this uh slice at
the bottom we say that this mechanism is
applicable
to networks which requires a small
number of vtns so that
even if each vt is associated with a
separate topology of las argo the
scalability will be
acceptable
so this can
with this mechanism we can make some
simplification to the control plane and
the data plane so that we
can reuse something existed already so
this is the purpose of this draft and i
think that the draft
also
it describes the scalability uh itself
so maybe you can also check the content
of the draft
hope i can i have clarified this
okay i will continue with this
so for the to advertise the t attributes
of each median alto bundle is extended a
bit
uh because outer bundle can be used
as a bundle of the layer 2 physical or
virtual membranes
and here each of the member link can be
associated with a separate region
and here we
define a new flag called exclusive flag
and to indicate whether these member
links can be used for sharing load
balancing or the age member link is used
exclusively for the associated media
and for the correlation between a flash
ago and the layer to member links
this is based on the extended i mean
group or color
basically each length member link
are configured with a unique color which
is used as an include rule in the
corresponding fad
and admin group of the parent list
reading is set to the union of all the
colors of its little two member links
with this mechanism we can ensure that
uh each flash algo is associated with
the parent layer link and the forwarding
plane the traffic will be forwarded
using the corresponding neutral member
link
and and the t attributes of the limit
remembering advertised based on the
existing rfc 8668
now here are the updates in the recent
revisions
basically we solve the comments received
both online and offline
we also clarify the role of the flag in
the outer bundle tlv let us clarify the
correlation mechanism between the flux
algo and the lymph membranes
then
there are some of the
improvement under in the descriptions
about the forwarding plane behaviors
based on the algorithm's specific
prefixes and adjacencies which are
associated with the vtn
and some auditory changes are most made
in these revisions
for the next steps we think the
mechanism and the content has been
stable
and authors would like to ask for
working group adoption of this document
thank you
comments
uh
peter you're in the cube
you're up
to pick up china so i found the solution
that you are proposing rather hacky
by trying to
mess up with the affinities of the l2
members and then being a union of the l3
member and all that stuff
you are doing this for a very very
specific case where you have l2 bundle
members this is not a generic solution i
think and i believe there are other and
better solutions have to solve this
yeah take that
could i make that comment
before i think uh
this is to
minimize the changes to the protocols
and we reuse what we already have
it's on the combination i'm not just the
one
a minor extension of the flag
if you have other proposals maybe you
can
also suggest them
on the list or offline
welcome
so um
i'm i'm going to take basically uh
joel's point earlier along with peter's
now
uh and just i'm just wondering
out loud
as a working group member
if you know just we don't necessarily
have to have multiple solutions to
something if we come up with a really
good solution that covers all the cases
so obviously other people are thinking
about this too outside the context of
this presentation and this solution
um
you know let's let's not create bespoke
solutions if we have a a nice good one
that covers all the cases
so i think going forward we need to keep
our eye on that
yeah i agree maybe
maybe one solution will be more
scalable but this two solution has their
own applicabilities
such as like uh even if we have defined
the multi topology we still have the
flat circle defined
to provide some similarity similar
functionality that is uh
why we
propose two solutions one based on mta
one based on flash up
because both are adopted
mechanisms in the working group
some people may use either one of them
based on their choice
um okay ac
yeah i got a quick one gee i think
that's a circular circular argument i
hope you know what that is i'm saying we
have to because
we want to have two and let people use
it i think i think what you're the
reason you you flex algorithm is because
it's less data plane resource and that
should say that because certainly you
wouldn't want this hacky solution with
flex algo if you could use mt i mean mt
is just so much simpler
so i think you need to justify why you'd
even consider flex cell goal
but after you've answered uh joel's
question
that would be the a second level
yeah i think there are two separate
questions the journals one i have uh
clarified maybe i can clarify this
further in the middle east
yeah for this one
i just just
give a answer why flash argo and both
flashover and and t vista solution
are proposed
they have different uh slightly
different
categories testis
right
but we can't have a further discussion
on the list
okay thanks let's uh move to the next
presentation uh tony
thank you
tony lee
sorry sorry
multiple yeah i know i don't have the
agenda you can't see it
cancel
tony there we go
all right tony you should see a
list to select from
there there we go
all right
good morning
uh let's see this is a
work in progress discussion
um
this was formerly called multi-instance
tlds we've changed the name to be called
multi-part tlds
this has been sitting on the back burner
for far too long i apologize a lot of
that's my fault
trying to get this going now
if people would like to participate
please do so
um what problem are we trying to solve
um
there are many cases where we did not
specify how to deal with the case where
you filled up the tlv
you got 255 bytes of data
and subsequent work has caused some of
these to fill up and overflow
and some of the specs do not describe
what to do when you run out of space
so we tried to write some normative text
the goal here is to um
write something that says okay if you're
going to run out of space insert
multiple parts of the tlv
i.e
three thing
two or more things
that have the same tlv code point
and you
treat that as a concatenated contents
um
we need to have this solution for all
the old tlv's that have not specified
things
we want to have a default in place so
that
if somebody forgets
there is a backstop
we are not trying to override solutions
for tlds that already have said
something explicit
um
pretty straightforward
just use multiple parts
um if you have something inside the tlv
that
specifies the contents and what we're
calling a key
you should replicate that key in each
part
okay for example type 22 tlvs
you've got a
seven octets of
system id and pseudonode number
and
there's a metric and
do you replicate that or not that's
discussed to be discussed
so you
need to figure out what the key is and
we need to agree on what that key is so
all implementations concur but we are
trying not to be normative about
discussing the key
um the problem with being normative
about talking about that is that then we
become a catalog of every tlv and we
don't want to do that
excuse me
so um we're going to add more examples
trying to make sure everybody agrees
um
let's see
and the other thing we were discussing
is adding a router capability uh to
discuss to to agree to using this um not
everybody's on board with this
um but we are discussing it
so
in discussions welcome
please feel free to chime in we need
light not heat
thank you
any questions
go ahead chris cool
uh actually go ahead katan
a question about the capability thing uh
so is it was this and i asked this on
the main list as well uh was this
intended more as an informational or to
trigger some actions on the router
um so the intent here was
there's a concern that
doing multi-part tlvs
could cause some
legacy implementations indigestion
what happens if you see two
tlv22s and you're not quite ready for it
if your code doesn't do that you could
do lots of different things
in the extreme situation you could crash
you could
only retain the first part you could
only retain the second part
the semantics are very very weird and so
the proposal was have a capability so
that you just don't advertise multiple
parts until you see everyone advertising
this capability
so my understanding is that there are
already implementations deployed which
do multipart so is this something that
we have seen
or has been reported
there are implementations that do
multi-part there are implementations
that don't do multi-part
this is known this is not an at issue
no i mean has have the problems been
so understand for as an operator for an
operator to know the capability of the
routers and use that information it's
useful but i think
it'll be it's a may be problematic uh to
have the router change behavior
based on this
i'm introducing it at this stage
well this is why we were discussing this
okay uh so i was sort of curious i i
think you spoke to this earlier but
since we we have you you said you don't
want to be a catalog but we also have
all the tlbs so far defined
you know have we gone through and and
said well this this is you know this is
a tlb that's obviously a multi-part they
didn't talk about it
um
i mean would it
especially with the capability thing i
kind of like it feels like if you put
the capability thing and you really want
to go back through all the old tlbs
and say here are the keys
you know or this doesn't need a key or
you know or something like that
well again we're trying not to be a
catalog because then somebody asks why
didn't you list this one
and
you know we'd rather have people apply
intelligence
the
capability should not make a difference
as to
the behavior
um
it should just be a compa
a trigger for being able to
advertise multi-part tlvs
just to ensure that everything in the
domain is ready
or in the area is ready to hear
multi-part
go ahead les
i think to say at this point about the
capability is
you know there are multiple
uh opinions on this even among uh the
authors
and the authors are going to be meeting
and discussing this
i think
we should wait until
the next version of the draft is out
if the capability is still there
uh
we will also you know be addressing you
know some of the
uh net you know concerns about how to
use this
then we can have a more meaningful
discussion i'd really suggest tabling
this discussion uh for a bit
indeed we're trying to make everybody
happy all at the same time and if that's
possible we will do the best we can
um and if folks have preferences is that
what they would like to see in the draft
please let us know
easy so i'll reiterate my comment and
list if you in your discussions you
decide that you won't advertise if not
everybody advertises the
capability won't advertise the
multi-part you have to specify what you
do with this additional information if
you just don't advertise it or how you
choose there has to be some statement
there
my thinking is you just don't advertise
it
done
okay uh so just a quick follow up on
that uh
uh
how does uh how does uh how do routers
decide which information not to
advertise right and what if router a in
implementation a decides to advertise
tlb
let's say 10 and the other router
decides to order tlu-12 right then i
mean
probably nothing will work a lot of
stuff will get broken
so even even
even amongst routers which uh do
multi-part right uh they would have
normally got everything but yeah
right well the the thing to do is to
advertise the new the old
legacy information
because that's what's been there forever
and then the new stuff that's causing
you to overflow into a second part
that probably should not get advertised
okay so i mean a very quick follow-up so
now we would then again just as the key
we would get down to uh cataloging and
saying which is old and what is new
right uh we start going by that down
that path again and i'm trying to
finesse this by adding language that
says that without being normative about
every single tlv type
okay yeah i think we can discuss further
uh on the list thanks uh thanks for
taking this work up thank you sure
hi looks like
this solution is not a backward
compatible right
it's backward compatible it's not
forward compatible
multi-part tlvs are not fully available
for example if we have uh
you have a prv is bigger
than 255 right
so you
you have multiple parts but uh if we
have older router and then that will not
recognize that one right
exactly why the capability
yeah so that one that means that
we have new things and then the old
router cannot support it and then we
have some problems
so
which is why we have the capability so
all routers can stand up and say we're
new we're ready please send us new data
i think maybe
it's better to have a solution and then
we have new scenes
multiple paths
also for the older routers
they don't have this capability maybe
just the law and then we can
have a buyer's problem
all routers will not just ignore okay
they will take and see
multi-parts and possibly do many bad
things including crashing
so we kind of know
because this new scene all the other way
don't know these things
so how how the old router process this
new things
right we don't want to advertise the new
things until we know all the routers in
the area
are
capable that's the point of having the
capability
yeah no i know that's a one solution i
think maybe normally the solution is
that
we have new things the old router you
don't know this thing and just ignore
and then there's a everyone happy right
um that would be nice but we can't we
don't have a good mechanism for causing
old routers to ignore multi parts
okay yeah okay
we're out of time yeah maybe i can think
about that thank you
is it really quick
discussing things with a bunch of
engineers we can't stop
following
the logic but
this is there's a discussion that needs
to be had here let's wait until
the next version of the draft
and hopefully if capability is still
there we'll have more content
to address
all of these points
yeah i mean i i hear you but
that's kind of exclusionary right i mean
we could also have that discussion on
the mailing list with people that aren't
authors
so
but absolutely well we're out of agenda
time though so yep like i do take your
point there
uh okay so let's move on to the next
thanks tony
now it's tony p
well fool me once no fool you twice
stop only behind me uh oh yeah yeah good
good hang on
[Music]
it's all right this is the distributed
uh
flooding
yeah sure i think this works
no it won't never mind how could that
possibly work i didn't put anything in
my computer
nothing works yeah never mind
yeah technology we know all about it hey
so i'm wearing my presentation t-shirt
to generate moire you know patterns
uh uh
talking quickly about the stuff uh that
we were running for a while which is the
kind of you know yet another flavor
can people here in the back
all right now in rockstar mode good
so this has been going on for a while
you can see there's another you know uh
flavor of this flood reduction stuff it
does a little bit more
um the shrut on it white and me please
flip on i joined because i know i work
on the draft now for a little bit um
influence it next one please
okay so history and what is it the next
steps next one please
so the history for a few
so the whole idea is basically uh based
on work that's been done before and
money you know like published rfcs
the five series uh the variant of that
is actually already as well implemented
you know and we have it well debugged
and
running forward with it in rift uh so in
a sense you know it's nothing earth
shattering here we just took it forward
uh
so new modified algorithm basically
based on the mana principle um
we don't do not need any kind of
signaling you know or protocol
extensions really
um
it does not require all the nodes in the
area to support it so you can just
basically drop notes that do that
and arbitrarily mix them with the old
stuff
um why it's important to have and you
know drafting rfcs because if you drop
people doing that they all have to do
the same thing right it's kind of a
distributed hashing table everybody has
has to run the same algorithm
completely distributed nothing
centralized
again no signaling right no indication
that stuff is even running
so the staff is kind of a further
development of
open fabric which was the stuff that
came out of linkedin and has been
actually implemented in fr but that used
kind of ling local flooding it was early
version
we kind of you know tuned that stuff
further and we do also something uh
above which is not only flood reduction
but also kind of distribution of the
flood load
across
the topology and not only just following
a single tree or two trees
um
so this fr has this early implementation
and now there's an implementation but an
unnamed obvious vendor right um
and uh we tested it works well i mean
it's not deployed yet but you know
we're pretty confident we have numbers
and so on next one please
seven minutes okay so i'll go in one
ugly picture um
uh a bunch of cars i hope you can follow
me so at the very bottom is the
originator of the lsp right so somebody
originates it and obviously the first
hop you have to flood it to everyone
there's nothing to be done
and then
in the middle uh if you read it on the
left a transmitting neighbor
this is the
note that sends you the lsp right and
the black guy the f is the receiver so
i'm at f
but it's very important that the
transmitting neighbor is kind of
important here right
so
the f receiving this lsps
needs first
shortest path tree
from the originator to transmitter so
those are the green links right
so you have to compute that from the
view of the transmitting neighbor
and then you compute basically uh two
things and some colors something has
been cut off so you compute this yellow
front
which are
all the intermediate immediate neighbors
of the transmitting neighbor
right so that kind of gives you like the
one hope thing
and from there on
right and you uh there is a lot of
optimization i'm a meeting you know like
you can kick out all these guys that are
on the shortest path through the
originator because you know that that's
all the propagation front
and then you compute
the
two hop neighbors the thl so from this
point of view of this first hop
neighbors you take the next after those
right so this is impressive basically
his view of the propagation front and
you're just somewhere in it right he
propagates through its intermediate
neighbors into two hop neighbors and you
somewhere in here
and you have to know whether you are one
of these guys that is responsible to
cover the two hop neighbors
right so so the logic is
until you make this mental step that
you're really computing on behalf the
guy transmitting towards you
you'll not understand the moment you
make this mental leap it becomes easy
right you're one of the guys in the
middle one hop away from him and you
have to make decision whether you cover
the two hop for him or you don't
right and basically the algorithm
reduces bunch of people out in a
distributed fashion if you're one of
those you have to retransmit then if
you're not you just shut up because you
know that other people already covered
the two hop neighbors all right
and the rest is just mechanics and
there's a lot of optimization like if
you know that the two hope neighbor is
actually only one hop away from the
originator can cut it out and so on and
so on but that is pretty much the whole
thing so for people who are less visual
oriented you know and can follow my you
know
da vinci quality picture you know early
da vinci
next one
i give you uh the stuff you know for the
algorithmic thing so
you co you assume all metrics run on the
graph
overload is of course ignored because
your flat on overload
then you build the shortest path tree
from the origin or to the transmitting
node right
and then you build
the
rnl d agents this one hop into hop from
the view of transmitting the airports
towards you okay
then you take
this one hop away
from the transmitting neighbor list on
which you are
and you order it based on system id
everybody does that and here comes the
delicate trick that you didn't see
in the picture
to load balance
who
propagates you also use the lsp id
so now depending on the lsp id that is
being flooded
different people are picked
from the first hop to propagate to the
second hop
all right that is subtle this year i
completely admit but
that basically gives you
a flat
balancing across the graph so it's not
like a single tree where everything goes
you know through
it is depending on which lsps are
flooded they will pick up kind of
different trees you can imagine it's a
simplified picture but it but it's
sufficient
so you reduce the volume by what we find
is about 70 percent
but
not by choking on you know a bunch of
links the whole flooding but basically
balancing us across the whole graph
um and
for people who say well this is like way
too much computation under stable
topology
uh you know you compute only on demand
right these things
depending from whom you see the lsps
which lsps you see and you can cache all
these results stable
because they only depend on the topology
and on the originator on the lsp id
right no sequence number nothing so once
you kind of cache these things out
stuff doesn't need any computation
and um the experience from the
implementation is actually the load to
compute those things directly relative
in your school
okay well yeah i mean i had my concern
so read the draft there's a lot of
consideration there you know the lsp id
and so on and so on right
so you don't do it per lsp id you do it
on some hashing functions the very you
know you you been bucket those guys and
so on but that's you know
rita draft contribute have an opinion i
mean i don't want to swap you you know
swamp you with this stuff next one
so what happens if the whole thing
partitions right like things are great
when things are great when something
breaks and somebody forgets to send
something
so the way we fix it is that
we keep the list of whom did we omit
doing all these optimizations right and
we run some small timers and don't
forget psnp so you know it's very dense
package you can describe a couple of
these lsps just by their signature and
basically periodically so if these guys
go to stuff they will all deter some
other way they may possibly tell you oh
you know
uh do you have this thing and you
already have it right so you add kids a
lot of this stuff cancels out already
but if these guys didn't update you yet
that they have it you basically bucket
those things and you throw it at them
and go like here's the version if they
have it nothing happens you get ack
minimal or otherwise they will request
it and repair the graph
right so
things go pear shaped apple apple-shaped
whatever uh you will have some small
hiccup right until the timer catches up
and kind of uh
you know
puts the stuff through what is not
really the the mean the minimal graft
that you computed and then hopefully you
know the whole thing settles again and
and and chucks happily
um
and this does not change any of this
psnp you know sent or um
received procedures right you don't need
to we operate just on the standard psnp
stuff we just play this little trick
that we only send them or you know where
we know we didn't send stuff to make
sure that the guy has it in case he
didn't set us yet the psnp or csnps or
whatever next one
ah oh yeah i'm also this is the last one
next one i'm still five minutes man what
will i do sing a song i don't know yeah
you don't want those just oh
thanks yeah so i won't sing the song um
nobody got properly scared when i said
that but it's okay so uh right please
look at the stuff um embarrassingly
simple um
osp
version would be valuable you know
fairly obvious i mean all the same
mechanism and schwarz jumped to shark a
little bit here put the work group
adoption on it but um
yeah you know
stuff's
straightforward if you think through it
uh took us after a couple of round
optimization i influenced the draft not
another another but the stuff is largely
in place it's implemented it kind of
works and
important to say this works for
arbitrary topologies obviously this is
not any you know club optimization or
anything like that
yeah i mean open for comments i'm kind
of done
this i like this version
uh
in order to order a magnitude
better than the original version i like
this version that it does and and it is
close to the you know i mean it's it's
different but it has a lot of the uh
same using the two hop neighbors and
covering all the two hop neighbors and
doing that dynamically is a lot like
the draft you mentioned the cds that
richard algiere did for monet it's
really it's really good the one question
i had is you know all those other ones
they tried to get two copies of it where
this tries to get one
oh yeah yeah
brilliant yeah yes
okay so observe that
so i omitted this this step right when
you sort these neighbors and then you
take the hash of the lsp to know where
you start and that will give you
balancing so you don't start with the
smallest system id depending on the lsp
id
well not really like a hash of it so you
don't have too many buckets you start
somewhere in the middle or you know
whatever for every lsp so you use
different guys and while you're taking
these guys off the list in a sense you
are looking which of the two hope
neighbors does this guy cover and the
moment you have full coverage of the two
hope neighbors you go like okay i'm done
right those are all the guys that are
really re-flooding now right nothing
prevents you and every node can do it
differently to
from generating a double coverage you go
like i'm taking these neighbors off the
list and i'm counting the two hope
neighbors whether they have been covered
twice that's what rift does and all
three times so whatever it can be a
local configuration
right and each guy can actually do it
independently some guys can cover once
some guys can cover
twice it does not really matter it will
just generate additional copies
but yes i think this is in the draft
maybe not well explained yet
but that's how double triple coverage
would work
okay
and the other comment i had this is a
quick one is
you're basically doing a
psnp of
all the
lsps that didn't get flooded so that's
essentially almost to the neighbors you
didn't flood yes
uh that that's almost a csnp that you're
doing every second that seems like a lot
uh
[Music]
i didn't think through that well don't
forget that you load balance right so
an lsp will go to a
if you did not
reflot this specific
lsp then you say like okay all the two
hope neighbors i didn't reflect this lsp
i have to psnp them but don't forget it
balancing always on lsps so you will
omit some fraction of the flooding and
that will
be used to generate this psnp saying you
know i omitted this lsp to you guys
so
it is a fraction you know how much of a
fraction will depend on the hashing
function if it's evenly distributed it
should be an even fraction
so it's not really a csnp of the whole
database it's just the fraction that you
didn't reflock based on the hashing
algorithm for these lsp
it's the ones that changed
it's the ones that did change but you
did not re-flood to that neighbor okay
that makes it a lot correct right yes
exactly i thought it would i thought it
was i thought it was all when i read it
i just took that i said why are you
doing all the ones that didn't change
and i well you see how my name ended up
on the author's list right so i had to
give it a couple of helpful twists yes
but let's uh okay yeah you can fix that
thanks
okay ben
hi ben madison work online um a couple
of questions and my apologies if these
are in the draft i haven't read it um
the first is it seems like there are
topologies where running this algorithm
would save you more
work than others
and there are probably you know probably
the more regular the topology the more
work you save
and in a lot of service providers the
network i run
i i'd imagine you probably don't save a
lot of work by doing all of the extra
computational work
have you looked at where that balance is
so that you can make recommendations to
operators about where they're still
appropriate uh
look at the average uh fan out on your
network the higher the fanout the more
you save that's pretty much the output
you know so the claw of course will save
a lot if you have a very sparse network
there are very few flooding paths and
like what the hell do you want to cut
out right
most most the generate case is something
which is you know hamiltonian path or
you know minimal cut you know i was like
yeah there's one way to flood it so what
do we optimize
i think you overestimate the growth
theory capabilities of most network
operations i think all right but
basically pros about that
the smaller your your average fennel
degree
the less this thing will be useful to
you right and the
the bigger the diameter of the network
the sparse rate is the less useful this
thing will be right yeah okay that's
that mean that's yeah and as to the
computation we were concerned but don't
forget you only compute when the stuff
hits you the first time on demand so you
of course you have the spanning tree of
the originator right
and then when it hits you with lspid
with fits in a bucket new bucket then
yeah you have to recompute those lists
but that's why i put it in the draft and
you take the lspid and you run a very
strong hash so from the same originator
you will only build maybe two buckets
right so the same originator will kind
of use
two trees maybe double coverage yeah
right and if you have a million origin
in the network yeah i wish isis right i
mean you were bound by relatively few
nodes so
you know worst case like go wild and say
okay i have
whatever 5k notes and times 2 for the
lspid buckets you have 10k of those
things to pre-compute and they're
relatively small they're like minimalist
right and once they're in place they're
in place if you start to flap links well
things get interesting yeah i i operate
a network in a part of the world where
the sparsest parts of the network tend
to be the most unstable
so i i'm
i would be hesitant to without quite a
good reason introducing more computation
work to places in the network that
already have
transient like moments of hell of a lot
of work to do um but i i think you've
answered my question right i mean you
you limited if you have a few paths and
a lot of flooding you're limited anyway
you're pretty much that like you know
there's no magic i mean quantum
computing would help you wait a couple
of years
okay so my other question was
in the case where you are kind of your
weight where you're where you're
computing this this load balancing of
responsibility for the re-flooding yeah
have you considered scenario where the
node that's responsible for re-flooding
for one of these buckets because of some
sort of a bug or a miscomputation fails
to do so psnp does that that was my
question
that partition recovers from that
scenario
even if the so even if the re-flooding
node didn't know that it's broken yes
even if it's the compute
if if the
if you introduce a note that is utterly
broken right and doesn't refloc properly
with the other guys the ps and ps will
fix it and we have something in draft
saying like if you see this happening
excessively uh well you better call ben
and say like 4am here's a problem for
you like that's that's procedure
yeah
well you should go with reputable
vendors which i always say you know i
don't want the main
introduce me to any um i'd be very happy
to talk to them
what the less these reputable vendors
does that cover it okay
okay less
quick uh
points uh maybe we should you know
take it to the list but i'm not totally
convinced
that you don't need to advertise whether
on a per node basis whether you support
it or not
and you know maybe i'm wrong but if i'm
not and i don't understand why you
wouldn't define this as an algorithm
that would utilize the dynamic flooding
uh draft infrastructure
okay yeah i could answer that yeah
okay so first bring bring me a case why
we need to actually signal anything on
technical basis if you find a case
why this is required it's an interesting
discussion the second question
sorry if i'm not going to flood because
i expect somebody else to flood and i
don't know whether you know we're in
sync
no think that through that mixes with
old nodes just fine
if if you introduce new nodes they start
to reduce everybody computing the same
independently the old guys will still
flood the full graph and that's fine
and you don't have to know who is doing
that who is doing that not
i i know it's on you yeah i'll take a
closer look the second quick comment is
you use the term
up-to-date psnps
as as your remediation mechanism i have
no idea how you would how you would
determine
that a psnp is quote unquote up to date
because unlike a csnp a psmp doesn't
have a range in it so you can't tell
that oh yeah this covers everything
between
you know system id x although you have
you have to list all of those things
psnps don't
don't give you that information
are you mean the one that you are
completely missed well no so think right
you got these thing so you know the
stuff exists and you push this psnp on
the guy saying i have this psnp and if
he doesn't have it he will request it
right if he has an older version he will
request it if he has the same version he
will act and you're done
yeah that's you that's not my point
let's
okay so i lost you yeah yeah i thought
about that
yeah you can't
you can't know what you don't know but
we don't have this problem you know i i
was thinking about uh what you call it
whatever you know the distributed system
stuff right uh no i thought through this
stuff we don't have this problem unless
you convince me we do then it will
become interesting yeah okay okay thanks
thanks les
i have a quick
ospf version is fairly obvious feels
like a comment from you
no it's actually uh
it's
i i may be half culpable okay
this so we can take it to the list but
we we were talking psnp and csmp uh to
me ospf you have a you know database
exchange that's
you know what i'm saying yeah you don't
have this sort of live i can't just set
a timer and throw some packets out and
get caught up and you were absolutely
correct and yes i didn't think through
this stuff i was just pestered by a
couple of sp saying like oh the other
was pf and you know
absolutely
let me break in we do have an
experimental draft for this i think
alvaro is an offer on it
uh okay
yeah i mean we could we could take that
i'm sure this will be experimental so we
could it could reference this that the
experimental draft do uh incremental
databases
or so replace them with relatively run
with it
okay
all right thanks good thank you very
much thanks
all right next up uh i think is peter
with upa
yes
so hello it's peter here i'm going to
talk about the
unreachability prefix announcement on
behalf of all the cultures
so the problem statement
the summarization is a reality people do
summarize unlike with mpls networks
where it was hard to do
due to the requirements of the n2 and
lsp
with other technologies these days
summarization is possible networks are
growing the number of routers is growing
significantly
and summarization helps i think that's
the fact arguing about it doesn't make
much sense in my opinion
obviously summarization is not only good
it
create problems and one of the problems
is that it hides information it hides
the
reachability of the individual routers
or prefixes
so the problem that we are trying to
solve here is
to be able to summarize and still be
able to signal that something has been
lost and that can be used
by various applications here we are
mainly talking bgp peak but it can be
used by any other you know applications
what this draft talks about is it gives
a backward compatibility solution
without any need to extend the protocols
so
it only only defines
why we are doing it basically
next slide please
so if you look at the
rfc
5305 and 5308 it basically gives you a
way to advertise a prefix as an
unreachable prefix there is a range of
metrics that if you advertise the
tlb with that metric it basically the
rfc says
this prefix is unreachable from the
traditional computation you can use this
for other purposes that's the language
that the rfc is using and all we do we
are defining a new purpose here
next slide please
so
what will and how will this work
the existing nodes which will receive
this
will just
you know flood this propagate but don't
use it that's
the
behavior that the current specs are
mandating
the recognition of this advertisement
and the usage is only needed on the
nodes that want to use this information
so typically this would be the pes
if they are interested they can be
configured
to use this information and pass it to
whatever applications may be interested
in it
the l1 l2 routers
they
would not propagate this today so that's
the change
in the behavior of the protocol that
probably is the good reason why this
trap exists in the first place is
because
we need to propagate this information
between the area so if an l1l2 router
attached to area x advertises this up
advertisement it goes across the l2 and
another l1 l2 router which attaches to
area y may need to leak this information
down so that's something that we are
specifying
that's something new
but again this is not defining a new
plb or anything we are just defining
that you should propagate the
unreachable prefixes
and we can even bound the upa to a very
specific metric if that is what the
implementation wants to do
next slide
please so very similarly i i don't go
into the details because it's basically
the same thing but if you look at the
ospf v2 and ospv3 spec it defines
an ls infinity metric which basically
works for external and summary lsas
and the spec says that this is one way
of flashing the information or making it
unreachable so you can either flash the
lsa or you can advertise it with this
metric it has the same meaning basically
it's unreachable
next slide please
and then again similarly to what has
been said for isis
the nodes will propagate this data it
will not use
or install these prefixes because it
they are unreachable if they follow the
spec
we need to recognize these on the
routers where we want to use this
information which is again configurable
and would be probably done on the edge
nodes
and again abrs would need to be
smart enough to recognize this and
re-advertise between the areas
next slide
so couple of
implementation or recommendations that
are worth mentioning is
obviously
we don't want to advertise tons of these
if there is a catastrophic failure an
abr or an n1 l2 router loses
connectivity to everything doesn't make
sense to advertise all the specific
prefixes as a as an unreachable
so there should be a bound
the
the use case for this is when a pe fails
when not when the area partitions or
some catastrophic failure happens
and
we don't need to keep this advertisement
for a long time we need this
advertisement basically for time needed
to propagate them
and plus some buffer obviously
and then we can basically we throw them
at the source
yeah next slide
and
yeah let's start the show
johnny
uh tony p juniper it's kind of the side
conversation we had in the hallway and
ac will tell me that i'm an old man and
they didn't do protocols in 25 years
same thing as with the you know reverse
metric stuff the infinity things can
trigger a really interesting box right
in lots of implementations
um
it's a courtesy draft i mean it's
completely valid standard protocol
behavior you know that you kind of use
for other purposes
i'm not overly concerned because if you
pull up all the abrs even if the router
is in the middle the crazy stuff and
forward i mean you will kill the stuff
on the abr right because the style you
know that stuff is unreachable so
yeah if we want to do it this way
you know it's a list of all possible
evils to abuse the protocol do this to
do this kind of stuff
thanks so just to let you know that
there is a an implementation from an
unnamed vendor
and we have proved this that a reputable
vendor oh yeah well i'll leave that up
to you
like unnamed sources
of salt right
okay yeah
um so
your your your comment is basically
if we have to do unreachable you like
this one it seems reasonable yeah by a
far stretch by a far stretch i think
it's mildly dangerous it's abusing the
protocol
and it should not be done this way if we
really are concerned about the service
going down rather than actually
losing the router completely because we
obviously
this is not for service this is this is
subtle right well i mean you kill the
reachability of the router right so if
there's a five different things and
you're basically concerned about
advertising my bgp thing went down but
there's other stuff
you you kill it wholesale but it doesn't
like well this is what happens anyway
today if you don't summarize right you
lose the reachability of a box and then
whatever else follows
there's no difference yeah i mean
you know now we start a little bit split
herring which may matter in deployments
but you know if
practically speaking this this is easily
done and it will be done anyway because
certain reputable vendors you know they
don't listen to reason always
yes yeah okay i didn't
go ahead with you come in
so
uh i i think uh as you mentioned the in
the rfc
you know ls infinity just
indicated that the related lsa should be
ignored during the spf or calculation
and
so
there is no rvc to indicate that such a
and that is infinity indicated the
prefix is unreachable so i will think
uh and also a point point out in the
middle east several other person also
point out that
we need one
explicit uh indication for the prolific
unreachable so this is my
this is my command okay
okay i believe we can safely use ls
infinity to indicate this if you read
the specification
very very
uh you know thoroughly you will realize
we can do that
uh in terms of adding a very specific or
you know explicit signaling for
unreachability on top of this
i still haven't heard any technical
argument that would convince me beneath
i know couple of poor few people have
suggested that
if they come up with the feasible
technical argument i'm all for it i
haven't heard any so far
there there may be
other situations that use less infinity
to indicate other things so i think we
should mix up
this field to the other perform okay
okay you can you can put that on a list
and we can we can discuss the one
example that you use that is for the ip
flex logo on osp v3 i don't see a
problem there but let's move that to the
list because this can get lengthy
okay
all right g
hello yeah
actually i send the mail to the list uh
i also read the similar comments as
itunes because
reading the rfcs it shows that this
rs infinity metric is just to
ask the receiver now to install this
prefix
on you not to consider this prefix in
the computation and now to
remove it from another prefix which may
cover this uh prefix right this is uh so
this is a new behavior comparing to the
previous statement in rc
maybe and uh rc also mentioned that this
uh
rs infinity can be used for multiple use
cases so in order to accurately indicate
the which uh use cases you are
using nate for and what is the expected
behavior of the receiver uh maybe a more
accurate
indicator will be needed in the packet
so i guess i already commenting on both
of your comments so i'm not going to
repeat that
okay zebo
hello okay
one question
that's the s infinity magicka of ip
flash ego
also need to be processed as upa
and
for ipflex algo what we defined if i
recall correctly is that we advertise
the
the base tlv within infinity metric and
include the
metric of the flex algo inside
so obviously
the metric for the base algo
or algozio in this advertisement is
never used so it cannot be interpreted
as unreachable it's just the field that
we put there because we are not
advertising algo0
in that base tlv
so that metric is always ignored
and it obviously has no relation to
algo0 you would have to go inside and
look at the metric for the individual
ipl goes and where the ls infinity can
be used as a upa
okay
ac
your mic is not on yet ac
completely with peter uh this and the
beauty of this is we use the same
mechanism used for backward
compatibility for the signaling now
obviously only the routers that support
the specification will act on the event
notification but i mean that would be it
no matter how you solve this problem
that would be the case
so it's um the two the two usages don't
are are complementary they don't uh
contradict one another they're both uh a
signaling of of of unreachability
right
uh i guess
as a working group member i don't like
any of these i know and and
you you you addressed my comment at the
very beginning by saying you don't want
to argue about the scaling requirement
but i i just i don't know
i'm still not sure like tony lee's idea
of like let's just do a reachability
protocol or the bfd ideas i i just there
are multiple ways of doing this
we've been asked
by the providers to solve this in igp
because they don't want to run any of
the other things even bfd even bfd
it's not that we are doing this because
we like this we're doing this because
we've been asked to address this this
way it would be great if those operators
would be showing up here and going you
know what i'm saying like i know
it used to happen
okay
all right well let's move on to the uh
relevant yes thanks
so um
[Music]
you will be up next
let me give you the
control here
all right go ahead and pick your deck
okay
okay so uh so i will print the
prefix unreachable announcement and this
is the
maybe the first time to make the
practice
how to uh
so here is a history of the proper the
solution we probe we propose first and
20 20 19 october in in
singapore in idea for 106
and also
after several
several item meetings
and we also discussed the uh the
solution intensely on the lsr list and
previously we focused on both on the
control plane and the data plane
convergence and after discussion we we
converted to the focus on the
controversy
switchover and we also discussed the uh
intensely for the use case of the such
information and i think
kindly we all and will understand there
are several several use cases
need such useful information and uh
online discussion there are also other
alternative solution for example
btp-based pulse and nlp
and the upa just is
introduced by peter
and
we we think the solution on converging
for the pure and the ups solution now
uh so here i just want to
introduce the update content
we we make the major
update
for the following content and the first
is we describe briefly the applied
scenarios
so because in the mainly discussion
many people wonder
which which service will use such
business so i think the foreign
application
can use the such a woman first in the
pgp service and the second is the tunnel
service
and the third is the srv6 srv6 just also
one kind of tunnel service so the p and
the ps device will increase it in such a
information so
we think the pfd based solution and the
other
[Music]
to um
also and it's not as recent for the
for the problem so we think the it-based
solution may be more suitable
and the root cause of the proper
solution is the following and that is
the samurais advertisement hide the
unnecessary
unreachable
eligibility of its current prefix
but the service that
uh based on the
detailed precipitate the prefix near to
now the invisibility of this prefix to
to switch over promptly to other
alternative endpoint this is the root
cause of the
propelled solution and for resolution we
need to also confine the negative
advertisement to avoid in the igp
flooding tour so
i think many person may worry about the
side effect of the such a notification
so
any any applications to the uh
so consider this this carefully
and the uh
we updated the uh
our solution is
the uh the
the the the message will um must declare
the explicitly the associative prefix is
unreachable uh with its prefix original
certain law
and the order to
avoid the
avoided the traditional router or
unsupported
uh misbehavior so we we set the uh
associated metric to the lcd affinity
so
this can prevent the unspot node from
misbehaving behavior
i think such a uh
such uh
action
is conformed to the uh
rule of the are released rvc that is if
you if the lsat carries uh the if if the
method
is of the lsa is ls infinity and then
the
spf for calculation will bypass the uh
bypass will bypass the such lsa so uh
the
unsupported node will not misbehave so
and
we also define the capability
bit for the negotiation of the static
ability so if all nodes support the
pa capability the ls infinity is
unnecessary
and the uh
the second part for the updated solution
is
uh we we consider also the scenario that
if only
some of the abr can reach the maid in
the prison that is when the network you
participated
participated so uh the abr account which
the prefix should advertise the one
specific route to the to the mission the
prefix so
this advertisement will let the traffic
divert to the api that can reach the
prefix
and we also mentioned the switch over
service switchover must take place only
while all the adr advertises the same
message
we also
make some
update for the implementation
consideration you know as i have
mentioned the papers
we must control the advertisement of
such message within the
area so we define the
maxim maxi maxi address announcement
shareholder to control the advertisement
of the pua and the similar tests
so
if the number of the unreachable prefix
is less than maa then adr can should
advertise the summaries and the poi if
reachable odds is less than ma the abr
should advertise the detailed reach
about this only
and if both of the rich band unreachable
prefix exit the ma then the and the abr
should advertise the ma unreachable
prefix and also set the same address
with max
metrics and
at that time at the same time the vr's
avr should notify the operator that
there are several isn't occur within the
network i think the the last uh uh
last
um scenario will be
occurred only in the
in the human network disaster so
and uh
so i think uh this stuff that has been
discussed discussed about two years uh
in the meeting on the main list so i
think
countries there are
enough
enough experts in switched this topic so
we think
it is time to move forward this document
and
we are glad to cooperate with peter to
uh to make the uh
make the overall
overall solution to solve this problem
and we are also welcome either closer
to this uh this loss and the document
okay that's all
okay so um
me and the queue as a working group
member um or not i'm sorry back that up
as a chair
uh some of the comments i read on the
list and maybe a little bit of the
feeling in a couple of these slides
uh
it's been worked on for a long time yes
because you know there hasn't been
consensus
and um there was a particular comment i
saw that said you know
it sort of like
it was trying to justify this as the
correct solution simply because
it had been around longer and that
that's never a reason
that you know it has to be
it has to be technically the best
solution right
it doesn't matter okay so i mean you you
definitely uh
we're there early on with this right
that and that is something that should
not go unnoticed
but that doesn't yeah that doesn't you
know favor your solution over a
different solution just because you you
know you recognize the problem first
um
so that was that's a chair comment um
i i guess this is also uh you know the
so it's good that you want to work with
other people and i don't know if
again if just because you started i
don't know if this is the right document
there seems to be a lot of
uh commentary on the list about
things like prefix originator and stuff
that um
you know people don't like right
um
so yeah i don't i don't know
no yeah i i see yeah
yeah uh you know
you know we we also compare the uh to
solution
with peters and tier and upa i think the
uh
qa
held a more complete
uh complete complete consideration you
know i think the indication of the
unreachable information just one point
of the overall solutions and we also we
are also accept
using other
newly defined flag to indicate the
unreachable prefix
uh you know but uh
this is um
as i saw this is just a part of the
solution and we
our solution also cover other
uh and you know this this is the
point are discussed within the
maintenance intensity so we hope that
the traffic to include them i think the
uh this is this is the main reason that
we want to four this is solution okay
yeah so um i there's no one else in the
queue so i guess i'll just go again but
this time as working remember i i did
find it a little
sort of
funny that like
you made a comment on peter's
presentation about why ellis infinity
wasn't good enough but it was good
enough to put in your draft
so it seems you know like
is it good enough or is it not good
enough right i mean
that didn't seem very genuine to me
uh
peter's in the queue now
so it's peter peter cisco so agent i
mean
we express many times that the mechanics
that you use to signal unreachability in
terms of advertising the originator as
zero
is broken
i don't understand why you are still
having that in your draft
and the second comment i'm going to make
when we started the draft i invited you
and i acknowledge that you came up with
the problems but you know with the
problem space as a first i invited you
to join the upa
draft what you did instead
you took and put the unreachability
metric to your draft and still keeping
your
source or originator zero there
i still honestly i don't know where are
you heading with this
yeah yeah the the we we also
studied
the possibility to use the newly defined
flag
to indicate the eligible information and
i i also point out in the main list that
for ospf of h3 there are limited space
to
to use to use in the flag if we rely on
the flag we must extend the uh ospf v3
flag first and then uh define the
uh define the one bit to single the
eligibility you know so if the ice we
need okay go ahead
yeah
i think the
we are open to to accept the
uh our option for the ex accepting
exactly indicate for the eligibility and
but i think it is just one point of the
overall solution you know um well there
are other there are also other points
that need to be considered
consideration
all you need is to signal unreachability
you need a mechanism to that
you put the unreachable metric you still
want some explicit one the question
whether we need an explicit one or not
is something that we need to decide as a
working group
if we are going to decide we want to
find another one not the one that you
use for sure i'm still not convinced we
need it but let's keep that as a as an
option
but then what is left in your draft
right
it's exactly the same thing as we have
in the other draft where we just use the
signal and reachability we don't need
anything else
no no
we we need to control
i think as you
have said in your practice we need to
define how to control the advertisement
of the such information we need to
kill the uh describe the situation when
the network is participating
participated so no i think i don't think
so
i don't believe so no
there are possibilities to the network
you know some apr can reachable and some
apr can reach so
such situation we need we all need to
consider it
you know the the single in just one
point of the solution okay um
i'm just going to break in because it
seems to be a circular discussion here
uh back and forth let's take the the
point of whether or not explicit is
needed i just wanted to point out that
our agent said something wrong about
ospf v3 if you're you weren't we
wouldn't use the lsa options anyway we'd
use some other flags and there are other
flags that are extendable anyway
sorry sorry peter uh odjin for breaking
but let's go to the next one yep so
we've got 10 minutes left uh and one
presentation uh
we need to get
yes
uh i think i have to stop you presenting
maybe and then give it to you again so
you can pick again
and then offer
now you should be able to select again
wait a moment i i don't see the
i don't i don't
know
i see that too i
now it should work let's try that okay
okay okay now okay
i can select now
yeah okay
so okay
yep
yeah okay so this is the update for the
advertisement of the staffing attribute
so
here i want to describe
why we want to uh what is the proper one
to solve you know uh here i just
describe a swiss scenario at the way
when we are in uh we are encountered in
our network the first is the interest
interest connections you know in such
scenario
the sdr um
will build the pgp session with your low
back of this and there are uh there are
several uh
interest link competition ram so we want
to uh recover the uh interest topology
within the
the 2s
the second scenario is
for the
internet exchange center you know there
are maybe
maybe several ways
connect within by the line interface and
we want to
also discover the cover the
interconnect topology within them the
third scenario is for the uh
any cost any customer service now you
know uh
some several servers with the same
address may be connected
in the
different network um while the stop
links so
we want to define one container to
transfer the characteristic of the stop
links in about snails
and to solve the
2090 interest topology cover for example
in the ptas and the oman is
and also we want to do some traffic
engineering to different servers based
on the stubbling characteristics
and
at the main list point out the robot and
there are also other um other scenarios
that may help make uh it can use such
information to select the
best bgb pgp next hub we can end it
later in the document
so
i think the the least plot active
protocols
is simple we just define one new
container uh that is a new sub
neutrality to contain the
link type and the
link prefix associated with the sub link
so uh all all idp takes the similar
format and we in this uh
listing
theory we defined the
newly the link prefix subtly to contain
the prefix of the stub link
and this newly defined theory will be
included in the correspond lsa and the
pdo
i'll pick as
uh
as a comment from the
from captain we will we may change the
container for uh for for this newly
defined tlv to more general uh lsa
and
here we want to point out clearly that
the prefix of trv is not the identifier
of the stub link it is just one kind of
the sub link attribute same as other
already defined stably
already defined
sub sub tlv for the link attribute
and here we
is the reason that we do not want to
use the existing container
you know as we have
discussed in the main list
uh several times there are two rc define
the
t related
uh
theory to to contain such information
about the interest link
but these
this
subtlety must be present for every
interest link for for example the remote
s number and ipv4 and ipv6 remote sbr
subtly
so
so if we
uh solve the problem
solve the problem based on these two rc
uh for the 90s now
then the then it will have the four
links
uh the first is not efficient for every
interest
stub link
to include the redundant information
and
it is not possible to describe the line
establishing is
and
for the
uh for any cast server scenario
we need we need some
logical information to describe the stub
link between s and the edge server
and also point out uh by academy in the
main list
such as
unnecessary information will be
populated and unnecessary the t database
so we we
don't want to use
against the
rc to solve the problems
so i think this is overlook
our solution for the problem and uh
also
this solution helped pm uh
what making working adoption for the
first time under there
i think the update contend has addressed
the uh comment for gillian from the
first adoption call and
if there is no other no other comment
occasion we can we ask to the working
group to fold it again okay
ac are you in the queue or was that just
leftover
yeah okay i'm off
it was left over oh okay go ahead les
the question is to the working chairs
um
this draft has been prevented multiple
times
it's been sketched extensively on the
list
there was a working group adoption call
the conclusion of the group adoption
call was not to adopt
why are we still talking about this
agent
no no no the question is through the
chair
yeah okay well i'm completely
understanding
no less i'm curious as well my comment
was going to address that actually but
i'm sorry i apologize
no no no no need to apologize you did
ask the chair yeah yeah so as a i'll
just say
go ah hang on a second so we did
everything les just said is true on the
mailing list he said the same thing and
you know there was words thrown around
about baseless comments and
they weren't baseless you know when the
adoption call was failed
i even asked you know
please you know be very mindful before
you bring this draft back
you know the working group had given you
an answer and the rough consensus was
not to adopt
and you know then we had
more mailing you put out new versions
and we had more mailing lists and you
still hadn't convinced people
we still don't have rough consensus and
we're still spending working group
resources on it
i mean it's you know
when is enough enough
yeah correctly uh listen chris i think
uh
i want to explain you know the the the
failure of the first topic is that there
are some
technical uh problem needs to solve and
it's not
not
not because
it is unnecessary so i think
the reason we want to adopt someone
properly that it can be used in the
network
and
i i think it is common uh commons so now
that
some working some document be adopted
several times
based on the command from the uh
from the adoption code process
so i think
we have updated the
draft and to to
address the command so if you have
additional comments for the updated
draft i think i can discuss with you if
you have not i think it is right now
to avoid it okay
i'm not sure i followed that but
if we could do that in email
um
i i
yeah i think that i think we need to
consider letting this one go because
it's
there are it's like you're trying to
come up with a better solution that is
you know
prettier or something and you know i
appreciate that but like you keep
talking about here there's a way to do
it this way and there's a way to solve
this other problem this way in other
words solutions exist right
and
you you're trying to make a better
cleaner solution but people aren't
biting right they don't they don't think
it's worth doing
no i i think the
uh
the the the
final year
okay
yeah i mean
one sentence and i think the final user
for the every every proposal
in the service provider i think the
third part has
more um more more right to
uh to
to declare or to
hazard
is it necessary or not okay
well you're right we give a lot of
weight to service providers opinions um
but
they still have to come with technical
reasons and
those haven't been shown that the
current solutions aren't
good enough
anyway so
i hate to end on such a negative note
but we're out of time um it's 1201
and so of course the mailing list is
available
thank you igen
do you have any any last any last
comments yeah i was just going to say
let's take not not an adoption call but
let's take the uh the question of
why we need an adoption call to the list
another one
because
you know that i i'll reserve my comments
for that uh mail fred since we're over
time
okay well thank you everyone and uh
hopefully we'll see even more people in
london
and hope hopefully we'll see more people
on the list discussing drafts other than
their
own yes
you