so
okay it's 1 30.
um i don't want to delay it
but let me
mention
i'm expecting my co-chair laura anderson
to be joining i did text him and uh
hopefully he will be able to join
so before i proceed let me welcome
everybody for joining
the mpls working group session for ietf
um
your working group chairs uh for mpls
working group uh myself tarek saad
loa anderson who am i whom i'm is
expecting to join and he did join now
uh
we have nick uh
lehman as well
but he's not able to join us today
our secretary mack has been very helpful
in producing
a report and
other things
mac chen
and a reminder to everyone that this
session is being recorded
before i flip to the next slide uh i
know that lower wanted to give a couple
of words and he's already uh raised his
hand so i'll give him the stage uh to
proceed please go ahead
okay thank you tarek
i have had a
short discussion with the davis seneca
open andy malice
over the
last two days i think
and we've been
discussing the 25 year anniversary of
the mpls working group
so i have a little bit of history
so
prior to
november
1996 there was a lot of
kind of unorganized work or organized
work organized by different companies
but
november 6 1996
we had the first what we call the tag
switching buff
at mit in boston
and
that was followed
um
by
that first buff in mit was outside the
aitf meeting we planned a new buff at
the itf meeting
in san lucia in april
but what happened was that
joel help and that was the
responsibility at that time he beat us
to the goal line and he actually
shorted the mpls working group
in march 1997 and
the meeting we had in
san jose was kind of a mix
between above and a normal
working group meeting
as i remember it dj and yours were
sharing and
i was a notetaker
and
roscal and eric rosen
i think yakov had presentations
the very first meeting that actually was
a meeting that also will run like a
[Music]
itf working group meeting should be run
was run in the iota in munich
and it took place uh wednesday august
the 13th
um
so that was all the
all the things that i people requested
slot people
people made presentations that wasn't
kind of a company sponsored and things
like that
so
i think we could actually if we want we
could consider august 15 1997 at
our birthday and uh
it actually
the
that day is actually corresponding to
the meeting in the
summer
so it's wednesday tomorrow
so
we can say that we made
25 years and we are going strongly into
the next whatever it will be 25 years
um okay that was it
thanks
i will i will send out the mail with
what i have said
okay thank you uh lower i'm very proud
to see mpls has made it to the 25-year
tick mark
and i want to wish it another
50 or maybe 100 years
okay
i'll have to run a little bit faster
so let me progress uh to the next slide
and unless you i still see you raising
your hand lower but let me know
okay
so this is the usual time where we
present the note well
uh
which um many may already have been
acquainted but for those who don't know
about it please
um you're encouraged to read
the best current practices
about contributions and
collab
participation at itf
so
please go through it if you haven't done
that already
um a bit of administrative uh pointers
uh we do have an mpls working group wiki
uh we encourage you to visit that
uh it has informative information about
the
activities that the working group is
working on we also have a github
page so we do
once in a while use it
and we we plan to continue to use that
we have a
a decent agenda with six items today
including the intro by the chairs
i am hoping that people who have not
submitted their slides
have the slides ready so when time comes
i can give them the
the ball for them to share their uh
slides
so those who don't uh who have not
uploaded the slides know themselves
uh we do have two errata's reported
since last time we met the first one is
pretty straightforward i think it
the authors
dropped
the rro ipv6 sub-object from the
sentence although they meant say two
flags
so i think this is
been taken care of by our ad
and it's an accepted
the next erata is
is against rfc 3031. uh there is a claim
that the u usage of the tur of the
uh
of the abbreviation l1 l2 and l3 may be
confused with
for labels mpls labels may be confused
with layer one two and three
uh discussed that with uh my co-chairs
and uh we did agree that
um uh with 25 years i'm not sure how
many years
for our rfc 3031 it's been alive and
people are by now
are very well acquainted with what l1 l2
l3 means in the context of rfc 3031
so
this is not too much of a
an issue
i do want the flag in terms of
document status update and since last
time we meant
we do have one rfc
and we thank all the working group and
the authors who contributed uh on this
to make it uh an rfc
um
we have an rfc which is
stuck in miss ref right now and
uh i checked the uh
uh the the mishra pointer it's pointing
to a draft that has expired
i know the i'm not sure if there is a
co-author
present that want to comment on that but
i know one the main author is in a way
so we'll have to follow up on that
and feel free law to intervene if you
know if you know of an update on that
um in terms of new working group
documents so the working group was
active
the past period and we have four
documents that got adopted
um thank you to the working group and
the co-authors
um
i'll quickly skim through the the
documents
and
uh before i do that let me give laura a
chance to to comment so concerning the
document
the sfl control
uh we have appointed mcshanis the
shepherd and he will actually submit the
or if you start writing the shepherd's
write-up as soon as
stewart repost the draft because it's
expired
yep
okay thank you
okay i'll quickly skim through the
documents we saw we left the status for
people to review offline
and
some of the drafts are on today's agenda
um we also left a summary of the report
uh for the mpls open design team
um activities and uh
that that
we talked about in the previous session
the joint session with pals
uh i'm not gonna go through it uh today
because we we already went through it
but people are encouraged to do that
offline uh if they need to
so
with that i can switch to the first
presentation for today
and i think it is rakesh that i'm after
and i can give you control if i can see
you in the list
interesting i don't see rakesh
oh i see him okay
uh
rakesh can you come to the mic if
you can hear us
oh okay i see you
i guess i can flip the slides for you if
you want to use the video
i'm fine either way you hear me
yes i can hear you yeah
yeah so i appreciate it if you can flip
the slides
thanks daddy i'll do that no problem
uh so hi everyone uh my name is rakesh
gandhi and presenting the draft on the
mpls iom on behalf of the co-authors
listed
next slide please
so agenda is a
quite simple requirements and scope the
summary and the next step
and next slide please
so requirements and the scope of this
draft uh basically is to transport the
iom data fields with mpls encapsulation
so in scope is the work that's being
done in the ippm
working group
so the first draft the iom data is in
rfc now i think it's rfc 9197 i believe
then the next one is for direct export
but irrespective of the data fields
here the the scope is on the
encoding or end cap
on the mpls side
and cover both the edge to edge as well
as the hop by hop iom
cases
next slide please
so draft has been around for a few years
now uh used to be in spring it was moved
to mpls
uh about a year and a half ago we had
mplsrt expert review
we received good comments including the
gas channel for iom
and this was just before the m a work
that got started
since then
the
encoding
of the end cap has changed
a few times
this one is the latest encoding uh
that's um
in the drop jacks mpls mna header uh so
we'll just review that encoding uh today
and next slide this
so uh the m a and indicators uh
basically as defined in the direct
jackson draft this morning that was
presented in pulse
there is a bit a flag in the ttl
in the next lse after the m a label
which is the
special purpose label
that indicates that there is um
post tech data present and
if there is a need to process
it hop by hop then there is another flag
for it
next type this
so as mentioned uh
there are two flags defined in the ttl
field
and in case of n2n iom there are
option types that's defined for that
in the ippm documents are
applicable and for hub by hop there are
also option types defined
for that
are applicable uh in these two cases
and next slide please
so as mentioned as part of the mpls rt
expert review suggestion was to use
iaiom gas channel
to carry the iom option types
so this is the encoding uh it would look
like basically all i am data fields
with the the header that's defined
slide please
so the complete packet with encoding
defined in this draft there is an mna
label the special purpose label
uh in the next lse there are two
flags defined in ttl
and post-tech data basically the iom
data fields
next slide please
so the procedure wise the encap node
will add the iom data the option type
and the indicator so which is the m a
label and the flags
in case i went
edge to edge there is a flag bni flag
because the hub by half flag is not set
in the m a the intermediate nodes will
skip the iom processing
uh
and as uh is the case with mna
that the mne header needs to be received
by the decap node that contains the
those flags
in the header
and basically d-cab node will process
the iom it may point the data iom data
to the slow path
and it will remove the iom data fields
and the mna header
and next slide please
so only difference in hub by hub case is
that there is a new flag set for it and
the intermediate nodes will see it and
it will process the iom data
from the posttec data
option types
next slide please
so next steps basically welcome your
comments and suggestions
there is some good
feedback for the
mpls extension header draft
that
hyu presented this morning uh so we do
have a gas base posttech data defined
um
it probably makes sense to use the
extension header as a common header uh
assuming that's what the working group
consensus or acceptances
this can be done as part of the working
you process
but if you have any feedback and
suggestion on that please let us know
and in the end
we are requesting a working group
adoption for this trial
i think that's all i had uh thanks thank
you
thank you yes we have greg in the queue
go ahead greg
um
because it will be embarrassing
to me
um
okay so um
i have a couple questions uh first
um
rfc 5586 uh
defines uh
gach4 only to be used on oam packets so
it's not to be used on the data packets
so that makes it problematic of applying
iam to the data packets which is i
understand it intention
second of all i have a question so you
suggest to support
all trace options defined in iem data
draft
incremental and pre-allocated
so you know that uh pre-allocated it's
basically when
each transit node adds data
to the packet
i think that's a very serious impact on
performance
and
i would be
very much concerned about that to be
supported in mpos
i believe that it's
[Music]
not useful
option for npls so maybe in some other
environments
it's useful but in mpls especially since
it's uh
beneficial but not required options so
uh it's something that concerns me
and second of all your request to
working group adoption is not clear
because
you're proposing a particular
encapsulation which
cannot be used on data packets so that
makes this solution that you are
proposing
not
realizable
yes so uh
on the line as well so go ahead rakesh
now we can hear you for sure
okay
uh thanks uh greg for the
um so gsch
recommendation came from the mplsrt
expert i do agree that in 5586 it's
mentioned it's not for the pro or the
for the data traffic that
that
iom being used so there isn't we
mentioned in the draft that this is an
issue
and if you recommend or if you
think that the the
highest draft extension header is the
right approach
for course data encoding then
that is one suggestion that we could
take as a next step
um yes thank you
i don't know what the
community will decide which solution to
accept and standardize
i hope that we'll decide to standardize
single solution
which one it will be it's
yet to discuss but yes i i think that
since iam is one of the use cases for
mna in the document that working group
adopted i i hope that
it will use their solution that working
group adopt for mma
yeah and currently as you know there is
only one proposal uh that's the highway
drop for post like data encoding and
that seems to be good
it's not controversial so at least at
this point unless there's another
proposal cuts it's like
right next time
welcome the suggestions
um
okay my understanding of proposed
solutions is different but if the
working group already converges on how
you proposal for post-tech encapsulation
it's very good news
yeah thanks
thank you um i am next in the queue my
question hopefully is very quick rakesh
is there any additional validation that
the ingress will have to do
before triggering this uh
action be it edge to edge or uh hop by
hop like capability check uh
specifically the edge to edge does it
have to check if the
egress is capable of
processing the extra header
or even the action timestamping thanks
yeah definitely there is a capability um
signaling is required from egress and if
up by up then
up as well
and this is uh either part of the mna
capability signaling or there is also uh
quite a bit of work going on with
i-feet and other uh pce based signaling
as well for that capability
but yeah there is uh definitely to avoid
dropping the packets so we do need the
capability signaling
thank you
um
i don't see anyone else in the queue
so thank you rakesh i'll move
on thank you
thank you
and next i have is
my camera
on mpls
mldp extensions for multi-topology
routing
i think we can go to the next slide
okay one moment
you guys can hear
okay yeah i can hear you my camera thank
you
so just to give a little background that
this draft we presented in iatf 181
and it has
been adopted very recently
and
it this draft has been in fact
implemented and deployed and i think
there were some comments which we wanted
to kind of bring out here
we can go to the next slide
so one of the comment was
how to handle reserve bits and initially
we had written it as a should be zero
and the command from working group was
to make it as a must be g road on
transmission and ignored
on the received side and i think that is
fair enough and unless anyone has any
other
option about this i think we are okay
with that yeah we can go to the next
slide
another comment was about can we make it
as a two draft where mldp extension for
igps which is like i t empty field is
separate and for flex algorithm but i
don't think we
we don't think that maybe a good option
are really needed because there may not
be a deployment where you really want to
have empty as well as on top of it flex
elbow
so you will be using either of them and
maybe that was the reason i don't have
historical reason 10 years back why
it started with two different draft and
then we finally decided to merge it so i
think we would like to go
with the way it is currently implemented
and the way the draft is
so that's all if and i would like a
working group to provide comment
and
i think by the next idf we would like to
go for working group last call
considering
it is implemented
unless there is some more comment or
some more discussion which is required
we have uh lower in the queue and go
ahead though
so
it's lower why are you waiting for the
next meeting
i'm just waiting in case people have
some comment otherwise from our side
from the other side we are okay for last
couple let's say let's say they have to
give you the comments on october 1st and
then we go ahead
we don't need need to tie this to a
meeting
okay yeah sure so we are ready for last
call for this trap
okay yeah okay you just send out the
mail and say that you you even ask for
starting the
publication procedure
after october 1st
but you send out the mail
thank you
okay we don't have
anyone else in the queue
uh so thank you my coming up i'll move
on
i have
uh
i have the next one is uh
deprecating the use of route alert and
lsb bing
and the presenter is kiriti
um
i don't see your slides in the list to
be shared
uh kiriti so let me see if you're
available
let me start by asking kiriti if he has
any slides to share or how does he want
to tackle that
i do see you walking to the mic yep he's
going so
i'm at the bike
um
so i do not have slides i was hoping
that maybe ron had uploaded the slides
i can give an update of where
closer okay
so i can give an update of where we
stand with respect to this
in the document in the lsp ping document
we had
um several modes
and one of the modes is
that we want to be able to
return the
the ping
the reply
via control channel
and it's not clear at the time why we
did that
um i think there was some concern that
if you return it over
another lsp or something
uh and you're you know debugging lsps
that would be a problem
so we so we introduced that mode and
then
um and then we said oh to make sure that
happens
let's make make the packet go up to the
control plane at every hop
so that's one use of router alert
the other was to make sure that the
reply or the original message
doesn't make it past the end of the
mpls domain
and somehow get injected into
traffic outside of that
and
we have several ways of doing that
so we don't need to do a
router alert for that
one uh
one point was uh brought out
that in uh
so the way we do that is we set the
destination address in ipv4
to 127 slash
um i'm trying to think eight
127.00
no 127 slash eight
and
unfortunately in in ipv6
there is not a whole subnet that you can
use similarly there's a single
address i think it's colon colon one
which which is something that greg had
pointed out
um so
that's a little bit of a restriction but
at the same time you know it's in we set
the ttl to one we we set a bunch of
things so that the packet won't you know
go beyond the last uh mpls router
and so
the idea was let's just deprecate
doctor alert
and that's the direction that uh
ipv6 guys want to go independent of
uh you know what we're doing here for
lsd bing
so um modulo this one comment
um i think this draft is ready to go
uh in terms of you know at least to do a
working
working group adoption
and then you know if we have to iron out
a few things okay
but then you know we want to get to the
next level where we
we say this is um
that whole approach
of having a router alert
in lsd ping packets should go away
um and
of course between the working group
adoption call
and working group glasgow
we need to make sure that no one's
actually using this
and that's our feeling
but you know i think we need to give
people time to say
have they actually implemented
lsb ping
with uh router alert
so that's basically where this uh draft
stands and i'm sorry i don't have slides
but that's a that's a summary of this
okay thank you kiriti we have people
in the queue for asking questions uh
and uh let me ask laura to go ahead
so hello kiriti uh
actually the point with this draft is
that
you presented it once before
and you are asking for working group
adoption
and we didn't have one single reaction
on the mailing list
so you your task is to actually make
sure that you have a discussion that can
motivate
make it the working group document
thanks okay
i mean we can start a thread so
we'll do that yeah please please do
okay
um zafar you're next
yeah there is a farley
uh so you mentioned that the ipv6 group
is also going in that direction could
you elaborate a little bit more because
i think there's an individual draft but
no discussion i i could be wrong on that
so i don't know the details of what's
happening in ipv6 but there was a
movement in the ipv6
um
six man
six men yeah
saying um you know we we want to
um get rid of
uh router alert
and i think in general they want to
make sure that the extension headers
that are being used
are ones that you know actually are
being used and will go forward
so i don't i'm not a regular attendee of
six man
so that's more of a side comment uh i
mean whatever we decide here
uh we'll have some influence there but
uh you know really
if we are not using it whatever
six man is doing
if nobody is in has implemented
uh lsd ping with the router alert option
either in v4 or v6
we should just take it out of the
document
yeah let's have a discussion on the main
list but you mentioned about the survey
i think the survey will be important
thank you
thank you um incorrect you're next
thanks
hi i'm gregory erickson um
as committee pointed out so uh there is
a
problem with the ipv6
address being
documented in lspp
and i think that
we might use this
work
it doesn't have to be due as an
individual draft but in the course of
their progressing into publication
to
fix this problem and then fix a
recommendation that basically
suggests to use a destination address as
an entropy
but instead of that given the fact we
have single address in ipv6 for the
loopback i recommend you use the source
udp port number as an entropy
but it's something for discussion thank
you
thank you
okay um no one else in the queue so
thank you kiriti but i'll double check i
think you are next cell so please
stand the ground and i'll switch the
slides
[Music]
okay yeah thanks
so um
so let me switch to this one
um in in this document we've proposed
a a registry an iana registry for what
we are calling the mpls first nibble
which is
the first four bits after the last
label the label with a
end of stack bit set
so so we're up to division o2 here
and this is joint work with uh stuart
bryant matthew bocce greg mursky and
lowe anderson
next
so there's been quite a bit of
discussion
on this
not so much on the open mpls list but in
the design team
and i think there was some concern
is this trying to replicate the ipv4
version number registry
um you know what is the goal here
and the goal here is to say
we've we've had a couple of
code points that we've put
that we use for for example the
pseudo-wire control word or the net
control word or the beer header
and we just said okay we'll use zero for
this we actually use zero for both
survivor control word and that next
control word and then we use i forget
what two or one or two for the beer
header
but these are sort of um just allocated
and
basically everyone just says avoid four
and six and then you're good
but i think it's a lot clearer if you
have a registry so we're looking at this
control words and the beer header as
early instances of what we are now
calling post-stack data
and so we're saying it would be good to
have a registry where we have all of
this
so that kind of um answers the question
why a registry
the other part
that there was some confusion is
does this registry mimic the ip version
registry and the answer is very clearly
no
we avoid four and six
but if tomorrow there's an ip version
seven
uh the psv could also have version i'm
sorry this um first nibble registry
could also also have an entry for seven
and
if you follow the recommendations in the
document
there will not be confusion between ip
version 7 packets
and
you know pseudo wire sorry
post stack data
so the recommendation here is you can
send a packet that's a native ipv4
or a native ipv6 packet without vsd
any other packet must have
some form of full stack data
in other words there are existing rfcs
that say you must have
for ethernet pseudo wires you must have
a control word
the idea there being you don't confuse
that ethernet packet with an ipv4 packet
so so that's sort of the third point
here
we want to mandate
a psd or control word or something
that doesn't start with four and six for
all non-ip actually more accurately
all non-ipv4 or ipv6 packets
now can we mandate this we already have
an rfc that says at least for ethernet
pseudo-wires that you must have it
um but you can't mandate it in the sense
there are implementations that don't do
this
you can rot them across the knuckles you
can do various things the providers who
have this
should understand that they're
opening themselves up to packet
reordering and other kinds of trouble
but you know
all we can do is set the rules and
people can decide whether they want to
follow them or not
the other thing the last one that's a
bit more controversial
is
should the fact that there is psd in the
packet
be in the control chain
so for example with pseudo wires
you say in the control plane whether
you're going to insert a control word or
not
or should be in the data plane and so
many of the mna
proposals say there's a bit
in you know the moral equivalent of the
fbi special purpose label
that says there is psv in the packet
or should be both
and
[Music]
i think stuart put it
in this way that he doesn't like the
belt and suspenders approach
um you know i think that's something
that the
working group
should um should decide
that you know there is signaling in the
control plane but maybe it's all it's
nice to also have signaling or indicator
in the data plane so that when you're
passing it um you you don't make a
mistake
so these are the sort of open points
next slide
so
um i think
you know that discussion that we had and
some of it was pretty vigorous in the
design team
needs to happen in the mprs working
group at large
but i think the questions to ask are is
this stuff useful
but does it belong in the itf does it
belong in mpls
and then is this a good enough starting
point for working group adoption i mean
there's definitely a lot of things to
to fill in and to clarify
but you know are we at a position that
we should do
working group adoption or should we have
more discussion in the in the
mailing list
that's kind of where we are
[Music]
and i think that's the last slide
okay
yeah i have a question please uh so with
signaling um it's a little bit i
understand if you signal in advance
uh you know i i will be sending you a
control word uh
and then you start sending traffic after
and that's a kind of a static state that
you're in
that all your flow or all your packets
from ingress to egress will
contain the control word and that's
understandable but when you're doing on
demand type of
thing
where you enable
you know
you're saying here a control word i can
give a different example you enable
something but then
your flow is already started so some
packets may carry that or some
some packets may not and there will be a
timing issue between control plane and
the data packets so we cannot correlate
when the state is uh ready for
you know uh
control work being present at that time
so
i'm not sure yeah that's signaling i
mean there is advantages in getting
carrying it in the data plane in that
sense
yeah clear guys do that as well so
um
even though they have a lot of signaling
in the control plane
in the data plane they have a
special purpose label that says i have a
beer
you know beer data which comes after the
stack so basically they have brpsd
but that's
heralded
by a special purpose label so we do both
like the control words
for that net and pseudo wires are
signaled in the control plane but not
the data plane
in beer we do both
and then
as you said there may be cases where
it's more ad hoc
and so you'll have things that are
signaled in the data plane but not in
the control control plane so i think
that's something that we need to think
about
and see from an implementation point of
view
as well as a you know make sure we're
doing the right thing with the packets
point of view
what is the approach we want to take
okay
there isn't any other question
so i will
proceed move on and thank you kiriti
i think the last presentation for today
uh
so i do have i think uh
either robin or
chuang long
uh i will shy okay
okay and do you want uh controlled uh
flip between slides i'm giving you
i don't do nothing
you can control it
okay
uh hello everyone my name is
from huawei and today my topic to
generalize the ipv6 town of mps
let's start please
okay
uh we know some technique on challenges
to mps
uh first one is the amherst legs the
mechanism of source education
for mp2p connections this causes the
difficulty and the complexity for omo or
mps
we know that also the sfl is defined
but a few
implementations
and the second the type of pillow out
cannot be directly determined because
no pilate type indication
and the third we know the mps is
difficult to encapsulate new forwarding
attributes
for the new features
such as the net spacing i feed and ep
and so on
and first the first
the process of
the esmp function is in complexity and
we know the interfacible or flow level
are usually placed at the bottom of the
labor stack for processing
and the internet behind the information
may also be impossible for the purpose
of the example
okay last slide please
uh before i
progress from long would you like to
take questions now or towards the end
do you like to think
uh
sorry
um
i have greg wants to ask a question do
you like to take it now or towards land
do you like to uh take the questions
was that's the video
okay i see greg already at the mic why
don't you go ahead greg and ask your
questions okay thank you um uh can you
clarify what you've seen the difficulty
complexity of oem over mpls
if i understand correctly for the
multi-point to point
connection i mean maybe in the next
steps i can give them more detailed
information
okay
okay are you okay to hold uh greg
okay i can hold
okay thank you thank you
please proceed
okay
so next slice okay
hit number three
okay
and
you know in the drafted jp6 draft
defines
the jp6 tunnel how to support the new
features
for example iom and ipn
under the exiting functions for the ip
tunnels based on the extensions to the
ipv6 extension headers
the right figure is showing the cab
solution or jp6
in this figure we can find the ipv6
extension hydra includes the
cab solutions of new features
and
absolutions of exiting tunnels functions
this is the jp6
the in-cab solution
if the jp6 tunnel is used for mps
there can be the following advantages
the first is the ipv6 source address is
used to do for more sourcing additives
and the second
the ipv6
uh that's kinda can
indicate the payload type
and the third is the ipv6 flow label
can are used for the smp
and the last one is the in-cab solutions
for the new features have been defined
well in the ipv6 and can be reused
easily
next step please
[Music]
okay
and in order to support the mps
based on the jp tunnel the method
carrier ms label stick
information is defined as follows
pressure all well known ipv6 profiles
need to be assigned
and then encapsulation the ms label
and the
second is the ipv6 pressure prefix
can be followed by maple the mps label
in cap solutions to form
120 bits
we quickly call it the ipv6 nps state
and type one
this is the following figure shows the
details from it
okay next slides please
okay the ipv6 empire said can be placed
in the ibvs distinction advice and how
to process the first label when the
packet is received
see this figure to the local action of
the label one is pop
then properly for one and
label two label three are moved left
to uh number left by 32 bits
if you look
label one swipe
then replace the enable one with new
label
yeah next thread please
okay uh if all the empty labels type
cannot be placed in the ipv6 distinction
device
ipv6 the hydra can be used to host the
remaining has mps labor stake
in this figure is defined ibv6 amputated
we call it the type 2
and the next multiple label cab
solutions
the type 2
it is used as the segment
in the root hider
after all of the label income solutions
in the ipv6 distinction address are
profit
the first label in the segment indicated
by the asylum will be protest
next please
uh some considerations about the control
plan
first of all the jp6 only processor the
way to carry mps label cab solutions in
the data plan
and the amps can travel and actually
need to be changed so
i missed the label
can still be
distributed using existing control plan
doesn't change anything
okay next please
[Music]
oh an incumbent
thank you
yes greg is uh the top of the cube
okay thank you okay okay now i have two
clarification questions uh the first is
to the first slide where you
mentioned that
motivation for this work is
difficulty in complexity
using mpos oam
and second is how in your opinion this
work is related to
mpls over udp rfc 7510
and mpls
sr acid impellers or ip
rfc 8663
uh
sorry my level is not a stable uh i
cannot listen very clear and jamie can
you help claire for it for me okay jamie
jimmy do you want to take that
question
yeah i can try to
help to help to answer that one
i think
the complexity about the oem for mprs is
mainly
uh due to the lack of the source node
indication in the
nprs package so that is usual
document is talking about uh
as for the ampers over ip and
udp encapsulation
um
my understanding is it is
a separate thing from the npr's original
impr's encapsulation so we were
comparing the npr's absolution with this
uh new proposal
here
okay
[Music]
little bit um
that you say that
mpls oem packet don't have uh source
information because
if we use ipedp encapsulation
for oem packets as we discussed earlier
for example in lspping so it does
include uh ipsource address
uh yeah that is another encapsulation
which may help to
encapsulate the source address but the
mprs itself does not have this kind of
uh capability
yes but it's matter of choice so
basically yes if you choose
then you can use sfl
again so that's already been solved
so if you choose non-ip encapsulation
then you can use sfl
and sfl so synonymous flow label
being
developed as a mechanism to identify the
source in mpls environment
yeah that one has also been mentioned in
the presentation well you can see
uh sfl is one option it is not uh
widely implemented or used in the
network
uh
okay but we already have defined and you
introduce another option that is not
being implemented by anybody yet
kind of strange thank you
okay
greg please follow up on the mailing
list
as well so i'm next in the queue uh
tarek sad as a working group participant
um
the as you know the mpls label contains
an additional in addition to the label
value
ttl and traffic class
fields
and the ib header as well the ipv6 in
this case
contains traffic class and ttl so which
ones will be respected and
your in your encoding proposal
if they're contradictory or different
so which is it the ipv6 ddl and the
traffic class or the mpls
uh hello tarik can i take this question
yeah sure
okay tariq i think that's a very good
very good question in fact this has been
taken into account
until now we think that
in order to maintain the original impr's
encapsulation
we recommend that the mprs ttl traffic
class will be used
instead of the ipv6 ttl or the
other
traffic class that's this is the
answer until now
but we thinking maybe in the future
if possible maybe we only encapsulate
encapsulate the label value but the ipv6
ttl
and
traffic class can be reused
but i think that
means much change
thank you robin i i was hinting to that
you know that you know maybe you should
consider only the label value rather
than the whole 32 bits
but
the next question i have is why do you
call it sid i is it srv6
related
uh
in fact yes in fact you use not a ipv6
address
but you know that we talked about some
of the this generalized srv6 i mean
this is the
segment that
encapsulated the impr's label
so we call it a
type of this seed
maybe
more appropriate
that's something
so it is srv6 then
to some extent that generalize the srv6
because you know that's the classic srv6
is the segment means the locator plus
the function plus arguments but here is
different from the classic
srv6 segment
okay i appreciate maybe you clarify that
in the draft as well
okay
okay um
i don't know if okay i don't see uh
so sorry
ac you want to ask a question
i was i was just going to say i think
you should change along with what you
said i think i was thinking the same
thing you should change the name of the
draft even shouldn't just clarify it
i agree
okay maybe
okay thank you ac
was there another question you had
no
okay that's it
um that's it and we're uh right on time
i
thank you so much
the presenters and this was our last uh
presentation for today uh again thank
you for joining and contributing to the
working group
looking forward to ietf 115
thank you
lava if you want to see any closing
remarks go ahead
no
um
[Music]
i'm fine i think next time it's
london it might be possible to travel
even from me
see you in london bye
okay
is
i hear you had your own amount of fun
five hours
right