which fight
thank you
so what you're doing here
that's good good
okay
good afternoon welcome to msr6 both
please take your seat put your chair
chair in upright position
put your phone in your airplane mode or
at least to silent mode please
because this session is being recorded
and we don't need any musical soundtrack
so we have busy agenda so i guess we
shall start
yeah and please scan this beautiful qr
code
so you're on the blue sheets
so note well
i guess you've seen it so many times but
i'll keep it on a screen for another few
seconds so everyone can read it
it's on the slide deck as well so you
can download it
so agenda
we are i'm going to talk for five
minutes maybe less
then we have 45 minutes to talk about
requirements and use cases
we are going to talk for a bit about
proposed solutions but i suggest we are
not focusing too much on this
and
and during those parts
please only ask clarifying questions
like i don't understand what you mean by
that and keep questions like i don't
think it should be done that way
to the
second part of the session we're gonna
have open mic discussion then we'll talk
about charter and
hopefully make some decisions
uh
please because we only have two hours
and i suspect
most people here could talk about on
this topic for like a couple of weeks
please keep your comments focused and if
you notice the first slide
we do not want to talk about
how before we discuss should we
right so
what we need to actually
agree right now is is this problem worth
solving okay is it a problem do we want
to solve it
do we want to solve it at
ietf and if answer is yes then where
exactly are we going to solve it are we
going to use existing venue or we need
to create a new one
and if you answer if you find answer to
that question we can discuss about
uh charter and deliverables and all
those things so please keep this in mind
right let's refrain from discussing
details of the solution because if we
decide to form a working group it will
be working group job not the task of
this both
uh
so i think
actually that's all i have
any comments
uh so just one important thing like if
you're going to join the mic line please
use the
meet echolite client if you're local to
join the line
uh so we can kind of manage between the
remote and local lines thank you very
much
okay and the first presentation
let me
msr use cases right
please come here stay in this pink cross
so people
remote people can see you
i
and i will be your
voice controlled interface to the sides
timer
15.
[Music]
if you want to look at the slides
can you hear me
hello oh yes no
uh okay
okay sure uh good afternoon everyone
here
on behalf of the author list i'm going
to talk about the msr6 use cases
i'm a tng
and
this is
some work just is derived based on the
mailing alias the the sun meeting and
all the contributions from different uh
people so here i'm uh presenting
uh can you do the next one
next slide yeah please oh yeah
um from the
meeting uh one
one one
two and also the melee discussion about
the the use cases and all the
requirement
objectives
and the team has already have already
laid a solid foundation on uh what will
be uh achieved what will be pursued and
all the you know objectives and uh
requirements
so
for the problem statement so um
hopefully is uh
you at least to get some background
about that things here i will just uh
give a uh some sort of a summary of what
will be the objective requirement to be
achieved
uh what is uh we want to get the uh the
first one
is
the native so basically we want this one
to be done on the native ipv6 so it's
not likely in cap over in cap over incap
the the second one is the stateless so
this case here we do not want to get the
gigantic number of software states to be
refreshed
every sometime in the multicast domains
the stateless
the third one is a large skill so it's
like we want to handle a large scale of
networks not just like a small
and in the large scale network we're
going to have a new numerous multicast
streams
and also we have some other requirements
like the the especially what we're going
to uh when i mentioned about the
technical domain is some extreme
dynamics
in the subscriber uh drawing and the
living
and and also we want to use the msr6
this type of mechanism to get some
add-on value and the features
that can be
coupled together
okay so for all the objective
requirements in mind
uh today i'm going to present four cases
uh from different categories the first
one is from the telco domain
it's like a 5g transport network the
second one is from the idc network for
the large-scale dc
the third one is for the enterprise
network it's like the vertical
uh is a is the case for civilians
cameras the last one is like a holistic
use case that is called sd1 but it's
going to span
the teleco domain network uh
cloud network in the price and also
public
okay i can go to the next one
the the first use case is the the
multicast for toggle as we know uh with
advancement of 5g technology and its
commercial deployment
the multicast communication start to
become a challenging issue for mobile
operators
3gpp
has already 3gpp has already defined
in the ts23247
enhanced mbs architecture to handle
to handle the different cases if you
look at the top left picture that is the
one
in the 23.247
i'm not sure if the the function small
or not but you can focus on the right
circle throughout the bottom part
of the top left picture
and here you can see the mbupf and look
at there this uh n3mb interface is at
the very bottom line and toward the left
side to the g node b that is the for the
multicast communication
if they zoom if you if we zoom that one
in into a large picture that will be
shown at the uh
the bottom left
but the bottom left is a still a uh very
high level architecture like a thirty
thousand football view
of a it is a real deployment but here we
just give a very high level view so you
can see all kind of the the ring from
the core from the
backbone from aggregation from the edge
until the g node b if you look at the
the magnitude of order on those type of
rings
okay the you know the ring you can
consider this one is like a multicast
tree but instead of a stick or branch of
a tree here you can consider it like a
ruin so each ring has a branch
and then this is just like a
a chain of rings but it forms a tree and
rooted on the right hand side like a ups
okay and then when you put everything
together here it's on the ballpark
around the 30 000 level okay so it's
it's so huge
it's so huge it's not just so simple to
handle this type of things in the
regular uh you know our existing uh
solution of multicast okay
and remember here this is for the taggle
domain you know for tempo domain and
also for 5g you can consider there are a
lot of requirements for the dynamics
like the mobile subscriber their
tendency to move
uh between uh
from one g note b to the next one where
5g has specified the different ssc mode
service at the session continuity mode
one two three so for those type of
things you're going to have some anchor
pd
the psa on the ups side so this one will
introduce another
dimension of dynamics so in that case
even if you try to you know you can you
want to do divide and conquer to put
this like a 30 thousand
node network into some clusters but the
thing here is like it's going to be very
dynamic it's not
an easy job maybe you need i don't know
how many csies but unless
something
to handle the whole thing so it's going
to introduce the the burden of opex
remember 5g capex is already a big
burden for mobile operators
so but put everything together
okay so you're you're going to know okay
what we want to achieve that is on the
bottom right there's like to avoid poor
flow state
to uh prefer selective
over uh inclusive just this one just so
you can consider like the dvmrp or the
pin dense mode those several things
or worse the sparse mode and also uh we
want to avoid unnecessary pack the
in-cap
okay this is a tackle domain since you
know it's it's it's a real and it has a
lot of requirements okay including the
tackle side the mobile side and the
transport side
okay yeah next one
next case
yeah
okay uh this one no no not this one the
dc
okay
oh yeah thank you
this is another case it's also a real
things
you know probably are familiar with the
the global uh the mobile network
operator especially north america or
europe and normally they're going to
have their own network cloud
to run the 4g or even 5g virtualized
support
but in in mainland china the mobile
operator actually owns both a network
cloud and public cloud here in the
public cloud is owned by public
hyperscalers so in those things we have
extremely large dc networks to handle
the 5g
core network you can consider you know
the subscribers in our case you know we
are the largest uh mobile subscriber in
the world in terms of the
numbers it's like a a billion so about a
billion subscribers
and then we have
some number of uh
dc network to handle the 5g cores so you
can you can know on ballpark uh how
large it will be
and also there are some other like hpc
uh
applications that require the large
required multicast communication to
improve the efficiency so when you
consider this one uh together so this is
another you know we put a number there
like a 30k uh switches layer three
switches with the links on 60 k so when
you put everything together and also
consider requirement we specific we
specified at the beginning
scale scalable and stateless native ip
dynamics all kinds together so this is
another challenge use case we have to
face
next
you know for this one is for the
enterprise or the vertical so this is
like the civilian camera um there are
some public stats i can i found uh
google it's like uh in in beijing it has
like eight million cameras
in uk london it has close to a million
uh surveilling cameras
so depending on the government
regulation or local governments or
policies so the the data captured by
those uh
such a large number of cameras will be
stained towards some places are some
analyzers this is the picture on the
left hand side so if those information
stand about those analyzers
this amount of information will be very
large and the number of modern streams
will be huge so for this case for this
case we do not want to we do not want
the network itself to be burdened with
the states
so uh for this particular case is also a
real requirement case now we want to
have the host the host can be the camera
or the analyzer to associate together
without going through the the regular
ignp drawing mld join those type of
things but this does
require the pre-config to associate the
host together
okay
yeah
you know consider all the three cases
you know in the teleco network
in the in a dc network
and also on the enterprise of vertical
so the last case is like a holistic use
case with add-on feature and values
we are talking about sd1 sd1 itself is
is nothing new but here when the skill
goes up you know this is another real
for one large enterprise company in
china it has cpesd1 node
up to the national uh the nationwide up
to 100k cpes and those cpes will be
connected
through like a tow code domain through
enterprise because they know they have
the uh their branch office
and through uh the cloud they may have
some uh virtual uh cps running on the
the
the public cloud and
those things will be connected to the
public internet
so this is really a big you know a big
deployment
and remember you know when those things
are connected uh together this through
they go through the public internet so
there is a requirement for the uh
security you do not want to expose
especially for the enterprise
so in this case
so in this case we want to have some
sort of way to encrypt
okay so remember we have the uh
requirement objective to use the native
ipv6 so for msr6 it's going to have the
advantage just to um to leverage to to
leverage ipv6 v6 extension header the
esp and the eheader to do this type of
encryption so for this holistic case you
have all the things uh you want for the
scalable stateless the native dynamics
of msr6 plus the uh the natural
encryption decryption embedded with the
ipv6 extension header
the next one so the next one is the
summary so here is the use case problem
statement has been uh laid down by the
colleagues and on the email alias and
okay and you know here it's just like
the the summary uh what i want to
achieve the one is the native ip6 is the
required and also the status is
important but remember you know
everything together we have like the
dynamics
and some add-on features
so
this yeah so this important things it
has all the objective requirement
clearly a setup
so yeah hopefully it's uh
yeah hopefully you'll be
yeah you'll get it yeah thanks go ahead
no greg your mic is not on i think it uh
no it's not
okay
better
uh my name's greg
can you define what you mean by native
ipv6
do
can you please define what you mean by
native ipv6 oh it's just like uh using
the activated header using sv header
without the end cap you know it's like
are you forwarding on the v6
v600 exactly exactly like sources
yes and all srv6 all kinds of native
but
but you're replicating there's nothing
replicating in ipv6 you're using it
extension so it's not necessarily native
you have new forwarding information
that's really no different than an
encapsulation putting it in extension
header doesn't make it native it just
relocates it in the header
yeah you can't consider but normally
most of the native part is we're going
to expose the epiphysis header
throughout the rotting side so when they
look at is not looking at some tunnel
okay there's something and then decap
and find some inside so that is you know
yeah go ahead
hi andrew alston i'm just wearing my
operator hat um
in the you referred to
non-encapsulated now if you go back to
the previous slide
that shows the public internet
that there
is by my reading
a violation
of the limited domain
as specified in the srv6 standards
and so i'm trying to understand how
you've got a use case there
that does clearly
violate a current rfc
uh
which are here well remember the
extension header is something like
like a proposal uh like uh proposed
solutions and the the colleague earth
and will be giving well i'll be giving
some uh description of those things so
which after talking about that in rfc 50
um
i think uh
andrew right like i think you have a
point but can we have that in the open
mic discussion because i i think like
the use case itself doesn't violate like
maybe a proposed solution might violate
like you know not encapsulating it but
that's a use case it's a use case right
so i i do get your point but we can have
that in the open mic discussion right
there's nothing that can be clarified
and i'm happy with that okay thank you
okay thank you let's take go ahead
uh stigmas uh just a clarification i
hope you can clarify um you talk about
the size of the networks they didn't say
anything about the size of the multicast
tree or or bandwidth or how many flows
you would have in the network so they
have some thoughts on that
you want well are you talking about the
network slicing to divide and conquer to
make a large domain into like sub
domains
yeah i think uh his question is like
what is the size of the multicast tree
yeah oh the size of multicast streams
okay if you look at the the first uh the
use case for telco and then we have to
give the ballpark oh can you uh can you
go to the
the the teleco case uh we have to give
the ballpark uh no yes oh no uh one more
no no previous previous yeah yes this
one if you look at this one the bottom
left one and then the ballpark for the
the ng-run is running as ip uh uh it's a
run ipv6 clear three it can up to 30k
yeah and then look at all the rings like
we have like a 10 for backbone 100 on
aggregation and for the excess and 1k so
this is like a chin of rings it's like a
tree but instead of the seed or branch
of a tree each one is like just like a
ruin and you like a ring instead of a
branch but those rings will form a big
tree
yeah but let's say for a specific flow
we're talking about maybe 10 hosts
receiving left flow or we're talking
about 30 000 hosts receiving oh there's
there's a bunch you know if you look at
well
it's been discussed in the previous
assigned meeting that the two itf
meeting ago regarding people talk
if i remember correctly the receivers i
think at least the 10 million or
something i i i it's not in my mind
right now but it's about the 10 million
level or maybe about okay
you know i think it's important to think
about you know for the the solutions for
use cases like
right right small trees really big trees
just a
kind of sparse receivers like spread out
or if almost everyone wants to receive
right yes receive a spread out and also
remember these mobile subscribers they
can keep moving among different g note b
and also 5d require ssc
service and session continuity
the mic line is closed just make a
street brief statement if you have a uh
way past the time i'll answer to the
questions raised in my uh part of the
presentation okay thank you thanks
go ahead yeah so 10 million receivers i
am assuming they are host not the end
points so they will not participate in
actual tree
actually they are viewing the same
streams but on different you know if you
look at this on different genomic on
different aggregation of access
aggregation those type of rings so it's
distributed remember here you know i can
i can see one more thing this is within
a city
it's not a province or state yet
okay perfect thank you i know we have
the remote participants so please stay
here oh
uh yes no no please stay here there's
like more questions
yeah uh human go ahead please
yeah can you guys hear me
yeah thanks okay a couple of comments
please first thing on the 5g
use case
as you know the g note b's or the e note
b's they do are hosts or they do igmp or
mld join
to the sell side router
and the cell start router is
where the trio starts so
really you shouldn't be counting the g
note b's or e note b's because they're
just hosts and for the tree you should
start
counting the
cell side router
because that's where the pim or mldp or
the tree starts
but uh my question is that this problem
has been solved for centuries like all
these alerts that you folks get on your
cell phone for earthquakes for
uh you know bad weather child abduction
etc etc all of the star stuff are embms
and they're multicast so every single
major provider in the world uh does have
multicast running for this emdms type of
application
which is very important for each
government within the world so that's
common number one and comment number two
is with regard to your camera uh diagram
if you can go to that one
or
it doesn't matter if you go there or not
but my understanding is based on the
multiple smart cities that we have put
together
the cameras they usually do unicast
to a server so there is a server that is
recording all these cameras real time
and the cameras do unicast to the server
and the reason that the cameras are
doing unicast is because of security so
the camera starts a ipsec tunnel to the
server which the server terminates ipsec
tunnel and any of the operators on
different areas within the country that
want to look at that a stream they do a
join to the server that is recording
those cameras so those cameras are not
part of the multigas domain usually
within the smart cities because of the
security issues they are unicasting to
these uh four or five data centers that
they are recording all these uh
streams uh live and then any uh any
operator police ambulance whoever that
wants to look at those
streams government they just do a joint
to the server not the camera
right like but that's a different use
case that's not the use case he's
talking about so
yeah i think you made a point thank you
i think both the points are noted thank
you
thanks hi jen
here i want to
give another example for the uh
for the lives for the multicast request
requirement from the
for a large large network arjun we
cannot hear you like can you um you know
yeah can you shout or get closer to the
mic or i'll come back we'll take uh
vichang and then we'll come back to you
go ahead
chuck could agree with me
yeah go ahead
okay
i just would like to provide a little
information about the native ip6
so
as you know ipv6 traffic
in
telecom network
is
increasing rapidly
cited channel mobile as an example
our 4g 5g network
the ipv6 traffic
has
exceeded
till now
in the near future we will
have the opportunity to see the
uh purely ipv6 network so if we can have
a native app this ipv6 network
there will be
a
good chance to simple
uh simplify the
network
and the second one about the en bmis
in fact
in channel mobile we
have already
provided the yam dms
services
in china and
for the backhoe network we have to
support
multicast
because
the
multicast traffic
is really big
for 5g i think
that would
have the similar uh
requirements
so
i didn't hear a question do you have a
clarifying question for tianji or are
you just agreeing with what he said
because that's what i understand
i just want to the response uh some
people
write the the question about
the mud cast
in
4g
embankments
solutions i think i've got it
got it and we do have time for the
discussion but this is right now for
clarifying questions only for this yeah
right so
we can talk about it in the discussion
thank you
yeah thank you hello
yeah yeah go ahead
yeah yeah uh so uh here i want to give
uh another example for the
uh
for the um multicultural service within
the large-scale network you know
currently the live stream are emerged on
the internet service and i think the
largest live stream not exists not only
within the 5g transport network it it
can span
the multi-domain you know in in china we
uh our
we operate held
uh several domains several several net
several domains connect together so
the
the multicast source uh always located
in one metro uh meta network under the
receiver located on the other side of
the
metro network so the livestream will
span the multi-domain so i think the
this such services are
sold
currently by the uh
syrian uh cydia network i think
and if you have a question for tng or
you're also agreeing because uh your
audio is very poor
uh if you have a question uh please type
it in the chat otherwise we'll take it
during the discussion time like we do
have an open mic time
okay i will type
my uh
my information really in the chat okay
okay thank you thanks thank you okay
sure please thanks
yeah great um sorry i didn't catch that
was the end of the presentation it was
still up uh
greg again
um i'm
a little baffled that we're not starting
with a problem statement that we're
actually looking at a unique set of
requirements
that can't be solved with existing
solutions that are out there to justify
some additional work
what we see here is a whole list of use
cases that are really not any different
than what's already been solved or can
be solved by existing solutions so
we've asked this work in the past to
provide a problem statement
and we never got one so i was hoping
today we'd actually see some
effort to show what the gaps are what
the needs are and justify this work and
i have not seen it i i think you like
you you should wait greg right like at
the end of this like presentations block
we should get something and if not we'll
go get it at the charter right because
like we cannot
without a problem statement we cannot
charter anything so i agree with you
yeah but i mean you go into use cases
without a problem statement it just
sounds like word solid good thank you
thanks
go ahead
hello
my name is gion mishram with verizon
and i'm on this slide deck what i plan
to go over
is this this state of multicast for usa
domestic operators
and then how how the um
from a technological perspective how uh
how the current state of multicast
applies to
msr-6 and how msr-6 can at a minimum
meet these base requirements
that that are used
with
technologies that are deployed today
throughout the united states with
operators
next slide
so from a video transport perspective
use cases um
we have uh and this is just typical uh
distribution so we have the contribution
network where we got uncompressed video
and then from a technology perspective
um
the what's used there is rsvpte
and within the contribution network uh
for um
for for a
seamless and
lossless video delivery at the source as
well as at the primary distribution
state as well rsvpte at the secondary
distribution on the right secondary
distribution
network we have rs
and that's
going to
um the access networks fixed broadband
and
as well as
mobile broadband
access networks
mldp
as well as pim
next slide
so here we're also sharing uh the ver
the variety the distribution flow from
at the very left showing the uh
uncompressed stream so the higher
bandwidth video delivery uh at the left
and then it's the primary distribution
network compressed video and then at the
very right uncompressed video
you know so the stream of of how how the
tr how video flows from left to right
and the uh
and the
technologies used on the left side rcpt
primarily has been used uh for domestic
operators
for the primary distribution as well
rsvpt and then as you get to the
secondary distribution
it's it's majority mostly um
mldp
uh for the for the uh distribution
next slide
this slide shows as well similar and
it's it's showing the distribution
structure starting at the very left
contribution so rsvpte at the
contribution layer primary distribution
rsvpte
and then mldp at the secondary
distribution layer and then out to the
access networks
mldp and
going to enterprises as well as
fixed broadband and um
and mobile broadband next slide
this in this slide shows
just a depiction of the of the public
internet an operator network in the
center showing the core core network
access aggregation and then the access
network mobile broadband and fixed
broadband so
so uh with that mvp mvpn um
uh pmsi
ptas that are deployed mldp is the
primary
i would say majority of
customers
in us use mldp and point to multipoint
that's probably the primary pta that's
used uh rsvpte at the so at the source
uh at the at the primary contribution
network as well as the uh
the prime primary distribution
and then mldp point to multipoint uh
multi-point to multi-point mldp
is used in the financial industry
primarily um and there may be some other
smaller use cases but
uh point to multi-point uh mldp is
really one of the
primary use cases that are used pre used
for most customers within the us
can you stay close to the mic because
people cannot hear you at the back oh
sorry thank you
sorry and um
so as as far as um
asm uh versus ssm you know from a
technology perspective and and uh pim
binder uh
majority of uh
uses from customer networks asm is still
what prep you know widely used on
customer networks um there have been a
lot a lot of enterprises as well as uh
customers migrating from asm to ssm
still
rarely
not use as much with the
bi-directional trees uh point to
multi-point to multi-point pea trees
within the core
so overall primarily it's really mldp
point to multi-point is really the
primary uh
technology that's used you know for the
p-tree within the within the core
um out to the uh from the core to
aggregation out to the
how to enterprise customers
um within the united states
uh next slide
so this this slide shows this private
mpls uh so in here just very similarly
uh the uh as far as the uh
mvpn use cases for uh
the types of uh
pmvpn um
p trees that are deployed and it's still
primarily primarily mldp is really the
primary and asm is still is used
primarily for uh customers enterprise
customers as well as uh
customers uh you know through provider
customers
that exist
for um
the other uh
the other mvpn uh
ptas that are used
it's not as widely uh mdt safy and some
of the other ptas are not as widely used
and here in this case as well
uh multi-point multi-point for uh pin
binder trees that is not not as widely
used financial industry
is really really the primary use case
where uh pim bider is used for
multi-point to multi-point trees
next slide
so this this slide shows uh msr6
requirements for ipvtv delivery uh so
really so here what uh what i'm trying
to depict i guess is uh
lossless video delivery and uh fast
reroute that's really one of the primary
uh
you know
primary technologies used for rsvpt fast
reroute is really a critical requirement
for uh primary distribution
as well as the
content distribution networks where the
source feed comes in
and then as well as with mldp
multitask only fast reroute
next slide
here we're showing as well with msr6
requirements for legacy technologies uh
uh mldp and rcpt so here as well we're
just showing the uh
requirements so mplc fast reroute link
node and paths path protection 50
millisecond reroute and then uh for mldp
um
mo multigas only fast free route as well
as local protection
next slide
so
in this slide uh what i would like to
show is here uh
a um
the preferred choice of transports has
been really for for operators in the us
it's really been between mldp and rsvpte
and primarily majority of the use cases
have been has been used as mldp within
the secondary distribution
networks the primary distribution and
content distribution has been rsvpt for
the uh path protection
um
and and with link node and path
protection for um
disjoint trees as well as um
where you have we're
requiring triple play services where you
have multi multiple pads
um
next slide
in this slide what i'm just showing here
and this is just for as far as msr6
requirements it's a comparison between
mldp and rcpt and and just showing the
benefits of mldp which is really
scalability
and as we're looking at our as we look
at msr-6 and how how that is its
similarities with rcpte
and and the scalability which is
important which which mldp provides
where you can have a single tree with
with mldp point to multipoint where our
cpt requires entries so it's a tree per
vpn so not as scalable so a requirement
that
we'll have to we'll
we'll play into at msr6 as we when we go
through the summary of
requirements
next slide
this slide shows as well comparison so
the so the benefit of rsvpte and that's
really where you have redundant pads and
you need and you need uh link node and
path protection uh for triple play
services as well as live live protection
um the use of um rsvpte with that 50
millisecond uh failover and lossless
failover
next slide
so here as well we're kind of digging
into so with rsvpte the live live
protection requirement
and this and with that you know have
being able to have
the lossless
zero delay
failover with live live production where
you have redundant pads
very similar to
live live i guess very similar to net
pre-off where you have where you're not
having a replicated stream uh from the
uh from the ingress to the egress uh
pre-off mechanism where you're actually
uh
sending two streams down to the receiver
end so having that that ability and
protection with the rsvpte
next slide
this slide shows the entire just the
overall end to end stream just for going
from the from the left side from the
contribution network uh
from the source uh through the
distribution so rsvpte
in the core network and at the
distribution layer and then as you get
to the access layer and then and two
enterprises and large medium small
customers uh their mldp primarily used
and then as well uh
i mentioned their triple play services
so wherever we have require
live live protection use of rsvpte
for for path protect link node and path
protection
next slide
so a summary so the goal of this slide
deck really is try really try to look at
uh the use cases and really the state of
multicast within
uh the us domestic
and and the requirements that at a
minimum that would need to be met by
msr-6
and and so in summary here we got fast
free route protection
um
injury engineering separate protected
pads uh scalability as we see with mldp
as compared to rsvpte the live live
protection loss lossless zero delay
and then lastly uh triple play services
next slide
so um this slide what i what i wanted to
share here is like you said the state of
uh
with usa domestic operators and then
srv6 deployments and and as as well as
migration towards an ipv towards ipv6
so so operators we understand in the in
the us you'd understand the benefits of
segment routing and moving towards an
ipv6 data plane
however the deployments have have been
limited
and and here what i what i've thrown out
in a few bullets really what the
requirements and kind of the benefits of
srv600 and pls and reason why you know
operators are looking but we have is has
not
has not been as widely deployed in the
u.s and really and just kind of just
throw it just looking at the bullets
here that i got laid out um
native srv60 airing capabilities with
srv6 with with us with an srh the
benefits of ipv6 flow labels so having
an ipv6 data playing the gains there as
well as data center um
deployments where where you have you're
using an nv nvo overlay vxlan type
overlay ip underlay where you know you
can take advantage of srv6 in the
underlay and then ipv6 benefits with qos
and then lastly mpls elimination so
there are there are some gains that usa
domestic operators can gain with srv6
and having an ipv6
data plane
next slide
so here's the last slide just a summary
of solutions that exist today
for multicast i've just related as
related to srv6
so
so today
mldp rsvpt they can be deployed in
parallel with our srv6
we do have
segment routing
related uh solutions that can be
deployed such as tree sid
and then
bgp multicast and bgb multigas
controller those are as well options
that that exist today that can be
deployed with segment routing
um and then as well bit
beers available and then lastly and just
kind of really a segue into the
solutions for msr6 is is the new
technology that we're going to be going
over today in subsequent slide decks
thank you
okay so we're opening the queue but
please clarifying questions only if you
agree or disagree with the presented
cases we can discuss it during the open
mic thank you
greg uh go ahead greg mursky
hi uh
gregory erickson um
i have the question about one of your
requirements lossless and zero delay uh
switchover sure
how you envision to achieve it
sure
so
i think the lost lossless and zero zero
delay
that would be achieved with uh redundant
paths
uh which is which is some which is
something that
is is deployed today that you can if
with redundant pads where you have a
replicated stream
similar you're going into the solution
space so um i think if i can refresh a
question greg is that a non-negotiable
requirement would that be a fair
phrasing of your question
yes okay all right thank you greg okay
thanks
hi tom hill bt i was curious really in
in the sense that i think a lot of the
use case for this is obviously going to
be in video distribution
um a lot of the benefit really from
doing this will be in video distribution
i was curious
how you envision
msr 6
helping
with tivo style services so pausing live
television for example pausing live
streams and catch up on that
um is this the suggestion that we
continue falling back to unicast or do
you feel that there's some benefit here
that can be made out of a new protocol
with regards to that
i i think that as well that question may
be answered as we get into the solution
space but i think with the questions
here
require regarding the requirements
if you could rephrase the question i
think let's say related to requirements
as we will be talking about solutions i
think in the subsequent slides
okay can i give a quick answer to that
yeah
they're
we're attempting to to restart work on
exactly that solution description we
started that in beer so the stateless
options all have ways to improve those
solutions and we haven't put that
specifically together for msr6 right now
okay thank you greg go ahead thank you
so i'm just trying to understand what
you presented here like i said in the in
the absence of a problem statement what
you showed us what the current art is
and your objectives are to be just as
good
as opposed to gaps that you're trying to
solve
well i think in this slide deck what the
goal was to show
what
what's what's deployed the state of
multicast as it's deployed today
and the requirements that we have today
and then and then in subsequent
solutions that are presented how these
requirements match up and at least at
least at a minimum saw you know provide
those you know meet these requirements
so i was actually just laying out the
requirements so i'm hearing yes the
objective is to be just as good of the
existing solution yeah that's exactly
yes is that an admission then that
there's no gap there's no real problem
to solve
well i would say in this in this deck i
was not actually
the goal of this deck was really to show
existing and meeting the requirements
and not not gaps i think in the
in the previous slide i think they were
showing some of the gaps so
actually i didn't see any it was again
just all solutions that we are have
already seen yeah so
again so what you're saying here is
you have no goals to do better you don't
have gaps from existing deploy to what
you're trying to achieve
and your objectives are to be just as
good what we currently have
i i don't see any other answer from what
you've said and what you've presented
thanks craig thank you yep understood
thanks greg thank you thanks uh tell us
please go ahead thanks i i think uh on
the agenda point itself you're running a
little bit late so like any time is
going to cut into the solution which
you're totally fine with okay so just
we'll try to get the use cases
requirements stuff nailed down as much
as possible thanks
okay um welcome i wanted to get down a
little bit from all the
details of the use cases to what i'm
extracting as the operational use case
requirements based on my uh kind of
staying around for 30 years with this
technology multicast and um what what i
learned from that next slide
so i think there's really one
core requirement which is that we want
to have a simple ipv6 integrated
end-to-end stateless ipv6 multicast for
ipv6 only networks
and what ipv6 networks i think all of
them we saw a lot of them being
listed here in the prior slides but i
also think that this technology is
quite valuable beyond the large service
provider networks but maybe not for this
point in time i did send notes out to
the iot working groups which i think
should have interest but maybe another
time next slide
okay so um beer has often been more or
less implicitly being brought up in the
questions raised here
so let's do a quick refresher on what
beer and ipv6 networks how they would go
together without new work
um so the beer architecture was not
specific to any particular
encapsulation but the working group i
worked on one particular header which is
pretty much in my view of the world
optimized and designed for mpls networks
to go along with them so it has all the
necessary header elements to support
mpls networks from the label uh to the
traffic class field for mpls the qs and
so on there's also additional header
fields that are not needed in mpls
networks just in case somebody would
want to deploy the same header in a
layer 2 forwarding network only
that's to my
experience mostly stalled because all
the people working toward getting that
deployed are really interested in mpls
networks so the solution
for supporting native ipv6 only networks
that are not running anything else is
not to be native ipv6 only networks but
to run the beer forwarding plane hop by
hop in parallel to the ipv6 forwarding
plane
and that basically depending on whether
you can implement beer hop by hop on
every router or just on a few routers is
either two layers or you know if if only
some routers are upgraded you are
running
end to end ipv6 over hop by hop
beer over then hop by hop ipv6 tunnels
so three layers of encapsulations so
that is that is working quote in the way
fine
as a lot of other technologies we've
done is working fine next slide
to the end that
my experience has been that
something really is working for ib
multicast when operators want to apply
use and deploy it successfully
when it is
trying to be as close as possible to the
unicast technologies that are being
deployed in the network and so i wanted
to give some very high level elements to
say that what beer is doing is just not
the right solution for a native ipv6
network because it doesn't match these
expectations
so we started in 89 with native ipv4
multicast and by adding that to uh ip
with exactly the same packet headers and
as much the same behavior somewhere we
needed to sneak the replication in of
course
we were allowed to reuse and extend the
whole ecosystem of ip and later in the
same way of ipv6 starting from the sdks
the socket apis the qs diffserv insert
rsvp acls all the layer 2 encapsulation
that ip headers were built for ipfix
ipsec i can go on
uh i've actually spent part of my career
of implementing or you know architecting
a lot of these add-ons to ip and i'm
just you know
really scared of having to do all of
this uh you know four beer
every time that comes around if we have
the option for existing ip networks to
have a native ipv6 solution as well
that would allow us to have the same
benefits of reusing all these ecosystem
elements that we do understand how to
build them for ip
we also
did try to come up with cool new novel
multicast routing mospf and dmvpn and
after a couple years we figured out well
that's going to be not of fun for the
operators so we had to revert to a
multicast technology that is
using all the deployed unicast routing
protocol just so that multicast became
operable
then basically we had perfectly well
working mvpn services for multicast in
mpls
networks which wasn't using mpls
encapsulation but which was using ip
multicast encapsulation they said yeah
the customers are buying it it's fine
but it doesn't meet our operational
expectation of our network which is
purely mpls forwarding plane base so we
spent another 10 years
to build native mpls forwarding plane
for those mpls networks well done total
duplication of ip but that's how the
market space works right you have people
who run native ip networks and you have
people who run what i would call native
mpls networks and
i think in that respect the beer has
kind of evolved over the time that the
working group has been trying to be
focused to deliver something running
really on the mpls solution and the
proposed draft for this you know ipv6
over beer over ipv6 is kind of an add-on
that
is really not meeting the requirements
of native ipv6 networks clarifying
questions
yes uh
greg asked already what is native ip yes
next slide
thanks for the
intro right um
so wait a second was it the next slide
go go back
did i
go back maybe no
okay i'm trying to yeah i have my
homework my dog trying to remember which
slide it was on
let me get back to it if it's not i'm
sorry i'm maybe a little bit confused
here um all right
that's that's next
no no i'm just trying to remember which
slide it was on right so um the
stateless stuff is was was the other big
thing right so let's uh talk about three
key parts right so me um the most
important part is the operation
simplicity troubleshooting and
everything else
where you eliminate a lot of complexity
of the stateful so
um
there's a lot of of aspects here in
details that i think we can revisit if
we had more time in the solution slide
but of course it was also the core
reason for beer the scale and
convergence is where effectively the
same
applies and in the solution slides i
think you should see that by going away
from what i call the flat bit strings
that be introduced into uh you know more
advanced processable
encoding of the
destinations or the destination trees we
think that we should be able to achieve
a lot better scalability
which we need for the large service
provider networks
and that would obviously also be
considered to be one of the core
requirements
the the additional thing that
people often forget is that when we want
to
replicate the ecosystem we want to get
all the way up to the application layer
and that means we need to get into
socket apis and socket apis have been
extended to support ipv6 extension
headers for ipv6 20 years ago with that
rfc number that's barely visible on the
slide whereas extensions for other
new technologies um that we have done
would be
much uh
yeah would have to wait another 10 years
that's kind of the minimum time we've
seen
next slide
no
sorry can you
i can
i'm kind of
no you've got the old slide deck
i i i gave you a new slide
press
i gave you the one one
so that's what you have
yes
okay looks
sorry for that
okay there we go
yeah okay thanks that was the slide i
was missing sorry
okay
so express divs over over beer right so
native ipv6 networks means ipv6 networks
with or without srv6
obviously the srv6 networks are the
first one that understand the benefit of
stateless
traffic steering so they would obviously
like to have exactly the same type of
stateless traffic steering for the
multicast traffic but in the end native
ipv6 source routing by hop by hop end to
end native ipv6 multicast hop by hop and
end to end so that basically means on
every hub you're forwarding the packet
based on the rfc 8200 rules including
the rules that apply to ip multicast
packets the rules that apply to source
routing and the fact that you're doing
that source routing based on
a
route header with the source routing
segments like
we have two of them for unicast right
srh for
um srv6 and the other one being the
ripple header for the iot networks so in
the same way we would have an extension
header for multicast source routing that
meets exactly the same native ipv6 hop
by hop routing requirements
i think it's also important to have the
daywi day one support for path steering
and strict and loose hops which
basically means to be uh equally
efficient in the stack
whether you have a support by hop by hop
for the technology or only on a few
incremental hops and then um you can
lose the loose uh loose hops so the more
scalable i mentioned before that's the
best effort and what we call the traffic
engineering path steering solution the
modes and that's where i mentioned the
flat bit strings have in our simulations
been shown to require more copies to be
sent to receivers for the same set of
especially small receivers things so i i
detail that in one of the solution
drafts that we have
and then of course very important as you
saw from guyan's slide deck the
integrated support in the header for
service guarantees beyond best effort
which so far has been punted off to
other working groups so combining these
things is really difficult when you need
to do these things hop by hop
and you only have or one routing header
that actually can be processed hot by
hop so that's why i think it needs to be
integrated and the rest is terminology
and and and a sample picture next slide
which is the last slide there
um i think
the really cool thing that we can do
with ipv6 by being something that has
been defined all the way end to end is
also for these constrained control
networks like a data center
enterprise iot and other spaces go all
the way up into the host using ipv6
um socket apis
and
then the typical use cases you start
with are the big data center
servers that are routers themselves so
they have all the existing routing
requirements
to to be able to apply the existing
technologies and then there is uh
additional requirements when the hosts
are not routers so that's kind of the
these last two slides the two high-level
requirements derived from the
operational experience and the need to
have a native ipv6 network
where stateless multicast isn't a
second-class citizen by using some you
know non-ipv6 native technology
i think then there's the magic inside at
the end
so yeah
right
that's what we would like to have right
msr6 keep it simple and make ipv6
multicast great again
um so native state is multicast for all
ipv6 networks
um stateless ipv6 multicast into
applications data center industrial so
on and reuse and share all the good
things that beer has done
all right thank you questions thank you
okay thank you uh greg mursky um
i have one question okay first question
is
what is alternative to
native ipv6
because it appears that in your
definition in native you include support
ipv6 and a service 6.
so
no i'm saying native ipv6 means
forwarding hop by hop on rfc 8200
whether it has
an srv6 extension header or not okay and
then what is
opposite to native ip well if you're not
going to do forwarding hop by hop on rfc
8200 rules
then what do you do
um i don't know i for example beer right
beer is a different forwarding plane it
could be mpls it's a different
forwarding plane if i'm going to do
forwarding based on an mpls header
that's not native ip if i'm forwarding
based on beer it's not native rfc 8200
forwarding but then we call it mpls
network if we yes if we forward on
ethernet it's ethernet if it's call an
mpls it's intellis it's not native
ethernet it's not native to mpls i think
that's that's why i'm having this
picture up we've used the term native
for ipv6 and multicast and so on for for
a long time to basically recognize that
we're doing the forwarding based on that
particular um forwarding technology so
ipv6 network okay
then second point is that
stateless
and simplicity of operation is counter
to each other
because
it's much easier to debug and
troubleshoot stateful network rather
than stateless
that's a statement and i think we we we
can make votes for that or so but i
think
there are people on the other side of
that equation as well thanks greg thanks
dolos thank you steve
so a lot of people are not joining the
uh thing so i'm just like keeping it in
my head so i apologize but greatly
appreciate if you can actually join the
app on there so i have stig tony p
uh
greg
joel
that's what's in my head
thank you yeah stigma yeah i'll remember
to use that sorry um
so it sounds like this is very simple
and just plain old ipv6 but
i suspect that you know you have to
encode new things in the packets you
need to process them and how you do that
processing is very different from ipv6
i know we haven't took the solutions yes
but no no i mean it it it is basically a
a steering header where we need to
represent a set of destination or a tree
not necessarily through flat bit strings
but through better encoding for the
scalability you know it started with rsv
sorry with brte you know me recognizing
the scalability issues but then we did
the simulation comparison so that's one
thing the other thing is the other
header elements that we want to make
sure obviously it needs to be native v6
so we need to have the multicast
destination address in the header and
then i'm thinking we also want to have
the qs header elements for example from
what we see we would need in a stateless
mode of operation for that net but
that's a lot of details that i didn't
want to put in the requirements they are
requirements in my opinion but i just
had them very high level yeah i suspect
that there are some complexities once
you start digging into yeah they're the
solution drafts where where more of
these details are being being set so
that's the other side
yeah thank you
tony p i don't know if you just went
away but
okay joel halpern from erickson
if i hear this
claim that somehow this is native ipv6
and somehow that means this is better
one more time i may scream
doing forwarding is hard
there is a thing called ipv6 forwarding
this thing that you are asking for in
this bath involves representing a tree
and involves replicating packets along
different branches of the tree properly
processing some different representation
whether you put that representation in
an mpls stack in an srv6 stack that
doesn't yet exist or in an extension
header it is still not the same as
current native existing ipv6
slides and
[Music]
[Applause]
go further back further
more further yeah further
further right so um joe um
we we can argue about the native um you
know i think nobody here rejected the
term when we were running around for ten
years saying uh go native for ip
multicast and we called it native ip
multicast so you know i'm calling it
native ipv6 um that's that's fine if if
if the discourse gets down to how we
call it let's just call it you know
uh rfc 8200 forwarding which is what
ipv6 does which is what this solution
does it does rfc 8200 forwarding rules
and then um basically no not all the
type of encodings are the same if you
have you know ipv6 in beer in ipv6 that
is not matching um what and uh
i'm still calling it a native ipv6
operator with an ipv6 only network wants
to have right so so that is
i mean why the heck are we having srv6
stateless source routing if we could
have done that with mpls as well thank
you very much right and that was of
course not acceptable for operators of
native ipv6 networks they wanted to have
a native ipv6 source routing solution
for unicast that's as simple as it goes
greg shepard representing me
uh
i can't match what joel won at his
emotional level was was brilliant thank
you joel um i feel all of that watching
this presentation so much misrepresented
of what happened in the beer working
group
what happened with this work along the
way but we can go specifically to the
host stack
because
beer is not a
routing protocol it's a forwarding
paradigm
beer says nothing about ip beer says
nothing about mpls
so all these
all this baggage you're hanging on the
discussion is a is a fabrication and
there's a misrepresentation at best
what's happened in the other group but
in the host stack when you say this you
know can't be done take 20 years it's
been done
i'm not employed currently and i'm
actually unemployable and after this
conversation i'm probably going to
make that concrete but uh
we had an aws uh beer overlay
infrastructure four years ago
all host-based
so to say it can't be done or it takes
20 years is is
at
at best it's black's imagination
and at worst is completely disingenuous
um greg um can i ask you a question like
as like your chair
so uh can i interpret your answer as
like you know beer is kind of open to
other kind of encapsulations than what
is defined like you don't have to answer
it like as like the chair itself but
like do you have any thoughts on it oh
i'd love to okay because we
when this work was first presented it
was presented as transitional
and we made it clear we're not changing
the forwarding plane for something
transitional when they admitted the
authors that they they wanted to go to
native beer
and when that didn't work and get their
work actually accepted we had this
whack-a-mole process around round round
round but what i made clear is that
an encapsulation sounds great we're not
changing the encoding
the the ads were clear when we had the
beer buff
this is probably a not an exact quote uh
from aaliyah but the message i got was
don't with a forwarding plane
so we had to get it right
and when you get it right and you cut it
in stone
you're protected
and
taking those bits and shoving them
somewhere else and violating layers and
calling it integration it's not
it's not honest discussion
and it doesn't represent
good architecture
it doesn't represent the layered
architecture that's have made all of us
successful here
so
i'm i'd love to have a technical
discussion
but
i have yet to be able to maintain a
technical technical discussion on this
topic
when there's so much disingenuous
garbage being flung out
and it just becomes word salad until
what we through attrition we finally
just give up
i'm not giving up
i don't understand how it is a uh you
know architectural garbage or what the
other words were that i forgot uh in in
your words when we are having an
equivalent
you could say of a multicast version of
an sr v6
routing header for ipv6 packets so
which is not markedly different than
encapsulating over v6 hot by hop with
the next protocol pointer no i mean it's
basically still hot by hop beer
rfc8279 based forwarding rules there
there is no reference for the forwarding
from you know uh a received beer packet
to send out your paper required
please let me finish it
so please let me finish
you the sentence
have an encoding that can stand
independent it can be encapsulated in
any way it
makes it flexible for the entire
community
when you integrate it
and violate layers you create a
dependency
i can't answer because you didn't let me
end uh finish my sentence
okay uh so just a point of order here i
think we are way over time for like the
solution thing so we need to have the
discussions because i think it's more
important that we hear about the
problems requirements disagreements and
hear about some solutions so we're
cutting
all the solution presentations from the
agenda and turning this now into an open
mic so
um queues are open uh
everybody makes statements and uh told
us if you want any other proponents to
come join you here that'll be good as
well well i think everybody from from
the team can say that obviously the
majority is remote so it would be good
if you if you show that it's the queues
are open so i think i think one of the
important part is to see that obviously
we have a strong opposition from the
people who want to protect their market
segment um with what the beer solution
has done um what whatever you say around
that and so one the solution draft intro
slides for example would list all the
vendors operators um and and and people
that we have seen to support our
direction and i think in the past and
you know in recent work many people in
the ietf stood up and told me
that obviously you know when there are
differences about
interest in solutions then we just
should check if there is a critical mass
in support of a particular solution and
if it's technically viable and then you
know if a competing solution is there
the same thing applies to it but uh not
using um more or less shame arguments to
try to um suppress uh competition i
think that's what i've been seeing here
thank you
maybe perception john go ahead hey um
i'm sorry for the uh non-technical
content
but there's two things i need to say
um
you remember the
note well that we all look at the
beginning do you guys remember the part
about addressing each other respectfully
i appreciate that um
everybody here feels passionately about
the subject
i don't appreciate people calling each
other's id you know
ideas garbage etc please don't do that
[Applause]
second point um
i was really uncomfortable with the
cultural appropriation in the graphic on
the final slide
i don't know if other people feel that
way but um
i
it made me feel bad
we actually had t-shirts in 95 that
we've been handing out you know native
ip multicast so i thought it was a
reminder of good old times if good old
times has become culturally insensitive
i apologize
okay 20p juniper
so we had this ongoing conversation you
know because when i look at the solution
draft it's basically beer packed into
you know extension header that's all
there there is to it when i looked at
you know
what was in the material for this buff
so can i answer to that no let me maybe
you know make a statement
so we had this running conversation for
three years and i don't think none of
the stuff that we said that the process
you know was run through resonated much
but that's still you know that needs to
go into the minutes okay
so i understand you know people in love
with srv6 okay
i understand
some people may already have the stuff
in silicon as was i think admitted in
the last bath all right
and as yakov said nothing prevents you
to take an itf standard and do unnatural
thing with the stuff and you know deploy
it
the point of idea is not to wide wash
silicons and not you know have people
fall in love with technology and just
build yet another thing because they
love it okay
the substantial problem i think that you
have is that
those use cases can be all solved with
the stuff is there today
okay
and you better really show a good gap
analysis because then i'm all open right
but there is no gap analysis all these
use cases can be solved and we can start
to drill the stuff but it will take too
long
having said that
um
and we had this conversation
violating layers always sounds like a
great idea okay but it isn't the costs
later in deployment
are insane if you really care about
running this ipv6 native
implement something like beer on
ethernet and you can send an ipv6 frame
over that
over a beer header without
or with less overhead that what you try
to create here okay
doing all these layer violations as was
explained i think we went through the
whole rigamarole at the end and we wrote
the technical justification and we laid
out what you you know causing with all
this stuff
this is most likely violating six men
and it's clearly violating beer
architecture doing that stuff all right
it stomps probably on three different
charges of three different groups but
you know it's
out my pay range that's the 80s
so that probably should go into the
minute processes have been run we're
like fourth or fifth time at the same
place
my point is made and i don't need an
answer because we had this discussion
and whatever came back was always the
same thing right the discussion about
encoding the encapsulation
took forever took us nowhere
so
tony thank you so like if i summarize
your comments you would want to start
with the gap analysis for the existing
protocols before you go any further
would that be a fair summary of what you
said yeah because otherwise what are we
working on just another variant because
somebody likes it blue rather than red
and you know additionally breaking seven
layers with always you know like this
it's more efficient this is like the
first thing i fire my junior development
developers about right if they go to the
code and start to make it more efficient
right so but i mean this discussion has
been going on for three years so we
didn't make any point
obviously the parties are pushing the
point but that is for the minutes no s
no without any motions as the technical
layout
and someone that cares because this
stuff fed me for 30 years and hopefully
will feed me for 20 years right and i
will have to clean up this stuff
operationally with people deploying it
thank you let's go ahead and um
greg if you can step up to the mic uh i
think you're first in the line
okay so when told us answers um 20 piece
question
thanks
you're on the mic line yeah
sorry it was so much and i just took the
notebook a little bit later so i may not
be able to remember all the points you
were trying to raise right so now this
is not meant to be beer this is meant to
learn from beer and it's meant to be
what i call a native ipv6 solution call
it just an rfc 8200 compliant ipv6
network solution
and yeah
i think many people also tried to sell
into ipv6 network
traffic engineering with mpls and ipv6
network operators on the unicast site
didn't want to have that so that's why
an rfc 8200 forwarding based
solution was done for traffic steering
in unicast and this is basically um you
know one
comparable option for multicast right
and as far as layer violations um no
it's not about the layer violations it's
about the functionality that you get and
the operational complexity of having to
troubleshoot fundamentally different
forwarding planes right and i i gave the
list of functionalities in the ecosystem
that are being used in conjunction with
ipv4 and ipv6 multicast that long list
that i had there and if you don't have
hop by hop and ipv6 or ipv4 packet
header with multicast then you can't
apply these ecosystem functions
hop by hop forwarding wise for your
packets and that is what applies to beer
sorry
um the shoe song of the
song go ahead
hi can you hear me well
yes
okay thank you some response to uh
previous comments the first one is that
uh i think maybe people just remember
some arguments or discussions in a beer
working group but the msr work is uh
very very beyond what we have done in
beer before and you will go into the
solutions there are multiple different
methods of encoding
uh based on sales routine
and that i think that is
not belongs to the scope of beer and the
second point is that ipv6 is not
relevant
it's it's not only one type of
encapsulation and it's not technical
preference ipv6 has its capability of
extension which is more friendly to the
host initiated case and also more
friendly to the flexible encoding we
want to support here
so i think the these two features are
the core of this uh
this bulb so i think people can give
more uh
pay more attention to the solutions and
they will see the benefits there thank
you
okay
hi there tom hill from bte
there's a slightly concerning trend
of claims that are being made
and they're not just being made within
this both certainly the first two
presentations made this claim
but it's been made very far and wide in
a lot of standards organizations
that operators
such as myself
fully understand the benefits of srv6
this is
very common
at best that statement is contentious
at worst it is an outright fabrication
this is not clean cut yet
it definitely is not cleaned up so
whenever we get told that lots of people
are really interested in this i don't
believe it because i don't see it via
any of the other means by which i speak
to my peers
and the other folks that run operators
run networks
in an operating fashion around the world
my problem with this is
a lot of that has been
used as a foundation for what you've
presented here today
and my concern is
in doing so are you starting from the
right position
or are you starting with a poison
chalice
can i
you tell me when you're done so no no i
i think this is an excellent point and i
was using so first of all i've i've been
just fighting for these 30 years just to
get you know equal treatment for
multicast in the networks wherever they
are
and not be degraded to a second-class
citizen as far as technology service is
concerned for the multicast right and
that basically
was learned from the examples that i
said where you know we started saying
hey we think this multicast technology
is better why don't you just use ipv4
multicast and mpls network works
perfectly fine we don't want to
re-implement the stuff for mpls and mpls
networks didn't like it by the way what
are you running mpls or ipv6 in your
network for the forwarding plane of
unicast
it depends on which network but okay for
them for the most part the main core
network is mpls forwarded yes with
respect to um srv6 i i don't have any
strong opinions right i'm just caring
for the multicast solution i think it's
important to understand uh that the way
that uh ipv6 not srv6 or so
um consider to be source routing to be
done is with the source routing
extension header we don't have only sr
v6 we also have an equal extension
header
for constrained iot networks using
exactly the same mechanism some
interesting routing detailed differences
right so this is not only proven once
but proven twice if you don't like it um
and and and and you think there's a lot
of problems with it but let me ask you
this is this a reason that you want to
forbid other people who want to have it
and want to have an equivalent multicast
solution to not get it is that is do you
think that's that's the correct
prerogative what you have what we're
asking about here is forming a working
group right yes right so how much work
should be invested in something where
one of the foundations of this
has been
up
to seem more important or more useful or
better than it is right but and for for
us on the multicast side right it's it's
uh on one hand uh
using the srv6 example as as the most
easy way for people to understand that
this is you know what what source
routing is doing the reason for doing
stateless multicast um is a lot more
foundational and a lot bigger you know
stronger in my opinion than for the
source for the source routing in unicast
srv6 and a lot of these things can be
shown with the benefit that beer gives
you an mpls networks i i completely
appreciate the the use case for
stateless multicast forwarding
completely i also completely appreciate
the use case for ipv4 should be a
service
and we should be building ipv6 only
networks everywhere
it is the
the long long contentious problem that
srv6 has caused within this industry and
to make statements to say that operators
really like it
is
is troubling at the beginning of when
the work starts so
we really need to make sure that we
don't rely on statements like that right
we really need to make sure
that they
that we aren't misleading anyone here
in the sense that if there is already a
protocol that has problems we don't want
to build on that again yeah but this
this is not i mean
except for the rfc 8200 mechanism of
using extension header um in ipv6 as the
code native however you want to call it
way in ipv6 to do source routing and
then you can have kind of up with your
solution right if you don't like like
like srv6 that's fine but nobody it
tells you that you have to use it you
have to judge i think the benefits of
the
mrh header that we're proposing for
stateless multicast based on the benefit
of of those multicast use cases right
and so i i gave a couple of of these
things right the statelessness as the
biggest benefit operationally and then
the new encodings that what we want to
do 10 years after we've done them for
beer right which was 10 years ago what's
the best we can do now we think 10 years
later we can do better right for those
ipv6 network for a longer term solution
right so so there are a lot of technical
details that
to a good extent would have been in the
solution drafts right and not only the
requirements there were scale
requirements and so on that drive
i think a significant set of differences
and yeah the the native forwarding is is
a big important one i mean there are all
these ecosystem things right i've done
all these qs thing diffserv insert acls
ipfix all these things and it's just
terrible to having to repeat that for
let's say just a beer based forwarding
plane instead of an actual ipv6
forwarding plane that just has source
routing added to it
right that's it's it's the whole bloody
ecosystem that that you're starting to
replicate it's already hard enough to
replicate the ecosystem from unicast to
multicast believe me i've done it for
all those those pieces from unicast
addresses to multicast addresses
and
you know but now we know it after after
20 years having figured that out for
multicast
you know we know how to do it and the
source routing is you know just
complimentary for that
good luck
thank you tom
andrew go ahead because uh you are in
line before the other people got on
thanks thank you um andrew um liquid
telecom um wearing that hat and purely
that hat
um
so
if i'm going back to the previous point
that i was making
can you hear me now that better
[Music]
okay there we go um
so going back to the previous point that
i was making
the fact is that that particular use
case i was referring to earlier
shows
srv sex
over the public internet unencapsulated
that's what the slide showed right
that is a clear
violation of 8754
clear clear cut it's got nothing to do
with the solution your use case is
premised on a violation
and you refer multiple times to
20 years ago
x happened
20 years ago we looked at source routing
and went this is a bad idea
and we deprecated it
and the security issues when you are
showing me use cases that are premised
on a violation
and then when people say but it might
not be srv6
but the simple fact is
is that that's what this is called msr-6
right
and i also have to second what tom said
because i keep seeing people saying
srv6 wonderful everybody's using it here
etc but there was a slide in the deck
earlier
that said there is very little
deployment in the united states that's
what the slide said
and to me i read that slide as
we came up with something people aren't
using it now maybe this will get them to
use it
this to me
reminds me of
a solution looking for a use case
and
i i cannot see how that is
in the benefit of the industry
i cannot see how that
fulfills the ietf mandate of make the
internet better i don't see it
thanks andrew so first of all i don't
think we have any kind of i would call
it native multicast and i think that
term has been established by you know
all these contributors in the ietf 25
years ago
when we started doing pim um we have
very little of that in the internet the
best uh that that we have are kind of
research networks and everything else is
in controlled private networks including
service provider access networks to
deliver iptv to their customers and so
on right so as far as the extent of
where multicast today goes and could go
with source routing i think it would be
very much the same spaces and i think
that's a great and excellent discussion
to have and if one of those slides was
misleading to say it's the random part
of the open internet that's not part of
the places where for example we have
existing uh multicast solutions that
just don't scale and are you know harder
to operate than the stateless versions
that's fine then i think there is a
mistake in that slide um
as far as judging
the market space and
the set of participants in the ietf that
are proactively working toward the
solution because they believe in it i
think that's certainly one of the things
to figure out
i would just like to understand to what
extent um people who prefer a different
technical solution and
all their arguments why their solution
is sufficient should have a significant
impact in the decision
um i think it's secondary
anything that's technically not working
is fine but you know if we have
competing opinions about market space
solution i think we should just vet for
each of them if they're technically
solid and if they have
enough support in the ietf uh
positively but not kind of you know
count the negative against it
if it's not technically but based on a
different you know market solution
preference
for the use case it's not just like we
have msr6 and then we're looking for
some
real deployment or something like that
no it's a very wrong
because the especially for the first
case for the teleco domain this
advancement of 5g technology and
commercial deployment
and then we with them like the tick tock
just like the the chinese version of
like instagram youtube those type of
things social media and you are going to
see the receivers on the
10th millions maybe i don't know it's up
to 100 million or not
and also over the 5g network so we are
seeing the problem with that and seeing
the dynamics scalable those type of
things and then we uh we try to get the
you know something to handle it's uh
we're looking at existing uh schemes
solutions and then we found
some discrepancies and then that's why
you know this and also for some other
use cases the same thing thank you
thank you attention yeah uh david go
ahead you show at the bottom of the cube
but you are on the top so goodbye
uh david lamparte um i'm just gonna
offer my confusion in in case it helps i
i came here to working well to a session
called multicast source routing and
i feel there's a huge
piece missing where
there's actually a discussion about
what how exactly does changing the
the location of determining the the
receivers for the multicast group
how does moving that to the source
actually
help us how does it was it what what
does this provide what is
where is this coming from i'm seeing
like
uh
a half solution maybe that is prepared
work in progress um
but
where did this start why why is it
better where is it coming from uh
so so yes so i had some more detailed
solution slides so when we all started
the beer work right so what what was
basically happening is that um at that
point in time service providers were
saying hey um you know this whole
multicast stuff is so difficult because
we have to troubleshoot multicast state
on the p nodes in a service provider
network so you know right now we think
we have enough bandwidth we're just
doing what we call ingress replication
so you're sending out every packet that
enters the service provider as a unicast
copy to the egress and then we said that
doesn't scale right um and we can give
you a solution that gets rid of that
multicast state on the transit hops
right and that's basically what beer
became and as i said in my you know
evaluation of how the working group
evolved is it's just the way it
implemented the forwarding plane aspects
especially the encapsulation very
optimized for mpls networks and there i
think it's great right so but but but
but this all goes back to what we
recognized after we did all the mpls
multicast natively for 10 years and then
service provider came back and said well
thank you for spending 10 years in the
itf on doing mpls multicast but now we
decided not to deploy it right so um
that's that's basically one of those you
know at least my origin story for beer
okay but um
so
now i'm asking myself
is this just moving the problem from
source discovery to destination
discovery
like
the argument chain is not computing for
me that is the what i'm trying to say i
mean i'm happy to take it offline so we
i think you know i don't think this
answer fundamentally would be
different for beer and msr6 right so
this is this is all about you know i
think high level um about the ipv6
networks versus mpls networks and then
also newer and better encodings of the
source routing things kind of if if we
break it down to you know fundamentals
thank you thank you david um uh yi song
please go ahead
you song is remotely
yeah
mobile and as an operator we have uh
deployed at more and more and
as introduced in the use cases we have a
very large
network and the potential multicast
services
that uh should we do live
streaming is also very huge
and the existing flow state solution for
the multicast cannot afford the
overhead for so huge days for the
funding cost and the existing stateless
multicast cannot
afford the large-scale network
topologies
and
come
combine all of these requirements we
i think we
need a simple and unified solution to
solve this
and
that can uh bring a new opportunity for
the multicast i think so
uh we want to uh form a new working
group
that's all thank you
you need to speak up your volume is
really low
oh can you hear me now
hello
yeah we can hear you jinbin go ahead
just speak up a bit
shin bin will come back to you uh chang
go ahead
hey chang hello
hi
uh thank
you yeah we can hear you go ahead
okay okay so uh i'm muchan chung from
channel mobile uh here i would like to
provide the two points of my
observation
uh the first point
i think
ipv6 traffic is increasing
rapidly
for example i just mentioned that
channel mobile's
4g and 5g network
ipv6 traffic
has reached
42 percent
about two years ago this number
was less than 20
so i think it the
uh
the traffic ipv6 currently ipv6 traffic
is increasing dramatically
so
we have reason to believe that
in the near future
almost all traffic will be ipv6
uh for operator we should prepare
uh for
the situation
so
i think a lot of discussion
we have
done
just now
i think ipv6
native
network
is a good solution for operator in the
near future
and the second
point
is that the
multicast traffic is increasing
rapidly
especially
some
internet live video
services such as
tick tock in china
which brings a large
number of
multicast traffic
but the zoos traffic
are currently
using
unicast solution
in
telecom network
this has caused
a huge waste of
bandwidth and
but you know
the
existing multicast
solution
cannot
support
cannot solve this kind of issue
so
from my point of view we need to
embrace ipv6
and support new multicast service
we need a proper
multicast
protocol
for
this
situation i think itf
should prepare
for those new requirement new
situation and
as a
operators
engineer
i suggest
i have considered
the new
solution
especially
friendly
for ipv6
on
multicast
protocol thank you
okay can you hear me
yes yes we can hear you okay
okay now uh in fact because there's no
time for the presentation of the
solutions i here just to give some this
the
suggestion about this the solution
in fact in the solution it
shows
in fact in the used case it shows that
the prt is not a skill enough to satisfy
the requirement and the user cases
presented
so
in order to solve this
in order to solve this issue we in fact
we need a solution to combine the srv6
segment and the beta stream
to propose the new multicast solution to
satisfy this requirement
because this solution is based on the
ipv6
so this
in fact there is the new solution uh
cannot covered by cx mark sabrina and
uh and the beer so we think we need a
new venue to dis develop this the new
solution so this is just a consideration
for the msr both
okay that's
just some this is the
thinking about from this the solution
and that's the proposal for the ms r6
thank you
harley
yeah
this is the hall from mrsa
we think ms6 is a meaningful topic
as discussed today
appreciates the presenter clearly
defined applicable scenarios for rmr6
and its native ipv6 nature
so as a vendor i believe it will be
great to form a complete solution or
music
and believe that a separate working
group is more helpful to promote the
process with this matter thanks
go ahead genji
yes um here i have four points to to
cover here
basically it's for the the both goals
the first line is just
based on the use case uh based on the
gap analysis that being done before and
on the meeting alias so it's going to
say
to answer the question is the problem is
a real problem yes it is
the second one is like well
unfortunately the technical solutions
um
have no time to be presented but also
those things it's going to show
you know uh this is something should be
done in igf and also it can be done in
itf
but the third point is like uh
people you know from today's participant
to their discussion and also from the
alias discussion from the sign meeting
discussion it shows
an its sma's subject matter of expert
are showing
a demonstrate a great amount of interest
on the topic
the fourth one actually is like uh is
that the reasonable to deliver something
yes it's actually you know if you
look at the uh the sunni hexa there the
team just
use p4 i think they did the
implementation and the emulation
for the msr6 uh
uh be i think so basically means it can
be done so for out of forcing together
well i try to answer the question for
the boss goal so yeah we do hope
uh this one msr6
um can be accepted or in to be done in
the idf thank you
okay i'll abuse my chair power and
hijack the queue to relay the message
from the chat from
dinner fairness is saying what does
multicast scale because receiver state
is not tracked if you require the source
to know about the receivers it's a
non-starter look at st2 from mid-80s
where source
initiated trees failed
yeah go ahead yeah so
i think one of the core understanding is
that um
in large networks most of the multicast
is sparse that's why we started with
what we call pimp sparse node right so
the total number of receivers isn't you
know the same as the total size of the
network
the size of receivers typically is
fairly limited and they're randomly
distributed based on the service that
you have and you don't want to have for
each of these small groups relative to
the size of the network a state on every
hub that you need to troubleshoot that
is one of the core value proposition
exactly what you basically you know
started doing beer for and
so i i think putting this into question
would equally put beer into
question do you know like is it the same
topic you're talking about okay please
go ahead
this is dino well torilis your core
author said
um
your co-author said that they need to
support 10 000 receivers are we going to
put 10 000 receivers in a source route
give me a break okay so maybe it's maybe
your answer is it's not 10 000 receivers
it's a thousand receivers made off of 10
routers okay so at that point the
replication has to get to the 10 routers
and then they each replicate to 1 000
maybe over the ram that supports native
multicast that's achievable but that's
not native multicast you'd have if if
you are sensitive to the native
multicast state all over the network for
those 10 routers then you have to use
overlays it's that simple that's the
trade-off no so i mean
the way we're thinking about it think of
a simple service provider core network
with whatever number of pes is the
number of
um you know uh destinations that you
need to do source routing for right and
one of the recognition that we had is
that um obviously it it may often be
good enough to just have something like
um
256 bit which which is kind of the most
likely standard in beer
and then we get a uh
an improvement by a factor of 256 by
just sending as many copies as we need
to reach all the destinations divided by
256 but obviously you can now have the
easy problem that especially when you
have small groups um you're sending to
10 receivers but you actually need to
send 10 packets so you didn't have any
multicast benefit because you're using
flat bit strings and each of the 10
receivers is in a different bit string
and that's basically what we run for a
large service provider topology as
simulations uh to show them but it's
it's it's you know easily understood
when you need to break up um the
receiver space into flat bit strings so
and those things can be done better if
you do better than the fat bit string
encoding which would be the next
generation of the encodings there i i
think there are way too much detail yeah
i think so yeah thank you thanks for
listening thank you responder you want
me to sit down
i think sit down would be good thank you
thank you uh uh shuru zhang please go
ahead i don't know if i got your name
right please go ahead thanks
yeah can you hear me
yes please speak up
yeah here is zhang jieru from china
unicom
um there are
there have been about uh 40 smart micro
networks and some byteball
night work notes
are built in isrb6
they are unicost
we really need new multicast for
large-scale networks which is based on
srv6r
ipv6
for me
msr6 may keep the knight work simple
this is meaningful for the operator
uh this is
the
we need the use case okay that's all
thank you
no no we will we'll get to it like
please we have some stuff to do um
sigily please go ahead
can you hear me
um
i i i think you have some feedback
issues so if you can type it into the
chat it's probably better
we are really running out of time so we
cannot troubleshoot this so please just
type into the chat thank you
uh no
is that okay
you're coming across very low but please
go ahead
uh okay thank you
uh i am sijali from beijing university
of
uh post under telecommunication
occasions
uh we would like to make an introduction
about our project uh in over a minute
but uh we didn't have
it enough time so we put it in this
section in the this classic okay
and we had a hackathon
a project for msrbe solution in this
ieft introduction uh it means in
includes two parts
the first one is gp4
implication of msrbe
under the emulations of msr6pe based on
intel tofino sweeties
we have brought the value
validation of
mrs r6
based on open source and we hope to see
further progress of this work in
ift
itf
that's all thank you for listening
thank you uh so we just want to have uh
tng did you want to make like a really
really brief statement on that thank you
for mentioning about the 1027 receivers
consider it's like a reasonable actually
it is
for our first case and you look at the
5g 20 uh 24 23 247 after the definition
about the five uh five mbs nihana
architecture from the ups and upf up to
ginobi and you look at that one that
link will be used to multicast and then
the number of genovi can go like
ballpark 30 000 and beyond so it is
reasonable thank you thank you thank you
so i just want to do like a quick poll
of the room because like i think a lot
of the disagreements coming from
the problem itself like not in the
solution space like even though we did
talk a little bit about the solution
space so i just want to run a poll like
please get on your
phones computers to
raise your hand or not raise your hand
um based on if you think the problem
statement itself is clear so the problem
to me is always clear so
i'll just run it for another minute or
so to figure out where to go next
because we don't want to
do things too ahead of like what we have
to do so thanks
can i ask
what do you mean by is the problem clear
the is the problem to be solved clear
from like
as as in
you agree that it is a problem or that
you understand what the statement of the
problem is do you understand what the
statement of the problem is right like
as
described by the proponents like so you
may or may not agree that's a problem
for you to solve but do you understand
what they're trying to solve thanks
that's what and hence the question right
if you don't believe you understand
what's a problem to be solved then you
do not raise your hand or pick do not
raise your hand which is equal under not
raising your hand or raising your hand
for not doing it
another minute
okay going once
going twice
pull close so um we have a very i would
say um evenly split room and like remote
room as well so it's i think um our
conclusion as shares and uh uh
to be confirmed by the ad
is that the problem statement requires
for the development um before we go any
further with this without like you know
going to a charter or something i think
we need to spend a little bit more time
um like narrowing down the problem
statement right and we can continue the
discussion on the mailing list
and try to make progress over there
instead of like trying to go through the
working group charter questions because
it does not make sense right because if
people don't have a common understanding
of the problem it doesn't make sense for
us to ask questions like do you want to
form a working group right because we
don't know what your former working
group for so
thank you all for coming we'll continue
the problem statement discussions in the
mailing list and
i hope to see you in another meeting
thank you
[Applause]
like
and like make it