okay uh welcome to uh privacy pass at uh
iatf 114 uh thanks for uh joining us
um
just real quick uh here's the note well
um i think you're probably well
acquainted with this but if you
need a refresher you can take a quick
look at this
reminder
a couple reminders for this meeting is
it's really helpful to
join the
uh meeting with the on-site tool so you
can join the queue
and so you can um
so we record your attendance as well
uh so please uh join the on-site uh
meeting
thank you also
please uh wear your mask except when
speaking
um
i think that's the main things
uh main thing i want to do right now in
terms of administrative trivia is to get
a note taker
can somebody please volunteer to take
some notes for us
be really helpful let us get us through
our agenda we do need a notetaker
going once
thank you
what's your name
marcus thank you
um so we have a a pretty full agenda
today
um
so with initial discussion about
deployment experience uh status of the
core documents
talk about
rate limited token
and then key consistency and discovery
are there any uh
additions modifications to this agenda
that anybody would like to make
okay then i think we can jump in dude
uh i want to note that we have a full
agenda for our very short session uh so
i will be running a timer to include
both presentation and questions on each
topic
can i
oh yeah you can if you yeah why don't
you do that yeah yeah yeah let me do it
all right
hi everyone
hi everyone um
it's loud
i'm tommy paulie from apple um
one of the co-authors on some of the
documents we have here and i'll be
presenting some of our current status on
implementation
and deployment testing here for privacy
pass
uh so first i wanted to point to some
implementations this is of
the base specs so this is the token
issuance
um and authentication scheme to
request
and redeem tokens
there are
a couple different open source
implementations if you want to try these
out there's one that is uh written in go
that cloudflare has that implements
client origin
a tester issuer either as one thing or
separate things
and you can use it for all the basic
variants and you can also test out the
rate limited variant
so this is a very useful tool for doing
interop there's also a new one coming up
from raphael
that does client origin an issuer for
the basic variants so
if you're interested in building stuff
these are good resources to interrupt
with
but beyond that
we are also doing some non-open source
implementations um and actually getting
some deployment experience
at apple's developer conference
in june we announced that
we want to replace captchas with
uh private access tokens which is really
just privacy pass but that's what
people wanted to call it for branding
reasons um so it is just privacy pass
doing the basic uh
type 2
a publicly verifiable tokens
and so we
introduced a broader developer community
to this concept and pointed back to
privacy pass if they wanted to get more
engaged
so hopefully that will kick up some
interest and i've already seen people
looking at this a little bit more
uh so yeah we're trying to increase
awareness
we are allowing developers of apps to be
able to
do token
uh issuance and redemption
as well as anything that's running
within
uh webkit environments on ios and mac os
will automatically be able to support
this now
and so we have attestation and token
issuance uh
that we're working with to try to kind
of get some tests going on in this
ecosystem but the goal is to have it
grow and to have
you know
other
attestation work and i look forward to
seeing
some of the previous privacy pass
browser extensions etc be updated to be
compatible with the current specs
for the test that you can do with what
we have on ios and mac os
currently
cloudflare and fastly have both deployed
token issuers
that are specifically for this initial
demo experimentation phase
these are the two issuer names you can
find more information about them
uh for our devices we are doing some
attestation with an icloud server that
is doing device and account assession
but
other platforms and other browsers and
applications can do other types of
attestation that could work with these
issuers just as well
ios 16 and mac os ventura are currently
in beta and they
support all the client functionality
automatically
if you want to explicitly test this out
if you have one of these
devices
that's on these builds
there are some demo origins like this
cloudflare one which will just always
say i'm going to give you a captcha
unless you can show me a token
but
also in the wild
there are
deployments that are actually starting
to use this and try it out
in non-forced cases
uh before i get into that just what is
supported here um on our client this is
only doing type two and i believe that's
also the case for
the uh issuers that they are doing the
publicly verifiable basic token types
that are using rsa blind signatures
for our client we are doing a split
origin a tester and issuer model
and our client supports
either
specific origin or cross-origin tokens
and there are some limitations around
what we'll do in the web context we only
accept token challenges and redeem
tokens to things that are first-party
domains within a web context
so that random
ads and other stuff can't start
trying to poke and get tokens out of you
so
cloudflare managed captchas is one of
the things that's already doing
requests for tokens and so
currently right now with these beta
builds
we're seeing 35 000 tokens being issued
per day
um
and 16 000 tokens that are being
redeemed so that you're seeing kind of
like the client fetching batches
um and not necessarily spending them all
but then
we're actually spending them
later to say okay get around this
capture because i've already done the
attestation
and i don't have detailed latency
information but it's all
very very minimal it's not really
impacting
any user facing
things so far so
i believe that's it for these slides
i guess if there are any questions
about the specific implications let me
know
there are links to the open source
repositories if you want to play with
those too
so
please try it out do interoperability
testing if you want
all right
seems like there are no questions that
we can probably
move on do you have anything
oh you are oh nick oh sorry i didn't see
it
hey nick
uh nick dodie cdc um
thanks for uh both translating and
giving us some implementation experience
uh i'm curious whether
well i have lots of questions but i'll
just ask one i'm curious whether we've
considered um
the problem of of over-reliance that
that some developer might just say hey i
hear apple uh can attest to all the
devices uh therefore i'm just gonna
block access
permanently to anyone who who doesn't
get one of these tokens and whether
we've considered sort of either protocol
or implementation implementation changes
that would
withhold a certain small percentage of
the time to encourage the developer to
to realize oh i can't get this the 100
of the time
that's a very very good point um so we
absolutely don't want
reliance like that
um in our communication publicly we're
like do not do i mean you should only do
this if in lieu of a captcha and you
always need to fall back
but of course advice does not give you
everything
one of the nice things is that this it
will not happen all the time and i
didn't go into those details but this
may be something we want to uh
add advice to in the documents probably
i think in the architecture document
let's talk about the whole ecosystem
so
uh first there's a there's actually a
human level toggle where some users can
disable this
but beyond that our attestation system
will
rate limit you but even on the device
we have
limits of when we are willing to get a
token or not so
um we will
not randomly but if we see
more than a couple token requests in a
minute or based on what process you're
in
we will just ignore some requests
so
you certainly would not be able to do
a site that did 100 and have it work but
i agree that this is something that we
should talk about more and i think
having something randomly
uh not due at some percentage of the
time may be one mitigation for this
all right okay thank you tommy
cool
and i think next is the bass drafts yep
and i think i'm
going to present that and then chris
will talk remotely
about the rate limited
unfortunately
a lot of the authors have
conflicts or in mid travel right now so
all right i am still
tommy polly but now i am speaking on
behalf of more co-authors um
chris wood and john iangar steven valdez
amongst others so we have three base
drafts here we have
uh the architecture
which essentially describes the
different models for using privacy paths
and deploying privacy paths
we have the authentication scheme
which is
how an origin can request tokens and
clients can redeem tokens and we have
the protocol
which defines two flavors of token
issuance one that is privately
verifiable and one that is publicly
verifiable
um so this is just a slide to go into
some of the recent changes
uh overall the authors think that these
are
pretty uh
pretty mature and um from like a
technical interrupt standpoint we think
they're
uh done and we'd like to get this moved
along but i think there are things
uh around wording that we still need a
bit of work on but we hope to
consider a last call soonish
some of the recent changes
include for architecture uh clarifying
the trust model removing some old text
that no longer really applied around
parameterization
and adding a bit more text to talk about
centralization although i know there are
other
documents proposed that will go into
more depth there
for the auth scheme based on the
discussions at previous meetings
clarifications around how to support
multiple origin names being related to a
given token were added
we added guidance around how to
handle and process token challenges
clarified what you need to do in order
to prevent double spending depending on
what type of
token context was being added
and we also added test vectors so you
can
confirm your implementations
and uh for the basic issuance uh very
little changed uh there were a couple
things really to clarify
fully how the token verification worked
some of it was just more implicitly
saying oh
you know how blind rsa works but we
tried to make it a little bit more clear
and we also
talked about
how you
get the token validation keys from a
consistent location
uh so
just the the couple open issues we have
that i want to bring up today uh one is
actually just based on an early ayanna
review um ayana has been doing a great
thing of actually before we go through
the full process they are reviewing all
of the working group documents that have
iana considerations in them that are
being presented so
thank you ayanna for doing that
um
so the auth scheme document defines a
registry of token types and the basic
protocol issuance defines two types in
there privately verifiable and a
publicly verifiable token
and the auth scheme also reserves some
types to be able to do greasing
of uh making sure that you can accept
unknown types within your off challenges
and redemption
um ayanna did have a couple questions
uh we were not clear
where this new registry should live
they assumed it would probably be on a
new privacy pass specific page i think
that makes sense so the document now
says that i would like to hear if anyone
disagrees with that
or what we should call it um that's very
much a bike shed and then the other
thing is what do we want the review
policy to be for new entries into this
uh what we put in for now
in the pr is specific specification
required
and so that would involve designating
experts and then requiring that you have
a stable spec in order to allocate this
i don't have particularly strong
opinions this seemed like the right
thing for entirely new
token types because
you have to have a pretty
full specification be able to implement
against it but i'd love to hear opinions
of the working group
if they can find their enqueuing buttons
chris would hello
uh yeah this seems fine um
i don't know if we need to say anything
more about the type of um
like analysis that goes into a token
type before it actually winds its way in
the registry like hpk for comparison
establishes a registry for like
different algorithms and it just says if
you want to be on this list you need to
like have to meet certain properties
um
certain security properties we could say
the same exact thing here um and then
require that the documents like
demonstrate in some way i don't know
what that looks like that they actually
meet the properties but provided that
that's i think that this is a reasonable
way forward
and provided that
who can assess it or able to reason
about the correctness of those
properties
right i don't have the text in front of
me right now that i propose but i i
think
there is a sentence there that it's
recommending what the experts review and
i think it says something along the
lines of like it needs to meet the
properties but
i think that's the interesting sentence
to
make sure is correct that it
that's the right advice to the experts
yeah cool
thank you
hey
there's kenazi yeah quick warrant
enthusiast
uh how is this encoded
uh these are not
varants this is i think a 16-bit
field because having a dependency on
violence here isn't really necessary and
that's a lot of token types
all right just the the really nice thing
about those is um
even though you have 2 to the 62 only
ever use 10.
and but what it means is that you can
like do whatever you want for
experimentation and it makes life a lot
easier so you don't have to do specific
communication required and let people do
i i try to push back on specification
required for the entire space because
the current it encourages people to just
skip by and out together and squat on
values if they don't want to have a
publicly accessible spec
so you're talking about essentially we
you know the approach of reserving some
experimental
values that can never be allocated no so
i mean mt would make this argument
better than i can
but that wasn't a great success in tls
right um
so
rather having somewhere where you can
just have like
uh what's the term um
not
yeah temporary
allocations i think that's fine and that
i think is compatible
with
specification required as far as i
understand like you can ask for a
provisional and then you can always then
say nope
we
is try to make this a bit more like the
quick one you don't have to go full
warrant even though i love that but
saying
some of the space is specification
required and some of the space you can
do provisional but provision all the atf
ioni reserves the right to yank it from
you at any time okay that way
you avoid all these problems and that's
been working really well for us that's a
good clarification just to make in the
ion notes okay
alrighty
if we have no other thoughts on that
then i'll move on
oh
um the other
issue uh number 141
is it was more of a kind of
architectural question about
what
what does the ecosystem do if
the
access attestation service which could
be the issuance service as well
uh stops doing the right thing so like
it just says you know it starts giving
out tokens willy-nilly to people who
aren't trusted or who didn't actually
solve their captcha or didn't meet the
bar
um
and
uh i think chris made this
nice little hilarious spider-man's
pointing at each other
of
essentially the failure modes here are
origins are saying i'm getting
some you know bad traffic
coming in
that you know clearly didn't actually
shouldn't actually have passed the
attestation checks it says issuer you
know why are you giving me these bad
tokens he says hey you know the tester
you're not
uh
doing the right thing and
the tester can be like oh my my checks
are fine how do you know that that's
actually fraudulent so we you know we
definitely need a way out of this
um
and this was chris's suggestion
for how to address this
in general this should be a rather
exceptional event
um
and
essentially the ecosystem needs to come
to
some recognition of hmm
you know either
give away for origins to report back to
the issuer
that things are uh not working as they
would expect
um
so i think we do need some extra text on
this i don't know chris if you wanted to
comment on what you were imagining
here
um
i didn't have anything specific in mind
right now um
because as you say
as i sort of jotted down here i do think
that this will likely vary based on your
particular deployment whether or not
it's like joint to test your issue or
split a tester issue or
um and what the configuration is of the
different parties
um
we might just note that you know if if
things go awry um
signals start firing for reasons that
they shouldn't start firing or whatever
um but this is an exceptional event and
you know applications should deal with
it
some way i don't have a very eloquent
way of like stating that some way right
now but
hasn't described anything specific
yeah it eventually needs to be at the
point where if
some party like an ancestor issuer
starts doing bad things they kind of
need to be kicked out
of who's trusted by the other parties
that you know the origins yeah i no
longer trust this issuer or the issuer
says i no longer trust this a tester
because i need to make sure that my
origins keep trusting me
um yeah so essentially the roles of
running a token issue and service
um
involves
maintaining your credibility and you
need to make sure you have some way of
getting feedback to make sure you're not
doing
you're letting bad clients in
and it's
it's not like i guess if attestation
fails once
that that uh that particular tester
should indefinitely be untrusted i can
imagine scenarios where like
i don't know there's like a zero day and
like somehow for some reason like at
that station is like subverted or
whatever compromise but once that's
patched everything's back to normal so
um
i mean we can work on the text offline i
think but i don't think the
the implication needs to be like
permanent adjustments to the trust model
just like temporary or grounds or
mitigations or something
right someone compromises your tester
if that's detected they take themselves
out of the pool until they can patch
their zero day and then they come back
yeah yeah
cool
all right and i think
that's it um so those are essentially
the main two
open issues we already have the ayana
pull request out so we just need to
refine that based on what we have here
and then we want to add this
architectural text
and beyond that we think these basic
ones are pretty good to go so
if there are other pieces of feedback
on those i'd like to hear it or if the
chairs have any comment around
what they want to see
i think the last call is a good way to
also
initiate reviews
sophia
yes sofia sally from brave um i was
having two questions the first one is
it seems like it's going to be alaska or
at least that's what it's been asked of
is this waiting also on the
standardization or the last call at
least of the documents that currently
are sitting in the cflg like the bo prf
or the blinded rsa that com they're
currently kind of dependencies on the
privacy past main trust
and the second thing
um the new current architecture of the
privacy pass protocol was kind of
introduced on the december of last year
and now it's there's an introduction of
different
issues and the testis and origins and
how they can interact with each other
and there's different ways that they can
either collude with each other or as you
just mentioned in one of the issues the
different entities can be compromised
has there any any interest of actually
of the working group to provide a more
formal documents of any security slash
privacy analysis of the different kind
of attacks and threat model that all of
those entities um colluding or
interacting with each other composed
cool uh for the first one
maybe chris will have opinions on
the relationship with cfrg documents i
think that's kind of up to the chairs of
privacy pass and cfrg to how they want
to coordinate that i think
those other specs are stable enough that
it would be fine to run them in either
order through that but maybe
ship them
off to
the isg or i irs g review
around the same time
that's fine um
and then regarding the other one i think
the document does you know try to talk a
bit about how you do the analysis um if
there are specific things you think the
architecture
should add for extra analysis then we
could add it but i i think it would also
be perfectly fine to have
further documents analyzing different
aspects of this i think in general these
split
models
that we have
for
privacy pass we have for
oblivious http we have for using mask
proxies they all
share some interesting properties and i
know there's even discussion in perigee
about what are the terminologies we use
for doing privacy analysis there so
this certainly should not be the last
word
on how we talk about this architecture
and think about analyzing these
deployments
yeah um
a quick question about credibility of
the entities that you mentioned can you
say more about those like is that going
to be part of the solution
which entities are we talking about that
the parties that involved in this like
you talk about credibility of those
parties if they misbehave or something
like this right
right so
in the architecture
you have the entities that are redeeming
tokens right and they don't
they don't necessarily get to see all
the information about the clients
themselves
and so they have a trust dependency on
the entity that issues tokens um
and
that entity's credibility comes from the
fact that either they are doing their
own attestation or checks like maybe
they had issued captchas or they had
done some verification
or they are working with one or more
other services that can do that
attestation
of the clients um so essentially it is
a transitive
trust
and credibility chain
there and it's essentially up if an
issue is going to work with multiple
forms of attestation it needs to make
sure that
it
is only using kind of good enough ones
to meet the requirements of the origins
that it's serving tokens to
okay that makes sense thanks
and chris
um
yeah just to respond to the crg thing
because you've kind of called me out i
think both of the blind rsa and the vpf
documents are basically ready for
research last call in that group anyways
now the process does take longer
unfortunately um and the iot than it
does in the ietf so i guess it's up to
the chairs as you suggested to figure
out how they want to
stack things and what the pipeline looks
like um
i don't think we need to block on
uh
you know
having gone through all of the process
in zfrg um
to move things forward here
um on the the
comment that was just raised at the mic
regarding like parties behaving
correctly
um
i mean i think pictures sort of par for
the course like we expect article
participants to uh implement the
protocol honestly just like we expect
tls servers to implement that protocol
correctly and not post keys to twitter
or whatever
um
and things break down when they don't
behave correctly and this is a little
bit different in that we're trying to
design against potentially malicious
parties in the protocol um but for the
most part like the the behavior has
specified we we just sort of assume that
they're
um they're following that classification
cool
all right i think we're probably out of
time
okay uh thank you tommy i guess uh you i
believe chris wood is presenting the
next session section
[Music]
okay um
all right uh
so uh this is an update on the rate
limited privacy pass issuance protocol
that we presented last time it's
actually undergoing uh adoption an
adoption call right now i kind of wanted
to um
take a step back from the internal
technical details uh of the protocol
because it is admittedly
somewhat complex um
we tried to spend a lot of time as the
editors of the document clarifying what
the different functions of the protocol
are what the different steps are and
what not um so here i just want to kind
of talk about the high level uh
motivation for the protocol um what the
different properties are in terms of how
much state it has a different uh
different pieces or different
entities in the vertical and what the
what the desired or end resulting
privacy properties are as well as touch
on some open issues
um
so having said that
uh as a recap because it wasn't covered
in the um the base protocol document um
privacy passes now
as a
architecture is composed of two
sub-protocols one of which is the
redemption protocol this is the the
protocol it's run between client and
origin for the purposes of redeeming
tokens and it's based on
well-established http authentication
mechanisms
origin will challenge the client to
present a token
or may challenge the client to present a
token
with certain parameters
in that challenge and the client if it
can satisfy the challenge uh presents a
token in response with its retried
request
issuance as the uh
complementary protocol which effectively
takes one of those token challenges from
the origin
and runs a protocol between the client
to test or an issuer for the purposes of
producing a token that's bound to that
particular token challenge
and
we've sort of arranged things such that
all of the complexity in privacy past is
sort of encapsulated in the issuance
protocol because there's expected to be
sort of like very few implementations of
these
like one implementation of uh one client
inflation that serves many clients and
so on whereas
um
uh
we on the flip side and the redemption
side we wanted adoption to be incredibly
easy so for example in the the basic
type two tokens that tommy was referring
to earlier like consuming and verifying
a token is as simple as verifying an rsa
signature um
it's really straightforward
okay um
i'm gonna walk through sort of how these
two things work in concert
so on the left we have the redemption
protocol
which uh as as day before the origin
produces a public keynote challenge the
client and the output of this uh or in
response to the challenge the client
produces a token
um and the desired property here is that
the origin learns nothing about the
client beyond whether or not it was able
to present a token that it satisfies the
challenge um
that just one bit
on the right hand side um the the
issuance protocol is again takes its
input this public key and challenge
turns it into a token with this advanced
between client to tester and issuer
which for the basic issuance protocol is
just a blind signature protocol or a vrf
protocol or whatever
and the desired property here is that
the issuer learns nothing about the
client um uh in particular that it
cannot link successive requests from the
clients together they each appear as
independent unlinkable requests
unfortunately the basic insurance
protocol does not provide an obvious way
to do
per client rate limiting
so say you had an origin that wanted to
to limit the number of times a
particular client
you know had access to a specific
resource
um it cannot do so because by definition
the only thing it learns from the token
is whether or not the token was able to
present
a valid token and the issuer the only
thing that the issuer learns is whether
or not um uh like token issue and
succeeded it learns nothing about or
there's no concept of state anywhere in
in the issuance flow
um this is problematic because there's a
lot of interesting applications um where
rate limiting is quite useful uh and we
don't want to fall back to things like
rate limiting based on
shared context across clients like ip
addresses
you have meter pay walls where you might
want to limit the number of times a
particular client is able to access some
content you might want to dampen the
damage or activities that spots from a
particular bot form are doing
and so on
rate limiting is used in many many
places so the question we ask ourselves
for this draft is how do we add great
limiting support to privacy pass without
compromising on the security and privacy
properties that were discussed for the
basic instruments protocol
and before talking about sort of the the
mechanism just uh i want to give a quick
reminder for how like rate limiting is
commonly implemented in practice um
uh
typically it's typically done with some
algorithm called a token bucket or a
leaky bucket depending on which textbook
you read where
the token bucket or leaky bucket is
driven by two independent processes um
there's one process which is like the
person trying to access the particular
resource that consumes tokens from this
bucket
and they're only able to access the
resource if there are tokens available
to consume
the
the other process the token
representative process will put tokens
back in the bucket at a sort of fixed
uh recurring rate
and the rate at which you replenish
tokens in the bucket determines the
overall rate limit
and so the way these two things interact
the dynamics of the the interaction
between requesting and consuming tokens
determines um effectively how clients
are rate limited
internally um uh you can think of this
being implemented uh using like a simple
hash table so
um when a you know a token replenish
event comes in
the token bucket will just identify the
context associated with the rate limit
and then increment some counter
associated with that particular context
so in this example
there the context is an entry in a hash
table there's a previous count and
associated with it and just bumps up the
count by t et is the replenish account
requesting a resource does exactly the
same thing
uh to identify the writ limiting
contacts and then go into the hash table
but now it just decrements you know the
the counter associated with it and if
tokens are available process the request
if not drops the request on the floor
okay um
so uh we wanted to implement basically
this functionality uh under certain
constraints um
uh as i was saying before we want to
maintain the security and privacy
properties that we originally had in the
protocol
in particular we don't want the origin
to learn anything beyond a bit and this
bit in this case is
not only was a client able to produce a
token
but
the the client was able to produce a
token without exceeding the rate limit
that is that is effectively the bit um
any other sort of state at the origin
side could be potentially used to track
clients and so we didn't we didn't even
want to explore that avenue
um we also wanted adoption to being as
simple as it was for privacy pass um in
fact the the tokens that are produced
for the rate limiting version are
indistinguishable from uh the tokens for
the basic issuance protocol both
verified with the rsa
signature um we wanted the issuance
protocol the thing that actually
produces tokens and necessarily deals
with the state aspect of rate limiting
to be as close to stateless as possible
of course it can't be stateless because
then you can't be really rate limiting
someone has to have stake around like
how many things uh how many tokens were
uh issued for a particular client origin
pair um and the question is like where
is that state captain how is it
enforced and whatnot
but we want to minimize the state
because we want to you know make it easy
or
to actually operate an issue or a tester
um and importantly for um certain
deployment models of privacy pass we
want to make sure that neither a tester
nor issue are able to link client origin
pairs together so right now in the basic
issuance protocol there's no there's no
information exposed to the issuer during
issuance um but if we
now consider a rate that's applied on a
per-origin basis
someone intuitively someone has to see
uh or enforce some state based on a
specific client and a specific origin
but we did not want that state to reveal
anything about a specific client going
to a specific origin like you know my
my laptop going to example.com or
whatever
um
so uh we're trying we're aiming for
something that's close to like oh db and
odo and sort of style where one party
sees like half of the half of the
equation
okay
so functionally what the issuance
protocol does in this document is it
extends the basic issuance protocol with
a couple of new properties and features
um the first of which is that the issuer
that's actually producing a torque and
necessarily learns the origin associated
with the token challenge
because
this is necessary because the
rate limits that are sort of enforced in
the system uh
potentially differ on a per origin basis
so the issuer needs to learn which
origin is this token request for so i
can pick the right limit and and respond
accordingly
um
a testers in this uh in this protocol
have a uh
much more responsibility than they do in
the basic issuance protocol um beyond
just relaying requests and responses
back and forth between client and issuer
they now learn what we refer to as a
stable mapping or as sort of uh
described earlier the rate limiting
context on a uh that is specific to a
per client secret and a per origin
secret and that word secret is important
as a tester doesn't learn
like client a is going to example.com it
learns client a is going to random thing
and then client b is going to different
random thing
um
and this state is necessary uh because
this
in this particular design of the
solution we have the attester
is the entity responsible for enforcing
the rate limits on uh per client and per
origin on a per client of origin basis
which we think is a reasonable trade-off
given all things considered
um uh and also differently from the
basic issuance protocol token requests
can now fail because if you try to issue
a token or request a token you've
exceeded your rate limit the tester will
just drop your request on the floor or
as actually happens in the protocol it
returns an error to the client
okay so uh functionally just sort of
walk you through what the issuance
protocol does at a very high level
without describing any of the technical
details internally those are best kept
to the draft uh this is just the
issuance protocol the redemption
protocol remains the same
uh
you'll notice on the left as input to
the client there's some public keys
there's a challenge there's some other
things um uh specifically a secret key
skc that the client maintains for uh
sort of its uh
for all of the rate limited requests
that it has to um or that it wants to
access through a particular tester
because that's that's the perkline
secret
um
but anyways uh there's a request
response flow between client to tester
and issuer and what the tester does uh
using this request response flow is
basically compute the stable mapping or
compute the rate of any context
um decrement
uh
account associated with that rate
limiting context and then
respond to the client with an error or
with the token request accordingly and
there's a lot of like complexity in it
or there's a lot of stuff that happens
behind the scenes to actually do this um
this actual stable mapping computation
um and do it in such a way that the like
the
a tester can't like try to
figure out what the client was after um
uh with without the client's active
participation
mary if it's okay um can i take
questions at the end
she's in the room i can't hear okay
thank you miriam
um
uh as a result of this particular design
um the the way state is split across the
the various participants is as follows
the so as before the basic issuance
protocol the origin keeps uh sort of a
constant amount of state in particular
it just keeps the token associated with
uh the token or the public key necessary
to validate tokens
uh clients maintain uh state that's on
the order of uh the number of servers
that they want to
request
a testers now maintain the most amount
of state
on the order of the number of clients
multiplied by the number of servers that
all those clients are accessing
and issuers only maintain state that's
on the order of the number of servers
that are
actively
configured for this particular issuer
um
there's
i guess
looking at the privacy properties um
uh as before it's not possible for
origen or tester to link any two
requests together to the same client so
we'd sort of maintain parity with basic
privacy pass here but as i said the
tester does learn this sort of state
this rate limiting context um based on a
per client and prohibition secret
um a rationale for why this was
reasonable was that the tester's already
in sort of a privileged position with
the client's ip address and the split
tester issuer model
and as a result it's sort of already
trusted to handle this sensitive
information and has less incentive to
misbehave because if it was gonna if it
wanted to just
do bad things to the client you could
just forward the ip address onto the
issuer
um okay so there's i think there's two
uh there's one sort of fundamental open
issue that's worth some analysis and in
consideration the first of which is
um uh this this sort of state that the
attester learns is effectively
equivalent to access patterns that
clients might have in terms of like you
know using browser in the web
it's unclear
how much leakage is actually um possible
or revealed through this access
through this access pattern um
and in particular
if an attester could combine this
information with certain auxiliary
information for the purposes of you know
potentially learning what origin a
specific client was after
there's another open issue that we think
we have a technical solution for it
would be we would have better technical
solution if we had a partially blind
signature um but we do not yet have one
um so we have a
different solution to it
um details are issue 218.
uh as a status update um to assist with
the adoption call we have two
interoperabilitations one of which is
the open source implementation that
tommy referred to earlier um you can
test it out it supports all the basic
insurance protocols as well as a very
limiting one and we do have security
analysis uh that was done it was
submitted for peer review uh
unfortunately it did not capture this um
this issue just deleted on the previous
page um but we're working right now to
update the the analysis to make sure it
is taken into account and that our
mitigation does actively present it um
and we'll hopefully update the work
group with that analysis when complete
okay that's it um thank you for letting
me run over i'm sorry miria um
i could take your question now
jonathan
um
does this uh consider civil attacks or
are they considered
here
what would be the civil attack in this
case
so i'm a client and i want to overwhelm
an origin so i just say to the a tester
oh i'm a new client now uh give me a new
bucket i have now 15 buckets and i can
do much more traffic
yeah so uh one of the assumptions is
that they access the attestation that's
done between client and the tester
prevents that from happening so you
can't just like endlessly spin up new
new identities as a malicious client and
do that sort of civil attack of course
if like your test attestation does not
ensure that that happens then there's an
obvious problem with this so um
the the protocol assumes that the client
a tester relationship enforces uh or
prevents that from happening so for
example
go ahead
buy ip address so
it could be by a p address it could be
based on like device attestations you
have to like you would have to have
distinct devices in order to do this
it depends on what type of attestation
is done between the client the tester
thank you
mia columbia thanks for the overview um
i have a question about so in the in the
architecture you propose the um the rate
limit is provided from the issuer to the
attester
and the other option would be to
actually provide the count from the
attester to the issue and then the
issuer could drop the packet did you
consider that
yeah actually that was how
the draft was previously written we had
basically the tester send the count to
the issuer
but we determined that that leaks too
much information in particular based on
the counts that the issuer sees they
could figure out whether or not two
requests for
the same client or not so as a simple
example imagine that the issuer just saw
like n requests in a row in sequence and
every single time the count kept going
up it would just conclude that these are
obviously from the same client
yeah i mean yeah so you're also leaking
a little bit of information because you
provide the origin count and it when
it's always the same i mean it's
probably always the same for many
religions or whatever but like there is
a lot like yeah it's a little trailer
okay
yeah yeah that was that was the the crux
of the trade-off um
nick30cdt
i
apologize if i'm repeating this question
but um
have we established evidence from um
people doing this sort of um
account creation or something like that
that this
uh metering will be
effective i i can see how this is
effective for the
um new york times paywall and and if you
want to come up with a complicated
scheme to
to do that maybe that's fine but um i
sort of get the impression that if
you're in the
abuse case
there's not going to be a single
threshold where where sort of yes no is
useful but you might want to know
the the number uh because you could you
could you know um escalate or something
that that's not always going to be like
good or bad in those abuse cases but
that they would want to just use that as
a signal so so do we have a sense from
those use cases that
um a single threshold is going to be
helpful
i think this is still something that's
under discussion in the anti-frauds
community group um uh there's a lot of
uncertainty with respect to you know
what are
the useful signals that can feed into
some anti-abuse system um and what role
like different types of attestation and
rate limiting plays in those scenarios
um
uh
i so i hope the conversation and an
answer to your question evolves in in
that group which is where sort of the
practitioners are iterating on you know
what is the value of this as a
application specific thing um
but uh i don't have an immediate answer
for you because that group uh
you may be you i mean you you're
actively participating in it and has
many conflicting opinions uh from
different people so we'll see how things
feel
okay i'll make sure we can see that
there thanks
yeah to try a minute just like another
author we have
yeah obviously we can't know
what how everything will play out but
when we have discussed
uh with various
anti-fraud systems that would be
interested in using privacy pass in
general
essentially like there's a spectrum from
like the basic privacy pass that has no
rate limit guarantees at all other than
client implementation
and like what they would have today with
actually you know like here is your ip
and here's your cookie and i can like
track you and like this falls somewhere
in the middle so like there are clients
or origins for whom this will
improve their ability to
use this as a meaningful fraud signal it
will not allow them to do all of the
things that they could do if they got an
exact count for a client and
re-identified someone
but it it increases the number
of sites that can use the use privacy
pass meaningfully today and
we'll see if we need to go further than
that but this is
a useful jump
yeah i sort of view it as a another tool
uh
for them to use
a tool that discourages use of like
existing uh tools that might have like a
bad privacy posture with respect to the
client
like tracking based on the ip address
for example
thanks for
thanks for that discussion uh
yeah just reminding the group this
document is subject to an open adoption
call that will end
in about two weeks
so please do comment on the mailing list
and share with the group your opinion of
whether this document is suitable for
adoption
and now we're on to our final section
okay thank you um
uh so this is this is just a reminder of
a draft that we
a couple of us have written on the side
um after realizing that there's this
common problem that's emerging in many
many different application areas inside
the idf oi privacy pass um
in particular
on um uh
in an attempt to distill all the
different ways that you know people deal
with key consistency and discovery and
practice um
and
uh
that's the intent that's the motivation
so this is not like a you know
tremendously new update to that document
but uh just a reminder and uh hopefully
at the end we'll talk about like what we
can do with this if we want to do
anything with it
okay um
so as i said
there's a number of protocols in the itf
right now that uh actually depend on you
know clients having uh some consistent
view of their keys so they don't when
actually using these systems they don't
reveal information that they shouldn't
reveal
um
to a malicious service provider privacy
passes one particular case where you
want the issuer verification key to be
consistent across all clients that are
interacting with that issuer
uh http is another one where you want
the gateway's public encryption key to
be consistent
and it's like configuration in the url
and all these things that provided that
information but it's there um tor is
another example where you want relay
public keys to have be consistent across
all clients
and fundamentally there's like two
common requirements for these different
type of systems which i'll call
unlinkability and authenticity
uh unlikability is informally that you
know servers can't link usage of a
specific key to an individual user and
that authenticity is that when the
clients are using a key it's a key that
was intended for that specific server
it's not like key the key that someone
else owns
that is not the intended server
so why is this important um imagine you
had like a scenario where there's a
bunch of clients interacting with some
server the server makes its key k
available to those clients and the
server uses that key
um
sorry the client uses that key a client
uses that key produces a function based
on the key and sends the the output of
the function to the server
the server um assuming all clients have
a consistent view of this key the only
thing it learns is that this was sent
from one of these end clients in the in
this particular set
if however
the server managed to distribute the key
in this particular way where one
specific client has a key k1 and all
other clients have a different key
usage of a key might reveal what the
specific client was
that interacted with the service which
is not great from a privacy perspective
and something we'd like to avoid
so
consistency here means that all clients
again have the same shared view of the
key for the particular server
there's also authenticity the other
informal principle um so imagine you had
now an adversary that sits between the
server and the clients where the server
makes its key available it's authentic
key available but then the adversary
slips in its own malicious key ek prime
and gives that to the clients
clients if they don't know any better
any function computed based on this
particular key k prime reveals something
that was originally intended for us so
in the case of like osttp that might be
an encapsulated request encrypted to
someone that is not the actual gateway
but someone else which would not be
great
um so we also want to avoid this
um and
sort of
simplifying things a lot uh basically
what the draft advocates for is that um
these two properties on linkability
authenticity
mean that every single client has a
consistent view of the server's intended
key and then that view is correct and
and systems that actually enforce these
two things
we call uh key consistency and
correctness systems
and uh the design space for this sort of
thing is huge i mean there was a
discussion based on key consistent ohio
earlier in the week um based on one of
ben's drafts um and that like touched on
one solution in this design space there
are other solutions that have different
like complexity in terms of operation
trust model and so on
um so the
the actual
system that's used to enforce
consistency and correctness can vary
based on all these external factors um
are based on all these factors some of
them
external i guess
roughly speaking the design space kind
of boils down to you know these four
things um
uh first of which is like fetching
through a fetching a key through a
trusted proxy so clients that you know
belong to the same annuity set would ask
a trusted proxy hey give me the key
the consistent and correct key for this
particular service that i'm using in the
server and the proxy is trusted to
present the correct key
you can fetch and verify through a
trusted proxy which is what the double
check thing uh double check spec uh
roughly does um
you can fetch through multiple untrusted
proxies or less trusted proxies and
verify that you get back the same answer
or you could sort of uh stick all these
keys on a bulletin board and audit that
bulletin board and make sure that you
know uh you're getting the latest
contents of the audited bulletin board
um or a bulletin board here it's just a
you know an authentic append only log or
something like that
um and these these approaches uh i'm
going to walk through the pictures just
to really drive the point home um these
are pictures are these these different
solutions again they
they have different applicability based
on
uh your your application configuration
your deployment module your threat model
and trust model and whatnot um
and so there's no one-size-fits-all or
correct solution here um it's a pilot
trade-offs so in the trusted proxy case
as i was saying uh
there's a proxy in the middle that gets
it gets a key and then bends it of that
same copy to all clients pretty
straightforward
in the multi-proxy case where clients
might go through different untrusted
proxies to ask the server to present its
view of the key
um clients can check to see whether or
not a server is trying to lie and change
keys
you know
in a malicious attempt to tag clients um
i have here listed that constancy double
check is sort of an example of this
slightly different but i'm kind of the
close enough in spirit that i just kind
of threw it down here
and then there's the bulletin board
external data database which stores the
keys and then clients just pull it down
and there's some assumption that there's
an ecosystem built around this bulletin
board for verifying that everything is
correct and consistent um
like connexing key transparency or
basically an instantiation of this
concept
um okay so um consistency has come up
time and time again um in particular
this week uh and i think we're really
going to have to address it with ben's
draft
the question is you know whether or not
there's value in uh this complementary
document that sort of describes the the
rest of the design space um or some
other pieces of the design space may not
be exhaustive um
uh there is no specific section uh in
the privacy fast charter that to sort of
address the key consistency or key
tagging issue
um so after discussion with the shares
we basically are proposing to bring this
document as informational as a working
group
uh like supporting document or something
to be published i don't think it matters
that much um to sort of uh help inform
the discussion around consistency double
check or other solutions as they emerge
and um
that's our proposal
cures to hear what folks think
yeah tommy
yeah
thanks for doing this this is clearly
very important um
i have no idea what working group this
belongs in i don't think it matters
too much we don't have one to do it in
but we should do this
uh the the one comment i had is
if i i wonder if the approach of double
check
not the specific protocol instantiation
but the approach of it could be
mentioned
more explicitly here again it kind of
seems like implicit when you're talking
about oh you have proxies you can go
through and you can go direct and like
maybe laying that out and bringing some
of the double check in because it feels
like different protocols like ojai
you know if there is a way to do a
specific ohio key config lookup
that can adopt double check but other
things
even if they don't fit into one
particular config bag like
different
key configuration
locations could use double check and use
these different techniques
so we could talk about techniques here
and then just let other protocols say oh
yeah and then you use
that technique or that technique or that
technique
that sounds like a reasonable approach
um
uh
and certainly we didn't mean to like
intentionally omit double check variant
it is as you say a different it is a
slightly different technique than the
the multi-proxy discovery um
i just kind of i like vastly
oversimplified things on this particular
slide so we could add a section there
alternatively depending on like ben's
preference here we could like just take
all this content like put it in an
appendix in his draft as like here are
alternative solutions that if you didn't
want to use double check or whatever i
don't think it matters that much um
uh although to tommy's point it does
seem like it might be useful to have a
place to
somewhere to point and say
you know this is the consistency
mechanism i'm using
in a specific deployment or in my
specific protocols
so uh the authors of this draft
have requested an adoption call um
for
uh
for this draft in the privacy pass
working group
uh
i don't believe such an adoption call
has been made uh yet but the the chairs
will
consider that um and and if an adoption
call is started you'll you'll see the
announcement on the list so uh please do
review the draft so that you're prepared
in case such an announcement appears
we are over time and we've completed our
agenda thank you everyone for
participating and making this a great
privacy pass session
is