now
oh
um
so welcome everyone to the
ietf 114 meeting of the quick working
group if that's not where you expect to
be either physically or digitally then
i would uh
hurry on over to where you're supposed
to be
so some uh things you know it's thursday
now so everyone's probably used to this
but
i remember the importance of the ietf
note well
this is a copy of it i'm sure you've
seen it if you need
to find references to it it is very easy
to find both on the ituf website but
also
googling anything related to itif note
well it's a fairly unique name
uh so for
some itf meeting tips um in-person
participants uh you probably used this
by now but remember to use meat echo
light when you were in the room this is
useful for
us chairs to keep track of the
cue
with both remote and in-person
participants
and also we want to stress that those
there in person should be wearing a
compliant
mask at all times
there are n95 masks available at
registration uh please remember to keep
your mask on
and remote participants i mean the
normal applies for making sure your
audio and video are off unless you're
you know presenting and
we do recommend
using a headset and or checking
making sure your levels are good on your
mics
so in minnesota
we have our
tireless volunteer and
robin marks
who is
who is uh volunteered to take notes and
we thank robin yet again
um
the blue sheets this is again being
handled through mid echo remote
participants doesn't have to do anything
uh those there again please use media
collite
for chat um
we are of course using mudeko and zulip
so
um
and
for the
cue the chairs despite our
and arguably larger than life presence
we will be running the queue with the
assistance of zahed who is
you can see up there in person
thank you zod
uh matt just to jump in quickly there
sorry uh we did have brian volunteered
to take notes as well that's great the
more the merrier um if somebody in the
room would just like to assist the
remote notetakers that would be greatly
appreciated um so do
dive into the notes and contribute where
possible um i don't think we had anyone
volunteer for javascribe though
um
would someone like
like that job
um just in case we need to
augment anything to the bike one of us
could probably do it too but
um shall i do that
jonathan that would be uh very helpful
thank you
all right
thank you all who are helping us run
this meeting
all right so agenda which can be bashed
uh so we have chair updates as usual
which you'll have to suffer through and
then we have three working group items
the first and longest is multipath
followed by the acknowledgement
frequency work and then quick lb
after that we have other items
uh including quick time stamps multicast
quick and uh
and talking about quick announcement
tooling martin would you like to say
something
yes uh martin duke google um kind of an
agenda bash but like rather than
actually introduce another presentation
i would just like to briefly say that um
uh i think most people are aware that
lucas and i have a draft to put quick
versions in alt service and serve dns
service b records as we just as we
dissociated alpn from quick version
um in http bis today they are likely to
like dramatically strip down alt-service
and not have parameters and become
service b would be the
like transport capability discovery
mechanism the upshot of that for this
working group is that we will likely
accordingly strip down our draft to just
service b
and the place where service b
stuff lives is in the protocol working
group where it applies which will likely
be bringing this draft too quick
sometime between sometime in the next
month or two so look for that and we'll
probably call for adoption
uh relatively early
since it's a simple mechanism thanks
thank you for that martin
um
is there anyone else who would like to
agenda bash or otherwise
have a note of order here
and if not i will move on to
oh miriam
okay mary is not ready to go okay
uh update since last meeting uh
uh as probably everyone hopefully
noticed and if you didn't i have great
news for you which is that http 3
became an rfc at long last so the and of
course another document which is q-pac
related of course is uh yes
this is obviously a big milestone they
lagged considerably behind
the other quick documents for reasons
that are not really worth going into but
we no longer have those on our plate and
they are rfc's where
they can live in perpetuity
so and then other updates the quick
grease bit which is a very simple uh a
relatively simple document but important
one is currently in auth 48
and version negotiation and v2 which are
sort of proceeding together as as was
agreed
are currently under ad evaluation
so other things we had issued an
adoption call and it completed for the
quick careful resume uh this got some
feedback that in about its potential
suitability for other
potential working groups specifically
the discussions around uh
congestion control's
life at the itf so
the chairs are going to take this under
consideration
uh qlog is not presenting today um
and this is not due to a lack of
progress but they are so
and expect a new draft for uh before 115
and updates to be on the list
we also like to call out that l4s which
you may have heard about at this itf
work was done during the hackathon
including interop
that with quick stacks which is very
exciting um because quick is you know
participating and working with l4s um
with the l4s work
and i think that is it lucas do you have
anything else that you would like to add
to our
boring chair updates
uh
nothing major just that you know matt
and i were both really excited to be
there in person this time around um to
actually meet each other for the first
time in however many long and meet all
the participants as well um
unfortunately we can't be there
for various reasons uh so thank you very
much for your patience and support to
people who have been helping behind the
scenes to make sure this session can run
smoothly
and i agree with that of course and
now we will both stop talking and we
will
allow muria to take over as the first
presenter
and my meat echo is totally
not allowing me to do anything so that's
interesting
okay i got i got it to work
try it again
ah no
there we go
okay hello everybody my name is mia
coolerin i'm
one of the editors of the um multi-pass
extension for quick but probably the
least important editor but i'm the only
one here unfortunately
um
yeah
so we published a new version and this
was actually quite a big update based on
the discussion we had last time the
biggest change is that we merged the pr
which which has the what we call unified
proposal we could discuss this last time
and i have a slide later on this and
there were some other a few changes that
i want to update you on one is that also
an issue we discussed last time that we
now decided to have some mechanism
to also signal that there might be or
that you want to use one of the pass
only for standby
motors and we have a new frame for that
there's um some clarifications about um
pass closure or like denying a path
which is also actually kind of new
protocol work so i will go to that and
then
more guidance about x scheduling and
delay calculations but that's also kind
of still work in progress because that's
some of the hard parts
yeah we didn't solve
or we didn't close all the open issues
we still have three of the open issues
that we discussed last time
time and so these are uh need a little
bit more work especially the first one
um it's on my plate to look at what we
actually decided uh or like why we
didn't allow servers um to migrate and
if that's still important for multiple
so i will do some research and come back
to that just didn't do it now
and the other ones are also looking for
a more input about like the actual need
for these things and so for all of these
three open issues here that we discussed
last time already we have to figure out
if this is something we want to do at
all if this is something we want to do
in the space draft or if this is an
extension in the future and that's
ongoing that discussion
we have also a few new issues
but i have to say these are a little bit
more on the editorial side i think so
like not fully but as i just said there
is more work needed about explaining how
to calculate act delay correctly and
maybe some of this is kind of um
normative but um it's not clearly so
that's ongoing
that's the two new issues listed here
yes so especially you know what's i
wanted to explain the problem um quickly
here but not sure if we will solve it
completely or um finalize the discussion
here
so um the problem we have is
if you
and there's still a part about using
single packet number space so if you use
single packet number space then things
like calculating your round trip time
and delay correctly what you need for
congestion control is actually not that
easy and this is just giving an example
here so you assume you have two passes
and pass one is quicker or faster has
less delay than past two and you decide
somehow on your packet scheduling you
send packet one to ten on pass one
11 to 20 on past two and then 21 to 30
on past one again
um so what can happen is that you
receive all the packets on pass one
because that's a faster pass
but then because depending on like how
you you decide about your egg strategy
you actually trigger an egg when you
arrive
when packet 20 arrives so that's the
packet that triggers the egg but of
course that egg will will acknowledge
all of the packets so 1 to 30.
and when you receive that egg actually
you don't know
um that packet 20 triggered the egg so
you might not know how to calculate the
round trip time or the delay of each of
these passes correctly
because packet 20 was sent on path two
but like uh 2030 was sent on pass one
but the delay you basically calculate
based on the egg is the delay of past
two so that's like usually what's
happening is like you get the delay if
you if you just do like whatever you do
with what would do today with eye
calculation you get the delay of the of
the longest path and not the delay of
the shorter pass so you have to be
smarter about this you have to either
you know add some more information to
the to the egg about saying like what
which packet does this delay information
belong to or you have to split up your
ex in a smarter way or you have to
schedule a packet in a smarter way or
whatever
and that's a discussion we're still
having
and
my phone goes to sleep and now i cannot
no no i can control it again
okay
um
yeah so that was just to explain the
problem and i think we should have the
discussion actually on on github because
it's not like
it's not like we need to change
something but i think we have to be
clear about what the best way to do
and then a quick um review about what
we've merged already based on this
question from last time so this is in
the new um past status frame
the past status frame has like this past
status information which is the
important part and what we specify is
really you have two two choices here
standby or available
and what it does it just really gives a
recommendation for the other site what
to send on the pass it doesn't tell
anything about what you're planning to
do on your site right but you give some
hints to the other side that it's
preferred from your point of view to use
one or the other path or to not use it
and that's it and effectively it's also
just a recommendation of course if
there's a situation where you can use
one of them you have to make a local
decision
okay i go on
so the other thing we merged which is um
a normative thing here is that we um
other than for
rfc 9000 where basically if you have a
migration event and you don't want to
have the new pass you just don't react
we actually give an option here to um
actively deny a new path by using the
pass abandoned frame on the existing
path
um so this is just because we have to
pass abandon frame we can make use of
that and that can just like avoid some
delay so it's like a little change but
it can happen some situations to
optimize
i go on
we can come back to this
okay and so this was the biggest merge
we have in this this site is mostly
recap slightly um modified recap but
mostly recap from last time
so um the question the big question we
discussed last time is like using single
not multiple packet number spaces and
like
um there are pros and cons on both sides
right so the one of the biggest
difference was like single packet number
space does support zero length
connection id and multi packet number
space does not
and that's the most of the discussion we
had last time from a code complexity
point of view there are kind of pros and
cons on both sides like on the first
look like single packet number space
seems to be much less code and much
easier for that point because you don't
have to introduce a new packet number
space
but then if you look at this like delay
calculation issues how to get condensed
control right making sure you schedule
the packet in a smart way that your
excise doesn't grow and whatever it gets
very complicated
and it gets like um it's not like uh uh
there is a normative way to handle it is
like depends on the implication how to
do this right so it's easy to get it
wrong effectively
so i think there was like a lot of
support from
from a complexity point of view to
actually go to multiple packet number
spaces because that makes the spec just
more clear
there is still a discussion about
hardware offload because there's also um
implications here so with multiple
packet number spaces you actually have
to change
um the the crypto part how you decrypt
the packet number because you have to
consider the congestion the connection
id but on the other hand if you have
modern packet number spaces it's
actually um easier for your hardware
offload because then you know exactly
you don't have to decrypt like
uh you don't have to guess the packet
number because you can much better
figure out where you are and you don't
have a lot of out of order packets
effectively in this kind of thing so
there are also pros and cons here
so
um
so this is very much nearly the same
slide as i presented last time and we
just merged this in now which means
basically packet multiple packet number
spaces is now mandatory
so if you um
if you negotiate multiples the
multi-pass extension you have to support
multiple player number spaces
but it's optional to use zero length id
connection id if you want to use zero
length connection id you also have to
implement all this other stuff
and then it gets complicated and we put
a lot of guidance and and discussion in
the document about what how to do there
and how to get your delay calculation
your easy hand easy and handling your
congestion control right but it's kind
of optional if you don't support
a
[Music]
single packet number space um and the
other end requires you to use zero
connection id basically you can only use
one path
even if you have negotiated multiples
but like there's no obligation to
implement it at least
it took me that entire in sweat google
it took me that entire time to get into
the queue and get the pages load um
can you go back to the last slide of it
just curious question about hardware
offload um
is there available hardware offload that
is
uh for quick today because i've looked
into this and i haven't actually found
it and
you might be right that it makes
hardware upload more
complex but it really depends on what
the hardware offload api is and so like
i'm not personally familiar with them i
don't know maybe
maybe this is much more widely available
than i think and
or maybe you're anticipating future
hardware offload that will exist
so um
okay
so yeah we should talk more in um
that was my issue a while ago and it is
speculative based on um conversations
that that i've had with hardware vendors
in the past um the issue 25 is
kind of
but no there's certainly no hardware
offload that certainly i was aware of
when i filed this issue it was just
concerned that by messing with the
crypto algorithm we're going to have
this other mode for multipath which
might not be a very viable thing
so the
we so there is no hardware offload which
is i think already deployed
but we did some research and we had some
work about trying like how to implement
hardware offload and we only went for
the multiple packet numbers based
solution because you don't have a lot of
packet reordering whatever which makes
your offload engine actually easier it's
different than what's today in rfc 9000
but it would make it easier if we have
multiple packet number spaces and given
it's not deployed yet that might
actually be um a reason to go there as
well
yeah i mean i i like i don't think this
is a showstopper at this point but it's
something you can consider and like if
we do everything where like you need
special hardware to do multi-path that's
probably bad for multitask no you don't
need special hardware to do multipass
it's just like you have to optimize you
have to have
um or you can do less with rfc 9000 and
you need more
if you want to support multiple packet
number spaces but it's the same logic
it's just like an extended logic right
it's not like you have two different
paths to go for okay thanks
okay so yeah we matched it
so
i just wanted to point out chair hat off
on the cardboard awful
load thing um
no uh yeah again there's no hardware
offload the
hardware offload that we have been
working on um the vendors involved uh
would probably not like multibath anyway
just they just they typically are not
happy about
the hardware doing anything related to
quick that's complicated um they don't
like packet numbers either so i would i
would say that
it probably is true that the multiple
pack and workspace is a little bit
easier to support well but um
it's also going to vary depending on the
vendor you talk to like what their
opinions are on what is hard and for
their hardware because
what what's interesting about this is
that different hardware uh can do
different things easier than others when
it comes to crypto offloads and
uh quick in particular so it's it's
probably a concern but i'm not sure that
it's something that necessarily has to
be designed into the protocols or taken
as a major concern
yeah so i mean um there is this issue in
github and it's still open and needs
more discussion but i don't think the
decision is clear in which direction we
should decide here
christian
yes
regarding this
offer
it's really the encryption issue
when we cannot have multiple numbers
without injecting
more than the packet sequence number
in the encryption
so that means that
whatever offloads that has to be aware
of not just the connection id in the
incoming packet
but the sequence number of that
connection id
so it's that's conceptually a really
simple fix in the api but it has to be
there this should not be
i mean if people can actually do
hardware offload
and extract the sequence number and
things like that the additional step to
support multiple number space is not
that high
it's just that
there are twos i mean you have to
extract 42 bits
of the
sequence number of the connection id
and you have to use 96 bit sequence
number which is composed of this id
and the 32 and the 64 bit of the packet
so it does change api it doesn't change
the complexity very much because you
need the cid anyhow
otherwise you're not able to
find the context of the connection
and if you can find the contents of the
connection you can't find the keys
so i mean the complexity should not be
used for down there
jana
hi um
so i want to
emphasize a couple of points that just
both matt and christine said but uh one
of the things when thinking about
hardware offloaders people typically use
the pcb model
to think about it
and which is why sequence number seems
like an attractive thing to consider
handing off to the offload engine
it's not necessarily true and in fact
true in the quick case for a number of
reasons one of them being that we don't
necessarily expect sequence numbers to
be sequential
we want to have gaps we want to be able
to do various things with sequence
numbers that's in fact part of the
protocol i would say philosophy and even
the design that
packet
our packet numbers are not basically
stream numbers uh stream id and stream
sequence number sure that's fine but not
at the
packet level we don't necessarily need
it to be sequential we don't need it to
be uh in any particular order the sender
ought to be able to send it in whatever
order it cares and uh the receiver is
able to handle it um that's important
and so i would say that uh going forward
again to christian's point
as well that
something explicit needs to be handed
down is very likely to need to be handed
down to the offload engine from the
quick sender and it is not something
that you can simply offload as a task
to the offroad engine so i don't think
that sequence numbers should uh play
a role in how we decide um
hardware operation
multiple or single packet number spaces
so
the problem is you want to decrypt the
packet number and um
and how you decrypt the packet number
depends on the packet number space right
so that's the part you want to do an
offloading
uh martin duke google uh so uh at the
risk of going down the hardware offload
rabbit hole um
uh like the encryption and decryption
problems are quite different the
encryption problem yes absolutely you
just passed the packet number with the
packet and i think it works pretty well
on the decryption path the the hardware
needs to keep some state obviously
because it has to you know predict the
the expanded packet number
uh you know it has to expand it from the
the truncated packet number so that's
like a harder problem
um
and it becomes even harder with
multi-path but uh right if you build the
ap apis right it doesn't matter and just
the question if vendors will find it
worthwhile to implement the apis and i
don't have an answer to that
okay
i go to the next slide
which is my last slide i think
um so we merged in this proposal
again saying uh um multiple packet
number space is mandatory single packet
number space is optional to implement
basically
and there's some more editorial work
here because like the way it's it's
structured in the document
doesn't make that fully cleared and but
it's really just editorial work um that
we will do
um
we have some remaining issues but as i
said again for all of these issues we
really need to decide if they should go
should be addressed in this document or
in an extension what's the part of the
the base document that we want to um
discuss
um so it's like i don't think it's like
hard to find a solution to this problem
but it's just a decision of what we want
to do here or later
um and then the most important part is
that we really want more
implementation experience
because you know if we all end up only
implementing multiple packet number
spaces maybe we don't need single map
number packet space or if we actually
think that zero length condition
connection id is not that important we
don't need single number packet space
um or maybe there's additional
considerations for
hardware offloading that actually
changes our mind so i think these are
the open questions and what we need is
implementation experience
uh eric kinnear apple just a really
quick question about the path abandoned
stuff is the expectation that the old
path receive both a path challenge and a
path abandon at the same time but we
still want those to be separate frames
so you try to open a second pass
and start the past challenge process and
if you don't want to accept that you
don't have to reply to the past
challenge and then there's no path right
so that's what we already have today
and just like to to avoid this this time
where you like time out until you get
like a challenge response back or not
you can on the other path that's that's
exist if you have multiple packet number
spaces
you can send a path abandon and just
give like a explicit signal that you
will not reply on the other path
that's it but if it when you first
initiate that that triggers a challenge
to go down both paths right because it
needs to be validated in both directions
so the new path is going to be getting a
path challenge saying hey is this
actually working in this direction but
the old path is also going to do so when
it sees someone coming in from a new
place
you're saying the old past is also
sending a past challenge
yes that's my understanding uh that's
sitting in the middle of a different
section of our c9000 essentially it's
for when the off path attacker forwards
some packets you confirm that on the
existing path
okay so the reason i bring that up is a
it's interesting to get both a challenge
and an abandon at the same time the
abandon refers to the new path so that
seems okay
it might also be possible to just like
put in the challenge like hey i don't
want this other one yeah so the abandon
only works if you have um pass
identifiers
yes and because you don't send it on the
same path and like we should look up
this part you're just citing because
maybe that doesn't make well it may also
have been overridden by some of the new
texts so i should go double check
okay thank you
alessandra gadini cloudflare
um we're starting work on multi-path
right now and
um my current impression is um on the
single path versus multiple packet
number spaces um question is that
the single pocket number space doesn't
really give us much benefit and
um implementing both is kind of annoying
so um we might end up just implementing
the multiple packet number spaces
um
we might reconsider later on after we
actually deploy the whole thing but um
that's my current impression at least
it's not super clear
what the benefits of
implementing both are and a quick
implementation kind of needs to support
the non-zero connection id um
case anyway so
you have to implement multiple packet
number spaces and the single packet
number space is just i don't know more
complexity for
not much benefit
so this is exactly the point so like if
you if you don't need zero length
connection id
that's probably additional overhead you
wouldn't want but like we're looking for
people who actually have a use case for
zero length connection id and i mean one
of the benefits is like you save a few
bytes right so that for some use cases
that might be really important
um and like there are two options here i
mean the one option is also we could try
to treat the
multiple packet number space solution to
support at least zero connection id in
one direction there has been proposals
but it's also like some additional
complexity it's not here if it's needed
the other option is also like put the
zero length connection id support in an
extension or whatever
but yeah that's the feedback we're
looking at so i think
um the the
the zero connection id case is mostly a
client use case maybe i think some
browsers use zero connection ids um
so supporting on only one side might be
okay yeah um but then i guess someone
who is
actually using that use case might
comment more that's what we're looking
for
i think lucas is next
hey yeah i i don't need to queue on the
chair i could have just interjected but
i thought it'd be polite um we've had a
few comments in the chat about my
squaring uh for anyone that wants to be
not in the room during the initial um
uh chess fights this is a requirement of
your attendance to to wear a mask at all
times during these meeting sessions so
please uh take this seriously um
this is important for our health we all
want to be able to go home
at the end of the week so thank you very
much
thanks lucas
thanks uh
ian's right google um
i i was more of a single packet number
space fan as an individual um but i have
to say that uh requiring both seems
worse than just requiring multiple
packet number spaces
in terms of zero length connection ids
the use cases i think probably could be
preserved so like for example there are
cases when chrome will open two
different ephemeral ports at the same
time and so chrome would have like two
different sockets and i would think it
would be perfectly easy to distinguish
which path uh a pack arrived on based on
the socket arrived on
things like that so
uh that's my general comment but i need
to go back through and
kind of look at all the discussion about
like how you ended up where you didn't
make sure that i kind of understand
everything that that happened so
so i don't usually stand up just to say
plus one but there weren't that many
people who were super into just a single
packet number space and i was originally
one of them and i would strongly agree
with ian that having both seems strictly
worse than having one or the other and
having multiple packet number spaces
based on the things that we've been
discovering as we go to implement is
seeming more and more attractive
me again um so to be clear i'm not
implementing this but
to me the attraction of
the single packet number space is to
like not write a lot of code and get
like cheap multi-path
uh cheap in terms of coding effort but
if we're gonna require multiple packet
if we're going to acquire a multiple
packet number of spaces then like
that's that's that's are you you have to
pay the entry cost like the point of
single it seems much weaker to me
yeah and i think this is actually kind
of a wrong assumption because it looks
much easier from the first place but
then actually getting all the packet
scheduling delay calculation right and
so on it might be actually more code at
the end and it's it's code that is kind
of not well specified in the end so you
end up with like having different
implementation doing different things
and then because the other end is doing
something weird your performance goes
down and you don't have any control
yeah certainly optimizing it would be a
lot more code but i'm thinking just like
if people wanted really minimal support
that would be attractive but
so it's i mean it's not only optimizing
right it's really just like
the the delay calculation example showed
this this just doesn't work correctly
it's like giving you some crap and like
yeah if you just want to make sure you
can send one packet from here to there
it's fine but if you actually want to
do the right thing it's you cannot
ignore it okay well if if like if the
if the coding simplicity is like
illusory then like to me that that
destroys like the the case for a single
single packet number space entirely yeah
thanks so i mean the point is um
multiple packet number spaces don't
support zero connection id in both
directions
there is a way there are proposals to so
if we need this use case then we need
something right
um if there is a way to maybe support
your connection id in one direction but
it's also giving you more complexity and
more ambiguity so like
it's also additional code so it's really
the question what do we do with your
connection id
is it a use case we want to support or
not
ownership your apple
like many other early informators we are
leaning towards multiple packet spaces
and one
if we are having trouble finding uh
current evidence that the zero lens
connection that single spaces are needed
today
uh we may
consider uh
emulating
uh zero lens cds by injecting a known
constant and essentially making it a uh
nonzero lens and hence injecting that
problem space into the other
hi luke from twitch
i'm noticing in a few working groups
that there's this tendency to put a
context or like a packet space id in um
to distinguish between sessions um mask
has it web transport we're talking about
a session id and here we're part of the
path
in there i'm wondering if overloading
the connection id is the right approach
um is this something we want to do for
like making load balancing more
difficult or
do we want to make this part of the
quick api like just literally put packet
space in the header or something
this is more of a question to the room
but
i feel like there's an api here that a
lot of different working groups might
use
i'm open to have this discussion but
like one of the decisions we made
earlier on is that we want to keep the
changes to the um base pack minimal
right and that would be a big change
i just think when we start
making copies of every frame like here's
an act frame but we put the packet space
in it here's a flow control
frame but we put a packet space in it
not saying the spec does that um
it it just screams out a little bit to
me but
all right off my softbox
point taking
question
to on this discussion
i mean
i started experimenting with indonesia
very early i mean it was my original
design a couple of years ago
and
i did implementation of
single number space and multiple space
to measure the complexity
the complexity of multiple number space
is that you have to add a bunch of
statements in your code to check whether
this is the multi-pass or the single
pass case and there are more checks like
that for multiple number space than for
single number space
but on the other hand the complexity of
single number of space is that you have
to add a lot of structure in your code
to handle that
and
for example
you have
in my original implementation
the
single space solution was five percent
less efficient about five percent as
efficient
than the multiple space solution
and i took that as a challenge like can
i
make them to be equally
efficient and the answer is yes i could
and i did that in in my prototypes
but to do that i had to
add a lot of code in the act scheduling
pass
i had to add a lot of structure
in the
store of packets to make sure that
packets carried not just the packet
number but were also linked to the path
in which they were sent and that we can
retrieve how many packets were sent
before them after them etc etc overall
that complexity as miria said
is
much more than the single number of
space
so that's the reason why i did support
and in fact that proposed this unified
proposal if
i mean the reason for the additional
complexity is the need to support the
zero length cid case
and we need feedback from implementers
there whether that zero length cid case
is actually needed
with multipass or not
that's what we need
yes i think you know that's the main
question and
uh if people
are having a use case for zero links id
and multipass um it would be good to
learn about that maybe put it that way
you answered google i was just gonna add
that i mean a byte is fine i mean at
least for chrome and other browsers and
such but um also i'm still i think i'm
not fully understanding the problem it
seems like
if i
can distinguish at the receiver which
path i'm receiving something on then i
can decide to use a zero link
uh connection id
and
if i can't
then i need to use a non-zero length
connection id and this
seems true
in the existing server deployments we
have today right i don't i guess i'm not
understanding like why multipath makes
this
actually different
like
like if i can tell from the affirmative
report like this is pathe or about b
then like i don't need
a connection id but if i'm a server i'm
receiving on 443 and i have 10 000
connections then
like clearly i need a connection id to
like multiplex them
so it does work but um
it
it just
makes your
scheduling and your acknowledgement code
more complex to get it right right you
have to decide
which packet numbers to use on with
which part of the packet number space to
use on which path
and that impacts a lot like how your
acting will look like it
impacts your ex size
and you also don't really know what the
other end is doing like how often do
they send x or not and when you get the
packet back there's like ambiguity about
ecn markings usually you don't know
where the ecn magnets belong to which
path so you have to if you get an ecn
marking you have to reduce your
congestion window on both paths because
that's the most conservative thing to do
or you have to be somehow smart about
acting but that's the other end that you
don't control and the same is true for
um egg delay calculation usually you
will only be able to calculate the delay
on the longest path so that's what you
have to cope with so you cannot fill the
shortest path delay in whatever and you
have to have logic for handling all of
that to make it work
nicely and i think correctly i mean like
as i said if you if you need like a few
packets it doesn't probably matter but
if you actually want to have a
performant connection
it it's not that easy anymore
yeah i i would completely agree i was i
was merely asking i think i didn't fully
understand why we can't have zero length
packet uh zero length
connection ids with multiple packet
number spaces
um
i think that's the question i still
don't fully understand but i can take it
off because like that because you get
the same packet number on both paths and
you don't know how to handle it like you
have to distinguish like what the fact
where the packet number belongs but if i
have two different sockets then like i
could just use the socket and be like
suckaday
socket i don't know
if i can i think the issue is not
rebinding um if you're not reminding on
the path
there's a lot of ambiguity no i mean
it's also like this doesn't it
the crypto to encrypt your packet number
right doesn't allow you to have the same
packet number twice or like these kind
of things
it just doesn't work christian
yes it's exactly what you just said i
mean is that if you have the same
packets i mean if you have packets
arriving with the same number
from two pass
then you have to inject a pass id in the
crypto to understand
which uh
key to use i mean
and and if you don't do that
then basically
your crypto is broken
so i can maybe you should take it
offline
and if you are interested i could have a
discussion with them on exactly the
complexity that we encounter there
but i mean
or you might trust me but i know you
don't
donna
thank you
um
so i i
it sounds to me like there's a fair
amount of agreement on doing
multiple packet number spaces
it also sounds to me like there's a
possibility of considering what else
we might be able to
now
this is an issue that's been like you
know doing the rounds for quite a while
uh and we've got some experience here
i'm happy i feel comfortable and
confident in saying that we can move
forward but that's my opinion
i
yeah so the audio wasn't super great um
but i think you said we should decide
now if you want to support zero links id
yeah um i don't know can you hear me now
is it better
a little bit yes
i don't like my video
i it's also in the audio from here where
stand is not great for me
so like yeah i mean um
as i said is probably janna also said i
believe and the question is really not
about like doing one or the other doing
single or doing multiple pack number
spaces i think might what we decided
already is that multiple factor number
spaces is the way to go and single might
be optional or not so the question
really is do we want support for zero
lengths connection id
that's the question to ask i'm happy to
make a decision now i'm also happy to
like wait for a little bit more
implementation experience and because we
have like a few not super hard open
issues but we need the discussion so
it's like we can decide now we can
decide next time or sometime in between
but yeah at some point we have to make a
decision
cheers
thanks miriam um just just from me with
my hat on but my opinion um this has
been some good chat and some good
engagement thank you folks um we've
taken the comments down about the
potential consensus call look out for
that um we'll discuss the follow-up on
the list if there's anything to be done
um one question i've got you talked a
couple of times mary about
implementation experience and you know
alexandra mentioned that you know the
the quiche project is looking to do some
work i wonder if if maybe at the next
hackathon in in november we should try
and form another quick table and
actually try and bring some folks to
do some implementation and interrupt and
create a target and maybe come up with
some test cases
we don't need that answer right now but
if people are interested in that let's
try and take that discussion offline
losses in the queue
yeah lars eckhart so i'm
not super closely following this
discussion in in quick
um but back when we did multiple tcp the
research not the standard
we actually tried to do the single space
um which we quickly found out you can't
for tcp right because if
middle boxes along a stream c gaps in a
sequence number space they just break in
all kinds of different ways but that was
the original intent because we thought
that sort of felt natural and then we
had to do the two space the the one
space per path and we sort of made that
work
with quick right we actually have the
option of uh doing the single space
um but maybe we have now enough
experience with multi-graph tcp in the
multiple spaces to see benefits that we
didn't see way back when
but um
i kind of sort of without as i said not
having followed this in detail
i kind of sort of wondered that the one
space back then that we thought would be
the way to go uh
wouldn't be the way to go here but
since i'm not implementing it i'm not
going to deploy it uh take that as you
will thank you so i think you're talking
about different economic spaces here
than where am i um yeah because in tcp
you have the the on path sequence number
and then you have a separate thing right
yeah and this is not the kind of packet
number space we're talking about here
it's really like the onpass packet
number space and it's really like do you
use the same numbers on both passes or
do you use different numbers the
different set of numbers on on passes
but it's the same
element right it's not like in tcp where
you actually have this additional number
the reason we have the addition number
is because we otherwise couldn't make it
yes so but what you wanted originally is
to take the sequence number the sequence
number field and put multiple packet
number spaces in that field and that
didn't work and so you had to have a new
field
anyway we were going to use a single
sequence number space across all paths
with a single field
originally
i think we're digressing and that didn't
work because of all the packets are out
of order in these kind of things
it mean because middle boxes see gaps
and they don't like that yeah
yeah so we don't have that problem
but having those gaps is also not
optimal for the interning processing so
it's possible but not optimal
jana again
hi hopefully you can hear me uh
reasonably i'll shut up if you can't
hear me
yeah it's a little bit better for me now
okay um uh largest point class yes
exactly i think
that uh
the difference here primarily and so i
i'll also speak about not just mpdcp but
uh even almost 20 years ago i did this
for scdp
i've used
sctp multipath implementation
and uh the reasons that we did that
and that those are exactly the reasons
that don't apply to quick specifically
both sctp and pcp had assumptions about
linear sequencing
both the protocols the senders the
receivers and metal boxes in the tcp
case all have assumptions about
sequencing
of packet numbers we don't have that in
quick
and so that's actually a freeing thing
in implementing this with single packet
number space in sctp one of the things i
quickly found out was that eventually
near the end
uh uh near the end meaning after after a
while of working and implementing this
my uh um conclusion was that
separate sequence number spaces would
actually have made things
far simpler
because a lot of the things that a
transport does
its recovery condition
all
things that are happening on a path and
there is a general assumption about
sequencing on the path
and a lot of these mechanisms that we we
build and we deploy have those
assumptions
so if you move to single single but if
you move to multiple packet number
spaces those mechanisms just work
with a single packet number space you
have to go revisit every one of those
implementation bits and you find it
we typically tend to build a certain
amount of reordering tolerance within a
path but sort of really blows us out of
the water
and you don't want to use the same
ideas of
reordering tolerance to multipath
because in multiple we have a lot more
information we actually know that there
are two or multiple different paths
within which we can expect a certain
amount of sequencing so all of that to
say that multiple sequence numbers
actually make except what trying to
that was max in the sctp case it was
backward compatibility it was the fact
that ag compression wasn't very good
when you split the sequence number space
and so on in quickly explicitly and
deliberately allowed for those things to
exist
and by design and by philosophy we've
allowed for multiple sequence number
spaces to exist and so i strongly urge
us to go towards that and if only things
are falling apart badly should we
consider single sequence number space
yeah thanks that's i'm used to input and
actually last um we already have two
secret number spaces in quick one is the
packet number and one is a frame
id right and and that makes it nice to
actually have this the split and using
not to pick a number space on the packet
number
uh jonathan just disappeared
yeah we're kind of at time i locked the
queue just just so we can make progress
and not spend too many times on this
question um if if anyone really wants to
say something do so
now
um
ian
um no not ian i think ian
yeah um i think this has been very
helpful and thank you all for um your
inputs
yep definitely thank you
that's it
all right
do you want to drive the slides or can i
drive it from my laptop
yep
what do i have to do just keep hitting
the button
maybe maybe oh
uh the quick time is stopped right
yep
no no that's right
thank you uh i'm ian sweat i'll talk
about act frequency and give an update
um
great so uh there were some updates
recently mostly
uh editorial as well as uh some
additional normative text in areas where
there really was intended to be
normative text but we never actually
bothered to write anything down
such as with ignore c
um so this is an overview
of the two frames that we have the act
frequency frame
it allows you to tell the peer how often
uh they should send acknowledgements to
you how long to delay them so on and so
forth
and then an immediate frame that allows
you to elicit an immediate
acknowledgement
um so i'm going to try to go through
these in order of
what i think will be easier to resolve
issues first and hope of getting some
resolutions um and leave the thorniest
one to the last and if we don't get to
it then i'm happy to take it up on the
list
so the first one's an easy question
should this be a one byte frame type
um we probably want to stick it with uh
pto packets in a lot of cases
um so i guess it's slightly more likely
to fit if it's one byte
we might want to send it reasonably
often
this is a
issue filed by martin seaman
um
what do people think
i see a thumbs up and a thumbs down
would people like to to give their
thoughts or
i'm honestly not sure how to resolve
this uh you know
um
but
i just left the meeting so i can't press
a button um i think it depends on how
often you expect to send this right and
that's not super clear to me
but like if you send it off and you'll
be on mine
who clicked the button faster
come on martin you got this
um
like
we only have like 60 of the short bite
packets
and extensions on average might need one
maybe sometimes two
we're going at a rate of
one maybe two extensions per year
so
we're not gonna run out anytime soon i
would say for working group extensions
where it looks like
the majority of folks are going to
implement them
yeah get a one by code point
done
thanks
yeah so martin thompson i
i've implemented this
and the number of times i send one of
these things is vanishingly small
and i have stats to show
that the number of times we send ptos in
practice
is also vanishingly small
so um
i don't think an extra bite is a problem
here and i'd rather see it left as it is
i i realized david's argument is a is a
fine one
um and we do have space but i mean we
also don't have to use it so
um leaving it as it is is fine with me
by the way the stats are like we don't
get ptos on like
80 plus percent of our connections it's
it's crazy
yeah when the internet's working well
you should not be getting very many of
them and and it turns out it works well
most of the time
okay
um
did the chairs have any suggestions on
how to oh john
martin oh yeah
[Music]
i'm trying i'm trying trust me
um
so
we can hear you this
i i don't
i wonder if this is again one of those
uh trying to optimize it well before we
really
have a problem here situation
i i think that we should i mean we can
we can go with one bite we can go with
two bytes it doesn't matter much i would
suggest that we leave it as it is until
we have more experience uh from
from various folks and we can always
come back revise the draft come up with
a new version and stuff of that sort
at this point getting this out and
getting this into people's hands is more
uh useful in my opinion
so
the uh uh leaving it at leaving it as it
is is what i would suggest
i agree with uh um martin's
uh uh comment that this is not something
we expect to send very frequently
immediately if you're if you're
immediate if you're asking immediate
acting to happen all the time
it seems that it seems like there might
be a problem somewhere else
but um
yeah
uh martin duke google i would suggest
that
we are approaching bike shed territory
on this and um probably nobody has is
gonna lie down on the road one way or
the other so having gotten pros and cons
i suggest the editors just like make a
decision
um and i'm sure everyone can live with
it and if that's not true then someone
will correct me
right
um it's been pointed out that i didn't
properly state my affiliation last time
so sorry davidskenazi quick enthusiast
um
i stood up to say something similar to
what martin said
what a beautiful bike shed you have i
really wonder what color it should be
um so
yeah i'm not going to lay on the tracks
here i don't care that much have the
editor's pick move on that sounds great
all right how about uh we have martin
talk and then i'll
um i might actually just shelve this for
a few months and just
get some more utilization and different
use cases of immediate active as well
but
yeah so sorry for opening up this bike
shed so the reason i opened this issue
is because the draft says that there are
some some cases where you want to send
this frame at least once per rtt
um i'm not fully sure if i understand
why you would want to do this probably
we can add some more text about that if
if you actually only only send this on
the pto then
i don't care but if you send it once per
rtt this might be worth doing
yeah that could probably use more decks
i think the idea was if you wanted more
fine-grained control over when you
received acknowledgments
um it's particularly if you were using
particularly long active layers in terms
of packets in time but um yeah
yep
thanks let's move on
um
so there's a lot of discussion uh in
various pr's about whether ignore ce is
useful um or one could say harmful but
maria was very kind in her
issue title um
it's also been restricted to pheromone
um so it's
it now says it should not be set if the
sender sets ect1 in its outgoing packets
such as for l4s
i think at this point i don't think
anyone is using this
um
and so i can see an argument that
given it's not seeing active use
we should just jettison it because
we don't need it right now and
um
and i'm not sure i as an editor want to
spend a bunch of time like
arguing for
ecn features that i'm not going to
immediately use but um
before
we remove it or something you know we
didn't have a consensus call to add it
so i want to
like bring it here and
just ask like what do we think
so martin thompson i'm not going to be
using this in the foreseeable future but
i can understand why other people might
say that they they would like to to do
something like this
the question not that i have for those
people
is if you're doing something like l4s or
planning to do that
would a transport parameter
suffice in this case
hmm
i might have a similar point so like i
think actually i personally think the
answer is no but that's not my main
concern my main concern is that i think
actually this shouldn't be part of this
specification because it really depends
on on the congestion crawl and the and
the ecm mechanism to specify what's the
best thing to do
and and so like you shouldn't have you
don't shouldn't have you shouldn't have
a need to single that because it depends
on like the algorithm you're
implementing to to do the right thing
and not the other end telling you to do
it
all right
um did does anyone have any other
comments on this
glory
we can't hear you agree
okay can you hear me now
good yes
so we don't currently have an ecn method
in the transport area which allows you
to ignore ce
except by just dropping in the packets
so this seems highly tied to the ce
method you use
so i agree with mira
the answer is
we should not keep it
sir you said we should not need it is
that what you said
no
we should not
keep this function
okay thank you sorry i'm getting echo
from i don't know maybe it's just the
speaker's part
um
yeah it's also like if you want to do it
right then it would be more complicated
than that so because you should kind of
never ignore the first ce but you might
not react to like follow-up ces
immediately or whatever so it's like
this is also too simplistic to make it
useful
um it sounds like i'm inclined to remove
it given where we're at
we can always add it back later if
if people decide that there's a
compelling use case and actually want to
implement it but i do not want to ship a
draft where we have a feature with no
one who's implemented it oh janna
i agree i was coming up to say that
we can use the transport parameter idea
for martin if we really want to do
something here later
but uh i agree
when we put this in just to be clear we
weren't fully certain how much
how much
traction this would get
but we can offer it in expected thinking
that there was there was an ask for it
sure we have ignore uh uh reordering so
we wonder if we should have this as well
and
so yeah if there's no strong push for it
we shouldn't add features that don't
have people asking for it
cool
thanks
okay
uh the next one is kind of a can of
worms unfortunately um not from a
design perspective but just uh it's it's
a challenging problem which is exactly
how much text do we want to put in there
about examples or suggestions of how to
use this extension
um
there's one open issue but there have
also been other side comments
uh particularly in the context of like
reno or cubic about what is the right
number like is it 8x per rtt or like
what what magic number do i need to
stick in there to get like decent
performance out of like reno and cubic
and i honestly don't have a really good
answer off the top of my head
um
but
i guess the real question is like
what should we be attempting to do here
like how much more text or less text do
we want um about
providing guidelines on how this
actually should be used
potentially with congestion controllers
that are widely deployed
so
martin zeman given that
rfc
9002 specifies a congestion control
algorithm that should be safe and
performant for for the use on the public
internet would be really nice if this
extension also suggested something that
will be
safe and performant on the on the
internet not saying that you can't do
something better but it would be really
helpful to have something in that text
for people who don't have a
internet wide deployment to run their
own measurements
as a follow-up question
um because i don't have this off the top
of my head does anyone have um a set of
constants that they've used with
regional or cubic with
uh that frequency frame that they find
work well
um or is this something where
i need to go run some experiments and
try to like
get some data
uh
because we currently run bbr by default
it at google and
currently don't have any cubic or reno
experiments but we still have the code
so we could go back and run those if if
that was kind of the way forward on this
so i was going to jump in here airhead
off
has someone that has been
thinking about experimenting with this
with an internet-wide deployment the
i don't think that we should put
anything or rather have the onus that
this
document
prescribes something because i think if
we
have that requirement this is going to
potentially be blocked
on publication for
essentially an indefinite period of time
because the answer is we really don't
know what to do here i don't think
anyone has experience
using this successfully yet with a
variety of congestion controllers uh
certainly not the one that we specify in
the base draft which
uh you know is not really being widely
used um and so
my thought my personal opinion is that
uh this document can serve as a
mechanism document and if people have
strategies that they want to use
uh that they they find a success with
those can be follow-up documents that
are specified hey this is how you can
use act frequency for this this is how
you can use act frequency to achieve
this because even with a single
congestion controller you're not
necessarily going to be
have the same strategy so for example if
you want to use cubic with that
frequency in a data center versus cubic
with hack frequency on like the internet
with a very low latency uh network on
the internet like
or high latency network on the internet
i think the strategies are going to vary
i mean we don't know at this point what
those strategies are going to be at
least i am not aware of any
thanks matt
uh
great
all right i guess you knew i was going
to say
that
10 is not a bad number to kick out on
for a starting point it's probably a bad
number in the end it's probably a bad
number at a data center it's probably a
reasonable number for an internet path
um
can we just see what we can come up with
here
and see we can make a recommendation
before we publish of a starting value
from which we can work for that we
consider safe
because surely two is very conservative
and surely an rtt's worth or two rtt
smith is highly um controversial so we
must be able to say something well i
suggest we pump we we work on it
thanks cory yeah i mean there there are
some boundaries i think about like
trying to get an hack every rgt
typically and such just
for guardrails but that's about all all
that there is right now okay why don't i
just keep this open and we can we can
work on it over time it doesn't seem
like something we need to fix today
thanks
[Music]
okay um
so this is one that we talked about
uh quite a while ago um a number of
other people have looked at the
pr again um how much time do i have left
by the way
sorry how much time do i have left
you have about five minutes in
about five minutes
okay thank you all right so we can at
least go over this again and
uh swap it back in and if we don't get
to the end that's that's completely fine
um
so this is the
idea of
uh
okay
so
one act is sent immediately upon a
missing packet
um
however the next ack
say you have one missing packet and then
10 packets in a row arrive and you set
10 for your uh act eliciting threshold
then you'll get one immediate ack
and then
you know you'll have to wait for the
other 10 packets to arrive and then
you'll send another immediate act and
then you'll finally detect that that
like missing packet was lost
uh because
if it's threshold based and it's a
threshold based loss so you start out
with
the last threshold of three
the first act wasn't enough to
immediately declare the packet is lost
and so you have to wait for a timer
and so
timers can be relatively slow
especially in like low latency like data
center sort of applications
so this can actually substantially delay
loss detection in certain situations
versus the base draft once you start
bumping up the active eliciting
threshold
so
anyway the
potential solution to this is to
communicate the reordering threshold to
the receiver instead of just saying
ignore order
uh and then the receiver sends an
immediate ack whenever there's a missing
packet
in this range that basically would allow
the sender to immediately declare loss
so it's basically
an optimization
as well as kind of a safety mechanism to
say
i'm going to declare loss at this many
packets
and so whenever you see
you know a missing packet that is in
that range
and so that would allow me to
immediately declare loss like send me an
act immediately so i can like do that as
quickly as possible is basically what
this is saying is a mechanism
um it slightly reduces the number of
acts when packets are also received out
of order because if you get a twiddle
you know one software the other instead
of sending an immediate act and then
sending another immediate app when the
gap is filled
you
like don't send the first ack and then
the gap gets filled and like
everything's fine so
it turns out for uh reordering on the
internet twiddles i think are something
like 60 of all
reordering it's some huge number at
least last time i looked um
so
there might be some small
performance improvement in low scale
reuterium networks
um
but
anyway that's an overview of the issue
um especially now that we have dropped
we're going to drop ignore ce we have
the bits to
you know make this like a one byte
number
uh which seems like a sufficient amount
of
granularity or we can just make it of
our end it doesn't really matter
so if if people have comments please
jump in the queue now otherwise you know
we we can uh let's move on
but thank you ian
no drama
[Music]
jonah
to me this seems more useful than just
ignore order
but i also didn't review the whole
discussion on the github issue
thanks
that's my take as well
thank you very much uh for your time and
i think i will give my career
hi i'm martin duke from google i have no
slides but i'm here to talk about quick
lb
um
jonna did you want to have a comment for
the previous talk
[Music]
no okay
very good um
so uh the authors for quick ob are
pleased to report that all github issues
are currently closed um if you're
interested in that i invite you to look
at the change log
uh or the uh submit closed prs there the
only one that probably worth at least
bringing up is related to the crypto
review that we received on the for pass
algorithm uh so this is the short cid
encrypted version
um
uh there was a simple fix that they
suggested that we made there was another
fix
there was another suggestion to uh kind
of the best practice would be to make it
a 12-pass algorithm we declined to do
that for reasons that are probably
obvious and um christian submitted a pr
thank you christian that um
explained the reasoning there in the
security considerations i invite you to
look at that email file an issue if you
have a concern
and if you have any questions about that
now i'm happy to answer them but i
really wanted to talk about is just the
future path of this document um
as i said like we've kind of reached the
end of our um
editorial process as far as we can do it
uh so one option is just to go to
working with last call
um which will of course generate more
issues but then but basically move the
expedite moving the document forward uh
the second option is to wait for some
more code
um the current implementation status is
that they're to my knowledge two
load balancer side implementations um
one is mine based off of nginx and
there's one from ant financial
um there are a couple drafts out of date
but because they're both load balancers
and no servers have implemented at this
time we cannot interrupt because we need
both sides of that interaction
um
i am currently uh my current focus and
my day job is to implement quick lb for
google quiche
on the server side
um
so we will have a server implementation
soon
and also probably certainly within the
next 12 months to deploy this at google
so option two so option one is working
group last call immediately
option two is to wait for that
implementation deployment process to
continue um and then working with last
call
and um
option three i guess would be to wait
for uh more people who are not martin
duke to implement this thing but uh who
knows how long that will be
so um that is all i have to present and
i would love to hear comments from the
community of what they would like to see
before we work in loop last call
jonathan
when my audio comes up
yeah uh janna wanted to
uh read wanted me to relay because he
has audio trouble
um
about the difference between ignore
order and reordering threshold
um
if you want to retain ignore order
please speak up now
otherwise reordering threshold is the
lightest direction will go
okay so that was a comment
for ian i guess do you have a response
or
okay for that was about the reordering
threshold right
okay
yeah i know the audio is very bad over
there he just said like if somebody
wants to keep ignore order please speak
up now otherwise we will switch ah okay
um
wearing someone else's document but i
don't see anyone
commenting
nobody in the queue
so all right
so returning to the question does anyone
have an opinion about the maturity of
the quick lb document and his readiness
working group last call
yeah cool event again um i don't have a
concern to go to work in google glass
call right now but if there's like no
good reason uh that we need to publish
it immediately why don't we wait for
your implementation
okay i'm seeing thumbs up
uh sprinkling a thumbs up uh with that
sentiment um
which is fine with me so you will
probably not hear from me for a while
about this document
um
and uh like i will do another report
once things are a little more mature
at google um in terms of doing this work
uh and retry offload just while i'm up
here is in a similar stasis state but
there's no active invitation going on so
that is sort of in the deep freeze until
somebody is is
shown to care
um
are there any other questions for me
or comments
ian
ian sweat google i had a question for
the group actually i was curious if
anyone else
besides you at google is working on
a quick lb implementation
eric in yours getting up
eric kinnear apple um
i don't think we have plans to
immediately deploy anything but we've
certainly been looking and trying to
provide feedback as we go and need
something with a very similar set of
attributes so
i would not give up hope
and i i would just like
while i'm up here make an appeal to like
server implementers that i mean one of
the intents here like the original
target use case for this was the cloud
that um cloud l4 balancers um
would implement this and then you know
people could deploy quick servers and
they could all interoperate um i think
certainly our long-term plan is to do
that in google cloud
um
so
you know i think those of you trying to
position your servers like this might be
an interesting market opportunity
um
anyway if there are no other questions
i'm going to return
the balance my time to the group thank
you
thank you
cool
next up we have
christian talk about quick time stamps
as we enter the um
phase where we stop talking about
adopted work items um and talk about
related or potential new work
do you want me to present the slides or
can you do it
you can you can take remote control
christine
if you would okay i i i did not expect
that i'm sorry take me some time
we can do it if you prefer
yes please
okay
christian the sites are uploaded you
just have to request click the request
button and then you can control them
you don't have to share your stream
so what is the request button
the request slides just click it and
select your slides
looks like a piece of paper the other
people think
it's the second it's a second i think
it's the second from the
left
just click it
second from the slayer
it's not visible on my screen there's
the raised hands and then the next one
to it
oh that one
yes
there you go and now you can
you know
one learns every day
yeah here we are
sure
good
okay so timestamps so what time do you
talk
the question is shall we work on it
and
[Music]
i i have been working on the timestamp
project for some time
and it has not
been progressing
very much because i mean some people did
implement it but
apart from pico quick and i believe
the light speed implementation i have
not heard feedback
the first design of the time stamp was
to solve the asymmetric case
in which there is high bandwidth
available on the same path
but limited bandwidth on the or
congestion on the return pass
and
the the failure mode there is that you
can often observe congestion
on the global pathway it's only caused
by the return pass
and the response shall be very different
so
with a time stamp
what happens is that the acknowledgement
are sent in a packet that is time
stamped
and the
the
congestion controller can use that
timestamp to understand which way the
condition happened
and trigger a different reaction
and that suppress things like a
longer t measurement or
wrong decision condition control or even
stereotype transmissions
so that was one
one use case for the timestamp
the next use case for the timestamp
is clearly for multipass
in the case of multi-pass we have
configuration
in which we have one
high bandwidth path
with a relatively long rtt
and one a low delay pass with a slightly
smaller bandwidth
what we see is that if we send
acknowledgement
through the short pass that's not the
path on which the packet was sent
we improve responsiveness we get better
connection control we get better loss
recovery
but
we need to have a smart way to measure
the actual rtt of the pass that combines
half delays one way and the other
and a comment i received on that
implementation
is that it it requires a phd to
understand you do rtt measurement
well
i don't think it does but then i do have
another phd so who knows
the um
the timestamp implement timestamp option
fixes that very cleanly because i mean
if you have a timestamp in your packets
you can measure each half delay
each way
and then
you can the implementation becomes
completely straightforward
and it's much easier now there are other
use cases for timestamps i mean they are
very useful if you do
delay-based congestion control things
that led back for example
but also high start
i mean if you if you use timestamps
during the high start phase in cubic
you will very quickly notice the
increase of
one way delay
that high start will realize on
and so i think that there is a strong
use case for having time stamps in quake
now
that dwarf i have is at version 10.
a very simple draft i mean uh
it just defined a timestamp
for m with a type and the timestamp as a
number of microseconds
[Applause]
and an enable timestamp transport option
which is basically what you find for
every extension the couple of a frame
and a transport parameter to negotiate
its usage
i would think that given that it is very
simple and they are well understood use
case we could take it on in the working
group
but it has been a long time and so
since that is a long time
my question there is
what next i mean
shall i
go ride against another windmill or
maybe just enjoy the sunsets
okay we'll not leave you on that leave
you there
so next step really is
does working group want to adopt the
draft
does working good want to discuss it
maybe it's not the right way maybe we
need something more complex than the
secretize time
there was a proposal to completely
change the arc format
so that we can have add a
delayed enact delay on each packet
we could do something a bit more complex
at ntp which
has basically three parameters middle
center timestamp the last received
timestamp and the delay since the last
receive which makes measurements even
more precise
but at that point uh
i am really wondering whether we should
pursue this or not
so
questions
university and i'm a newcomer of the itf
and i'm really interested in the quick
the quick working group
and the art group is
is also working on adding time and stamp
to the quick so i think it is really
important to add some timeliness
signature like
time step to the quick mechanism but i
think there are there are really
something that we need to have a
discussion and some implementation
should be more discussed in detail
let's say firstly
is it mandatory for the sender and the
receiver to do the clocks uh
synchronization
if they have to let's say generates
their own time step or is the timestamp
is only generated by the server itself
if the time step is only generated by
the server itself so the time step
cannot be uh be used by the client but
to tell something about the information
of the timeliness
but only to measure less the the value
delay from the center side
so i think maybe some more specification
may be
included in the draft and
is it also necessary for the
for all the package to contain a time
step frame or maybe some kind of package
that says acknowledge
the acknowledgments
the package visa acknowledgment that
needs the time step
so i think maybe some details may be
specified okay then my opinion thank you
thank you for the suggestion i think
that uh
at a high level i agree with you that we
should have a discussion inside the
working group
about what is needed and get feedback
and i think that's one of the reasons
like to see some adoption so we can get
these
multiple
people working together
on the issue of clock synchronization we
had a debate on the structure of the
firm
we had feedback actually several years
ago that there is that the frame should
be as simple as possible
and the document should only specify the
firm that the mechanism
because the mechanisms will be
the combination of say that frame and
the immersion firm etc
but i mean at a high level yes we should
absolutely have a discussion
ayan
uh yes ian sweat google um
i i was a co-author on one of those
documents that you mentioned about
multiple timestamps or timestamps per
packet and
um that is not being actively pursued by
us right now except
we we do have it implemented for one
internal project which has a very
non-standard congestion controller that
i think actually get published at some
point um i could dig it up but uh it's
so it's kind of in this weird state
where we basically just published it
just so it was kind of out there
but it's not something we're actually
pursuing i will say just from an
implementation perspective it's a lot
more convenient
to like be able to curry the time stamp
in
when you receive an acknowledgement
now there's a number of ways of like
making that happen in the code like you
could store the timestamp and always
have it received right before the act or
something like that but like just from a
code structure perspective having the
timestamp available even if it's only
one times down
at the same time that you're processing
the act
is is super convenient from a code
structure perspective but um
i guess i don't think you should give up
on this work i just am not
i don't have really good advice on what
to do next unfortunately but those are
my experiences
yes i mean
i i i do i do agree with the fact that
it's that's what we have in the pico
click implementation that the time stamp
is always sent together with the axe but
yes
martin
martin do uh google um
so i i believe i understand the case for
multipath but i'm not sure i understand
the justification for single path
benefit i mean if
if you detect that it is
like reverse path act congestion would
you like send more aggressively and just
make the act congestion worse
or what is the response if you obtain
this information in the single path case
well one way would be to tune the
frequency for example
okay
but also uh the the other way would be
to uh
understand that you
i mean
you you can avoid use
i have seen two usage avoid spur use
retransmission
and in high start
avoid
exiting i start too early because of
events on the act pass
okay i mean i'll think through that i'm
sure you've reasoned about it correctly
but thanks
you know
i think china's maybe having some audio
issues again i'll dive in with a simple
question there's some talk about um
time synchronization stuff that sounds
super complicated
like
i i think starting with something simple
if if we were to do this work at all but
starting something simple wouldn't
preclude more complicated stuff coming
in the future
we have space for extensions and frames
like
if there's some usage of this thing um
go that way you're sure some specifics
could change but um i'm seeing a few use
cases
and this is without a chair hat on with
the chair hat on i'd really like to to
understand in if people would really
object to this kind of work like we're
this isn't adopted but we'd be seeking a
clearer idea of if if we should be
seeking adoption or not for this work
because it's been kicking around for a
long time now i think we we need to make
a decision
what to do
thanks
uh jay collin um
i i think that there are some good use
cases for this uh you can apply this to
do like chirping and find
and apply some of the path dispersion
bandwidth detection techniques um
with this and i i
you know
do we need it
i could use it i think but uh
you know so i'm broadly supportive but
uh i would
i guess
like to see some development in the use
cases maybe
um
to kind of get a better handle on
on
other ways people anticipate using it
but yeah i think to me this looks useful
thanks
john linux i mentioned this on the zulip
but i'll repeat it here
the uh
i think this would be useful for a lot
of the real-time
media cases all the uh
or most of the rmcat style
uh feedback mechanisms um most notably
uh google cc which is the
congestion controller and the webrtc
use time stamps for one-way delay to
measure
to get the low delay uh real-time media
congestion so i think
if we want to for a lot of the use cases
where we're going to do
either rtp over quick or media over
quick i think this would probably be a
useful thing
yoshinichida from amazon web service
i'm not very you know following up
quick discussion but uh
so i'm wondering about measuring one
weight rate for high stats because no
high start is center side logic so you
need to receive back anyhow
so unless there is a condition on the
arc path
i don't know if the measuring one-way
pass is that useful maybe
we might want to see more use cases
spencer dawkins uh
christian am i understanding your your
ask is uh
about adoption of this draft in the
working group is that is that right
yes
that's really the case i mean because i
mean i
i don't want to be continuing to push a
draft and there is episodic feedback
every two years yeah if it is adopted
i mean then i'm going to continue
working on it otherwise whatever
could i ask the chairs to
help at least me understand what the bar
that christians should be looking at for
this is
for for adoption in the working group
i mean
is it is it close enough for you all to
call and say who's interested
speaking this is a chair with my hat on
um i think having this discussion at
this session has been good some of it is
is
knowing if the author wants to seek
adoption at all if they feel ready um
i
i'm seeing
generally positive comments like that
this could be useful
um
especially because of the format and
that they could apply to different
things but then
a few people saying they don't quite
understand the use cases like i think
what probably needs to happen is a
little bit more follow-up discussion on
the mailing list um and that um
probably i need to confer with matt as
well but i i'd kind of be leaning on
issuing an adoption call just to see
to flesh out
people who would strongly object to
adopting that work right now um and and
the reasons why and therefore you know
if if if those reasons are things that
christine wouldn't want to address then
he can he can go away and maybe in the
future somebody else can come and pick
up this style of work
that's what i'd be looking for
does that make sense spencer
yeah yes it does uh
so uh the other thing i'm thinking
you know
i think jonathan linux and i were headed
the same place
roughly which is uh
as
we are
you know like uh avt core has just
adopted uh an rtp over
quick
uh dra draft
uh and we had a
uh media over quick buff this week that
was not as much of a train wreck as it
could have been
um you know if if if
especially if that second uh
chunk of work uh gets chartered between
now and november
uh i think i think it would be
you know i would i would i would like to
see uh
an adoption call go out sometime between
you know like i say roughly
uh when it seems right to the chairs but
uh i know which i know which way i would
i would um
on an adoption call but do the right
thing of course
thanks um i also see there's some some
discussion in you know in the in the
jabber that i've been trying to keep up
with
um
i you know we will take on both these
comments and
uh matt and i will have a discussion i
think
all right do you have the ones from
china
the big one from janna
yet janna had problems joining or like
not joining the cube with the audio i
guess
um
yeah i can read john's comment uh
is mentioning that they should be
work on the variation of the one-way
delay which is correct i mean
all the measurements of delays over the
internet
are uncertain in the sense that you
don't know which the reference is
exactly
so
you'd never measure absolute delay
because there is all your equations all
your systems of the question
end up on the terminate
and you have to make an arbitrary choice
of whether the delays one way or the
other way what you do measure then are
the variation of the delay
and and that is correct
and
and we could go explaining that i
it's kind of obvious too but
the kind of stuff that i would like to
see after the adoption
because uh clearly uh that could be done
by a pr in the draft and a discussion
and i don't disagree with china that's
what actually used but
but yes i mean i think
i'd be very happy to watch with jenna if
someone if someone is actually working
on this and wants to improve
and want to become a co-author or
something i'll be happy to have one too
i mean it's not okay
i want to own that same
i think my audio might be working again
okay oh wow okay awesome
so yeah i agree with you i look clarify
this because i think this is a point of
contact confusion oftentimes for folks
um
just calling it one-way delay delta
is it makes it clearer however i think
my higher order point here is that i
think the draft is useful because it
allows people to actually have a
mechanism to experiment with yeah
but in in in without actually having a
lot of people
asking
for how for for usage of this thing
it'll be difficult to design a mechanism
that's going to
um
be worth standardizing that's my opinion
i think that we need people with use
cases before we can actually adopt and
standardize something
okay thanks johnna um
we're at time for this item um i could
say we'll we'll go away and do some
discussion um with various people um
this has been very useful so thank you
all for the comments
thank you christian thank you
thank you
next up is uh jake holland
hello
are you at slides
you're
uh
i don't have any means to run the slides
doing
oh on my phone is that the way i'm
supposed to do it
could you uh bring up if that's possible
oh great yeah hi i'm jake holland
multicast enthusiast um i'm here to talk
about uh our
multicast quick proposal
uh so i'll just be
mainly going over the actual proposal uh
if you want to see why
uh i went over that there was a barb off
at
the remote 111
and there's links to that and the slides
there we also went over a little bit at
that
went over a little bit of it in uh sec
dispatch at 112.
this proposal is largely a follow
follow-up to that sick dispatch 112
discussion where
some of the feedback we got is that we
needed a
specific
protocol proposal for the
security characteristics we were looking
to get with our multicast security
consideration stock that tried to go
over the security considerations for
using multicast to deliver web traffic
specifically but also for
generalized
non-web
traffic
delivered over multicast
so that's the well
i won't go in depth but uh i'll just try
to give a kind of a really basic
overview next slide please
thank you
so the basic idea is we're just
supporting
source specific ip multicast
this is anchored to a unicast connection
so
there's always a unicast connection
between a server and a client and then
the server can tell the client
by the way some of the data that i'm
trying to send you the way you should
get it is you should join this multicast
session you'll see some
1rtt quick packets there here are their
keys to decode obviously since it's
multicast the packets are identical for
every receiver these are shared
symmetric keys
that's one of the things we get into in
the in the security consideration stack
that's essentially the
security consideration section for this
document
um
and uh
because they are widely distributed
shared keys we also have separate um
integrity packets that are
anchored on the unicast connection to
that mean that even though the keys are
shared the packets cannot be spoofed
they must be
proven to have been sent by the actual
server that you're talking to
the server controls the entire
sort of
multicast
listening process on behalf of the
client they tell the client what to join
the client's not required to join these
these sessions but may join in order to
sort of get a better delivery
scalability
and
the client provides limits so the all
the all the flow control and congestion
control is different in a way sort of
dictated by the
requirements of multicast and we go over
some of that in the document but some of
it is sort of
why we're proposing this as experimental
at this time
uh but what the client provides is some
limits that the server's responsible for
staying within as it tells the client
what to do right
and the client sends ax for all the
packets that it receives and this is
very similar in a lot of ways to the
multi-path work
um the the packets are just interpreted
as a part of the unicast connection that
you've got
uh it's anchored on a client on a
channel id rather than a connection id
but that's essentially just a layer of
indirection to the connection id
and the reason for that is basically
that
again it's
shared identical packets that are sent
to many receivers and so
the server has to choose that
destination connection id
essentially connection id but that's a
channel id in the place that the
connection id goes in the multicast
packets
and the the unicast
frames communicate what those channels
what those channel ids are
all right next slide please
so the the multicast channels are only
for server to client data only for
server initiated streams essentially it
can be used for datagrams as well
not so much for web traffic because h3
datagrams
have a have a client chosen
id inside them but for non-web datagrams
it still should be possible
for server initiated streams it also we
think is possible
um
and the packets are just interpreted in
the context of that connection the the
of the unicast connection that you
already have
um
yeah
uh
any any questions about any of this i'd
be happy to go over but uh
let's just let's just move on for time
here
um again for discussion uh yeah next
slide
uh for discussion um
uh so we're working on an implementation
uh this is in conjunction with uh
several members of the w3 multicast
community w3c
multicast community group
we've been basing it so far on the
on the google quiche implementation
working toward a demo that could run in
a browser but
you know we just want to prove to
ourselves that it will work essentially
but we think that it will
um
in terms of implementation status or the
the maturity the of the spec and what we
think we solved uh we don't know of any
reasons that this does not match the
security considerations document but we
do think for web traffic we've recently
noticed that we probably need to
include something that more strictly
enforces the origin policy or allows the
the browser to enforce origin policy on
the
uh multicast packets that are received
we do think this is possible we have a
couple ways
to do it
that's not yet part of the draft but
just by
because the packets
are
integrity protected and can't be spoofed
we think that for example we could
include an
origin frame
in the multicast packets and this would
uh give the browser the information it
needs to
avoid including anything for a wrong
origin uh in the data that's processing
uh so we we don't think that this should
be considered
mixed content
but
opinions may differ on this point and
we'd be interested in hearing reasons
why we might be wrong here
next slide
uh we have a number of protocol
extensions and the reasons are
basically all just driven by um you know
we're asking for basically ten new
frames at this point
um
we outline them in the draft uh we have
you know this is part of the
implementation that's uh that's working
there
uh but there's essentially just
management of the
multicast channels in the unicast stream
where the server tells the client about
them
management of the client state
and then the acts that are associated
with it
plus the integrity guarantees that
require a separate uh integrity path
and we can go into the details of all
this uh i'd be happy to talk offline as
well we probably don't have
uh time for as detailed a discussion as
what we saw in some of the more uh
uh standardized pieces earlier in the
session
but next slide
the basic question i've got is
is this interesting to anyone we think
that we can solve a big scale problem
here um we certainly would like to
deploy this we're interested in
deploying it uh
non-browser at first because we've had
sort of a
skepticism i think from the browser
community so far
but from the isp community we have uh
you know
some consensus that uh the scaling
problems need to be solved there's too
many there's uh too many
events that are sort of exceeding the
capacity of the networks to deliver
when there's popular content this is
primarily driven by
[Music]
by popular sports and by large downloads
most large downloads would not be web
would not be web traffic but the popular
sports often is particularly when you
consider that
a lot of the smart tvs basically are
using web apis underneath
uh something like 60 plus percent
growing last i heard um
but
you know in addition various forms of uh
you know
browser apps and and
a lot of the clients actually using
browsers inside as well
so um
yeah i guess my first question is like
does anybody think this is worthwhile a
and if so like
what do you recommend we should do
before asking for adoption or
you know where should this go
uh and we'll be discussing this more in
mbo indian next session by the way so
come there if you're interested we can
get into it more
alex
hi alex ranowski google um i was looking
over the slides before you're talking i
mostly had the observation that i feel
like what you're proposing is not
something that is in quick but something
that could be built on top of either tcp
or quick with the type of control
channel stuff that you're doing so my
question is really is quick the right
place to do this or is this a separate
protocol for here is how i want to join
a multicast thing and a separate framing
layer for here is the multicast
available data
well
uh we're looking for some frames in the
in the iana registries for quick um
you know does it have to be quick
uh no i mean you can have different
multicast protocols that's possible
we could do something that has the same
security properties that's not quick
or we could have our own proprietary
extension if we're going to be shipping
fat clients um but
uh we would like to aim toward an
eventual
uh
something that can eventually be
included in browsers so that's kind of
where i'm coming from with the quick
effort thanks
hey larry zachary so i i like to select
this um already when lucas came up with
it a few years ago and i'm glad to see
that it's sort of being progressing
um
because we all had this gap in transport
right between the unicast and the
multicast and we could never sort of
figure out how can actually leverage the
power that multicast potentially offers
more easily for applications and for
um you know
users and then this
goes in that direction which is sort of
kind of exciting um
i don't want to speak about the adoption
call but sort of in terms of what i
would see do you think about this sort
of
how general a mechanism this could be i
mean there's some obvious use cases
right that are motivating this but
um this is sort of the first time that
we have an approach that mixes
unicast or multicast pretty easily and
efficiently it would be great if it
would be usable for lots of stuff thank
you
yeah that's a good question um
i guess i would point to uh the the warp
and rush proposals we think we can just
do as is because these use server
initiated data for pushing from the
server side so
uh
that that's the demo i'd like to run uh
you know inside a custom browser
is just use web transport
with the existing thing and it doesn't
have to change the application at all
i think that
you know server push based
hls or dash could do the same thing
although server push i gather is being
removed from the browsers unfortunately
so
uh i'm not sure that'll be any better in
the near future but we could also like
keep
keep a fork that keeps the server push
cache around and try it there for the
same kind of thing
but yeah we think it should be
transparent for the apps
yeah thanks
mike bishop um i'm a little surprised
that you're putting quick frames on the
multicast stream i would have
would have thought the multicast stream
would just be
raw data delivery and then the frames on
the
unicast quick session
tell you what to do with it basically
uh so
one of the one of the actually
nice design choices and in quick the
consequences of this are that it works
pretty well to just put the the quick
frames on the
uh on the multicast stream
and then use the same encryption
strategies
and use the same
use the same deframing
this is actually a very similar problem
to like the multi-pathwork right
this is just
you know you can have a stream that's
partially carried on one path partially
charted on another path they can be
combined as long as they have the same
data at all the same offsets right right
so
that's essentially what we're doing here
and
so you have a shared path on the
multi-path connection
well it's an alternate path for the
multi you know the the the multicast
uh the multicast channel is just a an
alternate network path that carries the
same data
so once you've decoded it then you merge
it as part of the same connection for
your packet processing
and you can have almost all the same
behavior it's just a you know yeah there
are some differences in like flow
control and congestion control there's
some differences in the uh the
connection id versus the channel id
um
but
most of the packet processing is
actually the same and and works out
pretty well
chair interrupt here we're we're over
time now um i'd like to thank everyone
uh jake sorry to interrupt you but i
think we got some feedback there um
which is kind of good i'd encourage
hallway discussion for anyone that
didn't make the cut we had one more talk
from emil um which we didn't make time
for i apologize emil um
this was in relation to a side meeting
that was held yesterday i believe some
of the participants of the quick working
group were there um
i i wasn't able to attend unfortunately
my understanding is this relates to
quick observability tooling
visualization analysis my kind of chair
comment with a hat on is that's work
that um is completely related to quick
and i'd love to see
happen um in the quick working group
where it makes sense so um i'd encourage
that kind of thing to be proposed that
the next quick agenda
if it makes sense and please speak to
the chairs about that um in in future
and we can have that discussion a bit
earlier maybe um that would be great
i don't know if matt has any closing
comments
nope um okay on that note i'd like to
thank our jobscribe and notetakers very
much i'd like to thank zahed for being
on the ground and helping with uh
the delegation of responsibilities and
everyone
have a great rest of your week
and a good lunch
thank you
bye
and the youtube folks are like in theory
but they're like
this doesn't work