okay uh i have my clock says we're right
at the top of the hour and uh we're
prettiest pretty small group so i think
we should just um
to get started
the join rate is uh not
not high and uh first i want to thank
you for joining um
this session uh we we conduct these
sessions pretty much before every uh
meeting or have done since um 2020
and the goal is at this point really is
just to get give people a chance to um
become reacquainted from medical if if
they haven't used it for a while and and
to point out
any uh new
uh features that um
have been
incorporated
based on community community input since
the last time we used it for an itf
meeting so
we have alessandra amerante here today
from
midiko which is great
and uh again thanks to everybody for
joining i i've uploaded um or i'm sorry
i have not uploaded uh i'm sharing some
slides
um
here uh
today and i'll run through those really
quickly and then and then
just run through a few
reminders but um as i mentioned earlier
if you have questions feel free to to
drop them in the chat and we'll um we'll
pick them up or
uh
also one of the goals of this session is
just test video and audio setup so we'd
be happy to
have folks raise their hands and then we
can
do
those kinds of tests as well so
uh yeah so with that i'll get started um
the slides that i'm showing here are
generated off of the template that is
provided in
the working group
chairs uh sorry the session chairs
checklist
uh which you can find from the
preparing
web page on the itf website
so i encourage you for sure to
take a look at those pages and
and just review them that they're pretty
short and they have some nuggets that
can be useful for
just getting ready for
uh sessions at the upcoming meeting
or even for interim meetings between
them
uh between ietf meetings uh just a
reminder that we're being recorded this
is record
ah
marco uh
i apologize yeah yeah yeah i see now
here i i sent that uh
that was my mistake and i copied and
pasted too quickly so i just sent out an
update with the correct links apologies
for any trouble
um
this is the note well again this session
is being recorded and as all its uh
meaning sessions are this session is
recovered by the itf note well i suspect
everybody here has is pretty familiar
with it
but it's always fun to read
a couple times a year which which of
course i do
again
this session is being recorded these are
some tips you'll see that i'm using
earbuds i'm actually using bluetooth
earbuds um which can work pretty well uh
but there are also sometimes uh
advantages to using wired your earplugs
and i understand um
earbuds sorry and i understand uh from
my younger daughters that those are
actually um
uh a la mode these days so uh don't
don't be ashamed to use wired
earphones and microphones
if you're on site this is the same as
was as was
true at 113
but if you're going to be on site it is
required to use medico to sign in for
sessions those
that sign in populates
the blue sheets
and um also provides uh qmat integrated
queue management for both in-person and
remote participants i think it worked
pretty well at 113 and that's the
feedback we got um so this
feature
is continued to 114
and if you're using you can use either
the light version or the uh full version
of the
medical client and if you're using the
light version you'll
notice
that it doesn't send audio or video by
default which is perfect for that
situation
you can use the full client
but you just have to make sure not to
send audio or video because
the in-room av
setup will take care of that for you if
you're actually in the room and of
course remote participants should just
whether you're a chair of a session or a
full
or or a participant you should use the
full version because um
that which is what what i'm using now
and what we all should be using now
since we're all remote uh and that
handles everything all in one place um
super handy
um
i'll just pause there
because this last slide is really just a
review of what i think everybody here
saw in the email which is we're having
these moderated test sessions which are
really just maybe more guided test
sessions because they're not really
moderated people can jump in whenever
they want uh there will be on-demand
testing beginning july 15th that is this
this friday um
and once
after friday the new version of um
medical be uh
deployed and you can set up um
test sessions and again instructions on
how to do that provided in the
chair guides uh on the web pages uh at
the url that you see here
um and you can you can set that up it
won't create a virtual interim meeting
or anything it's simply a test session
that you can use to test things out
amongst yourselves as chairs or you can
even invite your um presenters to join a
test session and you can test
everything their setups your setups
everything
if you if you set one of those up
and then in addition there will be um
i see i see questions in the chat and i
will answer those
as i see them so joel uh in the full in
the full um client you don't have to do
anything to turn off uh the icons um
oh i see incoming audio video yeah yeah
yeah
okay
great
uh
yeah and people are people are already
responding fantastic thanks for asking
the question though um
if you're asking the question i'm sure
other people have the same one
um then the last item here just in terms
of uh other resources
uh we have this at 113 and we're going
to do it again at 1
uh 14.
on site there will be a room set up
which is exactly like a session room and
again uh you can sign up via
a notepad again the link is is available
from the
chair
chair resources page on the website and
if you just sign up for a session
that'll reserve that room for you
and you can walk into the room
you'll see the setup exactly as it is
for the meeting
and um
you can
connect to a test session including um
and test out the audio and video in in
the room
uh and as well with remote either
chairs or remote participants so
uh
yeah i think that takes me uh through
all the slides uh that i have uh the two
things that i think i know are different
and alessandra i'll
give you this warning that if i missed
something please please jump in and let
me know the two things that for sure are
different um
uh
the link said i see that
michael thinks go to on-site link okay
i'll check that out if there's
if you can tell me exactly which links
are
uh should be changed uh let me know
michael um
so so back to the updates uh the one is
that uh medico is now integrated with
zulip so this chat that we're using in
medico
actually um connects to the um
itf zoolip server in a in a stream
called testing and
just as with previously with xmpp
um
the the medico um
view you see is connected to the to the
more general group chat service
previously was xmpp jabber and now it's
zulip um so you can also use uh the
zulip web interface or a zoolop client
to connect to those same streams
um
and
the other change is that on the
uh
lite client
you can also find a link to the to the
chat stream so
uh previously there wasn't a link there
and now there is so uh that answer is a
a pretty common request we had to make
uh that link uh available for
on-site participants who are using the
lite client
and um so that you can have
you don't need to necessarily fire up a
separate um
client or use the full version of me to
go to get access to the to the chat
stream for any session that you wanted
to you were using the like client for
um
and alexander those i think those are
the two big changes uh am i missing did
i miss anything else
uh yeah i know as you said uh those are
the
the biggest changes uh uh let me check
my notes
and uh
yeah we made some changes about these
lights sharing uh feature because we
were asked
to give chairs the possibility to take
the control of the slides back once they
handed it over to somebody else and this
is now available in each earth interface
and
also there is now a button to do a sort
of a bulk update of all slide decks that
are available on the data tracker even
though this should not be needed because
now we have fixed the wrong behavior
that we had at last meeting where slides
were not automatically being pulled from
the data tracker at the room's opening
and uploaded into miteko how this has
been fixed so
there should be no need to to do any
update any upload manually by the chairs
and uh
yeah yeah another minor thing is that
now
pronouns that you set in the data
tracker
should be displayed if you over hover
any
any participant in the participant list
if of course if any pronouns has been
set in the data tracker profile
so i don't see
any actually for the current online
participants
so i cannot double check that but i can
try to join with another user
so when i tried to join this session
just now and uh and i got the as others
got that we got the light uh connection
i actually was told that i needed to
rotate my browser
on my desktop before i could use it and
i couldn't do anything with it
um
so
that was really difficult and i had no
way of getting to the full no no no way
of finding or discovering the full name
except that i know the urls well enough
that i just guessed
um
so yeah i i i and of course of course as
soon as i did the other thing then i got
kicked out of the other tab when i went
back to try to to tell you what it was
again it logged me into the other thing
that was rotated it kicked me out of
this one
so
i think it would be good to have uh um
i mean i think i guess you want to
encourage people to use the light
version who are on site
but i think it would be very good to
have to be able to switch back and forth
much more clearly
um
if that's a possibility if you can just
throw a link or something or i don't
know what
um
otherwise i think that most people are
going to on site are going to learn very
quickly to just use the full version and
hope they remember to turn off their
microphone
yeah i have to apologize again michael
thanks for pointing that out i
uh it was my mistake to send the in
sending the wrong version it's a wrong
link the light link
um so sorry for the trouble there
um but it's an interesting point about
if people
unintentionally click on
the uh the icon for example
in um
in data tracker
from their desktop on and to reach the
lite version
uh since they're next to each other
uh handling that case
might be worth looking into for sure
um
andy thanks for raising your hand please
go ahead
a couple quick questions first of all
can you hear and see me okay
yeah you look great
perfect and the second question is um if
i am the person who has the slides
loaded and i'm projecting the slides
and there's someone who's speaking who's
in the room who has the
the like client on their phone how do i
hand over control of the
of the of
putting the slides to the person
to the speaker or is that not possible
yeah surely it's possible uh you said if
the the people that should present uh
has the delight client right
yes on your phone
yeah as a chair you can just go to on
the participants list and you'll see a
a control that allows you to pass the
slides control to somebody else and this
is only available to chat so when the
system recognizes you as chair so now
this is available to greg for instance
and
just like you have to be sharing slides
not sharing screen
exactly yeah
right
right yeah and i think that there's some
chairs that may still be confused about
that
yeah yeah what i've done in the past is
i pre-loaded all the slides
and then i
shared the slides directly from mute
echo
yeah and that's correct and this way is
lights will also be displayed in the
room and everything should work if you
want to just pass the control to
somebody else just go just find him
in the participants list and hand handy
control over screen
perfect that's all i need to know thank
you exactly and you can also take the
control back when it's done if it
doesn't stop manually the
controlling of the slides
excellent cool
uh the one tip i'll say is that it's
only possible to have one um because i i
run into this personally so you have to
um
be sure that you're just sharing one um
set of slides at a time
so uh
yeah okay
great great question thank you andy
bye-bye
uh let me just get back to the slides
and then
see if i can find my chat window
great
um
i do not see any other questions in chat
um does does anybody have a question or
i don't see anybody in the queue
uh does anybody have a question does
anybody want to test their audio or
video while we're all here
uh
okay
i'm gonna try
the
pool
feature just to
oh that's uh
that's wrong um
i didn't for my home okay uh so i've
started a poll
uh
just to see
who would be attending
uh 114 or participating in 114 in person
um
so uh that should be going on right now
uh and you should have been notified
um
we'll give it a few minutes
so you can hop in
um
uh just testing out
we'll give a five we'll use the counter
countdown counter we'll give it five
minutes uh
so there should be a countdown counter
now in the bottom of the screen so you
can see that feature in running
just trying to push all the buttons here
still don't see anybody in the queue
uh
don't see any questions
so uh
alessandra is there anything else you
think we ought to cover while we're
here
nope don't think so
okay
yeah hi shipping please go ahead
uh can you hear me
yeah very well
i'm a new chair so i know nothing let me
ask some silly question first uh
how do i
uh
start the mi echo
in
as a chair rather than a
you know a common participant
ah that's a great question uh so there
is magic
what happens is that when you uh click
on the url either through the data
tracker agenda or somewhere else for a
session
you log in using your data tracker
credentials
and medico
can tell from your roles in data tracker
if you should be chair for a particular
session
or should have that
those capabilities so when i clicked on
or i loaded the url for this session
i've been identified as a chair for this
session and so i automatically have the
chair rules and abilities
and this is um
this is a great uh this would be a great
example of where setting up a test
session in medico might be super helpful
because
you can set up a test session as a chair
and then you can see what medical look
like looks like as a chair
thank you very much the second question
is i saw you just now you start a timer
so how can i start this timer because we
may need to you know control people's
time
yeah that's a great question you should
see
as a chair uh and what i'll do is i'll
stop sharing this screen and i will
share my full screen so
you will see
everything
[Music]
you should see my pointer you can see
that the controls i have up here there's
this countdown clock uh control and you
can
start the timer
uh through the controls uh available in
this in this model so you'll it'll pop
up and uh it'll appear for everybody
once you start and you can set it to be
any time
where do you click to start the the
timer
didn't see
ah okay uh
yes
okay yeah this these are the general uh
controls that you'll see so you'll see
it'll be slightly different if you join
the session as chair
uh but
it'll be
uh this kind of
where where most of the controls are for
the session
okay thank you
any any other questions or
no
um so for sure you
uh
were able to use the
the hand raising tool and also the audio
stream tool so that's great uh i'll
leave this view
open sorry another question how do i
share the slides
oh fantastic um
so there are there are
uh two ways to do that uh and i confess
i'm not as adept as as possible the
preferred way to do that
is to open the meeting materials
uh
and i'm not i'm not doing this correct
correctly
so
alessandro i will ask you to help me out
because
i have forgotten how to do that myself
to be honest
yeah what was the question i was
distracted actually yeah the question is
how how to share slides and i want to
share both sharing pre-loaded slides
and um
yeah
this light so you have the
uh share preload this lights button just
next to the webcam icons where all the
controls are you have the microphone the
webcam the share screen share slides and
join the queue
okay let me um
yeah
uh let me see if i can show this in
action
thank
you
okay this will be so
try that yeah i can't show you the
actually how that works but there
right there is the icon and this is the
this is the point i made earlier is that
this
stream for sharing the desktop is now
occupied by me showing my screen so i
have to stop that and then
uh if i do stop that then i can share
a preloaded slide but i can't show you
what that looks like
but here
i will just share the slides and you can
see what it looks like and then
for me as chair i can or s because i
have slide control i can control which
slide is being shown
yeah actually uh shipping if rex stops
sharing his slides if you hit the same
button that's the the shares like ask to
share slides i think it's named in your
ui you just have to be moderated so you
you need somebody to accept your
requests and then you'll see the very
same interface that you'll see
automatically as chair without any need
to for approval in that case
yeah so if you want to try that
i can also trigger it
to you if you want so
yep and i see that we are looking at
your slides
so now you should you should as
alessandra mentioned you should have
control over
the slides through a bar at the bottom
of the window
yeah and you can also use arrows on the
keyboard if you want
um
i am a little bit confused so am i
selling the slides now yeah
you you are controlling the slides that
have been loaded into medico so
this is this is the
yeah
so just now because i selected this
ietf114
test session so i think that it's now
shown on the slide but i think that
at the beginning uh which button do you
click to exit all the buttons at the top
like the yeah it's one of the buttons at
the top now i triggered the button for
you
just to to show this other possibility
but if i now
stop this light sharing if you hit the
it should be the second button from the
from the left just next to the hand icon
yeah it looks like a little document
with a line through it if you're not
sharing
okay thank you
and and
one of the important points that you've
brought up is that
pre-loading slides
is really
a much better way to share slides during
the session so if you are sharing a
session and you have presenters that
will be using slides
obviously it's
nice to have them loaded into data
tracker because
then everybody can see them even if
they're not using
the full
go interface for example they're in the
room using the light interface and want
to see the slides separately
but also it just makes
it much smoother uh so you don't rely on
your network connection to
to share the slides
right understood
okay fantastic thanks for asking that
question that's a great question and um
definitely an important point
and i see marco in the chat has provided
a link to the uh
guide for chairs of medical sessions so
that's that's also useful and might
provide some info
about topics you hadn't thought about or
didn't encounter but um would be good to
know
uh our our session let me go back to the
show of hands tool
and see i'll end the session uh so
uh
it looks like um
eight of the folks here will be on
site and then are in person so should
say and
uh
three didn't raise their hand so um
uh they will be i suppose remote at this
point so
that's actually um
uh great i'm looking forward to seeing a
lot of people uh
to catch up with people in person and
and of course if you're
remote you can um
hang out in i think the gather
space will still be available
um and
the medico
sessions uh during the week will help
you join the the actual um
working sessions uh
so uh
we're now about 30 minutes into the into
the session and i'm hap i'm happy to
hang out um
for the remainder uh i think it's
getting close to the end of the day for
alessandro so
um
if there are any other questions in
particular for alessandro please please
feel free to ask
one point i didn't uh that i think is um
called out this is a final point i
should have mentioned earlier is that in
alessandro again you'll correct me if
i'm wrong but if you are sharing a
session and you've logged into medico
and you have the chat available and a
question comes up or an issue comes up
that you can't um
that you need help with
uh you can you put midiko
uh the word midiko in the chat
and then ask your question or raise the
issue and there is always someone from
midoko monitoring the chat for all the
sessions so that'll get their attention
and they are usually super quick to
respond and resolve anything
and i saw alessandro nodding so i i got
that mostly right yeah
thanks
great well um
like i said i think i think we're we've
covered everything that's super
important i will
personally i'm happy to hang on to the
session uh for
uh another 25 or 30 minutes or so in
case someone happens to join late um but
i want to thank you all for coming and
testing this out i'm looking forward to
seeing
uh eight of you at in philadelphia and
the others online so uh
yeah if uh any questions come up between
now and then
um feel free to drop a line to support
ietf.org by email
and
we can
get questions and
issues resolved that way i encourage you
to
set up your own test session for your
working group in advance either on-site
or using the
online tool available
starting friday after the 15th
so
thanks again for taking time out of your
day to
make sure things run smoothly for you at
114 and if anything
comes out that we can help with please
let us know
so
thank you everybody
thanks
so
hi um
uh
see someone has just joined um
let me know if
you'd like to test sending audio or
video or
uh if you
wanna test them
hey hey
yeah this is tj yeah thanks for sending
your email
yeah tj thanks uh thanks and my
apologies again it was totally uh
totally my bad
uh do you want uh are you uh
are you looking to test anything in
particular or do you wanna
see a feature happy to run through
anything you'd like
um specifically so um
so um so i'm sharing the i'll be sharing
the a and their w so one um presenter
will be presenting their paper remotely
so
um
how can i you know teach them to do so
yeah yeah so the most important thing i
would say is to uh make sure that if
they're
going to be using slides
um
to
have those slides uploaded
to the data tracker ahead of time
and
then
what will happen is you will be able to
see and i'm going to stop so i can show
you
what that looks like you'll be able to
see
uh
sorry oh crap okay hold on sorry uh no
that's not what i want
this is what i want
so i'm going to show you what it looks
like um so if they
uh
if they upload their slides you can see
that there's the share preloaded slides
um icon in the upper left underneath
your
name
if you click on that
yeah if you click on that what will
happen is you'll get a list of slides
that are available to share and i can't
show you because i can only show you
either my desktop or the slides so it
won't allow me
it won't allow me to do both but if they
preload the slides into data tracker
then it will be those slide that slide
deck will be available to share
and what you can do
is um
you can start sharing those slides and
i'll show you how it looks from the user
perspective
you can start sharing the slides and
then pass control to the presenter
so that they can control the slides
uh
and here's what else
so
for example uh
yep
so i'm gonna share the slides that i've
made for this session
and i'm going to pass control to you uh
oh i should have showed you that too
um
yeah actually let me let me stop and
show you that
um
it's it's very awkward because um
uh i can't show you everything but uh
there is a guy there's a chairs guy that
that lays this out um
yes i want to do that and i want to do
the whole deal
but not that one
so okay so now i'm gonna if i once i
start sharing slides uh from the share
slides icon up here
uh what i do is then go here and you can
for a particular user say oh pass
control slides
so i'll do that now and you'll see what
it looks like it is a user um
so
okay so i'm sharing the slides now i've
rolled over your name i see this past
slides control so now you
will have slides
uh controls at the bottom of the slide
and you can advance the slides um
yeah so it's pretty handy and then as a
chair you can you can revoke the
permission to share slides so you i will
take slide control back and you'll see
this so now i have slides control again
so
um
it's pretty handy the key is to upload
the slides before and then once that's
done it's all really really nice
the other thing to say is if
you are expecting
video because i know the nrw folks are
um
crazy and use things like video during
presentations uh you should just make
sure to let um
meet echo know about that ahead of time
because midiko as a as a
webrtc client uh
doesn't doesn't really handle video very
well and and medico can
if you can get them the video ahead of
time they can do some things so that it
works great for everybody
i have two more follow-up questions so
one is
so um what if um the authors would like
to present
all offline then how can you broadcast
this you know
broadcast this thing's presentation
through this
platform
yeah so if they want to use slides that
are not uploaded to data tracker um
that's possible it's definitely not
recommended because it ends up
meaning that if
it puts higher demand on their network
connection
and it's just not as it's not as
seamless like if someone has to take
over for them you can't pass control but
it's definitely possible and the way to
do that is you'll see
there's a share screen icon
just below your name it looks like a
monitor of computer monitor
and if you click on that
you can request and you can try it out
and see what it looks like right now
if you click on that
i us chair will get a request to allow
you to share your screen i see
and the other trick about that is that
you need to
you can only share us pre-loaded slides
or share a screen
uh you can't do both at the same time so
i would have to stop the slideshare
so the officer shouldn't use the keynote
or powerpoint for their presentation
they have to connect this platform
and uh
share their screen
even if they would like to present on
site right so
yeah if they're presenting on-site it's
actually
uh even
um more recommended so that for them to
use um
the medico's slide sharing the other
thing i'll say is that um
in the itf anyway i think it's also true
in the irtf
um the general idea is that slides are
available
as part of the meeting agenda
in advance so that
that's just sort of the norm
um so if they're
if they're presenting
like powerpoint or a
keynote format that they have to convert
to pdf i think to upload to data tracker
anyway
and once they do that it automatically
shows up in midico so everything
that's available in data tracker is is
available via midiko automatically
um
the last one is what if so um so what if
the presenter is you know would like to
present remotely but let's say his
network connection is not that good so
our plan is to request and recruit the
video
and posted youtube just in case
is it possible to use this platform and
play the video here or yeah
yeah for sure and that's ideal if you
upload the video
to youtube and then you have a url you
can share with the medical folks they
are happy to
there's a medical person that's in every
session so people who actually run the
platform monitor the session so if you
just tell them hey we have these uh
three or four videos that we want to
play during our session
uh and i think they've done this in the
past so it's it's not new uh they'll
just uh
be monitoring the session and when you
say hey play this video they'll play
that video and it'll show up through the
platform
which includes in the room in
philadelphia um
so that's that's definitely not a
problem uh and is a great way to handle
that stuff
so if something doesn't go well i don't
need to be panicked so
no if you if you preload the slides and
you have the video shared with midiko in
advance um everything should go super
smoothly um the other thing to say is
that like i said someone is in medico
and usually they're monitoring pretty
closely especially anrw
sessions because they're um
like i said
it's a little different but if if you
are in the session and in the chat for
the session if you type mideco
uh
that they have a they have a
bot that alerts them so as soon as that
string medico shows up in a chat uh
like sirens and red lights go off in the
control room that they have and they
will come and take a look um
so that's always that's always a
possibility
got it so should i type a chat
here
oh
i'm sorry if you type it yeah
i'm using this yeah first
thing
yeah if you type medico into the chat i
believe alessandra will pop back in
he's he's monitoring as a zulu abuser
but i expected that he will pop back in
got it yep
that's all thank you so much
no problem
uh any other questions
i guess that's it um so if i have some
more follow-up questions should i
uh to sign up this
table
um
the chairs testing
uh unfortunately not yeah
oh okay
yeah
so i have to cheer remotely
um but uh i i think i can find someone
who'll be on site so that he can help
but anyway so
so i'm saying the nose dot itf org itf
tears testing and i see a big table
for
impersonation testing so it is for in
person so okay it doesn't apply to me
okay
all right i i guess then that's it yeah
thank you so much
uh yeah no problem tj if something comes
up before uh
uh the meeting starts let me know i've
i've just dropped a line to alessandro
um who is sort of lead contact for us on
on medico to to alert him that uh
there will be there will be um
videos for the a rw sessions
um
so
uh and if you if you if there is someone
on site
uh or even if you even if you want to
test but you will be remote um
you can go ahead and grab one of those
slots in the testing
and um you can you can test as a remote
chair uh
okay you know in room setup
um i i don't know if it's possible i
know ietf working group chairs and irtf
working group chairs can set up um
test sessions ahead of time so they can
see and run through everything as a
chair and coordinate with presenters i
don't know if that's true for a rw
uh i'll i'll ask about that
yep
thank you
all right
okay uh well thanks for joining sorry
about the trouble if anything comes up
no we can help with you let us let us
know
yep thank you so much for your help
okay
cheers
uh
okay
you