all right it's time uh to start welcome
to um uta at itf 114
your chairs one of which is on site and
the other is remote um
you agree my co-chair
is
right there
hi
very good um so with the usual reminders
of note well
please note the note well well
and also on the uh itf code of conduct
that's uh
well be nice to each other speak clearly
at the mic and stick to the topic at
hand is one way of expressing it and for
this meeting
mask is required in the meeting room
with that
we have a a reasonably full agenda today
there there's a lot of stuff to cover
um
we do need a couple of note takers we
need a
well a normal note taker and if if
possible somebody to go watch tulip and
and channel
any discussions to the mic that can't be
anyone who can't sort of be um you know
either remote or
using voice remote or in person so
we get some volunteers to um
um
all right so
valerie is taking care of zulu but we do
do need a notetaker
oh perfect man thank you so ben schwartz
like volunteered to
take notes this is um this is really
good
all right
with that
um
here's our agenda today um
we
are going to start with rich
we're going to talk to us about the ip
address
issue um and then honda's to talk about
iot and i see hannah's here already joe
i haven't seen i haven't seen joe online
oh there you are perfect
right
so we actually have everybody here that
needs them here so rich do you want to
want to get going i'm going to
see if do you want to do this or should
i okay let me
all right
let's see if i can
make this work
there we go okay
uh hi i'm going to leave after my
session not because my ego is so big but
because
there's a conflict okay next slide
all right so
uh like two weeks ago
three weeks ago martin thompson proposed
that we add support for ip addresses
there is
um
the subject alt name
extension in pcx has a type for ip
addresses
the obvious thing to call it is ip-id
similar to dnsid and the other
terminology used in 6125 and 61-25 bis
rfc 9110 which was presumably martin's
for bringing it up has text about
validation the rule is very simple
a reference id matches if the ip address
matches
fairly straightforward
it's not uncommon in http
um if you've ever typed you know
http
colon slash 127001
you've done it
um presumably there's more mechanisms
that are going to come
http alternate service and some of the
other mechanisms that are being added to
http
are more likely to include more of these
kinds of things
and there may even be other uses outside
of http i don't know
next slide
okay so the issues uh it is admittedly
late martin said so in his comment um it
might make the draft more widely
applicable i don't know i i
i'll take him it was had his word
uh the simple wording change does have
ripple effects through the document
um
for example
in the front
near the front of the dock
it says here's the rules
and then you have to add like an escape
patch for step three that says but if
it's an ip address do this
it's just editorial where it's missing
um so the goal is we should want to seek
working group consensus whether or not
to do this
it wasn't clear if there was consensus
chairs thought there was i thought there
was no we're not quite right
there's an initial pr i reopened the pr
on the issue it's on github
so the pr is by martin initial
admittedly incomplete
the issue about doing it is there
not in the bullet list
but probably worth noting
is
uh
i'm going to be kind of busy with
nom-com for the next five months
so
but i have a co-author
a little bit busy
i'm just gonna pick all the old uh
incumbents and do them again anyhow
uh next next slide
so the current text
in the out of scope section which this
obviously would go away
is identifiers such as ip addresses are
not discussed
protocols other than http may want to
consider and then points to 9001. not
whatever 9000 something
as a validation model
um
i think that's reasonable description of
the issues
uh
looking for you know
what the working group wants to do
so with my chair hat how much is this
gonna screw us over in terms of time
uh timeline
you know i'm complaining it's probably
not a lot of work to do all the
wordsmithing necessary okay um so it's
more like a it's your availability
that's really sort of yeah and even then
i'm still just complaining so it's
probably not going to add much elapsed
time we could probably still be done
before the next ietf so you're comparing
a little bit but not too much i'm
complaining a little bit not too much
peter andre is also available all right
so yeah
um alessandro gadini cloudflare uh we do
have you know use cases for um
https and other
secure tls connections to um ip
addresses specifically
for example the cloudflare resolver with
the
1.1.1.1 address
so ideally
i would want to see this supported
i can help with you know review prs and
whatnot
yeah um
martin thompson
out of the queue now um
i put that that pull request together
and i do sort of appreciate where you're
coming from rich after having tried that
it is a little bit more work than simply
just adding sort of one bullet point and
removing the we don't do ips from the
from the front matter
it's not my document so i don't i wasn't
able to identify everything i don't
think very confidently
but um i think probably the most
interesting
aspect of this
uh the section that talks about
which one was it the
sans or
like not sans the srv or something yeah
this is about service identifiers right
sip colon foo sip s colon foo dot bar
yeah example yeah and some of that was a
little fiddly but
other than that the changes are pretty
straightforward that what you would
imagine
goes in here
so hopefully what i've got there would
be enough to get you
ninety percent of the way
unfortunately the last ten percent is
always the hardest part
i'm kind of asking you to do it yeah uh
to some extent
http already has it
has what it needs but i don't think the
text in
um
rfc 9110 is particularly good
now that i've looked at it again
i'm sort of looking at it going oh
that's
gee we could have done a better job with
that and
and this document here is is that much
better job okay so i
like
like others i think
i think the worth work is worth doing
even if it means one more cycle
uh
and a little bit of complication i'm
happy to help i'm i tried to help but uh
that's about the extent of my ability
i'm afraid
because yeah you know the document
better than i do sure yeah i don't want
to overstate
i don't want to sound like a grumpy old
man so i don't want to overstate my
concerns about it i'm really whatever
the working group wants is fine you know
um i should also mention we're about to
submit a draft that shows how to use ip
addresses in sni fields
so oh yeah that'll be a fun conversation
dot dot inaudible
so all right so um
quick sense of the room um
and i'll i'll use the hand raising tool
if people really want me to but
otherwise i'll just sort of do it this
way um
in this room
sorry
a message from alexey melindikov
in the chat
so he thinks that
this problem should be addressed but not
in this document
alexa is right behind you in the quran
go ahead alexa
alexa do you want to make a case for a
separate document
yeah hello
sorry um
i think the properties are slightly
different so it would be nice probably
i think it would be better to have a
separate document for this just to keep
it clean
so are you volunteering to write one
i don't mind helping out yes
can you repeat that
he didn't mind helping yes don't mind
helping yeah because so i i would
actually want don't want the working
group to block on this right so if we we
want to sort of
either proceed with like a a clear
commitment from authors to to kind of
come back with a
separate document or
um
like we proceed with this pr or we
decide that this is not work worth
working on at all
um so i don't want us to hang in limbo
here so
um
martin you wanna
yeah i wanna ask alexi why um because i
think the y is more important here at
this point
than just saying
this one or the other one
alexi
well
i think uh
your comments about
certain things wouldn't apply to be
addresses it just made me concerned
and
if it doesn't fit quite right you know
just make it a separate document
so i believe the working group should
probably separately ask
whether we should work up on this and
how it's done
so i i would i have you looked at the
changes that i proposed
i haven't quite caught up with
this but um
yeah so the reason that i think
this document is a better place for that
aside from having everything in one
place is a nice
and one-stop shop for people who are
looking to reference these things
is that there are some interactions with
the existing things and that was the
complicated part of getting the work
done it's not super complicated or
anything
but having an extra document that comes
in and surgically amends the the various
pieces of of an existing document
to to put ip addresses in there
is somewhat more complicated
than um
and then i think getting it done here
now that the patient's open
so
that's where i ended up once i did the
work that's all
okay yeah my coverage is i haven't uh
reviewed your pr yet so maybe
i can commit to doing it within next few
days or something like that
all right does anybody feel strongly
against um progressing with um pr54
what was it
strongly against progressing with what
progressing with pr-54 you're important
oh
if alexi can get his document done and
it's i mean you know i've sort of come
around to martin's viewpoint
right
victor
hi um are there
name constraint issues that perhaps
would add some complexity for ipid
do we have a specification for
ipid name constraint processing and also
does that live here or would that be
5280 and
refinements
so the doc right now talks not at all
about name constraints which i think are
kind of horked anyway right
um so presumably would be
50 20 50 to 80 bis which is never going
to happen
so yeah i mean
no they're probably i don't know if
there are anything
there's nothing workable about name
constraints for ip addresses that that i
can recall but that i may be wrong
so so the answer there is that there are
no names name constraints defined for ip
addresses nor do i expect there to ever
be given
rich's point about 5280 uh being set in
stone in a way that i think
is probably not a bad thing entirely
maybe you know if
alexi wants to do his draft
and thinks he can get it done in the
short term then we can maybe decide but
on the other hand i'm willing to
if the working group wants to do it i'm
willing to do it i just don't promise
anything
before 115 maybe a month before
i mean i've heard people stand up and
say that they volunteer to work on it
which is a good thing right so it's an
indication we can get it done yeah so i
was going to suggest that now let's not
expect rich to do
all of the work
i think peter was interested in spending
a little bit of time on this one the the
editors can collab if they want to ask
me to do something i'm willing to do
that
uh if alexi reaches a different
conclusion and wants to propose an
alternative way once he's had a look at
it if anyone else wants to do the same
we can do that but um
that's okay
i think at this point i'd propose we
leave it with the editors
to sort through what's there
and um if we get more feedback about it
from people who have committed to review
then we'll we'll discuss that all right
that's i think i think that's an
excellent idea all right let's just
let's do that and then continue this
confirm on the list
okay
all right and please people who have
stood up and said that they wanna um
um
that they are volunteering to review the
current pull request or you know
contribute other material let's try to
get that done as quickly as possible so
we can get the ball rolling yeah um one
thing i'll mention is if you haven't
please read the current draft because i
think it's
maybe i have an inflated opinion to
myself but it's pretty clear and simple
about how to do things which is
important i think for the community and
so then when we do add ip addresses we
want to make sure that we don't lose
that clarity and simplicity more than we
have to
okay i've got somebody at the queue is
eric i think you want to talk about name
constraints so maybe
yeah just briefly i looked yesterday
5280 and it does define name constraints
for ip addresses they're like other gaps
with search and ip address that we
someday will want to deal with um what
name constraints at least does seem to
be intuitive
anyway but as somebody as i think you
pointed out name constraints is a bigger
ratio it's not covered at all right now
yeah
okay all right thank you that's it for
for um
your slots let's see here next on our
agenda
iot profile on this
okay
so
i would like to talk about the update we
made with o5 first i want to go through
some of the changes that were made and
then to point to a couple of the open
issues
of which there are a number of them in
the github repository of the working
group
next slide
okay
so the first one is
so as you know in dls1.3 to use the
serial rtd feature you have to come up
with an application specific profile to
describe how
you deal with um
sort of the needed uh replay protection
and so in an earlier document we
uh added that feature and also did
um
sort of discuss this and and announce it
on the co-op list where it was actually
uh
debated and it turned out that the
co-working group right now doesn't see
interest in or need for the serial rtd
feature in dls for some of their uses
so
um
with that in mind we decided to
take it out from this document actually
park it into a separate specification
that maybe just temporarily as or people
are just happy with the way dls is
because there are obviously some ups and
downs of using the zero rtd feature uh
so
um that's where we are today at least uh
so it's not
like not gone forever but
at least for now so
that um
makes the document shorter so that's a
plus because there's a you need to
define a couple of um
additional co-op
uh options
to make that feature work
okay
the other one which is a little bit more
tricky is um the recommendation on the
um
the domestic ecdsa which we sort of took
over from
uh the previous uh
dls and dtls 1.2 iot recommendations as
well as from what the the dls1.3
specification says
so the recommendation there is
to use deterministic ecdsa
and
but then
it seems that the
sort of focus or the excitement has uh
changed again
in terms of that feature and there are
obviously currently discussion in cfrc
on
um adding the
noise or randomness back into
the ecdsa function as i will as you will
see on the next slide but uh
the point here is that
there are
attacks and specifically exploiting the
weakness that the uh
that random number generation is of
course a challenging topic on
iot devices and non-iot devices
specifically if you have access to those
devices and you can mount fault
injection attacks
um of course iot devices are often
you or the attacker often has physical
access so those attacks would be
applicable and even though we see a
increase in
sort of hardware based features for
security including random number
generation there is um at least the
perception
that
those are not as good as they they could
be uh which i don't want to quantify
because it's uh obviously depends on
from product or
i'm sure that the features vary from
product to product so i don't want to
make a general statement but at least
if you look at those attacks there are
cases where devices have had um
limited uh randomness in
and obviously that when applied to
uh some of the our protocols and also
the
the signature mechanisms that causes
problems
what i personally on next slide um
i struggle then with is to actually make
good recommendations because uh
even a protocol like dls uh there's so
we need sources of randomness in various
places and for example not just with
ecdsa but also with the ephemera
different helmet or with the um
with the randomness that is sent around
in a clientele sub-hello exchange but
in my belief um if you don't have any
randomness then you are set yourself up
for problems
but
what should the recommendations be in
that case and so uh thomas who is also
working on the generic utah dls 1.3
recommendation document which is
sort of separate
from the iud recommendation there
obviously there are some recommendations
being made which are now
sort of carried over to into this
document
so it's easy to write those document
those recommendations in some sense it's
another story to actually ex uh
implement them in in real
hardware and real software on iot
devices but
i think that's that's as much as as we
can do
at this point in time
okay
um
thank you thanks to michael richardson
uh i don't see him right now in the room
but he has done a very detailed review
in response to a presentation i gave at
the iot ops meeting
at the last idf
and
this is one
that we addressed already it's one that
concerns the use of intermediate ca
versus subordinate ca which we were a
little bit relaxed on on using the
terminology from rc 49
49 so we addressed that one
um
as you will see later he had a couple of
other reviews which we addressed already
but he didn't indicate whether he is
happy with them so we didn't um
incorporate them into the documentary
waiting for his uh final assessment
before we are going to do that
next slide
okay
so a few
um open issues one is um
what we call the feature
disparity uh is
and that was also discussed on the tls
mailing list not just on the utah list
is with certain features that were
they are different between uh 1.2 and
1.3 which are kind of subtle
for example
on the slide this concerns the
renegotiation which apparently some
people used in dls 1.2
to
[Music]
check
the certificate status at a later stage
so the for long-lived tls connections
they are apparently
uh which are which are used in
industrial iot networks
they
use that technique to find out whether
the certificate is still
valid using for example
ocsb
extensions carried inside that exchange
or just
triggering a certificate
checking again
um we went through the discussions on
the dls list and tried to capture some
of it in this issue that is linked here
uh but it's not so easy to
to really make a
recommendation on
what to do about some of those different
features clearly renegotiation is done
is is gone but should it should there be
some some extensions being added back to
dls um to enable some of those features
or is the solution that has been used um
actually not the right approach to begin
with and that's uh specifically on that
front the long-lived dls connections and
using that the renegotiation feature to
check the status of certificates is that
actually
the best way to do i'm not sure in
either case
um the dls extension is not something
that we can incorporate or new extension
incorporate into this
uh document anyway
and for the other one it's even if we
make that recommendation ah the
those who relied on that feature
previously are going to change their
code to to make use of it um not
entirely certain
martin
yeah honest have you um
considered the use of the exported
authenticators for this purpose
actually no how would that work
so it would require something at the
application layer that you would
essentially have
one side uh challenge the other other
side to
to present an
exported authenticator and you would
that other side would then produce
what is effectively a certificate and a
signature using that
certificate over something exported from
the um
various secrets
and that would allow you to refresh
your view of the currency of the
certificate that was used on the
connection maybe you don't need to
provide a certificate you just provide
the
authenticator but okay
that's recently that's a that's a uh
interesting approach i don't think that
was actually proposed on the list i went
uh through the discussions and didn't
don't think i saw that one uh it's
probably worthwhile to explore but uh
it was uh uh stephen fries from siemens
who brought this up because uh he is
working deeply on his industrial
iot use cases
and so uh i will definitely double check
things yeah there's a number of things
you can do
that might help so the the re-keying
that happens the key updates
allow you to refresh keys and give you
some degree
of post compromise security but um
this would allow you to
refresh the credentials what you don't
get is fresh entropy for the session so
you don't get the ability to do another
dippy helmet for instance that may
actually be a feature
from the iot perspective i don't know
um so um
yeah discuss it i don't know what the
what the right answer is yeah there's
probably a um
it probably what we would need is um
almost like a um
problem statement with assumptions to
find out like what specific attacks do
we care about and and do we care about
like uh like what keys are we
expecting to double check whether they
are compromised is it a long-term key is
it something
like if we do a key update for example
clearly we wouldn't recognize whether
the the certificates used in a mutual
dls exchange have been compromised and
and so on and so on and uh
so so maybe maybe that's uh sounds like
a good idea to actually use that um
example as uh as a trigger to debate
what exactly the requirements are yeah i
think that's a good way to go about it
yeah yeah i like that
one more person in the queue behind
martin
i'm assuming about this yeah stef
actually cool hey stefan
hi hannes good to see you uh yeah just
to shed some light on the requirements
so uh the requirement goes back to to uh
one of the tls usages that we have in
power system automation and uh there it
is a way that currently we used in the
renegotiation feature in tls 1.2
to trigger the certificate as a
certificate revocation check as hannah's
mentioned and while switching over to
tls version 1.3 we would basically
offload
that
functionality to the application itself
because there is no no
trigger coming from the tls stack
because renegotiation is no longer
allowed in tls version 1.3 so that means
that we
basically have some kind of timer in the
application and once the timer is up the
certificate gets rechecked
uh we can do the certificate we can do
the the key update
in tls 1.3 using the post handshake
messages but the certificate check
would still need to be done and
in dls 1.3 we had the possibility to
basically take the certificate that
comes out of the handshake and then give
it up to the application and the
application can do the revocation check
again
now
we essentially have to store the
certificate in the application to ensure
that after a certain time we can recheck
the certificate regarding its revocation
state
so that was the
basic requirement there and the
requirement comes from the fact that
once in a while uh the certificate for
long
i'm sorry the certificate for long-lived
connection uh is required to be to be
checked
for the for its revocation state to
ensure that it is still valid why is the
sessions running
thanks thanks jeff yeah that was good
back on so in um we obviously have to
victor do you want to
uh victor de carney uh google i have a
question for stefan actually
uh why or rather what threats
uh if you could explain on list or
if not now
uh
do we want to know whether the
certificate is expired given the
sessions already established it'd be
good to know what the actual reason is
beyond just doing the thing we've been
doing
so we can't hear you um
you're mute
no no not not yet feels like a local
mute rather than a
now you're
me taco muted
test test test
no
nothing
it just worked so
that's mysterious
it just worked yes no
i think he's trying to get away not
answering that question
that's cheap stuff
[Laughter]
all right
he could at least hear my choke that's
good
yeah yeah um stefan you
you want to come back to this in in a
minute or two and then you can or you
can type it into the chat
um honest has a few slides to go so yeah
yeah so in any case uh regardless of
what the conclusion is we need to sort
of like say some i think we need to say
something in a document uh and explain
like uh for those who who have been
using dls 1.2
what that means in 1.3 as they move over
okay next one
so this is the one i mentioned
previously there were two items uh
client certificate validation and also
um
sni hiding which are two separate issues
waiting for uh michael's input won't go
into those details so obviously in
the item i would ping him during this
week so hopefully he has some cyclers
and the other one what
one other issue or two other issues are
related to profiling of timers that's
something we did in the previous profile
for 1.2
when we noticed that the use of dtls uh
this is a dtls feature
um
the default recommendations for the
timeouts were not really adequate for
some of the
uh iud
networks specifically mesh networks
which have a high latency and
potentially high loss rate and so we we
went through a long effort to sort of
adjust those timers of course the 1.3 is
a little different so um
we have to figure out what the timers
are and then uh also with the rrc sort
of the
uh
the checking or the the document that
we've been working on in the dls working
group to do the um
the
the checking needed for
the path validation for the
connection id changes
so
of course anyone who has experience with
using ddls and specifically 1.3 for some
of those networks
we're happy to hear your uh
your experience
okay that's it i think that's it
all right so um
we're looking at a couple more
iterations before
we're ready to
shepherd
um
at least at least uh definitely one to
address those comments as you like it's
we're getting down to sort of coming to
the end on this yeah okay so all right
all right thank you
all right um
and that gets us to
joe
see if i can
no i didn't want to share let's try that
here we go
back to syslog all right yes back to
says slog again
so um uh you can go to the next slide
uh
yeah this just is a document that uh
uh chris and sean and i uh are working
on
the kind of summary here is uh this has
recently been adopted as a working group
item which is fantastic uh we're
basically updating cipher suites and and
transport protocol for for these various
uh rfcs
and really what prompted this was uh
the iec
uh
tc57 wg15
group uh was
reusing was referencing these specs
and
the the specs reference some older cyber
suites
um and tls versions which
they in order to be compliant with the
specs they would have to implement the
old things they don't want to do that
obviously for for good reason um so
we're kind of we we fixed up these
particular
problems in the zero zero draft
um
by specifying modern cipher suite to be
used and uh
and
you know recent versions of tls
including tls one three
uh next slide
um
the uh only major change in uh
uh the zero one draft
is um
around zero rtt
um we decided uh
that
we shouldn't use zero rtt with um
and we should be explicit about it with
syslog
syslog doesn't really have a replay
protection
um and in many cases zero rtt it's not
really
i don't we we didn't feel this would be
a very widely used feature either
because
connections tend to be long-lived
so we say must not use early data
uh next slide
so
we've already published a
zero one so we'd love to get some more
review so folks if you
could give us a little bit of review
then we can take that to
hopefully get working group last call
soon
yeah i mean there's it's fairly
not a lot of complexity here so
it should be possible right so
can i get a like a indication race hands
or hums or something from people who
have back who have read this draft
phone number can i get a few of you to
like say yes i will review this
so we can get um victor
um
on this
right
that's good so we can get victor and
hannes uh on the record having having
volunteered to review
that um sort of gets us that much closer
to uh working group last call and like
shepard that's very
okay good
right great that's it
um
which uh
takes us it gets us to
open mic for this meeting
um
and if nobody has
anything
um
maybe something
ben schwartz uh on the topic of ip
address identities and certificates uh
i i wanted to mention that
the
add working group has run into an
interesting situation
where
it would be
very convenient if there were a way to
mint a certificate that claims uh all
the ip addresses in a subnet
so uh so that somebody who for example
an isp that owns a wide ip range could
have a certificate that says yes i
am
willing and able to terminate traffic
for
uh for all of the
uh
all of the identities and this all the
ip address identities
in this range
uh currently i think there's no way to
spell that so anyway if anybody's
interested in in talking about that
that use case which is related to uh
encrypted dns on ipv6 home gateways
um
talk to me
and this is related to the
the um
public suffix licks list stuff right uh
so the
the motivation to briefly the the
motivation is that
uh
the the add ddr mechanism
uh if the if the home gateway's dns
server is identified by a public
address like a public ipv6 address as
opposed to a link local
address
uh then
the encrypted dns server must present a
certificate that covers that ipv6
address
and so
if an isp wanted to
operate an encrypted dns
service for all of its users
[Music]
then in this configuration they would
uh first of all uh per eric's comment
that they would need some way in the sni
to find out which ip address the client
uh is trying to connect
is trying to find a substitute for and
secondly they would need separate
certificates for for every single ip
address of every single
dns resolver and all of their customers
home gateways instead of
one big certificate that just says i
claim the entire ip range
anyway this is not something that's
possible today it would be an entirely
new
identifier format for x509
victor yes uh hi victor mccartney i have
a question i guess for for the working
group in terms of where to propose
something
uh
i'd like to
i think having possibly an extension
for a tls client
to tell the server to solicit its
certificate
uh because as we know tls client
certificates are optional if the server
doesn't ask for them the client can't
present them
and yet some servers for
interoperability reasons prefer not to
ask for them by default
if a client knows that
it is desirable to present a certificate
but the server is likely not to solicit
them by default
uh there could be a need for a message
for a client to say hi i have a
certificate
in in the client hello or somewhere
early on without disclosing much detail
about it because but privacy issues
until it goes into certificate
extensions in tls103 and is encrypted uh
so i'd like there to be an early message
uh to say please grab my certificate i'm
interested for this in email where i
could do it in an esmtp hello but it
kind of seems like the wrong layer
should i take this to the tls working
group to utah
should i just do it in the esmtp which
unasks the question but kind of does it
at the wrong layer
any thoughts or comments it's a perfect
question to bounce right over to our ad
yes
you were hoping not to be involved today
so i have sad news for you i'm not the
cognizant ad i'm just a spectator oh man
i'm sorry damn it but if we repeat it
i'm happy to sorry so right so the
question is where does where do where do
extensions to tls go that could be
applicable to specific application
domains
um
yeah right i mean that would be exactly
kind of my first question i would have
to take i mean i think i would but the
responsibility would have to take a look
at the charter in this working group
would make sense well i i think it makes
sense for it to be here but also it
makes sense for it to be in a bunch of
other places absolutely i mean i think
it's hard to have a universal answer to
that yeah
would be my personal opinion
i was just going to say there's nothing
stopping someone in any working group
here or even groups outside of the ietf
from defining tls extensions that's not
the problem the problem i think would be
the charter of this group which i think
probably
maybe doesn't include the ability to do
that without a rechartering but if this
is the right place to do it i think we
should just tweak the charter and make
it happen
personal opinion i've always understood
this working group to be kind of a
catch-all a last resort there's no place
else to do it there's clearly a pile of
expertise here let's leverage that
expertise for expediency
yeah
certainly a group that had had a life
expectancy far beyond sort of the
initial set of best practice documents
that i think people were envisioning uh
i i would encourage you to write
something up uh
draft up and presented and
we can talk about that option here or in
the whatever working group makes sense
so i i
you know
personally i think it sounds interesting
too
all right
going
oh
oh mark well martin is on the queue but
i think he
you were
yeah
so last call for open mic time
going once
going twice
all right see you in london
bye-bye
this was more like a security issues
uh
all right
there's