hi everyone on michele pietravalle I
work to place the providers in this
place so venice some of you
know me yesterday's open talk or why never
saw me play with tesla last night so
let's say I take care of some
collateral things weight talk talk that I
presented to  June of this year on the
occasion of a completely different event, however, since
it was liked anyway I tried to
propose it again here she wrote maybe it is
a slightly different target audience
this is a talk in a probably
technical it was a talk more dictated to  lee co
commercial marketing that sector ii
which however had some pretty nice 20 technical books
entitled that
obviously internet traffic
following the evolution of the
streaming market that is what does this mean
in recent years as you well know
played in all quite years now
all  the offices the services such as netflix
download megavideo all those
legal and illegal things that are there how
these services have affected them  fleece
provider
so what can my notice that has
changed in recent years before seeing
these four graphs here are four
graphs it refers adds I
don't even remember when they were but they are
things are four graphs of
peering traffic of four internet changer three
big one small thing  we can see
in we can see something quite
interesting the arrow indicates on all
the graphs around 8 pm of the
same day
what happens around 8 pm you see the
traffic clearly from
around 5 am where the minor peak goes up
goes up then stabilizes then  if we live
there is always around 20 this peak
quite evident you see this
graphs
completely different scales here we are
talking by scale and gigabits per second
here we are talking to say this is a
50 gigabits per second here we are
talking in terabits per second
this graph is  of 4 terabits per
second
this is inter 100 gigabit this
even i  n megabytes here we are at 200
I read well drums
all have this
particular trend towards dinner time
what does this mean simply
means that people come home from
work they start to eat and start
watching something steaming and after
dinner  during dinner something quite
interesting you see the graphs are
overlapping but they all have the
same characteristic curve looking at it
on its area no longer the daily
this in the daily area this is a
weekly area we see that
the trend is good or bad there is all
days the arrow actually
indicated something quite more evident you see they
are all more or less aligned here there is
a corresponding peak always
around that time very very
important remember that the scale in
cigarettes faces there was a  increase
of about 57 50 gigabits per second
this moment this particular
time slot of the day June 14th what was
what happened  or in your opinion at that
moment it simply happened to
the belgium italy match
what does this mean it means that
when once people watched
television they watched it so they listened to
the radio so the vendors heavy with the pc and a
half the vendor or in any case the
main service providers  of the time who were
the usual classic ones allowed
someone at random how it is evolving
instead now we are moving from these
devices here to these devices here to
see
and my audio my video streaming and
sell what we have passed from
those before that  they are the classic
television providers to these here if
I had a bit at random anyway just to
make the idea so the market is
starting has moved clearly from
a dimension we call logical wool the
digital dimension what impacts this
one comments impacts on a physical level
because  if in order to watch
analogue or digital terrestrial television
with some negligible difference,
I had b  i need this provider
side then repeater side this is
the user apt how the
situation on the user side has evolved now to
see me the influx in streaming and my
game my movie my what we
want I no longer need this
infrastructure  above but for
example I need these two
infrastructures motionless movement is
fixed this is one of the workers that
you have seen for the 20th around
all your cities
if I were the municipality I would never have
authorized such crap
rather make a hole  while the
underground shelter spain put me in there
here in mestre I refer to the
masters 200 meters there are these things
mounted in the middle of the sidewalk in front of
the gate just where the equal goes
well this therefore
fixed area this in the mobile area and side
instead not anymore  on the side of the sick user
provider we have gone from having this is
all that concerned directing
and so on basically to this one so
we no longer have  infrastructures
distributed throughout the territory but rather it was
a
clearly centralized screening infrastructure and what
substantially changed once if it was a
small amount of the content
available the programmer of the
television channel programmer the
current developer that programmer body
what program had its beautiful
archive of  tapes of what you
wanted took they decided what to
put and gave you the opportunity to
see that program then two programs
those three channels
now instead what changes now
permanently all available is
the user who decides what to see
then how you change what has changed at the
level  information basically that
before from a flow that had been
logical digital what you want
television that made me exit from
limpe from the studio in transmission to
the repeater up to the user now
clearly the flows have become
hundreds of thousands millions because
obviously each operat  hours that each
user goes he chooses what he wants to
see and surely it will not coincide with
what another is treating with all
the necessary exceptions to optimize
space so on the user side on the provider side
we have arrived at this situation
the user apt therefore provider vars users
do not  we have more antennas then we have
the columns that I
showed them and on the other hand the last mile they
call this way towards the user we have
things in the area the stop saw the
wired columns in the mobile area
we have this bts what is there but you
can't see why  my cell phone in my
pocket 4g hate you never make me 40 megabits per
second does not even know how many it makes
how nice it worked as I tell everyone
I key work in the field of wifi yes
wireless wireless hand because the children are
not there for the children from  someone else
me in this case the work find in
this case so what does it mean it
means that to
make mobile infrastructure scalable
I certainly have to bring fiber  emit
equipment of this kind the coveralls
also all in all
limited that for those of mestre there is a
map of the arpav with coverage of a
cellular abs so just to understand
this always on a being is the map
of the bs always from the site  and the arpav of the
bsd I do not remember if all the
operators or only some positioned
you see that is there are a lot of bsa to be
able to provide you with the connection
so there is a whole world behind the
I watch the movie in streaming on the
mobile phone that the user  final does not even
realize it does not even know that it is there it is completely ignored
so what it means essentially
means a lot of data a lot of cells
this is a car I made a
few days before the presentation
of the mountain in Sardinia that we have
repeaters in the space of a year and a half
they added this is our third
high school wifi for the annex added these
these these these because I need
to carry bana I have to do smaller cls
I have to carry many  more bs for the same
for the same type of service
let's do the math just grizzly
netflix that what the data
published a little maybe 34 quality
low medium high and ultra hd what
does this affect what I do it to you
I transfer it to the
knightley servers  I do it about 0.3 gigabytes
per hour go you not vitamin command it
means that I look at me it is an hour of team
mark 300 megabytes of traffic
average quality actually means sd better and
refers to normal television locations
reference almost a gigabit a  gigabytes
per hour high quality we are at 3 gigabytes
per hour it is ultra hd 7 gigabytes per hour
so we have a number of traffic that
we are going to move which is really
important that we do not even give in to
imagine
we do the math a little faster
about a movie in streaming  we are at 6
megabits per second about very
spannometric it means that I will have 6
megabits that arrive at miur ucan
making an estimate of how many users there
may be  eras connected for a
control unit of an operator of a street
of a zone comes out an account that
was about 384 megabits per second that
come out of my cab
clearly the cups are about 100 for
central comes a small neighborhood
etc. it
means that my central  in
short, remittances
of the city go to the
collection center in my central unit between gigabits per second
simply with a few users who
in the evening look via the internet
well 3 gigabits a neighborhood a small
neighborhood we are not talking about a
building where maybe we have the only one
200 people watching him towards
netflix instead clearly that mind
depends on a million factors this
cartoon is quite significant well
now solved his bandwidth problem
ok daily is not the solution
that can be adopted because honey clicks
I do not know what spotify I say  at home I
can't have a big pipe so it
brings me the internet in my data cent  er yes I
can have it I must obviously have it
is not the solution that allows me to
numerically scale the problem of the
capillarity of the users what is the
solution that went to apply for
example netflix
for snai clicks not because it is connected
to them in any way indeed  but
simply because what the
clearest published data
netflix solutions is is a classic appliance they
will call open connect appliance and it
seems to me an insecure 5 rack unit
tarech have managed to make us fit a lot of
stuff because there are 36 hard drives and 8
terabytes v6 from  a terabyte been alone
more back series of things them
these what they simply do are the
classic cash servers like google as
has them akamai as have them practically
all those and fan content delivery
so what do you say instead of
bringing me operator mille the rabbit
band  and my data center from here I do
the distribution of all
I periodically push my
contents on these devices  itives
scattered around the world where clearly
surely in the points with the big
providers or in the internet exchanges
so they had to hurt the providers and
so whoever did my occupation of the
first level and then distribution to
the user these devices deal with these devices
here we have 296  terabytes of disk space
that is what you have fix it deems
appropriate to have all the content
most in use clearly because I am going to
do all the non-existent tests
of content pilused close to the customer
how do I get it this I am an
operator providing very simple spi
just ask for it  if or at least 5 gigabits of
average traffic to netflix the task
the forum I wait a few days but
this nice toy arrives at home
clearly after stopping a thousand
cards that I am not going to open them to
disassemble them the distribution of contents things
that are clearly deplorable and we
do not  we will never
unfortunately I did not have an otherwise I would have
brought it here yes I'll bring it to you
they change en masse and I know it I know
very
well so this is the solution yes how
there is this there is the solution this were
the first that google gave you in the old
days and if I do not even know if google tv
is more this stuff
or what  akamai does the same thing also
these are ancient archive photos
still the flop of this is right to
understand well
said this the solves the problem
operators are my legal operator and
two for legal means used
authorized unloading I pay the rights and the
usual things  that of course we are
perfectly in agreement you have to do it
and all the others
really happen you all know
megavideo all those beautiful
streaming services not really complex the
copyrights and those and this ip tv
test now you have 4000 movies tv series on
demand is all streaming to skyhighs
all possible channels in the world to
premiums even testing is free if you want to
try
I don't know if you know them you pay them like
15 dollars a month 30 dollars a m  ese
according to the service you want that they
give me practically all the
premium premium channels theses I do not predict
operators but all those expresses in bb
tv this clearly is what
runs away because obviously I operator of
this service that every server in I
do not want to know where I can not  go
artfully he appliance to your home and see
that in this way the rite to pirate users
download they eat the internet
this is the fundamental problem because
he is the fundamental problem because he runs away
from optimization systems is not that he is
skilled you do not know where he comes from so
maybe he comes from a  lost operator
passes pliny peeling at 10 megabit
instead of the one at 10
gigabit you cannot organize a bit
problematic just to understand it
I apologized I was looking at a
small, very fast analysis that I had
done of the traffic of one of my
operators in the evening if  i dont
remember in person some time i had
pulled down on madame pato and about 670 4
gigabit bikes  they are gigabytes these are and
streaming traffic this is no longer
just that it captures everything that passes they
have been 100 gigabytes it is an analysis
this made me a little worried
because a simple flash that identifies it
all that is
megavideo etc. then when the
first  patient however about the
movie streaming via flash 24 per cent and
so much sopcast that here does not call it I know
this is not what I had the times
the sopcast labels so everything
we had seen before in here
69 per cent so 70 plus 24 is 94
3.1 percent streaming this captures me all
that is legal traffic so
youtube then sky go so those things
there impressive this number get
stressed this is a network of about a thousand
users in total and a provider
in central Italy we have not been name
anyway that  absolute residential
but I think I have no business user
this interesting this number because it
means that the situation is there  a little
getting out of hand it hit the stadiums
minds june this then june of
this year so definitely after
the arrival of netflix
I don't know if here I maybe caught the only
moment when everyone was
watching his latest movie just released on
megavideo  it could also be I receive
the capture made on the fly just to
make the slide maybe if I make
a capture on the slightly wider range of
verses but the numbers come out
definitely
they at this I do not know is a number
that I have seen for  case it jumped at my
eye mission slide well the impact
to this is an analysis made by cisco which
predicts the trend in the next 3 4
years or so where digital media adapter
means the number of connected devices that
can stream me it means
everything means  to say apple tv means
raspberry everything that is connected and
you allow me to stream and input
the number from 2016 to 2020 you see it is
practically not saying it has doubled but
we are passing to 141  million
devices and 242 million
important fact let's look at the impact of
traffic this is actually aggregate traffic
as you can see we are
talking about 80 to 2020 from 2016
I am learning about 180 what is the
premise bike so this what it means it
means  substantially that for the
future we will certainly need to focus
more on delocalizing traffic to
say how telecom is doing telecom has done
telecom for those who are informed a year
ago what did it do two years ago now
who acted as a peeling manger be
decidedly against this because
clearly who or service providers
must buy the pd that with telecom and
direct if he wants to reach users
recently otherwise he goes around
frankfurt for jesolo he knows where it is
clearly around the
esabyte bottleneck expected in a
few years of difference
this is enough  slide went to the end I know
that the power point of the mei that that
of the gray if they are not very com
patibili asks questions about it
very well thank you