well in the meantime good morning everyone and who I
am so let's start from this and I
work in a detective agency
consequently with me as for this
reason I also deal with
digital investigations not to be confused with cola
forensics instead then digital
forensics and I am passionate in
I write and for an online magazine I
collaborate with the chair of
legal informatics in Milan and I have been a
system engineer and technician for about
twenty years what I am here to
do today is instead to take you on a
path that I can explain to you  that
can make you understand what
logint is therefore open source intelligence
and and what tools open source
intelligence uses to get
to people's information and
we will also see the types of shots typical
of online users' mistakes the talk
in fact the title is  what the network knows about
us the imprudence of the user what
we will talk about we
will see logint so that elsewhere it is
nothing but the ac  onimo of open surce
intelligence the tools the techniques
but above all what is the
biggest danger for those involved in
computer science which is the human factor
kahlil gibran a lebanese philosopher poet
once wrote this reveals to the
wind your secrets you must not then
reproach  in the wind of revealing them to the
trees you immediately understand what
this means and this is also the sentence
reported at the beginning of a book a
manual explore the internet by
leonida rita believe that he is the president
of the investigative journalism association
and the council among other things  to those of you who are
interested in open source
intelligence and also defines the
first manual on
very complex open source intelligence then there are
a number of other documents on the net
but as a manual in which
some things are also summarized I took them right
dal is certainly an excellent an excellent
manual
let's frame the problem on the web
personal data at risk from cybercrime  me down to
500 million consider that cybercrime has
increased 30 percent this
year compared to last year
well before talking about open source
intelligence
let's take a step back what it is, that is,
what are the phases the 5 phases normally
that take place in  an
intelligence procedure not in an
intelligence activity cell humint human
intelligence is an activity that we say
useful forever on some note for
the management of the network of
human informers therefore the informers who make
intelligence then precisely the management of
these informers then  the news that
brings us is called activity of rivers
then there is the demanding sigint instead
deals with the interception of
communications li ning and from the
processing and analysis of images taken
by satellites from spy planes it is now
lately from logi drones we will see it
shortly  open source intelligence
therefore all those activities aimed at
obtaining information from networks,
let's say open by public r  eti il
magint as the fifth phase
of intelligence and deals with analyzing
the radiological spectrographic chemical signatures
of weapon systems and vectors
that can harm national security
what the
login activity of
information retrieval from open sources
let's see better what it is is a
method of investigation was born within
the secret services and is among other things
very powerful among other things we design is
very powerful because  thanks to users
it is becoming more and more even
within
intelligence organizations its contribution is
between 80 and 90 percent of the
entire information collection is
a refined and complex methodology
that therefore transforms data and
information separately  apparently
disconnected from each other and the experts in
any area of the network, therefore
including the deep web and and transforms it i  n
a coherent framework that is significant on
the investigative level, in
brackets I put criminal because as
we will see, as we will see, logint shares
the tools and techniques that
we will then go to it in a very synthetic way
to see it shares with the king with
penetration testing with
investigative journalism with  the
classic investigations with intelligence what
are the tools and procedures this
also serves to make us understand that
tools and techniques are not born
negative or positive but it is the use that we
go to make that identifies them as such
in order to be defined osint a '  activity
must have precisely the requisites and which
ones must use
unclassified information information acquired in
a lawful way so no to king no
wiretapping an espionage
if we want to define it osint however the
techniques are then also used
for other types of activities
public actions are used is  a
systematic methodical activity subject to
evaluation  ion must be useful to
answer these
intelligence and investigative questions is a very
important premise to make that
lawes int open source intelligence
should not be confused with an open source operating system
or with all those software that
are open source where for open source an
operating system a  free software
the open source intelligence and concerns the
public sources we access and to
do so lodging also provides
free activities but also of the non-
free paid type let's see then
what are the techniques many of which
I am already convinced indeed certainly there
with them  do you know precisely why the
techniques are shared by dalla king
from penetration testing
we start from the king of search engines
google google and if you look at us
we will see if you look at the source and beats
but if about one billion and 600
million visitors in August 2016 and it is
let's say the most used
search engine google has a double problem
regarding privacy deg  the users
and therefore
the our information that remains on the
network
the first is that with hacking tools you
call google a king
or google dork we will go to
retrieve the information
simply by making queries on
the search engine
in addition but google  with all
its beautiful cine applications it collects a
lot of information about us and
what many do not think and that when
we connect to google to access
e-mails and then we go to do some
research
or we use hangouts for a
videoconference  all these things
remain in google
and then it will use them and for
targeted advertising or even probably who can
say it for those who are selling it to some
advertising company well let's see how it
can be useful and how
google used for osint activity how many  of
you have ever tried to put
your name and surname in quotes on
google
well you realized something that
unexpected  ate un bye did not
even remember anymore that they appear
crazy so that social networks never come
out all but also the single
tweets that are put associations
where one works addresses
telephone numbers from the lists the white pages
on the fortissime from this point of view  given
the contributions first home there are the
funding the tenders so
simply by putting a name and surname
on google
we come to know many of those things the
advanced techniques that I told you
advanced techniques that are nothing more than queries
performed on the search engine but google
but similarly also to da sui others that
with advanced tools and strings
you go to both
retrieve information on subjects
let's say natural persons
legal persons but also it is widely
used for the penetration
testing phase to understand vulnerabilities
in fact penetration testing  the use
of google docs is perhaps one of the
activities that are always done on c  dares
the google docs are based I have put some
but man and there are so many
also on the net there is a lot of
documentation on this on
special characters the typical gold land the
quotes the minus the tilde and
the asterisk where we say those maybe
less used are the tilde to
find synonyms let's say of words
at least to remove from the query
something that we do not want
the results to appear as instead
search operators that can among
other things also the power of google
doc that can be combined both
characters  which operators between them are the
ones you see in the text then all
inter which is another operator but which
always concerns the category of the
inter type all inn texas inter we
will find all the documents that have
to do and have the word osint
all  'internal title is something that
instead goes to look in the title tag
of the web page and consequently to
those who are the titles come out,
among other things, very famous  el index of
then title index of come out
all the directories that it finds in short
google index of mp3 come out all
the mp3 directories so this very
convenient handy in a scream and often
used to find let's say that for
logint if these examples here are not
very fitting on the in screams for example
with the login precisely aspol admin point php
which is used to find all those sites
that have beliefs in the
log in pages to enter the
platform and the osint lin url can
still be useful because we want to
look for something  to be exactly
inside the war of a site
here we come we come be
the cache is useful
the word says so what can
be used the last cash registered by
google of a site the site
very useful this to see all the
subdomains of a site  domain so what do I
know
site site punto.it will show me site
punto.it but will also show me
director spunto site punto.it
commercial punto  site punto.it etc.
but I can also use a word before for
example contacts site site.it finds me
those pages of the site punto.it which has
the word contact
the fai type says the term identifies
that type of characters and that type of
type  of file so what do I know filetype
pdf finds me everything that has
as type of pdf file pdf extension
if I already put cv filetype doc it finds me
to all those who are cv files
puntodoc the google docs are powerful
because there is  ability to
automate queries and then automatically
find ready-made ones in fact when
kato a site that purely many of you already
know where they are
depending on what one has to do that I am
username and find the files of users
and  password
then go to lime user name and password and
pulls out the queries to be made by combining
characters of search operators
here we enhance the tool even more
I made some examples below
all inn texas sinda  co of venice
finds me everything I want to find
out I know what his name is mayor of
venice I don't know enough this simple
query finds me all the pages it
says mayor of venice surely it will be written mayor of venice pinco
pallino no mario rossi  filetype
colon doc finds me all the doc files that
have mario rossi inside the site
site punto.it minus site director punto
site.com and venezia finds all
subdomains of the site punto.it except
the director does not show it to me.  site
point 50 written paragraph and tir typo and the
venice narrows even more the search shows
me those that have to do
with venice so probably
venice offices rather than the site
point pt here we say here with this
we finish what are the techniques of
google dorking of advanced techniques
no of google I told you however that then there is
also the other side the other aspect of
google which is what stores our
information I took some common ones
let's say a very
comfortable one of the very comfortable screens of yes magazine where I laughed
really summarizes the thing then
starting from the fact that the online users
in the world are three billion 271 and 228 if
I use gmail and google second I
had to register to open
gmail as long as I did  the honest i
had to put my name and surname address
date of birth is those
yellow information to google sex age and
place
but not only 6 i use chrome and i do my
youtube searches rather than maps
google will know where i had to go
on vacation what i listen to  what i like
and what i watch where i work not only with
lang out and the google calendar could
know who i talk to who i am who
is my network of contacts from where how
long
do we talk what we write so imagine
shopping and wallet instead they will make us
understand where  let's make google understand
where we shop
how much we spend what we like in short,
etc. I have indicated for those who do not  he
knew a very useful
country-specific search engine let's say it's
a directory of
is a list of specific search engines
divided by area but there
are further filters that can be
done so what do I know and also there and also
in the language
I want to do  a search in japanese
because i am able to do it i'm going to
catch a japanese search engine
and i will usually be able to do it otherwise the
search engine has optimized based on
dns based on other factors they optimize and
localize
google results if you even if not
you probably ask him often the
results only in Italian
if you want those in English to
keep specifying it in the language if
you want to go directly to the site instead
a search engine that is located
in japan is obviously write in
japanese life surely you have
solved you have overcome this problem
seal those who already know seal
someone is the one we know without
having to study seal that is going to
fingerprinting organization with
collected archivist what ff does it is
phenomenal to understand from the metadata of the
files that it finds on a site how many
computers per year
who are the people who work
there because you understand very well that
if I agree I make my own fi bed
they put it and serve it  or we
publish it on the south on the site and I
did it I will come out the pc this the pc
erian di antonio made by antonio is
when little thing does he downloads all the files
he finds on the sites then at analyzes the
metadata he pulls them out and me  will
show and it is in this case I did
the yen seal summercamp of the site he
pulled out only two pdf documents
he also failed by analyzing the metadata
to understand a bat in which users
in the folders in the pc but on live
I guarantee the  I did for the municipality of Venice,
he pulled out the operating systems
that had in fact then surprising that
how many administrations still use
windows 98 for example and therefore
id operating systems  people who wash themselves
working inside the photos very
interesting for the photos
even manage to define sorry
I have for the photos manage to define
beyond that if there is the
active localization also that but also the type
of car that blues that  has produced
or device in short, device that
produced the photo another programmone
in fact the people I fly over because we
would not need let's say two weeks of
course just to learn these here and
malte go malte go
in this case you see I made the
query based on then I keep then
while seal uses the search engines
up to three uses we have indicated
here above
you see how much google bing uses and
this other one here exalead and
through queries therefore the search on the
south on the sites is valid instead malte go maintain
malte go also uses searches on dns
uses very complex searches on the
targets that we give we can point to
a person could show us the
emails where comp  this person
I did it on the common
domain.venezia.it doing only 23
phone number searches he
found me all the phone numbers that I
raise the municipality of venice on the
common domain of venice however he managed to
recover but not only
then I asked  the email came
to me so I already know that the municipality of
venice at urp municipality of venice inquires
handy cup municipality of venice
to educators etc. and the intranet or
the intranet exploded and showed me
the machines with their public ip  what they
have then let's say that this is
nothing compared to what matthew can
do
you know very well everyone with a
simple lewis on a domain
I know the name and surname of the person who
registered it I know where he lives and only
the organization he  head and I know that
you are a registrant there are
recently some services that when
you go to register the domain allow you
to hide certain information but only
for some types of domain some
tools but here  and you will
surely know more than me domain tools does it
a bit but there are
many that make you know how to say
both make you and luiz
but you also know the dns lookup they make you the
translations from one side to the other and
then retrieve all the information
you need for the osint neon airplane that
takes off for mouse int the
wayback machine is fundamental those who know it
these to this is very powerful that is
very useful because because someone puts
an information then deletes it
after a distance of days maybe
I delete it  I can go and see if
going back that web machine the
site as it was on that date in which
I presume he put it had published the
thing and I find myself exactly as the
site was a little while ago obviously serves
precisely to retrieve information from
sites  or pieces of them lost or
deleted after publication I
made the wayback machine on the site in
summer camp and we have the first image
that already had
better  the first archive that had wayback
machine was that of 2006 where among
other things the facts we discovered
were doing it in san donà di piave not here,
however, so it seems those who are so old from the
sun of the end summer camp that can
confirm this thing, oh well anyway  the
site speaks for itself so it was was
and they did it definitely okay
here you see simply we went to
see how their site in 2006 here we
break through an open door that is logint
now lives on social networks lives
on facebook in an incredible way lives
of twitter of linkedin of everything but also
all the others of the google category
there is a beautiful song the text
is beautiful I like that of j ax and fedez
that says I would like but not post and says a
sentence that took me by surprise c  'is
that he never really liked me that
says how the children will take us
seriously with the evidence that over the years
we have left on facebook dad who
every weekend was drunk lost and the
mother who throws  the directors go to every
concert
these are the words of the test and
this and that is this and that minimum that
worries me is minimal but we will see we will see
I will show you that you can find everything on
facebook so it is not the bra the
problem is having  sharing that is the fact
of sharing more than you
really should share and
why this often happens due to lack
of awareness of the risks often by
mistake often out of anger hatred
that is, they subscribe to those things now
praise online is incredible and what and
where are the portals more let's say  which
are the queen of social networks because
after that there is the network of contacts that
propagates the information
not nowadays, as I was saying,
the analysis of the data contained in social
networks is an invaluable source for
intelligence activity  on the web
personal data subjects date of birth
how many people put their date of
birth on facebook then I'll explain what
happens and leave it to me to put it
belonging to groups  the associations
left therefore we started at
noon and a half true it is therefore
up to 1 roja until one and a half
today they wrote you however well
limit we interrupt with us or for an hour
as the duration of the talk in theory is
the orientation  and religious sexual
show from another very powerful tool
that serves and that very useful to make
osint a very recent case for example
was that of a mother who was
alarmed after the article came out
that saw on the internet the photo of the
bedroom where they sleep  his two girls
but necessarily he had put the
surveillance cameras in it not the
control ones that probably who knows how it
was configured and on the routers and
consequently someone had managed to
steal the images inside
this woman's house shodan ago this shodan
allows you to  identify any
device connected to the network
and it is obvious that the worse configured they are
firmer does not find shodan finds
smart TVs only dan finds  beru terne
too rude and consequently if one
even the key I know of the
vulnerability of a router finds how many
there are in the internet to be able to
try to attack for example
frequent positions this also one
thing you love me love has only
surprised me  because then the institutions of the
phones of the manufacturers of the mobile phones
is not that they warn the iphone no the iphone
discovered that it has a beautiful option
inside the privacy settings
which is frequent position
the android co that happens the same thing
now sure they do not know the  it goes to
disable but maybe when one
knows it is better to do it because if then the
phone finds it to someone else heaven
takes a second that I go to the bathroom if
the colleague takes it takes it
love but the wife
suppose and these things can that
can  be born really unpleasant
misunderstandings because unpleasant inconveniences
rather than misunderstandings record everything I have
been more often and more frequently in
that place when I co  n what duration
thanks okay so here I
suggest for those who do not know about this
thing to check their phone is there
active or not the standard payroll function is
born with the function active
so you have to remove it it is convenient
in short web page and cookies inevitable to
say  that even the cookies
in any case track no
profiling ones track the laws, customs and
habits of all the users
who visit the pages it is okay the cookies
venice high the log files will be the
same because also the log files nene
that  there are on the internet and they record
our passage they record the pages
we have seen they record everything but
many activities that fall with you
in the private sphere of the people
there was an alarm from the
British privacy supervisor who discovered that
there is a technology that  allows you to
track the movements of the smartphone
using the mac address of the device
precisely that this thing happened in the
shops have this  technology that
caught the mac addresses of the devices
saw where they were going and what they
buy most often and mom
could not then identify who
were the
great people British privacy put
a brake on it because it's not that if I go to the
store, minimum I catch if obviously where
turn on they catch me the mac address and
then trace me which compartment I go to
or what I do
and yet it happened I usually on the
background of his articles I always put the
link then as if you want to go and
see you a beautiful article
that  did that carola frediani wrote in the press
a very very good journalist and he is
arrested so your smartphone knows
everything about you about your future
he made an infographic where he
showed that I think at 10 o'clock sending
emails are obviously recorded
emails somewhere the
provider knows at 12 30 phone
the operator with evening keeps
sender recipient type of call for two years
iamato the date duration the date the
duration then other data at 16 I
connect to the internet of my operator
keeps for a year when I connect
and from where I go on the e-commerce site
at 16 35 I am tracked by 15 other
companies the same when I go to the site  of the
weather dozens and dozens of the three that also
for media and media sites
so everywhere now with those on
smartphones
whatever we do there is the risk
is often the sum of being tracked
then it is obvious that they draw tracks by the
provider we see tracked by the site  e
commerce
but we are tracked and this the
governments know I recommend a beautiful
documentary that won the
oscar award in 2015 that the one that talks
about the history of modems with
nsa glue because it is very very nice on these
topics here in fact after the
detections detections that would then be
the revelations of the spying
of the intelligence agency and those
of the hecking team scandal on the
industry  private individual who checks
online the sensitivity as a municipality
towards the problem, however, it has increased
this is true there is no need to say it
of the researchers of the network security group of the
iti erice of the
federal polytechnic of zurich and giorgio danesi
stand of the university  London colleges
believe that it is the very infrastructure
of the network as conceived,
after all, it was born without thinking about the
problem of privacy or the data that
came in short
from user profiling
and it is precisely the network that is inclined
to surveillance
they then made an essay  in which they
present provide the new
anonymity system that will take the place of thor
and that should solve this
problem
the new idea is to have the
protection of privacy as an
integral aspect of the internet itself
now do not ask me how but this
would be the  idea in on earth and in hornet
the idea that internet providers can
integrate this service into their
infrastruct  ura digital offering a
more widespread privacy protection
will surely have to pass a long time
before ordet can take the place
of tower even if hornet has already collected
the interest of giants such as google
swisscom together with governments of switzerland
india seems to be panama fame for you have
known everything  what has
happened so far so far we have seen an
aspect that is related to
technology what is happening
nowadays is that many an aspect
that was not connected to technology before
is entering the network powerfully
and therefore increases the risks for  who
wants to know the facts of others,
now I will explain why, for example, with
the digitization of all documents
in the public archives, obviously
paying what is needed but archives
such as the land registry and online
if I register I can go and see
and know the name and a  surname of a person
and maybe the duty of which municipality he lives
I can see that real estate to all
properties  who has simply
sitting at my house
ditto for corporate information
once you had to go to the chamber of
commerce now with cerved 1 well you
subscribe or pay for the single service and can
know how many members a company
has made what turnover it is
budget
etc. etc. excels its offices and
therefore a lot of information
prejudicial protests other there are
specific sites mostly behind there is
a detective agency that has one that
has bought services from the bodies in
charge but by paying for the service you
can know if  a person is
protested gets a certificate of incorporation and
this was once done by going to
individual offices but not only in the municipality
where the person resided now you can
simply do it from home important point
you know that if I want I know the
name, surname and at least  in short, at a date of
birth of a person the area in and of the
municipality where he lives
I can get to have a family status as
well as a residency  to
freely without problems I will pay the
stamps I will pay a few
small pennies and I can do it because they are
public archives lana the registry office and the
marital status are public archives
once to do this you had to
go to the municipality for which the person
resided so many sites now a lot  never
again that so many municipalities are
putting online this thing for which
milan for example if you are not from
milan whoever you are you register but
you can do the family status or the
state of residence of someone who lives in
milan
what you need  obviously for this reason I was
saying first attention to what is
published and above all the data that is
used to identify a person if
I have my name and surname on
facebook but I put the date of birth
and where I live is enough to be able to
ask for one  family status in a
municipality ok and with a family status I
find out where you live because there is
also the residence together but also those who
live with you so this is the ge  nte does
not understand it and quietly in the wind
so they give me birthday wishes
yes ok but they also give you other wishes if
they wanted to come to your house
and do what they want
you see that in fact the
registry certificates, extracts and certificates of
state make family can  be
requested by anyone even if even if they are
registered in the name of other people they are
issued at all the
registry offices or through the
home delivery service the site of the municipality
of Milan which is increasingly
the municipalities will go in this direction
because they are useful services for
citizens  and also because in any case
they have the obligation to digitize the
documents another thing
the aci on the aci site but you know but if
I see a plate on the street I go to the
aci site I pay 8 euros but I see
whose car it is I see the name  and surname where he
lives
and this also while once you
have to go to the public
car register obtained from the top on
site then in z  ona and then usually one
did not do it now if one teases me
with the car and you want to go
to the cia site if you have the license plate
you can find out who the car is and
where this lives there is no license plate but
this is not  the
human factor has something to do with it and we
are about to close so far so
we have seen the
techniques with which we can get to
obtain information from people and
companies,
let's see why we can go
beyond public archives which, being
such, must necessarily  do it for which
they still have to put on the network
what is information that concerns us
unfortunately, however, they are only
public bodies so alas, let
's not hurt ourselves by going to
put other data on maybe on social media
on our site etc. and no
the amount of information
we publish on social media is enormous, however on the
internet it is not to be considered what we
spread that we put today but what
we  we have put
names on facebook since today to make a
profile of a person you do not look at the
post he has put today and you just go and
scroll through the bulletin board you go all the way
and you can know who are the friends
what he wrote  where he was on
vacation and all the other things very strong
those who write I go on vacation one
month how nice I go to hawaii go later come
back to us it will be a house burgled between
strange extras if the thieves thank and
date of birth photo of the view of the
terrace with the  geolocation that has
published the enthusiasm the photo of the
license just taken in the
meantime on the license a there is written
nothing true no to those who want to
harm us who wants to steal us in case he wants to
trace our complete profile to
implement social engineering because
then between intention  with the information
that you understand for example from facebook
or tweets from any social network or from a
site you can implement what social
engineering for which I post ch  and i know
that you like to go on vacation to
hawaii i
pretend to be a
travel agency i call you about what you have or a
promotional package simo to go
to hawaii you for your passion
maybe you fall for it but this is nothing
the agencies of  intelligence this
the detective agencies do this the
police
do this they do hand a lot more they can do
still very widespread and the
underlying problems are we human beings we
forget the internet no once
we put stuff on the internet it
remains for us then it comes out that  which is the
big problem of the right to be forgotten
because if I have been
condemned ten years ago if you go
look today my name still appears
because maybe there is the article
there I would have the right in theory no to
tacchio and then  10 years are gone I
got out enough must people
still have to know maybe
it happened and then maybe get an idea
that is no longer what is me now
no
so this is a gr  osso problem
attention because in fact
publishing is quick but then in ten years as
the song from our children's song says
one tomorrow that is they will discover that
maybe the parents went drunk
every Friday or that they danced
on the cube that chienes I understood so
this is the problem  it is also because
even the best technology can fall
under behavior in a t manner
but not only the technology itself
can be vulnerable if in addition but the
configured means that what in
theory should remain safe is no
longer so because it is published  maybe on the
internet I will
conclude by showing you if this is
very strong they have created a
facebook page called photo license mozzecane
mozzecane is a municipality of verona
if they are clever to say come on we put them
all the photo of our license now
someone was smart and
maybe just put the  photos and some data
come so you can see that I know
in the Mozzecane residence via Maria
Ausiliatrice
I know  the name surname because it is ok name and
surname here is the city is here there is the
street already or some
interesting information this has been overcome a
little more because he has also put the dates of
the date of birth is heck and sorry  and
I know that she is from Mozzecane I know where she lives and
that you also have the date of birth or
if I go to the registry office of ascom I have everything
of her and this is the best of
all because she put everything for which name
place of birth city  residence the
signature also the signature if I wanted to make a
document in his name
I can also copy the signature ok the
license number and issued by whoever
ita here this is this is nothing of
what you actually see today on the
internet
I put the two links  of where I took two
photos that I showed you that so to be
fair and I ended up in the space
I hope I have not bored
you if you have any questions good morning
thanks in fact a couple of questions
let's see since you have criticized some
public records
no it's not that the  or critic  ate that
burns me a positive result that is the sites but
they have certain mechanism it was very
correct you never said it is wrong
added that it was limited to saying I
don't like any more yesterday I had to go around
the seven churches
today the problem could be maximum
in the sense that if I download 56
million records and do an analysis I do
something that yesterday I could not exact
said this the fact that those registers
are public to some
ancient reasons and that they are at the base of the wall
ceases very important you did not talk
about  su brianza i.e. the idea that
if privacy is completely pink
the real point is the information symmetry
someone knows something about me I don't know who
knows something about me someone a little
aggregate a lot of data I don't
control my data there are some  social
networks that play the type if you want to
see that he has seen your profile
when you go to the team they see that
you have gone if you want to remain anonymous you do not
see that you see the second t  and it could
be a procedure as to say to be
implemented also at the level of
public administrations I give you
all the public data you want
but the data are of the person
I am talking about that person has the
right to know that you have
looked at him according to and this  it can be a
process to be put in place.
even physically in the registry office
this happens so there is yes the problem is
this I do not think that even we remove the
internet
I do not think that every family status that
one goes to make of one of a
common person they advise they do not do it because it
is prudent they are
not required not  I don't know I have never
informed myself of this they do it for the
prudent transparency that is said because
one day, one day if it comes out  i
something can be traced back but I have
never heard of anyone who
actually went to tell who
asked and I am not even if they give it to you
who asked for information about me I
do not know if they give it to you probably it is for
how it is made  but probably the network
now I think it is difficult that for
example if I download no I can
get there bye better perhaps from the
same institution from which I download yes future there
could be an idea that I know I
ask the municipality for the family status the
status  of a family that to whom the eyes of those
of that person who sends them
an email look should understand the
rationale of why these registers are
public and why we should
really understand but it would perhaps be
even easier with technology now
certainly yes but even if  a
chance to implement this thing
here when I
fraudulently register a stolen cat and charity
or things like that by specifying my identity
we are formed s  ignor mario rossi
that someone was true is the result of the
family in fact it is not that we can
then trace who actually was
in my opinion certainly it is that we enter them,
however, in a perspective that then you know and
of crime for which crime is
always a step forward
fundamentally so what I think about here he was saying to me
name alberto was something that was
alien to the fact
of crime that is normally it
could be done because because it could
be my right to know that you have
asked for my family status
however it comes to mind that this is not even
said because on ponies whoever
does investigations that must remain
hidden to also suppose an activity that
is a private investigator
probably must, that is, the municipality must know
that maybe
I did it for the forces of the  I order
the judicial authority but not to tell
the person from whom I asked maybe
this is the right key to reading
because they must be guarantors  ti
those subjects who make the assessments
protected by the law understood then
then after that it would be
difficult to distinguish who does it who
does not that is one more step
no no no money in fact it is true
it would be necessary to implement
china I just said it is  a little more complex
still because then I would have to
tell you this yes but I have to prove
it to you so then I should also give you the
document that I am an investigator
no his are waiting only because
the investigator can do nothing except
on behalf of someone not  it
's half
past one they're not hungry very quick question you talked about the
hornet project is that there are already some big names
who are interested in supporting it
but their intention to collect data goes a little bit
to the turkey to
anticipate Thanksgiving
what is the point then that the big names take an
interest in a project that lives
would invite themselves to
collect  data about us because
they have to do they have to make a nice face
and then purely they won't
and this maybe the chariots do because they
can't say no no no I didn't understand they
have to say yes beautiful beautiful
we settle down with that
public opinion then a lot  basically we do it
but the rest of the nsa the American government went
ahead for a lifetime to say
that it is not true that it did what
modena said so this is the problem
is a multinational may be
interested that the user can
only be traced by them  using their
services and not from others it is certain in fact
another
hello while even then if the last
question
ok the last question guys sorry
time is running out
sauces there are techniques similar
to google docs for the dark we are
a very special topic
in my opinion  yes but it already exists
here I had read an abstract or an
article published recently that
some researchers have made this
bar system  shield earning to
find zero day on the web in dar I look
then something is maybe not as
public as google
google searches but there is something there
communications in service
you have to run if you want to have lunch at
login to get poker