hi all i am andrea
easy work on youtube some software and
today's presentation on
france reconstruction of ntfs when
metadata is partially damaged
that the work i did as
master thesis so i am going to explain today
when i started doing this this
work I got the idea to take care
of this I actually thought
how important it is to know something not
only about the content of the files but also
its metadata that is the names of the files
or the dates on which they were
modified or their content
and I  actually asked there
are examples where this was important
actually there are and I wanted to
present some cases for example in
alberto stasi that you will probably
know for another very
famous case and was acquitted of
possession of child pornography material
that had been found on the  computer is
in the first time
the defendant had suffered a
thirty-day sentence of imprisonment  ion which were then
converted into a fine, however in the
decision of the cassation it was
underlined in several points how it was
important to know the specific
folder in which certain files are located in order
to understand the meaning that
those files had and the fact that they were
files found in  of the unallocated clusters
there were files that had
been deleted they did not directly
access and also the fact that the
names of these fragments did not understand
the content of the child pornography of
these multimedia file appointments
all these elements were
fundamental and have  allowed to
prove that for this crime alberto
stasi was innocent and therefore was
acquitted of a risk of 30 days
in prison or a fine
but it did not end there because a few years
earlier you did not exist united in 2008 in
massachusetts
michael viola who was an employee  for
a public company in massachusetts he
lost his job because on the
corporate laptop  and
traces of child pornography material were found
at first no one had
believed that this person
had no idea that there were these
documents but later it was
possible to verify that there was
malware installed on the laptop that
dealt with  visit up to 40 sites per
minute with child pornography content
so in this case the timing of
saving the files made it possible to
demonstrate that it could not be a
human being who saved in the
browser cache or in any case in the
file folders so quickly but it had to
be  necessarily a program
this person was then found
not guilty
after losing his job he had lost his
pension having spent 250 thousand dollars in
the lawsuit having made a second
mortgage having sold the car and
risked 30 months in prison
so you understand that it is  then year and he and his
wife suffered
health problems from stress
on  process you understand well that in this
case it is also the metadata such as the
modification access time were
decisive but it can even get worse
than that because he risked 30 months
a teacher in 2008 always in
connecticut and her name is giulia mero to
was teaching  as a substitute teacher in a
class in which he had done he had
logged in the official teacher
let's say supported on the
school computer because he had to show
content to the students
and while he was browsing on sites
suitable for children, pop ups came out
visit with content  pornographic
therefore not even child pornography but
simply pornographic files
rightly since they were not
child pornographic files they were simple pop
ups but some boys were seen did not
risk 30 months in slave prison 40
years of imprisonment because the
Americans up like this and therefore this person
risked 40  years of imprisonment
because malware was installed on the computer e
it was possible to determine this
only thanks also in this case to the
display of the timing of the
files and the government
were observed in the browser cache in the
meantime carlo was checked
for the files opened with the browser and then it
was indicated that the timing
they were not possible so it could not
have been a person who had
manually navigated between sites but that the pop ups
had come out all together
exactly as
the defendant said and then after a few years of
trials she was, let's say, acquitted
she did not do these  years in prison
words have revoked the
teacher's license because rightly in the
meantime we consider the guilty ones but you
understand that it is very important in this
case it is not so much the content of the files
alone but the metadata that is the
content of the files is important but to
understand that  meaning they must
also understand the context there is because a
file is located a certain approx  rtella as
a certain modification date because a
certain name etc.
so these are all the information
that we would not want to lose when
perhaps data is extradited from a hard
disk but it can also happen that it
deals with a damaged hard disk and
therefore  some information is not
available it is important to
reconstruct everything
available
and get it out
but there is a problem as
banking wrote in its
file system forensic analysis book that there is
very little published on the
recovery procedures when the  metadata is
absent or damaged and therefore I
decided to study this type
of reconstruction recovery and I decided to
do it on ntfs in particular very
interesting ntfs for two reasons the first is
that it is very widespread because
there is practically one in every house  of course
you can find it on external hard drives or
all computers that use windows
windows is in the picture and then ntfs has a
structure v  ariable
if you take two ntfs file systems
you should not expect to always find
in the same point
the table that contains the list of
files or the file that represents the
bad sectors etc.
however the pieces are those but you always find them
in different points so it is
important to succeed  to understand how to
access even if some references
information are not available here
to do this we essentially
go to look on our hard drive for
what tracks are and there
are three types of main elements
these are characteristic pressure
characteristic for ntfs the first type is
the  boot sector if you find this is very
convenient because it essentially
represents you where the partition begins and
in addition it also contains the
size of the partition which is useful
up to a certain point but above all it
indicates a parameter that I will then
explain in detail that says how much
large are the clusters and we need this
later
but there may also no longer be the
boot sector and not even the backup copy
and we see it later
then there are the file record of file record
are a series of rows let's say of a
table called mfp masterfile
table and these rows are one or more
lines for each file and for each folder
and therefore there is written for example
the file name and the modification access dates
a directory there are also
links to other records which are
called index records the index records
instead contain the  list of all the
children
so we call a directory so
all the files that are contained
within
and this is useful for us to do what
is the final goal that I
proposed at the beginning which was to
reconstruct a tree structure  i.e.
starting from a disk extract the tracks
that are there analyze them in a world that
I will explain shortly
and at the end reconstruct the
most accurate tree structure possible of the files
that are inside more in addition  to
those said about as a red mark
maybe of the files that had been
deleted
or somehow we can
understand that there were in the past if there are
still traces that allow us
to identify them then
the first thing to do is scan the
disk is to find all the file records but
there is a problem because when we
find the file records
we have scanned an entire disk
we do not know whether there was only one
partition on the disk of type ntfs
even if maybe some tracks are from
one partition  previous one that has been
overwritten with another partition more
or less in the same place so some
records have overwritten and others have not
then there is a very practical method to
first filter these files and
go and divide them into parts in the
diagram I put  on the slide
you can see for example the first file at
a number which is 29 the next
then I'm going to see each
element knowing how big where it would be  the
position of the number zero would be in a
certain point
I repeat this process also for the
second file and I realize that
actually these two files must
belong to the same partition because
they have the same offset with respect
to element 0 also the third is like this
but the fourth  you see that it breaks the
sequence so the fourth belongs to
another partition I have to remember
that I have to admit this somewhere else
then it happens like this again and again I
find a file that instead belonged to
the previous partition and I can
do this thanks to the  starting offset of
in this case it would be practically where
the m lt starts not the partition but the
file table if instead I had
simply looked at where the numbers
jump I would have found three groups and not
two
so I would have been wrong and in this case
also analyzed four because  there are
three jumps so there are 44 discontinuities
but in reality there are two groups of files
now I have done the la scre  mature and / or
split the record files into two
partitions that I do not know yet what
structure year
but I can work separately on
these types of records
the final goal was to build a
tree here this is the color of the two
partitions the final goal was this one
a tree  how normally a
file system works is an operating system that
exists of the file system the operating system
reads the tree starting from the root
then starts from the main node that
maybe on windows it can call us or other
letters and then goes down using the pointers
to the various children  and it reads the
next folders then the path is explored
from top to bottom
but what happens in this case if a
node for some reason has been
deleted or the track has been lost
because the disk is ruined it happens that
all the subtree then  all the
underlying elements disappear and it
may also be that I do not
realize in some circumstances that there was
or was in the past a  folder
that was in there then let's start again for
a moment from our elements that
we found scattered on ours on
our memory
instead of thinking like a
normal operating system let's try
to think backwards what happens if we
think from the bottom up if we
take  for each known
parent
at this point we have already
rebuilt a good part of the tree
and for these two files that have been lost
these two files do not already have a
parent but
we have not found this parent
anywhere.  'it was no trace
no record relating to that parent but
we know how to say the lead and I
the numeric of the parents of these two
elements so we can know ok there was
a folder that contained two fouls
I don't know what it's called
I don't know what date it had  I know that that was
a folder
that contained two items so
I'm not going to mix them with the others
at this point what I do simple  mind
I miss a piece because I do not know that
folder that parent has in this case
it associates them with a folder called
lost files in this way I have rebuilt the
whole directory structure and
this is an example on a very small
anti-reflective and true partition with
very few files inside  this is the output
of the program in the sense that the
milk code that throws it out of the program and
as you can see the first are
system files that have the dollar in front of them
are ntfs files that you find on
all healthy partitions then there are red files
one  which was already a file that
I found but which was marked with me
simply deleted then there are
blue files that I called ghost files
which are files of which I have not found
the record directly but indirectly
I understood that they existed thanks to
example to their children or to the
index records that still contained a
track not supported by the fesr record and
this was the first result of the
my reconstruction work is beautiful
very satisfactory but actually
up to here we have forgotten a
fundamental detail that I have only
found the tree structure of the file
system
I have not found anything regarding
the contents of the files and I have to
recover the contents of the  file there is
another problem that disks use a
geometry in sectors event fs a
geometry in cluster clusters is a
group of sectors which could be
two could be four we don't
know because each ntfs file system
uses a different power of two up  at
128 it seems to me
some are more frequent others less but in
any case we know it is so far so
we have not found where the
partition begins that hekla space nor the
sectors per cluster
parameter without these two parameters there is
only us that we recover the contents
of the partition
because  all references to
file contents are clustered from where
the file system begins
f  so far we don't know how big
class and how slow it is towards the file
system unless we have found the boot
sector that specifies these two
parameters but that's the simple case
let's say and then at that moment one
says but why not  I did the
computer vision thesis in which I find the photos
I find the points and and when you point them
what happens I
attach the photos and make a nice panorama it
would have been much easier but in
reality what I did here was
find where I had to place the  photo
is how much I had to distort it to make it
match with the other photo that you look
a bit is something that can also be done
here because what happens if we find
that the partition lists me a series
of and read directories which point
to  indications expressed in
clusters to their vector indices and a says
jol index my index is
cluster 0 that zero is impossible but they are
still an uncertain example cluster the
directory b lithium but  my index
cluster 1a director idc of what I at
number 3 what happens I have
a vague idea of how the partition is made
because I realize that it
had at least four clusters ok okay well
in the first there was an index record  of a
folder knows that at a certain number
in the second cluster there is a
rugby index record and in the fourth that is that of the
directory c
obviously provided that some of these
have not been deleted or
damaged by for other reasons
at this point I have a  'idea of how
the cluster partition is made
who is already something compared to before
more
always remember that we have
scanned the disk sectors so
we know that in certain sectors there are
index records of these index records
we find the
corresponding directory  reading the
file list because if that ten file list
and all these ten files say my
parent at number 4 ok then that
is directory index record number
four for f  orza because otherwise they would
all be randomly placed but I don't know
yet how big a cluster is so
I can only try and try with a
sector per cluster what happens if
I put a sector per class it happens that
it is wrong because this is not the
right parameter you see not  there is no
match so climbed for cluster
equal 1 is not valid for this
partition but now what if I try
with sector cluster equal 2
in this case it happens that it was right
thanks to the index record of the pointers and
the index records that are in the file
records  I found both the
cluster value bass that is where the
partition starts and the size of the sectors
all this without the boot record because
there was therefore no
reference of where nice the
hollaback partition of the back up the good doctor
dear where it ends  that I have found
everything I need this works with
an approximate matching so you
can do it even if there are some
discrepancies  and because in the end on
hundreds or thousands of records it is
enough to do a vote and I see that it
matches for 85 to 90 percent
anyway I have found the
correct position it is not important that it is one
hundred percent you can use
approximate sting matching techniques
in fact this matching is done in the
software using string matching so
I have two strings optimized in a certain
way because they have a lot of the ebook in the
middle but let's say I call the strings
are actually lists and then
the matching is done so
at this point I first  I had found the
tree structure of the file system
now I also found where the file
system starts and how big the clusters are
what does it mean that in theory
I know everything I know all the references to the
contents of fi and be able to recover the
files
then I put myself  to try I
tried a very small disk made a
case on purpose where I created a
partition of fs in the middle let's say with a
parameter no  n conventional which was 16
sectors per cluster which quite rare
and I put a lot of files in it
after which it is also 45 directories
after which I deleted the
initial boot sector the final boot sector so
there was no trace of where
the table of start  partitions
that however we have never used here and
I have also deleted all the file records
of the system files then mf tmt mirror
log file etc.
he tells me I have not
found any partitions and therefore
enough that is I am not going to do them
we open with auto psi maybe autop you do
some more work auto psi they
will not let me import the fai in the
case so I will not be able to try any more
work, not even carving  it will jump because
autoxy crashes it tells me no this
disk is not recognized ok I did not
expect it so I was expecting another
error just  well and then nothing
then I said let's try with
recoverable my software I started
it a compact do the analysis and
the bus and in the end it found 517
files about 240 megabytes of content
including all the photographs that are not yes
they see a lot however they are
viewable
they can be opened they are exactly
identical to what was the original content
then you can also export
csv files for example with all the files the
modification dates and the size of the files
the containing directory etc. and
therefore one can also  analyze the
creation access modification dates you
can export a file called body
file that is used by a tool
called time to make a pipe line of the
modification dates and then one sees in
what order the files have been modified and
this  it was done on a hard disk that
no longer had the beginning the partition at the
end is not even the system files of ntfs
all the parameters were taken
from  the traces found and it has been
rebuilt to the
directory structure that you can see in this
preview a little bit small and it is
exactly how I expected to
find it because I created the case
so I knew the head file
I knew which structure had to drink and  it
was found here
well this was more or less the whole
reconstruction process and I wanted to
tell you a couple of things that I had in mind
to do in the future as ideas that
could be developed from here to
improve recoverable for example one
could be add a '  graphical
interface because maybe someone may
also like to have the possibility to
select single files to recover
instead of all of them or common to
exclude deleted files or
recover only deleted files other
things that are much more practical to do
on a graphical interface
compared to a command line 21
maybe it inscribes some commands then it would be
interesting to add other modules
one thing that I did not mention and that
the structure is completely recoverable the
tree reconstruction
can be done independently of the file
systems there is that procedure that
he explained is very simple because it
works independently of the file
systems you just need to know a list of
files  that somehow I found this on the
disk the scan depends on the
type of file system but the
final concept here is a list of files this
list of files each file to its
parent I do the
tree reconstruction regardless of the file
systems so also to make a
gari system  in which I could not for some
reason and roads content can extract
however the tree structure and then you
can add them obviously
depends also on the type of file system you
can add specific modules in
which he passed the sectors one at a time and
how the module  ntfs does its own
math to figure out how to come up with
files for other file systems  your
module once implemented
could do the calculations and equally
another thing is that many of you will probably
know kane which is an
Italian distribution one of the two
Italian distributions of which deals
with forensics and developed by nanni
bassetti in the next release of kane
you can also find bit recovery inside
so among the many tools that are
inside you will also find this if you want to
try it anyway you can download it
freely because a free software and
then you can find it in practice I
basically explained everything if they
are a last thing to say
yesterday I was looking at  the slides I
asked myself but actually in addition to the
laptop or the desktop
what we often use and I thought for a
moment and I gave myself this answer here
that it is
an android tablet or an
android device they said it but it would be interesting to
try to make  work recoverable on
android actually works
perfect  by
modifying two lines of a file and
installing a simple python package
for android it was possible to execute
the exact same code on an
image file on the vote in the memory card
in my internal memory of the
device and do the whole process of
analysis reconstruction and extraction on
android  and then one explores the files
with the application he prefers so
I think it is the first tool that does
reconstruction in iraq and party running on
android I think it may be that I'm wrong
but I think it is so
here or I start thanks years