all the Monday morning warriors returns
today we are talking about the fact that
software programs hardware maybe
we have a little too much for what
we have to do
consider that whatever I say
about what you will see will
mainly concern the consumer market
so we are not talking  of
workstations we are talking about
what my mother uses to go on facebook
unfortunately for those who do not know them they are
work platforms I am a developer
in the web field or comparison founded
together am the mestre a club I
consider myself a supporter of
free software and I volunteer for  mozilla
how about on the mobile developer network that
a wiki for web development documentation we
start with this sexyssima photo by
william henry gates iii otherwise known
as bill who in 1981 said that 640k
should have been enough for everyone
obviously we are not so radical
we know that 640k al  nowadays they are not
even enough to start the
computer  I receive, however, this is except
conspiracy theories and anything else the computer
that brought man to the moon
that point you see on the
clock frequency on the cpu and a decimal point
is not a divider of thousands are
two mega hertz this computer was running
precisely  with this processor at 2 mega
hertz 4096 bytes of ram and 64k of rom
the program was you the program
that made the chicken fly was in 64
kb code total cost estimated
on the order of billions of dollars for
the record of tools for everything  the
program
for the realization of this computer let's
compare it now with the average computer
of a year ago which is this asus
f555 which as you can see a
processor three orders of magnitude
faster not to mention the fact that
multicore multithreaded multi all
ah sorry I'm  forgot the calculations
at six orders of magnitude plus 4 gb ram
against 4k and a 500 gigabyte hard disk
that the apollo program would have been
abundantly there we know  space would also be
advanced now let's talk about the web
because it is one of the things that has
brought the consumption of the cp
to somewhat embarrassing levels lately
this is the web
in 1991 about this is the first
web page ever created by tim berners lee or
at least rendered  public is only a copy
because the original lost
what is text is ing a minimum of
formatting and little else
this is pure text what is the web today the
web today is this this is the
page of the apple site  promotion of the
ipad apart from that we
can disagree on super computer first or for
the spelling second for in short
let's talk about ipad is a supercomputer
this page what is it is text
formatting and images especially
images
I would like to point out that the size  on
this page there are 3600 what you could
do in 1991 with three mega and 6 you could
do this two floppy there was one of the
best three-dimensional video games
in history something went wrong if
a  once
we could have something extremely
cool in two floppies and now
the ipad brochure doesn't even fit
then there are also other things that
we are a little too embarrassed to
talk about in the web so
java applets that were not bad in themselves but  oh well they
had been [ __ ] made activex
let's not talk about it flash fortunately
on the road to the grave what
happened what happened this happened
gmail not only did it happen gmail it
happened google maps
these are the first web applications of
a set of a certain thickness and  of a
certain popularity that they made use
of web technologies to show us
what it was possible to do in a browser
who's the fault of microsoft obviously who
's the fault of those who have merit it is
microsoft's merit to understand this technology
which is called xml http request that  for
those a little less experienced in
nomenclature it is what we normally
call ajax or a technology that
allows us to send xml to
asynchronous sync  in mind without having to reload
the page and being able to do it in the laboratories
results once it comes back then in
reality some very fi things have also been done
and on the web
this epic citadel for those who have
never seen it is one they have taken the real
engine which is an engine  to create
video games written in chip
I don't know anymore they compiled it in javascript
and ran it in a browser
this thing runs at 30 frames per second
in a browser which in my opinion is a
very cool thing but let's go back to the desktop
we see the evolution of microsoft office
in 2000 microsoft office and required
166 clock media on much more
likely single core 16 megabytes
of ram and 526 megabytes of disk space
for a complete installation of office
professional or fixed today to do
what you see that is  the cursor
that goes smooth instead of
jerking every time he typed a
letter requires a
processor sievert 2 gigabytes of ram and 3
gigabytes of space on it  sco to do
what to write documents in 2000 what
did write
documents something went wrong
we are perhaps writing too much code in the
sense that we are abstracting more and more
from the machine which in some ways a
good in the sense that it makes it easier to
develop from another point of view  view we
are taking for granted the performance
of our machines especially when
a programmer writes on a
workstation with controcazzi and the poor
user then has to run it on an
asus laptop with an atom core and 2gb of
ram scarce like me this guy who
says  read bad code but it rots and
requires periodic maintenance there
are bugs that must be found
this guy quiri crena is a guy who
wrote the first
apple ii virus in the 80s so in short there will be
few as ruining the lives of people
at  programmers i was thinking
maybe a core 2 duo
if we can get a processor i would like
to point out the date if it was  made here
maybe enough in the sense that we should
write programs light enough
to run smoothly on this first one
because it costs a little second because there are
a lot of incredibly
good machines I think I've also seen a lot of them
around here that still have this
kind of processors and  after 11 years they are
still used perfectly
functional now this obviously this
by pulling the question a little but how long
can we make an obsolete machine last
for example a friend how long
we can make a friend last
until June 2015
this computer installed in the
basement of  a school at one
point the school's heating system
stopped working they
went into the meanders to see what the [ __ ]
had happened and they found this
cicinho amiga 500 if I'm not mistaken
that controlled the whole
heating and cooling system in the
whole district  scholastic
I don't know if they have succeeded in satisfying the
progr  amma because if
the hardware broke that time I don't know if they
managed to replace the piece because
obviously it is a machine that went out
of production twenty years ago
ciccio martin here the author of game of
thrones in 2011  he claimed to
use a computer with
only wordperfect bumps installed to write
his own documents
that is to write his own books please
you think you were using imax
now let's see some positive examples
these too brought a bit to the extreme
this and but from the [ __ ] website that is
practically inspired let's say the first
web page ever created is only text only
html there is no css there is nothing and
now it is this thing weighs 5 k so
are our famous 640k and the gist
of the conversation between a [ __ ]
mother [ __ ] [ __ ] and the other is that in
reality the web should be content
not so much presentation I do not
completely agree and neither was
the guy who created this
page better but of the fac i web  site
that strangely even including some pieces
of css embedded in the page reaches 3
ke 69 here simply the guy
applied the css rules to line up
the text a little tighter
he changed the font color he
changed the font and little else
in short the  mother [ __ ] website a little
more readable another interesting thing
this ten that iap art competition that
ends in September so if you want to
win $ 10,000 in visa credit,
sign up now the challenge is to create
something useful on the web in less than 10
ke without using a library  javascript
and the judges could also look at
your your application with links
that has a command line browser
the goal is to create
an application that at the first load
does not exceed 10k then can go to get
stuff gradually depending on how
visual to you but you don't have to use
javascript libraries and then there is the
sackler project which aims to create an
ecosystem but userland to dis
linux tributions gnu linux not blue because
they replace the blue part for the
most part they have also created a
distribution called sta che
sta x static linux because they not only
say the code must be within a certain number
of lines because otherwise  it becomes a
brothel they also compile the
programs statically they do not use
dynamic libraries and another
interesting thing that I do not know if you have ever
heard of this little program
here dvd wm is a windows manager in which
the configuration is not done
with files but it is done  modifying the
sources in
ca very few dependencies occupies nothing is
very light it is great cool
if you like windows manager
styling precisely they have also created
this distribution they do a
conference at my tour around europe in
general and they are interesting maybe they are a
little extreme especially with
having to modify the source to
configure the programs, however,
I theoretically concluded with this one  I know if you have any questions I am
happy to actually have one
last thing
as you have seen I have not proposed
solutions in reality I wanted to open a
debate that we have even ten minutes
to do if we wanted to is yes in short I have no
solutions personally but I would
like to see that the writer  code was
limited a bit and remembered that not
everyone has their own xeon work station
with 32 gb of ram that's
all so questions you have to
start from the machine language of
course when it is started from the
machine language and you have to compile that is you have
to fit everything on a microprocessor  peak
then automatically without meat under
when someone told me but how not to
multitasking and multitasking then
learned to see what the 898 byte is
the last program I did well with
teramo is the pic at 60
16 that of the arduino well sorry sides
mega  sorry 32 or type you want to prove
with msp 430 that the coolest of all at
512 mbyte of ram
bye bye bye there is no question it
means  that I said a lot of
cool things you explain it well
it is not a question it is the
consideration that in my opinion for how
difficult things are going more and more
users more and more memory less and less
people who open sea well
everything right what you said
sin  that promises will not be applied
if I'm sure but let's start with us
maybe let's try talking about
paranoid people a friend of mine the other day
I was also saying to him he
threw a megagalactic [ __ ] on the fact that there
are what the multi core processor
what can they do  other whole forms
you are executing your code
and then he only uses 32
bit single core processors
we also write for him poor code he
will have the right to use a single core
I was wondering meanwhile introduce himself monza I
am livio rossa who works together with
class and  I see all day
that ass is pity I wanted to ask myself
whether or not to raise the question
of development tools because instrument  the
current ones tend to bring up
addictions as if it were raining we are
talking about grunt for example maven with
long pinks it is normal so much there are
libraries so much if I have to make a left pad
someone has already done it npm in store
ipad and these I could interesting
what you say left pad
tell us do you remember the story
of the fed was a library on js notes
that did an extremely stupid thing it
carried the strings a certain length by
adding spaces at
the beginning the thing that anyone can do by themselves
but in this ecosystem  of libraries that
do everything yes someone proposed as a
library as a module it was so
easy to install them use it that
many did for some reason the
guy withdrew it from repositories and thousands
of programs all over the world
all ran away at the same time
what I was wondering is that  current
modern tools can be used if you really want to reduce
the memory footprint and resources
of your
probabilm software  ente we should
start from that or not okay I
'm not saying that we all use turbo c plus
more thing but in the sense
we will probably have to start from those in
reality the question is this if I
write in I did write a
program that does a non-trivial thing
I can write it in c I can write it in
python too
bad that the one in python
will probably be orders of magnitude
slower and will need orders of
magnitude of more resources
so you have to balance
the development effort on
the one hand and the efficiency of the code on the other probably  if
we had the opportunity to write
development tools that allow me
to easily code
libraries or libraries in you
also know that maybe they hide the
complexities of c from me we begin to write
all compiled languages instead of
interpreted languages I don't know c '  is a
solution to be found there is probably
a solution of it seems silly that
thirty years ago you p  he could do it and now
it can't be done anymore I realized it was
much more complicated but [ __ ]
programmers collectively we can
find a solution together it
would be thread let's start
with the development tools he has a good idea
in my opinion there is the method it could
start already on October 1st just
one  tax on the size of the
program automatically try a
role to renzi who just charges
up the mega money and I can
assure you that the software will stay three k
in fact it will all end up in the
dynamic libraries and then programs will then be
small megons
I recently saw a video of  a
guy who tried to use an atari st
as a daily machine
apart from mp3 but obviously
most of the things
spreadsheets web mail you can do it very
calmly but you can
then probably also your
program in basic very fast elite  no that
's how long it took is I guess
other ideas oh well semi pecked around
you want to talk about it willingly
so thanks to everyone