addiction
we had the same story switching slights
year we had the same with the contact
information as we are like talkative we
want to get into contact with you
personally so we forgot to put their
contact information the first slow ready
actually we're like I hope it's
understandable actually were like three
ppl daniel is not able to be here today
because he's currently presenting it to
become in Asia my name is not feeling
among us
my colleague is going to do the second
talk as we're going two percent a
combined effort of our level or at least
a part of all day here today
yes what are we going to talk about
today
yes we're going to talk about a very
similar topics to one that we are just
seeing we're going to focus on user
friendly mobile security and we're going
to do it and an android framework where
you try to combine different
authentication mechanisms into one maybe
like i rly invisible and not observable
approach and the special thing about it
is we're going to focus on continuous
authentication at some point we're going
to focus on being cross device so
involved in multiple devices and we're
going to focus on risk awareness we're
going to talk about all of these in
detail later okay this short
introduction I think I don't need to
really introduced why security is
important mobile devices restore many
important details today and it is
troublesome produced those devices or
anybody else gets access to 84 unlucky
and the impact of security is something
that we just heard if security and
usability didn't work together and the
usability of two security that we need
is two too low
people are just not gonna use it so it
no security is of no use of course even
if the secret to be high and people
deactivate it so that all the time
basically with ppl txt winning bidder
locking mechanism for mobile devices we
see people just for convenience store
eating lots of possibly private data in
the cloud which if you have Tennessee in
your threat model is possibly the best
Urdu you may also select Disable
encryption mechanism simply because
people don't want to memorize different
passwords or the possibility of
memorizing very long passwords and
typing them very often so there is a
very huge need for easy to use mobile
device security in basically all
directions so what we are going to
contribute here as a research that
that's one of the lab studies organizing
to do when we are contributing
everything to display focusing on the
combination of usability and security as
far as we are able to afford it meant
poor terms and we're dealing with
authentication that's a topic we're
talking about now but we also dealing
about hardware security we are also
including books and see secure laments
we're also analyzing Melbourne at some
point sushi interested in any of these
topics in specific just a protests and
have a nice jet also like one of the
important topics that are organized
already mentioned to beginning the
digital 'tis something that's coming up
in the future that's all stuff to be
recovering in our lab yes especially
chart-topping authentication we are
pretty heavily focusing on biometrics
which everybody has it we have lots of
time and we can use them very
intelligent if we're lucky and sometimes
we focus on an unconventional approaches
that school because it possibly enables
new stuff and especially what we're
currently doing
that's not a stuffed it's important for
today is our new framework that we are
basically in the design phase now we
have its research in progress we already
have stuff but not if it is to come and
get started we want to talk about today
and we will be glad for input we call it
comment basically it's a framework
combines to risk awareness across T
weiss multi-device and the biometric
approaches into one framework goal is to
have different plugins every researcher
can easily that's the point
easily develop new approaches were you
have your own metrics are also like you
conventional security like peanut
password and included into the framework
so we want to reduce the effort under
one set of developing new things and
trying it out and you'll get any hits on
mobile devices and the second thing is
we want to combine all these security at
some point becomes rather transparent
for the user so that there is no real
deficit on on on on maybe having like a
fingerprint or having your pest but the
goal is also to have the framework
possibly just trigger you in case you
want to do banking and there is some
higher security required down the street
soon says you are authenticated already
but the confidence that it's really you
is a bit too low for banking so please
just provide something else and maybe
you can choose maybe you don't have the
possibility to choose it all depends on
the situation
understanding all these plugins
currently it's designed like if you have
a PIN or password
usually you get true or false decision
but with biometrics we can say it's
confidence that its you maybe sixty
percent 30% and combining these
different biometrics we can accumulate
that confidence
and it also makes it harder to detect
because mister break three such leaders
in the future instead of one only ok so
the caustic retreat after we had at the
beginning I think it's also pretty
well-known depending on the situation
you need different protests like if you
have two factor authentication to small
security not only having one fixture but
me being at very very very high security
things you need something more than two
factor authentication even and it all
depends on the situation soon it depends
basically on the situation which
includes the risk of somebody else
posing as you or somebody else trying to
get into the system and this is
basically were its things started an
interesting it depends on probability of
somebody trying to attack you
which could for example be expressed at
the time if you're at home and your
device is assumed to be next to you it's
improving then possibly in a texas emits
less probably if you're on the bus and
moving and possibly somebody just stole
your device combines location already
Mike sample the same issue with
strangers nearby mentioned you have face
authentication and Cameron detect other
people in the background then it's
possible not very safe to enter your
banking pin so that somebody could do
shoulder surfing and see your comp go
over the screen and just get your four
digit thinking the same as possible for
example with sweat off indication
if we hear other people talking we could
arise did you possibly in an environment
with different people standing right
next to you where for example speaking a
secret password or speaking your voice
at all for a voice recognition without
having a special freeze would be the
safest approach and of course the impact
in case you are you have your banking
application opened its maybe the impact
this big bigger if somebody steals to
the west with the open to bank
application down somebody just use the
device with which is currently doctor so
the impact also influences how we can
handle all these mechanisms that in in
one framework of course also possible to
have different devices if we think of
the cross he was approached maybe you
want advice more valuable than another
one because it s more excess to
sensitive data especially interesting
for people in important decisions if you
may be still devoted to the beginning it
might not be a problem but if you still
are currently still the mobile device
which is not locked the person could be
in huge trouble ok so hard we think we
should approach that we think about
having that confidence and that risk it
continues whether you over time and in
case like your think of Quito
vindication so you are authenticated
while walking you have to do is in the
pocket and you book in your gate is
recognized overtime if you work the
device is getting more and more
confident that it's really you know but
you may be able to just pull it off your
pocket and use it without entering any
PIN or password and if you put it out of
your pocket and put it on the desk that
authentication source is declining so
maybe at that point that story now it
that's maybe not exactly what I wanted
to show
but it's the same for the confidence it
just ghosts on the symbol to risk if we
like to detect multiple people and at
some point there are not multiple people
around you anymore that risk is just
going to decline and depending on these
measures we could you write for which
authentication is probably suitable for
the situation and we could also address
if it's sufficient the current level of
security and confidence or if you have
to input something else can I want to
like turned over to my colleague who is
going to explain in more detail
something about risk and of course
multi-device approach
working on this project
home so less as you must now you for
example you're sitting in the office
logged into your PC and suddenly you
realize that you should try to text
message to your friends for example then
you take on your mobile phone and start
typing you have to attend the case you
already know militant equation on mobile
device then you have to return ticket
actually so if we look this one in too
deep and basically already indicated on
Wednesday ways and knowledge but also to
continue on a device which is close by
so we don't know how many times we have
to do an indication again and again on
multiple devices and the thing is like
these multiple devices basically have
different contractors like smart watches
it's quite difficult to intervene again
and again on the basic idea is like
devices which are close proximity
measure user authentication results as
well as the list that we have already
mentioned in the previous lives each
other's this would significantly reduce
the number of extent is explicit
identification processes that are
necessary to perform the operations and
other daily tasks basically there are
some assumptions basically that user can
only be at one place at a time if he
successfully authenticated device
basically the user and device water
quality control over the devices within
arms reach and it also imposes some of
the challenges
that we will discuss bit later actually
so here is basically a big picture of
our family basically we have device one
device to we can have multiple devices
installed to conduct those devices we
have indication plugins we have this
plugins we have make decision making
models so still we have if we want to
share their trust are indications ted
between multiple devices then we have to
have some kind of action
argues that allows us basically route
shared the trust and confidence between
the devices so if we have only single
device then we don't need that extra
model but we have multiple devices then
we are going to need this exchange
models we are at the stage currently
scratching our heads all weekend
basically the very that we can see light
device within an arm's reach
belongs to the same learning to the same
person and chairperson between those
personal devices only this
implementation is from the developers
point of view basically we have an open
source implementation which is currently
work in progress and it's kind of pretty
extensible in terms of users can bring
in more against and developments of
course and risk tolerance and they can
extend the framework this kind of
pullback are you consider this land
security and researchers can use this
one for
research purposes and also support the
user studies basically we are also
inviting likely such as we use and
communicate until november is what a
developer research it has to do
basically to insert the plug into a
framework basically we have like I will
post information like just another
indication pluggin and then we have the
service which is basically the framework
service we give the permissions from
other application to read the
identification results and the next
level we consider this is basically what
we are extending the framework service
another application and we can publish
the results
confidence or risk whatever kind of
results we won't publish we can publish
it where this matter basically so this
is the only one that research animal has
to do to bring his application like
within the framework school so we have
like integration framework which sports
at the moment let multimodal approach
also we are extending it was across
devices and making it more risk of years
so that we apply security as far as the
requirement of the rest
basically and currently we have plugged
system
we have confidence calculation in future
we are going to words like ross device
at indications tuyen securing bomb
attacks with the template protection
because keeping those templates on
mobile devices does not make them secure
if someone get access to those template
it would be like 20 people to those are
in active development research is
already in progress
researchers oil industry partners are
welcome to join
basically and they can develop plug-ins
that's pretty much we have any questions
I have to question you say do you rely
on physical proximity but actually it is
open problem actually to identify with
the devices and proximity indeed or
maybe the signal is just too late so how
you deal with this problem and second
question did you do some measurements to
estimate the impact on battery life of
the device battery life still this work
is continuously in progress involving
yourself physically we don't have led
some version running on the mobile
devices we cannot say about the so it's
up there for the proof of concept and
the first question is difficult to save
devices within the close proximity
basically uses first has to allow the
trusted devices and then we have not
figured out how we can say like these
devices are unreachable very close to me
basically we want to basically find out
some very basically we can find the
distance between me and my devices
actually so these are still open
challenges
maybe like an extended for one sentence
I think as for some talks before ready
the goal is not to grab impenetrable
security and at that point because it's
just very very very difficult I think
it's may be easier to think of it as
combining many information sources to
make it harder for attackers to really
get through so if you like you measured
proximity to more information sources we
we measure and include too hard it's
going to be to really figure then so
even if it's possible to relate and
therefore this gonna be a bit tired but
at the moment we don't have like an
approach to completely disable attackers
from relief that's right I have a
question about the use case I'm coming
from the HCI aside and of course it's
not as if you have all your devices
every device has a corner of West
authenticate and so on but some devices
are not merely for one person for
example tabloids their lot of families
who are like to watch Netflix with the
family
iPad or next what do you do then do you
adjust
risk model to say ok this device doesn't
need a high risk threat model or did you
modify the user side that you say okay
these three people can can authenticate
with her voice how would you do that the
profiles basically to maintain a low
profile of every year that is using the
current device basically so we have to
switch between the profiles
just curious what were the results for
the gait analysis get indication we have
I should explain later results in two
different format basically is the same
day performance and across the
performance seemed to promise I mean
like when you train your model and then
you tested on the same day or within one
week later and the cost is basically
when you tested out after less than one
month or something like that so in the
same day we have performance around
three to four percent error rate
basically speaking in terms of equality
and includes day we had like 13 to 14
percent for a performance of the
christian identity is basically you can
see that the fall semester it becomes
more snow machines that is actually the
point that is both first met and fall
semester because if you're still trying
to figure out what the real reason for
the cross the river is it might be shoes
it might be different clothing so this
has not been controlled for it in the
current study people who did the cross
deterioration within 20 days in between
control issues
and we're not even talking about
handbags when the phone is not closed
today if if I might be extended for one
set the sentence again I think it's also
important if you have like a classifier
or a fearful of diplomatic source that
is just a bit better in random decision
framework and much very much
biometric sources you can possibly
combined in like in boosting are begging
approach to get something that is much
stronger than the individual components
so very very long run we possibly
include many of these sources and get
the pretty accurate result but it would
also be legal questions
then
thank you again