hello mr.
actually killed two factor
authentication I didn't do this by
myself some from vu university
supervised by her boss and most of this
park was done as a monster project by
pradesh so these are scratches to be
here and a little about me so system and
network security in the past I've been
working on and rubies here in Vienna and
as for a massive project i implemented
Traci Lords with some happen analysis
system and over the last year I've been
busy doing other stuff and one of the
results are paper at CES 2015 which is
about cfi so today my talk will be about
two things will be about two factor
authentication and then about how Google
killed it
so let's start here two-factor
authentication is form of multi-factor
education was waiting a long time ago
and its uses multiple components for
identification right so ideal you have
three of those something you know so
your username your password something
you possess bank card or smart card
reader and something you are fingerprint
or is it uses to authenticate yourself
right to make it harder for attackers to
hijack your account and this works
because the components are usually
separated right it's realizing the
separation of these components and for
an attacker to hide your account and we
really need to control all the separate
components that are you
they're meeting us an example i think
everybody should notice withdrawing
money from ATM right so you've got to
your to the ATM machine you put in your
barn cat
the bank card which is something you
possess the enter your PIN code which is
something you know and you get your
money right so we're doing this for web
applications is quite a hustle right so
you don't want every website episode on
smart card reader so it's quite
expensive to set up so we wouldn t be
great if we can use something for the
second factor that everybody has already
yes SMS that's the debt so how does it
work
use case that we are particularly
interested in its ebanking so happens
you're on the left side you are you want
to make a transaction so you communicate
with your back here either interrupts
banking first thing you do is you login
right use my pass work then you want to
transfer some money so that's why I want
to transfer one of the euros to account
number X so he said this request through
back to the bank will respond by sending
a attend a transsexual education number
to your mobile phone to SMS it says here
is called verification code xx 1 2 3 and
this will this one is valid to confirm
the transaction to transfer one that
euros to count number X right and then
last step is entering the skull in your
web browser underwear phase and you get
a transaction being executed
alright so the threat model of two
factor authentication and why do you
have this threat more ways that your
browser is compromised you have a man in
the browser so this is very common right
we have all the malware that still out
there dried X right now tire spy been in
the past
choose whatever and eubank let's get
stolen right but with two factor
authentication attacks are no longer
possible so attackers can initiate your
transaction but the
no longer confirm them so they can no
longer enter your bank account so what
did we see one once this was getting
deployed so we were starting to see new
with Jack variants on mobile banking so
one was instead of trying to set up new
transactions modified ongoing
transection show attacker would wait
until the user would initiate the
transaction but then instead of
transferring 10 silicon number X it will
change the request to say . transfer 102
my own account that was mitigated bags
pretty soon i think by including also
account information the transaction so
as message was received with actually
say this is valid to transfer money to
this particular account instead of so in
this case that the the victim would get
a message and you would you should see
that the target transaction number is
different than what he was a progressive
right so then the second thing we saw
was that attackers started to try to
control also over the second factor
right so people are going to use
smartphones so once the position control
lets span the user by sending an email
or SMS messages and social engineering
into social engineer him into installing
more on this phone and then once the
smaller was also installed then it would
be capable of forwarding incoming SMS
messages so the 10 course would be to be
intercepted and forward to the attack
and they came up with very nice name for
this rights sit more socially mobile 6
bit more and more whatever however this
is not straightforward
the current attacks that we see is that
a user must explicitly allow
installation right so you really must
click oh yes i'm going to install this
app right now on the phone and then
there's also google bouncer how I think
Nick didn't really discussed google
bouncer but his talk on Tuesday or
Wednesday was actually related so Google
bouncer is this awesome security feature
of android and the play store that
detects and remove malicious
applications and also between static and
dynamic analysis so the current mall
where is reliance on what we call site
loading which is this this option on
your android phone allow app
installation from unknown sources right
because that's the only way for them to
host their malicious apps somewhere
alright so how did google kill this
right
it all started with this this crazy
desire to integrate everything I would I
like to call and we're computing but
there are very different names that
people use so that is that just
synchronize everything synchronize your
browser your email your contacts with
your phone with your tablet with your pc
with your pc and your work phone right
because that's really the smart smart
phone through the smart thing to do
so how does Google implemented if you
have an Android phone you can manage it
from your browser so there I think their
features to locate it because you lost
it it was stolen you can wipe it to make
sure that no dangerous information gets
the but also you can install apps and
installing apps is really interesting
from our perspective because the
permissions that you need to approve
when installing the app they are shown
only in your browser not being shown
your phone
there's no phone interaction during the
installation of the map is artist look
this is this is my browser I'm locked in
that I'm a plate google come and I
opened angry birds app and i can pick my
device this access to so that's a
positive permission to use you can click
install and look at installing you're
sure this is safe
who says because you can only you can
only install apps from play and we have
bouncer right so balanced will protect
you
moreover apps when newly installed apps
they're inactive after installation
they're inactive and they cannot
out-of-the-blue do anything so a user
must explicitly at least once open the
app only then we can start on boot
only then we can receive SMS messages
and to anything interesting so in order
to elevate our men and browser to a man
in the mobile attack and to intercept
SMS system with do three things right
one is bypassed pounds or so we need to
find a way
new way to also hosts malicious content
in place then we need to figure out a
way to steer you into activating the app
and finally we can intercept SMS
messages to friends them and support
them out here that the app activation is
required only once
one two apps active phone go get
rebooted at will still remain active and
be able to interest himself so let's
start with the first . bypassing bouncer
this has been done in the past already
multiple times however google story is
yes bouncers ongoing process we keep on
improving it and we won't release any
details but that will just help funerals
but it's very hard to get your malicious
content in the in the Play Store so
let's assume that there's this is true
right let's assume that bouncer is like
this /
perfect this is perfect actually bouncer
that can pick out everything is
malicious why not upload the vulnerable
app instead right that's so let's take a
simple news app that connects to a
remote server to control and fetches
news items we control the app called we
control the server so if we make the
appt to some Native HTTP request then we
can craft a memory corruption so easy we
write the code so that is vulnerable to
move to park for overflow and whenever
it connects to our server we just
exploit the buffer buffer of flow and we
can actually two things that we want to
do without having the cold store in the
app on our way is to use web weapon that
few vulnerabilities you can find us in
google play this is this is what was
there my slide yesterday but I was
talking to make yesterday and because it
is not here and i was showing in the
demo and then yesterday evening we
suddenly got a message that RF was
banned and our developer account was
also suspended
so you can no longer find us in the
Google Play so this stuff that this this
has been done before right so that the
web for vulnerabilities are materials
and Martina hear from Vienna presented
this earlier but also having a
vulnerable app doing stuff right
is this be done before i do 6x5 works it
works I think we were there for 6-8
weeks least until I spoke to me
yesterday so second thing we need to do
is to activate the app right the apps
installed via the remote install feature
on the user's phone and then you need
only one user interaction idol user
clicks the app directly feed the app
icon or for you to install modification
or you can click on the custom you ride
my app opens of me right if you click on
this your browser
the app will also get activated so i
have an example of ours direct
activation works right on the left is my
phone and the right side is the is the
compromise browser and browsing to
google that an hour and right now the
extension so we implemented this is a
chrome extension it will it will start
running and we'll actually push the app
onto the phone so see it happening right
now so see they're this small icon at
the top that is actually downloading and
in installing the app so i made a bit of
a person stopped so I thought right now
I pull down the notification area and
it's actually our episodes thought so go
back to the home screen will show that
the after are now we have an icon that's
cheap backup which is not the same as me
or two but it's the same app it's our
app that just going to stop and also if
i go to the overview of install apps
will see their new surface and your
servers and delicate it's not the same
as mere two wasn't the same as backup
but it's the same app it's our app that
just got assault so i can open the g
surface and you'll see here that the
four stop button is not available which
means that right now tap is deactivated
alright so go back to my home screen to
open the notification area again and now
i will i will click on the mere to write
so we appreciate things a bit and what
will happen it will just press or
decided to close immediately and also to
remove the icon from the drawer so I
click it but it was very quickly see
something popping up and your back to
the home screen i will open the tower
again sir I open the app of you again
and you see now hear that . button is is
clickable so this means the app is now
active got back to the home screen and
touch are they will see here that the
g-pack of icon is gone right so only one
click app gets install and after that
only trace you can see is if you open it
in the app of you or if you go to play
story and look it up over here but you
want you to enjoy right so we think this
is it is hard to detect for user click
on the app it's open oh no now we're up
for whatever right but its active
weather we can do interesting some the
second way
2x10 app is using the custom your eyes
or and for this hour later we be abused
all this synchronization techniques that
we have now that right so think you can
do it you can send them we control the
browser so we can send an email to the
victim itself we could put replace links
in google documents sort of the food
actually
first open our app before doing anything
before redirected to the original target
we can post the URL to the facebook page
can replace recent apps grow but will
she always replacing bookmarks
alright so remember we control the
browser and we will replace the
bookmarks but make sure that the
functionality remains the same so
whenever the user will click on the
bookmark it and it will be redirected to
the original personal euro so we
redirect the bookmarked to link to our
control server and now depending on
whether or not to using the old or
slightly newer chromium app for the old
version the our control our webserver
real immediately trigger and intent
redirect that will open our app and then
our app will redirect to the to find a
bookmark or if you're new grown-up bad
to redirect after the user touches the
sweet then one once this is all in place
we can intercept messages right we have
control over the phone so we install an
SMS receiver and then for each incoming
SMS we store it we detect them or two
factors against it goes and with Alito's
only on peak at get though because it's
not no longer possible for for later and
revision we send the webview request to
our militia server we download an excuse
to come back to motel and then we have
control of the buying up over browser of
course already so we can login into our
banking environment
initial transaction and then received
the SMS and confirm the transaction
forty percent of the users soon on Pete
get so this means that for those users
they won't see anything happening our
users we all will see that encode that
they cannot explain in the SMS inbox
right so a live demo at least that
that's what I had planned we are
actually on good terms with the banks so
i wanted to show something else want to
break google authenticator because I had
a talk on Wednesday with Andrew and it
was saying yeah i'm i'm using google
authenticator right so it's not SMS so
that save I said yes but then I started
looking into it a bit more and actually
it's it's it's also SMS so we can break
this so like them over
I talked to nick of course our appt got
to dance so it won't be a live demo it
would just be a video so let's go there
and the first beginning is the same as i
said earlier i go to the google pays the
extensions get activated and it will
download the app
alright i will show that episode expert
i will now swipe away the notification
area notification i will show again that
there's a new icon and we show here that
the APIs is stopped
it's not active
ok so right now we go to the to bookmark
on my browser and the phone and I want
bookmark it's the wikipedia page of mr.
robot i click on it
alright and what will happen ' now so
what happens is instead of going to WIC
benefits i go to my own web server and
the web server i provide the web server
as a parameter the actual URL the
original URL of the bookmark and among
the latest version of chrome so my
server will do is will you all download
wikipedia page to show it to me so
she'll happening right now and since it
cannot directly redirecting intense to
our to our appt I had to inject some
JavaScript code that now whenever the
user to touch the screen it will
actually do the redirect so i will now
scroll and you will see a couple
flashing screens and then in the end
you'll see that we could be the pits of
mr. up coming up so scroll down they go
oh yes I'm wikipedia ok so i think i was
showing her again that yes the icon this
removed
and the app is active alright so we can
now install receive messages
ok so i'm back to my to my browser i'm
going to log out of google and I've set
up this two-factor authentication
thinking so I sign in again type in my
password and then i have to enter the
six digit code which is what you get
from the google authenticator app right
but there's also this this feature try
another way to sign in so that's click
on that and yes school
you can also send the text message to
your phone right and in my case the
google authenticator is running on the
same phone that also has this phone
number so if I just click that button
alright i will receive an incoming SMS
on my phone yes there is
and meanwhile my remote server higher
net cut listening for incoming
connections and I just got the incoming
connected from my mobile thought so from
here on it's just basic shelter can
execute commands while as as being the
app right
r ab I could go to our data directory
and so what's there
and then you will see here the SMS that
we received right so we'll just copy
paste the code come back to the browser
and login
alright so we think this is this issue
right i think users will be will be
possible for this user will be tricked
into into into getting this on the phone
so how should this be fixed we think
that Google should always require on
phone confirmation for app installs so
if you enjoy every browser make sure
that also on your phone you get these
messages saying hey you're going to
install this app on your phone are you
sure you want to continue it is or maybe
you're not so sure and want to leave it
here also this activation by clicking on
the on URLs is something to debate right
it really something that we want to have
or maybe two we kill that then this
remote install feature i will just
disabled I don't see any real
improvement that brings or at least make
it optional right so i can turn it off
and then also something that perhaps
it's some attention is looking at the
hiring tricks that we that we use to
hire app I think it's all features that
we exploit but it's really questionable
whether or not this is something that
you want to have as a feature but so
user the user because we've been in
contact with google for a while and
they're not sure where is really an
issue but the user until the fixes now
what's out for unknown app installs
right and perhaps even use a separate
account for any thought so that this
synchronization installing about apps
doesn't work and finally the google
authenticator user
set up a backup number 444 number that
is not on the same smart on the
smartphone on android phone right just
by old nokia and use that one as a
backup power
ok so that was that's that's that's how
we think that Google killed two factors
education right i think i have some time
right so let's also wanted to talk a
little bit about the reactions so that
I'm here some of the beginning so we
found this think play 2014
we tried to set up some stuff and we
first contacted google like me
acceptable just sent to email to
security intercom so we did that and
report our findings right and then a
couple days later with a response and
they were saying this attack is
medicated in two ways one there's
bouncer with your which will stop
everything malicious in place where at
to theirs at activation so we must admit
that at the time we didn't really know
about that activation right so we need
to look into that mean now we were also
involved in this
that's research project called mal pay
that involves all the three major touch
banks ABN amro bank and ing and two desk
at the demonstration there and the
letter ing these guys use sms-based
two-factor education to confirm your
transactions right and they were not
happy because the attack that we
demonstrate it does not require any user
interaction anymore after the apps
activated so that could take place in
the middle of the night usually wake up
and we'll see some 10 codes and SMS
inbox you would log into his bank
account and
it will be empty but then after having a
month later we got to the point where we
have written attack paper on this and we
send a copy of it to google and got a
response related marks and the ability
to launch an inactive app from the
browser feeling intent is not
intentional and we have opened an
internal back alright there's this thing
in the Netherlands is called ncsc it's
adults national cybersecurity Center and
they say that they're the central hop
and center of expertise for
cybersecurity and villains so we set
them also a copy of our of our paper and
responsibilities at school but it's not
within our research and development
policies so that later also at the ncc
cadets and Herbert gift demonstration
there the ncsu one conference and things
were not moving right there in store we
respond from google coming in and ncc
was not interested so we decided to go
public right so we were in contact with
folks ground which is one of the big
bucks newspapers and the published this
article it says big vulnerability in the
North thoughts right over on patreon the
considered a newspaper and very soon
this was copied by all all major or dots
new stations in the Netherlands and if
we went international because the
concept from paper and the Morgan there
are belgium newspaper so weird internet
already so then a little side story of
how this video works right so couple
days later after the the first Argonne
forest won't we
they published on another article
follow-up one slightly more details but
on purpose we released very few
specifics about the attack
right but no journalist or blogger these
days not no one cared to contact us and
ask hey what's up buddy doing I don't
understand this aspect of your attack
but i need two more details
instead we were being slaughtered by the
media right all this is nothing new this
be done already are your opening selling
his attack but just use a strong
password and you're safe and bouncer
yes bouncer real or law will help help
us and always make sure that no
malicious app will be in there in the
absolute right and then the rest is
computer world magazine with your
fingers
european or global and the deficiency
among countries there was this article
by this this reporter for the real world
and instead was a piece of postures blah
blah about big Android league and few vu
researchers and media raise fit so I had
to look about that means it's fear
uncertainty and doubt or in other words
we were guilty of fear-mongering right
this block it attracts 200,000 business
a month so we invited the author to have
a chapter because you get your office we
SAT there for three hours or so and then
two weeks later he revisited or post the
new article i was still might be
negative but in the end he did agree did
actually write this that google kill the
added value of mobile phone to factory
education also what we did is we set up
a web page with frequently asked
questions to address all the comments we
got from the experts what you can do and
that is actually really an issue that
two-factor authentication is actually
intended to to stop man in the browser
attacks right and after that fix fix a
little bit up to the end of love to lie
when we got a reply from google so
meanwhile he has been in contact with
couple of a google engineers and I
personally communicated that they agree
with our assessment but you reply we got
from the from the email
what's the following so this is copy
paste right there was a lot of
discussion about this but in the end we
decided that things are working as
intended and we have no played floor
plans change the behavior
moreover the email that they were saying
that they also look at our records and
we supposed to make misleading
statements right so three things not all
permissions are available so i think
somewhere on the pits at the air you can
do whatever you want but yes of course
you don't have this information right
and it doesn't kill all forms of mobile
phone to fa well I sort of disagree but
alright and the other at later android
versions SMS going to be deleted it
in addition they they concluded the
email saying that google has sufficient
or enter that sufficient security
barriers in place to stop this attack is
six points bringing up so one is first
11 victims bc your browser must be
compromised right yes but that's why we
have that's the threat model of to have
a right so this the resumption that that
the browser is is compromised second set
is attacker must upload the militia up
to play so yeah I'm saying here you can
still down there out but of course it
was it was bad yesterday but I'm pretty
confident that this is possible right
you cannot static and dynamic analysis
will not be enough to to detect every
malicious activity in a nap then the
victim must afford noticing that the
malicious app was uploaded to play so I
think he meant phone so this means that
the victim was not see our avenue apt i
will i'll just delete it ever will
answer as is shown if you have this app
is installed message which is the only
thing you see and if you click on it it
will actually help us to activate stuff
and the message the notification will be
gone
that will be very hard to find on your
phone so i think this is also not a
really strong . then for was the victim
must either manually activate the app or
click a link and activates the app so we
need some social engineering or of
course we can exploit the
synchronization usability features that
we have these days like getting
bookmarks or recent apps five was the
victim must be using an sms-based
two-factor authentication mechanism for
that bank and not a nap or hardware
token based mechanism writer so does
this mean that Google's saying sms-based
to face obsolete because it if it's true
then we should all call banks that are
still using is and tell them to switch
right right now not tomorrow right now
so it's right now don't worry about the
cost right needs to be done
moreover the fall back for those apps so
hardware tokens are are good thing right
but the focus for us apps is SMS right
google self is still using SMS as a way
to to deploy to evade for your account
so this this statement was I think it's
just plain wrong
and finally the the victim will still
immediately see that an sms-based n
comes in and he can contact the back
right so one thing is that for forty
percent of the uses this is not true and
additionally do you call your bank
if you receive a weird tan coat right
and to check for 10 coats between in the
morning and your mom or your sister so I
asked nick about this feels really cool
he was here but first the current
attempt to stop and I asked him to
comment on this writers have the slides
and the demos and i think is concerned
and I think that we will see some
changes or at least some reactions he
didn't have an official statement
because google doesn't do official
statements but i think i think we will
see some changes coming soon rights are
in conclusions we think this is serious
right we think is a serious but although
it's very hard to convince the experts
because you don't have you don't have a
buffer overflow to explain right it's
this is a design feature and it is
easier to show
oh yes you can do a rocket attack on
this very very cool modern software
yes that's about but this it's not
really about feature right we got mixed
reactions from google but we sure have
if their attention and I do hope that
things will get better soon we look at
iOS and Windows Phone they have similar
features to remotely install apps the
phone right but so far we didn't really
find API to read messages yet right
this may change in the future and there
is on easy easy fix that will work on
all versions of Android red just have
explicit activation when your phone
whenever you install app from your
browser for our I think that it is safe
to say that mobile phone to have a at
this based on SMS seems to be tuned
right and i also think that financial
institutions who come to the same
conclusion
and will over the next few years try to
phase out the use of mobile phone to
fame
finally the the one thing I learned from
is that the media's mostly clueless
so if you ever have something that you
want to share with media make sure that
you're very precise your statements make
sure you do your your various circuit
also try to be as is as real as precise
as possible don't don't send them large
videos are those presentations there
will only be interested for the first
part minutes after that we will continue
with your work
it's really hard to deal with the media
in this cases
alright so that's it
this is the link to our all the
four-hour rapids
yeah so thank you very attention
I thanks for the great talk
it seems that people are moving away
from using pcs and mobile devices are
becoming the standard endpoint devices
if someone solely using the mobile
device to perform their banking
transactions i would that change this
analysis so you mean that the rotten are
you have mobile app to do all the
different software taken all year right
I guess right in your case the rankings
being the U is being done on a personal
computer yes but if it's what if yes
what are going to move on is not scared
they're just using their phone so i
think one thing to notice is step that
all the people i think we'll still he
was the computer for quite some time
instead of moving through device but yes
I think one of my conclusions was that
while doing this work if you just use an
app only to do all the transactions it's
actually safer than using a browser and
the phone so its kinda contradiction but
i think it's true yes
ok so you sort of saying that bc is easy
to compromise and someone can take over
the web browser that I'm a phone it's
much more difficult to do that i'm not
sure
boxing I'm not sure that's really true
I think yes so with the sandboxing on
mobiles is really hard for one app to
access data from another app while the
pc if you have some point it's more easy
to get the root on pc and do everything
you want right inset everything so yes I
think that's think it's actually true
thanks
easy two factor authentication coming
back with the mobile phone being the uid
end . instead of being the second factor
sorry can you see with with that
assumption of the mobile phone being
this real endpoint of the transaction is
being started with what would you see as
the second factor coming back to that so
I think for I think for banks just to
seduce a smart card reader or whatever
right stuff something that's which is
only purpose to to deal with the second
factor and not something that's also
used for for internet browsing forever
in connection to the last question when
I want to make replace the to affect
authentication for services to the unit
using everyday life like my login to
Google at some pc what do you think
would be cool alternative student one
that we currently use in our mobile
devices alternatives for a google
authenticator you mean yes in everyday
life like not for the banking that I
need a karen explicit card for $MONEY i
think i think google authenticator and
also marks of Microsoft as your
authenticator is they're actually good
things but the problem is with the
backup option right so what if you don't
have your smartphone you can still send
an SMS message so that should probably
find a way to get that out of the way so
yes there should be a backup option but
make sure that this backup option is not
actually using SMS but a different
communication general or send it to a
non non mobile phone on mobile
smartphone
so part of the problem with two factors
education he was using SMS the channel
from browser to mobile phone so what do
you think about other channels between
browser and mobile phones have seen
example QR codes which is again with
your mobile phone camera which then
generate a code is something like that
safer or do you see where i'm not sure
exactly so I think Nick was also seeing
the same that the problem with SMS is
that it's it's like as shared data
protocol right so everybody can exit so
yes if you can find other communication
channels that narrow down the
availability then just think it's a a a
good good approach this and thanks again