right okay so before I begin I just want
to let everybody know that if you've
lost an iPhone
there has been an iPhone handed into
security so if you've misplaced your
iPhone just go to security I imagine
they'll expect you to be able to
describe perhaps the lock photo or
something like that but they have that
so I want to thank Albert a University
for giving us this venue additionally I
want to thank all of our sponsors for
you know providing us with the funding
to make all this possible I'd like to
thank all of our speakers you know for
putting on a bunch of amazing talks
today additionally I'd also like to
thank Cooper for recording all of these
talks but I'd also like to take a moment
to thank all of you as the attendees
this year we unbelievably sold out in
just a week and a half with absolutely
no information about the conference
released and we also had a 96%
attendance rate which is higher than
last year even though we had a storm
yesterday so it's amazing that you were
all able to make it up in time for the
conference I also want to take a moment
to say goodbye to the rest of the
committee all of these lovely people are
graduating this year hopefully and will
not will definitely not be wearing pink
shirts next year so I want to thank all
of you for the wonderful work that
you've done as well as the rest of the
fourth year
so before we finish up a few of our
sponsors have some prizes to hand out
I'm so I'd like to ask pentest to come
up I'm turned out there prize just
before I start couple of things
thanks for the bacon butties fantastic
the chicken curry excellent good coffee
probably one of the easiest events that
we've had the pleasure of coming to from
an organization point of view so I think
a lot of thanks go to the guys for
making it so easy and also thanks to I
think Jonathan D'Souza and Patrick Gregg
for writing the capsule flag challenge I
think that's right
so we ran a challenge at the pen test
stand and again thank you to all the
people that turned up to have a go we
would normally give the prize out to the
people who managed to break the
challenge capture the flag but Paul
Richie from the Glasgow office decided
that if you don't try you don't learn
and he's decided that what we should do
instead is to pick a winner randomly
from the 14 people that had a go at the
stand that doesn't mean to say they
actually captured the flag but they had
a go and I think Paul's right that you
don't learn without trying and I think
we should encourage that kind of
behavior most of the times at these
challenges the only people that have a
go were the ones that know they've got a
damn good chance of winning and I think
that we should applaud the people who
have a go knowing that they're probably
not going to win so we did do this
randomly there were 14 people had to go
like I say two people managed to capture
the flag online there were a lot of
people who did it and so just one last
thing before I finish we we're going to
continue the challenge online quite a
few people have captured the flag online
already but it will carry on and we'll
announce the solution first week in
April so you can have a go and you can
follow that at Penn test limited in the
Twitter account so and again some
unusual names are there in this industry
and
the winner is and gets right Callum
Garrett Lee Cullum Garrett Lee ride the
back
[Applause]
all right and I'd also like to invite
MWR up on to you know the front to hand
out their prize so I said well done the
everybody that came over tried our not a
lock-picking lock challenge I've got
back here the first person that got each
challengers name is in here to win this
lovely thing there are 12 names in here
much better odds
the winners Kalin again no like I'm not
even joking yeah like
it's actually Khalid right yeah can you
give us can you give us six numbers
please so I can put a lot on Leah we go
[Applause]
thank you very much and with all that
said and done we'd like to finally you
know thank you all for coming we hope
you had a great time we'll now go over
to bar one where we had lunch we will
have a hog roast put together by Patil
dub this year as well as a handful of
other things for folks who aren't
fortunate enough to eat pork
additionally I'd like to thank MWR for
sponsoring this year's bar tab so as
soon as you go over to bar one you can
take advantage of that yeah so please
make sure that you have your badges if
you don't have your badge the bar staff
will not be able to serve you but yeah
we hope you have a great evening and
hope you had a great time today
[Applause]