yeah hi I'm Jamie Hale and I'm here to
talk to you about my experiences deal
with the security of the internet things
are so on building the Internet of
Things rather than as a security
researcher or student you know trying to
tear holes in it I'm not a ghostly
apparition is the talk title might
suggest so if you're expecting something
supernatural I'm really quite sorry so
firstly it was a bit about me I'm a
software engineer I burn out my
consultancy called Karen baked and as
part of this I've worked on order on
demand systems and build entire
platforms for IOT vendors I also work on
mobile just six analytic setup that
requires a securely manage a lot of
debates data from an office advise
yourself some of the themes across over
the only really relevant thing I've done
security wise is chrome accent report
chrome bleed which with a Chrome
extension that check two sites were
vulnerable to the heart but your book it
somehow got an awful lot of press
coverage so for example according to
Business Insider I'm security researcher
spiral absolutely not
coin seal a common kind of modern
superhero and according to anyone who
actually knows me I'm massively
overrated so the last one call the most
accurate there but let's go into what
I'm going to cover today so I'm going to
cover a few basic things about security
Internet of Things and what we can learn
is it both as manufacturer and both as
people using it just a quick note or the
obviously IOT is a super broad spectrum
of devices my expertise lies in home
control so like white switch some plug
sockets so that's the frame of reference
I'll use ball touch you into a few other
bits and pieces as well we're gonna look
at some westerns learn from instance
both well-publicized ones and some like
war stories from my time in OT
saves just a bit of person experience in
there as well and the effects of vendors
like Apple and Amazon trying to get into
this market and then they've got some
time to put their friend the question so
please please use up side and so
seriously the set of things is pretty
difficult to sum up but it had to
condense it introduced a single like
emoji it's appalling I said that and I
work in IOT so we're not gonna make any
bones about it
security is a real issue for a lot of
Internet of Things firms but first
there's an interesting reason behind all
of this so let's examine the industry a
little bit in more detail so I liked
industry into tier 1 and tier 2 vendors
so those outliers on either side it's
not a perfect model but I think it like
it fits quite well so tier 1 vendors
these people you've probably heard of so
like Belkin Netgear that kind of
standard the main thing about these
vendors is that they own their own IP
they write the firmware they control
their cloud servers their own apps it's
all doing in-house and we'll talk about
that's why it's a really good thing
later tier 1 vendors also designed their
own hardware so their works their own
designs and they'll probably employee
industrial designers they'll probably
still use off-the-shelf chips though and
sometimes share PCBs with other
manufacturers there's a weird
expectation the people are Belk in on
their own factories and that isn't true
even a quill use Foxconn to make iPhones
with that said they'll have control over
production times and production runs
tier 2 vendors in comparison are
completely different a lot of products
like no name for no name vendors aren't
their designs they're cold anything
they'll have very what's been put into
hardware design as a rough figure
plastic injection molds for a custom
piece of cloth some piece of hardware
cost $20,000 each so it's far easier if
people just go ahead and use another
zone there's no cold audits company I
worked we didn't even have access their
own source code for their firmware or
server the firmware was just a binary
file that was handed to them by the
factory and let's be honest anything
could be running on that the server was
like a memory eating Java behemoth that
we ended up having to decompile and
recompile to make amends changes too and
the worrying about this that isn't a
one-off that's commonplace thankfully
the developers at that manufacturing
firm were good enough to leave all the
packages and obfuscated and the private
keys with no password required
so thanks books finally of course they
don't run their own factories but they
also don't control them either
production rooms are fairly often booked
weeks and months in advance which
becomes the issue for responsible
disclosure later on so all those things
seem pretty bad on their own right they
only tell me when he starts put them all
together that the real issue with the
industry becomes apparent so let's say
you found the critical security
vulnerability in the firmware of like a
tier 2 demonstration of them
when's that when you were passing a
security book what's the first thing one
of you would do it's fine like a
technical contact right so that the
company you can speak to and let them
know that something's not quite right
well unfortunately as we like touched
pinellia all software's done overseas
and there is no dedicates technical
contact the only choice is to speak to
sales and tell them they're suckers
broken that works super well so let's
say file you you get through sales from
likely and you've try and find someone
who can try and sort the problem they'll
need to go and speak to their
manufacturers engineering team who I
guarantee you from experience will deny
those an issue of this their system
it'll take two weeks three weeks more
the problem to even be acknowledged if
you're lucky they'll implement it in
their next firmware revisions was on the
next batch of devices has company gotten
over the outbreak function it cost money
so probably not and that pushes
responsible disclosure of your hard
fought book right out of the window if
you're on wiki they won't bother fixing
it because none of their exs end-of-life
none their customers care as long as
they're making mad dog so the only
solution there is just to drink
obviously so why does this happen well
it was that was something our people
already know IOT is a gold rush
developers our expensive upfront cost
but why sing someone else's design he's
generally just per unit so the capital
required startup internet-of-things firm
is far lower using other people's code
than doing it the correct way even we do
it the right way
security isn't a priority security is
treated a similar way to IT attrition
organizations it doesn't make the
companion money so why should the vendor
pay extra for it it's not gonna cost she
so it gets ignored the final reason that
security of Internet of Things firms is
so terrible is because no one assumes
they're a target
I've had people telling before that
there's Sony or bigger other companies
to choose from so wild an attacker pick
that that's completely for logic as all
of us here will know and when every
manufacturer then also thinks always
someone else to choose there's a serious
problem
behind the scenes now we've heard that X
year is Linux of the year when it's on
the desktop but really 2017 zero in
something the winners full stop because
briefing rooms on the winix and Betty
colonel everything which is great
because it makes my job easier
unfortunately he also makes my job
easier so Christine Collins he's far far
easier than it used to be it's now
trivially simple to start up your own
internet of things start up and start
selling products and I would say
probably dangerously so there's no
single equation or standard the Internet
of Things so it's difficult to know
who's doing it properly but this is
something I'll talk about a bit later in
more detail so I was going to jump into
a case we now for just full disclosure
some details have been changed to
protect the guilty I'll jump in so yeah
it's autumn I'm walking through London
I'm on holiday and I get a panicked call
from one of my clients there's been in
disputes over the cut of quality
products that they received and the
manufacturers fresh seems cook pull all
of their cloud services or until payment
for the number working devices is
received at the time that cloud service
was split between two main providers one
for their newer devices and one for
their all the devices our previous
project with that firm was to migrate
their new devices onto a bespoke
platform because they'd realize they're
having so much of their operational
dependency on a third party was a pretty
bad idea if migration was thankfully
COMPETES completes a few days prior to
incidents but the old folks we haven't
started working at those yet the whole
day part of the businesses hold a buret
we ends and we do as best we can
we take backups the service day we
change passwords we clean up bits and
pieces of course none of this
particularly helps when the
manufacturing firm is that door they're
on server so it's dead the backups are
useless because every restore just
reactivates the back door five thousand
units and our flying not even
controllable from their own Wi-Fi
network because everything goes through
the cloud what the hell do we do now so
step one is we look for data regress
we find that they didn't manage to think
off the database they're just holding
the clients ransom over the actual
server and that's operational capability
RAL from the data run it step two is
look at the source code oh wait sorry
yeah no there isn't any source code the
manufacturer has said that they didn't
need to have it and they were never
going to get hacked see earlier slide so
why would they have it we get a shipment
of about 20 of the older devices
around the dock from around the office
they don't sell the devices anymore and
all they have left our faulty returns so
we don't know if it isn't working
because we're doing it wrong or because
the devices don't actually work they
don't set so there's two models of
devices that they'll that use the older
server that we're not too fine
model a which is about 75% of the
install base a model beam which is about
25% of the install base so it's time to
fire the reverse engineering ion come
great so armed wave these slightly
faulty test devices and some information
with crack one open and we noticed that
model a has a similar chip to their
newer devices which we just released and
improved back-end for using their
existing protocols we looked in the iOS
app source code for the new device and
realized as a conditional in there and
it stops devices would start from we
were certain four characters of the MAC
address from using that app now to me
that would indicate there was a
marketing limitation rather than a
technical limitation and that the actual
underlying protocols behind those two
devices were pretty much the same so the
first one we tried to do is try to
unboard these devices to our new server
that we control using those protocols
and incredibly yeah it works or
correction about 75% the 75% that we're
running on model a worked model B
doesn't so we get a brought either way
we get our iOS developer to expedite
some updates to the iOS app and that
goes wide the next day and so the
support requests are quite receiving
starts down a bit so model B then is our
issue we have no cross code
documentation ZnO source code nothing we
holster local DNS service so it thinks
the pub thinks that it's pointing to the
clients server and we start trying to
unboard the V devices to a local machine
with a white shark intercept
intercepting all ye to be traffic
thankfully they didn't bother trying to
obfuscate or encrypt any of the
onboarding prosto otherwise I probably
wouldn't be here speaking to you now the
protocol works similar but not identical
to that of model a and the newer devices
the only real difference was the
checksum the checksum was completely
different to the first set of devices so
we figured the okay this manufac
who uses used or a white label product
to start with so I'm assuming here that
their actual month a manufacturer
overseas has been a bit lazy and reuse
that code somewhere so we went to a
triangle around and find a few apps that
look similar to our clients so we'd have
a actual server on board we there an app
- on board we've to compare the traffic
and yeah we we found that you know saw
the assets the same the UI is slightly
different but the names the iconography
it's all the same so we decompiled the
android apk but yes those are both
Android apps despite walking very much
like iOS apps both the android apk to
find which server
it was onboarding to and thankfully it
was still running to request which is
great so we now have the server that
devices on board with as I said before
onboarding wasn't encrypted so we could
compare the old service response to how
our new in-house server was responding
the good news was that as we expected
the only thing incorrect was the last
four bytes that is the checksum so the
rest of the protocol we had worked out
pretty much all right at that point we
had like one real choice which to try
and reverse engineer there and checksum
algorithm so we can implemented
ourselves and I I wasn't previous to
this but somehow my colleague - - that
ends two hours and he wouldn't let me
talk about this unless that boy went in
there so I'm sorry
we perform a few checks to make sure
that the devices are on board
incorrectly than they do so we bring our
clients to tell them the good news our
client sends out some marketing letters
letting customers know that we'd
upgraded their experience by giving them
access the new features that they all
that didn't have the customers well
their new feature access and there was a
federal rate of return which is
remarkable for a story of essentially
intrusion fourth modernization at the
good news for this company is that all
their new devices are now controlled by
oles end-to-end from cloud services to
firm one it was a lesson that was a
tough one for them to learn but their
customers now we think better off for it
so what can we learn from that lesson
the first thing and that again this will
seem obvious to all those in the room is
to make sure that you own or at least
have a copy of your source code if you
don't have thought that source code and
something bad happens like a supplier
their dispute
you're abridgement screwed and what you
have a big old slice of walk in this
instance we had two and they were both
down to manufacturing business our first
vice allot was that they reused the
chipset and the second one that they
reused the entire app and perhaps
protocol and more importantly were
obvious about it the second is that
attackers won't always come from where
you think they will the protocol but
that power bills bugs was actually
pretty well desert and the qual control
server was reasonable well designed to
avoid standard things like injection
attacks however the only thing the
company accounted for was for external
watches and they didn't consider that
someone inside the company or one of
their suppliers would be a source of a
problem and the first thing is that you
should have layers of redundancy always
I'm talking about in terms of cloud
service so I have backup servers and
also in control so what I mean by
control redundancy is the ability for
your users to be able to control a
device that you manufacture regardless
of anything else your user should be
able to control the device from your
local network it could be in the middle
of thermonuclear war and which is
traumas president probably doesn't seem
that in my opinon event to plan for and
the device should be controllable if it
has power my client counts it'll switch
on the side that you can use to turn off
as well control and I quite frankly do
not have the next level work from this
is called control this is the bit that
most people buy devices for this should
work but the real question is for what
length of time I would save five years
the minimum and as much as reasonably
possible after that there's no good
reason why you can't port all devices to
use your new technologies that but not
enough has changed in the past decade to
make existing device obsolete when you
buy an IOT device I believe and the
hardware there's no guarantee that
servers will be still running in five
years time or even if we come to exist
in five years time the final thing here
is vendor integration now this is the
tip of my period this is this is the
thing that I think matters the least in
terms of control redundancy if you're if
this and that integration goes down then
your users can still use your
application by open control file control
but the problem is that unlike different
control methods the vendor integration
is the one that the marketing uses the
one that makes the most money for IOT
firms so I've seen issues where we've
had to
you security I've been asked to reduce
the security about portable control to
make sure that if this and that works
properly because that's the bit that
they sell plugs on that's little devices
on and that's the bit that makes them
the money so that's the bit they focus
on the most
it's my jobs trying to tell max in the
case so yeah there we go
Google however disagrees about that as
you may be aware they acquired a company
called revolve in 2014 and immediately
they stopped selling devices two years
later they shut down the Oracle cloud
services and the render the app and hold
the useless didn't have a base part of
that pyramid
so that permit their will control that
wasn't possible we revolve so what
happens when the IOT firm that you've
relied on for all of your smart home get
shut down how will you use the devices
that you spend hundreds of pounds
integrating into your life so yeah so
yeah so the first thing when I'm buying
devices make sure that I have the means
to control it locally be it manually or
via a platform my home kit but again
we'll touch on that later and I think
yeah I've already touched on better
integration on this slide so the final
thing to learn here is that search
develop software developers are not
security experts we may claim to be we
may even be told we are by the press we
may even come to a security conference
and give a presentation on security but
we don't know what we're doing unless
your code has been audited and pence
acid by an actual security researcher at
one of you I wouldn't trust it I've seen
it go very badly wrong very quickly even
for huge projects like open SSL oh it
takes you someone not validating a
paywall don't parameter properly for the
internet to go mental okay so that's
something happened to me and what we
learn from it next in true Monty Python
style it's time for something completely
different
let's look at Mirai which off naming
conventions alone deserves be on this
list and what we can win from that suit
I'm guessing a fair few in the room of
her I've heard Mirai right for those who
haven't it's an alt botnet that took
over devices we'll go into the
nitty-gritty of quite how later perform
a record-breaking DDoS attack like it
pumped 616 emits second credit on
security and 1.1 terabits second at OVH
the French housing provider
whilst it was known that these attacks
were happening because service providers
had to deal with the matter oh it wasn't
publicly detected until the source code
leaked on a hat forums so yeah hijack
the using patient devices not book were
detected and it mainly infected things
like CCTV and IP cameras but also things
like DVRs and Reuters as an aside during
the research for this segment of the
talk I came across someone who'd avoided
the whole source code to get home with
this warning the sit valve the repo is
identified as because by some at AV
programs as malware please take caution
I mean that would be because it is
literally malware like bump gel or
briefer go over how Mirai works because
I'm again I'm guessing a lot of you in
the room know this but then also examine
the response to Mirai and the reasons
why I think pans out things panned out
the way they did based off being in the
industry at the time so the first thing
where I dated was continuously scan the
whole the internet for mobile devices
once they identify the vulnerable device
it attempted to brute-force SSH access
and advice by cycling through
61 different test credentials the
important thing about these is that they
were all factory already onto the
devices as we know most consumers
straight-up don't change passwords
unless they're actually talked to once
you attack a shell access it was shrivel
for it to execute a shell script down on
the payload and listened to any request
from command and control service before
the source code was released on hack
forums the original Mirai botnet had
three hundred thirty-two thousand
devices under its control since then
been you that used the same base source
code to the base same base CNC method
but with the attack vector modified to
target actual software memory abilities
one example of this was a Doge telecom
who had nine hundred thousand Reuters
attacks because they were running a
protocol TR called TR 0 64 which allows
remote access functionality and that
server that behind ROM access
functionality accepted command without
any authentication and was open to
internet on a port which was super smart
so yeah the final thing about this is
that it was such a low cost attack the
actual freedom of 30,000 device botnet
we're on 2 P VP SES and two badass or
service and made the null for some money
so I hope the target you're probably
thinking that attacks of this size are
probably at government institutions at
major sites that kind of fill and it has
to be hundred percent wrong this is who
they targeted minecraft servers for a
nice piece of continuity in this talk
the game serving question is actually
one of my clients so are both defending
out to issues in similar teams recording
now two issues at the same time the list
of devices tiles it can be found from
the default credentials that they use so
this is a list of them here how many
people have you bicker secured at home
and forgot to change the default SSH
credentials I'll freely admit
congratulations firstly about the
problem and will admit I'm part the
problem because that's at first that's a
very dangerous admission to make at
security conference and secondly yes I
did accidentally help DDoS my own client
no comment and I'm receiving mail for
questions so yeah from the password
voice on the previous page as I said
it's easy to figure out which devices
were most badly affected one specific
brand of camera XM was badly affected
with thousands of other cameras from
like Samsung and Bebo tech
say as I said earlier you because your
networking gear with default credentials
attacks as by default a camera mode
remotely variants of the Ishimura
attacks tags the separate vulnerability
with remote access as I mentioned the CR
zero six four four ability and that
attacks things like talk talk cake armed
which telecom and post office because
the post office offer broadband now or
and they all have their kick compromise
this goes back to the manufacturing
process that I described earlier there
has similar firmware and chipsets be
whole hit with the same from ability
what's personally brewing for me about
this isn't the DDoS that was bad but
recoverable but what truly malicious
person could have done with this level
of access if you can write script files
filesystem odds are that you can
retrieve data off the file system to and
ideal world you won't be able to but
both I've sufficiently demonstrated how
terrible IOT phone worries at this point
they factors two cameras example some of
which will store a history of video
recordings attackers had a window into
people's homes rather than the DDoS
attack the people can recover couple
from that could have ruined people's
reputations permanently it was targeted
so device is compromised by this attack
but I okay so love the world this is
just a single snapshot from encapture
showing the scale of the Mirai breach
the insulated nature of our supply chain
and Internet means that in the modern
era breaches like this spread fast
the worldwide scale who what Mirai
botnet is in the second stream
traditional heuristics who were use to
mitigate dears attacks are far less
effective when it's coming from
residential IPs from every single
country on earth have happened bring one
person reading but yeah so there was
only really three main ways that IOT
firms could've tried to mitigate the
threat and right and I wish them best of
worst here the best way the IOT firms
could have tried to mitigate the attack
was truly to software update to force
users to change their passwords however
for a second let's just flip back to the
wires this happens for a second there's
no strong business case release no blue
most customers won't even be aware that
their devices are being used as a botnet
and all that releasing software update
does is say to your customers oh hey
yeah we did something wrong you need to
change the passwords now they tell when
something's going on second fingers
you're introducing user friction so when
the user is next in the market to buy a
new rooster or CCTV camera they will
just remember the time they had to
change their passwords because in their
eyes you've got hacked it's only key
players like Deutsche Telekom who really
suffer updates that kit and that some
non user obvious wakes it was fixing a
vulnerability rather than a credentials
issue so the second way that
manufacturers could deal with Mirai is
to do recalls for a business perspective
this is a worst case scenario it costs
money with money for packaging and cost
money to create a fix it costs more you
ship it back the main reason you'd ever
need to issue a recall will be because
you haven't built in any over-the-air
functionality because as we said earlier
OTA costs money however I would argue it
would have cost XM far less money to
build in a noche functionality two years
ago then it would have been to recall
10,000 cameras update their firmware and
ship them all by how again
the final thing companies can do and
this is the cop our response is just
tell users to change their passwords
alternatively they can completely
absolve themselves many responsibilities
to mitigate this risk because page 243
of the instruction manual sells users to
change passwords as we said earlier
users don't change passwords and as well
as this MRI uncovered a whole host of
systemic failings about how we as the
industry write and maintain software
first of all default credentials it's
far easier in West effort for also as
manufacturing as manufacturers and
vendors if every device shares a default
username password and I view this the
mute point though if bTW of all people
can stick some stickers on their home
hubs with randomized usernames or
passwords your manufacturing process can
do it too the second systematic failing
here is a lack of user update
functionality in an awful lot of devices
be it over the internet or manual world
from a local network
this means that bugs simply don't get
wrapped retro actively fixed if your
walkie your reported rumor ability may
get a fixed in the next batch if you can
give the manufacturer give it up if you
have over-the-air functionality in your
software it means you can fix this
issues for existing devices and nip some
problems in the book this has made even
easier yeah
sorry this has made even easier if you
actually have access to your own
developers and your own source code
which we also said earlier isn't that
common the final thing is it showed how
slow some companies respond to new
zamurai it's disappointing as a consumer
to see firms care so it's all about
their own products but as I said earlier
LT is a gold rush this is expecting
behavior all this brings rounds one more
person point where traditional systems
like a desktop machine or a laptop it's
very easy to see what's running on the
device everyone in this room knows their
way around an operating system and it's
fairly obvious when something isn't
right you'll notice it back when
processes are an unusually high network
world this changes for Internet of
Things devices more often than not
they're black box systems so you have no
way of knowing what codes running on
there the vast majority are open source
and even if they were getting software
are guessing the firmware off the device
to compare against an open source build
is pretty difficult so how do we know
that our devices are being used as pile
of botnet we don't it could be done via
an exploit and you don't know or it'll
even be pre-installed the factory
antivirus royalty does not exist despite
what Selfoss may claim and they may try
and sell your for any critter even worse
than this is as precious little Hardware
integrity verification as well
when you buy an Intel chip you know that
it's probably not going to anything
malicious how do you know what forming
inside your device without cracking it
open and voiding the warranty so does
anyone know what chipset feel like few
roms on for example know exactly they
don't even know the manufacturer
yeah point is that users don't know what
hardware and software their lights and
home security are being controlled by
and there's no set standard for even a
real way to verify devices legitimate
that's very terrifying so this leads
onto another obvious question so we at
the moment we can't verify the Internet
of Things but how do we start - there's
no single standardization body sure
there's things like the Wi-Fi are
allowing us to make sure that devices
conform to Wi-Fi standards for a hefty
fee but nothing for IOT as a whole
quite simply there's no guarantee that
the device you buy today will work
tomorrow Apple Amazon if this and that
I've tried pushing their own standards
and people's trying to get on that game
as well we'll go over what Apple and
Amazon programs actually certify in a
second but for the Contin the concept of
any one of those gaining market
superiority is care of troubling because
competition quality will decrease as a
result of one single platform wins you
would think that as manufacturers we
would have code signings always verify
that updates come from us but I've seen
too many over-the-air updates not
implementing this checking to believe
that this is commonplace again it goes
back to what it said very beginning
security isn't on the cost sheet so
there's no attention placed to it so
yeah nowadays IOT is everywhere all the
major players are involved the industry
Google or Amazon are and so of the
fruity cold but at this point I've
signed so much paperwork for them and
don't even can say that name anymore
this is a really interesting fact in the
industry because there's a lot of
competing standards that's every
internet-of-things vendor is rushing for
compliance with and it's interesting to
look at what the security implications
of that are so soon as I mentioned
standards this probably was the person
that pops into your of yet so this SK
CDs fairly representative what's going
on right now but I've chosen just to
focus on home care and I was an elector
because that gives us two contrasting
opinions so homekit is probably the most
interesting vendor sanitization push
sadly it's one I can't go into juicy
detail over because they have a sniper
just there but I just got to go other
things that are in the public domain and
I promise these are in the public domain
if they're any Apple warrants they have
a home cat approval program that is well
and away the most for and expensive
appellation you can get right now it's
due to the sheer amount of testing they
do and compliance
documents that you've got to fill in
before we even get a chance of guessing
get brought into a store they also kind
of access to filter so because only
people who are in the industry for the
long game are going to pay Apple
a five six figures some strangle down
the homekit path Home Care is
interesting one as we interfaces
directly with devices Robin bio called
server x-force is ble as well as IP so
even at Wi-Fi as control makers and the
interesting thing about homekit is the
designers behind it as from the best
I've seen working in the industry
it forces security by design which is
kind of rare in my ot so how does like
home can use ble or IP control it uses
your Apple ID to generate public and
private key pairs that then become your
home kit identity so these keys are
sodding key chain for sync between
devices and only things in key chains
are actually encrypted all control
requests so turn your lights on carry
out locally and bio communications
protocol of Apple's own design it's up
towards its manufactured Superman that
so for example if our cloud servers go
down forevermore your devices will still
be controllable via home care as long as
the concept of an Apple ID exists in
some remote fall it switches the burden
book time from the manufacturer to Apple
which is something that many companies
find instructive to the point where home
kit only devices are started be released
as an aside this is why you need an iPad
or an Apple TV in your house to control
devices buy a home kit remotely because
they ask to the bridge on the network
and thanks to keychain they have a copy
of your public and private key so they
can successfully open together this one
got skis anyway sorry
another thing that mandates out the box
carrying kills the most randomized and
mostly branded a certain way so apples
section of branding and the generation
chess of Kohl's is longer than some
technical device specifications that
I've seen for entire devices the pairing
code is what binds your device your
Apple ID so it stops on network attacks
from taking over your device a piece of
Spira on your Mac for example can't
pulse or scan your network for new
devices and then try setting you'll be
using your factory default filter all
that really means that Mariah attack
isn't capable over home cat alone as
least as far as I can tell devices are
not accessible remotely apart from a
bridge and you'd have to break the IDI
two two two five five one nine
certificate standard to control them
without an Apple account and you can't
mine in the mill setup process because
each setup code has to be random of
course every specification in the world
doesn't mean anything if it's not
checked apples actually reduce their
requirements in recent times but they
still were in a full suite of tests on
production ready UNIX before they give
you the green light to even produce the
things again this force is kind of
security by design which is a huge thing
in our industry and that's out of this
is that you kind of have to hire people
who know what they're doing would home
kit and what Noel's doing with security
so that will generally mean that other
things are done correctly as well
but not always the other key player is
versatile exit so this has far less
restrictions and homekit and the cost of
entry is far lower it only cost about a
thousand pounds per base to summit
certification and that certification
will ask you for the lifespan of the
best the important thing here is that
devices still go per or British testing
this testing however isn't do security
it's just simply making sure that you
call the right things to watch work
Alexa they'll ensure basic things like
you know that you carrying traffic HTTP
for example and yes I have seen that not
happen but it's mainly Amazon century
the interesting thing they do that
Cottle's out is a two-way feedback
required that is they expect you that
your app should have a socket connection
or a similar kind of operation to ensure
the application status is instantly
updated so this is a functionality that
a current client firm a wife book had
but I featured that we decide to upgrade
around the time of their NAC testing so
Sal's wall dictates that it stopped
working during the two minutes they were
testing for and that was a long weekend
so I'm gonna round off this talk by
saying what I look for in IOT devices
and how you can tell companies at least
trying to approach IOT from the right
angle doing the Audi the right way is
actually really difficult contrary to
popular belief so yeah we they say we're
currently working with a firm called
Wi-Fi book and we have been doing them
since August I'd like to stay here the
company in case anyone is not liable I
need to keep Maxie and I always somewhat
side now I have a holiday hopefully
nowadays they're a decent example of
this so I'm going to work through some
things that we've identified working
with them and how we try to mitigate
so given the focus on alt
vulnerabilities right now there are so
many different attack vectors that we
need to be aware of the manufacturers
the main problem is that we need to
worry about every single part of the
stack we're out from the traditional
software startup which may have a single
application attack surface attack
service for now two device goals from
the actual hardware and firmware they're
cloud offering as well it's rare that's
one small T firm will have the expertise
in Hardware firmware and cloud services
necessary to fully secure a system so
what we've done we've brought in
consultants for parts that we are really
sure another thing to consider is how do
we handle personally identifying
information a lot of IOT firms don't
consider their data as PII
because in the days just log source or
switch port for example but the issue is
that what the kind of data we have is
gold mine is a gold mine for even a
petty thief we know when people who
turned their devices on enough we know
when they have timers set for and even
what they're currently engine usage if
someone got access to our data they
could work out some was at home or not
this is a huge responsibility for us and
we need to treat it with great caution
and stored a securely improperly this
also involves deciding how long we need
to store data for the elects invoice
case currently going on in the US is a
prime example of this so if those you
know where Amazon had been subpoenaed
for voice recordings made soon as you
have an elector from a couple of years
ago they've kept them for training data
and now the US government wants to use
them in a murder case
so while strain data is useful there
comes a point where customer security
and privacy needs to come ahead of
training your own that's why was
capabilities so what do I look for what
I'm bangle smugglers the first thing I
check for is if it has some kind of
external accreditation for small firms I
look for either Wi-Fi Alliance rotation
and Orbitz a licensed home key products
not because that means they're secure
but that Boo means that the amount of
money they've spent onto those two
programs means they're probably in it
for the long haul gravel tries to make a
quit book I think that's one of those
two things that isn't necessarily bad
just do a bit more research for bankers
the next thing on my list is either
device has over-the-air update
functionality it's difficult to tell if
manufacturers use signed firmware about
gathering the banner for yourself but
having LJ present and documented means
security vulnerabilities can muster what
can be fixed without retooling you're
being pushed out and come
pushed out some existing devices the
third thing for small Cubs at least is a
wasted technical point of contact having
someone listed whose contact scible
about security issues technical issues
means as a strong possibility they
actually write their own code
this means the book speaks use them all
has to happen and in combination with
all their updates this can only be a
good thing
the final thing on my list is some kind
of evidence of local control capability
this is optional because it's rare that
this feature will be documents anyway
have a scooch around online and see if
anyone's tried to get into the book my
rule of thumb small firms to just assume
the cloud servers will go offline it in
any moment because again I've seen it
happen there's no break so it's super
easy for me to say what you should work
for so how did I how difficult is that
waste to implement for manufacturers so
as we've just finished building smart
plug I'm quite well place to answer this
so we've been working on a port call the
wife book home which is home key
compatible it's a smart book it's quite
wild that it's gonna be the only home
kit smart book in the market that takes
my single book socket as listening the
site so what we found during this
process it was a blend of trade balance
what marketing wants and what the
security comes to Seoul inside of me
wants there's some things that would
have been awesome to do include from a
person perspective so one set up that
isn't simply possible to do without
ferryman the middle the project started
in December 2015 but we were brought
aboard him like autist so this meant
that we couldn't choose things like
chipsets or PCBs and there's a limited
selection of homekit compatible chipset
anyway so that isn't really that much of
an issue at least what that means now is
that we own every section of the stack
so we have the cave builds Pasha
sort of suffer updates the same day as
immoral to being disclosed if we can fix
it in fact the next thing is to think
about the security implications of every
single decision at one point we're going
to implement a trigger style some system
similar to what if this and that the
problem is that they'd be a huge issue
data collection wise
thankfully if this isn't that of just
release Annapolis SDK that we're
integrating instead so they can handle
that for us the final thing is on my
checklist was design for offline first
right so as I said before a nuclear
Armageddon could take out your data
center and your pork should still work
if you want it to so we're using mqtt
for client-side communication and it
means our port doesn't as of care if
it's paired to
all server all your server so if you
change the configuration URL what it's
good to go
so I say man that was familiar it's how
Quin central we do it so just a quick
aside we do all of this and if you go to
that site and use that code you'll get
some money off if you want to try a IOT
device I mean man throat replacement
right go there so yeah that concludes my
talk on the security of Internet of
Things so you want to ask me any
questions about any of this including
the process of building a smart book
then just let me know hi hi sorry the
the MIRR ie botnet stuff I've been
following it reasonably closely one of
the things are never understood is how
the devices ended up exposed on the
Internet aren't most of them behind at
least a Rooter farm or something or are
they using UPnP to pluck punch-out sure
so yeah that's an interesting thing I
think the main thing that I focused on
were whales research music we'll say the
Meraki soft because that is actually
network level that's the bit that is
exposed to Internet we've CCTV cameras I
believe it's a I think it was the UVA
you PMP punching but I'm not certain so
so actually people should be scanning
the neural networks yeah
my advice yeah say just scan your own
networks make sure that you haven't got
open ports make sure that you're
actually aware of what kind of data is
available like I don't have the control
you think you have yeah exactly rather
than it just assumed that manufacture
doing properly because they have
seriously yep so you mentioned about
sort of compliance with these various
new standards that are coming in and
that there's a cost associated with that
yeah what are your thoughts around the
problem of consumers always wanting the
cheapest device so going to the the
dodgy Chinese manufacturer who makes the
knockoff still compatible but not
actually compliant sure so this is a
really big issue for us actually because
we're in space in our space we're one of
the most expensive books on the market
because we do things like Wi-Fi
I enjoy working well or home care you
can buy a smart book for 15 quid and for
all intents and purposes it will
probably do the same thing the issue of
that I think becomes one of consumer
education so it's similar to our apples
done with iPhones so Apple come child
seven quid for an iPhone because they've
said hey it's better it's more secure by
labelled by the mile by the bar people
that have the same kind of thought
process for porks and switches but it's
something I think we as in should need
to do we need to educate people about
the wrist more just one on from the
question over there about a device sent
behind the network and obvious happen
net network address translation
translate between public and private
what's the implication then we move to
ipv6 where every single device
potentially has a publicly accessible IP
address sure so I think one of the
reasons that mirai was so successful
because was the limited space of ipv4
right you can scan every single ipv4
address in a week with ipv6 and kind of
security of obscurity comes into play
which isn't a good suggestion
but there is so many more ipv6 addresses
to scam that it's not possible to carry
out the similar kind of attack right now
i would suggest so IOT is beginning to
be used as a buzzword just like cyber
and everything else under the Sun so I
was more interested in how you defined
IOT being in the industry sure so for me
I all t really covers how actually I got
the Bosworth's ID because I would I
anything that was traditionally not
connected to the Internet that now it is
so for example even like nuclear power
plants I would argue that Falls and
royalty I think as an industry needs to
be better about how we classify consumer
Enterprise Realty because Colleen say
call them a nuclear power plant alt
device isn't accurate but it is
technically correct so
that probably doesn't any question yeah
so you say IOT is more of a process than
it is a thing yes I'd say that IELTS alt
is the process of making something that
wasn't internet connected to internet
connected soil traditional post-racial
switches
[Applause]