machine running hello everybody welcome
to an introduction to data mining and
machine learning so data mining machine
learning and knowledge discovery there
are a lot of different names for
concepts that are very similar of course
I wouldn't be making you experts in 15
minutes but I hope that by the end of
the presentation you will at least have
a better understanding of these terms so
this is the plan for today I will focus
on the discovery of knowledge in
databases with a small example and give
you an insight in machine learning about
me so what my name is jeremy i am from
switzerland a small but beautiful
country in the middle of Europe you
should totally come and visit and yes i
did already milk a cow and i love
chocolate i guess some stereotypes do
hold up i'm not very different from any
other students here in appetite but
except that i did do two weeks research
on machine learning before giving this
presentation great whoa bossing me
around already okay but first let me bit
let me give you a bit of context into my
presentation when you work in a company
sometimes you have to make this is a
decision and these decisions are often
based on data so the problem is that
when you want to exploit that data it
may be too big or beyond understanding
especially in the last few years we're
in the amount of data Rose exponentially
humans cannot keep up with with it and
we can only expect it to grow even more
even larger we call that concept
actually we called that concept big data
big data is the notion of having too
much data for traditional databases it's
too big it moves too fast or it just
doesn't correspond to the architecture
of your database to gain value out of
this data you know if you find another
way of processing knowledge discovery
is a process or framework that helps you
transform the data into information and
also helps you make predictions and
decision out of the result seems scary
at first and you basically have a bunch
of databases that you process until
let's say Excel data sheet and you apply
data mining over it in order to find
patterns that will help you make
decision the process is a quite simple
but the analysis can be complex
depending on the type of variables you
have or the dependency well of course
that's a good idea better than anything
else I hope you can see I see behind so
this is an example of the famous data
set where you have to predict if an
adult is going to earn more or less than
fifty thousand dollars here you have the
income here in learning more or less
than fifteen thousands per year
depending on these fourteen variable
from before after processing the data
sheet and finding the interesting values
the ones that contain information we can
then what we call mine for data see the
major step of data mining after
processing a database is to choose a
specific algorithm depending on the type
of problem you have there are a lot of
algorithms and I won't detail a lot of
them or actually any of them but I'll
maybe talk a bit more about them in
machine learning what you have to
remember here is that choosing an
algorithm is not in there it's not the
only important part you also have to
tweak its parameters that train it on
part of the data to create a model and
apply it to the rest well let's have a
look of how much code we need to do that
for example okay you can't see much
doesn't matter it's not I'm very
important this is an example of our code
that I wrote it's only a hundred lines
of code but it does the trick i would
say then worry too much because this is
just an example and nowadays you can
create one in ten lines of code and
whoever wants that i can
email in that specific case it gives us
a model that we can use to predict an
outcome so if your relationship
relationship is a variable so if your
relationship was to be in merit then you
would have not easy person chances of
earning less than 50,000 thing judge me
is the algorithm at a specific data set
a team do that and in addition if your
if your capital gain was under 7070 for
you have 95 certain chances of having
the same so of course we have to check
for the accuracy and compared to
performance with other algorithm but I
didn't have the time to do that well
again yeah I guess you want to talk
about machine learning a bit machine
learning is a lot like data mining that
the difference is that we define the
outcome of the program we define the
outcome and the program learns the steps
to go there basically machine learning
focuses on prediction based on known
properties learned from the training
data and uses a lot of trial and error
whilst data mining instead focuses on
learning pattern basically we can
basically use the steps of data mining
that a delay of training phase where
computer try and try all the time now
i'm just going to define three types of
learning techniques the supervised one
that we can see here we'll get feedback
all the time and we'll know if it's
right or wrong and try to adjust
basically the unsupervised 11 in the
middle the role is to receive data and
model the underlying structure of the
data okay and the last one usually has a
mix of label and unlabeled data and
receive feedback any of the answers
correct what that's true because machine
learning is very old well it depends
what you mean by all but sorry old and
was coined for the first time around
1959 so why is it suddenly come
back you know why why do we have that
mean he talks about it that the reason
to that is called deep learning now deep
learning is the cutting edge of machine
learning to understand it we have to
start in the mid-50s when the first
neuron model was being created its model
inputs some information lies we can see
here a matrix of it sums it and if it's
over a specific threshold will return
one or a zero it later on a few
techniques were invented to update the
weight of the information in real file
called a back-propagation that's
creating what we call machine learning
algorithm because it would come back and
forth and back propagated wait and
update them all the time so today we
have different architectures for what we
call neural networks that allow us to
transform known nonlinear models to line
your models by adding a lot of layers
and simplifying the steps in between
adding to that a big data set and a lot
of computing power and deep learning can
outperform humans in tasks we thought
only we could be basic you so now
machine learning is used in wide areas
subject new marvelous and to have the
same Curtis previous versions only ten
percent of the files chain from
iteration to iteration according to a an
intelligent company called deep in think
that I read on Google beforehand machine
learning can analyze and predict
different patterns to help security and
report anomalies it can also be very
useful in healthcare for example to
understand risk factors for disease in
large population and is also used in
recommendation and cross-selling for
service of services such as a muslim and
netflix i guess you all know now
to break it down we have seen that
knowledge discovery focuses on decisions
in companies and what we can gather from
the data to make them play today data
mining is a process in knowledge
discovery involving the finding of
patterns and finally machine learning
wants to make predictions when we train
the many Lee layer deep neural network
on lots of data using lots of computing
power we call it deep learning okay now
and finally I just want to make another
slide here just want to take a minute to
talk about the program called making the
most masters that we mark the students
out here another take we have the
opportunity to make our masters project
and company so if you're interested in
any of the projects listed here for
example in knowledge rediscovering deep
learning to Melwood prediction which is
my original goal and why I'm giving this
talk then you just need to send me an
email and i'll give you more information
easily and before the end i'd like to
know if anybody followed that how many
dogs are in this presentation oh he said
seven here you go okay thank you
everybody
[Applause]