the on there yeah there we go right i'd
be more not let it back around too much
because frankly was doing that great
during a grand talked earlier on i'm
great yes not virtual reality um I can
be virtual and I'm quite real so a bit
of a disclaimer which I'll get to in a
couple of slides about this talk but
I'll see em please come and go if you
think this is you know not that sure we
have a few interesting but yet
ransomware the back of we will not win
my name is Dan really would and I still
didn't know if it's actually a dashed as
a dash here security when the hashtag is
no dash that wouldn't work the code in
my day job I were to Infosecurity
magazine so we'll get to that in just a
second when you are submitting talks you
have to think of a title really that's
really clever and then I thought that
was the high slit rubbish so I'm I said
exempt from such sexy stuff without the
next so and that's one of the challenges
of doing talking three months out you
thinking I've got a headline a headline
then you think you know you slept with
it so this is kind of my alternative one
so a bit about me I look day job by
security of an analyst and done some
other work as well and yeah it's not one
for most important obviously that's
where I do now so just a little
disclaimer before I get going and the
reason why you guys see me holding
pieces of paper is if you do have the
choice to follow me on Twitter you'll
see that urn Oh sugar there we go right
which ones out here we go I found out on
Monday that I was doing this because the
virtual reality man couldn't make it so
this was written in three days and it
was done monday at about four o'clock it
was notes on my phone and here is in
touch in my hand so and a slide deck
slower yeah this is slightly crap i do
apologize advance cuz then that's
basically been my week and I'm very
delighted to be here first time at
security actually and yes in really good
day actually really delighted to round
off your day almost fucking got insecure
work so what I want to do today is I'm
not a techie Samantha disclaimer I'm not
here to come and tell you how to create
ransomware LC I wouldn't do that in the
first place
how to try to out defeat ransomware how
it coding was them I'm take a great
insight grin when I book the earthing
I've got no idea of timing on this tool
because i virtually run through it in
the bar about an hour ago and i hope i
think it works the time anyone says to
me you've got a history in computing or
security i said no grunts like the
things i do i just be from the previous
one I basically doing this it's about
2008 so as you know done this from there
before / presenting now and so I'm not
going to take your not how it works but
one can't right then see you is so the
business side of ransomware and how it's
an industry we're doing something about
in the impact it's having a pretty
massive issue continuous for the
business so the thing that kind of
bothered me a lot about ransomware what
more than feather that's really hitting
people is we've gone from big worms and
you see lots of film references in this
I love culture records film so if which
was broke on you'll be cheering every
time you saw one but we're all on coke
and I in brew some reasons though and
yeah basically we're gone from when I
started out in writing about IT was
somewhere I security it was configure
and some of you probably as old as me
remember stuff like that and then we
might went on to various other things I
don't get the sum one identify here at
the point when things that the threat
landscape completely change from being
very sophisticated to being absolutely
rubbish so essentially you know we
started with massive worms in 2010 and
you know who remembers sucks net sucks
now identified 2010 targeted industrial
systems in particular the Iranian
nuclear energy facility and great
documentary called zero days it's really
worth a terrible sides of it really
worth looking at problem is
sophisticated piece of malware ever seen
another one buku not felt like that d
you qu detector center of relevant you
try and illustrate it also looks for
information that could be useful in
attacking industrial control systems but
Gavin information flames detective 2012
used for targeted cider espionage in the
Middle East specifically very
sophisticated
certificates really really clever stuff
this is about espionage rather than that
she was a disruption that Stuxnet was
Gauss who's a man from Austria Austria
enjoy pissing them off talk but they'd
probably tell you who wrote guilty the
lines to collect designed to collect as
much information about infected systems
as possible still potential spanking
systems and social networks and stuff
like that very widespread it's much more
than flame but yeah previously Michigan
Red October I spent hours beings of that
night cyber espionage malware discovered
several 2012 operators five years
publishing Middle East really ok kid
stuff you know and you know basically a
sort of a connected world these really
five worms I just picked out a lot of
them worked on by Amber steal everything
from kaspersky hear things really great
work in the early part of this decade as
it were you know it's hugs its
diplomatic diplomats government you know
scientific research organizations want
to collect the information it want to
make sure that everyone knows what's
going on and yeah it's really bad stuff
so what input on discovery actually
particularly with red october 60 domains
are closed down immediately tech have
just disappeared you know very few
people who ever arrested for this and
you really reading suck me you'll find
there's a lot of rumor about who was
behind it being government stuff like
that so the thing was what happened in
2013 was everything great what those
comment detection stopped iron brass
from traverse keystone basically she was
red october that is if i'm done that to
going on now that we're going to find
out in about 20 18 deciding 2013 and
didn't remember the answer they gave me
but it's everything change face acting
didn't hear any more of these big threat
research it all become a bit more
standardized really in more kind of
average email list so what I'll kind of
want to know where all the big ones gone
and is everything happening now well its
kind on least as the hackulous can't but
they become pretty lazy I'm not saying
hackers I should take that hackers went
a academic malicious that meaning i
might mean for the fuck do it
ethical hacker you know did they attack
you Latinos if they kind of become much
more lazy you know was it just a case of
like well we can do all the drop all
these zero days that you know gives you
one shot I need to get blocked in that
city spent all that effort and research
so the cases they just thought well
let's try something a bit more easy and
you know it kind of did and it kind of
worked and as a result of that crits
around somewhere was created this one
for friends of the 60s and petting them
well today I was just telling you we're
talking about extortion here we're
talking about blackmail and yeah they
largely knew I mean we look at for
example in 2013 McAfee found that is
collected over twenty two hundred fifty
thousand unique samples a quarter of
million of ransom when first quarter
2013 that was more than double the
number from the previous year of 2012
2013 everyone starts making ransomware
distributing ransomware why is that we
will get to that in just a second but
it's actually the number they can
actually see too so I want to know 2013
coming changed in security something
changed in the world that we went from
flipping largest sophisticated red let's
open flame so something is noisy and
sabotage the cool which is a word I've
just created to make security change I
look to 2013 i was at what happened 2013
i stay right in 2013 there you go now
I've been generated thank you very much
frozen happens 400 million they've got
so many thanks to IMDb for that one so
yeah 2013 that was the biggest fear on
the year apparently saw some others 2013
well salmon farmers rien ovulated Pope
Benedict I'd skeleton a Richard the
third is discovered Oscar Pistorius
charged with murder mother factored
those Boston Marathon bombing Alex
Ferguson retire the epic in the Scottish
one zircon you Lee Rigby murders andy
murray wins prince george is born
chelsea manning sentence the phone
hacking trial begins and nelson mandela
dies pretty massive year eating 2016
speak for news headlines and maybe the
focus isn't on cyber none of those to do
with which side really a new president
came in what you've already there but
you know lots of stuff it going on in
the world that's very geophysical
nothing to refocus on cyber however
sixth of jun 2013 i'll give a prize of
free beer after party when you one crew
member 6 of jun 2013 that man free beer
that's the man that happened six of jun
2013 Edward Snowden appeared so yeah she
quite a big yes I this conflict myself
and just know three days later he
reveals himself six of jeans when the
initial stories go up in the Guardian
and some other places three days later
he he pops himself as it were 21st james
edward snowden's charged by the US with
espionage theft of government property
unauthorized communication of National
Defense Information and willful
communication of classified tricycle my
shuttle um yeah how much is another
drink right two days later he rides in
Russia first of august 2013 he's granted
one year temporary asylum in Russia
there he is he still they still of the
country still in Russia though so you
know I don't think Trump's can be giving
him any kind of a Manning esque you know
buys anytime soon so the question I
would raise here did espionage if it was
done that don't be numb by government so
these kind of fruit that governments are
doing it jack is on doing it almost
hackers were doing it but they're doing
it to the government I'll say it snows
you changed everything in security moved
it from espionage I'm also he started
ramsden we're pretty wants to quote me
on that Jamie if you're still listening
from early on the icy when I misquote me
on summary I guided with you if
production team is currently on Edward
Snowden created ransomware but he needs
something very significant and he
actually changed it so everyone thought
more now he knows that it's been are
just going on so hackers attackers
thought well let's do something a bit
different so ransomware appears now is
that coincidence or is it just I'm gonna
get some points later on I think why
ransomware has been so successful two
types of ransomware this in particular
their script around somewhere and it's
Locker rent somewhere quick so changed
your files he can't open them locker
basically looks down your advice very
specific only on mobile so yeah I'm not
here to kind of explain what it is but
you know if you get a screen looks like
that then you know you've done something
wrong I would be not really the FBI
we'll get them for them in a minute but
yeah otherwise you have 72 hours paid
fine otherwise you will be arrested so
you know if you're where what someone
outside of our little room here and you
know this is all conference not part of
our whole industry if you see you are a
blow to a fine of two hundred dollars
let's pay the fines three blank read the
fine thanks to google images for this
and you know send the codes to sign at
fbi.gov and rich person they can be
quite terrified by that because it also
one's going around you know things have
been detected in your work history
things you've been to you know it's a
bit rough really so this was a random
we're backing grabs of malware really
kind of destructive really noisy up the
timing has been so sophisticated and so
well built that subnet and flame it's
such a reward we get around somewhere
and well how prominent is it I've got a
few examples of just how prominent
ransomware really it so this is my
website and post security or what I work
for us to play ransomware target fifty
percent of all well do this is between
two rad where it was from about what
just that six weeks ago and so sweetly
49-percent has been the subject of a
cyber ransom campaign in 2016 well that
one ransomware double since July that is
going to checkpoint luckily accounts 41
fair whatever July's December to account
of 10.5 dependent will recognize malware
now it was ransomware that was in last
year CNBC report this was in December
that the six thousand percent increase
compared 2015 that's how much more
section has been by my IBM security was
in forty percent of all time message
from 2016 brilliant and quite
sophisticated everywhere why because it
was easy can make people keep blinking
on it DC I'm sure have you been that
she's quite a nice place to be honest
with you seventy percent of storage
devices this was in July right january
twenty generally twelfth jangly 15th 123
187 CCTV cameras were affected by
ransomware and shut down yeah we're
talking smart grid stuff now I think
this stuff is all connect the internet
right somewhere getting affecting their
that as well but 12 to 15 what happens
five days later he gets in
well I bet he got my back again is get
it often so yeah really really quite
significant this one was the rubbish
picture but probably the Austrians if
they came in the romantic seehotel llega
vert hotel in Austria that they had to
pay thousands in Bitcoin to cyber
criminals who demanded fifteen hundred
euros 1200 pounds in Bitcoin otherwise
they'd lock down the whole network years
big debunk this someone actually sure if
it was actually look in their rooms
locked out of the rooms or just hit the
whole network but either way it shows
how networks aren't just users any more
businesses and businesses connect to the
internet really being locked down
basically at la school barrage calling
in Los Angeles their pack psychoses file
email and the messaging system and
ransom them for thirty thousand dollars
they said you have seven days then as
Bitcoin of seven days we will move your
private keys and it's impossible to
recover your files of the ransom there
on the server yeah important stuff so
NHS Trust they've had a real problem
with this apparently thirty percent
suffered around somewhere at cycle into
a rodent Freedom of Information Act
request 129 NHS Trust 94 had suffered
some kind of ransomware problem one in
particular Imperial College 19 times in
only 12 months so something's going
wrong there but what an interesting and
so it's even led my place about eight
sums and eighty-seven percent said they
attack again access through a network
NHS device eighty percent toxic by
fishing will get on power ransom I get
them to your website in just a moment so
yeah really oh NHS schools bc government
yeah most secret everyone's getting hit
by ransom white line because it'd be
easy to create off the shelf you can use
it deploy in people click on this stuff
and it's all it's not very nice stuff
deal with really so SBI I've looked at
this one this stuff actually Ricky said
you should pay if you're all right your
hip that change their mind and so don't
say so hey you don't pay is still
something that's interesting really
gotta work out but it's alright because
California said deploying crampton where
is a crime so if you are facing califo
Anya according to january third going to
wild yeah you're going to be arrested
for deploying around some work sloppy
before that it was fine you know it was
probably up there with with you know
crossing the road or something like that
and when he went on a great green light
but yeah it's crying now so yeah just be
careful and everyone's going to roll
something like this out I don't know if
we've ever seen anything with the police
and cyber they throw at us cyber but
there we go they do kind of not keep up
too well but they say doing the best we
can really so that was that was then so
yeah FBI said what we paid you know we
still there with the LA school thirty
thousand dollars they asked thought well
this I got from the excellent Jeremiah
where work following him he works for
comical Sentinel one now who are doing a
lot of work on ransomware actually a 50
turn paid more than 10 grand 20 cent
paid more than 40 grand yeah pretty
decent figures actually if you can earn
that for the money but if they don't be
in California and after that sort of
money this is a little tricky defiance
thanks to andrew how you sent me this so
one two three four five and then once
you three four five so it kind of
matches up so it messages hospital 425
million that is or a demanded 1605 days
were locked down to around somewhere
lost five million in revenue of the
Hollywood keep and I there nine hundred
and seventy million lost 10 million now
I find weird about that look at that for
exactly the same one are 1700s if your
guitar around somewhere it's kind of
look at what everyone else is doing a
pro at the market would okay price of
the market really and they will around
for four days that is costing businesses
now yeah 10 million that was what
Gregory lost three million 10 million it
cost this hospital in Hollywood's really
quite one of the first edgy when
Hollywood Presbyterian Medical Center to
actually be locked down by ransomware in
here actually quite a sort of a
significant thing so kind of the problem
is fig you know with this and what
Jeremiah said the business model for
ransom where is working seventy percent
of businesses victims paid that the
attackers to get their data back
aesthetic studies found and you know
those we pay fifty percent take more
than 10,000 pounds we see you know one
in 1600 if you're not in info security
you don't know how to determine to
picture these sort of thing just ring
from consultant who's probably
why did you are then how do you think
there's a great pump until they fix it
or watch it makes you I've been that
point but yeah some yeah how'd you turn
to and if someone saying if you don't
pay me you know 20,000 pounds in Bitcoin
or 500 pounds whatever you know we
delete all your photos can be quite
terrifying for the victim so you know
the to sort of pick you learn types
around from whether we've seen the most
popular cryptolocker sorry which first
appeared we're ready Matt for 2014
procured just I'm 83 million u.s.
dollars for us taken down by authorities
it was created by a subgroup within a
gang in 2013 those infected were
originally that request was four hundred
dollars 237 pounds and or equivalent in
Bitcoin and victims are 72 hours to pay
up or face the fact that the keys will
be destroyed up somehow the threat
really is not just well with what your
authority digits you'll never see this
ever again that's cryptolocker crypto
wall again apologies for photo/fbi is
internet Crime Complaint Center she
didn't learn warning businesses and
individuals about the continued spread
of cryptographic ransom there as that
had earned 18 million after they were
contacted by 992 vixen the people are
kind of they see this me oh my god what
am I going to do well not many options
to you do and we're gonna get onto that
towards the end but you know where the
ransom may come from well ransomware
chris is going to Microsoft visiting
unsafe suspicious or fake websites only
emails or email attachments from people
you don't know and you weren't expecting
and clicking on links and Facebook
Twitter Skype I see quite a few of those
but even from people i know it's very
spread it drives by a lot of this stuff
xperia 22 a website click this and
knocks you down you know it like sort of
Stuxnet which is targeted against one
particular facility ransom where's just
hitting everyone acts like it's off its
off the shelf I think there's something
industry could be doing better which
we'll get to towards the end but
ultimately industry in taking down some
of these websites how does it actually
keeps on going so what would sort say is
have a look at what just happened
it there's lots of things that have
allowed ransomware to succeed in info
security and I will put my hands it's
the first on prescott which we keep
writing about it but all those example
the fuck did that many for a reason to
show how we keep writing about it it's a
thinking hey look you know I get bit of
coverage every time I do something bad
I'd up to it I'll admit to it but I do
actually go out and do and prove that
it's working encryption levels are
descriptive sha-1 char one which I wish
you wrote about ten o'clock last night
you know encryption we've done such
great encryption that people can't break
it and if that's what they're using well
its encryption is used by the bad guys
as well a like advice and how be
unlocked we'll get to that in just a
second and there's an immediacy to click
on stuff you see something you know look
at this video well you know someone of
Grendel them and presenting on these
it's all clear on watch this now how
many of you weren't in that sort would
think I'll go watch that there and it's
a it's a bad situation to be in are we
doing decent awareness I don't have
anything called side sides of streetwise
reached as far as done V or so he scored
it would come from them in London anyway
and if the idea was some of these
campaigns really Dolph I should probably
do a separate presentation tits out
brilliant they really were don't drink
our date milk but you'd use an outdated
who using an outdated a in care about it
a bit work yes we'll use it at the
problem with with a lot of users of
consumers and IT yes I he has led to
this immediacy that's allowed ransomware
to spread and you know actually become
come what it is so you know we carry
devices once over there now taken out
but you know I see something to click on
it what happens I'll do I've got myself
down it's pretty when droid yeah network
connected devices through you know
attached storage it's tricky and this is
all contributed to the you know the
scourge around somewhere on the other
hand it's it's a great dream for am our
developer they now have to build
anything cutter that's sticky
sophisticated anymore there's barely a
new 40 days anymore even though that
there's probably not that many around
the research level goes down it's off
the shelf you can buy distributor people
click on it and you inspect all of your
people that you know you want to insects
and you get paid millions for it
okay you might not last very long as it
said if you're in California get
arrested for it now you might get
arrested everywhere else so yeah it's
what i wanted to point out in this talk
was about hype really you know it isn't
about hype ransomware it's about it's
about to reel out it's a reality it's
the real thing and I don't think I want
to just to wrap up isn't comfortable
well ahead of time actually but is what
the industry has actually been doing to
try and address this so in particular
this one appears so six world with 2014
and keep an eye on that day or keep that
in mind for a moment because I'm
confused by something myself this one
that particular crystallographer victims
get files back for free this is the
story i'll just let you take that in
really this was obviously just finished
three years ago and the idea was simple
the game of his youth group who were
distributing crypto Locker they were
that sort of a few people came together
they took that controller crystal of him
and as a result one of the things they
did they publicly and fire i did a
online portal which you go there and and
unlock yourself as it were so yeah good
idea this is six of april 2014 i went to
this on monday so that's actually a
screenshot of my and my lap talking see
well coughing looking at and yes the web
site offline and great thanks very much
for that so i went to fire I and to fox
i see and this was actually one I think
six of August 2014 if I spotted this
afternoon I need to raise them on that
the love of providing decryption
solutions the cryptolocker there is no
different we just continued that website
in its association decryption service on
the same day I need to turn that with
them squared edges before yeah but that
was one thing didn't last very long and
I went to to them and foxy Fox YT said
as cryptolocker was no longer being
spread usage of the service with
decreased because Dan cryptolocker is
quite often use any type of ransomware
its they decided to quit for people come
in they're trying to get themselves out
wall and various other types of malware
but am I said to not give victims of
future rounds or infections false hope
by coming to our website bloody harsh
isn't it so and the antics one this came
out 2016 no more ransom if this has been
backed by government law enforcement a
lot of Enders a lot of Industry people
behind this my only concern is it turns
out and one day justice get discontinued
I'm waiting to see this whole post some
sort of melba ties me because I think
they'll be all sore but a lot of people
doing good things yeah you look on it
but my concern is that a lot of people
are seeing this you ever get a big blast
of information in about one week which
we call cybersecurity awareness week
sponsored by whoever and disappears and
people look at it and then I forget all
about it and I wanted to prove the
people scare about it by doing this poll
this was bit of fun we had for Christmas
one of my marketing teams she said can
you cooking up some questions for polls
so I just thought what was launched and
also look at that train I'm stone I just
rearranged the word and the Twain I'm
sitting that what it's called as he
hoped some of the joking 114 people
voted on this the only one good at math
vertical extender 114 were right the
rest clean your laptop ram somewhere
beyond so if anyone see a lot of
students in the room she want to create
a ransomware solution if you're welcome
to have that for free I've created it
and I'm going to give it away but yeah
it's pretty it's pretty serious actually
that these sort of things happened in
our little info security bubbles so
consider running well under time and I'm
nearly done so let go back to the bar
but yeah with ransomware effectively
people are kind of throwing money away
you know it it's cheap to make it's
cheap to distribute but it's very very
effective and those who are affected get
get locked down pretty straight away so
in conclusion really you know the
problem is getting worse it's not
getting better no one's out there kind
of saying let's try and actually and to
do this nice to think to the bottom here
there needs to be better URL filtering
attachment blocking if anyone here is
here at the tone looking to business
ideas upon actually leave your things
you can build I think that's one of the
things that
this industry could do is actually is
actually better URL filtering attachment
blocking two things that the business
could use to achieve stock mounts and
weapon spreading from I have I get a lot
in the vendors I get people close to me
we want talk about ransom I see you and
I'm like solving ransomware yeah and
it's like what what's your solution oh
we tell you back up more great thanks
further it rang bounced back up it great
everyone's your back up more stuff
exists you can backup to the cloud
searching signal we all doing mostly in
any way but come on let's just find
something more than just getting it
restore basically that's got me do it in
ish you doing something doing enough no
more man some ways is existing I've not
got anything about it for about six
months that's over the cryptolocker one
is now offline but I think the bigger
problem is i think we're expecting the
world outside to understand this and
know exactly what's going on anyone
who's got friends and facebook who
aren't in security through the
conversations they had about spybot and
oh yes i love watching people can try
and figure out i don't claim to be any
kind of expert probably proven my lack
of technical capability on this slightly
rubbish slide but you know i'd like to
watch people talk about ransomware and
trying to figure out what to do and go
do you like message forum but went
through quite a lot when i'm writing
this talk things like be sleeping
computer just people locked out after
they trying to figure out what to do
it's really tricky so just going to get
the last word over two very nice Gavin
Miller's from from terrible its
monetization of poor security hygiene
whether it's in businesses who aren't
doing that the URL filtering whether
it's in the consumers it's an industry
problem it's an overall problem
ransomware and we've seen the level of
businesses that have been hit and it's I
don't see anything really changing
towards so just to wrap up this I was
doing a bit ly is a rubbish idea on the
slide i did not call for info security
magazine about the economics of
ransomware how Bitcoin payments are
going up and down what we brought and
thought that is there its own info
security magazine up comedies behind a
log in wall but i encourage you to
create characters and silence delicate
evening at the info security virtual
summit three and play on smart there on
wed twitter and that's me and
think that we are done thank you very
much for listening
[Applause]