good should we should we talk about some
hardware hacking ok cool so um my name
is Joe Graham and I am a an electrical
engineer by trade it's sort of what i do
i love electronics I live it I breathe
it i've been involved in electronic
since I was 17 years old and started
building projects out of magazines and
just um opening things up and see how
they work in breaking things and taking
apart broken things and taking apart not
broken things and breaking them
um it's just something I've love to do
I've always loved being able to think of
something and build it and see it
working
I when I was a kid that wasn't really
the coolest thing to do to be involved
in computers and electronics was sort of
like having a big spike on your head or
something everybody just kind of looked
at you and laughed and everything
pointed but now i'm laughing so it's
okay i just figured as long as I was
doing what I love to do then it didn't
matter what other people thought which
is also part of the hacker mindset so
you know not even just hardware hacking
accra mindset in general there's
something that you love and something
that you wanna they want to do and
something you believe in something you
try it doesn't matter what anyone else
says so we're gonna talk about hardware
hacking and there's a few kind of things
about hardware hacking I tried to kind
of break it into a few a few different
areas but one is about learning and
having fun in the curiosity side of
things like how does that thing work
I'm just seeing how things are working
having fun with experimenting like these
you know like the badges you guys have
been tinkering with those that's an
important part may be solving a
difficult problem maybe there's like
some cool thing you're working on some
project or something that you're like I
wish I had a way to control this robot i
wish i had a way to do something with
this toy or like turn this toy into
something cool and you can do that with
hardware hacking anything that you can
think of you can make and that's what's
so cool just like with software but with
software he can't really see it right
you can kind of sorts sometimes you can
see the results but hardware you can
always see in electronics you can change
one thing it was
change everything and that's what's so
cool about it maybe doing something
that's never been done before
if you you know again if you have
something that you're thinking of and
maybe there may be something has been
done so that might be something like um
let's see what's a good example of that
I don't know maybe like the the 3d
printers a few years ago there was no
easy way for somebody just print out
their own object so it really never been
done on a scale you know they had big 3d
printers and things for big companies
but there was nothing that like me and
you could just go and build and and it
makes something so that's sort of
hardware hacking it's like and creating
something that's never been done in
doing something really cool with it I'm
sure you guys have heard this in every
single talk at at roots asylum not
breaking the law
that's an important one trust me you
don't want to break the law when you do
this stuff and the laws have changed a
lot since i was a kid i could get away
with a lot more than what you guys can
get away with just because the
technology wasn't understood the
internet wasn't understood electronics
and hardware like all this stuff nobody
i tried to explain stuff to my parents
and they sort of got it but the
government the government was in a
different world so things are just
things are just different but nowadays
you know you have so many opportunities
that you don't have to break the law to
learn stuff you can come to places like
this you can go to DEFCON you can go to
your hackerspace you can go to your
school who probably has no computer lab
or some electronics things so there's so
many workplaces that you can go that you
don't have to kind of reach outside of
the law to do things and that's a really
important thing so i'm going to go
through like some may be famous hardware
hackers that you may or may not
recognize just to let you know like
hardware hacking we going on for a long
time it's not just since no the arduino
processor maybe your or in the past few
years it's been going on for hunt for
hundreds of years
this old guy is as Thomas and you guys
remember what he what he developed he
created the light bulb that's right so
among lots of other things he's pretty
much the most famous for creating the
light bulb and i think let's see i have
it in my notes there's some car
diversity about how many times he tried
to develop the filament in the right
design of the lightbulb but it was some
thousands of times so ever you know he
tried all these different things and
just kept failing and over and over and
over and over and over again and he got
it right you got the one set up that was
just perfect that would be low-cost and
that would last a long time and that's
part of the hardware hacking mindset
it's trying things over and over again
until you get it the way that you want
and he took a lot of you know
everybody's making fun of him like
you're never gonna do it you're never
gonna be able to figure out how to make
it an electric light bulb that's good
he didn't listen to them and that's
another important thing about these guys
steve wozniak Steve Jobs recognize those
names you know I think what company they
created Apple yeah so here pictures of
these guys back in the day when they
were young
maybe like your parents age or something
now probably younger than your parents
of the they're basically kids and on the
Left that's that steve wozniak with
something called a blue box which is the
device that used to be able to use to
essentially travel through the phone
system using different types of sounds
and that was something where it wasn't
you know that was kind of on the edge
this was this was way back this was 50
years ago
um but that was kind of like I don't
know if it was totally illegal but it
wasn't totally legal but this was the
way of he was hacking and he was
learning but that and you know his so
was kind of fascination with electronics
and with the telephone system is what
led him to develop the apple computer
which is just amazing and then showing
down here that that picture on if you
can see in that box is little circuit
board in there that's the that's the
first Apple Computer that came as a kit
had to build it yourself but didn't have
a keyboard didn't have a monitor you
have to kind of hack stuff together and
that's where things were back in the day
lots of hardware hackers then think sort
of went away is the software for
computers became more common in the
internet people kinda shied away from
hard went back to software so it's
always been my thing of trying to like
get people back into electronics and get
it people back into into hardware
there's a more recent picture of steve
jobs with the with the macbook so
creating something new with hardware
hacking i just i want to show you just a
few projects that I worked on when I was
a kid just to kind of give you an idea
of what you can do maybe inspire you a
little bit to say I'm gonna try to build
something like that little mischievous
devices one of the top is a little hard
to see that was the first circuit board
that i ever made and all it has honored
as to two resistors there's not much to
the circuit but that would plug into the
telephone line i don't know how many of
you guys actually have telephones that
plug into things anymore but I still do
probably by the time you're older you're
not gonna have telephone lines at all
but this thing plugs in a telephone line
and you can use the phone as normal from
your house you can call your friends and
everything but if somebody tries to call
you
it appears as a busy signal so it's
totally it's fun to kind of mess with
people and I i used it to prevent sales
guys from calling her house during
dinner and I was worried that teachers
were going to call my parents and tell
them about you know what i was doing at
school so i plug this thing in so no one
could call my parents and I could always
just they could still use the phone like
it was nothing
oh yeah okay so let's see some other
ones the lower the lower corner that
little box
have you guys seen projects that are
built into like Altoids boxes and little
kind of candy boxes that you can do
these days little kits you put inside of
candy boxes because it's like a
good-sized this was a box from from a
long time ago similar type of concept
and I build a circuit pretty basic
circuit that would just generate a
really high pitch sound and we have high
pitch sound high-frequency sounds it's
hard to locate where it's actually
coming from because it bounces all over
the place so it is i built the circuit
put it inside of this box which is for
like cough drops and I'd sit in class
this was in high school I'd sit in class
turn this thing on and put it on my desk
it was just this noise would just be
like everyone's like oh what's that
sound but no one could figure out where
it's coming from the teachers can figure
it out or anything it was totally great
and then and then the final one is
something that I built towards the end
of high school and I heard about this
kind of as rumours where you could have
a laser in China laser off of a window
and get the return of the laser based on
vibrations of the of the window the
return laser would be modulated with the
audio that's inside of the room right so
you can sort of spy on people from
outside of their house or spy on your
teachers if they're having a conference
in a different room with a window so I
want to build this thing and see if it
was actually possible and the rumor was
like the government has been doing it
for years they've been spying on
everybody and they probably are and were
uh huh but this one I used a big five
milliwatts red lasers you can see it if
I was a government i use a laser you
couldn't see but i use a red one and it
worked ok i could play music in my room
and turn the stereo up all the way and
it would move the window a little bit
like it like barely hear it so it sort
of proved the concept and that was
something that I just want to do because
I didn't know if it was possible
so that's creating something new a
little more recent few years ago I was
on a TV show called prototype this which
is on discovery channel and it's on
netflix now which is basically four
people building prototypes of crazy
things so if you want to see like
gigantic ridiculous things like 10-foot
giant boxing robots that that punch
based on the movements of players
outside the ring that's prototype this
that's creating something new that was
just completely out of our head idea
that were like what looks good on TV
that we could kind of it would be fun
and we can like build something gigantic
so that had we had a pneumatic control
and accelerometers wireless
accelerometers in the boxing gloves so
as you threw a punch the robot would do
the same thing it was totally cool you
guys too heavy
did you see that movie real steel yeah
the rumor is that real steel was based
on this episode of the show I can't
confirm that but yeah so that's um
that's creating something new just
totally ridiculous
here's another one that's me wearing
full firefighter gear this was another
one from the show which was a high-tech
firefighter pack and firefighters most
the time they have gear that's kinda out
dated
an old but we want to try to design
something would be really cool that they
could go into a fire and put out fires
with like a superhero sort of Shh you
don't spray fire extinguisher out like
spider-man we had a heads-up display
that they could where they could see
through all the smoke and figure out
where other people are in the room so if
you imagine a fire and there's smoke
everywhere and you know total chaos they
can walk in and know exactly where
people are so they can pull them out and
rescue them
what else do we have on there we had an
identification systems are not only the
firefighters see through the smoke that
they would know where the other
firefighters are that's an important
thing is you always want to keep your
keep your people together that was a
kind of fun one that actually had you
know I as opposed to the boxing which
was just for fun this had a real purpose
and we tested this with real
firefighters and they got to actually
use it so you know you can actually
create things that help people that have
a up further golden just for fun
modifying electronics taking something
that already exists and making it do
something else or tweaking functionality
a little bit
this is my favorite example and I it's a
garage door opener for my parent's
garage door I built this when I was I
don't know 16 or something in the way
the garage door opener works is that you
have a transmitter which is what this is
and you set a set a certain code on the
transmitter and you set a receiver on
the garage door to match that code when
I push the button it sends a code if the
receiver matches that code is going to
open the garage door if it's not the
right code it doesn't just like a
password if it's not the right password
is not going to open the door but on the
garage door transmitter there's a set of
switches 10 switches that you would set
and that's how you would set your
password and the 10 switches could be on
and off so there's really only a finite
number of settings right you can have on
off on every single switch that ends up
being 1024 possible combinations you
could if you wanted to just individually
try every combination by hand until you
got the password that was right but I
decided to build some electronics to do
that for me so I have a little circuit
in there that will cycle through every
possible combination of those passwords
and open any garage door that uses the
system so that was fun
I didn't go into any of the garages that
I opened again not breaking the law but
it was a fun thing to show look this is
really bad security and at the time I
would you know this was right before the
security industry became this thing but
this was my first time of building
something that I could actually show to
people and say look we need to change
the way this is done and my parents and
I showed it on my parents store that's
great you know they patted me on the
back and I ok ok so they didn't date
they got a little bit and that sort of
the response that we see from a lot of
vendors these days like people that sell
hardware products if we find problems
like a good job go away and I can't you
know doing things to make them realize
that it was important and eventually
moved all their stuff out of the garage
all the important stuff that's a fun one
here's one that I just started working
on its it's incomplete which is why the
picture is incomplete but it's a anybody
have the tooth tunes toothbrush
yeah somebody does awesome so it's a
toothbrush that will play music for two
minutes and when you when you put the
toothbrush toothbrush on your teeth
through bone conduction it feels like
you're actually hearing the music it's
really it's a really cool concept so
plays music for two minutes because
that's how long you're supposed to brush
your teeth so i bought one of those and
it plays dynomite the song dynamite and
which is an okay song alright not really
my style so I was like okay I'm gonna
modify it and play my own song that I
like so i can brush my teeth to music
that I like so what I did is I took all
the circuitry out of the bottom of the
of the toothbrush and basically threw
that away i had to create my own circuit
that play songs but first i want to see
how it works i took it all apart the the
kind of speaker part that vibrates the
toothbrush head which is how you hear
the music i just had to wire so i could
treat that as a regular speaker and all
I had to do is build some circuitry to
play sounds are songs off of an SD card
and that's something that in the past
few years ago that would have been
really difficult i just did a Google
search for SD card wav file playing wav
files
there's tons of circuits I built up a
few of those to find the best one that I
could do in the smallest form factor and
I loaded a song on to the way file now I
can play my own song
the next step is to cram all of that
circuitry back into the toothbrush and
then use it so modifying electronics and
there's absolutely no reason why I need
to do this right i know how to brush my
teeth but it's fun right it's just
something cool
testing security center here at Def Con
there's a lot of security related stuff
there's all sorts of products out there
that claim to be secure antivirus and
hardware things and everything but
really it takes a hacker it takes the
hardware hacker to do to test security
and tell people if it's good or not
because you can't really trust the
people selling stuff because they want
to sell you stuff so it's up to us to go
to them and say now it's not exactly
secure or maybe it is secure maybe they
do deserve a pat on the back but in
general it's always good to test things
on your own and I'm that's I'm naturally
like that i don't normally trust what
people say i want to do things on my own
that's part of the hacker mindset even
as far as like you know somebody waiter
brings a plate 22 the table at a
restaurant there like don't touch the
plate it's really hot and I always such
a plate to see if they're telling the
truth
so here's one you can't really see the
screen so this one's actually not really
gonna be that exciting
this was an example of testing the
security of the parking meters in san
francisco this is some work i did a few
years ago when I just moved to san
francisco and i noticed they use smart
cards that you can that you buy that
have a certain number of dollars on them
when you put them into the parking meter
and the meter will add money to the
meter and take money off of the card I
was like that's cool
I've never worked with smart cards
before so for me it was a great
opportunity to learn something new
sighs like okay I want to see how the
system works i went through this whole
process to figure out how it works and
then created my own custom smartcard to
see if i could defeat the security i
wrote some code loaded onto my own card
and it's completely impossible to see on
the screen so you have to trust me i'll
play the video anyway maybe you'll be
able to see it
so normally put the card in it would
show you a value would say like twenty
dollars remaining or something in this
case can you barely see that 999 dollars
and ninety-nine cents that's a lot of
parking
yeah like four hours worth of San
Francisco but that you know the maximum
value parking card you can buy as fifty
dollars there's no reason it shouldn't
the system should allow somebody to put
in the card that says it has nine
hundred ninety-nine dollars and cents
but I could have gotten free parking for
the rest of my life but I decided to
tell the city about it and say hey you
guys have a problem if I know about the
problem and I'm a good guy
there's probably people out there
ripping you off and if you're getting
ripped off
I'm paying for that because I pay taxes
and I'm paying for these losses for the
city so I thought it was sort of a noble
cause for me to go and tell them about
it and they acknowledge the issue i did
try that card a little bit more recently
and it does give me a error you know
checkcard invalid so at least they've
probably set the limit down to fifty
dollars so it's a good first step
that's testing security here's one you
guys might like
are you old enough to DC Terminator 2
now okay you will at some point a few of
you guys did okay sort of Rover probably
like teenagers I guess this is some work
that that a friend of mine Barnaby Jack
demonstrated at a at black hat in Def
Con a few years ago of hacking ATMs
machines we get money out of from the
bank and this is basically an ATM it
looks big and you know huge and
complicated but it's really just a
computer running some sort of code that
somebody wrote on there I'm sure you've
heard about you know people that are
hacking software types of stuff it's
really not a very complicated thing but
people just never looked at them because
they thought it was a piece of hardware
is probably secure the barnabeez like
now I don't think so i'm gonna look at
it so he ended up buying an ATM brought
it into his house started analyzing it
figure out how it works found a bunch of
problems in it that would let him
basically load new code into the ATM to
have the ATM do whatever he wanted
there's a windows CD based device it
wasn't anything even custom we could
load zone put in there and have it do it
everyone
just like writing a program on the
computer and running the for running
your program same exact thing except
what he did in this case is half the
things bit of money so i'll show you the
video it play some music somebody just
hold the microphone up to the up to the
speaker and you'll probably be able to
see it but let's let's give it a try
is playing music
there's the money business
we could basically kick all these ATM
network
you could basically identify an ATM
force it to spit out all this money and
then have put somebody go collect all
the money and run away but since he's a
good guy he figured this out went back
to the ATM company said they're hear it
a lot of your problems you'll probably
want to fix these and they did
we're using technology if you have stuff
that your parents are throwing away or
that you find at school or something
some piece of electronics or some
product you can always reuse it you can
always pick the pieces out using for
other projects on the Left I have an old
macintosh computer that i turned into an
aquarium that was sort of cool you can
make bicycles out of crazy parts and
then that bottom thing is like a coffee
table made out of circuitry in anything
you can think of you can do and that's
the beauty of hardware hacking i just
have three little videos when I was
doing the TV show the producer said what
are the what are your three favorite
tools that you can that you like using I
said a soldering iron multimeter an
oscilloscope these are the tools that i
use on a daily basis how many of you
guys have used the soldering iron in the
workshop area almost everybody okay so
i'll show you a video about it even
though you already know about soldering
i'll show you kind of funny little video
that i made explaining the tool and
explaining the multimeters in cisco
basically just to show you there's lots
of tools out there that you can use so
the stuff you know might seem
intimidating when you see a circuit
board and you're like what do I do with
it if you have the right tools you can
do it right just like if you want to
build something out of wood
if you have nails and you have a hammer
and a saw you can build stuff if you
have the right tools might be harder if
you all you have is a scissors so if you
get the right tools you can do this
stuff and it's not so hard
so let's see here's the here's the
soldering iron
I've got a confession to make soldering
might not be as cool as cutting grinding
or welding but when it comes to
must-have tools for building electronics
it don't get no hotter than the soccer
soldering station has two main
components soldering iron this thing
gets hot up to 700 degrees hot then we
have to solder this is the magic behind
it all
it's a special metal alloy that melts it
helps fuse components together so they
stay on the circuit board for example
here's the circuitry I built for the
personal air bag without this thing we
wouldn't be able to detect when the
person was falling and went to deploy
the airbag from the six-by-six
all-terrain vehicle this was a battery
management system that sat on top of
each of our batteries the anger
management demolition derby
there's a lot of soldering here
soldering isn't all fun and games
it's pretty dangerous these fumes are
toxic you don't want to bring them in
and stuff can get your eyes not good
so even though soldering isn't that sexy
and it's a little bit dangerous without
soldering all of the electronics in all
of our builds to fall apart literally
their soldering you guys actually hear
that all you could
okay good i can't hear it up here so
okay so that's ordering here's the
multimeter is a really cool piece of
equipment
so your car won't start you think it
might be the battery there's one way to
find out for sure the multimeter
multimeter the multimeter yeah x3 here
comes to electronics this sleepy little
baby right here can measure just about
anything but until these buttons this
thing can measure all sorts of aspects
of an electronic system like voltage
current resistance capacitance and so
much more
so if i want to testify have a good
connection just set this a continuity
touch the probes I'm good
it's the multimeter is definitely one of
the best diagnostic tools we have up
here in the lair
it's so versatile you can even measure
temperature and tell you if you're sick
dr. our temperature probe wasn't working
that video I wasn't actually sick
alright then the oscilloscope this is by
far my favorite tool so here I'll show
you about it
one of my favorite tools up here in the
layer is a digital oscilloscope that's
the digital oscilloscope this thing is
like the Swiss Army knife of electronic
measurement tools and let me visually
see an electrical signal and how it
changes over time
check it out is remote control have you
ever wondered how these things
communicate with your TV with the
oscilloscope I can see the signal is
being transmitted from the remote
control to the television
here's what it looks like when I want to
turn off the TV this is what it looks
like when i change channels this is a
really high-end oscilloscope i can
adjust the size of the waveform and the
time that are measuring the waveform
waveforms are so cool i'm even wearing
one of my shirt
it sounds like this i'm wearing a sound
i use this baby right here for every
electronics project that i ever work on
41 build on the show I used it to debug
anemometer circuit want to thank
everybody for spending time with me and
my oscilloscope to see you later
let's go
so I show that video to my son was four
and a half and he says daddy why are you
hugging your oscilloscope and I thought
of a good way to explain to him how much
I loved the oscilloscope but I could
just a good tool to have because other
without the oscilloscope you can't you
can look at a circuit right and you can
see it blinking a light or doing
something but you can't really know
what's going on each of those signals
some other really cool stuff you can do
depending on if you have access to x-ray
machines with your dentist has x-ray
machines or your veterinarian has x-ray
machines maybe your parents have access
to one you can actually look inside of
electronics and see what's going on
inside the actual chips you have these
are connected and that's really awesome
and you have advanced stuff like
decapping chips so if you look on your
badge all those little black chips have
little tiny silicon dies inside it's
almost like a it's almost like a city
inside it's almost like a circuit board
inside of each of those little chips
microscopic if you look with a with a
microscope you can see different
portions of it and if you zoom down
close enough you can see individual
transistors that form the entire chip so
what you can do is take a chip if you're
doing security research or you want to
try to get information about apart you
can use chemicals or you can use special
machines that will remove the plastic
the black part of the chip and actually
get to the dye inside and you can zoom
it out and see what it looks like
so really cool advanced stuff and
there's been some talks at DEFCON about
how to work with those types of
chemicals very dangerous stuff but also
very cool so I guess sort of the final
kind of summary of hardware hacking why
do it why is it cool what to do
basically you know open things up see
how things work experiment and don't be
afraid to make mistakes you know that's
the one thing when you're in school you
take a test it usually ends up being
it's right or wrong right and that's ok
because it's you know your teachers are
trying to figure out how much you know
or how much you understand what you're
working with but really making mistakes
is ok especially if you're experimenting
if you're wondering how things work and
you know you wanna just try something
and see if it's gonna work or not just
do it don't be afraid of failing that's
one of the things when you fail you end
up learning more rides like if you take
a test you get a problem wrong you go
back and try to figure out why you got
it wrong so you don't get it wrong next
time with electronics and hardware
hacking if you want to try something
maybe it's not gonna work their stuff it
will take me weeks to try to get a
circuit right Thomas Edison right to
come you know how I don't know how many
years it took them to get something
right so failing is ok you just let you
get one year just one step closer to
getting it right eventually and don't
let anybody tell you like all your
you're stupid you're dumb if it doesn't
work like that doesn't matter right
if you like it and you love it and you
want to do it you can do it i guess the
final thing you're never too young to
start your all older than this this
little guy here who is my son who is a
that picture i think he was maybe a year
old or a year and a half or something
like that
he's four-and-a-half now and I have a
younger one that I'm gonna soon start to
introduce soldering to but you're never
too young to start you know you've
already started with your badges and you
can go and look around and see what else
has electronics in it see what else you
can try to to to build think of things
that you want if you've always wanted
your own robot or your own toy that
doesn't exist or maybe it exists in you
know you haven't there's no your parents
haven't bought it for you there's no
special occasion coming up or something
it's like okay just building yourself
try to put it together yourself and see
if you can do it and that's the most
satisfying anyway being able to do it
yourself and show everybody that you did
it instead of just going in you know
buying it from a store so i think that's
it
let me see that's it that's the end so
thank you enjoy the rest of your time
here
Who extra 15 minutes you have any
questions anybody any questions about
anything
yeah so the question was I learned all
of this stuff in school or do I teach
myself and the answer is both
I started learning about things on my
own I through magazines and just through
reading because there was no internet
when i started their computers that you
could connect the bulletin board systems
and talk to people but it wasn't the
internet so i could just google stuff so
i started mostly on my own and when I
got to into once I got to college is
when i actually started learning about
it because i just did there were no
electronics classes or anything at my
school when I was younger so I just kept
it on my own went to school studied
Electrical Engineering so now I had the
formal experience and I had the real
world experience which i think is kind
of the best of both worlds and then I
went off and worked at action a real
product development company to learn
even more about the process and now I'm
just on my own doing it so I think it's
important to to do things on your own
and to learn in school if it's something
that you really like
ok so the question was what parts that I
used to make the perpetual water slide
which was one episode of the TV show
that was this giant 30-foot waterslide
simulator so you could sit in the bottom
of this gigantic donut of water slide
and had water in it and it was
computer-controlled that would basically
let you ride and unlimited water slide
which was totally awesome that project
took five weeks to make and most of that
was i think we had like 20 people from
San Francisco artists and welders and
stuff building this giant structure but
the control side really was there is
some hydraulic motors and stuff to make
the thing move up and down and left and
right and go side to side and then we
had yeah basically a computer running
some code like a Macintosh running to go
that was controlling all the hydraulic
stuff so really all of the magic was
done in in sauces code where he wrote a
bunch of stuff to simulate that the
different movements of the waterslide
so that one was very software intensive
but that was my favorite project an
amazing thing to ride but it's all gone
now that the production company took it
apart once we were done which is too bad
but having a good thing to show it like
maker faire or something
any other questions that yes no no okay
well I guess there's a little bit of
time you could always run back to the
workshop area or I guess hang out here I
don't know what the next talk is ok not
sure either so hit thanks again