welcome to the stock
happy so many people
still hereof the conference because
issue of course the Lost Ark I'm
I want to start with the thanking also
USENIX Association organizes if this
of dizzy vent for the opportunity for us
to talk
give 'em just nice or commander
exceptional circumstances and
now we are basically not allowed to a to
present the paper
but yup we are allowed to I'm about to
present
the subtitle of a paper due also
dismantling this man thing manuscript a
wireless lockpicking
a few can mobilize it was joint work
between them I i'm their army I'm
overgrowth Burridge age a
we are from the rubble University 9 a.m.
flooded this year from
I'm University room so
hmm our server disclaimer not
you know do a recent the injunction by
the High Court long the star cannot
cover
technical core of our accepted paper I
reason we will not reviewed any do you
feel sees
in this talk also some
interaction I am basically
we will stick to slice I we will not
answer questions
I'm sorry for to but I hope you
understand
I am ru however rules
are happy to see what justice the
discussions in the community
also after newt or chrome may be
difficult to rise instead of
question answer for me I am I since
legal procedures are still ongoing
yeah wanna mention we can't really going
to the I'll
so what I am gonna tell them I well let
me give you an overview
I'll just for some juicy if you can
mobilize is what is it
most you know last year outstanding
as well on the USENIX conference talking
about Fuego mobilizes
I am but I will just revisit that
the therefore I am I'll show what is it
I'll talk about related work from I will
zoom in on this high-tech to work with
last year
because it's not so different for read
it now
and a the No pay some attention to
responsible disclosure for
I'm I just the reverse engineering
because this
in Folsom in these kinds of security
your
testing did the strength of security
mechanisms and
well up or not some other litigations
and alternatives that
that were proposed by the academia but
as well as the industry been of
finally within the conclusion so what
does it mean
if you go immobilizer buser electronic
anti-theft device
as introduce around nineties a and
its was mostly used in Europen smaller
countries but now those uses
also I a fairy a custom to use in the US
cars as well
a profound so hot wiring so you know
from the old movie set you can just to
put some wires together in driveway
well that is what tries to two
arm to be from an its it's even
mandatory
in several countries a it's based on a
on a
are pretty track in the low-frequency
review for you see I don't fire
and am that works in a way that the in
the car
basically has a new near to the ignition
ASM electric power magnetic field which
powers
with chip which is a passive ship
without a battery and then
day out some communication exchanges 0
show mornin next slide I but before that
though I want to make sure the
should not be confused with the the
remote locking system of a car
so what you owe me know you sure key
you press a button and the car opens and
then use
step in the car and you put your key in
the ignition turn it around and start
your car
it is the same device you holding but
actually you too
separate things I we looked at the park
where you put the you car you turn in
the ignition
and there is a low frequency for going
on and that's
aceptar chip and in this case a
and and opening the door or do designing
a lime
is is a completely different Barton
we didn't look good that's I'm
so that this is basically a a simple a
of you want what I show now it's a
how demobilize we're going very simple
way you have ignition lock and then turn
it around ignition lock in your car
and you have any other side effect
dickey a
where there is a transponder in this key
it's a very tiny
glossed the in this in this serving
and you see the red arrow pointing to it
at school transponder
transfusion response and well the
sounding name
an what you a what a base he does is
some simple cryptographic operations I'm
but how it starts as the following you
put it in the ignition lock and then the
car
detect there is something so it says
okay please
identify yourself and then the
transponder sends back
its I don't for its number not a car
looks sharp do a notice number
if it is in known by a wide miss than
it sense a around number plus approve
back to do then the car key and a car
key
validates okay is this car knowing my
secrets
a if so them it also sends back a proof
two-car and the car Danka
as well validated got proof is is
genuine
then you have a mutual authentication in
this setting although probably
most view already spotted there are two
things here once the jurors a
I'm there's a a wide this thing so if
you don't have a a correct identifiers
so you would just walk to your car and
tried to communicate with
then it would just be more you because
you don't know number which is known in
car
and secondly there is no randomness from
the
DAC from Bernard a the car can
there's no fresheners there are no wrong
number introduced by the carton
that means there's a replay attack
possible well
buddhism basically on car in mobilizes
on a pretty big problem because on all
the ones
i've seen and Lisa for so
how let me naming a tho bit about the
related workable Sun
over the years I am in 2005 for the
using security symposium bono I told
showed
I'm how you can actually recover key
over
offered dick digital signature
transponder chip
there was a a introduced in 1995 and it
only had a 40-15
so yeah instead you have to do complex
mathematical
tricks or do some cryptographic great
you basically good just search for two
key because
to 240 is not so challenging I am
well nowadays this is replaced by a or
DC 80 which is a proprietary algorithm
or or another chip would actually use a
ass
I am and on a 10-yard bit a
which are all going out later inner
mitigation search so
hmm then we go to ki larki la cosa es is
quite
some more work Don McKellar this
basically because
the key was 64 bit so it's been more
challenging
and the awesome interesting work you
could do on
on this cryptographic algorithm next
year also you could learn from it and
how you could
use improve or not make so similar
cryptographic States and the singer's
around the same time
and in the end the a
to recover two key units around
complexity of 244 encryptions
I show less severe than
war-related papers on this on this topic
am do to divest among nor are
of my knowledge actually a is the is
this QR
not longer deployed in there in
automotive industry
between maybe could be found in
some all work a
then all talk a bit about the high-tech
to
I thank you sir introduce as we're on
the same I'm
period 1996 and
has a key length of forty a bit so it's
between the city and
and the keylock we showed last year in
the
in our paper that did actually
complexity is only 22 37 encryptions
which you can use the computer room on a
laptop
and well on this
a on this particular ciphers is also
quite a a widely use product there was
quite some
quite some publications on sensor 2010 9
I'm this is progressive is he replaced
by I the tree which is also proprietary
but also there's some I think pro
variant which is using a yes yeah
so lemme revisit the bitter
high-tech to what I showed last year and
I just summarize the key issue she found
and
so so what kinda weaknesses did you
identify so
basically that the cryptographic
algorithm was a proprietary algorithm
was not community review and I've had a
very I'm your
particular structure so-so a I'm
rerouted to design
I'm we cassidy's the strength of this
magnificent
and we publish about well our
observations were the
was a a week cipher design bet you could
the initialization was
was a pretty short also I i'm
invertible so if you abuse at some point
you could you go over to stay internal
saves cipher you could
rollback referring to regional mutual
stage reach
then review the key done
so basically %uh summarizes that
security was significantly lower than
that between size
so there were some implementation states
as well
so there was no randomness from from
within to transform so the chip
basically in the dark
and know what I mentioned before
also the do a secret key updated
was not one up atomic operation so if a
key is stored in multiple memory blocks
are you
update from and you want to update the
Keen
and you have to do multiple rights
operations than
means that the of way at what stage
are you down you don't have a new key
don't have your ski
I'm so so basically this should be one
operation them and while the improper
use by car manufacturers
there are many many chung transponders
were configured
we actually founded in a in and some
experience we did with their with the
default or easy to guess passwords and
and the well the cars were also
some cars Rick figured with weird
weekends
I can imagine if you have a weeki weed
with a
certain parts in the beginning on %um
not really use
and answer be completely drops and you
can find recovered secret can
I'm drastically fast so
room whether the practicality uses a of
this high-tech to redact
I am but there are certain since it is
not
not also opening the cars
there's a lot more infor so based which
have to do is
you communicate with the car can because
you need to identify I showed that the
new beginning that
rescue me tonight and fired to to let a
car
at knowledge from did your known you're
in the white is now
a you have to do that and are therefore
you have to be in close proximity you
for
of your victim than you bypass the
security measures of a car which means
you have to force
locks disable the alarm and
force ignition mark as well because
you're
its just more to heart white stuff no
word
hammer or screwdriver or I'm them when
you
um you have to he's dropped the
immobilizer so that the message is
coming out with a act then a
around ignition lock then again you have
to communicate with the car can you get
because
you it's not enough to miss it too car
needs
messages from key and together you
you can do you could former computer
complex or mathematical computation you
can recover to seek
if you I've done all this so including
going through car
going to Keegan both sides then you can
go back to the car and you can handle a
picky
you can going to start car so basically
this is not really a practical way to
see you car and and
thats at least I wouldn't see I'm
manuscripts 0 our just that that very
briefly
in in this sense I'm
its introduce as well in 995 996 is
around the same miss
the new ones approving previously show
I'm the keel and Wilson 96 bits
so which is pretty good if you see that
you see
96 bits that should be very
strong insensitive of answer
but yeah we identified actually arm
very comparable weaknesses to what we
find in high-tech to
or what are described for I am
the practicality of that Act are really
seen similar in
in in how are you sure you know are you
know you can attack
a I said as we found in the high-tech to
you need the car and you can and do all
the steps
bob is key in this is still deployed in
cars screen
so that let me address the responsible
disclosure part of this
so what what ya let's first arc about
in general how does it work so
what you see you know the jurors in
issue you you identified a weakness
in a product that was there for a long
time and maybe use abuse but
not publicly known an you identify this
problem
and then you notify the problem only the
key problem owner
early on in early stage for you have
factual reasons a a pesky
you help them understand what you saying
because not always the
unionist and artworks
and a you publish them after a delay
sorry if you look at the recommendations
from a few then you have surged
I'm saying forty five days a Google
recommend sixty-day even drop that
I i've seen but yeah understanding a
recommendation is
sixty I guess and and from
at the Dutch government and there there
are some a
recently guidelines from Houston's how
to to handle this kind of
response with disclosure issues and then
they say well you have sixty days
should yes you should be reasonable time
for software
but hardware yeah you not always have
every
are drinking vice easy upgradeable well
nowadays are hardware runs
mostly software and runs firmware or
some other so far apart
but over does not a essentially mean
that is connected to the internet but
you can just
uploads so they say well there's is more
reasonable to give
hard for peace a some longer
ought to give due to manufacture overall
are true peace
longer time to prepare such thing to
prepare a response
and so their guidelines say six months
in a sense
are basically that's also what what we a
I'm
worry for so I am
are responsible disclosure in in this
sense we've done some some work
on on various topics and on
most widely known one mister my for
classic case
where we a we wanted to publish
our findings which we
which was actually contest them in court
by by manufacture an XP
I'm this is our open court case a
and into for texas also just just public
and
they been lost we published after six
months
also relations to very good with an XP
afterwards but it was just your we had
another state of mind at that moment
so well was so moderate samples an
eternity phones from Nokia
I'm in us while we punch up to six
months in in with at my crib to memory
as well published up to six months and
say mister high-tech to paper
last year Republic up to six months and
basically when we notified all the
Spartans
I'm date they contact us within 48 hours
or by a fire phone or or even on our
doorsteps
so
so so it was a real interaction
so up room well there's another thing
I'm
if you find issue a you have some kind
of notification
change because and do
more we learn from previews notify
partners is it actually
they demand for most the day communicate
with their customers
and hat couple resumes a for that
because
unit so we should not talk to them
because are
responder is actually bear
responsibility to do not define it
and a I'm also due to this party said
that
did the do not want to share customer
information with us
and and we not always know the customers
or
arm and also they know exactly who to
contact
so yup we we
we basically agreed them then search
strategies or
that's what we also
I've done since and and also encourage
I'm not to fight party to do
to take responsibility and to share with
the grass missus
quickly as possible so we know 25
a from in america most cases chip
manufacturer in
in twice in 2012
what is your email but we also need to
reduce the vmail
I'm I after a while
we gaming in discussion and we have
quite some collaboration we had a
conference call
several letters and emails personal
meeting
I constructive discussions but now at
the real
customer level Sonus pictured it is that
the car manufacturer you have no comp
were and so I want to address a believe
the reverse engineering
a matters and also related working there
so we have a.m. as a sole what is
possible if you reverse engineer
in you knew a I'm in an output looking
at the black box
you decompile firmware software are you
do to chip slicing
and and there's a quite a new approach
I wanna go BB YouTube i think is
promising
to do they actually need to refer to
side-channel attack
such an analysis so
well observe any input and the output
over
as how can reverse engineering data in
that sense
well bone out all showed that already
and
in here do snakes that a could just
look and set certain from initial state
in a cipher and looked in the
outgoing encryption bits an
it tried to to find a what those
the function that generated we did the
same with there are my for class
paper well we have internal stave
rituals earning your feedback shift
register and we
just puts up some bits there re you flip
the bits and looked in the output and
I'm
tried to fight him balance to a function
and it's a point well you have a bone in
their ways you can just comforting to
have fun
um I was also applied in a in the the
cordless phone
analysis done by your by
by so for people and looks at all
I guess is 10 where the the showed
how to attack the other indication for
Dex cordless phone
so what what to do with the with the
firmware others
for example Houston
a and several other papers and
you have a this paper showing a how how
you can
abuses in a car the I'm
you do so for running in a car and how
you can kind of change or a kinda for in
Jax
and stuff into for Americana some
militia messages
and let the car do several things you
know it should
your users you'd expect from also
demonstrated 2011
very interesting interesting torque I'm
a reason at all show the this Sat phones
aren't really so secure us we think
maybe
and they did by just looking at the
firmware of the Sat phone and the
be compiled with got the the prior
proprietary algorithm out and actually
show that the arguments week
an has several issues security issues
well most recently Miller and a follow a
sec showed in in
Def Con 2013 I'm that they can also do
well you maybe or auction north koreans
research in a data showed you can you
can I'm
actually make debris covered car not
work anymore so you can over ruled the
certain very important
safety features over car
fired you sir electronic Boerse computer
Clark so this this was some
so I there's an then we have to reverse
engineering about chip slicing
and there are several papers using this
this particular way to reverse engineer
and Nessa and Anderson interesting
papers a
pictures America silicon zoo website
showing I'm really how to gates
drink and what the real present & Sons
so term yes there's a the
access to the the mega malls crypto
argument so
it's it's its publicly already
spratt because the be judgment is online
an of the interim injunction
their sources also do we use a tangle
programmer
which offers publicly available I am
so basically by the contains the Megabus
cryptogram
obfuscate not encrypt it but obfuscated
and you guys know im you and I mean by
a non-technical person has quite some
difficult you understand
um it was cold murky but a judge
mmm but yeah surprised us because that's
it available since 2009
and it still busy being distributed as
an official product
answered diagnostic system for car
from car transponders in
what surprise even more hazardous to
many many other sources
available which contains Ogren Witcher
easy access over just an average person
and not protected
nothing cryptic not obfuscate
drive it so publicly available its its
for sprite for us better
was pointedly like this so but then
again
Norris's Megabus cryptogram is actually
already partially
bob's at the I'm challenges to security
engineering you found us a summer school
from
crypt young Crysler big-name star Burke
presented their that he actually reverse
engineer in Megamall scripture chip
for your chip slicing I am
and he showed high resolution pictures
/a
logic gates arm a drawing over schematic
over capone governor a core component of
the manuscript to algorithm
and bus lights are publicly for
downloads
almost a year now
so I'll just goal to mitigation
alternatives
I am there are proposed a
quite something some stuff in the in the
literature and I will not cover it all
I'm so so if you have their room is and
I don't mention with
I'm sorry is not intentionally just
because the slights get to fuhrman
an but the and also the industry has
occurred across from
some impute here there's some
proprietary chips which is a
as a successor I mention them before I
to tree in
and the CAD but they're also
ones that that the band on on opening
crypsis than
like a yes I'm
so what was in there economic literature
nursery required in this one was a
certain
since I think it inspired also
since the the paper from bono at all
because in
from 2005 under just quite some some in
yeah contribution on the by their
academia on this level someone to point
out actually
the other chips from so there's a
high-tech
proline from NXP Semiconductors and
gonna run from Texas Instruments but
those are kind of close I could not find
much information
although the UCAS which is a good thing
I don't know how to use it
and and also yeah it's hard to see
actually
I'm what what do you what to do or
what the want to try to accomplish I'm
in this has actually was surprising to
see that there is a semiconductor
company
Atmel the took a different role and age
a
opened up and they say how we want them
open immobilizer stack
and the risk even saying their data
sheet the the
be wanted been they're designed to be
scrutinized by
my academia or just general public
so it's a it's interesting and it's a
it's also also nice to see that this is
a a contribution
it's arduous already your products which
are
now available for a few years am
I did they basically a your kind of
promotes public evaluation of the
product
so I want to point this out as a
specific a interesting
so the conclusion I'm
yet %uh the moment she has a focus on on
safety which is a good thing of course
because its import that's not enough on
security
and he still use a proprietary in
outdated algorithms
no which could definitely be better
because me learn
a lot already like in the last decades
you should not use that
you and America should consider some
new up dade model like like Patch
Tuesday
an app that uses maybe im been harmed in
a car sense but you can imagine that
when you drive your car for maintaining
into a garage
you can just to a quick update and most
in the car is already running in
in for american just in software
so you can have so for update model
I'm so they see a this is such a
darkens I'm sorry I cannot the answered
any questions from from the audience I'm
but I think we have a very nice lied to
and
and it's our historical claim for the
paper