[Music]
good afternoon and a very warm welcome
to our afternoon panel session on
defending the cyber front with ai
my name is bruce watson and i have the
pleasure in honor of hosting the session
this afternoon
i happen to be a researcher and also a
practitioner in both cyber security
and artificial intelligence and it's my
pleasure to bring to you
a couple of very interesting speakers
this afternoon of course we'd like to
start off just by thanking ccdcoe
for their organization of such a top
shelf conference
it's really outstanding work um so it's
a real pleasure as i said and an honor
to have you with us today
um we know that you had a couple of
choices of different sessions that you
could have attended
and it's very nice that you've chosen to
join us for this one in particular
um in particular if i look at the the
topic area of artificial intelligence
combined with cyber security
it's a very exciting and highly relevant
part of the current cyber security
threat landscape and there are two
sub-topics in particular that we'll be
talking about today that
really mesh with i think the most
advanced topics that occur
within both of these fields the first of
them is
explainable ai so typical artificial
intelligence systems involve
constructing a system
often built from a lot of data these are
so-called training data
that are then used to build an
artificial intelligence model
most typically this is using machine
learning algorithms
and as a result we have an artificially
intelligent system which may be very
narrow
very narrowly focused to the particular
domain but is able to solve particular
problems within that domain
but it doesn't shed any light on the
internal structure of that domain
so in other words the solution is a
black box solution and we don't really
have any deeper understanding of
the structure of the cyber security
threats so it eventually becomes
important to be able to gain that deeper
understanding and to really be able to
understand
why the system is making certain
decisions that it does
and this would lead us to wanting a kind
of system that's a so-called glass box
system
or an openly explainable ai system now
it turns out that such systems are
exactly the holy grail of the artificial
intelligence research
so as desirable as they are it's an
extremely difficult technical problem to
solve and a vast number of researchers
are working on this worldwide
so we'll have the pleasure of talking a
little bit about one of those in a
particular
subdomain today which is very important
progress
the other one of course is as mentioned
autonomous system so
along with explainable ai we would also
like to be able to have autonomous
artificially intelligent systems and i'm
not talking here about
offensive uh systems but autonomous
defensive systems that can take care of
certain aspects of cyber security all on
their own without human intervention
and this is then something that of
course provokes a large amount of
international debate it has an ethics
component to it as well which is
uh is something that makes the news very
very quickly
and so it's a pleasure today to also
hear from one of the speakers
about recent work in uh towards autonomy
of such cyber defensive system
so that um coupled with explainable ai
will be the
two axes of the research that we
discussed today
so let me get to the two uh speakers
these are two speakers that you probably
will recognize from
from previous years the first one is
arthur's lathrunov
and the second one is roland mayer and
you can of course read about their
biographies within the uh the
proceedings
and on the website of cycon 2021 but in
a nutshell arters is a researcher at
nato's ccdcoe
he's got a strong interest in web and
network technologies
he's been working on of course cyber
exercises
locked shields in particular and he
spent some time also teaching at the
university of latvia which happens to be
where he is
currently a phd candidate working on his
dissertation
our second speaker today i also have the
pleasure of introducing is then roland
mayer and we'll be getting to him as our
second speaker
roland is also involved as a phd
candidate in this particular case in
electronic engineering
and information technology at eth in
surrey
and his interests are in security of
computer networks of course like many of
us as well
but he has a particular interest in
being able to use and leverage recent
advances
in software-defined networking and
programmability of networking
and he happens to have have obtained his
master's degree
at eth tsurig in the same department as
well so he's
very much at home in this kind of
research so
let me get to the format of today's talk
because i think you're not here to
necessarily hear me talk but
rather hear the the two viewpoints um of
our speakers
and we'll be able to return to a
discussion afterwards as well
so we're going to be starting off with
arthur in just a moment before going on
to
roland and i would very much like you to
already as we proceed to think about
particular questions you may have
it allows the questions if you pose them
soon enough to filter through to us and
to order the questions
so that we either discuss some of them
in between the two talks
or so that we could return to them in
the larger discussion at the end
now in the event of course that you're
watching this after the fact in the
archived version
of this session please feel free to
email us
we're very happy to engage on this topic
after the fact as well so without me
taking up more of our time
let me please turn it over to artur he's
going to be discussing explainable ai
in a particular problem subdomain thank
you please begin arthur
thank you for introduction and today we
are going to
to discuss one very let's say
specific topic and the specific topic is
classifying devices on the internet and
we will go into detail why it's
important later on but
uh currently we are trying to combine
expert knowledge and let's say research
knowledge and
my co-author is dr roman graf he has
been
in saigon for for many years
and when we started few years ago this
research he was
a full-time ai researcher in
austrian institute of technology and now
he is transferring his knowledge to
to private sector into accenture
so what's what is the problem
so the problem we have a lot of device
on the internet in reality there are
billions upon billions and
predictions say that in a
few years we would talk about 10 billion
or 20 billion of devices
so what kind of devices are these
so we are particularly interested in two
reachable devices what does reachable
means
means it's listening on one or more
ports
and this traffic is directly routed to
this device instead of being dropped
somewhere
so anyone can send
a packet on particular port to this
device and this device will process it
if anyone can send something anyone
can send malicious payload
uh maybe this device is vulnerable
maybe not if it's not vulnerable it
might become vulnerable in three years
when it's still connected in same way so
this is
kind of a huge problem and there are few
causes for it
first and foremost manufacturers
we see even today manufacturers
selling devices selling cheap devices
for
10 20 30 euros that does
some function in your home
some iot devices and
they have insecure default configuration
and some
some states are trying to battle it with
some regulation
but we are far from solution an insecure
default configuration would mean
uh the stuff that should
be listening only internally is
listening to the internet so this is
the easiest way uh we have seen
through our research a lot of vendors a
lot of
solution vendors that buy devices in
bulk
and develop solutions from them and
deploy in in homes
or in commercial organizations
and they have
some remote administration or remote
services that this vendor can support it
and if it turns out this vulnerability
then anyone can compromise these devices
and maybe all devices by a specific
vendor
and users of course users often
plug something in a way it shouldn't be
plugged
they click some settings that should
shouldn't be clicked and they
expose themselves to the internet and
this
is this is extremely common
or maybe there is solution to vulnerable
or reachable
stuff and user just
does not update software and we should
look into mirror and
and ask ourselves when was the last time
we updated software to our routers
or our iit devices or something
and and the answer usually is never
and what is the result result from many
billions there are hundreds of millions
hundreds of millions of reachable
devices on on one or more protocols
and in reality
maybe few millions are actually needed
few millions which provide
function on a network or on the internet
to the public
and that's all or we need some kind of
direct access without
cloud intermediary that is also a valid
valid use case
but do we really
want our network router to be
compromised if we are end user
and if our network router is compromised
it's
it's it's bad it means that any
any malicious actor can do anything to
us
steal our data inject some data in jet
malware so a lot of bad things happen
because everything flows through network
routers
and individual devices or set of devices
it does not even need to be individual
affects the whole regions i mean we saw
uh just uh just recently uh
fuel shortage because of hakka attack
it does not necessarily mean that this
was the cause but
we can expect that anything that is
exposed to the internet
might be compromisable we might lose
power we might lose
water we might lose fuel so
there are no good scenarios for that
case
and besides being compromised of course
there are other
other risks risks that there are
reflector software running that could be
sending
traffic uh to some victims
and and
[Music]
contribute to the problem or maybe there
is some proxy service running and
and the fraudsters use it to conceal
identity and use clean ip address so
many many options
so
what what is the current state or state
few years ago or even a decade or two
ago so
classification of devices is is very
old topic it's after internet appeared
with these consumers and commercial
organizations
the classification is under is under
let's say research topics and
we might know shodhan we might know
census these are huge
huge indexes of all devices on different
protocols
and you can click a categories there and
what will happen
will happen that there are limited set
of static rules usually few thousand
maybe
ten thousand and accordance to these
rules
the devices are kind of split around
and the issue with that is that um
of devices increases so there are more
and more devices from more manufacturers
every day there are more more different
ones
and it is not feasible
to to write manually
a lot of rules it's just it's it's
extremely complicated
and it operates on a data
that is usually referred as as banner
grabbing
and what it means it just means sending
a packet or two and receiving the answer
with some kind of
welcome message or some kind of
debugging message
so and and parse and process that
and it is perfect if if the rules match
it's perfect
it's fastest most efficient
classification way
except if no rule matches properly
then we can't classify device at all and
because of the variance of the devices
increasing
it's it's a huge problem and manual
classification
which is also quite quite common
if we have individual device uh it might
take
one minute or it may take an hour at
least it might take few days
but if there is some way to for it to be
classified
usually with active probing and
enumeration and
stuff like that an expert can achieve
high accuracy but i mean only for a few
individual devices
so as bruce mentioned
this is holy grail of of
application is a cyber security domain
because cyber expertise is common you
can take a person
from the university and it will and he
will instantly become
an expert it's it takes years it takes a
lot of
financial resources so to train an
expert
and keep him
without leaving so this is a huge
problem and
these experts are in high demand and
what we want we want to replicate
ideally we want to replicate experts
knowledge
and this is very let's say far away goal
we can't really do it
right now but what we can do we can
start
replicating some of the expertise
some some topic where there is knowledge
where there is intuition
we can work with experts to to define
this and
and train some machine learning
classifiers to to work on this
and even some some adoption would
decrease expenses and increase overall
security
so ai for device classification is not
this year's topic this topic is three
four years old when different teams
around the world started working on it
and there are two directions it's either
reachable devices
meaning the ones were discussed or there
are traffic flows
means there is you need some special
privileges
to to observe in a specific network
point
the traffic and and classify it
passively
and what is our goal our goal
is to close the gap between static
classification static rules and expert
classification
and
what we want to do we want to classify
large sets with expert accuracy this
hasn't been done ever and until few
years ago
and you want to classify individual
devices instantaneously now if you want
to classify individual device you need
an expert
you need many hours possibly
and here we could do it
cheaply and
quickly so
a year ago in cycon we presented our
our own research from this field and
we used the artificial neural network
we selected features we
we explained classes we explained
statistics so
if you are interested in this topic this
is introductory paper for it
and and now we build on top of it
so the challenges are extremely similar
to
to anything in
ai research it's labeling training set
and in this specific case
the rules become conflicting the more
you create rules the more conflicts you
find
and it means they become more complex
and more
uh longer and and slower so
you can't reasonably uh classify
by defining few thousand rules manually
it's just
after that few thousand it's it becomes
one
one device or a few hundred devices but
we are talking about sets of
hundreds of millions you can't really
match
everything and there are automation
approaches which are
which are great and there are research
that produced hundreds of thousands of
rules
but they produced it
in a way that every rule needs
to be manually verified to trust them
and
and they did not have resources we don't
have resources to
expertly analyze hundreds of thousands
of rules
so what is next
it's accuracy because
it is easy to show high accuracy
and it is somehow easy to achieve high
accuracy
and the question then becomes if you
have high accuracy
is it really high accuracy and this is
a kind of problem of misclassification
if we if we
look at the problem artificial neural
networks are black boxes so
we can't really figure out what is
happening
and what is the solution solution is
uh no what is challenges challenges are
that
every research in this topic claims uh
accuracy between
80 to 97 which is which is great
but if you start randomly sampling
and provide this to expert
he might question it and that is that is
the problem with every research
currently
available so the great example
that has been publicized
is there there are ics devices many ics
devices in many data centers so
why and it's it's it's
easy to answer from an expert position
expert says
either it's honeypot or there are some
ics devices needed for supporting data
center
it's and some other versions but
it sounds
easy but
why did it mass misclassify because
it's not trained properly maybe we need
to add extra features like data centers
data center identification maybe
the labeling maybe the labeling rules or
or
label creation was was poor quality
because
it's a huge manual labor and let's say
experts or
or top-level scientists don't have time
to deal with it
maybe features were poorly extracted so
there are a lot of a lot of questions
and what is the solution
okay
so first we do not know what is the
problem
because as we discussed it's a black box
we don't know what's happening
and if we don't know what's happening we
can't really fix anything
uh so what's the problem with
specifications so
in research it is okay to have bad
results
in science same so
we always want the best but we will take
anything
and if we can provide next year or few
years later
better results better accuracy this is
perfectly fine
this is this is research if you look at
let's say industry or cyber defense
trustworthiness is a huge huge problem
and i'm ignoring adversaries i'm just
talking about current state
let's let's take one scenario one
scenario there is
data flow this is data flow is malicious
it's encrypted so we don't really know
what's happening and it's fine to have a
encrypted traffic so classifier
misclassifies it and 97 seems good well
uh we have 600 flows
or 30 flows and and one malicious flow
so this malicious law let's say goes
through the accuracy
and of course you need defined policy
and this policy states that
let's say it's okay to have encrypted
traffic to web
but it's not okay to have encrypted
traffic to other places
and we misclassified our data got
exfiltrated
so false negative of not blocking single
instance
is catastrophic it's like it's a complex
solution and we are
kind of in in a problematic state
so and false negat false positive well
there is some usability issue but it's
it's perfectly fine so
how can we solve it
so solution is explainable ai
and it's uh by
let's say workflow and development it's
it's the same
as almost all other machine learning
classifiers so
uh what is different we different is
that we use
uh naive bias class model and
we use lime lime
framework for explanation so otherwise
it looks the same as as many other
work workflows for for research
so let's let's look at some some
examples what is our current state some
random devices so
what what does explainable ai really
provides it
it provides us different weights for
classes so highest weight is chosen
for classification outcome and it
provides us
weights for features and
weights could be positive could be
negative
so what would what would this
explanation
mean is for this device it would be
that it's a it's a spa device which is
quite common for
likely disc or something that we train
so
this is for every specific device we
have different
different weights so
the same the same let's say features
might have different weights for
for different devices in the same class
so this is kind of normal
and
so let's look at the printer but the
printer says that it's uh
hp we all know hp we know office jet
so this is perfectly fine and
what's interesting that there are let's
say some keywords
and some features from many different
places including autonomous systems so
the finance the finance feature is uh
is a from network name so so financial
institutions have more let's say
printers and
than other ones iot device
so interestingly for iot device
security headers are uh
kind of negatively weighted so iot
device
by our our model have much much less
security features and if there are
security features it's less likely to be
an iot device
interestingly there are specific devices
in austria
so a country code or
network name would is weighted for this
specific device which is actually
located in austria
positively
so infrastructure devices meaning
controlling
uh some kind of network or some other
non-ics features
and here we have a vmware horizon device
and it's it's quite
easily classified by a static rule so
nothing let's say surprising here
for ics device it is extremely
interesting as we see here are so little
features
so many features where
let's say filtered out by us as a noise
and what is left is is extremely
uh limited only for four features
and the analyzed analyzer it's
it's a spectrum analyzer but spectrum is
also let's say a network name for
in usa so it is weighted negatively in
this case because it's a consumer
network with not
really many ics devices
so network devices so
what do we see we see that if it's in
gateway
then it's it's likely a network device
while there are possibly other type of
of network devices
and
we have we have specific incorrect
let's say incorrect login or incorrect
name for a huge number of devices and
for this case
it is weighted as a heavy feature
for ib cameras we have heat vision it is
only software that is
dnr the and there is webs
it's only software that is that is used
in
in equation and no
other device classes uses it so it's
it's obviously
the highest weighted feature and it
would be the classified same way by an
expert
uh for for web server it's
it's quite clear that if we have apache
it's likely a
normal web server if we have uh
some kind of documentation description
it's it's a default installation
without virtual host name so this is
kind of
kind of normal and unclear
this and clear and categorized devices
these are devices that are
extremely hard to explain because what
we see
the features are very generic
and nothing is let's say weighted in
a in a highly positive way that is that
is
that could be classified by an expert
even
so overall what we see we see that
over the three years surprisingly ics
devices are
are in increasing numbers it's these are
low
impact devices but steals their ics we
have
infrastructure decrease iot is stable
which is great because
number of i.t devices increase but the
percentage stays the same
network devices are in decrease so this
is this is great
because network devices are the ones
that everyone has
in their homes where the cable internet
cable connects to
and ipip covers are stable
in decrease so there are more cloud
cloud cameras available
so future works is just to move on and
analyze misclassifications because now
we are transferring
our knowledge between uh
model and expert so now experts are
learning
how the ai thinks next step is to
transfer the knowledge back to
to ai and then we will see how how can
we improve it
okay thank you
so thanks very much arthur i really
appreciate that talk and i'm sure the
audience does as well
um i don't see immediately that they're
questions we should deal
with at this moment and so we'll move on
because i think you've given us enough
food for a thought for the discussion at
the end and i'd like to start off then
immediately with roland if we may and
roland is going to be talking about
um an ai powered game player for cyber
defense exercises
and it's worth noting that artur is
actually also a co-author on that paper
so we can clearly see there's a lot of
crossover research that gets involved
here
so roland if we may switch to you thank
you
thank you and i'm happy to present our
work
on this ai powered cyber defense
player this is as you already mentioned
it's a
joint work with art tour as well as
chemo heinrich from uh
gcd coe and luca gambati and vance
landers from arma swiss
to start let's let's imagine your your
job is
to mitigate two and a half thousand
attacks against about four thousand
systems that you're managing
so this sounds like a quite a stressful
job but in the end is basically what the
blue team members at log shields
need to do every year log shields this
is the world's largest
cyber defense exercises takes place
every year in talling
and it is a so called red team vs blue
team
exercise this means that there is a red
which usually which consists of the
attackers
and there are many blue teams which are
the defenders and usually there is
one blue team for each participating
country
we started to look at this exercise from
a research
perspective some years ago already and
if you
maybe some of you remember two years ago
i was presenting
a paper describing a system where
the collaborators and i we developed a
system
that could identify commander control
channels in the environment of this log
shields exercise
and we've shown that actually a fairly
simple classifier is enough
to detect large parts of the commander
control channels
and we also confirmed with the swiss
team which was participating at this
exercise
that this system actually works in
practice and
it was beneficial to them
for this year the colleagues as i
mentioned the beginning
and i we were thinking about one step
going one step further
and this time we don't just want to
provide some automated tools that the
blue team
can use to have
some more automation inside the team but
we want to have
a fully automated blue team so that's a
blue team where there is no human labor
required anymore instead everything is
fully automated
and the question that we answer in our
paper and in this presentation
is what would it take to have such an
fully automated plutine in the
presentation in the paper
i will present you the architecture that
we envision how such an automated
team could be implemented and the
component
which of which it is consisting
i will not be able to present your full
implementation or results
this is not in the scope of this paper
but we hope to inspire other people
and we ourselves we will be working on
this
more in the future and hopefully end up
with such an automated team
in a couple of years in a future
iteration of lock sheets
so when we want to automate a blue team
what would it
mean actually for this let's first look
at
the tasks that such a blue team would
need to perform
first at the very high level the task of
a blue team
is to defend its network so the
network usually reserves
spoken of as the game net is consisting
of
many different types of devices this can
be different workstations
with different operating systems with
different versions
uh client servers providing different
services
but also iot devices and
ics devices and some other special
devices
including things like drones and the
blue team
then needs to defend this network
against attacks
it does so in usually three main
steps first it needs to perform initial
hardening which means
to get familiar with the environment
with the network
and do some configuration changes such
that the systems
are more robust against attacks then
when the attack starts
the main task is mitigating these
attacks and restoring systems that have
been compromised
and at the same time the blue team also
needs to communicate
with other teams over predefined
channels
now this communication is maybe not so
hard for a human team
if we are speaking about a fully
automated team this will be
more involved of course and
communication here means
essentially for maintaining four
different
communication channels the first and
probably most important one is with the
so-called user simulation team
this is a team consisting of people that
simulate
real users so these are people that
would access websites that are hosted in
the game net
or send emails over the game net and so
on and if something is not working as
expected
they send a support ticket to the blue
team telling them hey
this is not working please fix it then
there is a
yellow team to which a blue team needs
to provide periodic reports about
the current status of the network and
successful and failed attacks
there is a wide team that uses voice and
video video calls
through the game net and there is the
green team providing information about
the current status
from a scoring perspective and it
provides services such as the reworking
of devices to the initial state
the exercise itself can be seen as
happening with four different stages
the first one that i already mentioned
this is
what is called initial hardening here
the
blue team typically prepares the system
such that they are robust against the
attacks which are
starting afterwards then there is the
monitoring and response phase in which
the
red team starts attacking and the blue
team needs to respond
by blocking the attacks or recovering
systems that are
compromised at the same time the blue
team also needs
to do this reporting that i mentioned to
other
teams for example the support tickets or
the reports about the status of the game
network
and also if nothing else helps there is
a
recovery stage where the system can
restore compromised systems either the
blue team can restore compromised
systems
either from its own backups or from the
initial
stakes that was provided from the
exercise organization
now looking at the framework that we
developed at a very high level
it looks quite straightforward we have
three components
one is input the other one is control
and the third one is output
looking at it a bit more closely the
input is what we call sensors
and these are basically components that
provides data
wherever one can collect data this can
be network traffic it can be event locks
monitoring information support tickets
or the credentials to access all the
devices
on the other side we have the output
which we call actuators and these are
components
that allow to perform some actions in
the
exercise environment it can be the
remote management of devices it can be
changing firewall rules resetting
devices sending
chat messages and writing the
reports towards the other teams in the
middle
we have more of the intelligence
consisting
first of a situational awareness
database which
consists which contains all the
information that we have somewhere
an ai engine which trains machine
learning models for example and the
control logic
which connects the information that is
there with the actions that should be
taken
and in the remaining of the presentation
i will now go in more detail
into all of these building blocks and in
the end i will show a little case study
with a concrete
example of a problem that might occur
and how
this automated team could handle it
so let's look at the sensors first
sensors can be placed at five different
positions first we consider
organizational inputs
everything that is provided from the
exercise organization
but this is for example the topology of
the network or the device credentials
then we have network sensors which
provide information about
the network device sensors providing
information about all the devices
connected to the network
application level centers which provide
information about running applications
and finally user interaction sensors
which
receive all the information provided by
the users of the system
so i will provide a few examples now for
each
of these types of senders
organizational inputs these are
as i mentioned things like the system
documentation
the devices and the services that are
running in the game
and that should be kept running um
it could include the credentials to
access and configure all these devices
it includes information about the
scoring rules that basically define the
blue team what it should do in order to
perform well
and it includes information about the
external monitoring about
which is essentially the current
performance that the
blue team is achieving at the current
course that it gets
second we have the application sensors
which receive
information about each running
application such as for example for a
database application
it can be the users and their
permissions what they can do in the
application
and it also can receive information
about the application state
such as the update status and all kinds
of log files
similar for the device sensors which
report
device wide information such as the
operating system that
is running device-wide logs such as the
people who are trying to log into the
system
and it can include additional monitoring
systems such as screen capture or
basically whatever
the blue team wants to deploy
then next we have the network sensors
which on one hand provide information
about the network configuration and the
state
this includes like file things like
firewall rules the topology of the
network the lows that the network is
currently
experiencing and whether all the links
are up
but most importantly it also allows
access to all the traffic that is
exchanged in the network and this
traffic can be captured and further
analyzed in other
systems for example to detect malicious
connections there
finally the user interaction sensors
these are mostly about
interacting with the user simulation
team and the support tickets that it
creates
so we move on to the next building block
of our framework this is what we call
the actuators
and similar to the sensors we groove
them into four
categories for network level device
level
application level and user interaction
actuators
again i will provide a few examples for
application level actuators we see
for example application firewalls that
could be deployed such as a web
application firewall that
inspects all the requests to our website
such application actuators
can change the configuration of an of an
application for example which user
can perform which actions inside a
database application for example
and it can such an actuator can also
install
patches to fix known vulnerabilities to
the application
on the device level we see the main
purpose of
an device level actuators in doing
remote management ideally over multiple
channels such that if
one of the management channels is
compromised from the right team there is
still a way to access
all the devices and another purpose of
device level actuators would be
to restore a previous state of a device
either the state that it had
before the exercise started or from a
backup that the blue team
created beforehand
the network level actuators these are
mostly about
changing the network configuration and i
think the most important part there
would be
to change firewall rules that define
what kind of traffic is allowed to go
through the network at which point
the user interactions user interaction
actuators then
would provide information to the users
for example through chat and email
messages which respond to the support
tickets that we mentioned
and they could generate the incident
reports about successful or failed
attacks and
also provide them to the green team
so that brings us already to the next
component which is the situational
awareness database
here it's fairly simple this is just the
collection of all the information that
we have somewhere it's all the
data that we receive from the sensors
all the ai models that we train and
which i will go into details in a second
all the outputs that we send to the
actuators and also external information
such as
known software vulnerabilities or
signatures of known malware for example
speaking about the ai engine here
we distinguish between four levels
of ai that could be there the very the
most basic
level is what we call reactive narrow ai
and this is just simple
these are just simple signature based
decisions so taking a signature of a
file and comparing it
to a list of known malware signatures
for example
level one is called limited memory
narrow ai
and this is typically what this meant
with machine learning
today so this is taking a data set
extracting
some models from it and applying these
models to potentially other data sets
in a supervised or unsupervised or
semi-supervised way
more sophisticated would be level two
which is at the same level as human
intelligence
or even more sophisticated level three
which
surpasses human intelligence but of
course these
two upper levels they don't really exist
today and if they would exist
we probably don't would not need to
define this architecture because the ai
would already do it for us
so we focus in the paper and also in
this presentation
on level zero and level one
for these types of ai that
one could do we identify five different
tasks that for which it could be used
first it could be used for
identification and classification
which answers the question of what is it
a certain object
so for example if the object is a
support ticket
the identification could say it's a
support ticket complaining about
email is not working then categorization
would answer the question what belongs
together if there are money support
tickets
complaining about the same problem it
could determine that all these support
tickets
complaining about problems with the mail
server
assessment would tell whether it's
important so whether
the blue team should care about these
problems with the main server
recommendation would recommend something
to be done
for example restart the mail server and
prediction would answer the question
what will happen if we perform this
action for example what
what would be the impact on our scoring
if we restart
the email server
and i will now provide more examples for
these ai tasks in all the four stages of
the exercise
i will only mention some individual
examples here
if you want to have the full table with
all the tasks all the faces and many
more examples
please have a look at the paper in the
initial hardening phase for example
a categorization problem could be to
find groups of similar devices that
should be treated
in a similar way afterwards in the
monitoring and response phase
the classification problem would be to
detect malicious network traffic
this is basically what we did in this
paper two years ago where we
classified between b9 and malicious
commander control
network traffic or a categorization
problem here would be to detect
malicious patterns in log files
the reporting phase it's all about
providing
human readable reports so the
categorization here
could group support tickets together
with monitoring alerts so people
complaining about email
is not working and the monitoring alerts
saying that the mail server is down
a categorization system could
determine that these two types of
information are belonging together then
in the assessment
an assessment problem would be to
prioritize the most important support
ticket
recommendation to formulate a response
to them
and prediction again the for example the
impact that this response has on the
scoring
in the recovery stage then
classification
problem would be to find devices that
need to be
recovered because they are compromised
and the categorization problem
would be to find similar devices that
might
uh act as a template for recovery so if
for example on one windows device a file
is corrupted
then maybe one can take the same file
from another
machine and use this as a template for
recovering
the file on the corrupted machine
so that's about ai the last
block is the control logic which
connects all the information that we
have
with the actions that the
blue team would take again we're looking
at the four phases of the exercise here
first in the initial hardening the
control logic would probably
determine to deploy additional software
such as
application firewalls anti-virus
software or additional monitoring agents
and it could install some patches that
such at all software is on the
is up to date and it could change all
the passwords to have a
pure initial configuration of all the
devices
in the monitoring and response phase it
would
disable exploited services when the
when a model for example says that the
service is most likely exploited
then the control logic could disable it
it would monitor and block malicious
system calls and to say monitor and
block
malicious network traffic on the two
different levels
for reporting it would generate the
human readable
reports either periodically for the
bluet for the green team
or when there is a request a support
ticket from the user simulation team
finally in the recovery phase the
control logic could try to do
self-recovery if there is a
backup from from previously
or it can revert the devices to the
initial state
over the exercise organization which
would
which would result also in a penalty in
the scoring
so that's basically all
for the components of this framework in
the last part
i would like to show a small case study
which connects all the things that we've
seen before with one concrete example
and the example here is that a user
receives a link
clicks on this link downloads a
malicious file and executes this file
and this is by the way something that
this user simulation team
would do and could be a problem for the
blue team of course
so what can we do against this or what
could
the automated blue team do against this
in the initial hardening phase
first it might configure all the clients
to send http
traffic via proxy such that this proxy
can inspect the traffic
second it could enable detailed logging
about files that are opened or executed
on a device
and third it could set up the recording
of all network traffic
and extract meaningful features from it
then when the attack happens or the
the user downloads the file there are
the three levels at which
this uh attack or the potential attack
could be detected
first the proxy can detect that there is
a malicious payload that the user tries
to download
second the logging could report that
a user tries to execute a potentially
malicious file
and third the network sniffer would
detect that
device is trying to establish a
connection to a commander control
server and in all of these three states
the system could act react accordingly
it could remove the malicious payload
block the execution of the file or drop
the
traffic towards the commander control
server
for reporting the system can take the
information that it has
the ip address from the web server where
the file was downloaded
maybe the name of the user the type of
the malware
the ip address of the commander control
server that was um
that he was trying to connect and so on
and compile all of this
into human readable report
if the detection of the malware was not
successful then
the automated blue team could restore a
device
to a state before the malware was
downloaded
so with this i'm coming to the end
of the presentation what i presented you
today is this
framework that we think would enable an
automated blue team
in some future iteration of log shields
what i didn't present
is an implementation of this or results
this is because
these parts are future work and um
we don't think that it will be easy but
do
we definitely think it would be
interesting to compare
the performance of such an automated
team with the
highly professional blue team members in
the normal
human teams so hopefully this
presentation
also inspired some people to work on
that as well
for example also merging
existing work which ex which there is
many
into this framework and implementing the
missing pieces and the links between all
the components
of course the same framework could be
adapted for other exercises
and it could even be adapted to real
world cyber defense even though i think
they're the work that would need to be
done is
is much much higher than to just try it
in an exercise environment
so with this i'm at the end of the
presentation
thank you all for your attention and if
there are questions i'm happy to take
them
so roland thanks very much you really
shed a lot of light on
what i think is is one of the the core
issues that we all face within cyber
defense and of course arthur's as you
know
uh you shed a lot of light on on some of
the other details which are
very much a pleasure to hear about so um
before i even get to some of the other
questions that we can formulate i have
questions already coming in
and this one is directed to you artur if
you can please provide more details on
how the data sets were collected
in particular because so many new
devices are connected to the internet
how feasible is it to develop a machine
learning classification model that can
actually be used in real life
so i think this is then the core
question that that we often see from
from machine learning would you like to
comment on that article
yeah yeah this is this is a great
question and i
maybe did not have enough time to
explain it in detail
so i mentioned that like
variance or heterogeneity of devices
increase and this is
this has been happening all the time but
now it's happening exponentially like
anyone can make a device and anyone can
redefine some some properties so
from let's say some kind of
static static rules they seem completely
new device
and this is actually the reason for
for this and previous research that
this amount of increasing devices
actually hurt static rules much more
so static rules can't make a good guess
if for the for the new devices
what we see is that
like our models that we are using for
three years
we are kind of uh we are getting
some results some guesses and these
guesses are are
quite quite good in in the time but the
issue is that
of course we need to retrain the model
every every year every half year so so
this is a problem we need an expert to
classify training sets and it is kind of
time consuming and expensive
and
was there any other part for the
question no no i i think actually you
touch on a very important uh question if
i can
take it in a different direction then
arthur thanks very much for that
because you you connect with the issue
of having a human in the loop
and this is of course very important for
retraining models periodically and for
monitoring models as well
so i would like to uh in the time
remaining maybe just make one
research statement and we can see if
this research statement resonates with
you we'll go first
to roland in a moment uh but the
statement is that ai
engines really are the only feasible way
for cyber defenders
to keep up with cyber attacks and cyber
attackers just the pace of development
and a kind of entropy argument that it's
easier to break things than to
fix and defend things furthermore i
would say that explainable ai
is perhaps um imperative for humans to
in a sense accept autonomous ai systems
so uh rolling we'll go to you first but
i'd like to
just hear if you can connect that back
to whether your work is maybe a jumping
off point for autonomous full defense
systems
and we'll unfortunately have to keep the
answers short thank you roland
yes so i think certainly automation is
definitely needed for cyber defense in
the future more and more
um whether it's only this fully
automated
ai i think maybe in the long distance
yes
i think it still has a lot of problems
especially if you take it outside of the
exercise environment that i was speaking
of
if you see what r2 was mentioning with
the
lack of transparency in many cases of
that people don't know what the
ai is deciding and why so i would for
quite some time
i would expect not
not the full trust in these ai
only approaches and
yeah but in the long run i think we are
moving towards
more and more automation can be seen at
some point as on the ai
very much agreed also from my side but
maybe that becomes a good connection
back to artur if we can uh
in the in the short time remaining
briefly um
if you could say something about you
know whether
you always see a human in the loop for
this or self retraining and self
monitoring is part of the future
so the question it what follows uh
explainable ai because
i think maybe something will follow
something something better
at the moment it
it it does not work without experts
things change
inputs change and i see automation in
this type of research and this
automation is completely
not transparent so if there are
training sets with hundreds of thousands
of of devices or hundreds of thousands
with rules and this is obviously made by
some kind of automation
and this automation is is not clear so
expert is always
important and regarding uh
the only way to defend that is
ai or machine learning in in my research
context
it is a matter of time before
adversaries will use
device classification to find
compromisable devices
so we as researchers have to use it
quicker
and remediate these devices this is kind
of the problem
indeed thanks very much arthur and i
regret that we have to end the session
there it's
such a pleasure starting a discussion
like this and i think we'll hear more
about that
before i close off briefly i'd like to
very quickly mention that we'll have a
20-minute break now
after which at 17 hours 20 italian time
you may join the discussion on the stage
one
and that's going to be the eu challenges
and outlook for cyber security in the
digital decade
so please join us there in closing i
would like to thank you the audience
everyone listening and of course
you arter and roland for your excellent
work and presentations and of course the
discussion
and i look forward to hearing from you
next time thank you
[Music]
you