[Music]
welcome back
we hope that you enjoyed the sessions
and the break up next is a panel on the
impact of disinformation on societies
and alliances
moderated by major jessica dawson from
the army cyber institute at west point
please jessica the stage is all yours
[Music]
good evening i'm excited to be here and
introduce our panel on disinformation
we know that disinformation and
deception have always been part of
military operations
but recently with the scale and speed of
social media pouring an accelerant on an
already burning flame
disinformation has created an underlying
existential crisis
not but just for militaries but for
alliances and more broadly the societies
that form the basis of these alliances
this panel will discuss the impact of
disinformation on these alliances
on public conceptions of trust and
military operations as well as to
discuss proposed solutions
our panelists are a diverse group of
individuals from a variety of
backgrounds
miss lydia snyder is the special
assistant to lieutenant general fogarty
at the army cyber
uh center at fort gordon and advises him
on the social media disinformation
environment and
information operations more broadly
professor dana weinberg is a professor
of sociology and data science at queen's
college
city university of new york and the
director of the new war research
consortium
which focuses on the role of narratives
and disinformation
and last but definitely not least mr
janis sartz
the director of the nato strategic
communications center of excellence
which has been on the front lines of the
information war since its most recent
inception in the online world
[Music]
since the disinformation wars have been
heating up with governments using
disinformation to control their own
populations as well as so discord abroad
i'd like each of the panelists to start
by telling us what they see as the main
challenge of disinformation
please tell us a little bit of how you
view the disinformation problem and
tell us something unique that we might
not have thought about um
lydia would you start us off uh yes
thank you very much for having me and
thank you everyone for being here today
um i think the fundamental problem with
disinf
the fundamental challenge with myth and
disinformation is actually
just humanity we've had this problem
since we i think probably invented
language
if you look back at history you know the
salem witch trials that was
missing disinformation issue the fact
that iceland and greenland are named as
they are was an effort to get people
you know to keep one keep people from
going one and
going from one going to the other the
fact that we think that
napoleon was short he was actually five
seven that was actually
a campaign run a long campaign run
to try to discredit him so this has been
a
component of the human experience the
thing that makes it
the particular challenge now is our
technology
is the connectivity the fact that
those incidents and and the way it used
to be was
little ponds right it was sort of in a
village in a region
um more confined now with our technology
it can spread worldwide very quickly
and the other challenge with it is that
it
another component of the human ex
the factor of human excuse me the
feature of it as a human
just a component of humanity is that it
is profitable
the macedonian kids figure that out
pretty early when they were creating
their
uh articles just to make
just to get clicks the the interesting
miss and disinformation were the ones
that were profitable that that you know
the
they used to say that a lie gets around
the world before the truth gets their
boots on
but now it's the you know the lie does
three laps and becomes a conspiracy
theory before boot
you know truth has even gotten her feet
on the ground so
it's humans we've always done this
our technology has expanded it it is
profitable
and now the technology is designed to
continue to spread what is profitable
and unfortunately miss disinformation
is right so humans are going to come up
with this stuff
the technology helps spread it
and helps actually corral people
into it even more so it's a
complex challenge of just humans and
then we create a technology
that really accelerates it the thing
that
surprised me when i first started in
this space
was that edward berniers i don't some
people on this
conference may know that name if you
don't it's really interesting to go take
a take a look at it
he actually was both the father of
psyops and of marketing
and they run on very similar techniques
and i'm coming from the marketing world
and i learned the techniques through
marketing
you know it takes eight to ten touches
to move someone's opinion and to move
them to the action that you want
saturate their world with your their
message figure out what keeps them up at
3am
and message to that and then i
discovered psyops and
oh gosh they do the same thing and what
happened was
he actually invented these concepts in
world war one
and then after the war he needed a job
so he did
his book called propaganda which is very
similar to machiavelli's
book and that it was a job it was it was
a resume
so he was helping american companies
understand the value of communicating to
the masses
the messaging that you want and if you
look at the
original large companies of america
procter
gamble ge uh general motors they were
all his
first clients and you can really see the
effectiveness of it
as i took a look at it i realized
marketers
we have been
running information operations campaigns
on the general human population psy
operas did it
militarily and meanwhile marketing has
been
using you know the the whole of humanity
whole society
as a test you know as the test lab
and what happened with social media and
i'm coming from that world
is what ended up happening was a
an accelerated test lab where you can do
a b testing
in a short amount of time and you can
find out what worked what didn't work
and you can
quickly alter your messaging
to make it more effective and what we
ended up having was
a laboratory to really be able to hone
and create like ultimate information
weaponry
and really take how to manipulate
human perception to the next level so
i highly recommend studying bernays and
um starting to study marketing books
because
the two converge thank you yeah i think
it
it's really interesting that you point
out that this is just one giant lab
right chris wiley says when they were
building
some of the foundational work at
cambridge analytica they were trying to
build you know society in silica right
they wanted to replicate society and
silicon and do testing
and they realized they didn't have to
replicate anything they had access
direct access to
to everyone you know with all the
information that we voluntarily offer up
dana would you uh tell us what you think
about like where do you see the main
issues with with disinformation
some of the wording you know takes us
off track in a lot of ways i think you
know we started off worrying about
misinformation and disinformation and
this idea
that you know facts were coming out that
weren't the right facts or that were not
facts that were favorable to
um different groups for whatever reason
and i think when we look in this space
what we're really seeing more than
this this question of you know what what
is the information that should be out
there and what are the motives of the
people behind it
is this this set of influence operations
that go much much deeper
building on what lydia has said about
the technology and the marketing
techniques our team has been working on
really trying to understand the
mechanisms of what makes some of these
messages so
sticky what is it that that really grabs
on to people
you know kind of going back to her idea
what keeps you up at 3 a.m
and we've been looking at social
narratives as part of what's going on
in this space so our our whole idea
is that and i guess this would be the
surprising thing that
you know these these pieces of
information whatever they are whatever
is motivating them
when they're attract when they're
attached to certain kinds of
social stories that get at our core
values um
have this emotional resonance for us and
what's been happening in the mis
information and disinformation space is
that
there's been this huge play on emotions
through these narratives
and when it starts to happen it
threatens our sense of
identity and it threatens our our sense
of tribe
and so all of a sudden we become very
emotionally activated and our rational
minds start to shut off
and now all of a sudden we're actually
not talking about
facts or truth or you know uh persuasion
in the in the sort of more common ways
of thinking about it
now we're interpreting things through
the lens of our
sense of what groups we belong to in our
identity
and so if you think about the way that
this operates these
these narratives these social stories
that you know build on
big schisms in these different societies
you know certainly in the american
context the the narratives that are
being used effectively will look a
little bit different than they would
in in another country um and yet the
mechanism we believe is the same
that you take a gov narrative for
example in america of government
betrayal
which came out for some groups of the
civil rights movement and for others
came out of vietnam
those things come together and you start
to then layer different things on them
you know these ideas about a corrupt
government and now you're talking about
stolen elections or you're talking about
a coveted hoax or something else and it
has so much more power
because it dives into this very deeply
held story
and the other the other piece of this
is that once that happens not only can
you use these narratives to start to
pull people into conversations
or even to twist the narratives to turn
them against certain groups defining who
the in groups and the out groups are
but you can also use them to draw the
boundaries around groups
so if you take different social
divisions that were already
lurking underneath the the surface these
narratives gives you
give you a chance to call them up to
maybe redraw them or reinforce them
and to make the group feel both you know
collectively identified solid with each
other
but then also a sense of threat from
outside
and in the misinformation and
disinformation space what becomes so
complicated then is when you want to
counter the information that's out there
that isn't in line with the
the agenda and if you go into a counter
narrative in some ways you end up making
the groups dig in their heels
because it doesn't matter whether what
you're saying is truth or not
you're all of a sudden hitting this
boundary that's there
so you know to to think about these in
different ways when we want to think
about alliances or we want to think
about how do we
deal with polarization some of it is
really getting on top of these
narratives and using them to draw these
larger boundaries around us and them
dana that was really really insightful
in terms of thinking about you know
how you built off of what lydia said
about the marketing and how basically
we're using disinformation marketing to
to build these these tribal boundaries
in a lot of ways
um and to weaponize a lot of what the
the sort of more banal things that lydia
was talking about
giannis your take on this
well um i think first and foremost i
agree
with with both previous speakers
but i'll probably have a slightly
different angle to to the issue
and first and foremost from a social
perspective
democracy is an intricate process it
takes
a lot of elements to fall together to to
make sure that we have a functioning
democracy
and it happens that the information
space is basically the central element
of of that process because that's where
we
build our perceptions that's where we
create our world views that's where we
create consensuses and as we speak
we are undergoing the revolution in that
information
space namely through social media
through online digital engagement and
etc
and in my view what is has happened
in that process of revolutionary
revolutionization sorry
of this is that we've lost a lot of
elements
that make the process of
societal uh debate
uh societal discussion healthy
because unlike the traditional media
space which has
uh checks and balances and regulation i
would argue
this new space doesn't have none of that
and in a way we're very much at the
mercy of
the many of the social media business
models which prioritize obviously
engagement and emotions rather than
fact-based
approach but also they really don't look
at the
how much they would be spending on
dealing with the hostile
uh activities on their platforms and you
know it was all due respect to the
uh platforms activity in the online
environment and great declarations
of how they're dealing with the
uh hostile influence campaigns our
research points to the
to the fact that much more needs to be
done than
currently that's first thing second
thing obviously yes human has always
been tolerable and we've always had
these
uh biases and it has been hard for us to
to create an
objective point of view or objective
worldview
and uh that was kind of over the
uh decades and centuries where where we
were
evolving in our social systems we tried
to kind of
make people more more rational
more little enlightenment type
people but what we have right now
with the increased use of technology is
that
technology is actually quite good at
tricking people in their biases
into certain beliefs and that is what
i'm
i'm really worried about down the road
is that this equation of human
biases versus the the technological
development
and the the way technology can
i would say manipulate based on these uh
elements human behavior
is something we have to worry down the
road but within that landscape what i
would argue
it's it's basically a dream landscape
for the
disinformation actors be it
for profit be it
um different interest groups that i'm
are ready to divert to disinformation as
their
means of getting influence or ultimately
the state actors
and that's why i think this combination
of do two factors
the revolution of the information space
we're facing and the issues because of
that within our societies
and the exploitation of these
vulnerabilities by hostile actors
is the kind of reason why
we are in a situation like we are and
sometimes it's hard to sell
where the kind of objective element of a
new reality ends
and where the activity of a hostile
actor starts and sometimes
they're hostile actors in particular
trying to really kind of
hide themselves into the normal into
what we would call a
social and societal processes that are
happening
within this new information space
so i think you bring up a really really
good point um particularly with related
related there's a couple of things that
i want to come back to on that but
particularly where you talk about you
know these these hostile actors hiding
inside of the societal processes
um one of the things that that dana and
i have found as we were working on some
um some of the russian disinformation
was the way that they very much
pretended to be actors
on the right and on the left in in the
american social media space
um dana did you want to say a little bit
more about how they used deception
to kind of help us tell stories that
drove us further apart
sure yeah so in the
i mean the russians are really masters
at this in a lot of ways you know coming
at this out of
the soviet manipulative uh context and
then bringing them
to to social media and so when we
started to look at narratives we found
that there was
a lot that they were doing there both in
terms of
how they were telling stories but then
also in terms of how they were
pretending to be certain kinds of
storytellers
so i'll just use the example of the
military for this because i know that's
one of the topics that we're interested
in on this panel
but uh if you look at the
the words that they used in their posts
and their profiles
uh the russians in their in their
disinformation campaign
in in or their influence operation
campaign rather on twitter
um in english had 12.9 percent of their
uh tweets and and coming from either
messages that had military keywords in
them
or came from profiles that had military
keywords in them
so on the one hand you know when we
started to look at this you would see
that they would use
narratives related to the military to um
give more credence to certain things
that they were saying to
hide you know as jana said within these
societal processes
and and you know give this sense that
what they were talking about was
patriotic
that it was serious that it was
legitimate um and then they would use
the narratives that were related to the
military to
um you know smear certain candidates in
campaigns or to give halos to others
they weaponized them against different
groups in this case it was
the muslims the mainstream media
liberals and
the government itself and on the same on
the other side of it they would have
these
military profiles and the military
profiles didn't always use the military
narratives that we saw
but they were extremely vitriolic for
twitter and their content
you know twitter's such a mainstream
platform that people are
even though there's a lot that goes on
there it's a little bit more um
tame and polite than when you go into
the more private chat rooms and the more
um fringe groups and so even there
you had these these military folks right
and here we in this country the military
is one of our most trusted institutions
and you had then seeming representatives
you know service members and veterans or
family members of those folks
again all fake profiles telling us
stories
that would turn us against certain
groups and would seem more legitimate
because they were coming from these
perceived heroes
i think that's a really fascinating idea
to to use the military to weaponize
against elements of of the government
um lydia to come back to you and to how
have you seen
the military be used or the military
rather struggle in this space
um that we've been talking about right
because the the the militaries of the
west are um
part and parcel of of democracy as as as
janus pointed out right and this is a
complicated process that the military is
a part of
in some ways where have you seen the
military um really struggle in this
space
so for the us military one of the
biggest struggles
is that despite what a lot of twitter
accounts might be trying to say we
actually
do have very strong
respect and for the boundaries of we do
not look at u.s persons we do not
analyze their we don't engage and look
at
u.s persons social media or anything
like that
and the adversaries know that and they
are in there and they are pretending to
be us
um and so it's it's a real challenge for
us
that we have we can't look at ourselves
in this way because those russian
and those those other adversarial
accounts are mixed in with
with real americans so it
it they know that that's a seam right
they know that that's a spot that we
can't look
and so they jump right in there we have
the other challenge too
you know general nakasoni ended up
creating an official twitter account
because there were so many fake accounts
out there pretending to be him
not just from uh state actors but from
other
you know other opportunistic actors so
it it
imitation accounts targeting
us military personnel it
that's one of our biggest challenges i
think is is is
that we are limited on how we can
look at ourselves
and we know that they're in there and
they we know that they're doing it
um and we know that they're targeting
and they're trying to
turn like the example right they're
trying to actually turn
u.s military personnel to not trust the
military to not trust the government
and if they can succeed in that that
that will definitely be
a large problem for for us so i think
yeah i think those are the two the main
ones at this point
thanks giannis i think when when so when
we when we listen to what lydia
and and dana have have talked about in
terms of these stories right
and and as you've pointed out we've
we've spent the last you know
500 years or so trying to be more
rational and trying to you know
participate in this thing called the
enlightenment
in many ways it almost feels like we're
moving into a digital dark age
um what are some of the the things that
that you've seen that give you
hope in this space right so you're
obviously looking at this from from a
conglomerate of nations right
as part of the nato alliances where do
you see that that we've got some some
signs of hope that we're starting to get
our arms around this problem set and
and we're starting to to really start um
leading better in this space and being
more effective
um i think yes there is
hope but uh
um temperate hope let's put it this way
so um in the way we see it of course
there are two areas where nations start
to really invest is
the resilience of society uh
also pointing to the resilience of a
military but but certainly you cannot in
this particular
case kind of put military out of the
general society resilience both have to
be resilient that's one part
and second i think there's an increased
uh
understanding that the way we are
running our own information space
the way we're uh asking uh
what we are asking from social media uh
companies
is not sufficient and there needs to be
more
of a kind of regulatory framework wait
by the way they hold the keys to our
agora of democratic process and in
as one of the key principles of
democracy the ones who have power have
to have some
transparency accountability
and oversight and that's something also
that i i see
both in the eu but i'm increasingly
hearing also from united states there's
an
increased interest in that but i'm
worried
i'm worried because right now we're
trying to fix
the problem that we're having right now
the problem that we had yesterday and as
we all know
technology is moving fast really and for
instance one thing uh
we two years ago run an experiment uh it
was a
latin forces where we were the so-called
red team
well the the the concept was we had to
identify only in the online environment
who are participating soldiers scraped
for open source
big data on them and then based on that
big data trying to impact their
behaviors
and we ended up being able to
make soldiers disobey orders uh make
them
you know reveal their positions within
the exercise
scenarios etc etc
um and that is actually in my mind
pointing to the future problems it's not
only kind of individual tata that was
was with some some troll or imposter
from russia or iran
that soldiers will be encountering but
increasingly that would be
automated systems and i think also the
the the risks coming from
the big data we're admitting is is is
significant especially if you combine it
with a micro targeting
uh not from a for a political purpose or
from a political standpoint but from a
hostile influence perspective
and there will be many other issues that
i think technology is about to bring
to our table deep fakes and etc etc
that will once again test our limits
of uh of our capability to respond
i'm really glad to hear you bring up the
micro targeting and the big data problem
that's something that
that i know that lydia and dana and i
have all been really working hard to get
the us military to take seriously as
a national security threat um when we
think about
um you know a lot of the things that
have come up here really are are getting
at
the profit model the underlying profit
model of these social media companies
um does anyone think and i want to leave
this one kind of open to whoever would
like to jump in does anybody think that
reining in the profit model um would
would help in this space if we were to
disincentivize
the profit being made from the
disinformation space if we were to
disincentivize the rapid spread of ideas
like we're seeing
would would changing the profit model
and the profit calculus for these
companies have an impact there
i can i can hit it a different i have a
different angle on this
but so not only are the social media
companies profiting but there's a whole
gig economy of influence
so you know if you're an influencer
sometimes it's about the status and the
prestige but
a lot more of it is about the
merchandise the clicks
the views the advertising capabilities
and so
you know part and parcel with the the
money motives that are out there for the
social media companies to
uh propagate these messages to make
their platforms
places where the data can be used and
where the algorithms can
can push certain things you know
especially from a marketing perspective
if you think about these influence
operations as a marketing exercise
that's still there but then you also
have an army of
um individuals sometimes networked ones
sometimes working solo
who are also benefiting in a variety of
social and economic ways from you know
spreading these
these engaging messages oftentimes the
ones that
create outrage and and upset
i think that's a really really good
point of all of the different folks that
that are benefiting from this this
current model
did someone else want to jump in on that
yeah this is
sort of i'm going to go ahead a little
bit to where
what how to try to solve this um
right it makes money if it makes money
people are going to do it
and you know remember from the early
days of the internet right it was the
first rule of the internet was
don't feed the trolls and that's where
we are as we are feeding the trolls and
it's not just the the the nasty little
gamergate comment trolls which is where
that you know started was
but it's all the trolls it's the people
who are tweeting out
content whether you know whether they
believe it or not they're treating it
they're tweeting it out for the response
and if we could as collectively as
humans
stop feeding the trolls stop uh
responding to that then that would
that's the way you would
de incentivize it that's the way you
would take the money out of it that's
the way you would
pull the the profit out how do you get
people to do that i sit there
and i watch these things go and i think
everyone
just remember the first rule
and i think the way that we get at that
i think i froze
there you go the way we get at that is
it's going to take grassroots
much more individual engaging with
people more personally
effort if i had not gotten this job the
thing that i would have been out there
doing
was building my network of influence
ambassadors but not for money
but for teaching
the miss and disinformation tactics and
what is happening so
not everybody is going to want to hear
from me about
how the russians are putting information
into their information stream
the key is to go find the person from
that tribe
from that group who will listen and will
understand and who will go then teach
their tribe
it's going to much more take
connecting with people individually you
know putting out snopes and articles
people just they're already inoculized
against those i think what we need to do
is we need to start figuring out how to
start building the tribes of
miss and disinformation debunkers and
i'll hand it over
giannis yeah well uh first
we we run a system that tracks russian
uh social media
media botnets and over the years and
it's been a year
since we've been doing so so you kind of
start establishing the
who they're uh answering to and the
command control
uh arrangements but what we always find
surprising
that almost all of those systems also
run
at a commercial uh enterprise
that means that 70 to
90 percent of the time they actually
sell their manipulation
services to whoever is ready to buy and
i think that's an interesting thought
that some
russian state actors that are developing
these systems and fielding them
in particular to to advance their
interests and harmed ours
and our societies on the side
make quite a lot of money just by also
selling it
and i think it's it's it's quite a
paradox and
and of course therefore my answer is yes
we have to deal with that
i also agree with lydia we we have to
look at the
kind of humans being and doing more but
in this part of the region there's
actually quite a lot of
kind of activity on a on a societal
level so called elves
the the groups as uh non-governmental
groups that self-organize to fight
trolls and etc etc
but i have to say after seeing these
phenomenons
for like four or five years it has
a place but it's limited we
i think have to address wider
[Music]
problems including as i've said
regulation of social media being able to
make sure that
they're doing what they're supposed to
do to root out for instance these uh you
know authentic
behavior bot systems um
to spend their
kind of abundant money also in in the
ways to protect the
consumers that are online uh that's uh
first second uh and which is i think a
fundamental discussion to be had but i
think we're going to have it
who is supposed to own data and i know
there have been
quite a lot of discussions but coming
from a security
perspective i find that the current
practice is
not quite good
i understand how it might fundamentally
change many business models but i think
that is something worth debating
yeah i think you bring up an excellent
excellent point about the the
fundamental ownership of data right
so in in the united states we have this
idea of copyright that the minute you
put something into a a physical medium
you own the rights to it
when we start thinking about people's
data and all of the ways that that can
be used to manipulate against
to manipulate individuals right it
really raises a much bigger question
about
the ownership of this who does actually
own this right when we think about
medical data when we think about mental
health records when we think about
blood types and like all of the folks
that went and did the the blood typing
to get their their genomic history
right like all of that data now are
owned by other companies by private
companies and we know that some of our
adversaries are eagerly either hacking
their way into this or or buying it
and just because it's not a threat now
doesn't mean that it won't necessarily
be a threat in
in the future um giannis can you say a
little bit more about what you would
like to see
in terms of regulation in this space
because i think you know i think you're
absolutely right that we can't count on
companies goodwill because
their primary directive is to make a
profit right um and just telling them
hey be good citizens
clearly isn't working so what would you
like to see in terms of regulation and
and then lydia and dana i'd like you to
speak to that too
as well before that regulation
just just a short point we just had an
experimentation on
uh big data brokers and
i have to say that you can buy anything
you wish for and it's like
so detailed especially for the u.s
citizens not covered by gdpr
and having a large data broker market
it horrified me at least okay so now
more about that yeah on the regulatory
uh
points um i do believe the three
principles that we have to ask from the
social media
a is a transparency to a regulator on
algorithms to make sure that they are
not uh unnecessarily prioritizing
a b or c things and actually ability to
go in
and have an independent uh view of it
second obviously is that
we have to be able to independently
review their security practices
as i've said uh we've come a number of
times
in the situations where for instance
companies say
one thing saying well we're doing a
great job to take down so
so so many uh botnets on their platforms
and then we when we run an experiment we
go to those uh
shady dealers uh buy their services and
and and try it out on on our
our own accounts in facebook and see
well
it's cheap easily accessible you
basically google search for the provider
and you get it
um so there's there's really kind of
need to have an
independent ability to check and if it's
not providing
have a good hefty uh
penalty and ultimately as i've said in
my view
also the the data ownership issue has to
be
uh reviewed because it leads i think
down the road to
very very significant problems and of
course we're right now
uh talking of the world where
most of that is a western product
companies but as we know
increasingly chinese products like
wechat tick tock are coming in and then
on the back end there's a chinese social
uh social credit system
model somewhere running probably some
certain things so
it's i think absolutely last moment we
start to talk about it
i think you you bring up absolutely
excellent points and i agree with with
all three of your regulatory proposals
dana what would you propose
i mean i think the only thing that i
would add to that is this
idea of a right to privacy that you know
right now
all of our information is seen as a
commodity rather than as something that
is integrally part of our identities and
that you know we have a right to keep
private
and with all of the information that's
out there already as you've already
noted
there's already a significant risk to
anybody who's engaged with these systems
you know even the credit card companies
have data on
in the us 98 of our households so
even putting the genie back in the
bottle i think is going to be a very
difficult thing and it's going to take
some sustained work over
you know quite a period of time to
really prioritize this idea that
we do have the the rights to take our
information
to to be private about it and to not
have it be sold for profit
i think that's that's an excellent
excellent point chris wiley makes an
outstanding point about privacy
you know being fundamentally related to
to human agency in his
in his book um that i don't want to say
the title in polite company but
it's an absolutely excellent book mind f
um lydia what would you recommend in
terms of of
uh regulatory oversight
i agree with all of this and then i
would say that the sites need to come
with a warning label like cigarettes
so the next part is when when
came from the analytica broke i was
really excited because i've been
tracking that
and and i've been the crazy person on
facebook saying stop taking these
quizzes you're giving right
and i was excited because i thought
it was going to be explained and people
would understand and what people took
away from that in my world
was facebook is collecting data on me
but
you know and they they i'm excited that
at that point people in my world
got the concept of if you're not paying
you're the product which a lot of
people seem to have also forgotten now i
think that there needs to be more
warnings
throughout the the tools throughout the
the sites
of do you like the cigarette warnings
that's what i would say let's get some
let's get some warnings on there so
people can start to think
and realize
the the tools that they're using and
what it is doing along
the way i think those are all really
really excellent recommendations across
the board i would add two if i may be so
so bold as to jump in one i would like
to see universities change their irb
rules to
enable research using all of this data
that are out there
right now a lot of the universities will
push back on projects because it's
people's data that they didn't
necessarily consent to
being collected and yet research
universities they're some of the only
folks that have the the capability
to provide some of the the oversight and
the investigation of how these tools are
working
um and the other thing that i would
propose is advertiser registration
right so right now anybody with a credit
card can can log on to any of these
platforms and start buying
advertisements
um if we were to to require advertisers
to get
you know to register with with a
government agency like the you know here
in the united states the federal you
know the ftc the federal trade
commission
um then these platforms would know that
the person that was advertising
was a known entity as opposed to an
unknown entity
um i don't think the the the social
media platforms will ever go for that
but i think it would be a really
interesting way of of splitting the the
difference in terms of still allowing
advertising but providing some
some regulatory oversight there um
i want to come back to um one more point
that we were kind of talking about and
draw the lens up a little bit higher in
terms of alliances
right we've really talked about
democracy and we've really talked about
the stories that get told inside of
society
and and the profit model here where do
we see
the challenge of of of alliances
and and being able to to maintain you
know this this thing called democracy
requires trust it requires knowing that
the person working in your government is
actually
working you know somebody that you know
in the and that they're you know you
assume that they're doing the right
thing in in the american narratives the
stabbed in the back narratives right
it's this
is very anti-semitic conspiracy that the
government has been taken over
and it's working to enslave the american
people right
um so you can't have a democracy if you
don't believe that your government is
is part of the the democratic process so
when we think about alliances and we
think about
democracy more broadly how do we see um
alliances coming together to influence
this because right now the regulatory
process
is sort of state by state in many ways
um
or in america and um i know the eu has a
little bit more of a collective effort
here but where do we see
you know nato really working with with
the alliance factor to try
and and and combat this um so giannis if
you could start us there
well uh clearly from a nato's
perspective we're we're looking at the
security implications for that and and
and the security
implications are pretty wide we're
talking not only of
military or military operations we're
talking about the society implications
you might be having an excellent
military operation but you might be
targeted
by the hostile actor within your home
country and
ruin all the success of a military
operation and it is very likely scenario
that we might have
in the near future so i think it's first
and foremost
the the kind of from nato's perspective
to raise the
security perspective the urgency but
clearly nato doesn't have
the uh many tools to work
with that although one say thing that
we've learned in our
center is that you have to show real
life examples that people can relate to
and for instance this experiment that we
run with the soldiers
it's news about that spreading in the
forces like a wildfire and you know
soldiers almost like drop their phones
because of that
um so it is through example that nato
can
can give these guidances but by and
large i think there are
basically two entities that can do
something about it at this point in time
it's either eu or united states
as a country and the best if we can
be done uh more or less jointly because
that's where
we can set the key parameters how
this should function in a modern 21st
century democracy and keep the freedoms
and
values uh but not allow this
disinformation and fracturing of a
society
as we're seeing right now so that's
where i see that alliance and we as a
center have been
continuously talking both to eu
parliament as well as u.s senate on
these issues to
to just raise the the the flag of
of the risks we're running if we're not
fixing it
today i think that's a really really
really great point
um lydia
i mean i think one of our biggest
obstacles right now
is political will because the the
the purveyors of the miss and
disinformation have done such a fabulous
job
of creating ways to undermine this
um when giannis was talking before he
was talking about how
the debate and discussion have been
undermined in in our world now
and if you look at it right if someone
comes in with a differing opinion or or
if
if someone suffers the consequences for
saying outrageous things you know they
they cry cancel culture i'm cancelled
so i i think it's
we need we need our leaders to be brave
and take the risk
and and be ready to you know take the
the troll and and the real person
onslaught
and and dare to to make do this alliance
and do this work
it's going to be a hard fight because
those that are trying to keep that from
happening have actually already built up
a really effective
system as far as ideas and language and
being able to wrote people in to
undermine it
yeah i think you're you're absolutely
right about that um in
in in a lot of different ways and it's
it's quite disheartening because we're
sort of trying to push the snowball you
know push the avalanche back uphill if
you will
dana yeah i don't have a lot to add but
i think that the pandemic puts a lot of
this in perspective as well this need
for
getting ahead you know an information
advantage in the information and
disinformation space and
one that really recognizes that while we
do have our our national boundaries and
our
you know uh traditional alliances that a
lot of the things that are happening in
the world really transcend that
and so it's really imperative that
different governments work together
and um you know try to
to work on what's happening in this
space
and so you know if one country regulates
but the others don't
we have this sort of whack-a-mole
problem where we might be able to
contain something just a little bit
but our communications are so far beyond
you know these these these boundaries
i think that's a really really excellent
point and and thinking about boundaries
um we actually have a couple of
questions from the audience
um one of them is actually really about
boundaries about professional standards
right so it says you know and for a good
portion of human history you know there
really hasn't been a professional news
industry with with editorial standards
um it really did develop in
in the the sort of early parts of the
20th century
do we think it's realistic for us to
expect that we can return to a
professionalization
um or to any kind of professionalization
in the the social media space or in the
media space more broadly
um lydia
um i have a dream uh
so where we are right now with a lot of
our media space is right
they they've learned i'm off camera here
they've learned that right
we're playing gladiator games on our
evening news right it's the
fight for the best sound bite um
the thing that i've seen there's another
um
person who does in-depth dives on on
content and information
unfortunately he's very biased in a
certain take and he generally goes
vulgar so i can't share it a lot
however i would be surprised i would not
be surprised if
news decided to
try some of these deep dives and go into
the information i think they would be
very surprised
at how hungry people are
for something besides the sound bites
i i think that maybe the way we get to
it is just the natural evolution of
people are tired they get tired of this
and they want more um
in-depth information and and if someone
would dare to take the risk to do
well researched in-depth well-produced
reports i think they would be really
surprised and
yeah how do we solve this i think i
think we're in a cycle
and i think that we're going to have to
hit a
harder rock bottom before we come back
to our
age of digital enlightenment it seems
yeah
anyone else want to tackle that one we
have a couple more questions go ahead
if i may just quickly first of course
you have to recognize u.s
space and i would argue also uk spaces
are particular
if you look at many other nations there
are more central ground in that
information
space and still more of a quality
uh kind of information available but
what we have in a smaller information
spaces
these uh media business models are dying
out in
in smaller countries like like latvia
for instance it's almost dead
and it's starting to go into other
bigger language spaces and that is also
because
most of their revenue ad revenue goes to
the large social media companies so
that's one part of the problem the
second of course there's no way to turn
back
but of course you could think of
theoretical models where
some of the editorial choices and
decisions
can be given out to tech
yeah i mean the the question of
editorial is really really interesting
and and tech likes in america they like
to say that you know they're not they're
not
content you know editors they're they're
just platforms but yet with their
algorithms we know that their their
algorithms are
are built to make choices about what
content that they're going to advance
versus not
um so i think that re reframing the idea
of what does it mean to be a content
publisher or editorial
and looking at the role of algorithms in
that i think is a really really
interesting point
um another question that's come up is um
is there any we've talked a lot of
defense here do we have any ideas that
that folks would like to share about
offensive tactics that we that we've
seen maybe work um who is doing
a good job in some of these spaces um is
anyone
well well if i may you go sorry media
you go
you go you go first okay okay
uh well actually uh since uh
russia is about uh 200 kilometers from
here
uh we've been tracking uh how does it
work and and what they feel is is the
risk
and of course uh most of our uh
adversaries that are running these uh
campaigns against us
are actually doing that because of
weakness not because of the strengths
they just have found a particular
weakness in our own societies but they
have
more than that but they have a different
author
authoritarian system in essence instead
of having a
free flow of information which we in
democracies cherish and try to
to to protect they want to control so
that's what they're trying to do
so what they especially after 2011
they've tried to really build the
systems that
protect them from outside impacts
but what we can see right now
that people within these societies like
navalny
like uh the guy who just got arrested
the
the the one that was running nectar
um in in uh the belerution guy
they are the ones that really make it
really really painful by just very
simple thing exposing the troops
so i think that's what we have to do we
have to support these
these kind of people that can expose the
realities to the people back in these
countries
yeah i think you bring up a really
really good point and one of the things
that
that i've i've been trying to point out
to to to military leaders
is that that what happened to navalny
can happen to any of us in the in the
social media space we can all be
called from the herd so to speak and and
segregated away there is no strength in
numbers
in in many ways um we've got about five
minutes left and so
what i would like to do is to give each
of you you know a couple minutes to kind
of sum up and
give us one main takeaway that you would
like like the
the conference attendees to uh to to
kind of remember as they take away from
this
and then do you have a book
recommendation so what is one thing that
you would recommend that
that people read to get to get you know
deeper into to what's going on dana if
you would start us off
yeah so on the book recommendation i
would i would recommend the chris wiley
book that you
mentioned earlier um that is the sort of
one of the whistleblower stories out of
the cambridge analytica
uh scandal and really goes into detail
about how a lot of the micro targeting
works in
in a way that i think makes it really
accessible
um in terms of takeaways i think one of
the things that's been really
disheartening to learn
over the course of of these studies is
just how far behind we are in a lot of
ways and the genie is already out of the
bottle
and so instead of trying to find ways to
put the genie back in the bottle
i think we need to start coming up with
other paradigms for
for what to do going forward and one of
the big things that we've seen coming
out of all of this is just
how how there were these underlying
vulnerabilities and rifts in our
societies
that were just right for exploitation so
that you know the world is becoming more
and more polarized
and our own communities are becoming
more and more polarized
being involved with the pandemic and
being stuck at home and
you know relating to people through
social media has allowed for
us to find these echo chambers and these
these
thought bubbles of being with people who
think the same way that we do and it's
amplified a lot of these divisions
hopefully as things start to open up and
we're doing a little bit more offline
we'll be able to start moving more
toward cohesion and yet at the same time
there's a lot of damage that's already
been done
and so part of the the the
solution to these problems in the
disinformation and misinformation space
really have to do with building social
resilience
great points lydia um
the book i recommend is the brand gap
by marty neumeyer coming from the
marketing background
it it comes back to explaining the
tribes that dana was talking about
earlier and and
we we figured that out a long time ago
with the marketing and and this
is the the challenges we're being
divided into tribes
the irony is the faster we build up we
break down the walls of the internet
and and create more connectivity the
quicker we are building up our own
tribes on the internet and building up
our walls
on the internet the thing that i wish
everybody would take away from this is
if you're not first you're last to quote
ricky bobby
from child negan
and the the challenge is is the russians
are out there they're out there running
the narrative in marketing
in ideas the first to market the loudest
the most consistent that's what gets
internalized
i don't feel like we are in there
putting our messages
out consistently and loudly enough and
we don't have to counter theirs
we have to say what ours are and onto
you
giannis please close us out uh
well for the military out there i would
recommend
being biased our own report from nato
stratform coe
camouflage in the digital domain which
is providing some tips
what can be done for the military to to
avoid being tracked
in the online environment which might
provide some helpful um
advice on the uh big picture
uh i think there's no time to waste
we are running out of time to fix these
things because
uh as we feel all the system
we are having in our countries is
starting to wear down
but we have also to be mindful that this
is not going to be the end of it
the technology is coming with a new uh
new things and to me in this
digital disinformation domain i in
particular would point to the
5g enabled emergence of
internet of things that is coupled with
the
increased spread of augmented reality
devices which
in fact will uh couple the the reality
and digital reality which i think will
have
a very new wave of vulnerabilities
risks as well as attacks on the human
cognitive space
and second a
point of hope um
one thing that is great about the
democracies we might be making bad
choices we might
probably do mistakes but it is the only
self-correcting system we have so i'm
looking forward
to the self-correction that we're going
to do all together
i think that thank you for for leaving
us with with an element of hope i think
we
we do have a a system that is flawed but
like you said it is self-correcting
thank you all um panelists for for
putting putting the time in to conduct
this panel
i hope the audience got a lot of
information out of this and
again thank you all very much for your
time
thank you