oh
the red light goes out okay can you hear
me
not yet
it says it's on but there's no light
are we are we long batteries maybe
let's try this and i'm gonna leave this
up okay okay we got a good red light
okay you can hear me okay
all right so our next presenter is going
to be penelope
uh she's got her title is code hedgehogs
changing the s
and sldc to secure as opposed to
software development life cycle or
systems development lifecycle
and so basically she we're going to try
she's going to
talk about software secure software
development
using a shift-left effort and aiming to
identify security vulnerabilities early
in the development life cycle
so takeaways from this talk will be
ideas on how to engage developers
in shifting the security posture of the
organization through secure coding with
a simple analogy
concrete steps at each phase of the sdlc
and fund ways to learn how to do it
a quick review on how to enter
integrate secure coding at each step of
the software development life cycle
and then discuss top application
vulnerabilities and mitigation
techniques to defend against known
attacks
and then there's three different
approaches to threat modeling
and wrapping up with recommendations on
how to try your hand on the other side
of
gamified red team challenges where
coding skills
give you a decided advantage penelope is
an experienced
cyber security professional and a
learner and passionate
about all things cyber she has two
bachelor's degrees
i didn't i was going to ask you what
were they previously in so
the first one's called political economy
of industrial society
okay peis and then the other was
i was a k-12 k-12 by the way and now a
master's
in as well as a masters and now a degree
in cyber security and information
assurance
very good so she's an actor she is
active in the black hills information
security community
uh speaking are you going to planning to
go to deadwood
deadwood yep okay so there you go she's
going to give a presentation out of
a presentation or just attending
volunteering volunteering there so
um active so active with black hills
information security community
and appointed friends of bhis uh
designation
not only known as the nerd herders
not familiar with that one so all right
uh you might even stumble upon cameo
appearances on the newscast of
backdoors and breaches demos found on
youtube or twitch
she's an educator at heart excited to
share her expertise and
audiences whenever given the opportunity
nlp also has her comptia security plus
and cysa plus certs
and uh an adjunct instructor at northern
kentucky university
in the gen cyber program so welcome and
uh
the floor is yours
hopefully i can keep you entertained
long enough to uh
okay well i was expecting 30 minutes so
let's see how this goes
so you may have noticed he did not say
my last name because it is roshkova
and when people see it they are just
like i don't know what to do with that
exactly and um so i married
russian and uh i've learned a little bit
about the
russian culture and in russian the word
anecdote kind of means what
it means in english but it is more like
what we use for
like to tell a joke and so that's
actually what i want to start with today
and give you some insight into why i
said
uh code hedgehogs and so this
uh let's see if we go here
because the light is let's see
okay
yep i know we tested it before i started
to talk
it's not just me
all right so let's see
yeah so like that pointer's working
so it'll go backwards oh there it is
okay there's four all right so
apparently all right so
my russian anecdote so there's this
group of mice who are
chatting among themselves and they say
to them they're talking about like how
they have this terrible position in life
they are at the um bottom of the food
chain
they don't like being there anymore what
can we do about this problem that we
have about being at the bottom of the
food chain
and they're just like we can't figure it
out but i bet you that wise owl
can give us an idea so the mice head
over to the owl and they asked the owl
and they
explained their situation about how they
don't like being at the bottom of the
food chain
and what can we do to make ourselves um
less vulnerable and they uh the
owl says that's a good question
let me think about that for a minute and
the
owl says i've got it you can become a
hedgehog
and the mice are like oh that's a great
idea isn't it we have
uh quills if we're hedgehogs and we can
roll up in that ball
and you know we're not going to be as
easily to be grabbed by those mouths
because our quills will like protect us
that's a great idea let's become
hedgehogs and so they
walk off and they're so excited and
they're just like oh my gosh i want to
be a hedgehog
let's do it let's do it and they stop
there's like wait a minute he didn't
tell us how
how are we supposed to be hedgehogs and
so they're like okay well we let's go
back and ask him
and they go back to the owl and he's
just like yeah of course i didn't tell
you how to be hedgehogs you know like
i'm the idea guy
you go figure out how to be a hedgehog
so you know the owl gave them a great
idea but then they didn't know what to
do with it
so that's kind of where we are with
um programmers today right programmers
um
kind of can be the mice in the cyber
security
vulnerability space right they are who
they are
and sometimes don't see the reason to
have quills
see please yes okay
so um this talk hopefully as
uh carl said in the introduction will
give you some ideas about how to shift
your security posture
and give you some talking points for
when you're dealing with developers who
kind of say well we don't need to be
hedgehogs
so when we have the secure development
life cycle whether it's waterfall or
agile
um generally speaking the security
starts
at the testing level right so um
they have not been thinking with the
secure
posture in mind as they get started and
when we get to testing and doing quality
assurance that's when it starts to
happen
and so we get the dynamic analysis with
the tools that are in place and
hopefully the tools work
and you might have some pen testers come
in and
test it at that point but the new idea
in this area is to shift left
and one of the people i'm going to talk
about later says push left right because
it depends on the environment of whether
they're willingly
going to go to the left or if they're
going to have to be
encouraged to move but we can start
at the beginning and we can look at our
documentation that we have in place that
is probably in your risk in governance
and figure out how to start this project
with the planning to begin with
and you can go all the way through the
life cycle by adding in
relevant steps along the whole process
that are encourage a secure posture
and so that by the time you get to that
testing
that quality assurance level you've
already been thinking about it
and the thing is when you start early
then it's more cost effective
both in terms of time and money
and then you can move on and make sure
that it doesn't just stop at testing
but it is also included in the other
steps where you're going to have you
know when you're in deployment and you
have the final security review
you can create that incident response
plan and hopefully based on what you've
been doing through the previous steps
have it built in there
and then the maintenance part of course
as well
to have your developers in mind of like
oh these are kind of the things that
are out there and if the new ones come
up it's not going to be
news to them about how this process is
working
so along the whole way you want to keep
in your mind
like the threat modeling process and
adjusting your priorities and risk
reduction
strategies as you move along so it can
be a much more dynamic process
so where do we start right so if the
developers like never really had this
education
when i gave this talk to like a group of
students who came
up through tech elevator and they said
oh we only got one day on security
and so you know it's a 14-week program
it goes fast they don't
necessarily know what that means to
secure to code securely
so you know start you know start with
something that's out there
well established and if you look at
these top ten
like nine of them are things that
developers can help with right like the
insufficient login and monitoring is
like the only one that is not
kind of in the programmer's wheelhouse
and you can introduce them to the
website you know you can take them there
and you know pick something to show them
off
your list and take them through the page
so um and if you're in a dynamic
situation
i was not going to challenge the demo
gods
and try and do anything live
but it breaks it down so it gives you
across the top the thread agents and
attack vectors for broken authentication
it gives you the security
weaknesses and the impacts of having
broken authentication
if it's not something that's in the
forefront of their minds
um then it breaks it down in the next
four blocks right so for
all of these vulnerabilities there's a
page like this that it was
you all may already know that but
programmers probably don't
and you hear a lot of things from
programmers well um i use an obscure
code
um i don't need to worry about that um
you know it's it's third party it
doesn't really touch anything important
i don't need to worry about that so if
you focus on what you think is likely to
happen
um you're probably gonna get um cause
problems for your security team
but if you instead focus on what can
happen
and be prepared and if you start with
that process as i said from the
beginning with that in mind
like we don't know what's going to
happen we don't know who's out there who
wants to
attack us then we need to think about
what can happen
and not what's likely to happen
so the most common vulnerabilities
exploited during
pen testing are here um
so i am i got into
cyber security because i was coaching my
son's cyber patriot team
oh
okay so i uh
so cyber patriot blue team i love blue
team i like being on
uh on that side of it and he
when we first started the team we went
my first event was b site cincinnati in
and i played the ctf there and i just
fell in love
with cyber security and so that's how i
moved from
education into cyber because i when i
my my new choice my son decided i was a
homeschooler and my son decided to go
back to brick and mortar i was like what
am i going to be when i grow up now i
get to choose
and this was like the automatic thing
for me because
i just love it all i and i love the
gamification
and so uh i
am not a coder one of the first things
that i learned in my program was that
coding can be really important in cyber
security right like
high school so i'm kind of the same age
as phil and and
uh dr c here we had trs 80s
in my high school lab i learned to code
basic
a little bit of fortran cobalt and
pascal which i don't think any of that
is used to get uh used today
and it was so long ago it's not like i
remember how to code
but you know i've had some fun with
python now and
i took a little java so i can play with
code i can
use it when i'm playing my games enough
to like figure out how to break it
and so that's me right i am
if you do not have input validation in
your code
i can figure that part out right so
that's like the easy one i think to kind
of start teaching
your programmers that that's important
right
um let's see if this works here
can we push play on that i don't know if
i can do that from here
to the square you guess where that goes
square
that's right
and how about this rectangle
it was working
a cylinder i think that goes in
the square hole
[Applause]
that's right
i know how to do that i don't know how
to code
but i could like figure out what to put
into those forms when i'm on a web app
and like figure out how to break in i
don't i'm still at the point where i
don't necessarily know
what to do on the other side but i can
like get some access
[Laughter]
so um i think this is like a great thing
to show your coders right like
what are the people on the outside gonna
do when you
you put a form out on your web app and
you didn't do
what input validation because you're
like oh they know how to read directions
it says to put this in right right well
maybe the regular user
is going to put things where you want to
but your pen tester is not going to do
that
your script kitties aren't going to do
that and um
it's not secure right and if it's
someone more malicious than that you
definitely don't want them going in that
way
so um again so preventing the
sql injections there's like a bunch of
stuff here that there are probably
people in this room
who know exactly how to do all those
things but i know that the one thing
that can stop me
as a new person is validate every user
input
and i think that's a great place to
start and i think this is like a place
where you can
show programmers that it's important to
improve your security posture
you can also introduce them to um
miter so my
college program didn't teach me about
mitre i did it as a special project
in my program right but if even cyber
security professionals in a
a good program you know my i was in a in
a cy
ah see sorry
anyway the nsa approved uh education
program
right mitre never came up in a single
one of my classes and i kept
coming to these events right and i would
hear about it and i was just like so
i want to thank you out here who have
been doing it
for teaching me what i wasn't learning
at school and
i learned about mitre by coming to these
talks right so
if i'm not learning it in a cyber
security program that's approved by the
nsa
your your programmers probably aren't so
you could introduce it to them and you
can say look these are things that can
happen
you know introduced during uh the design
phase or these are the things that are
introduced during implementation
or if they're taught a specific code and
you can send them and say like these are
the
vulnerabilities that might be there if
you're using
c or java or php right there's a lot of
php
out there and so you have a way
to introduce them to things that they
might not have been thinking about in my
experience when i've talked to
like those tech elevator people it's not
that they're not interested it's just
like oh
we didn't know so let's know
and if we know we can get them on the
path to
being able to code hedgehogs instead of
mice right because if we have mice
it's going to be really hard to turn
those web apps that you've
created ignoring the first four steps
ignoring what vulnerabilities are out
there and then expect them to make
hedgehogs
at the end so you can introduce them to
the idea of threat modeling
my favorite uh explanation of like the
vulnerability versus threat
uh explanation because you know i'd go
had
lots of that for sure in my classes
right but a very simple way
to help keep it clear in your head for
me is
the threat is from the outside the
threat is the thing that is
outside of the system and the
vulnerability is the weakness within
and then risk is the intersection of the
two so i think when people can
look at it from that way without all the
long explanations of
oh these are this is a threat blah blah
blah i can't even remember what those
classroom ones were
but i know it was a lot of words
but that has really helped me when i
learned when i first heard that
explanations just like oh it's suddenly
clear
so let's make it as simple as possible
for them to kind of understand
what are the things we're looking at so
then we know what our you know hopefully
we have some ideas from the things that
we just discussed what some of the
vulnerabilities the
internal things are that could be
weaknesses of what we are
uh coding and then let's give them some
insight into what the threat model
i mean what the threats could be so it
could be attacker-centric right
do you work somewhere where um uh
industrial espionage can be a problem do
you work somewhere that you're somewhere
in the supply line
that it could be like you know classic
espionage that
they might want to use your third party
to access
something that's a little more uh
classified or
up the uh international food chain
software centric again so we talked
about like what are the platforms what
are the components of this
of the um application that you're
building
and have a sense of like what are the
weaknesses
in your components
and then asset centric do you have pii
in there that people want to get access
to
do you have state secrets that you know
somewhere down the food chain
like that you could get access to and so
giving them a sense of like these are
the thoughts that are going through the
attacker's minds and what
comes up to the surface for what you are
creating
so it gives them the background
to understand that you know how do i
identify
the known vulnerabilities the threats um
how do i understand these risks and then
they can go on and like start deciding
like what security controls besides
input validation
right which should just be automatic
that they should put into place how do
you prioritize those risks within your
organization right that's not just you
know
the conversations kind of like what um
micah was talking about i
i don't know if um uh
dr c like knew what i was gonna really
be talking about
because i just sent him my slides but he
i love serendipity right
just like oh my gosh like my talk i
think it's gonna make so much more sense
coming after mike i could not have
planned this better
uh thank you so much and he was blessed
right
he had somebody in his organization um
who was a security person who had um
that
web app background um one of my
uh compatriots who
uh is a strong technical cyber security
person
took his uh took a job recently and he's
been there a month and he's like
not like loving it you know and he's
just like couldn't you have done this
talk a month ago because if you would
have been talking about the fact that
to be a really great web app
security person you should probably have
had some development experience first
you know before you try to be that
person
and he's a great technical cyber
security person but
he's not a he's not a developer and he's
struggling so i mean
building up our developers i think for
our need in cyber security
to get those people already coming in
with a
secure posture mindset will give
us a pipeline to bring in better cyber
security people for that outside
so um and if you have
those people who already understand the
development side and we train them in
the cyber security side
the priority prioritizing risk and
creating a risk reduction
strategy are going to be a lot um well
they're not going to be easy ever right
but hopefully
a little smoother
so um the considerations we want to take
into effect are you know the
technologies leveraged by the
application the client client-side
databases that people might want to be
trying to
uh get gain access to rest
the native programming languages of the
app and the integrations again
what third parties are going to be
attaching to us
and then we want to look at the the
risks that are non-technical a lot
the loss in terms of time if you have to
rewrite
it to make it secure the loss
of um from a branding standpoint or a
reputation standpoint
if something goes wrong we have the
theft that we talked about which could
be the monetary or it could be the
information
whether it's secrets or personal
uh the pii and then again the delays
right it's going to be a lot easier to
move
uh through the development process and
build it in than it is if you have to go
back and try
and turn your mouse into a hedgehog
so i think you know
from a business standpoint it makes
sense to train these people early on
to have security built in
so then again the house right how do i
build
secure coding skills
so let's say that they come out of tech
elevator and
um then what right because they got
their one day
in class and even if you're in a
four-year university if you're going
down a certain track there's not
necessarily going to be cyber security
built into your program
so they're a great talk so again love
serendipity when i was
writing this talk originally i did it
for um
that women who code um
this popped into my feed right this
devsec con 24
24 hours around the world they broke it
up into the
three segments of north america
europe and then um like the uh
japan uh australia time frame and so
around the clock you had experts from
around the world available to you
and um it was great this was my favorite
one here right because again i like the
gamification so
so i recommend to everybody go spend
your 20 minutes with
rosemary wang and play i spy and
insecure delivery pipeline
and it it doesn't have to be dry right
it can be fun
so if you want um something a little
more dry you can go to bright talk also
and do those
searches there and you're going to find
you know into
like the the sales people who are trying
to sell their
uh products they'll also have it and you
can learn from them too right you don't
have to buy products
to learn how to uh utilize the the
methodologies
so it's easy to find talks
you can find blogs so this is a tanya
janka and i don't know if i'm saying her
name right
and i joke that you know i don't
recommend her just because she has the
same color hair that i do
but she's awesome and if you
if you ca i'm not sure if you can read
it here but you know so she starts here
like
this bottom one is pushing left so she's
the one who says you know you've
i ha and she works in the environment so
she probably knows better than i that
you have to push left um
and it starts with part one and she has
like five parts i think of just the
pushing left part
she has up here url url parameters
um whatever it is that you're looking
for
um it has safe uh dependencies
so she has right here we have 12 there
she has two pages
of blog posts and she is from we
hack purple and she created that
organization
and um so right here at just one website
you can get
two dozen mini tutorials on how to
become
a a better more secure coder
and then there's my favorite part right
the game so again
at the same time that i was like writing
this this is my first experience with
this
this company and so at the i was
attending
virtually the um way west conference and
they had a ctf there
for coding and i played it a little bit
and again like i think if i'd been
a developer or coder i would have done
much better in it
but i loved it right so um and
when i went in there what they do is
they give you these blocks of code
and they mark a few of them they say
which piece is the one
that is insecure and so you pick that
one
i actually got a couple right
and then um it gives you the opportunity
to fix the code
right so then it gives you um the option
to go in
and fix the code so it can be fun right
like it's challenging
you get immediate feedback that oh yes i
was able to spot what needed to be fixed
um i bet you can't guess guess which
piece i found
input validation um
and so there are fun things out there to
do in order to learn
um command and control so
my very first one in my account
i was only able to get 75 points
in my first event with uh a command and
control range
and um honestly it could have just been
that i learned how to follow the rules i
don't even know at this point what my 75
points were for
but um and it was i do remember that it
was
their social networking uh app
and so over time so we can learn even i
can learn
you know not being a developer how to
improve so this is my most recent score
right i think it probably goes to 12 000
or something
but i'm really proud of my 37.70
compared to my 75 that i can learn uh
how to break the web apps right so again
i'm not the developer
but i can learn more easily how to break
the web applications
so um if you're a developer if you
wanted to go to the red team side
you're probably going to be way awesome
because you're gonna know
what other things you can be
compromising that i don't know because
i'm not on that side of it
and it's also if you're gonna stay on
the development side or do the blue team
side
then you know what people are using to
get into you
and so bhis actually buys
um the command and control when they
retire
and that one's not free right so
for 30 a month you can play inside of
their cyber range but not only do they
have
the old web apps that you can
play with but they actually have lessons
built into it so it teaches you what
you're looking at
at that web app it teaches you how to
compromise it
and so you can build it in a supported
uh
environment so uh
you already heard i have a huge bias
towards
uh black um
because i've learned so much from them
and so this is like
i think a great opportunity um and you
can go on the website you don't have to
like pay the 30
dollars to see what it's like right you
can go in there and poke around a bit
and see like oh is it worth my time what
would it be worth time for
the people in my environment to spend
some time here so
um i think if you use some of the tools
that i'm suggesting here maybe you can
be even better than a hedgehog right
maybe you can coat a porcupine instead
um so again that same week when i was
building this
this job came through right and i was
just like
i can't apply for this job right but a
developer who's been through that other
training
they could probably apply for a job like
this right like if you
code securely and you're um you have
that mentality
of a secure position then when these
jobs come up
out there that we have a huge need for
we can
kind of like piggyback on that code or
pipeline right
and um have our pipeline filled so that
these jobs are fulfilled
so i'm looking for any questions
okay so questions
anybody have any questions
when you're talking about scenarios like
all case scenarios
or just worst cases when i'm
like for the developers i think that
they should focus on
all scenarios right now and then there's
always time and money and there's the
balance right because that's where you
get the pushback right
but i think that the uh oh and i didn't
mention
back when i was going through the slides
but i think that as if you can have
a system where you the posture and the
mentality is already i want to secure
code securely then um
you're going to be able to broaden that
a little more easily right because it's
going to be already within their
bandwidth right like so if some of the
input validation is just automatic and
they're doing that then that gives you
room
to like add something more right and
it's also going to save time again when
the person who's doing the if they
it's a big enough company and you have
that specialized person who's going
through and saying ah
you missed this you missed this right if
it's and not having to have it be sent
back
so i think if you um have that mentality
it's easier to do more than if
than if you're starting from zero
any other questions we got any online
no we do not no not yet okay so i i have
some stories that
uh obviously uh through my many years of
cyber experience coding
hacking and testing all that good stuff
i've been doing this for
over 30 years so one of the stories when
you talk about secure footprint oh by
the way i love that video that was great
when i talk to developers uh through
some of the stuff that i've been dealing
with in the past is that
uh you know a big great example is the
is the zip code field right so you ask
them okay put in the zip code
so they designed it right they don't do
any of the input testing or validation
or any
kind of stuff and so you put in 45431
the area code here
uh in the area but then you're like hey
well what about letters and numbers
right so uh when they're developing this
stuff they should be
only allowed to enter digits
and not alpha alphabet right
and so you know those are ways to test
it so i know
daryl's got some great stories that he's
told through the years with putting in
percent x and some other things in the
input fields and
you know the other one is uh bobby drop
tables is another great
example yep i know how to do that one
[Laughter]
question
no no i'm just talking u.s right yeah no
no no
i'm talking u.s right so when you're
filling out and you get
because it's a u.s address you know
that's where the zip codes are usually
i mean that's you know now expanding out
into the international
well that's that's a different
requirement but again right
based on that input or even phone
numbers right
you know how many times you fill out a
form and you type in
you know extra characters in there um
they're getting better about it because
now it rejects it says
digits only you know you can't even put
in the parentheses for the area code and
the little hyphen for between that
so they're getting better they're
getting smarter the words are getting
out that you know
this development it should be you know
doing this
secure coding earlier in that
development process
that well that's right right like what
you're saying if there's a check right
so like
um if it says maine as the as the state
then it will probably you know the coder
can write it so that it skips that
uh validation and maybe jumps to a
different validation and the same for
the international like you know there
are ways that the coder i mean that's
you know that's the point right the
coder should be able to like think about
what is that
person going to try and stick in there
and how do we keep them
locked into getting just what we want to
get from it yeah i mean
i mean back in my early coding days
right it was
let me get it done to be able to turn in
or do the
do the job right i'll go back later and
fix it
right sure right you've all heard that
we'll go back and fix that later when it
goes to production
and what ends up happening that that
test
stuff gets the into turns into
production and it's never validated so
you know that's why we've got to you
know provide this education and
start doing the earlier processes of
testing and developing
earlier in the life cycle for this stuff
so because you know most typical
programmers they just want to get it
working because then we're moving on to
the next thing
they're lazy you know and they just want
to get it to function
and it's like why would anybody enter
something in anyways because
it says to put in a zip code why would
you put anything different in there
right because that's why most engineers
programmers people think because they
want to get it done
i'd like to offer a friendly challenge
sure are they lazy or are they being
incentivized by the organization
for a different metric than what you
care about make sure they're
incentivized by delivery of features
not going from breaking the critical
delivery dates true
that is a good point right that that
could be that as well
and when you when you say you know other
incentives right when they
uh based on features right microsoft
excel anybody remember a few years back
when uh you know
they got paid by the line of code nobody
actually checked
and it actually had a flight simulator
embedded
because they've got so many extra lines
of code and you've had the right easter
egg you were actually able to launch
some flight simulator out of excel if
you had to write keystrokes
right because nobody checked or
validated based on the number of codes
it was that was that on purpose well
sure it was because they got nobody was
checking but that's an input validation
and let's do some like libraries within
your organization right because i think
um micah makes a very valid point
especially when you're looking
at some of like the agile and you know
you have your two-week sprint and you
have to get
certain things done in that amount of
time and is that my priority
so building that secure posture as part
of your culture
is crucial right and then maybe
incentivizing kind of like what you're
saying like oh
i built this piece of input validation
that we can add to our library
that you know you don't have to like
necessarily start from scratch
and so within your organization having
some templates in place that people can
use for things that are done often
so uh any other questions comments but i
did want to ask
uh you were saying um you're working
with
northern kentucky university university
is part of the nsa
gen cyber program program so that's a is
that a center of excellence through nsa
um well right so thank you for giving me
that back so yes it is a center of
excellence
and um so their program is a center of
excellence but they've also have like a
an additional project there are only 10
in the country
they only award 10 right places the
opportunity to teach a gen cyber class
and so um dr anker
and um he lets you just say dr anker
because his
last name is harder to say than mine so
it is a long
um last name that starts with the ch
chad potty maybe um he
was able to win a
one of the contracts to do the gen cyber
and he spent
two weeks teaching high school teachers
cyber security so that they can get it
into their classrooms and hopefully get
that idea of like oh this might be a fun
thing or
uh to do when i grow up for the high
school students
and it was a whole range you did not
have to be a computer science teacher we
had
um some generalists we starting down
like from the fifth grade
and we had like a chemistry teacher and
a history teacher
and so we talked to them about like well
how can you talk about
uh cyber security in the classroom
depending on what your
area is so you know i think that the uh
cryptography is easy to do in history
right so you can talk about it during
world war two
you can give them or you can talk about
caesar cipher exactly you can talk about
it
even in the ancient history so yeah
so i i was going to add to that right so
i was very fortunate through my through
my career i was actually
given a scholarship through nsa for it
was back then it was called information
assurance scholarship program
and so they they sent me to school to
get my phd and that was paid for by nsa
that's awesome right so that's that's
how i got my phd but
they've it kind of changed the name it's
still available right now through other
various institutions and they're now
formed it out to the universities where
they
have the center of excellence uh and and
so that scholarship is still available
for your and they've gone they've
actually moved it down it used to be
masters phd
but now they now they also do it for
bachelors and they're trying to get it
that pushed down to
the high school levels as well so but
it's now the
cyber security scholarship program but
if you go out to nsa's website they have
all the educational institutions that
are associated with
centers of excellence that are funded by
nsa to teach cyber security and get
enrolled in those programs so
if you're if you know folks that are
trying to get educated looking for extra
help or assistance
a lot of times what they do is if you
accept that scholarship you'll have a
job
on the other end working for a
government entity
where they help place you to actually
then pay back some of that scholarship
money
but you're doing work in cyber security
right you get your degree they pay for
it and then you go and then
they give you a job like i mean how
often do you get to do that kind of
stuff so
that's awesome it's really a great
program so i am a beneficiary of that
and
so one of the things that i try to do is
actually also promote that because
one of the clauses so to speak uh was to
help
advertiser promote right the nsa
scholarship programs
so there are a lot of institutions it's
grown quite a bit over the last few
years
with nsa and i didn't realize northern
kentucky was one of them so yeah
and the cyber academy at muscatatuck is
where i went in is
yeah that's that's nice the cyber range
out there yep yep i was there before it
became that but then they were making
that transition so that's that's pretty
neat where you get to go test some iot
stuff
so it's a nice iot range out there in
indiana so
that was that's pretty neat so if you
get a chance to do that
um the other thing i was going to
mention um
so you were talking about oh nice
initiative i don't know if anybody's
familiar with that national initiative
of cyber security education
right that's uh sponsored by nist right
so they put out all this academia
stuff they work with the various uh
educational
institutions right and and try and help
form uh relationships between the
universities and the businesses and
stuff like that to help promote cyber
security education
so that's a that's another avenue if you
go to nist uh
look at nice national initiative for
cyber security education along with
nsa so that's another avenue to look for
for like scholarships for
for people trying to get you know
bachelor's masters phds and
and cyber security and then also you
know they help partner with
them placement afterwards for for
education
so it's um here in here in dayton uh we
got wright state
and ud and they they also have cybers i
was a
adjunct over at wright state they have a
four plus one program
where you go in your senior year start
taking classes for your master's
you do the four plus one and then you
come out with a master's in cyber
security
so that's a pretty good program so
you're only in five years versus six for
a master's
in cyber security so your your undergrad
will be computer science computer
engineering
something of that nature and then your
masters would be focused on cyber
security uh ud
does more of the uh information
management type
uh or the business side of the house
so that's kind of the relationship
between ud and wright state here in the
in
in the dayton area for for academia so
yes go ahead matt student claire oh yeah
and sinclair thank you
and sinclair they do a lot of uh early
entry-level stuff they help with the
associates
and there's and doing certifications
they work with
the various uh working employees uh so a
lot of their other classes are geared
towards the
the working person so they're they're
either online or at night so you can
you know work towards get your either
your certification or your associates
and then transfer to ohio state wright
state ud
university of cincinnati kentucky now so
um a lot of educational opportunities
but you know this is stuff
that uh is is very critical uh and
you know hopefully as you continue to do
this because you started in
education right transitioned into the
cyber field
right but these are different avenues
that you can use to help with that whole
education
there are more programs coming out that
are
targeted at them like nku has just
recently added i don't
think it goes live until october you can
start your certification process
there and then you can work towards your
masters once it goes live in october
yep so all right anybody yes go ahead
um
yes cedarville is part of uh they are
one of the they were
uh i did a nist a nice conference with
nist a few years ago in cedarville yes
they did have
uh some classes down there that were
part of the i think it was associated
more with nice
not necessarily nsa so but you know part
of that nice thing is is they
develop the curriculum and they share so
they'll say
cedarville we want you to write this
particular class
but you have to share it with the other
universities right and so what they do
is they pick
certain universities to write certain
classes
that they may be more focused on or
their area of expertise based on the
professors that are there and stuff like
that and then they are asked them to
share those modules
to help other universities create a
cyber program
so yes thank you for that and i think
that's the way that gen cyber is kind of
set up that way as well so
like the the curriculum that we wrote
for that two weeks we provide
lesson plans to nsa so that they can put
them out on their website so yeah so
just have that background and then they
form it out to the appropriate
universities institutions and stuff like
that so
and also i saw where sinclair offers
a logistics base
it's like a background
logistics one no okay
right so yeah logistics is huge i mean
we've seen that back in december
with supply chain right yeah
with supply chain that's that's a huge
issue right because if you're purchasing
stuff that is not secure that can be a
challenge too
and they're they're supposedly trusted
um
you know supplies so um refresh me
solarwinds
right so the solar will intact uh
they were how many locations
did they get into because that was a
trusted source supply
right that we thought was all safe and
come to find out uh
they were throwing the ball all these
years or for quite a while
so focus all good stuff anything else
any questions
all right penelope thank you great job
[Applause]