Hi guys, good afternoon everyone, it's
one from here soon I want to thank and
congratulate right they detour a
Silent forest ahead right but seeing Angela is good I
'll share it here on the screen
So I hope everything is ok it's good
no more using  right, moto caught and wait
for me to search
for accident investigation in it's better Vitória
Soares here now I'm going to tell
me this I started the idea of what are
doing the technical course helped after
that times my graduation and postgraduate studies
instead of  another order the new tip that
it is known that the milk graduates Sem
Floresta and I complete in the area that
if this and I answer I am an
information security analyst good is that I
bring some events it is not that I am
part of it but not an example of
get christmas his focus is to join the three
trees in digital law computing
forensics and information security of his
saying Chapter ASP Belém I am saw and
left it recently so
holding my and so magazine no  its
as the cover and then it's exactly the theme of
our presentation basically so
let's quickly right,
Google Maps is basically when
we talk about security right we
always have the layers of protection that
I have a Siena laxus Fairy dance feet
called security but we implement
guarantee a  security we know that
100% Léo tupia security we
always try
and make it a little more difficult, before
it would not be based on that.
top 10 is not a
very interesting survey, he
says that the estimate of damages in faith
2005 is 10 million, right annually, observe
that attackers don't play, no,
on top of that, I'm going to make a small
presentation here, look at
the animal on the screen, so knowing  that Finn
if he is one of the machines that know Top 10
Electro Kids here is part of the concept of
presentation so basically
we always wanted to do the
co campaign  awareness in the last ones when there is
someone who receives that email that
ends up breaking, right And here next to the
machine 1
, André's birthday meaning to who he
is
and the card I have a c2d Remembering
that this is not for
educational purposes  are basically that it would be
the attacker's C2 made a mistake already the company
user pretend trishna icon I already have the
information that will leave here,
o user
Joãozinho Pedro Conde down and receive
a file and say that he was going to report
2020, no one will open it and it will download
the file and execute it
the speech from below where he headed that he wanted
a Shrek at the end of
the rain
that Patricia already downloaded it,
increase it a little bit 1
the report, right
I don't know it will it will open it
doesn't know about it, it
's basically  what's going to happen there, oh,
his goal is not to be encrypted, that
's
good Rangers so don't be made of metal so much
his machine, right as the other
machines, depending on Tocantins
knowing it before, a great part of it already knows  in
making a cake cast there, right to
paint, tried to record as much as it marks
Zé Tô Anyway so here for users you've already
had your machine compromised in that of
a king so on and on the other side
of the attacker himself
Hi bug, the attacker appeared here  already
received all the information the same
machine the empire the time
I don't know if all the information is not
the information of your victim it is
so do it like you didn't even have to enter now
the response team we feel a
truth not here to be able to know  right but it
was like the tram broke then
the head and
G1
and you're going to break it wins more process
friends
Andthen
I
'm coming back to our presentation here
Andthere
and you those Guys should be here and do
n't let security
here basically head of security
and any unwanted or
unexpected event that is confirmed or
suspected related to compromising
operating system and
personal data network security exposure ace  Unauthorized ss
and system modifications
without knowledge in
Good morning, I grew up too, right
in front of what would be in short, right
is this incident response?
Incident response a set of methodologies
that aim to contain and minimize the impacts
of a  city incident comply are the
result of an attack and dies use or even
a large proportion of disaster this phrase
here is a great friend of ours, right,
and let's event that the game Antônio where
this even a little bit that would be an
incident response is following here
so  we talked about fincher And we
also talked about ren waiting so I
did a research in the past, it's
basically yes if your company
suffered a raffle attack with salvation
you would be aware of some
options here with one of turning off the
computer to Rescue  of Disconnect
all cables and give to the support is
scared but don't be calm because type
of mat or tries to solve the incident
or other options  tions there and the result here
PSOL
I'm here at Silêncio's bar yes last year
no one gave more than 20
billion voices so it's the result here between the
next 1479 g36 and almost 15
of these days so basically ac39
percent don't get scared  no longer
keep calm because the person is very
nice is not the second option then try to
solve incidents as usual and the
other option disconnect everything, right connect
by accidents in ideal you have to
isolate the machine here from the esports forensic dentist
and pick up the machine later  who suffered
So, if you're going to try to make a
Dante, we're going to try to do some
procedures to try to see if
Sigma Cristina can get anything from me, then it's in the
methodology that I used oppressed it here from the
beginning, right, it's basically going to be on
top of  response on the back of the incident
on top
Ah ok it's good with me for your title
so basically here we're
using garbage here, no altruism right
So you're talking [ __ ]  I hate a little about
them here so I can believe it's the
evil delight, right, soft, right,
developed by the screen, right, with everything
to get information
acknowledgment that the maximum amount of information in the
job and several and that have already
used Morte and our next one takes the
same what would be the normal
information on platform visa then a
tip How to set up the thought of
sharing action  in which and you
can do the following you can do the
registration storage do an
analysis of all the activities
related in this, all the incidents
that have occurred within your organization and one
other very cool thing, another Miche
speaking briefly and that he has the
capacity to power  share these
threats with others corner me with other
resorts So it would be basically this
here PSOL is I have my mix right then
I have my base, right, there are
several accident information that I
return from feeding you to post
sharing other companies and other
institutions and
That's it will strengthen a lot because
sometimes the neighbor may have had
an incident, he has already registered it. So he
already shared  so on top of
DaquiDali you can try to step
forward, right from the hearing, possible attack from me
if you're going to be anticipating
basically in the personal trash it's Serv
And then yes, now I'm going to do another one, there
's basically enough on a
use not one  seen from within Mal it was
raining here
[Music]
e-books after you Selena Gomez and go,
I feel I have some
Transformers and that can be helped
by some an example if I uninstalled
a mix in more answers installing
others and  with us and come in I'm
sorry I'll be here later dude
music it's Prince Charles and
I'm giving Tom together several
Transformers here that I can  If you're
installing it, it's going to give you a
lot of help on top of these songs,
what
am I doing?
here they are looking for
a will A singu and yes result here
but basically here after you
have your own ones in these ones that are
cpace hash among everyone you may
be looking here not fast here
you can't get something and the hash
car mast take the rest of the
artifacts that you managed to extract and
add here and basically just
right-click on
it and look for it in Mister universe to
scan So my uncle did it, let's
remember a little but it's for  save a little
more time here
oh Whindersson so i made the
scalpel witch told a few other years to
threats that they are correlated
already since you that other teams made
here look that already p  see it so on
top of that here the others
cataloging love go on I'll just do it just walk
here look for more information on this Is
there anything else it was related to
that 20 about incident teaching
that rest I added here I can't
give a right it stopped  at Mixed
and it will not scan
Hi Google how are
you So you can come here
crying here with me a Transformers
in Paris the school
the episode detectors here look
the military open one
What's up
And then you go get these
here and so I don't touch the two
layers of protections either, basically
because I brought it here, o
It's a song of sharing snow
that in Brazil there is no community in
it the president xi right that
aims to share these teeth, right
So be it if you  there is a month that comes
nature in your environment in you
can ask for it, right, it's like
i said i move it may
monday it's with other garbage try to get and
update the ba  If I don't know something
beautiful, I don't think it's worth your while
I look at the other, right
?  like this in the
honey sharing part
on Max, I'm going to go all the way. After you
managed to get all those sweets, right?
Nec
basically such one of these here right And will
do the incident notification part
incident analysis support
incident response management to
found skill and the Cool engine here
is that the education and training part
on information security consume
I made an addendum here  right, basically I
did it here that a few hours is Contour, then
it causes people in your company, right, it
ended up being funny, for a month, it
's good to talk a little bit about how
to train one here is to join the
two teams in this Jardim and Prontinho right
to talk for another let's go PUC this one
is Vivo right I can for all the layers
of security
how was it these
days, attack that we have a one,
he takes you, Mike, right, he has the ttp
Neck, the technical tactics and procedure in
and here in this case it's so I brought it here
so basically let's not attacking uncle,
right  he gathered all the
information, right, several things died there,
as is the name of the employees,
right. Then he goes to the surface
where in the E, it is in molex to take what he
did there, one goes through a step three
here, right, use executed that
malicious file, right  that file to
connect with
the attacker's own silky one, right and Finn here is
there when they can here, right, data in
the execution part was something I
brought here basically with better or in
my technical report po  read Of course that's
not all, but
it's talking about
the incident sports reports with
two others here and pass kimmich I
have one that was provided by the
staff of the only thing that happens I found a lot of
baby food.  model here that you can
find on their own website, right then
location issuer company date that was the
next incident not study the
model you can adapt current
company is not
the one started by Natal a description
state and there Wagner
good guys basically this is just a
few  references that I bring here
were available there, you know, questions,
doubts, we are my contacts and
if they are available to organs. Thank
you very much to all of them and
[Music]