Hi guys, how are you? I'm in crisis, it
's part of the Garoa hacker club and also
several other Communities. Your attention will be
better in a little while and
I would like to thank you for
your presence at this event.
living for the idea for the initiative to
create this track in Portuguese, right to
value our audience, right?
And let's be honest, not everyone in the
market speaks I understood English well, so it
's very important that we take the
initiative to help people  And the
community here at Verdade is the theme
of my conversation with you, I wo
n't even call you a lecture I made some
slides to have an illustration but I
would like if it was more of a
conversation and in the end it was interact a
little with Felipe, right  we're going to
exchange some ideas as well to
complement the ideas that I'm going to.
And then leave the project here on the
slides so the idea of this
conversation is for us to talk a little bit  I
don't think about the communities, right, it doesn't go down, we
have our market, which is
something I think is extremely cool, it
's very positive and how it helps us a
lot from a career point of view.
to foster our own career
even for those who are starting in the market
without a very cool opportunity for
you to enter the market through the
Communities and as they are also a
very cool support in this phase of the pandemic, in
this phase that everyone is isolated
concerned, right, going through a
credits situation so i didn't comment on
the moral achievements i've been working in
the security market for more than 20 years
there as you can see by my non-
white hair right ah i'm one of the
founders of Garoa hacker Club who was the
first guy, ok  this here in Brazil
that we've
been wanting for ten years here in São Paulo also
organized together with some friends they
organize a really cool event that bysite
São Paulo, every time he performs here
in São Paulo, we also celebrate 10 years
of bsides recently,
but unfortunately this year and last year
we didn't hold the event for
him because of the academy and fortunately,
I'm also part of several other
communities in this part  of the pants he
had there and he's part of Once and I'm going to
comment a little bit about these
communities but halfway to the end
of my presentation Okay so let's go
there,
as I commented,
we can talk a little bit about the
communities  and how they help us to
build our career and how they
also help us survive in this
pandemic phase and my motivation to
create this one that can be summarized
in this meme
in off Down in remorse
right along with the rest of the whole world and
then the rest of the whole world gets super
scared desperate because there's one
here give one because there's  a show
locked up at home can only talk about
computers and we talk like that, guys,
but that's not normal, right, so the
guys called quarantine for us,
normal life
It's logical to
discredit the whole social problem, everything
programmed, economic, the
humanitarian crisis that we're going through because
of that, right, but this is a super very
interesting kind of old man for
me to stay in the Home Office to stay
working in my pajamas locked at home and
don't come  no one is normal it's wonderful
right because you're complaining about it right And
this is our life normally right And
then so to open it opaque right then
yeah let's go in the quick
sincere perspective on our
job market here it's impossible to do
technology market and  even
safety marker not to mention the great lack in the
great blackout of professionals that
exists in the area, there is a very
very large demand for professionals  sionals by
professional
and specialized security professionals, but even more
worldwide, ok, this is not only in Brazil and if
I am only in the United States and it is a Global problem,
the people of this want the
same organization responsible for the
famous cissp certification.
right study report on the
work of the job market in the
security area and then leave one from
last year they also started to map the
lack of it not late.
demand for
3.12 million
security professionals around the world, don't you put it
all together to lack veltter for an open vacancy,
we're looking for professionals, etc.
we would need to train immediately
now like this in the blink of an eye
3.12 million people
And then this demand is not what  means
in practice this means what do
we have with 0 unemployment rate in
the insurance market  ance in the
technology market too, right? That is, when
we're talking about the global crisis, the country
is in crisis, it's starting to close, etc.
so it's unemployed. That
's really a serious problem.
skin when you go out on the
street for those who work with technology
for those who work safely in
particular the unemployment rate is zero
you don't get unemployed you are pigs
and sometimes it can take a while for
you to put it in for you to find the job
of your dreams it's not  so it's never
a bed of roses but the fact is we have
a demand for professionals much
greater than the number of
existing professionals and much
greater than the capacity of the general
professional market today.
managers and for the
companies themselves, this is a
very large program which means that
people cannot hire people
to manage their security.
yeah Oh and because of that, companies end up
not being able to protect themselves
properly not that she knew she didn't
do adequate protection right That's
another matter for another ok right but
anyway That they wanted even if they
were on a budget, even if he
was  really comfortable with the
ability to protect themselves, they didn't
want enough professionals to
do this protection and when we
start looking for specialized professionals, they
're like I want
a pentesters, right, I promised mobile I
want the cloud security architecture guy
when you  you can go
into the specifics, then you really don't think
it's whitefly, ok, so this is a
big challenge for the market but for
us it's an opportunity because if we
stay correctly in the ias, we
don't know how to navigate, so we
can find great opportunities
for  job here girl
professional opportunities for example something
i always eat  to my friends, right now,
whoever wants to live only lives in Brazil
because the demand for professionals
worldwide is so great that for us
technology professionals
specialized in security with
professional qualifications we can find
jobs anywhere in the world, okay,
just go  back and quickly you're
employed to work on the photo
Of course if you want to stay in Brazil, it's
super good super respect I'm in
Brazil right I like it in Brazil but it's an
example of the consequences of this
scenario there of demand for professionals
and even  I found it interesting in this report
they give it like that, but this reason is by
country, so we can see, for
example, here in Brazil according to
estimates
of 600,000 security professionals
working in Brazil and there is a demand for
300,000, right.  for every
two professionals that generate one more
to meet this demand and the numbers
are all over the world, they're not very
different from that, okay I'll even do it  It's a
school to provoke you,
right, we know that our market,
which has logic and security market,
is predominantly
male in a few women
working in the market, so I ask
if every two men we would make an effort
to bring one  woman for the
security area we killed this GAP
, this lack of professionals and
solved this this lack of balance
between men and women in the area but they
are spreading what has already been said that
some slides so there is no excuse,
so remembering this.  a
global scenario is a demand in a fragility
of
is very great so the fragility
for companies and again for us it is an
opportunity that we have to consider this
an opportunity for us to pursue a
career we like in a
company we want from  suddenly in a country or
in a branch that we have, the world
has its doors open for us, it's up to
us, right, to take the initiative to take
control  Read about our career of our life
and say, Puts man I don't know I want to
work in Canada, it's always been my dream,
ok, so the effort, I seek fluency
in English, seek some
specific training and come back, we
can, ok, I have many
colleagues  working in the
area they want in the country they
want so they always received a
job offer because the market is
overheated, right for companies, they
are also challenges rts staff so
nowadays that working relationship between
employer and employee is
the former employer sent
employee  and it was like that and it was very
common you see bosses told you like that
man you have to do everything I do it
has to be like I said I do
it, I do it because you'll never find
a better job out there and I'm already
against it today  he is a good professional, he
has so many job offers that he
stays with the company if he wants the
company he wants, okay so we have to
use this  o in our favor OK the first
big message there for me the big
news tip of the day but I
ended up not putting an image to
illustrate this here but we
have a lot of difficulty for the new guys to
enter the security job market
it's super as to why this
happens first because companies
think the main factor is actually
because every company wants to hire a
senior professional and Mega ninja
full of requirements paying the salary at
a bargain price at the concession
And then I said that this  It's a
sincere vision of the market all screwed up. After
this, right, and on the other hand, no
company wants to bring a new guy, no
company that is to train a professional, ok,
so everyone is looking for a
professional
.  find it
when you find it six months later in another
company and steal the professional if you
watch the company that you hired did not
know about your professional, right
?  new to desperate wanting to
enter the market and can't because
there are very few opportunities
for junior professionals to work
I felt in the area, right, the requirements and
vacancies for junior professionals today
this type will fill a page you
say so guys man
intern You are already demanding
knowledge from him to launch, right So
companies are not only not
making the effort to form the base, right and bring
more people on top.
Hi and we see this very constant on
a daily basis, yes you open social networks
There are groups on WhatsApp telegram
that share vacancies in the area It's coming all the
time Senior analyst vacancy
on the list Ninja setra that's not when the
guy says Soares says last you
want it all you want protect so much
to pay so little ok and you see  there are few
vacancies for junior analysts when
there is not
.  They were on the wrong side, right, the
companies' appetite is to try to count on an
analyst who has already graduated, considering that
this is a very limited number of
people and what we need is to bring
new people into their new blood in the
market This companies are not
doing Tabs  the companies that are
concerned about this are really making an effort to
do this kind of thing
and let's be honest, there were the companies
that did, right. There are training programs that are
so concerned about this, but there are several
companies that don't just want to
hire a professional ready.
great difficulty that we
have in this job market to bring
New Blood and for new blood to find a place
in this market, we have to make an
effort to really seek this, and
another aspect is the discrepancy between
men and professionals and opportunities
that the night market gives companies
for men and professionals, you can
easily find surveys on the internet that
show that professionals  female professionals
they are less valued in their
careers they earn room they earn
lower wages than their male colleagues and
they often have fewer
opportunities for career growth
than their male colleagues too, right
I'm just talking about classes and women I  I
'm not covering the entire portfolio, right
All the variety of people
and let's go, it's because as our
market is extremely masculine but it
ends up being very sexist
and prejudiced too so we give
little opportunity for diversity, that
's also if we  this opportunity comes down,
we could
easily solve this problem of
lack of professionals so you can have
an idea only Twenty percent of
technology professionals are women
Eighty percent are men, right? So I
have eighty percent of the woman market,
I only have 20 men in Twenty per
one hundred women and I have a
very big lack of professionals if this is
this  proportion was
fifty-fifty, I bet you there would not be
such a lack of professionals in the
market, which is our big problem today,
so we have to work on
this issue of diversity in the area of
technology and this application of
diversity
to safety and not only bring
transgender women LGBT people of the most different
colors and variations etc. we have to
know how to respect and it becomes more important,
it is not enough just to bring it is not enough to
simply pick up and fill the truck and
download a lot of women in your company
you have to know how to respect these
women without  knowing about
equal opportunities for these women, you have to know how to
treat them with equal with equality with
respect, which is even today our
society is not used to doing
this not technology problem this not
security pollutants problems of
our society but within our
world  we have an infinite number of ways
to improve this situation.
s of our famous new normal how
do we stay in this issue of the
academy first pandemic is
growing until today, right? We are
here in Brazil living the second
wave already talking about a third wave and
Brazil is so innovative that we do not
wait, don't even wait for the second wave to end to
start the third we're already in the middle
of the second wave, it hasn't gone down yet,
we're wanting to do the third
wave right?
the number of
dead people is very large, isn't it a pandemic
that is really a social
problem health problem economic plan in no
way do i want to belittle this about
rita i ask my greatest respect for
everyone lost you a relative a
family friend an acquaintance  I think that
practically nowadays it's practically
impossible
and for someone who hasn't lost
an acquaintance at this award,
I'm unfortunately myself with a t  I get
pissed in an ICU today, it's not because of
the video I think everyone there is
going through this so it's people
who are being hospitalized human
beings who are dying Families who
are losing their loved ones are
companies that are closing down because
of  economic problems right from the
quarantine and Lock Down forced to and
we're there fighting and fighting to
try to survive in this issue of
pandemic when we see these numbers
that we formed which was with this
reality is scary it's scary as a
human being right when you say  that I'm
dying, for example, 12 thousand people a
day in Brazil. That means that, then,
I would say that 10 bonuses fell
in which accident there was on earth in
the 90's here in São Paulo, right then,
falling 10 Boeing per day, the
TAM accident killed  199 people, right, we're
trying to come here who are killing ten
times as much a day here in Brazil,
so these are really
scary numbers.  you don't care, I
do it but you have a little more
awareness you stay at home you protect yourself you
end up depriving yourself of
social contact, depriving yourself
of leisure time that you were used to
because of trying to prevent and prevent the
as  people around you in relation to
no one so it's a social problem it's a
political union Economic problem that
affects everyone I think there's
no one who's going unscathed in this
family it's a different people's point of view
so it's a
very serious concern right.  Morse Lock Down
Here we go here is a photo of
What happened here in São Paulo that for the
first time instituted quarantine in
March 2020, that is, we
have been living this
quarantine crisis situation for more than a year.  collapse in
the health system takes sounds for over a
year living in this
extremely stressful situation, we learned to
live with everyone with a mask, right, the
proposal that these two little signs have
here  in my house it's not a nail on the
door, it's nailed on that house
too, we learned and we were forced to
live with a mask and today it's even part
of our clothing on these days I went
down to get a pizza for delivery
And then I forgot to  put mass it
felt like a naked sequence faced
the rest when I realized
that I was without a mask, I felt like I
was missing some clothes on my body,
right? So this has become a routine
.
Paranoid is now
a time for all of us, right And then we're
all living a
quarantine session some people live
alone two live with relatives live
with relatives right others I live at home with a
lot of people too right so the
situation of living in quarantine  It's not
easy when we talk about which Morse
there is the traditional Home Office there is to
fix the quarantine it's
totally different things the traditional Home Office
normally  even one person
is working at home
while their relatives
are working outside the home, right? The
children are at school, you have
a whole routine of living together, but in the
Home Office of the quarantine, everyone is
in the same space, right, the husband
working online with the wife
who is working online with the
children they are taking online classes and
this whole family nucleus has to
turn around so that that small
family space I can serve everyone for
the decent internet there is a
social program here in Brazil too, right  So
this issue of living in
quarantine lunch during the pandemic period is not a
simple matter, it's not a
simple matter either, and by the way, whoever
has the opportunity to work in the Home
Office at home has a space, it's a blessed one,
right?  large person that
here in Brazil, because the vast majority
of the population does not have a decent job, they do not
have a job that allows them to work from
home and they do  that when there is this
job for me to work from home there
is no longer decent enough domestic texture
for me to work
so whoever has the opportunity to
work in Home Office with their little table
with this little light to make video video
conferencing is a
very Fortune person.  in Brazil, it's the top of the
pyramid, so if you're in this
opportunity, know
and your disadvantaged position, right? And
let's be honest, the vast majority of the
population in Brazil doesn't even have
this internet Vicente, right?
social problems that we have but this
is a subject for another conversation and then
when we do the impact of the gym
at work there are several statistics I
looked for one of them here,
in general, the gym increased
people's stress at work due to the
pressure  of a pandemic situation due
to this pressure of work in the Home
Office, right in the environment is totally
closed with the whole family  locked in the
house too, right? Many companies were
forced to adapt to a tidying up regime
if they didn't have it and they open up with the shampoo
to adapt their way of managing
people is also increasing
stress, right so I think so I
don't think so  I was born in artistic stages
What's with Mia she had a
very big impact on the stress that people
are having a measure of work right and
I see colleagues who are really
stressed so worn out to colleagues
who leave who resigned from the company
who were totally  worn out has
a colleague here asked for 30 days of
vacation because she is totally
stressed out like she will be locked
at home but she will take 30 days stay
disconnected.
I know I can
turn around and say I'm super well I'm
happy I'm not happy The vast majority
of people also identified an
increase in the workload  and they
're also working longer hours because not
everyone can separate properly
If it's the time to stop it's an
increase in the beginning of many work stoppages
in the domestic environment I've already had a
phase where I worked until two three
four five in the morning
This is the Home Office before the gym
this a few years ago because I don't
have to control what time I
have to stop right Unfortunately today I
have and I'll give you two tips the two
things I do I particularly
here right first I defined  for me I only
start working from 10
am because when I
worked at the office the guys
arrived at 10 in the morning so if I
started working at the office at
10 because from home I have to post
work earlier so I put it on break
here, from ten o'clock it also starts to
work, if any WhatsApp e-mail arrives
before 10 o'clock I wait
for 10 o'clock in the morning to start working on
it, right I think  that the excess is
something urgent, access any
important meeting, ok, due to
give due care, but
otherwise I wait from 10
am to start answering then I
could have answered that
WhatsApp before I was there posting here in the
group  family I saw that WhatsApp arrived
the job could have answered before I
could but if I answered that
WhatsApp at 9:30 in the morning I would be giving the
signal at 96 in the morning I was already
working I'm waiting at 10 to
answer that message ok so I
set it to  me the start
time and I was told the
stop time which is obviously a little more
flexible because I'm not here at the
time I like to stay late when
you start work the work doesn't
stop coming, right but
around the time of the soap opera on the Jornal
Nacional I saw him say so, you
understand, I can stop taking it and now it's
enough, you have to turn it yourself,
talk enough  Let's get some rest Let's
turn on the TV let's watch a series let's
watch Big Brother whatever you understand
but watching Big Brother is less
worse than working until 11
o'clock midnight there right every day so
I set myself a moment  at the
beginning and establish one for me
and take a breakpoint, right I leave the TV
on at the end of the day to have that
detergent noise situation
detergent at home I'm working I saw the
little noise ok that's when I see that
SPTV is starting say  Pa, it's
getting late, right, it didn't even dry, the soap opera that's
on then say Oops, it's getting there
when it's time to stop. Did the Jornal
Nacional?
from work and I
recommend everyone to do it
otherwise we get really crazy
working late don't realize you
can't disconnect ok this is a
very graphic problem
eeea  people we communities is not to
support us so much in the matter of careers
and there is a pandemic when we talk
about the communities from the point of view of
career the first thing that had the
communities they are a great source of
knowledge us communities where we the
people of  technology we share
our knowledge freely
and there we are talking
online communities discussion forums group on
WhatsApp that Space
specific communities the community exists for
us to share knowledge among ourselves,
not to share it with
us, to learn together that it is very
important, right  other aspects, right? If
you have the opportunity to study
the self software, right, self-learning,
I'll go back to study, right? You have a lot
of quality material shared
by your colleagues, you can stop and
use this material to study
if they
have a lot of p
the materials, I think they have a lot
of study tools too.  So you
have to have all the material at your
disposal for you to study so you can
learn new things at your disposal
it's just a click away, you
're studying you're learning you're
doing more experimenting you have the
opportunity Food building for
you  testing new things a curiosity
This photo was taken in Garoa, right we
decided to make popcorn in a
can, then I had one on the internet how to
make popcorn in a can of
soda and we did it then it
worked, right, the Roots way of making popcorn
but we have one from the time that
we don't find out What is the
temperature at which the popcorn explodes, right? Then
we got a heat blower EA
Itaguaí light isn't playing, it's a
heat blower in a big corn popcorn for
us to see and what temperature  from that PE
I was going to get out of the popcorn, right when you have
the opportunity to do this even from
your company, which company will let you
use their equipment, right to measure
at  emperatura in Itapipoca explodes That's not
what you can do in this one Face
can do at home you can
try it at home you can raise
a VM hack it tweak it put a
security setting and if that
tool it got it Only really
works right when you're
trying it  there community home
with friends you are learning a lot
more things than your work your
work routine allows you to learn
So there is a very cool role, very
fun, very important, of the
Communities, right and a very
important question the issue of the Network you
end up getting to know  a lot of people you end up
being known, so for those who are
entering the job market,
communities are an excellent
opportunity for you to
meet and become known and
so networking is what moves the
world, and forty percent
of practically the hirings
networking is done in this one
Francisca da, this is more like this pr  The best thing
in practice is now
that we have few
security professionals in this scenario, how do you
think a good professional, right? You have
to have a little professional
usually, by
recommendation, it's the Portuguese word for
the Network, ok then Network you meet
people  will be known by people
is extremely important in
our market and very important for
our career too so participate in
communities will speak at events
put your face to become known
this is very important for your
career What about the academy issue
how things have helped a lot of
people to survive in this moment of
Economy, for example, right
The denial Network versus friendships
we make
pandemic
events are online events right mixtapes events
even short videos chat stream  s
etc that help us to keep
up to date and pass the time, since the
vast majority of hobbies that we
would have in the traditional world have been
curtailed from us, right folks?
to do
is not excellent, this is an excellent
opportunity to study and learn
more. Communities are playing a
lot as it is with lectures with
events, right? So we have
to take advantage of this
quarantine opportunity to study and learn more
is the way to go  geek of surviving a
pandemic
Hi and then I would like to finish this lecture, right,
commenting quickly on some of the
Communities, there are many, many,
I ended up leaving out several
questions I could stay here all day
talking about the Communities, right, but I would like to give an
example.  my tribute and
thank any super important
of these communities so when
hackerspaces my bag effects they will come up
m initially in Europe, then it
was the United States and for the rest
of the world with the proposal that you have a
physical space to bring people together in
interacting about the various aspects of
the
hacker culture.
Technology network security in
general and programming we
talk about hardware we talk
about bi rack too
they are
somehow fighting
and this hashtag is the tip here
in Brazil we have several of those did
we the kid who was the first or she
already drying the hacker laboratory in
Campinas we have hacker Face there in the
south right Uchiha that the  we have the Raul
Hacker Club in Salvador it's not the
Calango in Brasília or the Chapecó
sack up there that I caught several,
right, to get some, in fact, we
have several of those made in the  The
kid's website we keep a list of which
races are undone their assets, ok So
it's worth looking there if there's a
Face arc in your city, interacting with
the people, obviously because of the
gym. All those people are
closed, right, we had  that restricting
our activities that were originally
always face-to-face to stop doing
face-to-face activities regarding the academy and
start doing some activities
online is even some here
and they closed the harassment they had, right
because it was very heavy to maintain the
rent and maintain one of the courses
Headquarters at the moment everyone is
locked up at home, some others Here
people continue with the series,
for example, the boy continued
with our headquarters Campinas LHC The site is
still headquartered too, right but you
of several others who unfortunately
closed  the headquarters kept things and
when we come back to teach, I can
compress them, they will set up a new headquarters
and come back to  face-to-face activities
so it's very important to continue
participating in those fish to continue
fostering these communities
in our cities around us Another
community that I could not fail to
thank and revere is the ASP.net Web
application Project so the
amazing community that produces a lot of
Super material  Cool, paper, top 10, no
tools,
material for you to study,
chapters all over the world, several
chapters in Brazil, chapter in São
Paulo Chapter in Rio
what a loss a community
that is extremely active there in the
market the class that the Relax community is
very cool also when we
started strong which type I had it I did
n't even know that I can post that the
security was already there, go and talk
about  Cloud security is
their main paper on Nelson
Cloud security species he ex  This for over
ten years he was material Pioneer talks
about this subject they have several
gas projects behind Matrix
control Matrix is that without a soul is an
Excel spreadsheet even with all the risks
related to Cloud computing and how
it is referenced  in the
main legislations and regulations and
safety standards of the market and it
helps you to say make a check of what you do
here we have it here I don't have it and even
a high up they have a faith
their own certification sk also they have a
lot of material too  for those who want to
specialize in cloud computing security
So also not
very cool community there you produce a lot of
cool stuff I even just security for me
their being the supplement several other
things is also the good top community
super cool that she that they  have
a wise man and sing in the community
of women security essays in Latin
America that has several chapters of
tranquility here in Brazil also that the
The main objective is obviously to encourage
more women in the security market, to
bring more honesty into the market is to get
the women who already have it and help
train them even
more and take them even further
.  men to help the
project there he called her they
call it laugh China they for them that
basically like that the red people
they allow men interested in
this cause concerned about this to
help bring more conversation help to bring
content lecture training spreading
the community  so the jaguar is a
very new and very cool community and
you always have to take things to make
more women like that. They have several
projects including a project to help in the
training of young people help in the training of
professionals. There are only several injection lines,
too, right  it's worth visiting
their website and getting to know the community
but ah I recently made a post on
my blog
Hi e  so i've identified more than 20
communities of women in technology
more than 20 communities that enjoy and
support more women in the area of
technology and security too so
we have to really embrace these
communities, support and back, right and again
make this our community
security and technology is much more
inclusive and diversified for us, there
is nothing to gain from this, right? It's a
very cool community, it's the
binary mind that has the binary chat also
that YouTube channel, right time I'm even with
their mug
here.  which is a guest very
focused on sharing knowledge, the
videos on the channel are really cool.
We talk a lot about careers. There are
free online courses,
right?  There are videos
on the channel almost daily, it's very worthwhile to follow
a really cool community, right, including
Felipe  to introduce me to college, the
Smart rack, the meat, trying to
bring back that original concept in the
Indica rack, it's a cool thing, it
's a good thing, it's something that has to do
with our culture, it's not
necessarily something more rubbish. Rack exists healthy
totally different things but we
have this one, we don't say, we fight
for the Fair use of the word is that no one
will do it for us.
it's bad
to know criminal right Black is the one who
calls what you want but me when everything
You know that minozzo Cyber measured
computer pirates you see each term
like that but it's bizarre being the sides but
they are totally different things
the hacker is not the person who  he wants to
study in order to learn in order to
change things and the guy who is really
wanting to do something bad is in a
community that I recently discovered
that we are all about  n this
time of pandemic, isn't it? And here's my
provocation, also this mental hacker and
he's not starting, there's not
much yet but it's still provocation, right,
we have to think about our
mental health too, we have to think a
lot about our health  again I see
many colleagues who go through
stress go through stressful situations
some know how to solve some don't know ok
I'll lie if I say that I
never participated in my career
I've had several, right
and we have to be able to
survive  we work in this area
without letting stress and consumption
Have your moment of relaxation, your
Hobby, it doesn't matter what it is, it can
be exercising, it can be brewing
beer, it can be watching a series, but
we have to have our moment of
relaxation rest to
survive the market so stressful
and challenging for the security market.
Doubts, we
'll be following you here today
in the chat but also to bring Felipe
here, call back for us to have a
quick chat Zinho to close this
subject Felipe is also a very good person in the
community, right and has a lot to
add.  then we take the opportunity and comment on
the various other communities that I don't
talk to him my latest body that
there are incredible that supports
and it's not exact man, it's first Thank you
there for taking this madness with
us, right finally then I can
finally say more to  people I who are from
the security community and in Brazil know, right?
Didn't want to don't know before, who doesn't
know anything about information security in
Brazil. I wish I'm fighting
again for this chat, I put
all some things here during the  your
presentation, right? I think it was
sensational because he talked about the
issue of the community school labor market,
I think he touched on a
fundamental point, it is essential to talk about
it, right  And especially when it
comes to new opportunities, because
the market is really that
thing, the incessant search for the Ninja, right, the
guy who is out of his mind, so
literally intelligent market is
that way that pays more, I would end up
taking it And then don't look  a lot for the
professional who is looking for a
change of career or
and the new guy that I was even marked
about four five months ago on Linkedin
a person of cut who is over 45
years old was a guy with a lot of experience
in the technology area but  not
security for about a year
two that he was studying and security
and still didn't have an opportunity he
was clamoring for an opportunity in
information security and it was
interesting in the post he did that he
wrote so I accept a
Junior position  I want to enter the area And then I
saw a network there, it was cool, we
started talking to you in the
private conversation and everything worked out well he
got a job  it wasn't on my
continent of the company that I work
today, it was another company but that
caught my attention because it came to this point,
right everyone, training people needs to help
them, right?
situation, so if we talk about
a community, for example, how
are we doing the event, right, but I didn't even make
a soundtrack in Portuguese organized by
a community called close by
in the United States, right, in theory, he
expects the founders solar is the  overboard the
diosef and there must be more people like that,
right What do you want to organize the channel of
disagreement in this man and then stay there in the
comments
about bertin about by.  About
the rainbow tinel, there are many things that
we have for sure today among all
the things we play with a lot, huh,
chat about the debate about
certifications about this one about this
pandemic
issue, the cheating mental issue, right?
I'm looking at my willing and a
lot of community and I literally I
agree with you dear when you talk about the
Community of events, right I'm
particularly known but it gets into my
head Garcia has nothing Secure
your 2015 And then I started to know the
community, right and get to know  the people the
community And then it's interesting that
we were communities there, or if, for
example, I've already sent an e-mail there to be
able to participate in
voluntary matters because I agree, right This
sharing the same opinion as you,
right?  so it's not because it's
focused on developing or
helping women in the labor market in
technology and also safety and a man
doesn't  you can participate, on the
contrary, I think we have to be a
volunteer and believe in it too,
so I think it's sensational
as many communities have promised and today
what we have most is
and to talk and chat, right That's
what calls remembering a point  It's also
very cool, it's something I had to
discuss, right, password that has today there's a lot of
content on the internet, it's super easy for you to
have access to content, but it's very
difficult to separate even
quality content that happened from the bad, right
then there's a concern  very large number
of professional colleagues and communities
in this type of people who
seek knowledge on the internet are worth trying
to graduate using bad content, they
will graduate full of holes in their
education in their education in the kidneys in
install, then unfortunately they will not be a good
professional  navigation
very big effort in terms of time
I have dedication and if I try to get a
bad content it will graduate very badly and
the c  omunities charge this hole in the
communities you said, door in a
lot of control in the community in
discord' ok I'm sure all
the content is of excellent quality it
's just because the ones that are
freely available that you can eat in
your time
Nerf at any time This is the
quality content, whether the
communities also help you to
separate this chaff from the wheat,
you naturally end up getting involved
in a group of people who are already
more experienced for those who are
starting in the field, right?  the young woman
doesn't because she's changing trucks it
doesn't matter, but you have access to quality content,
right in front of ASP,
it's the open world, yes, of knowledge
about really safe
So much material so much
tool available for free,
just download and leave using it. It's a
vulnerable web service for you to test
your knowledge  right of the top 10 they
hold will tool for you to
fix problems and right then the
communities they produce they
select what is good for you to
learn for you to study go on the
binary mind portal the videos of my session
in saxony in various interviews are
excellent  super cool but they have
they create a lot of videos they are born there are some
courses there so let's go there exposing
geographically forget it with
sensational excellent ones,
please, I think it's fundamental, right, it
's very strong, right, doing one of the
world conferences.
I can even get the defenses with
groups spread across Brazil and around the
world, right and in Brazil today I'll be
able to form part of the defense a São Paulo group from
that part of the team organization
So there's a lot of that, so we
chat a lot about the type of  content, right?
I think it's another
example from
the inside  of a content, right, so
there's this filter, as you said, it
also asked to accept any
content and to give a career guidance to the
independent people, right, regardless of the
sex
in 24, that's possible, right, or I'm an
example of that, right, I've been for six years  I
was coming from a sales career, you
understand, it's unimaginable to think that I
could develop a technical career
in security, right and I even did one, I
gave an interview at the cast point with
Felipe, who is one of Elaine's Uai blinds,
he invited me to  to be the
first one also spent my guest
and he I told him man I was
Diogo's salesman, you understand I had to
explain to him in English that
the possible car was the script.
And then there are a lot
of egg trays and I used to pass by the village
telling the neighbor that he only wants to buy
30 eggs is one in my time he doesn't want
something today I should have it here but
you understand.  Yes, an
expensive career, if I got it, it's possible, it
's just us who did it. Maybe the
most experienced ones are within this
community, security, right?
I feel bad for
those who are watching us, please I
love to go up to the general safety school community,
the club is already in and
they support them, right?
and I, for example,
received it above, I'm talking about my
career, I make plans for a month and a half I
'm seeing this a
development community of dad you don't to
not need it here and dad I don't want to
understand how the developer's mind works
Paiva to this I am
immersed in a comment studying
peace studying the pay structure of
conditionals studying pairs understanding
employees understanding collections how
my conversation works  ersa being a
developer conversation here it's crazy
son it's not the basis I believe in the
community that I have to study the
basis for the head notified to be able to
later I'll come to mine
you already know I said this one that
I would need to do this  no but I
want to learn it's my wish I want to
go running I learned from the community that
I need to lay the foundations, right? So
it's chronology encompasses everything right?
diversified then
you suddenly entered a community You want to
learn safety for example Go focus
here on safety right Then you meet
a community There you are You are
repeating interacting there and you think the
communities are toxic because sometimes
there is a community alone there
toxic people these  communities you're not
going to stay people ends up leaving the one
that gives me that person I've already done that
I've stopped participating in communities
because of  one or two toxic people
got it, but like that There are so many
communities, thank God in this one
unfortunately it's that you have
freedom, community here is
not serving me not talking about the type
of knowledge I want I'm going to get
the other, right today
we have several of them  there are half a dozen
but I left out another 60 or I
always know there, right Oh and there are a lot of those
with heartache because otherwise I'll stay
with you here just talking about the
Communities, so we're having this
opportunity for something you said
like that  right, security is also one of the
technology things, but it feels like
taking the little world of security if it uploads our
video we have careers
within security ok guy who takes a test
it's not the same style as the guy who does
blueteam it's not the same  squirrel of the guy
who does forensics is not the meanest
of the guy who does it here design
security architecture it's all the
squirrels that complement each other Vasco it's
nice to know a little bit  I do everything
because the first person who is cool is
fun but because they complement each other
but so when
you enter the career, you start to
specialize in the specific subject,
so the specialization courses,
the test, are not totally different
from the specialization courses  who works at
luck do blueteam and who are
super nice and super valid legs or
something I already got for my health I want to
study more about soft I was at home
working in a blueteam ok someone went there
recommend i recommend taking a
pentest course i  I said nice guy, it's worth
doing, you know, it's one more knowledge
you deliver so you know how to
defend you have to know how to attack so
you know how to attack always put you
defend OK, but for you to specialize
in that area of work You have to
focus only on your little money  if it's
with the best course I don't take in
that area, because the employer will
look at that there, you understand.  it's just
that he's going to talk to someone else you know how to
hack that's cool It's super worth
my bad Greek but that one else wants to
know if you know how to use the plans that the
blog paces in the air water Leo solution xyz
right Or be it the solution of the day it  that
person
is from that career so only
knowledge that complements each other and
again we have a very
cool opportunity that accident
technology we have several trees
I open there was another one of them is
that we must be agitated, we have
a letter part of the other, it's
something I'm starting to do now I
want to work with concentration and
working with human beings, there's something
that is a separate challenge  There are also
people who are complacent about security,
and people who keep seeing
regulations, creating and revising standards,
etc. I am part of the benitec group
that magazine Listen to security standards
you understand I needed to do this,
I didn't need to, but it's a part
of society, the community
because there's nothing here, you can
even do it here
at ABNT, ok so it's a little help,
I'm kind of making the community and
society the mask  by pentest he will be
able to read an ABNT standard he kills himself
understand why it's boring for dudes But
even and the guy who wrote the standard if
you play him a bar ask
him to see it now find vulnerability on the
site he won't get it was
knowledge  that complement each other and
we have to know how to live with this one with
this diversity of knowledge and
get a little face that
interests you and train as a professional
I think it's super worth
it.
the communities they help a
lot is what we should hear a
lot about it, right Just like me and whoever
ends up showing up a little more End up
listening to it, right Where do I start, right
what do I do  OK, so yes, it's in a
community, I think it spoke well on the
issue of how to detox or it's not perfect
I thought you did
n't comment when we talk about
learning this, you're talking about
something else I said,
it's being  human each human being has
its own learning model So as
much as I say, do it, don't you
understand it that way
so I don't have 15 hair at home.
the same mother that my
brother we open spreads his mother me and they
started a similar career, right I
started doing the initial process he
went to do it with me is ab I finished
he didn't finish because he said EA
to me it's not possible I have to  to be in
person there in the career I used to buy
then I'll go commercial I resurrected
a job technician for security he
went there and became a waiter today I live in
Portugal and he's doing computer
skills hahaha face-to-face But what what Why
el  and there's the learning model so,
for example, I was studying Python, right
Then I told him, man, look at the
videos about Guanabara that I just got to
know about a programming language.
I remember the
name I went to look at the videos and I said
man of the time because the didactic for me is
not worth it no no not
fit for him it fit say the
man the man showed the camera and way
I don't know I couldn't do it
league exactly brought each human being
we have a learning model that
can recommend, right, negative see
YouTube right and so on more
discover how best and
also the community will listen to
various types of examples and will have
to add a lot to you until  a
personal example and it's going to be happening now
it wasn't a place because of the academy and then I'm
looking for things to do to
refresh my mind this week and I
started taking a course in  French at the Alliance
Française I signed up for the French course,
right, basic French, brother joar is flying,
that's not
the cost, it's totally online because,
nowadays, it's totally online when
I took an English course. Spanish course
was all in-person, right classroom  ok
Teacher or private teacher who used
to go to your work ok I'm not
taking classes online right I bought a
book because I don't know how to live without fear
but this step we don't know how to buy
the book that has a PDF handout but I
need  I'm not even using a book, I'm not
using it right, right,
I'm putting things on paper because I'm
a guy who, for me to learn, I
need to scribble, write everything
I know that many people don't, if
I assimilate the knowledge they have  that
enter the ear through the eye, pass through the
brain and reach the hand and the paper that
I don't absorb either, but that
's also the way sometimes before
learning, right ah, there are people in the end
who don't  He used a notebook like that, classmates
and here each blank table, this lady
I believe in the room understood, so it's kind of
important that each person has their way
of learning, right and communities they
end up in a way giving space to
everyone in this inside  the
same community has several ways to
learn and one thing I think is
coolest that I see more interesting than
I see in those fish, this issue
of collective learning, ok because it
's something I always do, all of
us were raised within  a model
where For you to learn for you to
study you have to put a
classroom Where there's a guy in front who is
an Expert a guy or a woman that
Expert Expert in the area and keeps
vomiting content at you and you sit
passively taking notes and  listening to what the
person says and assimilating that,
those fish, they have this
culture of collective learning so
if you arrive, you won't have a
face that  it's having an activity it's not
a person
at a lecture it's a crowd sitting
at a table doing everything together, it's ok
, you know, you get in there in the middle
so let me do it too help me
then Carnival will help you around do
something else to  join Aunt Júlia ok and
I see it often in the fish bag,
right when we had the guy in
attendance and he will soon come
back, everyone, when he
first comes in contact with hackers Face
always that traditional
Duty mentality to get there and  there will be someone who
will pick you up and put you on a
chair in a classroom and will give you
a class and actually that's not it, it's just
those images that I presented there,
everyone around a table
doing four five six  brothers understood this
is a need for collective this is a
learning model that we don't
have in our daily life that we don't
have in the work that we don't have in
the classroom, right And that complements you That
I kind of add that learning
through experimentation through help was
always in my community of it's you
and this one doesn't, don't know that the dear
Mr. Professor graduated teaching the
basics don't you have people that each one
manages more or less and without so together they
add knowledge  and it doesn't with all
the two learned together ok that's a
very nice thing of very
rich communities very rich indeed yes I do the
same and I remember 2015 when I
met her two HC And then when I
met her there and it wasn't much
It's interesting that I went to Garoa and
that's exactly what I got
there to get there, there will be someone lecturing, right, it
's the same I had come from another
world, right?
power seems like Someone
said something dude start tinkering with
electronics if talking about it I'll
get there to see if the first time
big camel dog or there in the pit
bull dog bunch right there isn't a tin room  there's
a lot of sitting at a table as well As it
went and playing with electronics and
talking and talking people like that
on the walls like this decorated talking
on
the guy that's right that's the atmosphere of
the cigar net community, right I think I
came here to learn Arduino  but you see
there in that box there is that one starts to
do and a lot of people a lot of people get
there you go away you weren't used
to this kind of education this
learning model we were
used to the traditional model of
the teacher's classroom spewing knowledge
in the head  of the students passively and
like that again we said
hello how are you, so this is the environment
I don't know the communities Open I
believe in you say Sometimes Depending
on who's there, right For some reason it did
n't work out and go to another one with another
get along really well and have a model of
learning and grow and evolve so that they
keep making this exchange, fine, right
knowledge that I think is more
important. Sometimes the  we schedule there
so the Arduino night you get there
everyone is talking about Star Wars, you
understand, you know the anthem, man who
's doing it, don't you want to understand,
then he totally talks about the
lack of CE programming there and then we
open  there an app and it starts to wake up,
got it And then say it if it was Look I'm
with it here let's root And then someone goes
there and brings an old msx to make it
work But you want the night to give the
anthem Yeah but [ __ ] it is too  here and
I'll be discussing it up
and down, you know, it's Our geek culture
that we have to value And there I
think it's cool that we
can do this I can do Rap, right,
I brought this this
American project that we  even the
guy participates is sensational because nowadays
we're afraid to say no I'm a
hacker because we still don't
unconsciously end up associating right
[ __ ] it's a bad guy right dammit it's a
creative guy right There's a stage number 6
talk in a  from the interviews about
who he does he talks about the mouse he
's a creative guy and it's one of the
phrases right there in the pencil on the beach and it's
interesting to see people thinking about the
United States so we'll go to
Europe and Africa a  people in Australia it's a
matter of politics us Congratulations
Uruguay and it was very interesting
first Uruguay was arrested I'm going to make
a rack it takes one night I don't know if
material was arrested and then explain He
counts 50
the crazy one that is nothing more than this
concept  de Neves, you can't look at the loose I
wanted to delay I wanted to show you that I wanted to
be creative but it's
cool and you open there if there's the G1 any
press service is there fine it
's cover news arrested the biggest hacker in Brazil
when we the criminal understood  she said you
know I want it's naughty driven
it's really stealing the pensioner's money you
know it's just
something funny like I'm a super fan of
Igor right Tauan they're some of the
few professionals in  security that
they are they have embarked very cool
on our new social networks and
communication platform if they put their
own Instagram and they are
sharing a lot of cool stuff even the
project is really
cool Senac is like a CPF style it's
sports right so it's a  CPF with
narrative, right, so it's an event model
that they created, by the way, it
's very cool, isn't it another model
that I think is very cool, very
interesting, very fun to
watch. And they use social media a lot
and they  go through something
that we go through in Garoa so that it's all the
time someone comes to see that the
hacker community Get in there and talk next
help is needed to hack Facebook
invade my ex-girlfriend's
Instagram only we'll take it off
I want to tell you that I
don't know how you're in the
wrong group right here in the quiet here it's hacker
in the sense of that one day use of
knowledge right it's not a bad guy v  You want a
bad guy, got it? You want to make cream,
go put a bad guy Don't talk to
us but don't tell you that I don't,
since you want to do is look for a
bad guy
we security is connected to the
networks we listen a lot on this demand
ok, do mine do mine here for
me this and I'll want another
one
I recover
Instagram password. Answer me like this, from the
table, dude, do you have a forgot password, or
call the bank. They made it easy
not to understand that a way without
doing this, there's no way to do it in your
person, which is a nice thing to
not do that itching  ok, because of the
criminal, we don't do this service
here, don't say that we don't do that
, it's information security, don't do that
so but that's it, it's a fight,
we'll keep talking about it here. I
wanted to thank you, needy  open a
space there for the words signs, right
brigade in your time, right then, the
opportunity to share a
little more knowledge with us, the
person who is the author and not the article, I
thank you for the peace
Oh and leave it open for your
final remarks then I  I would
also like to thank you for the opportunity
to congratulate you for the initiative, right,
to congratulate everyone, you're
watching us and finally, let's
go firm and strong, right, the famous word
phrase is not Together we are stronger, right,
community is very  because of that,
together we are stronger together
we learn better we study
better we better the world and we
can survive this damned Filipe
so it is I also wish a lot, a lot of
strength, a lot of health for everyone, right
I think it has increased a lot  seriously that
we're living So I think everyone,
right, take care of yourself, take care
of your family and friends, it's the
best way it was possible, right ec  How can
we cut it with friends when the
community is so don't let A
Nóia at the academy have to consume, right?
take some good things,
let's find our
way, right Ah, it's locked at home, I'll
ask to study, it's not just the
streets to remember, right?
It
's running again, I don't know many
professionals that colleagues who had
health problems, the hammer rush,
it ends up acting, right, so it ends up becoming
a health problem that you take care of if you
improve, right, but then you don't need to
reach this stage, right?
we knew Care huh right and again there
was a fan just there to
help you to be a help network ok
s take this
kid of ours much more inclusive much
more receptive
we have toxic I think
cool [ __ ] is not black it's cool but it
can all be done with respect right it is without
being toxic Thank you turn off guys and
even the intelligence test