hello good afternoon and welcome back
after a break I hope you are enjoying
b-sides so let's move ahead and see how
to hack the drones before I move I just
want to know how many of you have
already hacked the drone or in you are
you have some plans to hack the drone he
our drone basically we are talking about
severe drones okay it's not the military
drones okay so just to make it clear
yeah you already hacked on you're
planning to do it okay we will see some
of the cases here what people have been
doing in UK like they have been flying
the drones in Gatwick Airport and some
of the area so what turu and what not to
do so we will be taking all those stuff
ok so let's start now
so this is our today's agenda we'll
having a brief introduction about drone
technical perspective what is the drone
and how does it work how does it
communicate then we'll the most
important part we'll also have an
overview of what the drone laws in UK
and then we will see how to hack a drone
like a pro basically the method most of
you must already be aware of that so
we'll see we will apply the similar kind
of method to some of the popular drones
and then we'll also perform we will also
see how to perform GPS spoofing over
another drone which is basically niji a
phantom and then we will see what is the
future with the drones so this is the
future with the drones so the guardian
has reported that rain cone could become
world leader in the billion dollar drone
industry and you can see that Goldman
Sachs says that in by the year 2020
there will be almost 100 billion US
dollar business and PwC has already
launched his own drone unit so is there
someone from PwC working with dawn unit
okay no problem maybe you can set it up
basically PwC is has divided the drone
unit into three major areas wherein they
are deploying drones over an
organization it is also used for
monitoring construction monitoring then
asset maintenance and monitoring this is
a useful resource drone industry insight
which tells you about the business scope
where drones are being used and in
different parts of the world so you can
check the website this will give you a
more updated results so what is roan
drone is basically your flying camera
which can be used to monitor a specific
area or it can be used to take images
drone can also be a flying gun so you
can you know shoot somebody from the sky
it's not for like you and me in general
like and we need to make sure to how to
stop all those things so we will also be
seeing you know somebody should not use
it in the wrong way
so in general drone is your Superman
where in flies in the areas where you
always dreamed of so you can your drone
can be your Superman so when it comes to
the technical features of the drone
these are some of the common technical
features for the drone the first one is
about estimation and control algorithm
so this algorithm helps our drone to fly
in the air and it also helps us to
return back to its previous path so if a
drone lost the control from the
communication control is being lost then
the drone can again come back to to the
path to the base path where it started
flying then drones also comes up with
balancing technology
so anything kept on the drone can be
balanced so this is another feature of
the drone this is mostly used now from
Amazon and likewise different companies
are using for delivering Pisa and
current products it also has onboard
sensors which keep it flying in the air
then it has altimeter which is which
helps to maintain proper height it has
GPS GPS chips which directs the drone in
different location and likewise it has
propellers which which also helps to
maintain a proper algorithm in the air
and it has multiple rotors and batteries
or rotors basically there are multiple
rotors in case if one of the rotor fails
there will be another one as a backup
which helps to keep the drone flying in
there and in terms of battery there are
in general there is a battery for 12
minutes to 40 minutes of support and you
can also add up remove or removable
batteries for depending upon the load
your drone can handle the batteries
flying time can be increased ok now
comes the communication method so these
are the four major communication method
Wi-Fi is one of the most mostly used
communication method which is basically
used to send data from the drone to the
controller and likewise so then there is
a GPS communication which helps
okay fine so I can move around now so we
are talking about the communication
method the second one is GPS
communication which will your drone will
be fitted with different kind of
locations and likewise you can take the
drone to different areas then the third
one is a Bluetooth which is which works
on a specific radius and it also helps
to send data from the drone to the
controller and then we have an RF
transceiver with 900 megahertz to 4.3
which can help to send data from for a
larger distance okay so we come to a
part where in talking about the drone
laws in UK so we have an official guide
from Federal Aviation Authority which
administration which talks about no
drone zone so this was the example which
I was talking about some time back you
guys might have already heard drone
causes get big Airport disruption and a
drone flying close to get big Airport
led to the closure of the runway and
force five flights to be diverted so
this is something you know somebody's
did this silly job and it caused a big
trouble okay so when it comes to no
drone zone these are some specific areas
around UK you're in these have been
marked with different colors and it
defines different areas wherein you
should not fly the drone so we will see
what are these different areas marked
with different colors the first one the
red one is about danger areas which is
basically military areas and high
intensity radio transmission area then
you have prohibited areas which is
airspace area then controlled airspace
aerodrums airports and we have some
restricted areas which are prisons and
nuclear facilities and yellow one
represent the military Aero rooms so if
we check the map this is how it is being
divided so you need to make sure your
drone doesn't fly in these areas and we
have the drone code so drone code
basically gives a guide for anyone who
is trying to fly a civil drone
public place what all rules minimum he
should be following so the first one is
about don't fly in your airport or
airfield you need to stay below 120
meter observe you are drawn at all times
and stay 50 meter away from people and
property and never fly or draw near to
aircraft and enjoy responsibly so
basically you need to have an eye on
your drone it is not something like you
fly a drone and it goes somewhere you
will be the one who will be responsible
we will see how how is the process of
you know mapping the drone with humans
so if you buy a drone it will be mapped
to your you know some kind of identity
this is another example which talks
about flying the drone which talks about
you know keeping a drone at a height of
150 meter and 50 meter away from a
public place or any building and you
need to be away from airports and
airfields also just to point it out if
you try to you know play around near
Airport then you should be aware of that
it's in a criminal offence and you can
go to prison or for up to five years
okay so this is open good website which
talks about another guidelines on how to
fly a drone and we'll see a brief
overview here so as I told as I told you
are responsible for each fight so
whatever task your drone do if it is
taking a picture
you know deviating a privacy so all
those will be directed to you and then
again it talks about you know keeping
yourself away from aviation keep your
drone inside and also you need to learn
how to Dreyer how to fly a drone and the
most important part which is now you
every one of us be aware of about data
privacy so you need to make sure you
consider the rights of privacy
these are some of the latest
developments in terms of drone so we see
there are the new powers for police to
address illegal and unsafe use of drones
and you may soon need to take driving
tests to fly there so how you have the
driving test for driving a car you same
way you need to it's in the process of
you know maybe you will be soon have to
take a test for flying a drone and again
house of Lord had calls for a compulsory
registration of every single drone
flying in the air this is one good
website no-fly zone which maintains a
database of no-fly zone so basically if
you are you don't want that your house
no drone should fly in here by your
house then you need to go to this
website and you need to give your GPS
coordinates so this database will be
used by most almost all of the popular
drones so they make sure even if you try
to take your drone to a specific area
but it is if it is mentioned in this
database then it will not move forward
in that area so let's see what are the
different ways of you know protecting
yourself from the drones
this is another this is the first way
listed here which is about drone
defender so this is a gun which which
which you know helps you to shoot the
drone then it fails down in the on the
ground this is another way which is
being used by the Dutch police you can
see the Dutch cap also on the Eagle so
basically an eagle is used to catch the
drone this is another way drone catching
another drone so there is a drone with a
net and then it will catch a drone
now V being a security geeks will be not
using any of these way we'll see how we
use a laptop or our smartphones and how
do we control the drones so this is I
will be discussing two most popular
drones this is the first one which is
parrot ar.drone and is being
manufactured by a French company and
we'll see this is the technical features
wherein it talks about this is a 1
gigahertz 32-bit ARM processor it has a
Linux OS 1gb RAM and it has front and
round cam it has USB Wi-Fi and
ultrasonic multimeters now when it comes
to well I already the most the biggest
loophole for this particular drone is
that it is using an open Wi-Fi
connection so when a controller is
communicating with the drone it is using
an open Wi-Fi connection and so an even
if he is able to do thin de gate the
controller then he can take over the
drone so we'll see how does it works
this is the typical picture from a
controller perspective this is how a
drone is being looking from it so here
is an iPad which is acting as a
controller so this is a normal scenario
wherein we have iPad which is acting as
a drone controller you can also have
your smart phone which can you know
along with drone there are a number of
apps which if installed can act as a
controller and you have a drone flying
in there now the game changes when when
the hacker comes with the Kali Linux and
with an alpha wireless card so we will
see how does he utilize this so the
first task what we do is I guess most of
you must be running this command in some
of the other does does anyone have used
this command previously before ok where
do you use it
exactly so same wave of how you do a
wireless hacking the first step is to
disconnect the client from the access
points similarly you will be
disconnecting the drone from the
controller so you used a replay command
and you specify the MAC address of the
drone and then you specify the MAC
address of the controller and 20 is the
number of do 10 dication packets which
are enough to disassociate controller
and the drone once it is done you can
connect to the drone so here is a video
demonstration how does this task is
performed
oh there is something wrong
for videos and English ones
okay basically this command if you see
it's as as I specified you specify the
MAC addresses of the client and the
drone and you will be able to disconnect
that so here we have specified thirty
five so once this command is being
executed it will send do 1035 G of
indication packets and the control will
be lost
okay so this is how you can see
okay so you can see there are the
authentic Asian packets being sent and
once all these packets are being sent
you will see that the controller
displays no connection or a controlling
lost
so this is how you can find that
controlling not available so this is how
an controller will be appearing so at
this point of time so before you know
performing this attack you need to be
aware of what are the MAC address range
for parrot ar.drone so this is another
useful website which gives you what are
the MAC address range being assigned to
different products so you can simply go
to a high triple e dot org and find out
for parrot ar.drone what range of MAC
addresses are being assigned
so once the hacker gets control over the
drone he perform a best basic and maps
can he finds out that for this parrot
ar.drone it has open port for FTP as
well as telnet this is one of the issue
with lot of IOT products wherein you
know they are not concentrating on
security so this is just a way of
exporting those over liberties so once
we find out that there is an FTP
connection we try to establish an FTP
connection and once it is established we
have the access to the images videos
whatever images videos are being
captured by the drone you have the
access for all those things
similarly we try to perform a telnet
connection so with this you are able to
get the root access and now you are you
can get you know access to all the
directories the Linux OS which is
running in the drone so once you this is
an again demonstration wherein it will
show you about ten net connection
so this is a root account and wherein
you are able to access all the
directories so you can see there are a
number of things here like there is a
power off there is a reboot so if you do
a reboot or a power of or something
their own falls on the ground
so you see here one's the power of his
connection close so this drone which is
flying in the air it this is how it
happened
so once you have the root access you can
play around with different Linux come on
and find out you know what kind of
processor it is what is the disk space
available and these are all the
processes running under the root account
this is another you know it's showing
the what is the disk space now there is
another way of controlling drone so
basically you can also control your own
using the your browser so how do you do
it
for this we use node.js interpreter and
once you install this you need to clone
the project's git repository and you can
connect to the drones Wi-Fi network and
once you do this you just need to run
the command node dot slash server dot
J's once you run this command simply go
to your browser and type HTTP localhost
with port 3 double-o 1 and with the help
of the browser you will be able to
control the drone ok so when it comes to
controlling the drone from the laptop it
is not as easy and flexible how it is
with your smartphone but there are
multiple things which you can do like
here for example there is a command for
you can write a simple javascript code
which can help you to you know reboot or
power off and there are multiple things
maybe you can spin your drone in the air
for a certain amount of time and
likewise there are multiple tasks which
can be done with the help of different
JavaScript so here there is a brief
example which talks about code to take
off spin clockwise and land so if you
want to explore more about this option
then there is one good resource note
copter calm which will give you know if
somebody's good into programming and
want to explore more options this is one
of the good place he can you know check
it out
then comes another drone which is by the
name DJI phantom and as I mentioned
earlier DJI phantom comes up with the no
fly zone database so here whatever you
know no fly zone or whatever GPS
coordinates you have specified the
database will be maintained and DJI
phantom will not be moving in that
particular area so and there are like
almost more than 10,000 entries which
are marked as no-fly zone but and
another good thing about DJI phantom is
it doesn't have an open Wi-Fi connection
so you cannot simply you know the
authenticate the controller and get
connected but there is a way
GPS spoofing so we perform a GPS
spoofing attack and we try to bypass
this database no-fly zone database and
even if somebody is able to bypass this
it can take the drone in those areas
where it should not go which we saw some
time back this is almost recent kind of
example we are in GPS spoofing attack
was performed and the drug cartels we
are able to hack the u.s. Border Patrol
drone and they took it to some other
area so that they perform the irregular
task of you know so now what is the
problem with GPS signals GPS signals are
the most popular one but again these are
the most popular unauthenticated and
unencrypted protocol in the world so
every one of us use this almost every
one of you uses maybe to find the
location it is also used in the code to
track the criminal tracking the cargo
there are like multiple usage but if GPS
spoofing attack is being performed then
this can even you can play with the
evidence of the court and likewise you
can perform a number of tasks also
another problem with these kind of
issues is it is prone to spoofing attack
so we will see what is basically GPS
spoofing
and how you can perform it on Dzi friend
'm so this is a typical scenario wherein
there is a controller and there is a
drone and his controller will be setting
up the program based on the GPS
coordinates and we will be directing the
drone where he should the dawn should
fly where it should stop so you can see
here after the coordinates have been set
up the drone will be receiving the
signals from the nearby satellite and
based on you know the 3d axis it will be
flying in specific areas so this image
will give you a more much better view
you can in three dimensionally this is
how the drone looks so with whatever GPS
coordinates coordinates are being set up
your drone will be flying accordingly so
this is another 3d view from the drone
now the problem again comes up when a
hacker comes into the picture and he
initiates the GPS spoofing attack
wherein he'll be he'll be directing the
drone to fly in those areas which are
not actually being set up by the
authentic controller so what exactly
does it the hiker will be having the
same kind of GPS signals which can be
downloaded from internet there are
multiple websites which helps you to
download the fresh GPS signals once
those signals are being downloaded you
can perform a replay attack wherein you
play those signals and try to send those
signals to the drone and when the drone
will be as we we know that there is no
you know authentication check from the
drone to the controller even so if the
drone is receiving the signals drone
will try to you know try to understand
it will understand that this is the one
the authentic controller so even if it
tries to send drawn in some restricted
areas drone will be moving in that area
now another point here is in more
of the cases you know when you are
trying to perform GPS spoofing attack
you will find out that the drone and the
controller and the drone are already
connected so first part is you need to
make sure that the the authentic the
origin controller need to be
disassociated with the drone for this
there are certain devices which we'll
see so firstly this is a device hack RF
one which helps you to perform replay
attack so it comes up with a big range
from 1 megahertz to 6 gigahertz and this
is available online you can get it some
to 30 phones now as I was talking about
to disassociate the drone from the
original controller is by using GPS
tzemre
which is an easy way for disconnecting
the receiver from authentic satellite
but it is again not for you and me to
use because there is an offense under
the wire wireless telegraphy act so
knowing you we use such a device to
block GPS signals and if somebody want
to explore more laws this is the website
you can read about in now how do you
tackle GPS spoofing at present there is
no specific countermeasure to fight GPS
spoofing attacks and the biggest
challenge is encrypting civilian GPS and
since it means large update to the
infrastructure and lot of money when
this signals GPS signal started there
were two kind of signals being
distributed the one was for military GPS
signal another one knows for civil
civilian and military where military GPS
signals are encrypted whereas the
civilian one are not encrypted another
way to counter measure is to have a
digital signature wherein you know who
where if the drone is receiving any kind
of signals so if it is coming from the
original source or not that can be
authenticated so when it talked about
the future with drone this is something
in pipeline a company called autonomous
flight they want to transform the city
transportation
and they are in the process of
developing a drone which will which you
know reduces the time of transportation
and a passenger can fly in the drone and
you can reach to the airport from
central London in 12 minutes so this is
something you know in already in the
process and but again this may be again
prone to GPS spoofing attack so in case
passenger reaching to he through airport
he there might be chances that he may
reach to he may be dropped in somewhere
in the River Thames so you need to make
sure that whatever drone you are
planning to make it should be avoided
with GPS spoofing attack these are the
references which I referred and this
these are lists of the URL which has you
know overview of drone laws the slides
will be available on the website so you
can you know refer it to later on that's
it
[Applause]