good afternoon everybody I'm Jessica and
I'm the marketing director of twisting
sharp media we have created awareness
campaigns using videos ambient media and
the power of comedy so I want to talk to
you about doing something different in
your training so when I think about the
kind of training I received before I
came into the security industry this is
going back about five years ago now I
thought about what kind of how did that
make me feel what did I do
and one particular memory really sticks
out to me I was working at Volvo
now-familiar
it was two days before the end of the
month very busy time all I'm thinking
about I need to hit my target I don't
need to think about anything else but
hit mine and my team's target I get that
dreaded phone call from my management
saying you've got to do your training
why have you not done it try and argue
it out can I just give me a couple of
more days I'll do it then it's too late
you've got to do it now so I'm forced
into doing this annual training that
comes around once a year sitting there
it's boring straight away I don't want
to be doing this right now I'm looking
at all this information
I'm skimming through it I'm not actually
engaged with what I'm reading I'm
guessing a lot of the questions I'm
thinking about does this really make me
engaged am I remembering any of these
points no not really I don't remember
anything that I took away from that
training back then so when I started
thinking about what are people doing out
there to get a message that nobody
really wants to listen to what people
doing to help get that message across so
I came across this
300 surely will be winning our way to
your next port of call but before we
lift off we'd like to give you what we
call the bare essentials our safety
aboard this flight even if you fly with
us quite a lot we'd appreciate it if you
take a second look
poor baggage shall be tucked away over
here or under the seat in front of you
we require all passengers to follow a
crew member instructions in light of
science if we happen to switch on the
seatbelt sign please return to your seat
and fasten your seat belt
not so tight as to lose the feeling in
your legs but enough to ensure that it's
snug and that's low across your hips we
recommend you keep your seatbelt
fastened throughout the flight but if
you do need to get up and do the seat
belt by lifting the flip the production
mass does drop down in front of you
don't stop to ask why oh boy if you
could have fun in another color simply
pull down on the mask face okay noise
and mouth in tighten by pulling on both
sides of the elastic now did you all see
what was going on there they were all
completely naked so I remember the first
time seeing this video you're looking
you're looking again yeah they're naked
I'm engaged what's going on what they're
trying to say but you're getting the
message as well because you're engaging
in it it's something different now the
person behind this for the lady called
Jody Williams she was a person that
launched this big campaign now Air New
Zealand were the people that created it
it was called bare essentials to safety
that got 7 million views in 2009 for a
safety video
Berryman New Zealand alone only has
under five million in population
it proves this Gwent a global people
went out there looking for something
found something different so it wasn't
just watching it on a plane it got
people engaged I love this quote that
she talks about because it wasn't just
about having a video it was about
marketing a camp
doing something different you know in
your teams you're probably working with
internal comms communications people
that are helping bring out your
campaigns internally they're the people
you want on your side
they're the people that already are
doing communications all the time so if
you're running training make friends
with these people they're going to help
your training more engaging so when I
think about marketing I think why do we
do marketing why is it important well
it's about changing behavior it's about
stopping and getting people's attention
it's about trying to do something
different to get the same message across
so when I look at this particular
picture you've probably seen many of
these pictures the recycling pictures
they all have changed behavior over time
you know now if you've got a plastic
bottle and you're thinking and he's go
put that in a bin you go to put that in
the general waste somebody probably will
stop being so old recycling is just
there because people have made a choice
you want to be part of that culture and
it's the same thing with you guys in
your training you're trying to get
people to make the right choice but it's
how you're making that right choice so
again when you're asking your employees
to do something different
for them you're asking them to come away
from their day-to-day job the thing that
they're paid to do the thing to them
that's the most important thing you're
asking them to do something different
they don't see the point they don't see
the relevance they don't know why any of
this matters to them why security that's
not my job that's what I tease therefore
I hear that all the time I was one of
those naive people that used to say that
but going back to my story is because of
the kind of training I used to receive I
didn't understand it it made no sense to
me so when you think thinking about
relevance how can we make security
relevant to your employees what they
really care about well they're thinking
about finances family so when you're
thinking about their family if you're
thinking about keeping their family safe
they're more likely to lean in so if
you're doing training and things that
they can carry on at home for example if
you're trying to find information at
home what you're doing what your family
members doing they're looking on YouTube
most likely they're not reading a manual
of loads of information they're doing in
a very different way if you're teaching
them about how to keep their children
safe on social media the likely it is
they'll lean into that training but then
they also might lean into the other
stuff that you're trying to teach them
about keeping the company safe it's
trying to make that relevance connection
as well so they don't just see it as
it's just a work thing now when we talk
about lots of information you can see
that you're skimming through it now just
trying to get that information you're
taking all of that information in
studies show that you only actually take
in 20 percent of what you read what
about now if you're remembering key
points you're not remembering all of
that but whatever I told you if you put
a visual in front of somebody same
information but a visual way the likely
it is you're going to remember it
because you remember in ninety percent
of visual stuff so looking at that
marriage taking ten percent away from it
you can still work out what that image
is Rawdon really reading the content
that you've previously seen
that's a simpler way of seeing it like
your brain will just work it out if he
was trying to think of a word and some
of the words were looked up in the
middle your brain would automatically
try and work out what that word is
rather than lots of information being
shown to you
so for me we ran campaigns with lots of
different organizations and this is some
of the feedback if it's done well and
they lean into the marketing we had
companies doing things with large
character k'tau
they put posters around the place they
showed videos fair enough a huge humor
but they did something different and
when they did this this is the kind of
feedback that our security date team got
from their employees they're talking
about fun engagement people have learned
something that's what we're here to do
the security people you're there to
teach them these things you're the
experts that make it fun I know that's
hard to say in security but try and make
it fun make it relatable to them so
three things to take away from today I
want you to be brave try something
different
don't give them a manual to read and
expect them to remember everything or to
care make friends with you internal
comms
they already market your team already
you want them onside they will help you
if you go and speak to them early they
will help you get that marketing
campaign going
and finally just make it relatable think
of different ways that you can help them
make it relatable and finally if you
look at these two images you're saying
what would you prefer to do if you're
explaining something to somebody in your
home life a friend a family and you were
telling them something about security
how would you do that would you give
them a document with lots of information
on or would you give them a visual or
maybe a video I know which one I choose
thank you
[Applause]
any questions