I'm gangster are we ready okay
I always just pointed out that this has
wit instead of width so I'm gonna do it
with a little bit of style here this is
automated production deployment to wit
HIPPA high-trust compliance the thing to
know here is I am very impatient you can
ask my team anybody I work with I like
stuff to be done right away so I I want
to see changes that I work on get to
production fast if there's the bug fix I
want it fixed and rolled out as quickly
as possible
I want security fixes out fast I want to
know if customers like new features and
please take my word that I'm a better
developer than I am a presenter or slide
creator so along this I go to these tech
conferences and I see people like
Netflix and Instagram delivering code
you know a hundred times a day and it's
awesome because they can really quickly
iterate on new features for their
customers and I'm always jealous when I
leave there they've bought these great
pipelines that they've built but they
also have gigantic teams building them
and I don't so I work a small company
all growing larger every day called life
omec and the other wrinkle is that all
of our data is sensitive data so we
manage the data for doctors and
researchers to analyze their patients so
you know some organizations have a
question of is that sensitive is that
personal and it's like a pretty safe
assumption that everything in our
organization is personal and sensitive
so it's tempting to say well we just
can't move as quickly as Instagram or
Netflix because we have sensitive data
and we're a small team and we want to
maintain compliance but I'd like you
guys to leave with the the hope that you
really can so
let me tell you about this cool idea I
read recently it's called the suckers
choice actually had already done this
presentation before I learned the term
but it just fits so nicely I think too
many people stop when they say something
like well you can have speed or security
you know you can have quality or fast
delivery and I think most of the time
people are just kind of fooling
themselves about that you can you can
think you don't need to phrase it in
terms of something or something else
the suckers choice says just change the
subject to say and so I want security
and speed and so our kong is head of
security for life Oh Megan so I said to
him hey I want to go continuous delivery
all the time with no humans and I just
want to get everything done really fast
and I want to maintain compliance how do
we do that and he says um we can
probably do that so we work together and
I want to show you what we built it's
possible quick overview the tools we use
these are pretty standard but I'm gonna
just I'm gonna refer to things kind of
generically and some further slides so
this keeps you what's what we're using
in mind
AWS we're fully AWS we use two or three
accounts primarily two for this talk so
we have a dev account than a production
account we use get bitbucket
which is really nice because bitbucket
has extra API so that I'll refer to
later we use Jenkins for all of our
build test automation production
deployments and we use JIRA to track
bugs but key for this talk we also use
JIRA to track change management requests
for things like modifications of
production or promotion of a build to
production and finally we use security
tools I didn't list them all but one is
sneak or snake and
yeah so here's the flow from a
developer's machine to a change in
production this is probably pretty
standard I'm gonna go through each of
these steps but we've got you know local
deployment we've got peer reviews we've
got deployment to dev we've got our
change management request and then
finally promotion to production so first
up this should be I hope pretty standard
for everyone
local development on people's machines
this is where you do regular testing
this is where you do unit test creation
we do continuous delivery and before you
can even start to think about continuous
delivery with security you have to think
about continuous delivery with with
quality and does it actually work so if
you're not doing test cases we probably
get to stop listening and just go work
on that problem instead then come back
and learn about security so every change
we put into our master branch goes up
under a pull request in bitbucket
everything is peer reviewed by the team
one of the things they check is that we
have tests and then obviously the pull
request has test automation running
automatically as part of that so then of
course you get the code review and this
is where we will iterate over whether
they've built the right thing whether
there's bugs whether their style
problems whether the test case actually
passed when they run in Jenkins and you
know it's iterative this is like one
little bullet but this is obviously one
of the slowest parts of the process
finally team members click approve and
it gets merged and when it merges it's
gonna go into the dev account of our AWS
account so this is an automatic deploy
every change that goes into master
deploys directly to our dev account and
it's nice so it's this is like instant
integration testing
so after some amount of time Tim it
depends on the team people decide that
whatever's in dev is good enough to go
up to production and so what we want to
do is we want to create a change
management ticket to track the changes
we're making to production so we open a
change management ticket later somebody
approves the ticket and then finally the
build will be deployed to production so
I'm gonna go into all these steps in
more detail but as a high-level that's
how it goes so some key requirements we
have because we want to maintain
compliance a couple different one is
that basically nobody can act alone to
modify production this is probably our
our biggest most key requirement I think
the official phrases separation of duty
where you can't have one person that
just acts maliciously and make some
modification to production so one key
thing that human approvals in the CM
process is is sort of guaranteeing that
at least another person has to be
involved in order to approve the
production change now
the other thing we want to do is we want
to make sure that all of our changes to
production are auditable and kind of the
more history the more data we can get
there the better
that's gonna take time and you'll see
that and we also want to verify that
security scan to run scaredy cans secure
security scans let us validate which
vulnerabilities are in the packages we
use and lets us um it less is just know
sort of where we're exposed at that
level this is where sneak would run or
verrico something like that
all right so here's where my impatience
comes in the CM ticket both me creating
it and somebody else approving it is was
the slowest part of this process because
it just takes I mean it's like you did
all this work and then you got to go
through and dig through all these change
logs to try to figure out what you did
just to create this ticket and then you
gotta wait for somebody to be around to
approve it and it's just know so we're
gonna do a lot better so let me describe
what we got so far this is our old
process developer runs a job in Jenkins
Jenkins will actually prompt the user to
say tell me about all the things you
changed tell me the build you'd like to
promote tell me about the ID of that
build tell me your rollback plan give me
the full list of things that you would
normally have to have and a change in a
change request for production JIRA issue
is then created based on that input and
two things happened right JIRA will send
emails to the human approvers again this
is the old flow and in parallel it'll
kick off another build that says deploy
whenever that Jenkins thing I mean
whatever that JIRA ticket is approved go
ahead and like resume so we've got a
Jenkins jobs it's just spinning waiting
waiting waiting for people to approve
and then you have this left side that
flows down so you've got the JIRA emails
go out
you've got human approvers looking
through what happened then they click
approve Jenkins resumes and it deploys
to production so the - right so here's
where there's some possibility for
improvement one is creating the ticket
so yep we have to list out what changed
that feels pretty pretty mechanical and
a side note has anything been removed
which is actually it's very mechanical
but it's also very easy for a human to
miss and then reviewing the change this
is these are all then these don't take a
human to do bitbucket PRS for all the
changes that seems checkable all PR is
reviewed by peers yeah
seems okay and security scans like
there's no reason for like an actual
breathing person to do this
so here's the new flow the new flow is
developer runs a job to promote and they
fill in an incredibly lame set of
details instead of going through and
listing out all the changes that
happened since the last production
deploy like you normally would do my
personal favorite reason for approve or
for promotion that says newer builds are
better than older builds so I put that
in there and then the change management
ticket is created emails are sent to
approvers but also we have this new
thing called the change management bot
and it says oh I see something happened
here well I'm gonna go ahead and I'm
gonna take over I'm gonna review the
changes and if everything looks good to
me I'm gonna just go ahead and move the
ticket into implementing and it doesn't
always do that it only does that if all
the processes are followed but in the
best case scenario I don't have to
collect any more detail change logs and
humans don't have to review those detail
change logs again that's the best case
scenario so here's the how the CM bot is
actually implemented we have a web hook
coming from JIRA we analyze bitbucket
Jenkins and JIRA to track down all the
details we need in order to make sure
that all the correct processes are
followed then we go in at the change
management bought updates the change
management description so it wipes out
my lame new builds are better than old
builds comment and it actually describes
all the things that have happened since
the last build and then we leave what I
call a verdict which is yeah everything
was good the guy the team followed all
the right processes and I would approve
or mmm
no we found some deviations from what's
normal and a human needs to get involved
so the last step of course is then
acting on that verdict so we either
automatically approved a ticket or or
not so let's go through how we collect
up all that data what the change
management bot is actually doing and how
they all strings together so the bottom
level of our stack is get commits
nothing and surprise here one rule
that's really easy to check is that all
commits must be from a LIFO mech
bitbucket user this is one advantage of
using the life of the bit bucket API is
that it'll actually tie your commits
back to your like org users so you can
kind of see right away is everyone who's
making commits to this repo actually in
your organization surprisingly that's
not the easiest thing for a human
reviewer to do if it wasn't for the tool
we also ensure that all the commits are
fast forwards or all the commits are
merged commits not fast forwards and not
squashes I'll go into why that is but
basically we always want the tree to
look like this so the merges are just
plain merges and commits are from other
people on the team this makes it really
easy to analyze specifically when we get
to this next level here pull requests so
every merge and the master must be
associated with a bitbucket pull request
again the bitbucket API makes this
pretty easy to do you can see bitbucket
pull request links in the merge commits
you can then fetch the bitbucket pull
request you can compare the hashes to
make sure that it's an exact match and
not somebody just making it look like it
is and you can go through the whole
history of the pull request all the
changes that were made and who approved
it and you can really build up like very
high confidence that all the changes are
actually being approved by people who
are not the author
so every build that merges into master
does Jenkins deploy into our dev account
and this is also where we would have the
logs for security scans so when the
build runs it's gonna do the security
scan it's gonna collect the data it's
gonna put it in the console and the
build actually points back to that merge
commit as well so when we on the next
step when we create the change
management ticket to promote something
we can link back to one build exactly so
I'm saying I want to promote connect
widget build one two three and that
point that a specific Jenkins build that
Jenkins build points to a specific merge
commit that merge commit has all the PRS
associated with it and so you can start
to see how from a single change
management request we can work backwards
to this full list of artifacts and
verify that sort of there's nothing
phishing going on in this new promotion
so this is sort of like shifting the
table on its side we've gone to like
bottom up and now we're gonna go one
particular change management request
first thing we're gonna do is we're
going to say okay change management
number three well this says I want to
promote build three to production the
first thing is gonna do is it's gonna
look back and find whatever the last
build was so maybe change management to
was pointing at build two but you know
they didn't have to promote that built
maybe there was maybe we skipped we
never committed merge number two up to
prod so you're just gonna collect the
last build that was associated with the
change management ticket that was
approved and deployed to production so
you can imagine you've got two builds
and then from underneath that you can
collect all the merge commits and from
there you can collect all the pull
requests and you can just step through
and meticulously verify and collect all
the details of what changed who changed
it who approved it did the test run like
where they're security scans done
and you can collect all that from what's
in fraud now - what is going to be in
fraud next so little pros and cons of
the current approach versus the old
approach so automation is extremely good
at walking this full tree of all the
changes that have been made since the
last deploy I am not good at remembering
what I did I'm not good at remembering
what I did this morning let alone two
days ago or three days ago
so I'm bad at I've had it remembering it
I'm also not very good at meticulously
going through and collecting all of that
data but the bots obviously can go
through and list every commit every
author every approval and it's a very
very very accurate changelog of what's
going into production so after its
collected all that data the bot is
really good at lifting it all out nice
and pretty and I would never have done
that I would have done like I said here
I would have done exactly the minimum
amount needed to get it approved by my
security team right I don't have evil
intentions I just have a lot to get done
and I'm not particularly good at
designing comments so automation is much
faster than I am
i digging through to collect all this
data would take me significantly longer
than you know API calls so here's an
example of one of the commits one of the
comments we put in our change management
tickets so this is a good one you can
see it said well I found the last
approval was changed management number
one one two six seven it was closed
fraud because it deployed successfully
the new build is connect widget 319 and
it says that these are the changes so
one merge commit with a linked pull
request all green check boxes with a
description of everything that's changed
there so I would never have taken the
time to make something just nice I would
have said something like
we mists we missed a property it's just
a simple bug fix come on please you know
something like that right but like this
is fantastic and so you can look through
and see it every single time now here's
an example where things did not go as
smoothly so in this case you can see the
verdict on top which is no I'm not going
to approve this for you this says
something humans are needed because some
deviations were found and it highlights
the deviation amongst all the things
that we're good right so we still have
the audit log and we've got kind of
overlaid with a judgment about whether
those changes were good changes or not
good changes so in this case you can see
the last one it says there was a problem
with the added zip file commit and it's
because there was a commit author who
didn't match a known user now you can
see from the author tag that this was
just like somebody hadn't quite set up
his laptop for the first day of work and
nobody caught it in the review process
and so this is the kind of like this is
great right like this caught what could
have been a real problem it also gave
the security team enough information to
to make a judgment about whether this is
right so like maybe Oracle looks at this
and he says okay well who's Joe like you
know but he's gonna know right away oh
yeah sure Joe he's just hired the other
day he hasn't configured his machine
I'll approve this it sounds right I can
look at the commit I can go just right
to that commit so even when it does fall
back to human approval it's still faster
than it was before so we'll do a little
pro and con for the approval side versus
automation automation super good at
going through and verifying that every
change is exactly like it's required to
be I'm gonna go through some edge cases
next that humans would be very
hard-pressed to catch
the automation does not have a problem
with that and human approvers just like
human developers are vulnerable to being
rushed and spot-checking changes right
if they've got this is like their 50th
change management ticket for the day
and they've got something else going on
or their kids has a soccer game I mean
what's the chances that maybe they take
a shortcut
wait the automation is just never gonna
do that so this is one of those cases
where it's like you get better results
and it's faster at the same time I mean
this is this is just all this is all
good stuff there's no reason to think
that security has to be a slowdown this
is more secure and quicker automation is
good at catching edge cases and human
approvers you know I give no good things
about developers hmm that's weird
so there's there's we have better things
to do than this like the time that we
get back we can work high-level features
we can look at big picture security
stuff we're not wasting our entire day
reviewing changes of what happened in
production right there's just no value
in that not not for the business again
automation is way faster than humans and
automation never has a weekend or a
sleepy or as a family problem than
humans do so let's do the real you know
hardcore why is this even better than
not just is it faster and more
meticulous but I think there's some real
edge cases here that humans just are not
capable of catching so the first one
that jumped out to me when I started
implementing this was detecting changes
in merge commits so if you are familiar
with git and particularly the tools like
web tools you've got this PR that looks
good and it's got a button that says
merge right you click merge well no one
on the team actually a no clue looks at
that merge commit
right like you approved the changes you
were looking at and then you click the
button and a new commit appeared and no
one ever checked out that commit right
like everyone just sort of assumes that
the tool is doing the right thing no one
is slipping extra code into that merge
commit I mean you can easily make
modifications in a merge commit but no
one no one verifies that no one no one
approves it and so one thing that the
automation can do is it can actually go
through and verify that all of the
convert the merge commits are what I
consider empty commits which is every
change in the merge commit comes from
either the target branch or the source
branch and no one snuck anything in so
even if a human is merging manually on
the command line which some people can
you know you do no one's sneaking
something in so if there's a merge
conflict in there somehow and they have
to do a manual change the bots actually
gonna catch that and say someone just
made a change that was like non-trivial
and wasn't approved by somebody else so
humans gonna dig in and look at it the
other case it's very very hard to catch
especially with the UI's as they're
currently written and I'm thinking
github and bitbucket is that what
happens when you have one PR with
multiple committers so I commit
something my team reviews then somebody
else commits something and it sure looks
like everyone's approved but that last
change just went in is it like how does
this work and the UI is unless you
configure I'm just right or you're
really good at looking at the activity
page it's very easy to be confused and
think that everyone has actually
reviewed it but again this is where the
bitbucket API is really great because
you can look through the change log of
when a commit was added who approved
after that commit and you can really
verify that every commit in the PR is
actually actually being reviewed by
other people I guess you can't you can't
verify that they did a good job
reviewing it but you can at least verify
that they are saying that they did and
clicking the button in line with all of
the updates
so something that surprised me when we
first rolled this out is that we started
detecting commits it had been removed so
if you are looking through the history
of what changed when you like craft your
response for but these are all the
things I've changed since the last of
limited-production
you don't see the stuff that like got
taken out of the history but when you do
a get revision to revision compare the
bots can actually detect that and they
can say hey you you actually took out
some commits and in our case we say if
you're taking commits out of production
that's not something that's ever gonna
be approved you're gonna have to get a
human approval to explain it and then
squash merges that are an odd case
they're a bit like that merge commit
case this is one that I don't love but
we're kind of stuck with right now which
is a squash commit it's saying I have
all these changes and someone approved
them and then I clicked squash because I
like a pretty line in my kit history I
mean it's for like so something right so
you want the pretty line see I'll count
this to a squash commit I'll get all
that cruft of like back and forth and
it'll just go into a single commit well
the problem is like no one's reviewing
that squash commit to verify that it's
the same as the ones that you had done
so if I was a malicious person I would I
would get approvals and all my changes I
would click squash and I would edit that
commit so that it was different than
what people had approved right and a
human is very unlikely to catch that so
in our case we just really can't handle
it there's this is one place where the
bitbucket API just kind of falls down
once you've squashed it's lost the
history for what had been approved like
sort of pre squash and so I can't easily
do a diff I'd love it if there was a way
or if somebody has an idea of how you
could make this work because it's
something that bites us all the time you
can see the last bullet here which is
changing culture and this is something
that I'm probably most excited about the
changing culture not the last shame
point but basically every single new
higher clique squash because they think
they're being nice and making it look
pretty and then their team is blocked
and has to have a human approve
something and you know they quickly
never click that button again and
there's no way you can turn that off in
the bitbucket
UI right now it's really a shame I wish
we could just say like for our org never
never never allow squashing because we
want that audit trail we want if someone
was to look back at our history of get
changes we want to see a link to an
approval from peers for every single
change right that's what it looks like
in our change management ticket that's
what it should look like in our get
history and our bitbucket api's we want
to see that really strict list of
approvals all right so changing culture
this is cool this is even cooler than
moving quickly worst case scenario is
that you fall back to human review so
there's no trouble there's no jail
nobody getting fired if you didn't
follow the right processes but it's just
like it was before you have to explain
to somebody else why you made the
changes you made not so bad but now
because the worst case is to fall back
to human review and human review is slow
or inconvenient the team's really
eagerly try to follow the right
processes to avoid this like sort of
slight penalty so you get this incentive
of moving really quickly when all the
security processes are followed and the
team's naturally reinforce this behavior
they're like please do not use squash
newbie because I don't want to be
blocked from promoting my bug fix you
know on a Saturday morning right I'm
rushing to get this done I don't want
you to be the reason that slows me down
and they don't say I don't want security
team who's not working on Saturday to be
the reason they're saying it's you who
didn't follow the process right so you
get this really nice this feature of
like self-regulating teams and then
the security team doesn't have to play
the bad guy anymore right so in some
ways the security team gets to be the
hero here what happens is someone makes
a change let's say they forgot to
something happened with the PR and they
accidentally merge before they should
have and not every change was completely
approved the change management bot says
no no no no no like this isn't this is
not legit you can't you can't deploy
this and then the security team gets to
come in and save the day they're like no
let's go through it together right let's
work together and we can fix it and so
they actually come and sort of like
rescue this otherwise broken state so I
think just in terms of cultural dynamics
and incentives having the tool do a lot
of the grunt work check the processes is
actually like a win for people in an
organization so this lasts this fourth
bullet here motivation this just came up
last week we had a problem that I was
working on it was a Saturday morning
something was broken in production we
needed to do a slight tweak to mmm maybe
a dynamo configuration so one way I
could have done it is I could have
opened up a change management ticket
that said and again I got to fill in
details here so I say like oh I really
want to modify this dynamo table because
this thing's broken and I just give me
manual access and I'll just make the
change real quick and then I'll be done
with it
promise I'll write down what I did right
and you know like that happens that's
fine but it was Saturday and I knew I
was gonna get a slow approval like I
mean I wouldn't expect anyone to be
working on a Saturday so but if I
automate it if I did all of my changes
as code and I could just find some team
members to review my code for me well
now I can promote it to prod I can
deploy it I don't have to bug anyone
well on other than my own teammates and
my changes have been put into code right
I could have tested them I have had to
deploy to dev first so there's lots of
things here that I kind of like motivate
teams to do just by having this in
of really fast deployments so the future
there's a lot more you can do especially
if you hook on to this notion of
changing culture so one thing we could
do starting at the bottom is more
security scans so maybe we say well now
in order to get to keep the fast
approval to promotion you need to also
scan with new security tool number three
right and there you can say you don't
have to do it I mean we will just have
to manually verify all your changes if
you don't but if you do well you can
keep this really fast automatic
promotion right and this is a nice way
to have a conversation in my opinion and
again I'm coming from the dev side of
things I would say okay yeah that sounds
fine right like I'm happy to implement
this tool to keep this nice little
carrot it's totally worth it to me to do
that I'll jump to the top we use
terraform for all of our changes to
production infrastructure well and dev
infrastructure and I think there's
definitely room to improve even if
everyone on the team has approved a
deletion of a dynamo table maybe it
makes sense to just never allow deleting
dynamo tables as like a fully automated
rollout to production and that's
something that would be hard for a team
to catch doing manual approvals Trekkies
you're gonna dig through all the
terraform file changes no but you know
automation could catch that and it could
flag it and then allowing automatic roll
backs I said that it will catch when
things get taken out but in some cases
like a rollback you're very
intentionally taking all changes since
the last approval out and there's no
reason why we couldn't say well if
you're asking for every single change
since the last approved failed to be
taken out of production that's a lot
like a rollback and if the last build
was approved and maybe it's only been a
day since that happened
and maybe Pedro doodies going off maybe
it just automatically allows the
rollback I mean especially if Pedro GT
was going off that could be a fantastic
hook so there's a lot of work for sure
and since we built it the first time
through you heard our Kong yesterday
talking about Jupiter 1 and Jupiter 1
does a lot of data collection for you so
if you don't want to re-implement all of
this that I did they have been nice
enough to open-source a library that
will automatically make some of these
judgments and data collections for you
it's here the Jupiter 1 change
management client it would save you an
absolute enormous amount of time I wish
that it had been there when we first had
this idea but no no luck so you guys
should definitely take advantage of it
and thank you I think we have a couple
time for questions
a little bit
if I don't get your question now just
please write me my messages are open on
Twitter so you can just write me so the
open sort just work with get bucket I
will work with the order like github
okay I'm sure that it works with
bitbucket right now I know that we have
github integration in Jupiter one in
general I don't know oh okay erica is
telling me that his open-source version
is actually better than my closed source
version so that's a fail for me um we're
gonna have to switch over yeah
apparently the open source one has
github too so we do something very
similar and in my experience when you're
working with auditors and they've seen
the same solution patterns they never
give it much thought they're just kind
of saying oh we've seen this before a
thousand times we're just gonna check
our box when they see something like
this all of a sudden they have to
reinterpret all of the requirements and
start making judgment calls and it
invites this whack-a-mole game where I
guess one of the areas we saw the the
most whack-a-mole games is even nested
relationships where they start to
question who Heather who has
authorization and access control to turn
off PR requests who has authorization
and access control to change things that
you're depending on in JIRA so I'm
curious what type of whack-a-mole games
did you get into with with HIPAA
auditors yeah I think you're right in
some ways those béchamel are actually
like kind of good questions in that they
are almost more in line with like how
you really secure your infrastructure
than the normal types of questions but I
can say that after going through
auditors we've done this for two or
maybe three years now the response has
always been well you guys really know
what you're doing yes it's different but
this is really great this is a breeze so
in general it's been positive
but yeah I could see not everyone
getting that same experience some places
the compliance regime to do separation
of duties the approval on the PR was
somehow sufficient is that not true in
your environment like like you already
have a second person required for
approval right so now it seems like you
have three right yeah so so the part
about no one can act alone is definitely
that separation of duties aspect and so
one side of it is all the changes have
been reviewed by peers which is kind of
separation but not quite and then
there's a question of who makes the
judgment about whether it goes into
production and so in our case the bot is
actually sort of acting as that
separation to say you know these are
well established rules that the
organisation has already agreed upon and
codified so that's sort of that that's
that alternate identity I think did you
yeah so the question was those green
check boxes of those picked by the
development teams or or picked at an
organization or by like an independent
party and we were a small company so we
have one security team and for us it was
a collaboration between what rules would
be sufficient to make security and
development both happy and they're
implemented one time the teams don't get
to pick on its an organization level
this is what it means to be ready for
production do we have any more questions
so the way you have this setup it
assumes that everybody's constantly
checking into the trunk well it assumes
that people are anything that goes out
to our development environment or
anything that's going to be promoted to
production is ultimately going into
master so then how do you deal what do
you guys do branching do you do like and
then how does is it all done through
feature flags and then when a set of
separate code branches have to be merged
back in how do you deal with that big
merge or do you not have that issue we
do use feature flags a lot to avoid that
issue we tend to go small interative
changes like the launch dark approach to
features so we don't get a lot of
long-lived side feature branches you
could do that and have it go to dev
without a problem that that would mean
you could very easily do a deploy to dev
on a branch when it goes to production
you're gonna have to merge and I haven't
heard a lot of people doing like multi
branch deploys to prod so that's not
hasn't been an issue for us we do do
lots of small changes instead of long
branches
okay so that's time let's give a hand
format
[Applause]