one my name is Morgan Roman hi they work
with me and this is about how to prevent
developers from doing bad things with
your existing framework and essentially
stopping them from shooting themselves
in the foot okay I call it banning foot
guns so quickly about me I work on the
application security team I work at
DocuSign I have two others standing over
there and I want to give special thanks
to a couple people who helped with
building out this process and to
ultimately decide what led to all this
we were tired playing whack-a-mole
with bugs and that's why you have me
right there playing whack-a-mole at RSA
at some vendor booth so want to
introduce that and I want to make one
thing very very clear I'm gonna use
examples with lots of weird little
frameworks and libraries it's this is a
strategy it's not particular to any
library and you can use this in whatever
so if this example I will show you will
be in.net you can totally use it in like
a rails app or something like that and
also if something confuses you and you
just want to ask a question right away
I'm actually totally open to just
someone raising their hand and yelling
it out because it's kind of fun alright
so let me get to the very simple idea
the whole principle behind this all and
it's basically this you have a and B the
developer or really anyone wants to get
from A to B anyone know how you get from
A to B straight-line that's it developer
will always take the easy way the
straight-line the issue and the entire
crux of this presentation and this idea
is this this is the secure way you have
to do validation you have to do encoding
you have to do with lots of logging you
have to figure out what's going on
behind the scenes right you have the
secure way in the easy way and they are
not the same and that is the entire
principle and the whole goal is the
following to make the secure way the
easy way because the developer doesn't I
mean they might care about the security
but ultimately they will always just
take the easy way to be able to ship
faster so I want to nail this in really
well
this is bad this is good bad good we all
got this all right so this is great
right and this is like our ideal and I'm
just kind of like here's the castle in
the sky so the developers will do
whatever is simplest right and if it's
the simplest it's a lot easier to train
and you won't get in anyone's way they
won't have to make this tough decision
like this guy so I also want to mention
that I'm not really reinventing the
wheel I'm sorry I'm not inventing the
wheel here I'm just reusing something
that's already been done and so I want
to go through a handful of existing
examples on what has already been done
to do this exact same process so let's
go into that just a little bit the first
one is how to reduce XSS right so
there's a lot of frameworks out there
react to angular or whatever and by the
way I will have a lot of code in this
presentation they're just gonna be
little snippets like this but if you
want to take a minute to like take it in
just let me know if I'm going a little
fast but essentially react says okay
instead of you know interpolating HTML
or whatever user input inside the thing
by default we will just encode whatever
variables that you put into JSX
but if you really absolutely need to and
you can see on the second line have some
dangerous HTML you know and then you get
HTML in the page which is the essence of
cross-site scripting is when one user
can put HTML on the page that doesn't
come from the website itself and it's
able to take over another user's page
then what you get is you get hey this is
dangerous don't do this you scare them
this is something Tonya talked about and
I would quite liked you know that and I
think it was Clint who did like date was
it unsafe cryptography md5 hash or
something like that which I absolutely
loved but essentially the same concept
is right here you developers will
usually just not use this because like
oh it looks dangerous right and it's not
the default way so let's talk about
string concatenation aka sequel
injection so sequel injection
basically it's just when you have a nice
string that you're going to send into
sequel to execute a sequel command and
then you just so happen to have some
user control parameter in it and then
somebody you know they're they're real
jerk and they just go ahead and put
something horrible and they're like I
don't know that and then dump the whole
database not not the best thing in the
world but as it turns out there's a
thing called ORM S which is object
relational mapper z-- and they usually
just let you do most sequel commands
without having you do dynamic sequel
whatsoever and have you know basically
handles all those situations so this is
the exact same command on the second
line which is just filter by you know
the name whatever the user controlled
variable is but I want to point out with
this in both these cases the developers
just wanted to query the database they
didn't really want to shoot themselves
in the foot they were just trying to do
what their jobs so but we've already
made it a lot safer just by introducing
an ORM by having it go on this filter
rather than dynamic sequel you just
ruled out a lot of sequel injection all
right let's talk about xxe in dotnet so
by default in previous versions of.net
they would allow you to get this bug
called xxe which is essentially you
define a variable in the DTD the
document type definitions and that
variable can access places on the
filesystem do all sorts of nasty things
explode the file to be massive a lot of
nasty stuff right and then to turn it
off you had to say prohibit this thing
to true but by default it was just
totally allowed because it was in the
XML specification honestly the only
people that ever use this were hackers
so and I I mean I enjoyed it I find a
lot of findings with this but nowadays
since by default dotnet just says all
right this is prohibited and you have to
turn it back on then developers do it
the safe way because it's on by default
so you can just see this it reads from
the filesystem right there and it'll
evaluate it but I want to emphasize one
more time the developers just wanted to
parse XML they do not want to shoot
themselves in the foot so
how do we do this how do we make the
easy way to the secure way so we've seen
some examples that have been done before
but obviously not all your problems have
been solved otherwise we wouldn't be
talking here right so I have a four step
process that I just follow and I do this
so basically I find the bad pattern
right I make the I make sure that the
bad pattern is just something I see a
lot so if I see a lot of cross-site
scripting in a site or I see a lot of
rito-san decide for example for all
sorts of reasons I'll just find that and
then I'll make the safe pattern the
default one so find a way of writing a
wrapper class and I'll show you exactly
how to do this and then I'll even show
you how to train the developers and like
the most efficient way and then a really
quick way to build some tools to enforce
these new rules because you don't want
to just make a rule and then you can't
do anything about it if someone breaks
it so let's talk about an example read
us
this is regex denial service to explain
what that is essentially if you have an
inefficient regex or a user control
budget regex that is inefficient you
will basically open yourself up to
saying okay this can be resolved in
non-constant time it's basically having
a for loop in a for loop so you have of
n-squared
for those who have taken computer
science courses and the safe way you
just wrap it in a timeout that's all it
is so the developer has to remember
every time they use regex
to include that little time span from
seconds right do they always remember
does anyone think they will always
remember you all right I'll talk to you
later
but they have to remember that and
that's a that's not the best thing so
here's some code to just make it safe by
default by the way I kind of like
sanitized it so be you know a lot
shorter but essentially you don't really
need to know everything that's going on
here ultimately if I recommend you just
have one of your app sack engineers or
engineer write this if you're not the
most technical person but ultimately the
only thing is this default timeout is
one second now you can make it two
seconds it doesn't really matter it's
just that there is a timeout and that's
what makes it safe by default and then
down below on the couple other lines I
just had this my safe regex class
inherit
the rest of the base regex class and
that's it any questions about this
before I move on cool so here's the
sample training now you can take a
picture of this but I'm gonna give you a
even better slide take a picture of what
you'll actually have the template right
and you just have basically two
sentences explaining why this is bad
what you should do instead
and then the examples below and if you
notice the examples below are very short
very sweet it says what they shouldn't
do and what they should do and they look
about the same length so it doesn't look
that much harder for the developer so
here's actually the format take a
picture of the slide because it's a good
one right if you use the bad way the bad
thing will happen instead use the good
way since it stops the bad thing do not
do this do this instead you basically
have the entire template for most
developer training right if you have a
better idea go ahead and do it
I found this extremely effective and
just hey wanted done and I'll break this
down a little bit so I really recommend
you don't include Securi lingo so well I
can just go here yeah there's x''k see
everywhere right and people here will
get me right but developers that would
take a long time to explain and they
just say oh you could write to the file
system that's bad right and we can and
you can talk about that and that way
they get it right away also show the
example how they intend to do it right
before you show them the right way now
there you may disagree with this but I
quite like this and I've seen it be very
effective and if you really want you can
include a details about a loss so how
often or when should you train the
developers what I found a lot of success
for is when the developer gets access to
the project or repository because at
that point they're usually very excited
they want to put in their first commit
and you say okay here are the rules
welcome right and then on any sort of
you know reasonable cadence so once a
year or once every six months whatever
you find is appropriate for where you
work
retrain for their specific department so
if they're working on a Ruby project
don't give them the dotnet training
footprint plain simple right it's just
not relevant to them and this way if you
keep remembering to do this you're not
this security guard because well doesn't
look too effective and in fact we can do
this in an automatic way so here's code
analysis for regex denial of service and
I'm a huge fan of a thing called deaf
skin it's made by Microsoft it's free
basically it's grep and with some JSON
configuration files and I can break it
down how it all works but ultimately you
just look for a pattern like that now
that's about 80% and that's all you need
and if you really want to go more in
depth in a more complex way you can just
use something like Rosslyn or any other
static analysis tool and this little
code snippet right here just gets you
the type for the whatever type that the
class that you're looking at so you can
ban classes alright this is a JSON file
it looks painful to read I'm gonna break
it down for you but this is the regex
class rule very similar to what I use
for dems def skin basically you start
with a very simple rule it's just new
regex and then I had to do a breakout
for the parentheses very very simple
it's very important that you have a
clear description right and then maybe
even link to some documentation if a
developer ever sees this you might look
through these first but if you add it to
maybe your CI CD pipeline you want to
make sure that it's developer friendly
they know what to do they know what to
use instead right so right there it says
please use safe my safe regex class to
generate this rather than the standard
regex library and then by optional my
optional thing this is one of the things
I like about Def Jam is you'd have
exclusions and they're really simple and
it's very powerful all right well you
were taking a picture I saw it you good
okay I don't want to interrupt anybody
so when you when should you do this
right so while the developer is coding
in the IDE IDE is great I work at a
company where people use lots of
different development tools and work on
lots of different projects so it's a bit
difficult to do and I couldn't really
get adoption so instead I found out the
developers are very open to feedback
during pull requests so basically we
include this as part of the CI CD
pipeline right at that point when
developers are most open to hearing for
suggestions and also I recommend doing
on your own cadence it's like if you say
once a month months once a week whatever
you choose for the entire code base that
way you can catch anything that previous
stuff didn't find and this place of
course is target is the security team so
we have made it very easy to stop regex
now service in your entire code base all
we did was find the bad pattern make it
the safe pattern the default one and
then build tools to enforce these rules
easy let's talk about xxe so here's some
code basically we have the sax parser
now I'm not picking on them for any
particular reason other than they just
showed up but in their using Java and
you get this same xxe problem so what
you can do is simply inherit make your
own safe you know sax parser and I
recommend doing it the exact same way as
they do so they use a factory method so
I just say all right we're gonna use the
factory method as well and then I just
say do this and you make it safe by
default and this way the developer
doesn't have to remember that because I
won't remember that crazy set feature
URL thing and then you have the training
this falls the same format as the slide
I talked about that had that format
essentially you just want to have
something like okay don't use sax parser
the bad thing will happen and then use
my safe XML parser Factory and then it
blocks the attacker from doing these
kind of attacks and then you have a very
clear example what's safe and what's
unsafe and then voila here is your
static analysis simple have the pattern
once again it's meant to be about 80%
good and but then again it's just a
quick line of regex right there so you
get it done very fast and then once
again I want to emphasize having a good
description good recommendation is vital
for a good communication this one I went
through very fast so are there any
questions about this one
cool you all get it very nice
all right so we made it easy to stop xxe
we followed these four steps and we just
solved that across your entire code base
congratulations now you just have to do
the work all right let's talk about it
another bug I like to call this one a
fun one how'd you get an email like this
anyone want to tell me what's fishy yep
you're gonna get rerouted some big bank
comm redirect some evil fishing site
comm and you know you got to stop mr.
robot from hacking you by giving him
your username password obviously so this
is an open redirect essentially you have
a site that looks like it's legitimate
but then it'll redirect you to somewhere
evil and then they fish people so you
trick users and even then actually can
get cross-site scripting if you if the
payload is this just this little
JavaScript column whatever script you
want and we often recommend people to
use whitelist and then we often get
stuff like this so once again audience
participation let's play spot the bug
anyone want to tell me what's wrong with
this you're smiling so you know
sorry I can't hear ya that's going you
hope you're alright but that's that's
that's a fun one the dot he's so he said
that the dot is a wildcard character any
character you want so it could be you
know my safe website be calm and then
whatever else you want in your URL what
else is bad
anyone want I also want to tell me
what's bad yes clearly not well done all
right yeah that's the bad part and then
here are some things that'll get totally
past this whitelist and by the way this
comes from in a real example I've looked
at before and I asked hey please fix
this and then I get white lists like
this and I'm like yeah I can break
around that really fast they don't they
don't check the protocol right so you
can just okay cool
put JavaScript alert they don't
understand that the dots are wild cards
and they don't check for like if it's a
domain or subdomain so the string is
terminated or not yeah oh I'm I'm sorry
that's hard to read I should fix that
but my safe web site XCOM evil website
calm so bad sub domain but it still
validates the regex
then evil site calm and then in the
query string so question mark foo equals
my safe website com sorry for making
this is hard to read and then the last
one I give as an example it's JavaScript
: alert and then my safe website calm
because it would just totally validate
the regex right there sorry any other
questions about this slide but this idea
cool so if you rely on the developer to
always build this they might often make
mistakes because they daren't thinking
about crazy breakouts you know if you're
the app second engineer you're the
person who breaks things so the person
they're the people that make things so
often times now I'm going to show you
the code for this one because it
actually gets kind of annoying ly
complex so I'll just explain it you make
a safe redirect function or class
depending what you decide and you just
have like an internal redirect method
that blocks all non HTTP protocols why
do you need a redirect to an FTP site
well you might but if you really need to
you can add that's special case in there
and then only Brett allows redirects to
your site you can kind of assume these
are safe and this is great because you
rule out a huge amount of them because
okay you're redirecting to a site you
home and it's definitely not gonna have
JavaScript in it great but then you can
also add this external redirect for the
times you do need to redirect to
external sites and you can set this up
to require a whitelist as part of the
parameters and if the what is it if the
developer puts in like an empty list you
can pick that up with stack analysis
fairly quickly so let's talk about some
really basic rules that we can write and
essentially grep for with dev skin like
I said I'm I'm a fan of this tool but
you can use whatever tool that suits you
right you have this pattern so fairly
simple find this redirect it's kind of
one of those things you write and never
read because you can see all those
lovely question marks and you know back
slashes and stuff and then you have sort
of conditions that can you know say it's
totally safe if you're using safe
redirect and then I want to emphasize
only aim for about 80% you're never
going to get these perfect but if you
aim to make it good you can get there
pretty well and then you also have other
rules and you can add things like oh if
it's extraordinary for us to go take a
look and make sure that the whitelist is
good right so you have high priority
rules and then low priority rules
because things that you know are
definitely hey you're not following the
rules here or the ones there like you're
probably doing the right thing let's
just double check okay let's talk about
another bug the dangers of server side
request forgery basically if you can
call one server and get it to talk to
any other server so basically the server
that you're talking to and you're able
to get through the
in this case is able to call other
servers inside the data center and that
variable is user controlled then you can
just bypass the firewall because you
could say well this this server is on
the internal network fallout fairly
useful you can get past a lot of IP
whitelisting it's a great and powerful
bug and you know it's kind of scary so
what could you do with server side
request forgery
once again audience participation for
those of you who know tell me what you
think you can do with this just shout it
out yep
what's another one oh he sorry I should
say that cuz he doesn't have a
microphone call internal API internally
sorry internal IPs and then use that to
take down your system
you got one sorry
yeah metadata endpoints listen to those
and get some private information
exfiltrate that I like that one so I
don't have that as an example for the
answer so alright I'm just gonna give it
to you so you get past them firewall and
you call internal IPs
you can call external servers with very
long responses and this is a good way to
have a denial service attack gets the
server will you know take a very long
time to parse it you do file read as it
turns out that's fun and you can do a
file right and what happens when you
write the overwrite the default HTML in
an iis server this is kind of obscure
knowledge anyone know basically take the
site down and you do that with one
request it's quite fun got in trouble
once now I can talk about that ok so
sometimes you actually do have to make
web calls right this is a feature and I
have this horrifying acronym right there
SSR FAS so it's horrible but it's
something that a lot of applications do
have to do like they have a web hook but
you can make it a lot safer and just say
hey don't use the standard HB request
library use our safe wrapper class that
blocks internal IPs have a built-in
timeout blocks calls to the file system
or like can limit certain things so it's
like if it's doing an internal IP call
and you're normally blocking that that's
a great thing to law because that can
usually pick up a lot of hackers because
who else is doing that
and you have the state version make sure
inherits all the base abilities of your
standard web client library ok we're
gonna go over all these steps one more
time because I want to hammer it in and
hammer how you make the secure way and
the easy way the same thing so you look
for the bad pattern and what I like to
do is I look for a common sort of sync
if you think about it so everything
boils down to one thing so if you're
looking for sequel injection everything
really boils down to dynamic sequel now
there are other ways but everything
really boils down to one
thing in particular and if I see that
I'm like oh I can abstract that pattern
and make it safer
so three examples that we went through
in this case you know to do a regex and
none'll service it has to reach a
regular expression xec requires that you
parse xml you can't do xxe with json I
hope you can't and open redirects
require some place redirecting that's
how you that's how you find this right
you find these sort of problems right
there and then you make the safe pattern
the default one so we did this one for
reg external service but you have your
like safe reg X or my safe reg X in this
case and it has a default timeout you
know you have a coder do this once right
you might have to maintain this but it's
worth maintaining and then finally you
should train the developers use safe
pattern if you haven't taken a picture
of this it's super valuable and it's
like my go-to because I don't like to
write a lot of things but I do like
having a template and just have ad lips
and voila done right so this I this is
my favorite thing
and then always include an example
because otherwise they won't get it and
build tools to enforce the rules you
don't have to use the same tools that I
recommended there are a lot of good
stuff out there use whatever that you
like and it's easy for you to integrate
with your system I'm just a fan because
I know how to write regex and most
people know how to edit the regex and
it's fairly easy and I just have a super
grab
right and then make sure that it's only
about 80% effective because otherwise
you'll be spending hours and hours
trying to fix it
so finally go back to the main things
find the bad pattern make a safe pattern
build train the developers to use the
safe pattern and build tools to enforce
these rules so that way you don't always
have to keep watching and you ultimately
make this secure way the easy way all
right thank you all any questions
[Applause]
cool I assume you all learned everything
oh sorry
he thinks it's great by the way yeah I
think I think it's great in are there
any bug classes you feel like this is
not a good approach for I have not had
the best well no there here's an example
of where I've seen it work really well
and the same bug class and then really
badly on a different project so
authorization issues so in one project
basically all authorization went through
one class so I just looked for every
controller that didn't use that class
and it was like well they did this for
me like this is easy but then project
where authorization was like you know
weird layers and layers of calls like I
just couldn't use this like it I
couldn't find a common sink that's the
main thing that like makes this useful
or not is if you can find a common sink
or a common point where the bug happens
then you could probably use this but if
you can't it's just not applicable cool
does that answer it very well
what coping so he asked what coping
techniques to do that I have for working
with organizations with thousands of
code bases well I kind of work at one as
you guys know we have way we have a lot
of code bases and a lot of acquisitions
the the main thing is I so I can't
always hook into their CI CD pipelines
and oftentimes it's gonna be in a
completely different language I've never
seen before but which is annoying but if
I have seen it before I usually just
have my my rules and I just run them
again because that's what you can do
with dev skin and I have it saved in a
JSON file which is nice so I can reuse
work I've done in cases where okay now
we need to implement a new version of
this library because it's you know a
different code base or in a different
version of the same framework or
something like that you just have to do
the like work on that and you have to
choose the most what's the word like the
most valuable applications to do do to
do this on sure so I think maybe you
just answered my question but it was a
little unclear if you were pulling on a
regular schedule and then running a tool
or if you were blocking on the merge
request or if you were pushing for them
to run the tool in the IDE
I don't do the IDE one but the other two
I do so I I have not had a lot of luck
with the IDE method because they just
ended up too many projects and too many
weird some people using sublime some
people using Visual Studio etc etc right
and it rather gets annoying riding a
plugin for everything but I have found a
lot of success on pull requests so
though I highly recommend you just scan
thered if you don't scan like everything
in there PR but just the diff or every
file in there PR and then scanning on a
regular cadence I have a kind of timer
that I just do this on a weekly basis
and I just get you know Monday morning a
kind of oh this is a weird thing and I
might talk about this in a separate talk
but ultimately I do get me a git commit
from a week ago
run the scan cuz it's fast enough to do
that I do this it automatically happens
it's
don't even check until Monday do the
scan on a git commit a week ago and then
do the scan on I get commit now and then
do the diff of that output of the tool
and then I have all the new bad for that
week and that gives me like a good thing
to start on Monday morning sure in the
world of dynamic languages where you can
sometimes do frightening things with
monkey patching and whatnot where do you
find to be a useful place for for those
types of tooling do you ever try and you
know add logs every time someone calls
the unsecure md5 thing by rewriting a
thing or or is there a point where where
you're like yeah I'll just stick with
the static stuff because you don't you
know it doesn't have side effects gotcha
so he asked with dynamic language is
some like Ruby Python JavaScript I mean
even with dynamic languages you do write
the code before you ship it thankfully
so you do get to see the code and you do
get to see the pattern so the example of
open redirects you know if it's in like
like in a node.js app I can think of
essentially you most of them will have
the pattern res dot redirect or response
I'll redirect so why I like instead of
using like a full thing like es Lent or
like more complicated static analysis
tools just using super grep or dev skim
or whatever right or grab is it doesn't
need to be able to parse the code it
doesn't need to be able to compile it
because he'll sometimes you can't
compile it just for some reason requires
ridiculous configurations or it's a
dynamic language so you don't compile it
so while I like that is that helps in
that case but then again it's the
dynamic language so who knows what it
does and I think that's fine thank you
well thank you all