okay so
okay please welcome Hennis and you were
going to talk about me Asha always thank
you thank you yeah my name is Hannes and
I talked on the last two born hacks
already over midrash yes so this time I
will focus more about the stuff we did
in the within the last year but I will
also give first a brief introduction to
my office then my current situation also
and then what I what I find noteworthy
over the last year and this is an old
slide this is mainly three points its
conics which is repository signing then
a dns stack and then calif project I've
been working on over the last years so
what does me Russia is it is well I like
this visualization of a stack what we
commonly use as a service so we use
applications so the application is just
on top on top of year and the
application contains of some
configuration files distributed in your
file system somewhere then an
application binary and the binary is
like the dynamically linked interpreted
Python script or something like that so
you also have a language runtime like
the Python language runtime or the C
language runtime so the Dipsy and so on
and that's only the stuff you see or you
you you face on your application side
what you are actually interested in but
then you also have this operating system
which is usually a fully fledged system
with user processes kernel threads and
file system and networks tag and this is
all implemented in the kernel and this
very general purpose and very much and
then you execute basically that
application within that operating system
on top of a hypervisor so the hypervisor
is another operating system which
manages all these virtual machines so
you have a lot of layers of abstraction
and a lot of layers of
coat which are the year and so debugging
all of that stuff is complex because you
need to go down drill down some layers
every now and then and then you have to
get to know to the file system kernel
code or so in order to debug concrete
problem so how that application is
basically the top of the iceberg is
basically the code you actually care
about the code you developed the stuff
you do but then you have the bottom of
the iceberg which you can't see and that
is the code that the operating system
insists you to to use and insist you to
you need and whenever there are security
issues in an application also or
security application here two issues in
a whole program you have to take into
consideration that also the code you
don't care about but which is part of
the operating system might be vulnerable
so any security issue also in the
operating system may affect your
application or your deployment so what
does it mean Russia's me Russia is is a
library operating system where each of
these systems is tailored and tailored
exactly for that purpose so only a
single purpose Virtual Machine it mostly
or mainly targets hypervisor technology
as well but instead of but we reduce the
trusted code base so we reduce the
attack surface drastically and we also
reduce the number of attack vectors so
the different ways you can get into the
system are smaller because we use a high
level program language and we reduce the
trusted code base or the attack surface
by reducing the code size so instead of
having everything in there you have a
various single purpose operating system
which solves exactly one problem so
compared to a conventional stack on the
left me rephrase on the right only
contains runtime system and
the application code itself so you don't
have the general purpose operating
system and all of that kernel services
because usually you don't need it if
you're running a single service and a
single service might now be a DNS
resolver or something like that so now I
wanted to briefly give you a
demonstration of how such maraj system
may work and in order to do that I
prepared a very simple application I
hope you can you can see that this is
huge as I can get mm-hmm so what is a
midrash OS what is a simple term in
Russia as eunuch kernel well it is
obviously a hello world application
which at the moment only says hello but
it does though so it defines here a
function that is a function it's called
start so it's the main function of an
application and it says oh yeah well
here's a recursive loop and please
execute the loop four times that is done
here and the loop function goes goes
around and prints prints hello this is
done we had this locks call and then it
sleeps for a second and then calls
itself with print Assessor will execute
itself four times this is the whole
operating system I want to show you it's
yeah only ten lines of code with me
Roger as we now can target different
backends with that thing and we also
need to take care about some more
compile time dependencies and some
marshaling so we need to configure the
operating system as well and the
configuration in this case is very
simple we say at the top level that we
want to register a thing a virtual
machine called hello and it should just
execute main with some default time
source so we have the time source and
other
sources from the operating system
explicit instead of them being implicit
so if you want to use the random number
generator you have to say so if you want
to use a file system you have to say so
and you have to deal with that
complexity already a programming
language so there's no big UNIX sockets
API or POSIX API which is there already
but you have you start with nothing so
there's nothing there and if you want to
use any resource any external resource
also like the console or the network
interface you have to configure that
explicitly now what does this register
here do it says main and maintenance
just a reference to uni kernel dot hello
that is this stuff we saw here above
it's the module hello and the final
unicorn oh and it gets its signature as
basically it gets passed a time so a
time source and it will return a drop so
the start here also actually gets a time
which is here of of a specific type so
the it's a module which has a specific
API and that is defined here in the
midrash time LWT okay now we have those
two files and now we have a command-line
utility which is called Mirage and now
we can run Mirage configure Mirage
configure will generate some code and
afterwards we can say make which will
build the code and now we end up with
for the binary called
hello which is a symlink to that file
which is which is 64 bits dynamically
linked executable which in this case
depends on the threading library and the
lip mm and the lips II so it's a normal
UNIX executable I can execute it on UNIX
and I see the output I would expect so
it says four times hello to me so that
is the
basic thing so it's only your next
executable which is dynamically linked
against some more system libraries plus
it contains some more criminal code
which is compiled to native code and
then statically linked so although oh
camon code is directly in there the size
of this unicorn also this is a hello
world example and the size is at the
moment 11 megabyte which yeah
is not very great we can distribute that
will become a bit smaller but there's
also a Oh camel o camel itself is a very
active language so it's not yet finished
and there are some opportunities to
reduce the code size and we can get it
actually down to 700 kilobytes or so but
as an alternative I can say me Raj
configure - t4 targets and then I say
you KVM you KVM is some back-end which
initially targeted only KVM on linux
which is a hypervisor technology but
nowadays is the same piece of software
is able to target other platforms other
heart of us as well in this case I'm
running here FreeBSD system so targets
freebies the hypervisor called beehive
and behalf a similar to a VM type 2
hypervisor so it requires you to use the
virtualization bits of your CPU and it
doesn't do the emulation so it requires
EBT for the extended page tables and VDD
and VTX only but and now I can execute
that now executing a KVM virtual machine
usually on linux requires you to run QA
mode to emulate all the system resources
so the network interfaces and the
console and the VGA and whatever we
thought this is a bit complex and bit
too much code so together with some
people from IBM research
children called solo 5 which is minimal
minimal thing which can run in the host
system in order to manage virtual
machines this is called UK VM bin at the
moment and UK VM bin gets as an argument
so the midrash configure and make now
producing boundary called hello dot uk'
VM which is completely statically linked
executable so there's no dynamic linking
anymore involved and it doesn't run as a
UNIX binary because it's not a UNIX
binary it's an elf binary but it
requires to be run inside of such a
solar 5 system or yeah and so now I can
execute that what I see here what we see
here is the same output
so again application said hello four
times but before that we see the boot
screen of solar 5 so solar 5 was just
initialized with 500 mega self memory we
can actually would use that by giving it
only let's say 60 megabytes of memory 16
is not enough yeah
24 is enough yet currently still not
finished but we can get away with less
memory we just need to three go to the O
camel runtime environment mm-hmm which
we haven't done so so that that is what
we can do with me ROG so we have the
very same code base and on the one side
we can execute it as a UNIX binary on
the other side we can execute it as a
virtual machine and this wall works not
only with a hello world applications but
also with other applications with which
use network connections and block
devices and so on so what is supported
in inside of Miraj these days in terms
of protocols is what I
this is likely incomplete but this is at
least first show what what is there and
not the question is why it is difficult
to implement the new protocol for me
Roger s a fool camel and the reason is
because we actually write that all from
scratch because we write it in all
camels so we don't reuse any systems
code written and see and yeah developing
protocols in in Oh camel like developing
protocols and other high-level languages
is quite some quite some effort but if
we have a tcp/ip stack we have an HTTP
implementation server implementation
actually - server implementations then
we have a DHCP server we have an A
student and Cambridge also worked on a
BGP implementation I worked as already
outlined in on a DNS implementation and
also some let's encrypt stuff then we
have a partial working ssh server
implementation we have a TLS
implementation which is now for 4 years
old i think it still legs
TLS 1.3 which was just finalized the
other day but yeah i've some some
branches for that then we have a good
implementation which is pretty complete
so we can pull and push to get
repositories to the remote site but we
can also use a git repository inside of
our virtual machine without having it on
a block device so we can have a git
clone and a git checkout which is purely
done in memory so you just yeah you
don't need to have a lot of persistent
storage for a lot of services and in my
opinion then we have a partially working
open PGP implementation which I think
we'll talk about on Tuesday a bit more
and yeah we have some monitoring and
logging support for syslog and
Prometheus and in flux TB and SNMP
what are the targets so what are the
targeted platforms and initially it
started out as a exempt reject meter RS
so the initial target was then it was
done it was initially developed by some
of the people over also part of the Zen
team then as I mentioned we switched
over to also be able to run on KVM
nowadays we also can run on beehive on
freebsd and even on vm m from the
OpenBSD project another hypervisor we
can run on is mu in separation kernel
which is in my opinion very interesting
because it is removing a lot of
dynamically resource allocation away and
also does doesn't only statically
resource allocation and this developed
in SPARC ADA so in a language which is
also not prone to various spatial and
temporal memory safety issues backends
on in the the name of system so hardware
processors is MD 64 which is yeah
deployed everywhere so the x86 64 bit
then we also target arm the post and
3200 64-bit for Xen and 32 and for KVM
and 64-bit and then we can also target
the so called cloud like Google compute
engine and Amazon and telecoms cloud
maybe so what what happened inside of
the Oh camel and me Raja has ecosystem
within the last year it is I think major
changes that we reworked the build
system and we now adapted to a high
percentage new build system which is
actually easier to use than the others
especially for newcomers because you
don't have to deal around you don't have
to further round with three different
file types and so on and it does not
depend on the old tools so to say so we
can hopefully in the future get rid of
some layers of a
strike of abstraction and layers of
names which are no longer required then
open up amidst the open is okay my own
package manager that is finally that
will finally soon see as major its
second major release and that is great
because there has been work over the
last three years on open to and this
finally dear so there's currently a
fourth release candidate and it will be
released as the final in in September we
also worked on the documentation
generation front so that is more the
local community which worked on that
which generates API documentation and
they even embedded it to have a workflow
to write to be able to write a book so
they write the book and some Styles some
markdown style thing but include some
code examples and these code examples
can be extracted and can be compiled
them so to ensure that while you've read
your book your code example actually
working and I think that's great and I
hope that we will be able to adapt that
same library for writing some some texts
and somehow tools about mirages then
also within the last year Oh camel did
some major releases and one was for six
where strings are no longer mutable they
used to be mutable since the beginning
and then they switched over and made
strings immutable and now finally by
default all the strings are immutable
obviously that breaking change for old
code which hasn't been maintained for
quite some time and we also needed to
adapt quite some quite some code to be
safe with immutable strings since the
beginning of this year I'm working on at
a nonprofit company called the Center
for the cultivation of Technology and
Germany and I am working there with
project called whoa
which is which goal is to develop robust
digital infrastructure and our real goal
is to enable more people to run their
own digital infrastructure and and be
able to take back control over their
data we try to collect money we are
donations or and and/or commercial
contracts and/or public funding and
everything we develop is open-source and
we are obviously still looking for
donations and also for contracts now for
the first big project I've been working
on is Connect which is repository
signing I've been working on that since
nearly four years I think and this is
now the fifth prototype implementation
and the fifth design after after I met
with one of the professors who designed
the base system which I base based and
design and the user Tron so it's based
on the update framework from Justin
couples and others what is the the main
goal here is to establish trust into
community repositories and community
repositories are for example a packet
repository where every author submits
their own packet so you don't have a you
don't want to have a single point of
trust or at least I don't want to have a
thing upon the frost and I also don't
want to have to trust the repository
server because that might be compromised
at some point so how does that work in
connects each package is maintained by
its author or a team of authors and the
author is supposed supposed to sign
their package on every release and
signing the package includes the
checksum of the table all of the release
but also the built instructions and the
dependencies like external dependencies
to libraries and and then if every
package also does that the only
Connection we are missing is who's now
responsible
for which package name because we have a
globally unique namespace of oak ml
packages because we need to formulate
those dependencies in there and this
this delegation is done by by a set of
generators Genesis are maintaining the
repository or the main open repository
and obviously we can have any number of
autumn of repositories with any number
of packages and any maintenance in there
yeah and the goal is if the janitors
signed such delegation to a specific
author or to a specific team of authors
then the authors can do with that
package whatever they want I mean they
can draft new releases without the
Genesis having to having to do anything
because they already delegated it to a
specific author and the author can rest
at new at new releases or it that fixes
fix up the build instructions and new
dependencies at new version constraints
and so on how does that in reality works
well so this single author for a single
package is no longer true because there
are lots of packages which are
maintained by teams and and also my may
have multiple keys so I may have a key
on my laptop and a key on my desktop and
I want to be able to specify oh it
doesn't matter which key has signed this
release it might also be that I want to
require oh I have a Yubikey so an
external hardware security module there
are stove one of the keys and I want to
have that HSM need to need to sign the
release and also one of my other keys
that let also in tough so in the update
framework to the introduction of forum
signatures which basically means that
you can specify oh I want to have three
signatures out of the list of
ballads people who are valid authors so
if I want to have if I require three
signatures out of general a to Jennifer
II some delegation or any delegation is
only valid if at least three of them
have signed the delegation it's also
true in the real open repository like
from running it over time and we have
just a good repository which we are
hosting on github at the moment and
there any authors any package also
submit their packages it turns out that
authors are not responsive enough for
big breaking changes so if someone
releases their library and that is
dependent on by a lot of other libraries
and now he he releases a new version of
that which breaks the API but he didn't
tell that upfront then we may have to
fix up a lot of other packages to
introduce a new version bound so a new
upper version bond that they are not
compatible with the new release doing
that by the individual authors would be
the right thing to do but sometimes
authors are on vacation or so and we
don't really want to wait for three
weeks or four month in order to just put
through a new release of a package
that's why the janitors so the trend
rows are those people where all the
trust is initially then is initially
delegated to they are able to also
improve approve checksums of these new
pega dress or of these adjusted packages
yes this this also means to twelve to
required forum here means also there's
not a single key which is able to
compromise the entire system so if
general becky if the key from general
hobby gets compromised or if i managed
to steal it
i cannot introduce new packages or make
something valid because i
need at least three keys out of those
five in order to to do something which
is threat valid yet another thing and
reality is keys get compromised so if I
design a system which relies on public
keys and so on I better think about how
to mitigate min to mitigate compromised
and how to deal with it and there are
various ways to deal with that so if
here Jennifer
a for example gets loses their key then
three out of the other four janitors can
still say oh yeah well that's fine
Jennifer is no longer part of our group
what I can add janitor a with a new key
so they can actually roll that over and
they can expand and shrink their own
team yeah what is the progress of konnex
well there's as I mentioned there's now
a new prototype implementation with the
revised design which I revised together
with one of the update framework people
that is available now it interoperates
also with OPM - so obviously this
project itself needs to integrate
somehow with the package manager because
package manager I would like to tell the
package manager to only install valid
packages and the only small small area
where needs to interoperate with OPM
itself is during repository update so
how a repository update nowadays works
in open - it is it fetches the diff or
it fetches the new repository then it
makes a diff then pass then it passes
that information or that file - connects
and connects it's just a UNIX boundary
which connects verify address the UNIX
binary which says yes or no so which
returns zero of one
and open to only if it successfully gets
gets a successful return code from
connects very f5 will continue to adapt
this updated repository and I so I
prepared some some bits and pieces
oneness so open open to is as I said
currently in release can indeed state
but once it's out we can just add at
repositories with open repository at and
now I have a connects test and I will
use a local repository here then I say
the forum for the for the root so for
the for the main trust anchor is one and
the public key which is able to sign
something is having this sha-256 check
them so in this example is only a single
key it's not the optimal solution
because I would like to specify here
three out of whatever but this is just
for test
now that failed because it already had a
connects test yes
invalid repository signature update
aborted so something went wrong here in
the test report every year my itself I
can also say connects verify
[Music]
so manually oh it says uncaught
exception hmm
yeah we'll get to can make to that later
so what is inside of the repository is
apart from the janitors it's first file
called root which specifies what are the
janitors so I have two levels set up
here and next to next to the generators
also can specify snapshot and the
timestamp bot in order to preserve life
nests guarantees and specify means here
it specifies the the name and then on
the right hand side an expression in
this case it is an expression of forum
of two of the generator 1 and the
generator 2 with their specific public
key hashes and then the janitor 3 so
there are three different generators
with these public key hashes where two
of them need to sign any delegation
order to make that delegation valid what
else is in here is named well the name
is root and then a list of public keys
which are the root public keys and this
is the RSA this is just RSA key which
which checks am I then specified on
command line
what else is specified here is there
where are the keys and where is the data
I want to verify or I want to have and
the list of signatures and and this in
this case it's only a single signature
by the key name the root a and the
signatures in here then each of the
genitals have their own file where they
also have their own signature and in
their file they specified their target
so they can specify the delegations and
targets
and the targets are the actual data
files so they contain the consists of a
file name so to find them fufu 1.0 slash
as the size 0 eggs 1 FF and it's digest
should be this checksum and then another
file name which is path slash opium
should have that digest now this is only
a single generator and the single gender
then also has their public key in here
and also has here delegations and it
delegates the past
fubar to the user so the user fubar is
here and the user fubar can only specify
targets which which are below the
directory food for example test or txt
and the delegation to fubar here oughta
means that fuba is the only author
responsible for that sub directory so
there doesn't need to be a quorum but
only this single fubar but inside of the
root file I had an expression that I
need two out of the three Genesis to say
to make something true this is also the
reason why there are multiple genders
here and the junction 2 has a different
set of targets files and no delegations
in this case and the third generator and
the third generator also has a different
set of files and then as well the
delegation to fubar so two of them have
the delegation to fubar and that makes
the delegation only valid if only a
single janitor says something this
target or delegation is not treated as
valid so what else I also wanted to talk
a bit about micro dinars which is
opinionated DNS server and resolver dns
itself this protocol used
or over the Internet this decentralized
and delegated key value store where the
root authority is at Jana and her 13
would service and they delegate country
domains and till these two other
registrar's and they delegate and for
the sub domains to other people and name
services the main purpose of DNS is to
resolve domain names to IP addresses
that is yeah that is why it is used or
what this use most on the internet but
it does contain also lots of other fun
stuff so you don't have to use domain
names and you don't have to use IP
addresses but you can just or any key
value data for which you are
authoritative the project itself started
actually out because I wanted to
implement DNS resolver recursive
resolver so my motivation was so I
really want to understand what are the
difficulties in resolving and domain
name now obviously I can always go to
Google's name server and ask Google's
name server what is the IP address for
google.com or for facebook.com or so but
I wanted to actually do it how it is
defined in the RFC so instead of going
to to a caching resolver I want to go to
the name service which run by Jana and
by the but the other companies and just
go through this whole network to find
out which name server I have to ask for
what so the motivation was a recursive
resolver I figured out pretty quickly
that I want to also be able to configure
that recursive resolver like
blacklisting advertisement networks or
having local overrides so I if I own my
own domain I maybe want to have a
different name server response
for me as an internal user of that
domain so my development network and so
on does not need to be public but I on
my laptop I want to use be able to use
DNS for resolving also my internal names
and then I figured out that actually DNS
has a lot of configuration information
already in band and the protocol itself
specifies zone files which is a format
for serializing
domain name data and put it into the
server but it also specifies dynamic
updates of such zones and it also
specifies authentication so
authorization of packages of DNS frames
this all let me think oh yeah I can just
implement the DNS server and then use
the DNS server which has dynamic updates
and so on as a front-end or as a
configuration front end for my recursive
resolver this also means I don't need
any persistent state just delegate that
this is not my problem here right now I
just start with a clean state and get as
a boot parameter may be the secret for
the H Mac and then you can do dynamic
updates or dynamic configuration changes
of the resolver yet this led me to
actually implement the authoritative
server in DNS or for DNS which
implements zone files so it can pass
zone files can receive dynamic updates
and obviously if I can receive any
dynamic updates that's not much news
because I want to have some
authentication for that and for
authentication DNS specifies teasing
which are H Meg secrets so you have
shared secrets which you can do another
method of authentication which I haven't
implemented yet but I'm going to
implement soon is to just use DNS over
tillis and required in TLS client
certificates
the server itself does not need any
persistent states
so no persistent block device or so the
DNS server is just another virtual
machine image which you start and which
has its initial data like the hmx secret
and afterwards you can fill it
dynamically with more data so if I look
into my examples I will briefly go to a
primary implementation
this again is a unicorn also I have a
configuration which is now a bit more
complex because it already includes some
IP information because here I'm using
actually in artistic then I have some
more peg addresses dependencies and then
the unique kernel itself now says oh
yeah here's actually my data my data
contains of start of authorities of some
entries and some a entries and also some
secret H Mike secrets some secret keys
which are all in the end set to the
primary name server which is which done
then does listen listen on the network
stick now I can say Amy Raj configure -
tuk VM and make and I end up with the
primary dot uk' VM which is another
unicorn Oh which I can now start so I
now I have to pass the the UK vm bin so
the whole system process the information
which network device unicorn should use
I use tab 1 and then I pass the virtual
machine image and now also increase the
lock level
so now I have a server running on the IP
address 1004 t22 on my local machine
which is all connected to a local bridge
and I can now dig any so I can request I
can request information about the zone I
configured here the zone is named me Raj
can also try to initiate the zone
transfer which doesn't work because it
doesn't respond that says transfer
failed because zone transfers here
require here require a key so if I give
this dick Keith with the zone transfer I
actually get the whole zone out here so
that's that's basically how I run at the
moment my name services they are just
those me Raj unicorn odds which don't
have access to any block device so they
can actually not write any any data they
cannot record IP addresses and so on and
I don't need to another step once I had
this DNS server is that I'm continuously
running into this issue of let's encrypt
certificates needing renewal and let's
encrypt is a very nice specifies a very
nice protocol where you can prove your
ownership of a domain we our DNS as well
and now that I have a DNS server written
a no camel which does dynamic updates
and so on I thought oh yeah let's
integrate the let's encrypt library
which a friend of mine maker has
implemented in all camel and just used
it and now now I end up with having a
unicorn which is a DNS server and which
is also able to
deal with the let's encrypts at my
protocol and provision certificates
provision certificate signing request to
certificates and how I set that up
because I don't want to have all of that
inside of the primary name server I just
have a secondary name server which deals
with the let's encrypt updates they
store the let's encrypt certificates and
the lot let's encrypt certificates
running rehearse also in DNS because it
is a key value store after all itself
let me just store my signing request and
my certificates in there all this
storing is obviously protected or
authenticated by the H max secret which
is only basically a signature but
there's no encryption involved but that
doesn't need to be any encryption
involved because it's not private data
there's a certificate signing request
and certificate and now this let's
encrypt Dena's secondary server goes
along and waits for zone updates and
whenever the receives an update it
checks whether all certificate signing
request have matching certificates we're
matching is defined as oh they have the
same they have the they use the same
public key so the request and can
actually use it and the certificate is
still inside of the validity range
so since let's encrypt is only valid for
90 days it will renew then after after
89 days I think at the moment or idea it
is okay now still I haven't had any
persistency so I don't store any data at
the moment on disk it's all only in the
memory you can get away with that by
running multiple DNS services and you
just have a failover from primary to
secondary if the primary is down and and
and so on okay I have to hurry up in
gudinas I also have persistency using
git because as I mentioned in Oklahoma
we are in Morocco as we have a good
implementation now I can just push zone
update also to a good
three and commit that and the primary
can retrieve get information so can
clone a git repository and use the zone
file inside of the git repository as a
zone file so wrap up I have server and
resolver I interoperate with other
servers I don't have any custom
configuration language because I thought
Dean as the protocol is expressive
enough I have this hidden secondary for
persistency and let's encrypt I let me
briefly talk about called of Qaddafi's
protocol used by Columbus to sync
calendars
this is a project which we got funded by
a broad track fund which is a very nice
funding program called off itself is
based on vector which is yeah the data
and versioning in indie web so it does
some authentication using HTTP
authentication does XML request which
specific for retrieving and uploading
files we worked on that since April this
year and it's still work in progress but
it's coming along well and it is just
impressive how much how complicated such
kind of protocol is on the one side you
have HTTP and exam embedded XML request
on the other side you have the iCalendar
file format which is more like RFC eight
to two key value thing but then they
thought keys and values are not enough
so we need multi-line values and then
also we need parameter keys and values
for each key so it actually turns out to
be pretty complex to pass and to operate
on it also the recurrence rules so you
can define recurrent events like weekly
event but not in the 50th week but only
in the 48 week or something like that
that's all I am prepared so what does
manraja is it's an operating system
engineer
using a very radical approach by just
getting rid of everything we have right
now and redeveloping it in inside of a
fresh high-level language it avoids a
lot of root causes of common flaws like
memory safety issues it has a very small
trust computing base and a reasonable
performance I didn't show any numbers
but from our work on TLS it turns out we
were up to 85% the speed of open SSL
yeah and let me thank all all the
computer contributors to me Raj OS which
is now in the whatever 50 people or so
and I'm also organizing every six months
the heck retreat for the midrash system
if you're interested in that the next
one is in early October it's a weekend
Marrakesh and yeah welcome to to join us
there that's all I prepared dear I think
we have some time for questions any
questions thank you for the nice talk
the konnex it was I did I miss it or is
there some like proof of publication
mechanism so like if if you're a
developer and I've compromised one key
of one developer who's the only
developer of their package and I control
your Wi-Fi can I do a targeted malicious
software update and get away with it or
is there some mechanism to and there's
there's a mechanism called the snapshot
BOTS which receives the repository
checks all the signatures and makes a
new signatures over the global view of
the repository but if you compromised
the repository update mechanism you can
yeah thanks to the snapshot bought and
the timestamp board which just does
every five minutes
and times them and a signature on the on
the whole repository you can check for
liveness properties like that you don't
get that the attacker can't freeze you
to an existing bad repository now if if
I compromise an author key and the
author doesn't as long as the author
doesn't detect that I can publish new
packages under their name that will then
hopefully be discovered by the repulsor
maintain us at some point hopefully
earlier and they can then revoke the
public key or the delegation to the
public key I guess I'm more worried
about if it's a targeted attack where
the attacker does not actually put the
new package in the public repository for
everybody but instead just presents it
to their victim so they know you're a
developer you're on some Wi-Fi and the
attacker is physically near you and has
compromised one author key is there a
way to be sure that the package I'm
installing right now is the same package
everybody else would be installing and
yes thanks to the snapshot bot because
you as a client you first check the
signature of the snapshot pot and that
signed all of the authors so the
attacker would first need to inject that
new package into the snapshot bot right
and the special multiple snapshot watts
or is that yes you can have you you can
also have a similar to the other forum
signatures you can specify oh I want to
have three out of those ten snapshot
BOTS which then hopefully run by
different organizations and they all
need to agree on the state of the
repository right thank you
thanks it up
thank very nice
[Applause]