oops
and we'll manage to somehow updates the
system and show the slide so at the
server setup all you need to do as you
also have the clone info screen info
screen repository at the server and you
can just get pull this address and then
this is the runner scripts so all you
have to do is your heart you'll have to
call consent row with the path to the
directory of your content of your slides
and then it'll just run continuously and
also handle new slides and so on we
support HTML files pictures videos you
can also just have a file called
something something that URL and then it
will find out how to show that you can
also have shell scripts in case you need
some more complex features we use that
at work so you can also configure a
slide should it last 20 seconds 20
minutes should you don't be only be
shown and certain certain days on
certain intervals should only be shown
with a probability of 0.5 or 22 or so on
so in conclusion this is continued on
github and it works right well we have
had its battle tested in two different
location on four screens for more than
two years now and it's surprisingly
stable it's just a single Python program
so thank you
[Applause]
yes thank you
and the next speaker is pure
okay hi everyone my name is Pierre and
together with my colleagues we have
spent last three years developing the
open-source project it's now it's closed
but we plan to open source inborn hack
but the fun was too great so we need to
postpone to the upcoming week ok so this
is the application management system
it's not strictly pure technical one its
combines the release management function
orchestration faction deployment faction
together in one open source up so what
is does application orchestrations who
when what how deployed to the production
stage in QA environment because you
should be able to know what is going on
in the infrastructure sometimes release
manager to put on hold some release due
to simple box sometimes sales guy should
know that new red button feature is
coming in December because you need to
talk about in the sales presentation so
this is application orchestration and
deployment deployment just get the files
and put onto servers sounds easy but
it's not at all
we are using unsealer roles as a
deploying steps so you can combine
deployment pipelines with roles and
similar roles existing roles so you
don't need to write your own maybe you
already have some roles and last release
management if there's a release with
incorporation maybe there's some
dependency for order feature between the
features maybe we need some approvals
from other department so thanks that you
can you can cover that few words about
infrastructure and looks huge but it's
very simple the kerfing here is
application application is a herd of the
system so everything is around the
application application could have
environment it's obvious artifacts
artifacts on the left are dress five
packages like package with your web app
whatever nodejs
something like that and application
could have the change change it just
deployed read read button on production
you set up the date how to do that using
the deployment pipelines on the on the
right what is crucial here is you could
use only few of the components that you
really need maybe you don't have need
for a deployment at all you just want to
track the versions it's possible you can
just register a version set that this
version was deployed to production or to
the staging whatever without putting any
files you have your working deployment
solution currently great you can just
register the results here in inputted
tune now what version is running where
okay so now I will show some really
short examples all right looks good so
the first one will just create the
application where's my mouse I will copy
paste the commands
so the pooted core is the core system
with open a P so you it's just a ap and
we need the command-line tool to talk to
the IP you can write your own because
it's a rest IP we write command line in
pure bash just for fun because then
everyone's should be able to extend our
command line tool so creating the apps
in our system is I'm doing copied so
it's hard to do
one hand that's okay I will put a
microphone down
okay the application has we'd created
let's check that out
some ugly bash table but you can always
add JSON switch and this is what you got
and every output could be turned into a
nice JSON output now we will try to add
some version so we are fully supporting
semantic versioning as you can see on
the end of the command I've just
specified that the next version is major
ok let's ease the application so now we
got two versions 0 1 & 2 let's add some
dummy environment it will allow us to
set the deployment status okay maíam
register and now the last part let's
let's tell the application that
deployment on the production was
successful so some debug output we don't
have time to talk about it and let's
check out the deployment result here so
you can see that it was successful I can
clear screen and okay now now is my
butter so this is like 3% of our
features we'll open it in next week so
write me an email if you like to know
more and watch the github and hacker
news about the about the system thank
you so much
thank you and now we do you want to be
my the slide should be on there
okay please welcome hello this does not
support powerful screen but okay
do you use PGP emails who uses PGP yeah
still you haven't given up do you also
sign your emails like so you know yeah
you can sign emails and that kind of
shows that you're in possession of the
private key that has signed this email
right so here's a signed email this
looks legit right do you all think this
looks legit I mean it's in Thunderbird
it says good signature from Bob
so anyone seeing anything suspicious
here so it's actually not a signed email
it's an HTML mail and I've just added a
picture here which says good signature
from Bob so this is a signed email this
is real and this is the fake have you
seen the difference this was quick right
so Kenny so there is a small difference
which is this whatever red letter thing
here but I would say most people would
fall for this right well I'm not sure
how many people here you stand about
maybe some people use much this looks
also legit right it says signature made
Saturday something bla bla bla
following data assigned that looks also
very literate right it's also fake yeah
of course I've just pasted in the text
here into the email so yeah
yeah that was kind of it I guess the
problem here is that people display the
information about the signature within
the email which is obviously controlled
by the person sending the email
particularly if if you have something
like HTML mails where you can design
them however you want I reported this to
any mail they have now changed it so
they have switched around the header and
like now that this would go above that
which would make it more obvious but
yeah
[Applause]
in the pocket I don't want to say
okay these will come calling on the
stage in this talk we're gonna be
talking about diplomacy AI thank you so
in two-player games a eyes beat humans
fairly comprehensively now so chess this
is 20 years ago gomu recently with
alphago poker is interesting because
it's a game of incomplete information so
as such one player doesn't know
everything that the other player knows
in that sense it's unlike chess or go so
these are more complex games but even in
poker BOTS are beating top humans now
dota 2 is an interesting game for the
21st century generation so last year
open AI was beating a top human
professional in the one-on-one mode with
a particular character in dota 2 this
year
the open AI bought is beating humans in
5v5 mode it played against for former
professionals in one commentator and and
is winning now so even in one year
there's very rapid progress being made
he looks we're wondering if I can also
do it well another plum and a game for
diplomacy it's a board game guys
players it's a game Lake of risk but
there's no there's no nothing random
about it you can make support other
people and their units you can convoy
them also like like they're yours and
you can talk with people by yourself and
also in a group but uh but you don't
have to do what you say it you can like
say that you will support them but then
you can actually backstab them so one of
the challenges posed is that
unstructured natural language processing
plays a central role in in games of
diplomacy and also it has more than two
players and so the question of which
ones to ally again with and against are
important so there is a there is a
diplomacy League every year the
automated negotiation agents competition
has a diploma so this is a knack has
been running since 2010 and for the last
two years they've been running a
diplomacy league this year it was in
Stockholm in fact earlier in fact last
month last year the winner was a bot
called frigate which was which was
designed by two researchers at the Tokyo
University of Agriculture and Technology
this year there was no winner and that
was interesting the the rules for this
year were that to get to the second
stage you first you're bought had to out
perform a random bought with with
statistically significant difference all
bots that outperformed this random
bought were then play against each other
so only one of the submissions in fact
outperformed the random bought and it
didn't do very well when playing against
the full so I think having only one
entrant that made it past the first
stage they then ran the second stage
with all of the bots and the bots that
got passed the first stage didn't do
well against the against the full array
of bots so you're playing against bots
you're not playing against humans and
the bots have been hard-coded rather
than displaying any true learning so
hard and they're they're hard-coded in a
very greedy style as well so for example
the the the an act League focuses on
negotiations rather than movements but
the sort of hard-coded rule
all that one of these BOTS would have is
accept any proposal that gives me a net
increase in the supply centers that I
control so these are very myopic and
they're very simplistic so the state of
the art in this area is still very
primitive and as a result we would still
like to see a bot that can play and
maybe even beat humans and diplomacy
thank you are there any questions yeah
what's our relation to the project why
are we doing this because we like the
policy yeah we visited the researchers
in Tokyo as well and and so I thought it
was interesting to see what the low
level of the state of the art is and it
seems that this would be a great
challenge problem for people interested
in natural language processing and in a
eyes as I say most of the the
environments that we've seen tend to be
two-player games so this this kicks it
open and it's a classic board game as
well so it strikes me that there should
be more attention focused on this than
there is at present thank you
[Applause]
okay now we can welcome Morton and just
a second awesome we're running hello
everybody and I'm Martin I'll talk to
you guys and the thing is that we are
starting up a PBA and IT security next
year announcer and hey we want friends
so I mean I live in in food I've been
teaching at your Academy I don't even
know what the continent is anymore yeah
all about skinny little belt we are
called something new now because we
merged who knows when I teach ap degree
students which is and an education after
high school so this is would be the
first two years of a bachelor in other
places but when we also have these top
offs for bachelors and them I to Linux
Network IT security and Python should
anyone feel like talking to me about
those things I like to talk about that
anyway just to I thought that given the
audience perhaps all these acronyms
might be relevant to mention IDs ID
security
you probably know what that is but the
PPA is a professional bachelor it's in
ten mark we have this system where we
have AP degrees we have Bachelor
creature of math degrees and PhDs and
probably something else and and the
academic bachelors probably want to know
the best they are the ones that
universities make but we make
professional bachelors which are we like
to think of them as being more close to
the industry and being able to do a lot
more practical hands-on
as opposed to a lot of theory so a PBA a
professional bachelor in IT security
would be a practical working person who
knows how to do IT security in what's
called in a company and not all these
nitty-gritty how to do crypto algorithms
for example so as I said we are starting
this up in Windsor in next year but it
is already running in Owens and ko Ming
so this is actually something where you
actually you should be able to find
candidates soon that has days education
and then just a quick overview of what
they're doing this would be three
semesters 90 CTS points if you into this
world Salmonella introduction try to
security IT governance system security
networking communication security
advanced IT governance software security
and then you have all the electives and
internship and a final project so as you
can see if you find some guy who knows
these things you're probably well suited
to to security and company and that is
basically the goal of it so the thing is
that when we start doing these things we
of course start discussing a lot amongst
ourselves
hmm what kind of stuff should we so when
we talk network security what is that
and so on and since we are an academy we
want to collaborate with companies and
so we call the closest big company and
they say oh yes we are doing Windows
we're doing VMware and we have a pillow
and so far wall therefore you should
teach your students that and I will then
go to my boss and say oh we have talked
to people in the local area and they say
VMware Windows and Palo Alto so let's do
corporate America education yes and then
I start looking for a new job because
this is very cool and from an teacher
point of view this is actually quite
interesting all the stuff you can get
for free from these guys
90% discount on hardware and all kinds
of really cool so from a resource
perspective being a teacher this is the
easy way and yeah and that's not what I
want to do so in my opinion the quick
the big question is since we don't want
to do the corporate America way what the
hell do you want to do and we need help
we need to have no companies we need to
know people who wants to help us build
this education so that we are gonna make
some really kick-ass professional
bachelor's in IT security coming out of
Yale in Owenton so basically we want to
know people who takes who take security
seriously who actually use it or
actually work with it
in a good way so please come to us and
we will do all this internship we will
do collaborations we'll do projects for
you we'll do whatever we want as long as
it's in the domain of this security so
come talk to me especially if you're in
the Friant region that would be best
yes it's blinking
[Applause]
good afternoon let's see should be some
I'll have two short talks can I say one
about diff I guess many of you use use
gate or otherwise all our versioning
systems at least you used if tools
someone that doesn't use the diff tool
is full screen I thought I had bit of
problems with if if you have a bit more
complicated if they easily get very hard
to read and you can use side by side dev
tools and it makes it a bit easier to
compare the files but even on a on a
single screen on a formal terminal it
there is a lot of improvement I saw a
lot of chances for improvement so for
example when there's whitespace changes
easily gets unreadable things are
shifted small changes are hard to see it
normally if lists only the different
lines and you don't see any of the small
changes if there's especially if there's
also whitespace change or something
and things move around and if you have
lines with only a matching bracket or
only else those lines often match up
with all our lines because they are
double they often they are quite often
in a file so they match up with the
wrong line
and so what I did is make an improved
DIF algorithm it has been on my computer
for a few years but now it's all duds
born heck what can I do
maybe it's a good time to finish this
algorithm and put it online and what I
did I made some changes I used the
patient's algorithm from pom Kohan to as
a start and made a bit some changes so
whitespace get less influence repeated
characters have less influence short
lines are short and duplicate lines they
are not counted and also to make it more
visible the output the if you have a
block of code and another block of codes
you can normally first the one is put
and then the other the deleted one and
the added one what I did is interleave
them so you can see line by line the
difference and then in those lines the
unchanged parts are displayed in gold so
this is a diff just as gate outputs it
doesn't matter what algorithm you use in
this case you see that it's very hard to
see what's the difference there are some
pardal eated and a part other than
there's one line that's the same then
there's a few things changed another
line that's the same with those lines
that are the same are not really
interesting lines they they appear more
times and else of course appears a
gazelle you know of times in a file so
with my new algorithm did the algorithm
this is the output so you see that
actually everything almost everything is
gold so it's the same there's a word add
a word change there there's a line
there's an underscore deleted there's a
bit of text edit here's a bit of text
edit for the rest it's all indent
changes there gets a lot more
information then there is
[Music]
one other tool that you can use because
there's older already order improved
diffs like ingot you can use word if
makes already a lot less garbage then
then the standard diff algorithm but
also this is not super useful and it's
also not a compatible diff it's you can
use this as a patch for example so I
called it Klondike live Klondike is a
version of passion so I thought matches
it's written in Python now it in a
integrates well and get as an external
diff tool it's a lot slower than the
internal diff tool in ingots so that
could be improved but it's waiting a
second for a bunch of patches is also
not a huge problem
so at worst quite well but it would be
really nice to implement it in other
tools in graphical tools and also make
it faster so if someone cares to join
please so then I have another talk about
something completely different and
should be a mini Jackson where yeah
is there yeah
[Music]
so this is I open a different different
presentation for the convenience this is
a project I'm working on now for a long
time it's a music instrument this is my
latest version which is way simpler than
the version I started with the version I
started with is a it's a self-contained
box with synthesizer and keyboard and
amplifier inside so it works by itself
and this finally after a few years of of
developing I thought let's make it
simpler for myself and focus only on the
on the main important part the keyboard
which is the main main improved thing
especially since in the mean time since
2009 I started on this other tools
became available like an axolotl the
keyboard synthesizer board it's a
intuitive instrument its expressive and
portable small it intuitive mainly the
the node layout is the thing that
started this project which is a logical
intuitive blow to lay out and for the
rests as per second portable I'll keep
it short yeah and in the history there
have been quite a lot of new note layout
mainly early in the 20th century or the
end of the 19th century people
experimented with other node layouts
which then then a linear piano in the
entered the piano one it sort of but
it's quite limited it's you have to
learn every skill new it has a different
shape and also you are stuck to the 12
tone tuning with it with
Veta piano they tune pianos differently
in the back in the 18th century with
that created problems because there's 12
notes and 12 keys per octave so that's
yeah here's some attempts to to have our
keyboards most of them have a lot of
keys you see this node layout is these
are based on the circular v which is a
base in music theory and the pitch
height so you have two circle of fifths
the pitch height and if you put notes on
the on the on the lines and then you
will get this layout simple idea it
creates a sort of sort of rectangular
sort of hexagonal layout similar things
exist but not not orthogonal the nice
thing of this layout is said this
isomorphic every every musical the
distance has the same same shape so for
example a a minor a minor third is
always this major chord is was this
triangle minor chord is this triangle
and it works with different tunings so
if you for example now I set it to a 31
no tuning in a 30 in a 12-ton tuning the
b-flat and a sharp they are the same in
this button in this note layouts they
are located on different sides their
sharps are here in the flats are here
they sound the same in a3100 tuning they
are different
which makes that a third is way cleaner
than in a than in a twelfth on tuning we
are quite used to twelfth on tuning so
[Music]
we don't hear it as good as Indians do
for example who are used to clean
tunings and it's it's quite compact with
one hand you can spend for octase
something
I also modified my accordion to have the
same layout I started actually on
acoustic instruments and then I got into
electronics and made an electronic
instrument because that makes more space
it's also expressive all the buttons
they are
three directions sensitive in three
directions
it runs on a STM microcontroller yeah
without far plops I wouldn't have made
possible Neve impossible for me to learn
all the stuff I need it for this okay I
am yeah and I used only all the software
I try to use only open-source software
of course for this world of course demo
video you can see on the website
[Applause]
thanks it up
what do you have to report
oh yeah
okay you'll introduce yourself Linksys
yeah hello and Linksys I'm working on a
lot of Harper related problems and yeah
there was some some time when I got done
with some other phones which broke down
and now I had to buy a new phone and
yeah somehow I I bought new of iPhone
because I thought okay I got a Qualcomm
based phone I got a mediatek based phone
what's what's left there
what can I try out on mobile phone
chipsets
so I basically bought a new phone and
before I just try our try it out to find
the kernel sources of the of the phone
and it did not look so much ugly there
were several already quite a lot of
sources even some parts are up streamed
so I certain give it a try
let's see what's what's there so because
I like to have my own binaries on my
phone so I was really want to have my
own ran right on it that it did not work
out and in the end I thought hmmm should
I take the hue of iced Android which
asked me a lot of permissions or should
I just take out a random binary from a
form and I took that one but I didn't
had so much update so I had to I really
went back to to compile the things and
so usually if you have Android you have
first to unlock the bootloader and get
somewhere this cookie as as code it
would be nice to have it just in the
same box but usually you have to go to
the website and then you can flash you
can flash your imagery as a bootloader
which is accessible by USB and but my
and what did not work I just see a black
screen what should I do
so usually if I'm also working on on
routers like Frey funk and open wrt so
there's always a serial way we can get
some output but where is it on the phone
and I did not found it I just
disassembled it went with the
oscilloscope and try to find it but
it did not work out that way at least
and so I had a phone I could go back to
he was operating system or even that one
from the phone I have no idea why that
one worked but mine not but without just
seeing black it wasn't good
so yeah the cellino's kernel boots maybe
maybe just missing other parts yeah so
great I created the backup and went back
to start experimenting with partitions
so I don't know if somebody had always
seen what's what kind of petitions such
a phone has I mean when computer started
with the old days we had four partitions
but then we evolved a little bit and so
this is the partition table of the phone
so yeah you see a lot of partitions
likely it's 42 so maybe they that was
the reason to get up there but for
n-word usually you you you have those
sweeper traditions are as important this
is the rescue system usually you have
some rescue system which also Android
uses as import and yeah yes the Linux
kernel and here's a user space basically
so this is the user space and yeah but
let's see it's not all I basically
modified this thing because as I said
maybe that does not match my Linux
kernel but there are other interesting
this is the bootloader and this thing
it's called factory reset protection and
those are also some quite interesting
ones so but how did I done it I my boot
loader does not allow me to directly
modify it I have to boot into the
recovery and then I could modify the
image and but what then happens I have
now a complete black phone I can't even
go to the recovery after
even the recovery should be there for
recovery but nobody's thought about him
somebody want to play with more about it
and so because I hadn't back up I could
look into look into the bootloader and
find out what my eighties there happened
I even found out how to get the serial I
haven't tested if it's working but I
there's a way to get it out of the USB
data ports actually and but then I also
found out how the fastboot OEM basically
works it's basically just a sha-1 on one
of the partition safe that's called user
key and their sources reset protection
which which prevents me from doing more
with over the bootloader which basically
works the same way but somehow they did
two different things this is some
algorithm which is a password key to
version and it's you you you use it from
your from a hard drive to decryption but
it seems to be not enough to just do it
they even have signed the result in the
same partition already awry yeah so is
it worth my talk I've found more out but
the time is already over yeah so
[Applause]
cool
I'm ready hello beautiful people so I
want to present to you our network
management tool that we have made in
someponies cook collaborative basically
if you are tired of network manager or
if you are tired of the w-whatever
whatever or all the other network
managers that are pretty for linux
then we will present you a simple
alternative that will handle probably
what ever you will need on your desktop
or laptop computer and also maybe you
not pull your hair out when you need to
connect to a new network we have the
github page add ponies slash net it has
a fairly it has fairly good
documentation it's pretty self contained
and self explanatory in regards to when
you run the command you can have a help
command and we have some example
configurations with all the options that
are possible within this tool it's very
simple to use a quick example that I
have here my well not my but an example
version of the config we have this is
formatted in llamo and we have a common
field with which is with these options
that will fall through all the different
kinds of profile you will define so you
can for example globally said that you
would like to have a random MAC address
or you could just set that your mega
test make it rest should be and any say
MAC address because why not your global
DNS settings global hostname stuff like
that you can also set a global interface
so you don't have to type out what
interface your profile wants to use all
the time if you only use your Wi-Fi
interface you can set the ignored
interfaces so the tool won't use them at
all which is pretty handy otherwise it
might be confused
sometimes we are trying to guess what it
is you're trying to do and do some magic
so you don't have to type out everything
if it's if it's if you're able to know
what it is if we can rebase achill eread
your mind will do it for you you can
define different kinds of profiles you
can define a VPN profile so you can
handle all your OpenVPN a wagon VPN
configuration through the tool this is
an example these keys are valid but this
is not a valid address so it's not a
valid entry you can we have assert some
certain profiles that are pretty static
like the wire so the only thing that I
have defined for Wyatt is my wire
interface which basically means I
haven't defined anything else all the
things from common will fall through and
then it will pick some same defaults
otherwise then I have some different I
have a different wire interface similar
because it uses the wire interface yeah
sure why profile sure then I have some
some access points listed like I will
input in our ponies Network I want to
connect we're using normal VP a two with
a personal key so it's very easy to
define the a society and the personal
key at CCC for example it's pretty easy
to handle the anonymous authentication
and the phone hack is using the same
setup so we can differ we can just
define what is the SSID and then define
the parameters of the enterprise
connection it's pretty neat we also
handle like you have an open access
point just set the SSID it will
automatically connect it works pretty
well with a Durham so if you have ever
had any troubles with a Durham just use
our tool because basically this will
make you able to connect to it really
quickly without any issues a quick
demonstration when just run the tool you
can see the status of your connections
I'm connected to phone like right now
since this is a list of my profiles if I
wanted to connect to boneheads again
with a new identity because all my
options are random then now I will get a
new hostname new mega red stuff like
that
and basically if the connection isn't
then I will be able to connect not
sure if it we can also just scan to see
if the connection is actually pretty bad
yeah Duke Duke take some time there we
go we can see like all the access point
stuff like that and then we can
basically just try and connect again
hopefully it works there we go
we are connected we associated we are
sending a DHCP request waiting for the
response and this is not the tool that's
raw it's basically just the network so
that's it these were all the lightning
talks for today but we have another
session on Tuesday so if you want to
present something of your own feel free
to submit the submission through the
website might currently be broken but
you can ping me on IRC I'm sorry to feel
or just approach me at the camp and
thank you all for coming