come today we have Mao knows who's going
to talk about testing threaded C and C++
code with his neat hook tool let's give
a round of applause for Manos yes hello
my name is - as I was introduced I'm a
PhD student at Uppsala University in
Sweden where I research tools and
techniques for testing concurrent
software for example when using threads
and I'm going to talk to you a bit today
about one rituals we have worked on for
a while and in particular give you help
you to understand how it works well
enough so that you can apply it yourself
because it isn't really that hard so the
target audience for this talk is the non
computer scientist so if you do computer
science you might get slightly cringy
because I use imprecise language in some
places and you'll have just have to live
with it the point of this talk is is to
make basically anyone who needs to to be
able to use these kinds of tools and
really the things I'm going to teach you
today are things that are not specific
to this tool really but things that you
need to know to use any tool in this
entire category so even if this
particular tool isn't what you need
maybe you run a different programming
language you do a different programming
model there are probably similar tools
for those or there might be in the
future and in that case the skills
you'll in learn here will be perfectly
transferable to that so the talk will be
mostly centered around me showing you a
bunch of examples so I will show you a
bunch of code with various bugs that I
either introduced or or fix and show you
how to apply these tools and and what
they can do I will also talk a bit about
weak memory moles since that is
something that comes up a lot when you
do threaded programming
and is one of the harder parts and how
these types of tables help with that and
finally I will show you an example of us
testing some very non-trivial real-world
code from the from the Linux kernel so
that you can see that this is not just a
tool for try examples even though most
of the examples that we show our toys
because that's the way we can fit them
in a 45 minute presentation so this is a
very boring introduction but parallel
problem is hard right you've probably
seen this picture before it's from
Mozilla headquarters and the text on the
on the wall is probably not readable but
it says must be destroyed right
multi-threaded code and here's a
standing desk so the point is everyone
makes mistakes when writing mob threaded
code because it's it's just so much to
think about and the space of things can
happen just explodes and another thing
that makes it very hard is that at
testing which we usually use to verify
that our software does approximately
what we want you to do at least doesn't
apply as well to multi-threaded software
because if you run it twice a
multi-threaded program it might do
something different a second time so
your unit tests might run fine one day
and then fail the next day and and this
is undesirable and and the fact that
having passing tests doesn't mean so
much in that context you might be aware
of tools of race detection tools like
like well grind and thread sanitizer
right and also you have done threaded
program probably have at least heard of
this so these tools instrument your
program beforehand and they will create
warnings during runtime if your program
does things that apply to some
heuristics they have for bad behavior
for some definition of bad but
unfortunately these things - were not do
not give guarantees even for the types
of problems they do look for they do not
currently
to find them but all hope is not lost
because there are tools that can give
these types of guarantees and this is
what I'm going to teach you today so
nidhogg is a a tool it's a program you
you compiled on your computer and you
run your unit tests through them so so
you write your unit test as normal and
they have to be unit tests so that is
they have to to be programs that don't
take any any additional input you cannot
have tests interactive programs it this
way for example and and what network
does is that it just runs your test
several times and actually
systematically tries all the possible
things it can do due to the way multiple
threads interact and thus because it
tries everything at the end you have a
guarantee that if it can crash you will
find it but also unlike things like
unlike rays the textures there are
benign data races but network is
designed these types of tool doesn't
need to be that way but network is
designed to not complain when you have
benign data races so what it looks for
is is what you would look for when you
run your unit test you look if it
crashes or or the output is wrong or
something like that so I will it hook is
designed to work on the level of LLVM
bit code so what you do with you take
your unit test and you compile it with
clang - I will be a bit code file you
can link this together
this command is not very commonly used
but it exists you can link them together
if you have multiple source files and
then you give that to need again it runs
it for you there are also other ways for
example if you have a bit of a bigger
program if you have an entire build
system there's a rapid
shift around clang called w LLVM which
is a bit of a mouthful but it is a
drop-in replacement for CC and it will
generate a bit code in a even using a
build system that doesn't know this
thing and there's also our convenience
front-end if you just have a single C
file which is what we're going to use
for most of the day yes so need hook is
open source and available on github so
if you really want to look at the source
code feel free that's not really what
you need to to be able to use it but
it's it's freely available so let me
show you a very basic example of of
concurrent program so this is a program
in C as you might be able to tell it's
large enough for you in the back to read
yeah which we have a main function which
spawns an additional thread T and then
writes a variable and that which is a
parameter to this thread T and thread T
does something and assume that its
parameter is already set so if the
program correct it's not right so let's
try to run it and see what happens
so clang example 1 and we need to say P
thread I believe then a dot out and it
doesn't crash my assertion doesn't fail
maybe we were just unlucky seems fine
well I've toyed with you enough of
course what can happen is is this can
happen before that let's see if we try
to run this thing with knee-jerk if it
what it says we say nidhogg and we say
legacy which is the front end a Texaco
that's an input and we tell it which
memory model we want if you don't know
about a memory model is just ignore this
for now I will get to that in in the
future and we give it input file and it
produces a bunch of output but the
interesting part starts here so this
means that need hook around this program
twice and after that it found a problem
which is assertion variation which is
this x equals the one we had and the
above the error message we have a trace
of what the program actually did to come
to that point so this thing this bracket
0 outer bracket means the main thread
and then 0.0 is the first thread spawned
by the main thread and so on so these
are the thread identifiers that that
need to create for itself and the
execution of this program went like this
first we spawn the thread in this case
the declaring debug info isn't quite
precise enough to give us there the
correct message here but this is the
threads phone since afterwards we can
see the second thread running and then
the second thread runs performs the load
of X upon which we run the main thread
again and write 1 to X so obviously we
have loaded whatever was in X before it
was written which is probably 0 since
this is a static variable and then
finally the program crashes because of
this ok so this is what need hook does
right it it runs the program a couple of
times to in this case because there are
two behaviors of this program and it
sees if it can make it fail so how does
it do this so it hook takes your program
and runs it instruction by instruction
it doesn't actually create multiple
threads but rather
whenever there is a there are multiple
threads that can run it arbitrarily
picks some of that one of them to run at
the singles in a single step
so this trace we saw was well it
corresponds very closely to what NIDA
actually did internally but so it
executes the first execution of the
program which it just picks arbitrary
threads to run so in this case it didn't
it pick the correct non crashing case
that's the first execution and then it
finishes that and then it does analysis
so who here can tell me the traditional
definition of a data race in shared
memory programs you have probably seen
this before but I'm sure you're a bit
shy in case it I'm going to say
something very academic but the
definition typically reads something
like this two threads accessing the same
variable and at least one of them is
writing it and if you have this then the
order of these two accesses matter right
because the right changes what they read
will see or if you have two rights to
change what the end result will be so
need hook looks at this racist it also
considers other types of of races then
later races like like the order of of
which two threads which gets first to
get a mutex and so on but it looks at
these types of races and it tries to see
if it can change the schedule it just
executed so that they are wrong in the
different order and then it puts puts
all these executions in a queue and then
it just restarts running your program
replaying up until the point where where
the race comes and then playing that in
Reverse and then an arbitrary execution
afterward and then you just repeat this
process until you're out of new
behaviors
explore so this is the conceptual let me
show you a figure of what it what it did
on this very trivial example we had that
I showed you so we start by running the
first thread twice creating another
thread and then writing 2x and then
right running the second thread and then
it is done so need hook then since this
race between the read of X and write to
X and put in the Q that it wants to
execute after spawning thread T we want
to immediately switch and execute T so
it puts this in the queue and then since
there are no more races in this program
it restores execution picking one of
these these executions from the from the
queue and it runs it to completion and
then it finds the assertion failure so
conceptually this is this is what yoga
does doesn't seem so hard right so
that's all fine and dandy but but what
are the limitations right surely this is
just something that works fine for for
examples for for tiny toy programs but
that breaks down when you run it on
larger code so so what are the
limitations of these techniques well
it's actually actually quite simple
there are basically two hard limits on
these techniques the first limit is that
a input program the unit tests must be
deterministic so what that means is that
every time to really runs your program
it must do the exact same thing it did
the first time so you're not allowed to
to look at what the time is and branch
on that like a random number generator
which to do and if you do file i/o you
have to be very careful some tools could
conceptually intercept these things and
and make sure that that no funny
business is going on but needle does not
do this
so so if you do phyllo you should
probably make sure you are only reading
and that that you are closing all your
your file descriptors before you start
your threaded workload there are also a
second limitation is in that the program
must not run forever and this is a bit
tricky to explain so I will instead show
you what it means because I think that
will make it a lot easier to grasp but
but but the problem with running forever
is that that this implies that the
program has either infinitely many
behaviors or that it doesn't terminate
in which case you just get stuck right
because it actually runs your program so
let me show you a second example so say
that we wanted to fix this program but
instead of doing the obvious thing we
introduced a queue data structure so
this is this is not supposed to be there
yet so this is the same program but
instead of having a global variable X we
use a library that provides five for Q
and this Q we can put integers in and
taking the result and we use this Q to
to shuffle the integers between between
the main thread and T because we hope
this will this will solve a race
condition now our program will work so
the Q interface is a bit particular
peculiar in that the in queue operations
always succeeds but the dequeue
operation might return either true or
false depending on if the queue is empty
or not so so in order to make sure that
we actually get the the number we want
out of it we just have to loop until it
succeeds so let's see what happens if we
try to run it here on this program
sample - OH
[Music]
copy edge header files as well
and this is yes so we're getting into
the nitty-gritty already so I told you
that needle you would only complain
about real errors but there isn't some
exceptions to that just through this is
just some mess in interface really but
but here we have a sort of a warning of
strange behavior that is that is opt-out
rather no obtained and what it says is
that is queue data structure uses
mutexes but it doesn't call init on them
because I was too lazy to I didn't want
to put an init function here so instead
I use static initialization and so you
have to add a really long command line
which is in the help text so you don't
have to memorize this and then it works
well I say that but there doesn't seem
to be much happening right it's just
standing there and doing nothing let's
add another flag print progress and it
will print how many behaviors it has
explored already 400 behaviors 500 and
Counting so something is strange right
this program isn't very complicated but
it just keeps going so the problem here
what lead hook does is that that it will
first run an execution when where this
the queue operation succeeds on the
first try and then it will see that that
it can change the behavior of this thing
by by switching it with this thing
so it switches them and now try the
queue fails the first time and then
succeeds and then in the second
execution it says oh we can switch it
with thank you again to make it fail
twice so it switches when in queue again
and ok now we have an execution where it
fails twice oh and now we have it every
yet another call to the queue which we
can switch with on queue and then we can
make it fail four times and it will just
keep going like this forever so this
this checking will never terminate even
though it is quite obvious to you
that his program must terminate at some
point because eventually the main threat
will calling you so there are a couple
of things we can do about this I will
because and those things are based on
the observation that this is basically
the behavioral program doesn't really
change based on how many times this loop
runs that that even if this loop
succeeds on the first call it try it
will do exactly the same thing as if it
succeeds on the tenth execution so what
we would like need to have to do is just
to try to run the program once really
because that is all that is actually
required to see to see all the
assertions and have them read all the
things they can there are a couple of
ways to do this one of them since we
have one of these loops that that that
if it fails and loops
it has our side effects we can replace
it with with a special intrinsic that is
actually not unique to New York but has
a bit of a complicated name anyway
called verifier assume so if we have
this intrinsic if we call this intrinsic
with a zero and let me just show you
what happens this will make the tool
abort execution of the part of the
search tree the tree I showed you before
where the verifier assumed zero call is
placed so if you just place it in main
we are just aborting execution before
anything interesting happens
and we are seeing nothing right so even
if you change this assertion to say
local is two it won't even find it right
we are terminating immediately but we
can use this to turn a pure loop like
this
[Music]
if we passed a success value from the
queue to assume now we're suddenly
ignoring the case we're assumed fails
where the queue fails because as we
argued before this doesn't change it
doesn't add actual actual behaviors just
just behaviour as for us as newbies
concerned
so now I didn't change the assertion
back so obviously the local is not - but
if we change the assertion back we can
see that they took after exploring two
traces in this case because it needs
actually around the second trace before
realizing it calls a zoom zero and and
is uninteresting we are able to check
this program as well so fortunately in
real world code these things are not so
common they're usually in like low-level
threading primitives and above that you
have blocking behavior or other stuff
that that makes it so you don't have to
do these kinds of things so in need who
can actually do this on its own for code
that isn't so complicated so I had to
introduce this queue data structure to
even be able to fool need hook to to do
this evil thing to not terminate here
but there is another thing you can do if
you don't want to change your code right
because that is sort of sort of icky if
you have to introduce if thefts and
stuff into your your code just to be
able to test it yoga also has this flag
called unroll which is a bit more
heavy-handed and will basically force
any loop you have in your program so
this is don't loop here to never be
executed more than than some number of
times so in other words it just uses
this this as you mechanism to stop it so
if we say unroll equals ten it will
execute the program
ten times and then the eleventh it
realizes it has gone too far so this is
a way to do it without actually touching
your code but obviously you will have to
to consider all your loops in your
program that you are not actually
preventing it from from from doing some
interesting behavior because using these
tools you can very easily prevent
yourself from finding real bugs if you
are not careful so that is the key part
you either use very for su and basically
you cut off a part of this tree that
means your builds of different orders
you can explore or you use unroll flag
and prevent loops from going further
than a certain point so that's it about
limitations of these techniques so let
me show you some other things that you
might encounter so say that you are have
a program that is calling a library and
this library is not part of all of the
files you are feeding to network in this
case it will let you do this call
functions such so called external
functions but it will vary
pessimistically assume that these
functions will go in and touch all the
memory you have justing just to be safe
that it doesn't miss some some kind of
strange behavior so it will definitely
reward this function with every other
memory access you have that it can and
obviously if you are using external
functions sometimes this is undesired
behavior because it makes Reed needle
run really slow because there are just
so many permutations of these things to
try so you can avoid it to do this by
promising to need hook and of course if
you break your promised and will not
will not give you any guarantees anymore
you can promise to network that that is
function has no no side-effects it will
not change its behavior if it's
reordered with something and will not
touch any memory so an example of this
is if we take the program we had before
right and we want to see what it
actually does so we add some some printf
statements here now if we run this
example so we use the unroll flag here
as well you can see that it runs it a
lot more times than then the 11 we saw
before and what is actually happening
here is that that that it is relieving
this waiting call into an q in every
possible location it can find where it
might do something interesting and and
this just explodes the state space but
obviously the only side effect printf
has is that I put stuff on screen in
this case which is a side effect we
don't want it to look at so if we use
this extra flag we get the 11 traces and
if I decrease the unroll country can can
use this to see a bit bit the different
traces it was exploring right it first
it immediately in cues right if we look
at the source
I have starting message first in print I
don't need to pack it this hard and then
it creates a thread and then it prints
just before putting something on the
queue and then we get awaiting message
for every time the DQ function fails so
the first execution take you immediately
succeeds the second one fails once and
this message is actually the other way
around because obviously it's not
automatically executed together with
them we thank you function so
and in the Siq last execution executed
it fails it twice just like like we saw
before or well I told you before that
now you can actually see it that it does
this alright so let's talk about this
thing called weak memory so just so I
have some perspective can we do a show
of hands how many of you know of weak
memory metals already okay not so many
all right good
so just to add insult to injury to make
programming even harder CPUs don't
actually execute code like nidhogg does
just picking a thread and doing it and
then picking some other thread and doing
it it actually executes it in a way that
that that makes it behave as if the
statements in your program are somehow
changing order from the vendor they are
appear in the source code but this
behavior only appears when you write
multi-threaded code so this is obviously
very painful if you are writing with a
threaded code and on an internal machine
for an example when you do a write to
memory it will not actually take this
this right you are doing and put it
immediately into memory but it will just
put it in a buffer in a queue somewhere
in the CPU and then it will keep on
executing your program and then at some
later point it will take this this data
and and then put it into the memory
system and this makes your program do
you have a question well yes yes indeed
so as I will tell you need who will
allow you to to see that the way the CPU
does these things or can do these things
according to its specification at least
and and you can check if you insert
barriers you can check that you have
done this correctly
so yeah the this buffer effect I talked
about which is appears on the Intel but
also on most CPUs actually and most
abuse actually have more behaviour but
but Intel is relatively relatively nice
to you in this regard this so the memory
model in which this is the only kind of
behavior strange behavior you can see is
called the total store or remodel and
need who can can can test programs under
this model with the same kind of
guarantees that you get for well without
that so you if the CPU is allowed to to
do these kinds of strange things it will
find it and tell you that your program
will fail under these conditions however
there is a gotcha and that is that it
does this by simulating these behaviors
right it doesn't actually create more
threads and if you call an external
function it doesn't know what that
function actually wrote so it will not
simulate these things so if you are
using external functions please don't
please just compile them into your input
too little because that that way you can
keep your your guarantees so let me show
you this because I'm sure it's a bit
hard to understand just by me speaking
so here I have a relatively simple
program again I'm using using variables
directly in this case I use volatile to
to trick the compiler to do the right
thing but you should probably use you
see eleven Atomics I just didn't because
it makes the example shorter but but
some tools in like need will scream at
you if you don't you see a lemon Atomics
because this is well with volatile it
isn't what I showed you before it's
actually undefined behavior but but if
you were using c11 Atomics you will get
the same behavior that I've already show
you so let's take a look at what this
program does so it has two threads in
this case the main thread only spawns
these threads and then then then stops
so the interesting behavior is in these
two three
and these two threads have two variables
they might communicate via so t1 first
writes to one of the variables and then
reads the other
and whereas t2 does the mirror thing so
it writes to the other variable and then
reads the first and this is part of one
of an good old mutual exclusion protocol
that so it this is supposed to guarantee
that that that these printf which are
sort of the critical section here will
not both be executed but so if this true
is it possible for for this program to
print fizzbuzz or buzz face for that
matter
one person is nodding someone else is
shaking their head okay so yeah it's
sort of a trick question because because
obviously if if if you just look at this
model where one thread is a qubit of
time either t1 is writing first and in
that case it's impossible for t2 to read
0 here or t2 is writing first which case
it is possible for t1 to to read 0 and
if we run it on the nead hook it will
also tell us as much so it executed the
program three times first time it
friends face
second time which means nothing because
this was just a section of the of the
code and the last time it prints buzz
but it never prints fizzbuzz all right
but remember this thing I put here on
the command line that has now grown
quite long I can delete some things to
make it easier to read this as seating
so SC C stands for sequential
consistency and it's just the technical
name for this this model where one
thread executes at a time but let's see
what happens if you replace this with
yes Oh which is what I talked about
before suddenly need to execute your
program four times and the last time it
actually prints this thing that we were
hoping it wouldn't is this spooky
fizzbuzz it's this thing that shouldn't
be possible either X is written first of
Y is written first and yet both threads
will well read zero here and this is a
natural behavior like if you if you
write this program and run it trillion
times in your Intel CPU eventually it
might do this and and for a bit larger
programs it is will appear frequently
but since it's so small it's sort of
hard to get a CPU to do this so how how
do you fix this I mean if you have have
this now we're not talking about how we
fix this we do help me fix your program
I mean your program does something you
don't want it to do right so so a guy in
the audience talked about fences so
there is the thing in on x86 for example
you have this special instruction called
m fence I believe and then I just add
some stuff so that the compiler knows
what what this thing is so if we shove
this this magical instruction in this
barrier instruction in now
suddenly an x86 CPUs I mean two CPU is
not allowed to let let this instruction
go below this instruction so the barrier
sort of prevents this kind of weak
memory behavior so let's see what
happens if we run run into on this thing
again so now we're back down to three
behaviors and of course you should
probably not use assembly intrinsics and
unless you're doing low-level and like
embedded programming or unless you
really have to and of course you can
write the c11 equivalence here which is
a bit longer so I will show you on
similar thing so if you use c11 Atomics
instead these by default unless you use
a really long form of local store and do
these kinds of fences for you so that it
will not behave this way so also if you
do it this way you will not get fizzbuzz
and actually since you are using c11 you
will never get face bars on any CPU if
you use these things so and tools like
need who can help you verify that your
code doesn't do something strange
excellent
so um over how are we for time I guess
we're good
yeah that's plenty okay so I promised
you a larger example so there is this
synchronization algorithm in the linux
kernel called read copy update which
lets you do atomic updates on on
arbitrarily large data structures by
doing an a pointer exchange and then
then
it has some mechanism to make sure that
you are not freeing this this old copy
of the data structure until all readers
have disappeared and in order to make
this is really scalable and it has grown
complicated over the years and is
currently at over four thousand five
hundred lines of very tricky
C code and it has historically been a
source of quite a few long-lived bugs
that have have only surfaced years after
they were introduced so in a case study
we used did hook we extracted a unit
test of this thing and used in hope to
test this and and by entry introducing
all these these historical bugs we were
able to to discover them and also in the
case where none are reintroduced you
were able to verify under the conditions
that so for this particular unit test we
have and so on and that there are no
more such bugs and so let me show you
some of the stuff we had to do to to
make need who eat kernel code like that
so actually there most of the the time
spent not on making making the code
please need hook as much as it is to to
detach everything to mock everything in
the Linux kernel to make it a standalone
unit test so there is a lot of of of
shrimps here around the primitives of
the
Linux kernel like hundreds of lines of
of mocking that that basically it takes
this highly integrated part of the Linux
kernel and makes it a standalone thing
that you can just use to to write a unit
test around so so these things are not
really you need to be specific code
right it's sort of it Maps like it Maps
the thread functions of the Linux kernel
onto P threads so on so let me show you
actually so these things everything's we
wrote but there is of course the parts
of the Linux kernel here and these are
mostly untouched so they're basically
the thing we touched was was things like
entry introducing these old bugs so
there is there is a lot of places like
this where we have have reintroduce
things that that that were bug fixed at
some point in the past so with this we
can actually run let's use this terminal
if I have the thing there is quite some
amount of
so I will accidentally teach you a bit
about the command lines into Xfinity
okay so you can't ask about compiler
flags here and then you have a - - and
then you have neat hook flag so all
these things I taught you before like
and this is a bit scary because MEMC CPI
could very easily be used to do racy
things right it modifies memory but in
this case we have manually checked all
places that called mem CPI and see that
it does nothing scary so this is just
some function that that need who doesn't
implement but it but it could it is a
bit one of the things that probably has
tools like need to have mature you
wouldn't need to do any more because
they already understand these things and
will do the right thing by default and
then we pass the name of the file which
is lit mustard C and I forgot the memory
model let's do TSO and you know since
this this of course takes a while since
it's so much code and in particular
there's about 40,000 behaviors I think
needle explores in this one unit test
which is actually quite simplistic how
long I forgot the unroll thing so here
we have also in this code there is also
this kind of a retry loop and just so
that we don't have to modify the code
because that sort of makes it less clear
that we write what we are actually
verifying if we have to change the code
to check it we're using unroll and then
to change that because we'll eat more
and more memory as the executions become
longer
it doesn't really eat more memory has to
become more executions just as they
become ridiculously long
so this will will take about well 20
minutes on our first computer but
probably 40 on this laptop but let's try
one of these force failure flags right
let's try to enable this thing and see
if we can find this bar on line 1890 in
in our see you yep
found it in two seconds and most of the
box I can show you the other ones as
well are found similarly fast right this
was found in three seconds and so on
right so probably if you have a bug in
your code and need you will find it
pretty fast as well but and if it needle
takes a while then either it's because
you have these these kinds of infinite
behaviors or it's because there are no
bugs and it is actually trying to
exhaust the space of all possible
behaviors of your code which for this
particular example takes about 20
minutes alright that was final example I
wanted to show you so there are more and
more research spent on tools like needle
which are used to test this real code
right you feel this C or C++ not some
some modeling language that you need to
really implement your program in and
this lets you you test that it's the
actual code that you're actually running
behaves properly a current part where a
lot of work is being spent is anjana
lysing these techniques to this 11
memory model which means that that tools
that will come out somewhat soon and
we'll see when they are actually
available these are academic things so
so making battle-hardened tool is not
what we are sponsored for unfortunately
but when they come out you will be able
to verify that your program not just
under under mmm Rumble or some
particular city you would like we did we
need you here but but at your program
assuming a correct compiler will behave
the correct way on any on any CPU and of
course all the skills I taught you here
will be perfectly transferable to these
tools because they are they take the
underlying principle is the same and
also if you are programming for some
Android foreign language and Java or
London there are more there are tools
for this as well so to conclude and
nidhogg lets you use unit testing to
test multi-threaded code which is has
traditionally been a hard thing to do it
is open source it's quite easy to
compile
you just need to link it to LLVM there
is just simple configure and make and
make install sequence and then you have
it on your command line just like i do
and you know please check it out that's
it
do you have any questions
hi
what CPUs are currently supported by
network
so aside from sequential consistency and
total store order which is basically
trust Intel CPUs need hope implements
for one thing I've member all called
well there is another CPU that
implements to trust order and that is
SPARC CPUs which you might have I guess
and Spock CPUs are also capable at least
older ones of being configured to run on
different memory model called PSO and
since it is sufficiently similar to you
so we implemented as well aside from
that there is there is some support for
for the power memory model of PowerPC
but some of the features I showed you
today do not work with this memory model
and and it is also the implementation is
also a bit slow so probably once tools
for c11 come out this will be preferable
assuming they are they get a level of
polished indeed question you don't be
able to warn you about having
deterministic behavior yes
so looks for four branches where you
have well place it in your code where
your pro code goes one way the first
time it executes it and then the other
way the second time and will produce a
warning and there are some edge cases
that will make need hook just crash but
these are relatively this is something
we will be fixing so so yes the short
answer is yes it will warn you
okay all right thank you
[Applause]