the besides DC 2017 videos are brought
to you by threat quotient introducing
the industry's first threat intelligence
platform designed to enable threat
operations and management and data tribe
a new kind of startup studio Co building
the next generation of commercial cyber
security analytics and big data product
companies welcome to the fifth annual
'besides
I know I'm amazed - I didn't think we'd
make it this far and the third annual
Crip kits when they are when they asked
me ok when they asked me to do a Crip
kids 3 years ago I said sure
and I remember afterwards being almost
in tears because all I could think of
was what went wrong and what wasn't
right and what I felt could have been
better and how I felt like it had failed
but the kids coming up to me afterwards
all they focused on was what they
thought was amazing and what they loved
and what they thought was fantastic and
they didn't see any of the stuff that I
saw so I decided to relax a little now
and realize that I think y'all are going
to have a fabulous time we're bigger and
better than ever this year we have added
two kids escape rooms for those who
didn't know thank you to endgame and
Raytheon they have sponsored those rooms
[Applause]
if you'd like to attend the escape room
you need to go to the booth in the crypt
kids area where will queue kids and get
you the room numbers and and figure out
I'm going to say this we've never done
this before I'm not quite sure how to do
this please be patient as we try to make
this run smoothly it may not be real
smooth in the beginning but we're going
to do our best we'll take notes and
we'll try to make it better next year
we have also added a PI bakery Raspberry
Pi and with the blessings of the
directors I am announcing officially now
and there will be flyers at both the
front table and in the PI bakery there
will be a pie bake-off next year so you
kids have one year to work on your
recipe and bake us the best pie you can
and there will be a contest and the
winner of the contest will receive a
black badge adult badge - besides DC
we am also really excited beyond words
to announce that the individual who will
be quote running of the kids CTF the
share will be an eight year old lung
young lady and so I want you when you go
in to give her lots of support she is
amazing and I'm super excited so we are
actually trying to get more kids
involved with teaching and running with
other kids so that's our first like
major staff member drumming something
that's eight years old so I'm really
excited about that one the last thing I
want to announce is we are going to be
banding again this year if you have
never done this before we try to match
kids to parents for some semblance of
security so that nobody tries to walk
off with your kids so be patient as we
move you guys through that kind of
there's a little bit of a bottleneck but
once we get through it it's good to go
and we will if you have not read the
program be having I know that I've had a
lot of feedback about folks that come
with their kids and they can't really go
to the after-party at the Iron Horse or
they don't feel the bright leaving their
family and their hotel room and going
out drinking we will be having this year
for the very first time and hopefully
for forever after this in all ages
afterparty bring your own board game
where your funky PJs party tonight
everyone's invited you don't have to be
a Crip kids ticket holder all children
are invited and you have to bring an
adult with you or you don't have to
bring a child but if you're an adult and
you'd prefer not to drink or you're just
looking for a quiet space want to play
some games and chill everyone's invited
to the congressional where we do the
regular crip kids come on down tonight
between 7:00 and 10:00 and just hang out
and relax have a good time kids are
welcome everyone I just ask that if you
are an adult and you prefer to drink to
keep those two separate okay don't bring
any drinking in there and if you have
already had a little bit please don't
come in and ruin the kids fun okay
that all being said I want to talk about
our keynote introduce her when I have to
find someone as a keynote I try to find
somebody who can both be a voice for the
kids but also bring them a message and
this woman that is about to speak with
you as someone I met years ago she is
kind she is inclusive to all she's a
champion of women in stem but she's a
champion for everybody not just women I
am trying not to cry as I get ready to
say but she's a wonderful woman I'm so
so honored that she has agreed to come
talk with us I'm so excited for her to
share this with you today
so I'm going to turn this over to Kimber
Doucet her biography is in your program
and Miss Kimber would you please come up
[Applause]
good morning well good I'm glad you
talked to back to me so let's just start
by being real here do you guys get
nervous if you have to ask a question in
class what about no what about when you
have to present in front of your class
yeah but you still do it anyway right so
I am pretty nervous but I'm gonna try to
be as brave as you are every day so
let's uh let's get started so welcome to
a bright new hello world and my parents
in the room will probably get that joke
but see so hi so a little about me I'm
gonna keep it really brief my name is
Kimber
Doucette but everyone I know calls me
bat like the fluffy little animal not
the baseball thing I like bats a lot I
really like comic books does anybody
like comic books oh thank goodness
injustice right so this little picture
of me I just stuck in here because I am
tearing apart a computer and I have
screwdrivers in my ears
don't put screwdrivers in your ears but
this was actually in 2005 at Apple's
Technical Training in Cupertino
California and I was one of the very
first women to successfully complete and
get Apple certified desktop and
operating system certification so I got
to meet Steve Jobs which is pretty cool
so I have a couple of jobs I work as
head of infrastructure engineering at
18f I'm not gonna bore you with that but
basically I get to play in the cloud all
day it's super fun and when I'm not
doing that
I'm a mission information specialist at
NASA anybody heard of that one or yeah
so lasers cryogenics and optics stuff
ground systems super fun but mostly I
like the free stickers we get I'll be
honest
and I really like hacking stuff so let's
play GameSpot the hacker raise your hand
if you think the hacker is a alright how
about B okay how about C alright well
I'm gonna give I mean give some of you a
hint it is pretty hard to type wearing
gloves and a balaclava that's that funny
mask he's wearing so we're gonna rule
that guy out but a and C those are my
hackers on the screen so what does that
mean oh no you might have a hacker
delivered in your house right now it's
okay everything is gonna be fine
we got this right we're gonna work
together we got this so kids I'm gonna
talk to your parents for a minute now so
you're just gonna have to like sit
patiently adults we do this right we
talk while you're in the room and
pretend like you're not here alright so
parents let's talk about this I know
there are a lot of really smart adults
in the room but do you ever watch your
kid and think oh my gosh how did my kid
just figure that out and maybe you have
to accept that your kid might be smarter
than you are at their age they're pretty
observant so you kind of have to watch
what you say watch what you do because
they're absorbing everything like a
little sponge right so let's talk about
some qualities you know all these things
right they're tough to parent mm-hmm
they'll push back do you guys hear why a
lot like who's kids say why who's kids
except because I said so
nope they want an answer like you've got
a bad answer they want to know that you
acknowledge their achievements that you
think their ideas are important don't we
all right they're not just rambling
they're gonna say the same thing to you
a dozen times and they're just trying to
get you to acknowledge that they said it
right and they need some freedom to
explore their ideas and it's really
really hard for technical folks to watch
their kids and
and technical challenges and not like
mmm helicopter parent right we want to
save them from our failures if you put
that battery in upside down it's gonna
blow up your board sometimes you just
barring safety issues right you have to
let them fail and figure things out on
their own and we all know that we're all
if we're those of us in InfoSec you
realize that most of us are here because
we sort of stumbled our way to this
place after successes and failures
through what help desk fixing stuff
system administration work networking
whatever so there's little bad news
right does it feel like your kid wants
to be in charge do they I kind of want
to call the shots cuz they know what's
best
they got this they just need you to back
off and let them do their thing
and if you're doing it right which I bet
most of you are you're smart kids they
already know they're smart like you've
reinforced this attitude you've
encouraged them and now they know
they're smart and now you've kind of
opened Pandora's box they have a very
low boredom threshold right like five
minutes ten minutes whose kids are bored
I mean it just comes with it right cuz
they've they've already moved on to the
next thing so speaking of that mmm let's
talk about some good news with freedom
and guidance they're gonna do great
things
positive reinforcement how far does that
go encouragement we all know this but
sometimes we get so wrapped up in what
we're doing it's kind of hard to just
take a step back and realize that
they're just exploring their world and
we have to kind of be the conduit for
them
so speaking of boredom who's bored
really really more adults than kids you
guys are the worst
all right let's build a thing you ready
all right I did not make the appropriate
sacrifice to the demo gods but we're
just gonna like I'll cross our fingers
and do some good mojo that this actually
works out so if you have a card
we'll if you have a card remember I
walked around and handed you a little
card I want you to hold your cards up
high in the air okay all my folks with
card doesn't need you to come right up
to the front you can do it if you're
scared I believe in you and you can do
it but if you don't really want to do it
you can give it to a friend let's see
how many do we have how many do we have
one two three four five six seven eight
nine - Oh perfect great so there Legos
on three separate tables look at your
cards your cards have a code on them and
that's all I'm gonna tell you you ready
did you look at your cards to figure
anything out there I'm gonna give you
ten minutes or so give or take depending
on how this neck the next thing goes to
build the tallest you listening tallest
most stable structure you can got it you
got about ten minutes ready
all right go okay while my Lego builders
are working on this activity the rest of
us are gonna be super bored if we don't
figure out something else to do so let's
do something else you with me let's
solve a thing who likes crypto who knows
what crypto is ish all right well it's
gonna be pretty clear what one little
branch of crypto looks like in just a
second
who likes puzzles perfect let's just
call this a puzzle jokes do you have any
jokesters who likes jokes okay this next
puzzle is joke if you know the punchline
I'm begging you just zip it and you just
have to sit quietly while everybody else
figures it out parents no hints okay we
need this activity to draw out for 10
minutes you work with me here please
all right I want you to raise your hand
when you think you have the answer and
the first hand I see goes up mister
Franklin is gonna come find you and give
you a card that I want you to hang on to
okay you ready
all right why did the skeleton cross the
road now parents I said no hints but if
you need to hand on like a device
because they need a notepad or something
feel free right so I'm gonna watch your
hands really
Oh figure out the puzzle
this one's one yeah maybe oh you have it
don't say it out loud mr. Franklin can
you go check raise your hand so you can
see you big and tall
[Music]
so this is kind of how your parents jobs
go when they're like this close to
figuring out of things somebody beats
them to the punch and gets all the
credit
this is life
does he have it
no you don't get no grownups you people
you got one right
somebody figure it out you got anybody
Zeca to get a car yeah Oh check back
here that's okay
however my builder is doing down there
okay give him a card good job
yep just get one card did you get it all
right we'll do one more right over here
and then we're gonna I'm gonna give you
the punchline okay right over there
yep all right you ready let's see if
he's got it
all right good job okay so here we go
well added the skeleton cross the road
what's the answer to get to the body
shop come on come on all right so we had
two folks figure that out it looks like
our builders need just a couple more
minutes so we'll do one more puzzle
we're gonna try harder one
you ready so parents you can help with
this but don't give them the answer okay
you're ready here we go
when does it rain money
[Music]
first hand up gets the card
you can use your notepads on your phones
I see a couple iPads with parents my
builders are doing a great job aren't
they can you give our builders a hand
[Music]
okay we got about two more minutes
weirdest keynote ever right you're just
sitting and solving puzzles and it's
fine
all right do we need a hint so if you
look at the bottom I've filled in some
of the the letters of the code for you I
just didn't add them to the puzzle up
top so I bet if you filled in that e4
you'd get pretty close to an answer you
have it all right let's check it out
right over here
yeah she's right there
[Music]
you didn't solve it Frank Lane
we have a winner all right we ready yeah
when does it rain money when there is
change in the weather come on you know
that's funny all right
congratulate our winner all right great
job let's check on their builders ok
builders wrap it up put down one or two
more blocks
look at him scramble this is like mice
crumbs okay all right that's time
everyone I want you my builders to take
a look at the screen can you do that for
me let's talk about teamwork
so teamwork the combined action of a
group of people right we know what a
team is I want to ask you guys a
question why did you split up why did
you separate what do you think did I
tell you you couldn't work together did
anybody hear me say that no so I gave
you some cards and they had some codes
and like maybe you could have found the
people that matched your codes and
formed a team but that would have been
three teams but either way you all
worked individually which has actually
never happened to me before in this
exercise so we have a lot of independent
thinkers here which is fantastic so I
tell you what you just had about ten
minutes I'm gonna give you about two
minutes to work together and let's see
what happens can you do that can we all
work together let's see what happens if
we combine resources do you know what
that means what happens if you combine
the things you build you think that'll
happen show me let's see
all right they don't need it I don't
know they can do what they want do you
want to tear them down do you want to
build them up you want to add somebody's
to the top of yours you want to make a
bigger base do all the things you have a
good idea go share it with a friend okay
so what we've done here it seems a split
off into a bunch of individual teams
which is also never happen what if all
12 people combine Legos help me make my
point here people all right so our
towers are getting taller
we'll just let them play for a minute
and and and again if the demo goes
correctly they'll have something taller
together than they had separately you
with me yeah okay all right
so how we doing you got one more minute
make it count
don't get stressed out no pressure
there's just like a hundred people
watching you
[Music]
I just want to go down there and help so
that paint base see that's like a good
solid base you should just combine that
with somebody else and put their thing
on the top but yes we try everyone work
together but we've got the outliers on
the end down there who are the little
engineers we can tell see right here in
the front row this nice young lady said
everyone worked together and it'll be
stronger and bigger okay there we go
that's time everyone you can step back
from the table let's see what we've got
good job that's okay now raise your hand
down here my builders if your towers
taller now that you worked with a friend
yeah great can I ask you all to take
your seats
but please hang on to your cards you'll
need those cards in just a few minutes
okay that is like my infrastructure
sometimes you just have to lay it down
and let it ride there you go all right
don't forget your cards good job
everyone thank you for helping
[Music]
[Applause]
so together we're stronger now think if
I had given them 30 minutes or an hour
all together with maybe the pile in the
middle of the room you see how I'm
working through the way this will work
better next time but I think that we
learned a lesson can we say it together
sure okay who doesn't like spongebob
right he had to make it to the top so
kids you're not off the hook I gave your
parents a stern lecture but you have
some work to do too you ready
who's paying attention raise your hand
if you're paying attention touch your
nose if you're paying attention all
right that's about half of you what I'll
take it
responsibility I could read all of these
words to you but I'll just that just
doesn't seem good it's just too much
let's keep it simple you ready this is
bad if your parents teachers or other
adults to trust they're trusting you
enough to use their electronics their
tech go online or even better how many
kids in here have parents or adults in
their lives who bought them their own
computer or iPad or Kindle right you
guys are pretty lucky so don't set it on
fire okay
look at this kid this is good this kids
building things doing a good job it's
okay to use electronics and technical
equipment and tools for things other
than they were intended because after
all that's the definition of hacker
right so if you do that you're hacking
but don't put anything that puts
yourself in harm's way like don't do
things that put yourself in harm's way
either in person or on the Internet
there's dangers there too
but I'm gonna leave that lecture for
your parents if you don't know if that
thing's safe or not at home at school or
even here today just ask an adult okay
and they'll they'll steer you in the
right direction leadership leading
people the state of being a leader again
definitions let's break it down this is
bad don't do this when you go to your
group meetings please don't like pull
your friends hair or your friend of me
or your enemy or any of those things but
this is good look don't they look
happier and they're probably not gonna
get timeouts or grounded or have their
Kindles confiscated so it's important to
exercise leadership but another thing I
want you to understand is that you can
have more than one leader in a group
sometimes being a leader means stepping
back and let somebody else take control
like take charge take control sometimes
I have to step back and let somebody who
knows more than me take over the project
and that means you're a good leader too
at least that's what I tell myself
decision-making you have to make
decisions every day beginning kids
pretty hard so just again let's break it
down this is bad don't go to jail don't
go to kid jail
whether kid jail is actually jail jail
or timeout in your room or you know Oh
questions we'll save right till the end
how's that sound so yeah don't do this
but you can do this right like she's
following directions she's probably been
given instructions she's doing things
she should do she's getting to play
minecraft who doesn't like minecraft so
we want you to build code Explorer but
we want you to make good choices as
you're doing that and and your parents
will be there to help you every step of
the way so if things get tough I want
you to close your eyes and take a deep
breath so I'm going to teach you a trick
right now for when you're stressed out
it works for grownups too I totally do
it all the time you ready okay who's
gonna participate I look pretty silly if
I'm doing this by myself I want you to
remember a rhyme one two three I'm
taking care of me what we're gonna do is
we're gonna take a deep breath in
through our nose for the count of three
so and we're gonna breathe out through
our mouths and when we do that we're
gonna think to ourselves I'm taking care
of me and if we can do that three times
it takes all the stress away there are
these things called mind monkeys and
they make your brain all stressed out
and then your body has the physical
reactions if you can take a step back
and try breathing totally helps you
ready it's not gonna fix everything but
it's really good starts let's try it in
three rows
althrough your mouth don't spit on your
friends and think I'm taking care of me
one two three I'm taking care of me
right one more time
don't you feel better I sure do some
days are gonna be tougher than others
I like cat memes it's a thing some days
you'll want to rage quit
I can explain rage quitting very simply
who plays video games who throws their
controller when they're angry me you
know what I have to do I have to go buy
a new controller and I don't beat the
level because my controller is broken
that's called rage quitting right when
you play the board game with your
friends and then they're winning and
then you just like storm away and don't
let them have the win
that's rage quitting don't do that it's
tough cuz we all do it adults do it too
just try not to I just want you to hang
in there
I like sloths true story but it can't
leave this room it's a total secret but
when I pop boxes or hack things I know I
love bats but actually my signature is
this sloth picture or the sloth picture
being like the sloth being dragged away
by police and I'll leave it somewhere on
the box so then people know that I got
there first I want to tell you and not a
condescending way that your parents and
the adults in your life have a lot going
on all the things you have going on like
then throw on top of that bills and
mortgages and jobs and marriages and
stress and co-workers and then getting
you clothes and new Kindles all these
things right sometimes they don't
realize when you're sad or frustrated
and you have to talk to them you have to
tell them sometimes they won't know
unless you tell them
try to remember they're still learning
and also remember you have a way you
have a little tool I gave you a write a
rhyme today to take care of yourself so
if you're frustrated and you go and you
scream at your parents it's gonna go in
one ear and right out the other but if
you can take three deep breaths first
and come to them calmly I bet you're
gonna find that they they hear you so
ready let's see who learns ready deep
breath in right isn't that nice
all right here's where it gets real
you're gonna change the world and I'm
not even kidding
every single child in this room is gonna
change the world and if you don't
believe me and you don't think that's
possible you could just ask your parents
how much their world changed when you
came into their lives about your parents
will agree with me you've actually
already changed the world
but you still have some more to do and
you're just getting started
so are you ready who's ready for crib
kids today who's gonna build some fun
stuff who's gonna build something cool
who's gonna learn to code apparently mr.
Andrew Cole is teaching kids to code in
PowerShell tomorrow
nice who's gonna make some new friends
maybe practice some teamwork like we
learned today right okay so everyone who
has a card so now there should be 15 of
you I'm gonna have you come line up
right along this wall because I have
some special prizes for you okay now I
just want to let the parents know my
problem solvers my three folks who solve
the crypto puzzles mr. blinky bling is
generously donated some electronic
badges so you'll have to help them
solder and then I have a donation from
the Cryptologic Museum I'll by Fort
Meade totally worth going to see they
donated some some wonderful stuff here
too so I'm gonna leave you with my
special thanks I hope you all have a
wonderful time this weekend
thank you for having me
[Applause]