the besides DC 2017 videos are brought
to you by threat quotient introducing
the industry's first threat intelligence
platform designed to enable threat
operations and management and data tribe
a new kind of startup studio co building
the next generation of commercial cyber
security analytics and big data product
companies so I submitted my talk
originally it's supposed to be case
study on hacking aces routers
specifically from the application layer
there were many other people chosen the
front of me and I was chosen as a backup
speaker and now you know why how can I
can work on this if you want to go hang
this under like in your slides up ok
thank you ok so my talk is about so I'm
an application security engineer my
background is a software developer I
don't mess with routers in a regular
basis or on an annual basis and what I
do is I do security on application layer
that means Java apps web apps no GS apps
we don't descend below level seven
however I happen to have a router and I
got curious about what's actually inside
the router and firmware it's kind of one
of the things I never had a chance to
look into so I spend one night unpacking
the firmware and like just started
looking into it and what I found in
there is actually I got five CVS of her
actually hack into the router but all of
them are still on application layer
there's nothing on the network layer so
again so my talk was really about thank
you
it's about even things that we don't
expect from the application layer we
don't expect those things to be in
routers but are there anyway so I'm a
sorta developer I work for a big
financial institution who wishes to
rename unnamed you could google it and I
have some background in around anti-spam
piping so if you know what SPF is and
DKIM I was involved in those things many
years ago I also wrote the RFC for comma
separated value files if you use those
I'm going to talk about expectations and
this is my standard warning don't hack
your friend
as permission now there's two parts to
this talk first I'm just gonna run
through the process my total process of
what I went through and then I want to
show you what exactly that was that I
found so I'm not a pen tester I'm a
developer
I'm the guy that and testers hate
because I install stuff on my computer
that you don't want to see what happens
is that I never dealt with firmware I
know
hypothetically what firmware is I know
what a router is I know what it's
running but I never actually looked into
it so I have an Asus router and over the
years I was curious what's inside the
router so they if you know anything
about Asus they're not exactly very
regular with their updates so when I
didn't come up with an update I was kind
of trying to figure out is there a way
for me to kind of crack it open and see
what's inside now for those of you who
work with routers all day it's probably
a no-brainer but for me coming as a
software developer way way up in the
stack the router to me is a box it's a
box you stick on a network and you let
it do its own thing
so what was curious to me what basically
is the point of my talk is I started
from the application layer and I ended
up in application layer even though it
was a router now this way this basically
took about a night I download the
firmware I open the buffer I found the
file what in the world is a file it
turns out it was some sort of a Linux
partition and again I'm just going on
blindly
I'm opening the files I'm looking into
them so I open the file now one thing I
do know is that routers do not run
Windows and if you have a router just
running Windows you probably shouldn't
be having it inside the router there
JSON files and the ASP files now ASP
files are dotnet IAS files they do not
belong in routers so obviously there's
something something's funny so this was
the essentially the command flow is that
I took the file IO download Ben walk I
opened it up never he's been walked
before and here's what I found now I'm
not interested from my point of view
and looking into the sea source and the
command the luminescent configurations
and there that's not what my expertise
is in so what I was looking for is just
curious just see what's in there
so I see these ASP files now in the
application security world and ASP file
is a Windows I script obviously that's
not what the router is supposed to have
but when I went in and inside these
files it's actually turned out to be
HTML and JavaScript for whatever reason
ace has decided to package their web UI
files as a SPS there's some sort of an
engine interprets them I don't know what
the engine is I didn't think into it but
what I did see is a DOS or JSON code now
once it Duggan into all the way down
what I saw was JSONP now JSONP for those
who are not familiar is that the browser
security model prohibits us from loading
JavaScript files across domains JSONP is
a way to kind of bypass that and if you
tell the server here's my callback
function in JavaScript and give me the
JSON what it does is it doesn't just
return the JSON file to you it also
wraps around and executed the callback
function you provide what happens is
that to bypass the security model
instead of using the standard ways you
load it you would do is a simple script
include udo script include you pass it
to your server it loads your JSON now a
router is not a place where you've wanna
find JSONP and in the second part I'm
going to actually show you what that
looked like but essentially what that
means is you can do calls into the web
UI of the router and you can get stuff
back this is an example of what one of
the files looks like again I don't know
what the engine is I didn't dig enough
into it there must be something Linux
see what it is exactly I don't know but
what you do see is it's kind of like
it's putting some data into it now at
that point what I'm have is I have the
router that's working with the UI and I
have my source code and the names start
to match some names match some names
don't match so
I'm not in an outer world anymore now
I'm back to where I started were my
expertise lies which is application
security now what I'm looking at the
router I'm no longer looking at it as a
box I'm looking at it as somebody wrote
a UI they have a web application which
is insecure it happens to be running in
the router versus a conventional
computer but that's what I'm looking at
so I started looking at it now this
point is I'm not thinking in terms of
ports I'm not thinking in terms of what
services are running on the router I'm
looking from a point of view of an
application security engineer and what
we're looking what if or is this is a
web UI there are common things that are
described in the OS top ten that web UI
is have they're vulnerable
those are some of the things you can
start with but basically just start
looking around as if treating it not as
a router but as any other application so
I started looking at this there was no
specialized tool and not use Burke a lot
of Chrome I put up the developer tools
in chrome and I just started going to
the router UI and if the firmware is bad
from what I hear the UI apparently was
even worse the quality of the code at
least I saw the JavaScript was from a
security angle was pretty bad so at this
point over a couple days so I found one
I found two found three - four
eventually or five different CVS if you
follow the entire chain all the way to
its end you can take over anybody driver
now there is a very big difference in
web security and application security
how you take things off okay
how you take something over vs. network
level and in part two I'm going to go
through it now at this point so I just
spent a couple nights looking at a
router I've got a bunch of issues now
what am I supposed to do with it if I
was a black hat hacker I know what I'm
supposed to do with it now luckily for
aces or not I Canada aces now aces took
a while I always go through cert for
those of you who've dealt with
responsible disclosure it's kind of cert
isn't always helpful but if a says this
if the vendor decides to go back after
you at least you have a second
individual independent party that was
involved eventually they fix that one of
them we still have a disagreement on
they don't want to fix it I think it's
an issue they don't think it's an issue
and I'll show you what the issue looks
like about a talking about a month to
fix it
Aibileen extra months afterwards to
actually disclose it the funny thing
happened is once it was disclosed and
again I don't know why this issue over
any other should the media suddenly
picked her up high reported an issue in
a single router model based on what the
users are started sending to me 45 the
somewhere between 40 to 50 different
aces models are affected I think pretty
much every single one
Easter's officially only release patches
for specific ones but as sort of these
other things start coming out of the
woodwork they start affecting the rest
of them the last issue is being worked
on as far as enough for at least for the
router that I worked on which is the RT
and 56 they do not have a fix
however they do have a fix for
everything else so bottom line is is
that from me as an application security
engineer it's good to be curious even
though I'm I don't touch the network
level stuff in this case it was a good
it was a good thing and a lot of times
we have silos that we work in specific
areas we don't necessarily always follow
things now what I wanted to do at this
point is when I actually go through the
seven vulnerabilities in interesting
thing about aces aces is actually under
a legal consent decree because their
orders are not secure and I believe
d-link is going through the same issue
the Federal Trade Commission is slowly
going through all the various router
vendors and suing them to force them to
do security that I think that that is I
think one of the reasons why Asus
responded so fast because my experience
with other vendors even Google has not
been that fast there's 42 models
everything it's RT - since I wrote the
slide I think that the number crept up a
little bit because some of the routers
Artie is the retail model there's also
the 4G models there's a couple of other
variations everything prior to 2017 is a
fact that there is at least two open
source projects derived from the Asus
firmware I think one is the Asus wrt one
is the Merlin project if they copy code
from Asus and Asus is very good about
GPL disclosure then they are probably
affected I did not test them to give you
a scale in terms of sort of the rest of
the internet their market share at least
according to what the industry people
are saying is 4.3 percent in last year
for the high-end Wi-Fi routers basic
anything over 100 bucks there our share
is much more it's like 13% now very
important point is the last one this is
not Network level that means you cannot
just go into show them or sensors or
anything like that and start scanning
every single IP you will not find these
issues because this is a web security
issue not a network security issue this
quotation is path is different in some
ways it's easier in some ways is much
harder so it's not something you could
just your pop open from a port so these
are the CVEs that I found there are
essentially are four of them
miter miter when they assign them I
think they were recently I asked for two
they signed for there's a fifth one so
these these are basically r4 and what
these four are are as follows the first
one is the one that's the worst that is
known as the CSRF now CSRF attack relies
on the fact that you don't have state in
the browser when the browser talks to
the website there is no state so there's
various tricks that we do to establish
state the most common is a cookie but
essentially is if you're logged into
beta my telecom any other website can
start posting stuff to the same to send
them in because the browser will just
take the cookie and send it over now
that is not something you want to see in
a router because if you do have a CSRF
issue in your router that means you can
actually do a post to the router UI from
any other site and change things the
next two are somewhat less of an issue
if you do have connectivity to the
router then I mentioned earlier there's
a callback you can do callback from any
other website remember there's no web
security at this point because the
people that all do you I chose to bypass
it by putting in JSONP you to call the
router and you get stop back and I'll
show you some of the examples of what
you can get back but there's a lot of
interesting things that come out of the
router you have to be authenticated
the third one is there's an unoffending
here endpoint if you want to go and
start attacking your users and you wanna
see who has a router or who doesn't
that's the endpoint you would use you
could choose once you know what they
lack on the local network looks like you
call that endpoint as a matter of fact
the official Asus application that they
have Android that's the same thing and
then you can actually detect whether
somebody's running or not running an
Asus router and then the vulnerabilities
are listed in order of the CPU numbers
not in order of severity the last one is
the Wi-Fi password disclosure there's an
endpoint in the router will give you the
Wi-Fi password now at this point
Asus chose to actually make it a little
more secure that is an XML endpoint not
a JSONP endpoints so web security in
browsers at this point kicks in and you
can't actually do this but if you manage
to somehow cross a natural boundary if
you on the user's local network you'll
get their Wi-Fi passwords now these are
the actual CPUs how do we actually what
do we do with them what do we how do we
put them together so first of all just
to review about CSRF unless you're using
a mod of very modern browser with the
latest version of Chrome and using
something called same site which is very
very new every time you do requests to a
site a cookie gets sent back and then
establishes a devil established state so
that will happen as anybody can sort of
write in that session the proper way to
get around those issues is that for
those who work in application security
we have CSRF tokens which are tokens
that are generated every single time
something comes back from the server and
we have this
that second token back that is not what
is happening in the Asus router JSONP is
the other one JSONP is a way to bypass
basically any every browser restriction
there is JSONP originally was invented
as a way to when the beginnings of
security in web browsers were put in
that's what
how much people starting to figure out
we cannot load data from other sites
through XML HTTP requests how do we do
this so they came up with JSONP which is
not really a standard it's a convention
but essentially is you could do a script
include and you tell the server here's
the callback function I want so you can
lose script including say callback it
will give you back piece of JavaScript
rather data and that callback and
executed in will in your within the
context of your with your machine now
what will happen is let's say if you
have Bank of America and Bank of America
does this so they have adjacent the
endpoint then anyway other website can
you just go and do bank robbery on comp
slash JSONP and get whatever data does
something back in application security
world this is very very bad
the funny thing is if they were not
using JSONP ease of using XML HTTP
request which is what most sites are
using then web security in the browser
kicks in automatically it wouldn't have
the session so somebody went out of the
way and actually put in the JSON v this
is the exploit chain now if you notice
destination is very different than
Network level network level exploit
chain starts with scanning there's no
scanning here the first problem is is
that we cannot actually get to the UI of
the router because running internally
it's running within the local network it
should not be accessible from the
outside the way you will need to do that
you need to get somebody who is on that
network to visit a malicious page you
could do a watering hole you could do
spam you could do a fake
you know app whatever it is you have to
get somebody to actually click on that
link and hit that site it's and it will
not work otherwise but once you do that
then the next step is let's say you did
manage to fish someone you did manage to
do whatever it is and now they are on
your site
then what we do is is the second step is
there's that end point sorry the third
that the second step is you have to find
out what they appear interests
now most browsers most modern browsers
support a protocol the protocol called
WebRTC which is used for essentially
video chatting skyping and stuff like
that WebRTC has got a bunch of security
holes even though I think there's a
black presentation a couple years back
essentially here you could tell your
browser and ask it what is your local
range and will tell you what the local
LAN ranges now at that point so let's
say you know the local range most
routers will sit as the first one so it
says one into one six eight nine nine it
will be probably 99.1 that's when you
get to the third step is again the user
still on that site they hit that site
the site runs the JavaScript to do web
RTC the next point is it runs the third
step which is it calls the JSONP
endpoint and says are you alive if it
gets a response back that's an Isis
router now you are at step four now this
may sound like you know this never
happens right no no everybody changes
their credentials if you look at the
studies that been done most abusers do
not bother to change their credentials
for the router because there are is
inside of arbol so what happens is the
AC drivers come with the full potentials
the things have been admin password or
admin admin that's when the next
vulnerability comes in so the CSRF
attacks so again we're dealing with
several different steps I'm gonna go
through all of them but the CSRF
attacked and lets you log into the
router number five you can use
additional endpoints to collect
information on the router and number six
is when you can actually use the same
set of vulnerability to do whatever you
want
in my example you to none involved
access you put an I port
you could also for example number seven
Asus routers have ability to some logs
remotely you could add also but at that
point every setting within the router
can be changed and what's interesting
there is the user has to be visiting a
malicious site and it's saying
they don't have to be logged into the
router this I can do it all for them and
all it doesn't take very long it takes
maybe 30 seconds and then then it's done
now the first step is obviously the
hardest this is this is why this attack
is not rated higher because this is not
the kind of thing that you can clear out
right of warm for this is a kind of
thing to just scan all ip's you have to
actually trick someone to visit our site
and there are many ways to do that you
could phishing spam watering holes
whatever it is you have to actually do
that first step now a conventional
phishing attack lets you when you click
a site it asks you ask you for username
passwords if a gmail site a lot of the
detection mechanisms around fishing will
look for that this does not all this
needs to do is you visit any site
because the user will not see the
JavaScript commands that are happening
behind the scenes so what they do is at
this point you give them some how to
visit a malicious site now at that point
using WebRTC and that's the link to one
of the security one of the security
issues flash is another way for it to
leak you can also assume that that one
that's zero that one that one's probably
default if you're using a mobile app
that may work also my router the one
that I worked on doesn't have the last
issue but some routers actually do if
because they control the DNS they have
default the mains defined they will
always go to router so you could check
whether the main is there and then
access the endpoint and at that point
you'll see whether it's bases around or
not an Asus router but the third step is
so now you have the visit of the page
you either hit you find out what the IP
address was or you hit on those domains
that is the endpoint that you need to
hit if you hit that endpoint on IP it
will give you that information the
information is very basic from a
security angle that sounds pretty
innocent all it's going to tell you is
what is the model what is the SSID of
the network and what's AP address of it
the second one is even smaller but by
itself this is the one that we actually
still arguing with ASUS about they
haven't fixed it because they don't
consider this to be an issue I consider
this to be an issue because it's another
way in further in like for example the
model number some of the Asus models
have patches some of them do not if I
know what the model number of your
router is then I can target specific
attacks to that model I think in they
are convinced at this point there is
this an issue but they haven't fixed it
yet
so you have you you have your website
you call these two endpoints you get
some data back now you know the user is
running they're running an Asus router
this is an example of an actual code
that will do that I have it's called in
my blog this highway this is a very very
basic way of doing it obviously more
sophisticated way of doing it but this
is how you would do this in JavaScript
you append a child element with a script
include you call whatever that endpoint
is either will come back when an arrow
will come back with the data you looking
for next step is the actual login the
default login for the router is admin
admin it needs to be base64 encoded very
simple example just a form you fill Phi
the form you do form that submit either
you're in and you're not in any way you
verify that is the next step but
essentially this relies in the fact that
the user is not the user will not change
their credentials which is true in most
cases however I do want to point out in
this point this step if they change
their credentials it's not much you can
do so it does rely there's multiple
steps here that need to happen but based
on what I've seen out there and the
service they were done most users do not
change the credentials if they did
change their credentials then you have
to go with you know you conventional
phishing or something similar so at this
point you know there are router IP you
know it's running an Asus you know which
model is is it's running and you're able
to log in to the interface now you can
collect additional information here if
you want the CV there highlight on top
which is the XML one is not accessible
from the web but if you make a fake
mobile application or that's application
you can access it that gives you the
Wi-Fi password
I don't know how valuable Wi-Fi password
would be or not because if you're local
to the network it may be may be valuable
if you're not local to it you then the
password has to be reusable somewhere
else I don't know how true that is the
second one is 58 92 there's a second set
of JSON endpoints so in the one the
previous steps are highlighted again
JSONP can be done cross domain this is
the second one that I should like in
additional information you could get
information about the router about
things that are attached to it here's
some examples information about what the
one link looks like you could get the
next to a pretty interesting that as an
active scan around all this around the
access points there it takes a it takes
some time it actually puts Loden on the
router you could potentially do as the
router that way the next one gives you
information about the local network you
get origin information information about
the external IP the last one can open
web dev access to the router the web dev
access is routed through another server
so all of these things are interesting
but I don't know how much you can do
with them they're interesting the here's
example getting this term I P address
now why is this gonna be address
important
maybe they open the internal access on
the router maybe not most races routers
do not have that open but there's an
example of what you can collect again
very simplistic this is no libraries
nothing this is HTML 101 there's nothing
complicated here or how you actually get
information into the browser this is
where everything comes together so at
this point you have a user on the same
network into visiting a malicious page
not a phishing page just a malicious
page the page used WebRTC to find out a
local IP range we did a JSONP call to
figure out Asus router with the CSRF to
log in you could where we want because
every setting in the browser can be
changed through CSRF
the same way that the sierra on login
that's this state to the state of your
login to the router is there so for
example if user is logged in and you
don't know their credentials you could
do this also but it's easier to just try
to log in and you can do all of these
various things so what I would do is I
would open him on access I would live in
the remote access to a high port so
Sheldon doesn't find it and I would also
limit the remote access to the IP range
that I want so I can get in and nobody
else can get in if you want to do you
could change user name password I would
not recommend this is not something the
attacker probably would do is they
respond because user may figure out
something's wrong but then again how
often does somebody log into the router
so of all of the vulnerabilities of
those four this is the one that's the
most severe because this one actually
lets you change the settings on the
router but to exploit this successfully
it's not something you can do from
outside you have to actually be user has
to be on a local network and they have
to be able to hit a page you're giving
them I haven't tried weather outlook or
something that's web-based but not
browser-based can do this I don't think
you can because javascript is limited so
you gotta get them to visit a page now
this is the admission of UI for the Asus
router those are all the various options
this just a few of them but it's way way
more of them in there and basically this
is how you would actually tune on remote
access again it's very simple it's a web
form you have to be able to you have to
be logged in from the people in the
previous steps once you logged in
basically this is what you do this code
is incomplete in purpose but anybody who
digs into the UI can figure it out I
have not been able to consistently
reproduce it on my router 100% of the
time it only works sometimes I suspect
there's a timeout of some sort in there
other people have reproduces
successfully and left comments on the
blog and saying that other models don't
have the timeout but again this is a
very simple very simple attack CSRF form
that submit and and that's it you're in
there
here's another example in the UI also
let's say you do not want to do that but
you want to see what the person is doing
on the router on the network level there
is a remote logging server there I don't
know how detailed those I don't know
whether it goes into actual network
level but that's another example you do
a CSRF attack same way and you go and
change the settings and then the user
doesn't know anything
they're not gonna know what's gonna
happen so what what's the worst thing
you can do you can have any mode that
you can have a missionary access the
router now one thing also that's
interesting which is the last point yeah
you can mess with the router you can
mess with another experience you could
diminish of access you'd also be the
former the users not gonna know anything
at that point I mean that's also
something that can be done through CSRF
as well at that point it may become
somewhat warmer wool again if there's a
worm it's spreading it has to get to the
other users and with application level
attacks is kind of hard to do that but
yeah if you have a bishop access a
router you could update the firmware
there's at least two open source ones
that are out there it's trivial to
download and modify them so that's
basically you know just to go back to
the exploit chain is you get them to
visit the malicious page detect a pea
wrench to WebRTC figure out if step
three if they have an Asus router login
through CSRF number five you could
collect the data if you want to it might
not be helpful to anyone you could
choose not to number six you do remote
remote access or change the settings or
firmware whatever it is that you want to
do actual malicious activity and then
you basically done now one last thing
also now I mentioned that this is all
about application security however one
more thing after I found mine somebody
found a bunch of network level ones so
just what I will focused on was
application security however there are
other attacks in the firmware that are
also network based there is very little
information available about these two
CVEs
the only that's available is that Asus
has not fixed them
and it's unclear whether it could be
remotely exploitable or locally
exploitable but that's where you
basically get back into the net sack
territory now
what I learned from this is that
manufacturers of routers don't I don't
know much about security now we would
hope they know something about network
security but what I found is application
security often is even worse it's also
important to know what kind of router
you have now my the router that I've
used the Asus router when I was doing
this work which was last December they
haven't had any security patches I think
for two years at that point since they
released this patch which was back in
March there's no more patches since
since then so I would not necessarily
become you know when you're buying a
router make sure you know what you're
buying and make sure it's updated the
other option you could do is go with
open source firmware open source
firmware like open wrt Merlyn they some
they maintain their stuff better but
again the vulnerabilities that I'm
discussing here unfortunately are in
both because I have it necessarily seen
the open source ones fix them before the
manufacturer does admin credentials need
to be changed that's an important point
we think that the network boundary
cannot be breached easily in this case a
CSRF attack or JSONP attack is something
that a lot of people who operate on a
network land once early realize and are
able to even do applications on it
certainly realize the router is a box
but it's got a UI if it's got a UI and
then it's got an application its
identification by vulnerable CSRF JSONP
those kind of things can cross from one
side to another and bypass browser
security another thing that I do
recommend if you want to deal with your
browser or with your router which is
something a lot of the southern edge of
my own routers I do not administer them
when I'm logged in to somewhere else I
go into anonymous mode in somewhere else
and I like that when I'm done why
because these kind of attacks and I'm
describing can't be done without you
knowing it you will not know anything
you could be logged into your router and
you can be visiting some site and you
may not realize there is a piece of
advertising code that brings in a piece
of JavaScript and in that piece of
JavaScript I was talking to your honor
because these type of attacks CSRF
j7p in cross from side to side without
anybody knowing anything
last piece also is that when I was
originally trying to find information
about the ASA security team there's a
lot of interesting stuff out there and
none of it was from Asus a lot of and
part of the problem oasis is has
multiple country sites so some of the
attacks here especially on the mobile
side which I didn't dig into a lot but
if you have an asus app you better make
sure it's actually comes from asus and
sending for that stuff if this is if you
want to make sure that's an Isis website
you got to make sure it's coming from
Asus especially since one of these that
I've seen is some of the main name stuff
those domain names of Asus have
registered I'm not actually registered
publicly and someone can register them
publicly and grab them so there's a lot
of a lot of sort of things to keep in
mind when you're when you're Virata
everything I have here is on my blog on
the blog post all of these CVEs have
been reported as I said three out of
four have been fixed if you have any
questions feel free to reach out to the
questions thank you
[Applause]