the besides DC 2017 videos are brought
to you by threat quotient introducing
the industry's first threat intelligence
platform designed to enable threat
operations and management and data tribe
a new kind of startup studio Co building
the next generation of commercial cyber
security analytics and big data product
companies well we're here today to talk
about PCI and more specifically PCI for
pentesters my name is Joseph Perini I am
vice president of technical services for
PSC the PSC is a qsa company which means
we help organizations become compliant
with the data security standard now I've
run the pen test team for about nine
years or so but I actually started as a
qualified security adviser that means I
was an auditor and if I got to be honest
I suck at being an auditor because
frankly I get really bored sitting in a
room eight hours a day people telling
you that they're compliant and I my eyes
kind of glaze over and I just don't
trust it I like being a pen tester
because I don't have to take people's
word for whether or not they're
compliant I get to check now my team
does about 400 to 500 pen tests a year
now we don't do all of the pen tests for
our customers so over the last nine
years that means I've been able to see
quite a number of third-party pen tests
and some of them been pretty good some
of them have been really bad but mostly
it why is this
flipping back and forth there we go but
ultimately doing it this long I become
really passionate about pentesting and
PCI so much so that I co-sponsored the
special interest group on penetration
testing back in 2015 and I wrote great
big sections of the guidance that came
out so I hope I know what I'm talking
about at this point so let's talk about
some background here what is PCI all
right back in April 1993 CERN went ahead
and released the World Wide Web into the
public domain that's when the internet
was born now it's been said that two
things drive the internet porn and
e-commerce and there's a lot of both now
this ecommerce on the internet spawns a
whole new avenue of fraud and the card
brands are just getting hammered on a
regular basis so in the fall of 1999
Visa says enough is enough and they
create their first security program for
merchants and it was called the the
cardholder information security program
or the C ISP so great all the other card
brands go yes me too me too when they go
out and they create their unique
security programs for merchants visa
says all right everybody you've got to
be compliant in 2001 and that date comes
and goes and nobody's compliant but why
well think about it for a second you've
got if you're a merchant you've got five
different security programs that you're
trying to be compliant with and the card
brands you know they don't necessarily
get along together so you could be
compliant for discover but that doesn't
necessarily make you compliant say for
Visa or for master cards so it's a real
mess now if you're a hacker this is
awesome because we've got all these new
e-commerce sites out there and they're
all running on iis with asp and there's
sequel injection everywhere and you
can't swing a dead cat in any
direction without hitting a poorly
protected e-commerce site now cyber
source says back in 2000 that there will
be one point five billion dollars in
online revenue lost to fraud and that
number is gonna triple over the next
decade so in 2004 the five card brands
to get together and they say we're gonna
create this thing called the payment
card industry data security standard and
they release version one now in 2006 due
to feedback they create this thing
called the payment card industry
security data standard Council to help
the standard and to help guide merchants
become compliant so since then this
council has given us eight different
versions of the standard so what is the
council supposed to do well the council
is - supposed to oversee the standard
now they don't do it by themselves they
take input from participating
organizations which are really large
merchants and service providers and they
take input from the queue SAS and they
take input from the card brands now
they're also responsible for certifying
the qualified security advisors making
sure they know what they're doing when
they go in the field to help merchants
become compliant they also manage this
thing called an ASV program or in an
approved scanning vendor which you need
to have scan you quarterly in order to
be PCI compliant now counsel does a
whole bunch of other stuff too they do
an internal security Assessor program
they do a payment application qsa
program they do a PCI forensic
investigator for when your security
didn't work out the way you thought it
was going to they do a PCI professional
Program pin transaction security
point-to-point encryption they even have
a program for qualified integrators and
resellers the people who are responsible
for installing payment applications in
point of sales so they they cover quite
a bit now who has to be compliant
basically anybody that takes a credit
card regardless of size
has to be PCI compliant and you're gonna
fall into one of two buckets right
you're either gonna be a merchant or
you're gonna be a service provider now a
merchant is defined as anyone who takes
a payment card with one of the with the
logo of one of the five card brands
great so if I have a swipe I've got a
cafe if I'm amazon.com I'm a merchant
now the other group is a service
provider and they're defined as a
business entity who isn't a card brand
but they're directly involved in the
processing storage or transmission of
cardholder data so these are companies
that provide services that could impact
the security of the cardholder data
environment so a good example of that
would be say Iron Mountain now Iron
Mountain's got a bunch of tapes that
they're taking back and forth and they
contain card data so to some extent they
need to be PCI compliant if I'm a
managed services provider and I manage
the firewalls for a merchant I have some
responsibilities of being PCI compliant
because I could impact the security of
that merchant if I handle the
point-of-sale systems for a bunch of
restaurants again I'm a service provider
and I have to be PCI compliant now
compliant with what well in total there
are 416 individual requirements which
are you know broken into twelve or
basically six different control
objectives and they are build and
maintain a secure network protect
cardholder data maintain a vulnerability
management program implement strong
access control measures regularly test
and monitor networks that's interesting
and then maintain an information
security policy so which bits do we as
pen testers care about so there are four
requirements that get our attention
the first one is requirement 6.5 which
is to address common coding
vulnerabilities well this basically
tells us that we need to use OAuth 10
and the cwe 25 when we are assessing web
applications
and then 6.6 requires that you review
public-facing web applications and there
are three ways that you can do this you
can as a merchant you can either do a
static source code review or you could
use a vulnerability of web application
vulnerability assessment tool or you
could just skip your code altogether and
you can just put a web application
firewall in front of your web app and
that will help you meet that requirement
then requirement 11.2 is about
vulnerability scanning and this is for
both your internal and your external now
anybody can do your internal
vulnerability scanning but your external
has to be done by an approved scanning
vendor now 11.3 the requirement for
internal and external penetration
testing can be done by anyone who's
qualified so there isn't a certification
for them so now we've got this PCI
standard right we've got four hundred
and sixteen requirements now
everything's hunky-dory
it came out in 2006 and we're good right
no boom I mean the first one was TJX and
it was you know multi-million dollar
compromise and if ya look it's like
every year since the PCI standard came
out there's been some major hack what
the hell this was supposed to fix this
why are we still having this issue
well merchants will tell you it's
because the standards are ineffective
it's too hard to implement and it cost
too much money and then security
professionals will argue that it doesn't
go far enough and it's all about
checking the box ok great so who's at
fault well I've given this some thought
I've been doing this since PCI came out
and I think I've got the answer if you
think PCI is crap it's because you're
doing it wrong I believe that were to
blame so I believe the claim by some
that PCI is nothing more than a bunch of
kids with clipboards running around
merchants checking off
check boxes is probably pretty accurate
for a lot of Q essays and pen testers
aren't blameless either I've read some
tragically bad pen test reports I mean
the report was pretty oh it was gorgeous
it had great graphics it had you know
professional fonts it had pie charts
galore the whole thing screamed
professional but when you read it it was
nothing more than an esse skin in a
dress so a PCI isn't easy
and if merchants you know could figure
this out on their own they wouldn't need
us they wouldn't need Assessors I think
some of the problem is that the security
firms in pen testers individual in
particular haven't really looked at the
standard I mean looked at it dug into it
and pulled some guidance out of it the
other problem is being an Assessor of
any type is a really awkward position to
be in so if you do your job too well
your client hates your guts you'll hear
things like oh he asked too many
questions he digs too deep he's too hard
on us great if you do a crappy job
though your client gets breached and
then everybody wants to know who the
Assessor was because they did a crappy
job pen testing is kind of the same
raise your hands if you've ever done a
great job on a pen test and somebody got
fired yeah awkward so you know at the
same time if you don't do a good job
there are five other companies just
waiting in the wings for you to screw up
and take your customer away from you
so I honestly think that there to some
degree there many companies are just
afraid of rocking the boat for fear of
losing a client and I think that needs
to stop we need to as pen testers we've
got to understand the standard and then
developing an accurate and effective
approach to performing our pen tests we
also need to be willing to stand our
ground and educate the customer when
maybe we don't all agree on what the
outcome of the pen test means
so let's talk about some of the common
challenges for both clients and for pen
testers think the biggest one for
clients is that this wasn't their idea I
mean think about it nobody wakes up in
the morning and goes damn we should be
PCI compliant let's go out and get a PCI
pen test no they don't they have to they
are required to do this stuff and I
honestly think that affects their
willingness to cooperate and engage the
other thing is that PCI can get really
expensive so you've got to get if you're
a merchant or a service provider you've
got to go out and get an Assessor then
you've got to get your ASV scans and
then you've got to get your pen tests
internal and external web application
and then if you've got a payment
application you might have to have that
looked at
to then they're gonna find things and
those things are going to cost money
you're going to have to upgrade software
you might have to buy Hardware you're
gonna have to implement certain security
controls it's going to be inconvenient
and it's gonna get expensive really
quick the other problem is that pen
testing has a real tough time
demonstrating value and when a customer
has a lot of demands for their budget
I think pen testing is a great place for
them to cut corners now the other thing
is that the standard doesn't always
scale it doesn't always work for smaller
customers PCI there can be technical and
financial barriers for smaller companies
to go ahead and really embrace PCI in
some cases it takes a full-time person
and if you all you've got is a system
admin who's already wearing multiple
hats then you are probably not going to
do a really good job of PCI now what are
some of the the challenges for pen
testers well there aren't very clear
instructions on how we're supposed to do
this there are no cut-and-dry rules
about how a pen test is supposed to be
done so that's why we're here today I'm
gonna call out where we can get that
information and then there's no PCI
certification for pen testers now for
the quarterly external scans you have to
get an ASV an approved scanning vendor
and these companies go through an annual
baseline testing which means that the
council can be assured of a relative
level of consistency well there's no
such consistency with pen testers so pen
test companies really don't know what
they're getting or whether or not the
pen test company they hired is even
qualified to do the job so and then
lastly I think for us and I've said it
before as I think we're afraid to push
too hard a PCI really is supposed to
have teeth if a merchant or a service
provider is not compliant they're
acquirer will start to levy fines and
these fines can quickly add up and in
some cases you can put a smaller company
out of business well I don't think we
want to be the bad guys and like I said
if we hold them accountable or were too
good there's that fear that they're just
gonna go find another company that's
just easier and softer and we'll just go
ahead and let them pass but again I
think if we educate ourselves and we
educate our customers and we can start
looking for ways to bring value beyond
just checking the box on a list of
requirements we could make PCI real
security so how are we supposed to pen
test well there are four primary
documents that we're going to get some
information out of the PCI data security
standard testing procedures has a
testing procedures 139 page framework
for assessing merchants and inside of it
it includes testing procedures and
additional guidance around the specific
requirements so we're going to want to
look at that and then the 2017
penetration testing guidance I got to
say I'm quite proud of this one because
I spent you know over a year working
with other security companies and a
merchants and service providers and
participating organizations and we took
input from the card brands and you know
we put together a document that was
published in 2015 if you ever get a
chance to
a pci-sig I say do it just jump into it
it's gonna take some time but you'll be
amazed it's quite enlightening what it
takes to get you know everybody with
who's got a different agenda and
different ideas - all finally come
together and agree on something it's a
lot of work and it's pretty amazing
now the ASV program guide covers pretty
much the mechanics of being in a ASV but
we're going to glean a few ideas out of
that as well and then lastly there's
this guidance for PCI DSS scoping and
segmentation and this introduces the
concept of a connected system so a
connected system is anything that talks
into the cardholder data environment
that could impact the security if
compromised
that's a connected system so we're gonna
look at those documents now let's dig
into these a little bit and see what
information we can glean from them so
from the testing procedures and guidance
this is a good piece of information this
is the key takeaway we are required to
simulate a real-world attack situation
and identify how far we can penetrate
into the environment that's awesome
because that kind of changes things and
kind of sets the whole tone for how the
pen test should be performed this does
not mean we get to run a vulnerability
scan slap our logo on it and call the
color to pentest anymore this could be
real fun but this document also tells us
that we need to target the CDE and the
connected systems cool we've now we know
exactly what we're going for
it gives us permission to exploit
identified vulnerabilities I don't know
if you've ever had a pen test where the
customer said no you can't do
exploitation a post exploitation it's
like well then what am I doing here
this isn't a pen test this gives us
permission to do that
it also says though we need to use a
defined accepted third-party methodology
so you can't use Bob's House of pen
testing as a way of doing it you've got
to use something that's known the NIST
800 115 or the open-source security
testing methodology use something like
that
your approach on that and then it says
that we have to do this at least
annually and after any significant
change there's always a question of
what's a significant change and the
answer is always well it depends a
significant change is traditionally
anything that could impact the security
of the cardholder data environment so
for example now let's say the customer
changes a firewall rule is that a
significant change probably not
you could just you know run nmap again
and make sure that all the firewall
rules look or a nipper or something to
just make sure the the firewall rules
look okay or let's say you had
cross-site scripting in a web
application and you fixed that alright
well we'll just check for that we don't
have to test the whole lap again but
maybe you add a whole new network or you
re architect your application and add
new functionality those would be
significant changes that should trigger
another pen test and that will require
for you to come out and again work with
your customer so I've been talking about
this thing cardholder data environment
and CDE so we should probably define
this and the council defines this as the
people processes and technology that
store process or transmit cardholder
data which is the the pan the primary
account numbers and or sensitive
authentication data which in part is the
three numbers on the back of your credit
card so it includes this thing called
people so that kind of means that we're
not just attacking a static set of IPS
or applications this changes things now
we have to go after the people who are
part of the CDE and these are
traditionally defined as the privileged
users who have access to or a
responsible for managing the cardholder
data environment or they use in scope
applications we'll think about it for a
second we get to hack them so now that
means maybe we can look at other stuff
that they use in their day-to-day job
their internal corporate domain now
we're beginning to take a look at a
bigger picture now if you just said okay
all I'm going to do is hack the CDE
you just point your tools at it you look
at the perimeter you'd walk away
fine but now if we look at what are our
CDE requirements are we've got these
people that we can start to go after
let's dig into the pentesting guidance
so you would think that pen test
companies would know the difference
between a pen test and vulnerability
scan but I have seen some reports that
demonstrate quite the opposite
now we originally did this for merchants
because a lot of merchants really don't
know the difference but it was good for
some pen test companies too we also
talked about in this document of black
box versus grey box testing now I am
quite the advocate of grey box testing I
think it's a better value proposition
for customers than going in blind a lot
of what we're going to do in a black box
test is just look for you know your
architecture your IPS we got to figure
all that stuff out and we will get there
but we will spend a couple of extra
weeks doing it and we're gonna have to
go through all your emails and we're
gonna have to find your Visio diagrams
tell you what we could save a lot of
time and money if you just give it to us
upfront and that's again better value
for the customer this document also
talks about what to look for in a
penetration tester if you're a merchant
trying to hire them or if you're a qsa
looking at somebody's report trying to
figure out whether or not they knew what
they were doing so we talked about some
of the key certifications things like
the OS CP we did not say that having a
cissp makes you a pen tester so we're
trying to offer some real guidance on it
then we also added this consideration
for social engineering and I wrote this
myself because I'm I was quite insistent
that we bring up social engineering one
of the things I don't understand is that
in the standard and in PCI we don't
really talk about it but if you look at
all the major breaches there has always
been some element of social engineering
even if all it was was a phishing attack
and why we don't test for it or educate
or you know have that conversation about
it blows my mind but this year I went
ahead and proposed another sig
specifically just on social engineering
now it's not a sexy topic and that it's
got a snowball's chance in hell of
actually getting selected but I'm hoping
it does because then if it does we can
start to put together some sort of
guidance about how to do this
effectively without demoralizing your
users with and getting some real benefit
from it and then we also put together
some report content guidelines because a
lot of the reports that that we were all
seeing or just all over the map you
couldn't really tell what the report was
about and in some case you couldn't even
tell at the end of it whether or not the
customer was compliant so the ASV
program the third document that we're
gonna pull information out like I said
before it's mostly about the mechanics
of being in ASV but there's a couple of
things that we can pull out of here that
are important to us number one it tells
the ASVs that they must use either NVD
or CVS s for setting their severity
levels cool because please do me a favor
stop making up your own severity levels
I know what you're trying to do I've
seen the reports you're trying to stand
out you're trying to do something that's
unique and you know put your stamp on it
but really all you're doing is confusing
people you're rarely more effective than
the existing third-party standards and
what happens is is you end up really
messing up the remediation process
because then the customer doesn't know
what to prioritize they've got one
document that says one thing and then
they've got another document that says
something else and they never quite
match because you were coming up and
calling it by different things let's
stop we can use this to put together
some sort of common severity language
great then we're all on the same page
again let's make it easier on the
customers and then the ASV program
called out these things called automatic
failures it's it's kind of cool so you
automatically fail no argument we're not
going to discuss it you fix it if we
find out of date or obsolete operating
systems in the CDE you run in Windows
2003 not unless you've got an extended
Microsoft contract you got 2000 doesn't
matter you're fixing it other things
were if I find a database open from the
internet guess what you automatically
fail for God's sake go fix that now
if you're using default credentials
Tomcat Tomcat on anything it's an
automatic fail and then then we talked
about other things like web applications
securities cross-site scripting sequel
injection directory traversals these
were all automatic fails cool we didn't
have to have any discussion negotiation
or argument and then some other things
that are kind of interesting were
information disclosures that they
consider an automatic fail if you reveal
the internal IP address scheme through
you know you're a web application call
or something like that you expose it to
the Internet that's an automatic fail
you've got to go fix it for both error
messages you got to fix them revealing
source code you got to fix it so the ASB
program kind of gave us some things that
we could arm ourselves when we're doing
a test with so that when we communicate
to the customer
it's very cut and dry and very clear
what they have to do we want that we
want to make sure that the customers
know what they have to do so that
they're not confused
all right the guidance for PCI DSS
scoping and segmentation is another
document that we can kind of pull some
info over it I hear a lot of times why
are you looking at that that's not in
the scope for PCI r-ark USA didn't want
to have anything to do with that like
well you know what maybe maybe not just
because it's not in scope doesn't mean
we shouldn't maybe look at it so this
guidance kind of gave me a little
justification for that behavior it also
talked about the connected systems that
need to be in scope the other thing it
talks about too it's a good reminder is
connections from third parties now let's
say you're a service provider you
provide a banking application and you've
got a whole bunch of credit unions
across the United States that connect
into you well have you ever done a pen
test from one of your customers you know
like well no they're our customers we
would never do a pen test from there
well why not you don't know what that
risk is you don't know what that
connectivity looks like you don't know
if somebody's screwed it up for example
until you actually test it and this
document says hey you know what you need
to consider it and the other thing it
tells us is that we need to do
segmentation testing so a cuss
demur who has using segmentation to keep
certain parts of their network separate
from the CDE well we got a we got to
test those segmentation then I'll talk
more about that later in the
presentation
so there's always an argument around
scoping the queue SAS argue it you go to
the PCI council meetings you hear it
between the council members and queue
SAS merchants want to argue it and I've
got the answer it's pretty simple it's
not out of scope if it can be used
against you let's face it I mean hackers
do not have scoping rules why do we let
the merchants put limits on it we've
seen organizations get nailed out of
left field right we've target we don't
know where it's coming from now if we
were just focusing on the systems that
the qsa has to look at we're gonna miss
a whole bunch so if we increase our
scope so that it's basically everything
then we have a greater chance of
protecting our customer now it does mean
that you're gonna have to stop and
educate your customer explain the risks
and that's okay it's an extra step in
our process but we're experts and
clients do want us to guide them so
let's do that
now does this mean we get to go all
medieval all over their networks no we
do have to act responsibly and
reasonably and we do that using a set of
guidelines called the rules of
engagement we're all familiar with that
right have you ever had a pen test with
a really whacked out set of rules of
engagement where I had a bank they told
us if you find a password you can't
reuse it because somebody might get
offended okay well you couldn't do
anything exploitive god forbid you look
in somebody's email by the time we were
done and we were like okay you know you
could have done all of this yourself but
we're happy to do this I mean we like
your money but it's not really valuable
for you so the best part of PCI is that
it sets the rules of engagement for us
what we do is we go back to that
original primary objective
the intent of the penetration test is to
simulate a real-world attack with the
goal of identifying how far an attacker
can it penetrate into the environment
now we get to be exploitive we get to
chain attacks together
there isn't anything here that says well
you can't do that no you can't do that
it basically says we can do everything
we get to do a damn good pen test for a
change this is awesome
now does this mean we get to do crazy
stuff no how do we meet this intent and
do it safely there are some common
things that we need to discuss first off
don't bother with any denial of service
attacks think about it if you knock over
a server with a whole bunch of card data
in it well that's probably going to be
about as secure as its ever gonna be
because if you can't get to the card
data right it's good so there's that the
other thing is you need to have a
discussion up front with your customer
about how you're gonna handle risky and
fragile infrastructure so if you've got
a customer let's say financial
institutions a lot of these will have
mainframes right if you scan a mainframe
it locks up and then you've got this
really uncomfortable conversation with
the stakeholders and your customer and
you're probably not going to be invited
back so get a hold of them first talk to
them about this what do you have in the
environment that could be affected ask
them the question if you have you ever
done a scan or a pen test before and
something went south and then talk about
that and decide how are we going to
handle this we can't just not test it
but we can come up with better ways
maybe rather than doing automated tools
we're gonna have to do it with some more
manual stuff maybe if it's a web
application what we could do is we could
test it in staging so testing and
staging versus production can you do
that sure why not but you need to have
some criteria that you set with your
customer first off the code base has to
be the same can't be a version before it
can't be a version after it's got to be
dead-on and also make sure that whatever
environment
they give you a stable a lot of time
that staging environment is like the old
rickety box that's underneath somebody's
desk make sure that it they're not
changing it that it's not a dynamic
environment that it's stable and the
code is static and if you can do that
then great you can go ahead and test in
staging if you can't maybe you should
talk about when to test maybe during
testing during off-peak hours is the way
to do this I prefer testing during the
day
I prefer testing with realistic traffic
you know real-world attacks happen at
all hours they don't happen you know at
two o'clock in the morning necessarily
so I like it during the day because a
couple of reasons if I have a question I
can pick up the phone and somebody's
going to answer if there's a problem
there are resources that can immediately
respond to it so this is good now I do
have some customers that'll say well
you've got to test it at night that's
fine we'll test it at night but you've
got a promise that you're gonna pick up
the phone and you're gonna answer me the
call when I call because I've got a
question or when you didn't give me
something or something's not responding
right so you kind of have to negotiate
this with your customer to make sure
that you get everybody on board and be
careful about customers that do things
like say well you can test but you can
only test in a two hour maintenance
window knock yourselves out guys if you
want me to do this in a two hour
maintenance window that I'm gonna have
to double the amount of time that I'm
gonna spend on this because this stop
and start thing really screws with the
efficiency and it's also increases the
likelihood that something you know bad
could happen inside a system so usually
I push back and shoot for at least six
hour windows for testing depends upon
the customer but most the time if you
take the time to explain what the risks
are you can get some agreement now when
do you stop well that's the other cool
thing about PCI is that it actually sets
the success criteria pretty clear for us
we knew what our targets were we had to
go after the CDE and we have to go after
connected systems well cool having an
established success criteria prevents us
from going too far
and it also makes it easier for
everybody to know when we're doing a
good job so maybe just compromising the
perimeter of the CDE is success criteria
and we're done
great or maybe they've got this set up
where they use a jump box ssh into an
RSA key whatever to get into the CDE and
if you can compromise that intermediary
box you're good great that's the success
criteria I've had some customers that
have said hey look if you compromised
our corporate domain we're good that's
that's we're done we know it's just a
matter of time at that point I love
those customers those guys are engaged
they know what their risks are or even
something like access to source code
it's gonna be different for every
customer you just want to make sure that
you sit down and document it with them
so that you don't go too far and if you
do get into the CDE stop don't get cocky
don't try and prove the point go well
we're gonna get credit card data out
well no you're not cuz things go south
really quick and the next thing you know
havoc alarms go off
got to remember the CDE is a
money-making vehicle for the customer
you do not want to interfere with that
because you do want to be invited back
okay I'm not tell you how to do pen
testing you know how to do pen testing
but let's talk about some unique
characteristics of PCI pen testing so
for the external pen tests they're
actually probably some of the easier
ones because they they're like anything
else HIPPA a regular pen test and every
web applicator every application pen
test is the same they follow the typical
pen test approach of discovery and
numeration vulnerability scanning
exploitation post exploitation there's
there's no magic and pci for that one
but be real clear that most companies
have no idea what they have so asset
management especially for some reason in
PCI is going to be a real mess so what
you can do is take whatever I piece or
think targets they give you and compare
that with the ASV scans because they
should be the same and if they're not
bring it up some one of them is wrong
and if it's wrong you want to make sure
that you're making your customer or
aware and that you come to some sort
the conclusion the other thing is try to
expand the scope as much as possible
take what they've given you do some
OSINT on it and then take that back to
the customer go hey we found all this
other stuff and asked the question this
way don't ask them if it's in scope
because they'll go no ask them if any of
this stuff could impact the security of
the cardholder data environment because
that's key
it's not about scope it's about
impacting the CDE or getting in so try
and poke at that a little bit if you can
do that with the externals then you're
doing okay the internals are a little
bit more complicated so the internals
are definitely harder to scope and
they're definitely harder to price
because usually a lot of your scoping
and pricing is just based on static IPS
number of Web Apps and that's not how
the internal pen tests are going to work
because everything's in scope it's not
out of scope if it can be used against
you you need to have a pretty damn good
understanding of that customers
environment now ask them a question not
just what do you sell but ask them how
do you sell it so a lot of customers are
going to have you know multiple channels
so they might have e-commerce that might
have brick and mortar they might have a
call center all of these places are
gonna be where card data is going to be
coming in so get an understanding of
that up front before you scope it
because you don't want to under scope
you don't want to put too little
resource and too little time on this and
then when you're there remember you're
attacking the privileged users yes
you're gonna have some opportunity to go
right at the cardholder data environment
and there might be some instances where
it's wide open and you're in those are
boring those are 20 minute pen tests but
as your customer matures it's going to
get harder now you're gonna have to go
after those privileged users and look at
non-traditional networks don't just
thank Corp and CDE go after the voice go
after climate control go after the guest
networks guest networks rapidly become
de facto Corp networks because
everybody's too lazy to get on the the
Corp Network printer networks I mean
these things it's weird they don't get
the same attention
I know in a pen test before I've gone
ahead plugged into avoidant Network and
add access into this other system and
then I could pivot through that right
into the CDE so peek at it take a look
at it don't trust the scope and I said
that before in the externals and this is
kind of a theme customers don't know
what they have they'll give you this
list of IP addresses let's say they've
got you know for class C's and a 10 dot
network well do they have 4 class C's do
they have 20 class C's you know it
doesn't hurt to run math scan real quick
across a slash 8 and say hey what are
all these other networks that that came
up you know pull all the machines out of
the domain and convert those to IP
addresses look at the the networks that
they're on poke at this thing a little
bit see if you can get more information
out of the customer and finally automate
as much as you can because you are
fighting time that is the downside and
the limitation dependent of PCI
pentesting it's all about efficiency and
a trade-off of time so if you can
automate and be more efficient you're
gonna do a better job for your customer
all right reporting
no one likes doing the reports everybody
loves doing the pen test the pen tests
are cool but doing the reports suck and
it shows in a lot of pen test reports
that I read it really shows that
nobody's into them but these are some of
the things that you should have in the
pen test report for PCI all right
the executive summary we all know that a
statement of scope this is important you
need to document this what was in scope
what did you test where did you test
from what was included and then you need
to put in your statement of the
methodology that's kind of required so
that the qsa looks at it and goes ok
they didn't they weren't winging this
they didn't make this up and then your
statement of limitations now if you had
some limitations well we couldn't test
during these time frames or you know
this system we we had to do manually
great put it in the document that way
the customer knows that there might have
been some limitations and they didn't
get full coverage that's ok but document
it and then testing narrative now this
is more me than PCI
the way I want my pen testers to write
the reports is I want them to do a
chronological narrative with the exact
tools and techniques and the syntax for
what they did I've had customers come to
me and go you know we really don't want
to fix any of this because we think
you're magic and we don't think normal
people could do this and we don't think
it's really can't happen there isn't
really a risk okay
you know I'm management I'm not that
good if I can get in it's a problem
so in our reports if we can put a
testing narrative in there that is real
clear and that so that even a junior
windows administrator could do what we
do they can replicate our our results
okay then we have made this real this is
now something that isn't imaginary or
theoretical this is a real attack that's
good we've brought value we've
demonstrated that this has some tangible
value to the organization and then
finally some segmentation results need
to be in your pen test reports and then
your findings need to be clearly
documented let's talk about findings so
in your findings what I'll and the first
one is again me less more me less PCI
but you're gonna run into situations
where you're doing a PCI pen test and
the internal corporate network is Swiss
cheese they really have paid no
attention to it but they did a good job
of keeping you out of the CDE so now
what do you do how do you how do you
write this up well I like to write it up
just as normal just as if it were the
same severity levels that for anything
else but instead now we just indicate
whether or not we could use it to get
into the CDE and if we couldn't they
don't have to fix it but we brought it
to their attention and we brought it to
their attention with the real severity
level why is this important well now
they can use our report to handle or to
affect other regulatory regimes I mean
if you could have gotten into HR and
Finance that's important they should
know about that sort of thing and now
you've created a report that they used
for
ci but now has value in other areas so
that makes the penetration test report
more valuable you need to put in the
risk and severity and again not a risk
in severity you make up on your own use
something that's established I know that
CVS s does not work for every finding
but try and and do it as closely as
possible to some third-party methodology
put in the targets affected references
if you can find blog postings about the
vulnerability great do that put in your
description another thing it's not
required but it's a good idea is put in
this the steps the customer can take to
test remediation this is going to help
them you're gonna find remediation is is
always a challenge and if you can show
them how to test that they fixed it this
will make retesting a lot easier okay a
word about segmentation testing I
promised I was going to discuss it
segmentation testing is required by
requirement 11.3 4 which says you must
test all out of scope networks for all
segmentation methods to make sure that
they are effective cool well that can
also be a lot of work well how are you
supposed to do it well the penetration
testing guidance says that you can use
the first two phases of a penetration
test which is discovery and enumeration
which is nmap right so you could run
masks an or nmap from an out of scope
network towards the CDE and that would
satisfy segmentation testing the problem
you may run into is that you've got
customers with hundreds of out of scope
networks the nice thing was is that this
requirement came out at the exact time
we were doing the SIG's so we were able
to draw to everybody's attention that
this is nuts
you're gonna have people spending days
doing segmentation testing costing
hundreds of thousands of dollars it's
not worth it so we came out and in the
guidance we do have sampling is okay
what that sample size is I can't tell
you needs to be reasonable it could be
ten percent could be twenty five percent
you'll you'll know your customer better
it depends upon the the number
of networks if it's you know 100
networks maybe you do segmentation
testing from 10 or 15 if it's 10
networks maybe you do all of them you're
just gonna have to kind of take a look
at that on a case-by-case basis now
something that's changing is service
providers have a greater responsibility
they have more cards and therefore they
are required now to do segmentation
testing every or twice a year now they
may not necessarily ask you to do it and
that's okay
teach your customer how to do it on
their own because the requirement
doesn't say that it has to be done by a
pen test company or an ASP or anything
it just needs to be done so you're not
going to run back out there just to run
a scan or nmap and you're not gonna send
out an appliance because you can't move
that from network to network to network
teach them how to do it themselves teach
them how to document it again you're
bringing value to your customer and
that's gonna get you invited back it's
gonna let you do a better pen test okay
issues on remediation follow me along
with this one so let's say we hack a
client like this I've got they've got
wpa2 I grab the handshake I pull it down
I crack it and I jump on their network
then I do L LM n R and n BN s with
responder and I grab some more hashes
and you know what summer 2017 I've got a
I've got a credential fantastic so now I
Kerberos their domain and grab their
service provider named hashes and I
throw those up in the GPU cracker and
give it you know for six hours and hey
I've got a domain admin cred cool so now
I take that and I attack those
privileged users and with that
I get on their box and I wait for them
to connect to the CDE and then I pivot
through and I've got my success criteria
I present this to the customer and they
come back to me and they say you know
what we're just gonna fix that first
thing we're just gonna fix the wpa2
we're not because the way we figure it
is if you couldn't get that you wouldn't
have been able to get all this other
stuff all right well this is what I tell
my customers pen testing is really about
doing two things
it's about finding initial vectors
about finding escalation paths now let's
go back to the the biggest limitation we
have with PCI which is time frankly I
may only be able to get one initial
vector during the time that I'm there
and then I got to find the the
escalation paths so yeah there's a
chance I could have missed one or
tomorrow there could be a new
vulnerability which opens up another
initial vector which means that if you
only fix that one there's a chance
somebody's going to come around find the
other and all those escalation paths are
still going to be there and you have
accomplished really nothing in terms of
securing your environment so we tell
them you've got to remediate everything
in the attack chain you can't just do
that first one again we're pushing back
a little bit on the customer but if you
explain the risk you increase your value
so the other thing I get is you know
what we've decided as an organization
that we're going to accept the risk on
that vulnerability no you're not there
is no risk assessment or at risk
acceptance in PCI the only people that
get to accept the risk are the card
brands because it's not your risk to
accept its cardholder data and only the
card brands get to decide now I've got a
pretty good idea that they're not gonna
let you get away with that so yeah no
nice try the other thing is planned for
the client to maybe not always come up
with the best solution for remediation
let's say you've you got in and they're
decided that they're gonna spend a
million dollars implementing some sort
of I don't nak solution to keep people
from getting in and if you spent maybe
if you've been on the phone with them
for 15 minutes you could have pointed
out that hey nak is not everything it's
supposed to be and we can bypass that
with this and you know save them some
money so it's important don't just
deliver the report and walk away you can
do that with a lot of other pen tests
because you know they don't have to fix
anything with PCI stick around advise
them tell them hey before you spend any
time or money or effort in remediation
let's sit down and talk about it let's
do a tabletop discussion
because you know I'll bring a couple of
my smart guys and they can probably you
know tell us right up front whether or
not your solution has a chance of being
effective or if we've seen it before and
we've already bypassed it we're gonna
save you some time and some energy so
retesting is important with PCI in fact
it's one of the the few regulatory
regimes that requires that you come back
and make sure that notable exploited
vulnerabilities have been corrected so
there are two ways that you can do this
you can either do direct observation you
do the testing yourself you the customer
has cross-site scripting and they fix it
and then you go in and you retest it
well that's that's direct observation
you've you've done it the other way you
can do this is through review of
documents where the customer sends you
screenshots or you know output from
something let's say they had LL M&R in
the environment and you made them fix it
well send me evidence that you applied
the GPU across all the systems and send
me a pcap file
well I'll review that and that's
sufficient so sometimes I don't need to
go back out on site to do the test I can
just rely on the customer coming in and
doing it but what's important is that
there is no sampling of evidence in PCI
so if you've got 60 boxes with eternal
blue then you need to have evidence
showing that all 60 boxes have been
fixed you can't go and with 10 you've
got to have everything in order to make
sure that they are effective this
regulatory regime could come back on the
customer and you need to show that
they've done everything that they could
all right we were at 51 minutes so in
summary it's this you know what the
standard will drive your pentesting
engagement if you look at it and pull
out those pieces it actually gives you
the information it gives you permission
to do a really really good Bend test and
exploitation is required this is
fantastic so take it
Chane different vulnerabilities together
go further and deeper into the network
then you might be doing otherwise
remember it's not us against them we're
there to bring value we're there to make
sure that they're secure we have this
then it stops being a checkbox and we
get a better job we also develop a
relationship with the customer where we
become a trusted partner and again don't
be afraid to be the expert and being
afraid or being the expert sometimes
means you have to say no you have to
push back you have to say this is how it
is I'm the expert and then be able to
tell them why pointing back to the PCI
documentation and because if you do this
correctly I honestly believe that this
could be one of the meant best pen tests
that your client has ever had all right
guys thank you it's nine o'clock you
came in I much appreciate it if you have
any questions you can get some answers
on the PCI security standards council
this is where you can find these four
documents you can download them you can
find me at japery nyet pay us w.com or I
am je Perini on the twitters thank you
oh yeah you got a question come talk to
me oh sure why not
[Music]
okay no the whole is devices support
ipv6 by default it's a table so it's a
PC I've still valid validated it's just
another vulnerability man it's not
there's nothing special about ipv6 if
it's not being used and properly set up
then what have we got
we've got man in the middle attacks
against ipv6 that we can use it's if
it's not appropriately configured then
it shouldn't be in the environment so
you would put that down as a finding
well the testers taking some risk but
you gotta you know you gotta ask did he
miss it because he didn't look for it
did he miss it because he didn't have
time there are things that you miss in a
pen test that is the reality of pen
testing but it should be in your
methodology to test it to look for it
yeah it's not again it's it's it's like
saying you know is it patched or you
know does a vulnerability exist in a
system it should be something you're
checking there's a lot of stuff in in
you know ipv6 that heck we don't even
have to it at this point do because
there's all this other sort of stuff but
the fact that it exists there and it's
not configured properly is a
vulnerability that should be listed in a
report yeah does that satisfy your
question yeah me too
but it's up to us so you know again if
we see issues like that we need to
document it and educate the customer on
it
again your your you're approaching ipv6
as though it's something special it's
just another vulnerability so they don't
have to call it out
they don't call out eternal blue they
don't call out art poisoning it's just
another vulnerability if if the pen
testers aren't looking for it well
that's not the PCI counsels fault or
responsibility make sense yep any other
questions
doing all right again thanks guys
[Applause]