the besides DC 2017 videos are brought
to you by threat quotient introducing
the industry's first threat intelligence
platform designed to enable threat
operations and management and data tribe
a new kind of startup studio Co building
the next generation of commercial cyber
security analytics and big data product
companies so good afternoon my name is
Daniel Bohannon and today we'll be
talking about Revo coffee station I'm
kind of looking at some of the depths of
powershell obfuscation and how we can
use science to detect it a quick blurb
about me again my name is Daniel I work
for Mandy and I'm here in DC so it's
nice to be at a local conference here
the commute was awesome mmm I've been
with me in the it for about two and a
half years started out doing IR
consulting for almost two years and have
recently switched to an applied security
research position so I really focus
heavily on office Gatien evasion and
really applying detection at scale to
all of our clients and customers at fire
I'm India and there's my Twitter handle
there I want to give a huge huge out to
Li Holmes he's not here today but we
both did this research together and Lee
is just an awesome awesome guy he's the
lead security architect for Azure over
at Microsoft and he was actually one of
the original PowerShell developers so
it's pretty cool to be talking about
PowerShell and writing PowerShell tools
with a guy who literally wrote the
language it also is very humbling to us
how little I know about PowerShell but
fortunately he's a really humble guy so
he he let me know gently the things I
didn't know and I'm a better person for
it so we're gonna talk about today it's
kind of looking at a treatise on blue
team Follies as a blue team er I've made
all these mistakes and I hope to share
them with you in such a way that you can
take it and learn from it and then some
of the cool new stuff that Lee and I
spent several months on this year to try
to tackle this problem of detecting
office gated PowerShell so like at a
very high level when it comes to
actually investigating attacks or
PowerShell is used which PowerShell is
used in almost every single
investigation I've ever been a part of
because it's native on Windows 7 and
later attackers love it copy and paste
it's easy there's tons of PowerShell
from offensive PowerShell frameworks out
there and so attackers are using it a
lot also to be noted there's a ton
of Blue Team PowerShell frameworks out
there that defenders are starting to
pick up on so a lot of really good
things on both sides of the fence
but when it comes to actually
investigating attacks where PowerShell
is leveraged at the very least you want
at least command-line argument
information so you can get that from
your security log forty six eighty eight
or system on Eid one the the really
juicy stuff you want those at the bottom
which is power shells specific logging
particularly PowerShell five and this is
a blog post for a Microsoft and one at
the bottom for one of my colleagues at
fire I basically looking at kind of
where the benefits you actually get with
PowerShell five and how does it actually
stack up against this kind of
obfuscation that we'll be talking about
so how am I an attacker break our
assumptions when it comes to detecting
PowerShell well let's say that we're
going this route of looking at
PowerShell Dec see when it runs I'm
looking at its arguments and looking for
malicious things now obviously echoing
out the word success is not malicious
but just kind of showing in a really
small example how you can get code to
execute and maybe undermine some of our
assumptions about it appearing in
argument logs so in this case typically
will see command or something else
launching PowerShell and you have your
command that follows you see it runs
perfectly fine here however you don't
have to actually specify the PowerShell
command in its arguments if you just
look at Power Cells help you can
actually push stuff in a standard input
so you can do something like this and
have command echo your command your
PowerShell right host and then pipe it
into PowerShell - or PowerShell ie X
input and PowerShell runs it just fine
now why might this matter well you can
see the top power sells arguments only
contain that - or that ie X input but
the actual command itself if we're
looking for right host success for
ground green then that's actually in the
parent process so we've just shifted
arguments into the parent process so as
a defender if all your rules are based
on Power Cells arguments then this might
get by you so maybe we start to look for
any processes that have pipe followed by
PowerShell well the problem there is
that depending on whatever process
you're launching it from you can
obfuscate in that process as language
and kind of started stacking different
languages of obfuscation so the example
at the bottom I'm basically chopping up
power and shell and the two command
variables which are a process level
environment variables and then echoing
it into p1 and p2 such that you can see
the parent process has
pipe p1p2 and not pipe powershell so
that rule wouldn't really work if we're
looking for piping than powershell and
we actually see attackers is doing this
in the wild this is from mid-february
this year this is from financial threat
actor known as fin eight where they're
basically at the very bottom you can see
they had this PowerShell command they
were putting in one environment variable
called Microsoft Update Catalog the
second environment variable shell - and
then they were echoing var1 and devar -
which looks really really familiar to
what we were just talking about and they
were launching all this from a windward
are from from a word macro so you
actually didn't see a lot of this on the
command lines which was really really
interesting another way that we can
basically kind of move pieces of
information around and keep it off the
command lines is through just
straight-up process level environment
variables cope doors are really popular
piece of malware that does this
typically launched from office gated
MSHDA and run keys and stuff like that
but basically you'll see PowerShell
invoking with IE X the environment
variables some you know random name var
environment variable now typically we'll
see dollar sign EMV colon to reference
environment variables but there's tons
of ways that the bottom is just some of
the some of the few ways that are really
uncommon but that you can actually
extract environment variable values out
another way that we could do this is we
could basically pipe our arguments into
clip and then just pull them off the
clipboard so maybe we're thinking why
don't we just look for these arguments
in PowerShell about XE than in its
parent process so the problem there is
what if we introduced a third process in
the mix so instead of command spawning
PowerShell what if we said command
setting the the arguments into
environment variables and then a second
command echoing does environment
variables into PowerShell and then power
shell launches it well so technically
this works but we don't get any we don't
get any benefit out of this because as
we can see we still see the full command
in the parent process however if we take
notice of this pipe if we escape it one
layer and this is this isn't PowerShell
we're doing command level escaping so
when I escaped it for the first command
but not for the second one and if we do
that then we're golden
PowerShell runs with nothing and it's
arguments about what happened and the
parent process only has the name of the
process level environment variable and
not the contents itself so we'd actually
have to go all the way up to the
grandparent process to get this and this
is kind of a tree structure they're a
little outline of what this looks like
so maybe we can say okay well why don't
we just take any process that any
powershell process and recursively go up
the stack all the way to see all the
arguments to see if any of them contain
these malicious arguments well the only
problem there is that there's tons of
ways where you can pass information back
and forth with no actual relationship
between the processes themselves or no
recursive relationship up and this is
one example of basically spawning
command where pieces of code are stored
in the title of each command window and
then WMI is used to query them out and
reassemble them back together and then
invoke them clipboard is another example
you could use user level environment
variables you could pass information
back through a file or registry there's
tons of ways you can pass information
back and forth such that it won't show
up on the command line as you'd expect
so the good news in all of this is that
PowerShell script block logging catches
all this no matter how it's run no
matter how it's passed in PowerShell 5
is just insanely awesome in terms of the
preventative and detective security
controls that are in place for a
scripting language it's is stupid
awesome the bad news is is that there's
token layer off the station that
persists even in of these script block
logs and that's one notice as we go this
PowerShell shield in the top right each
office keishon techniques we talk about
when that shield shows up that's saying
hey no matter what else may have missed
it this is going to show up in
PowerShell logs now it may look slightly
differently than you'd think and I'll
try to basically touch on those cases
but it's really really awesome to have
that kind of data available so let's
look at an example of office gating a
PowerShell command in some really crazy
ways so we're gonna start with the
cradle or the remote download cradle
which is basically this one-liner
command which is in memory execution of
some remotely hosted PowerShell script
attackers use this all the time because
frameworks use this all the time and we
all like to use frameworks and copy and
paste code from one another so veil
power sploit Metasploit you name it we
see this all the time
so let's kind of plate red team blue
team which is kind of how I define my
life basically basically breaking my
assumptions as a defender and then how
can I bolster those assumptions so at
the top we have an attacker command
which is this remote download cradle
with this bitly link which is totally
legit and then let's say as a defender
if we want to catch this on the command
line how could we do that well we can
start to build out a list of terms of
the
where if we see invoke expression new
object system net-net web client and
then download string HTTP this would
catch this exact command so now let's go
through and see how we can obfuscate the
command at the top and adjust our
defender terms at the bottom to kind of
you know stay head to head with all the
attackers doing so first of all system
dot is not necessary almost anywhere you
see it in PowerShell PowerShell is gonna
automatically pre pin that underneath
the hood so an attacker doesn't have to
put system dot so if an attacker doesn't
absolutely have to have this in their
command then I don't want to make that
assumption as a defender so I'm gonna
pull it out of both the URL in this case
is just a string and it's a string token
we can do things like concatenate it in
line we're also not really limited to
double quotes we can use single quotes
whitespace push it around stuff like
that we can also set it as a variable so
let's go ahead and move that HTTP from
the download string portion download
string now this is the most common
method that we see so download string
lets it take a step back new object net
that web client is creating a dotnet
class for the net-net web client class
which has many methods download string
is just one of them but there's quite a
few downloads string download file and
download data are some of the most
common ones that we see download file
will hit disk so it's more of using
commodity but download string and
download data data will be a byte array
as opposed to an expression itself but
maybe we can just say okay
why don't we just say that download and
we'll catch all of these so let's do
that so now for this dot download how
might this little parentheses bite us if
we have this as part of our detection
well you can actually take a new object
net that web client and you can set it
in a variable and then have variable dot
download string typically you'll see
some frameworks you know calling that
variable WCC have variable name dot
download strength there's no parenthesis
so let's go ahead and remove that from
the arguments at the bottom now that dot
how could what could an attacker do to
make this dot really problematic for us
as a defenders well they could put
single quotes around download string
doesn't make it a string but it it still
breaks that dot but then we can put
double quotes around it and what I found
is that if you have double quotes if you
look at download string you can actually
do is then put a tick mark in download
string and it still runs crazy right now
why does this work well the tick mark is
the escape character for powershell
and it has meaning behind these
escapable characters
you're from know you know beef or
backspace' new line all this kind of
stuff but if you escape something that
has no escapable meaning it just runs
and this is not this is not just true of
powershell if you do the same with
command with a carrot if you escape
something that doesn't have any meaning
to be escaped it just doesn't do
anything and goes ahead and keeps on
running so you can put a lot of tech
characters and a lot of tick marks there
as long as you stay away from those
special eight characters that have the
special escapable meaning but if you're
like me you really want to put tick
marks in front of those characters so
all you have to do then it just
uppercase them and then you're good to
go
so now any method we can put double
quotes around it put ticks in front of
any character that we want as long as
it's not a zero because unfortunately
there's no uppercase to zero so you know
how to lock on that one but the
problematic thing from an offensive
perspective is that this persists on
command line arguments as well as all
the way into the script lock logs which
is PowerShell is the latest and greatest
4104 eid really really awesome really
sexy logs but these tick marks are still
there and if you'll take a closer look
you'll see the concatenation is still
there so at the end of the day script
lock logging will basically log every
kind of layer of the onion if you have
this command encrypted and encoded like
100 times every layer gets its own
script lock logging even if you're
running something remotely even though
you'll never see that in the command
line arguments it'll all show up in
PowerShell script block logging but this
token layer office keishon will still
persist so how do we deal with this as
defenders well we're not done yet we
could try to regex all the things right
and basically take into account any tick
marks if we go that route I would
recommend also adding open read because
we looked at download string file data
open reads another one that returns a
byte stream instead of a byte array and
we've seen attackers use it a couple
times but it's not too common so if you
want to go that route make sure you have
dot download and open read but I would
advise against it because if you put
parentheses around any method then you
can actually treat it as a full-blown
spring so you know as string so you can
basically concatenate or reorder it do a
ton of crazy stuff and in this case
you'll also see there's this dot invoke
after that method that's only required
in PowerShell to PowerShell 3 and later
is smart enough where you don't need
that dot invoke so a lot of the
obfuscation frameworks that I've worked
on I make sure to include that dot
invoke by default so it works on any
version of PowerShell but as a defender
I want to make sure that we're not
focusing on that dot invivo
for for detection because it's not
necessary in later versions so let's
just remove download string from our
defensive kind of list alright net at
webb plant for this we can put double
quotes and ticks we can put print season
again treat it like a string concatenate
it reorder it chunk it up into small
pieces whatever we want so let us go to
the first option and say yeah let's just
go ahead and get rid of net dot web
client from defensive perspective and
keep going now new object so we're left
with the two pieces were left with our
invoke expression and new object and
these are both commandlets
now PowerShell is super super friendly
and inviting to people who have never
written PowerShell before but it has
tons of aliases which basically means
PowerShell has a commandment called get
child item and if you want to list
everything in a directory you just say
get child item on it but if you have no
clue what PowerShell is then you might
just type Durer and it will also work
because that's an alias for get child
item if you come from the linux world
you can just type LS and that works
because they have all these aliases that
translate into the thing you actually
mean and there's shortened forms of that
and so power Shelby's you a lot of
options that's great from usability
perspective but it's terrifying from a
defensive perspective because now we
have to find all these different options
and make sure we have coverage for all
of them the good news here is that new
object doesn't have any of those there's
no there's no alias systems there's
shortened forms of it so I was really
excited when I came across this and Roz
this is gonna be a really solid
detection the only problem is that
PowerShell is too helpful sometimes so
there's so many functions in command
what sometimes you kind of forget you
forget which one you that you're looking
for and so you can basically use get
command and say get command show me all
the commands or functions to start with
a new dash P and just put a wild card at
the end it'll list all this information
now the cool part here is that this is
not text that's being returned as
PowerShell objects now why does that
matter well we can basically take the
result of a single if we basically have
it return just a single command let we
can then pass it in to invoke expression
which will automatically convert that
object into the string of new object and
then invoke it but we can actually be
more creative
since we're dealing with objects instead
of invoke expression we can use the dot
or an ampersand which are invocation
operators now here's our list it's
really fun let's move those wild cards
as long as we're returning a single
object this works and this is new object
so instead of specifying a new object on
the command line we could actually
replace that T with a wild card or keep
replacing a lot of characters and as
long as we have a query that will return
only a new object that's
now new object and that doesn't appear
you will not see new object appearing on
the command line arguments or in script
block logs the one place you will see it
though is in the 4103 Eid which is
module logs so basically think about any
kind of huge screen module logs are the
ones that I've not found really good
ways to obfuscate it but the problem is
is that if you have a huge script you
would have hundreds or even thousands of
module logs for just a single execution
of a script because it's looking at
every every command line every parameter
binding all this stuff so really really
helpful really robust but a lot of logs
so how do we actually meaningfully piece
that back together to the tech this kind
of stuff we're not done here yet command
also has an alias of GCM and there's
actually an undocumented alien called
command because PowerShell will
automatically basically take get - and
prepend it to anything you do to say I
didn't find when you type the word
command I didn't find a function I
didn't find a commandment maybe you may
get - command oh you did that's what
we're gonna do
so again rewind every detection that
we've ever built as a defender for
powershell commandlets that included get
- we totally don't need to get - so we
want to make sure that we don't define
that in our detection otherwise we can
get burned on this another thing we can
do if we don't want to use wildcards we
can always just say basically take our
command let name and chop it up in the
sub strings whatever we want and then
specify it there with get command these
are several different powershell one
gato syntaxes for doing this exact same
thing if you ever look at posh code org
it's one of the first powershell gallery
like distribution kind of sharing
platforms and it's been around for a
while which is awesome because there's a
lot of PowerShell one dunno syntax which
still works today but no one really is
using it because it's really verbose
like this well if you're an attacker
it'd be great if you could find some
things that no one is familiar with and
no one's looking for because this might
do exactly what you need but no
defenders looking for us so if you
notice this execution context that's an
automatic variable within PowerShell and
we're going to see this coming up again
and again so you want to make sure
you're looking for that for all this
stuff with git command we can do the
exact same thing with git alias but
instead of dealing with a full
Commandment name we're dealing with the
alias name itself so we have get alias
it has an alias of gal and then then get
aliases alias is called alias because of
the git - beforehand makes sense all
good all right let's keep going
so never we add all these things let me
say ok I'm going to look for new object
I'm gonna forget command command TCM get
alias all this kind of stuff
and at the end of the day it's not
really gonna be feasible to find all
this because whenever you can get any
piece of a command into a string then
you're golden you can manipulate it in
all kinds of crazy ways but if we did
want to go down this route we have to
keep in mind you put tick marks in front
of all these things you can also use the
you can just instead of using get
command you can use those invocation
operators again and to start to treat
the Commandant name as a string and so
on the Left we have concatenation on the
right we have reordering and then
reordering is really really awesome
because some people will say okay well
concatenation I don't care about because
whenever I look at logs I remove all the
whitespace and special characters such
that new object will come back together
and then I evaluate at that point well
new things like using the dash element
operators start to reorder commands new
object will never come back together no
matter how many special characters and
whitespace you remove because it's
absolutely reordered and this is where
it gets really really challenging so
let's just give up on this be a real
list here so we're left with invoke
expression now as a defender if you
don't know where to start with
PowerShell and you have command line
logs look for IEX and invoke expression
pays crazy dividends if you're it's like
the best place to start just start there
so what's problematic about invoke
expression well you have the alias of IX
the ordering doesn't matter you can have
at the beginning at the end of an
expression you also can put tick marks
in it because it's a command lot like
anything else in PowerShell you can use
invocation operators and start
concatenate or reorder ie X and invoke
it with the Dobbs the ampersand
invocation operators then let's step
back and say okay well what why why all
these ways to execute code in PowerShell
this seems really problematic right and
what we'll talk about in a second is
oh-lee and I basically assemble this
huge PowerShell corpus of scripts to
kind of study what's normal what's not
in terms of finding evil which we'll
talk about in just a couple slides but
basically three percent of scripts in
the wild use invoke expression in the
script itself which sounds like a small
percentage but it's actually a lot of
scripts out there so you can't even
feasibly say I don't want to let invoke
expression run in the script context but
again on the command line it's pretty
uncommon but then you have its cousin
invoke command now invoke command is
typically used to run a command on a
remote system and it's it's expecting a
script block whereas a invoke
expressions is expecting an expression
but if you don't specify a remote system
it runs locally so you have invoked
command ICM that invoke or invocation
operators
you also have invoke returns is invoke
with context tons of things out there so
okay let's say we're adding this to the
list of like invocation options right
well we also have powershell wonder
whether there's that execution context
again we have invoke script but really
what I'm worried about is how do we deal
how do we deal with this ampersand in
this dot how could we feasibly look for
this on the command line without getting
insane false positives well in this case
we're dealing with script box and maybe
we say if I see a combination of an
ampersand or dot and I see the left and
right braces which is what you have to
have to denote script locks then maybe
we're good uh it would help with false
positives but at the end of the day you
don't have to have curly braces to
define script locks you can actually
convert expressions to script locks
using these are two options here using
the script lock dot in that class of the
create method or PowerShell one that has
some text again and then for each of
these you can apply all the office
keishon we just talked about and get
crazy results there so there's still no
silver bullet at this point kind of
sucks invoke cradle crafter is a tool
that I released earlier this year and it
has over these are all the memory
invocation options but has over 10
different invocation options that no
random we go and generate including some
ones we looked at and then some other
crazier ones so if you want an idea of
some of the crazy things you can do to
basically form invoke expression or IEX
to invoke PowerShell code then this is a
tool that you can use just to randomly
generate that kind of syntax all right
take a breath that was a lot i've been
joining up here for a while the good
news is is that this is really the
extent of how you can off you skate
powershell the bad news is that I'm
totally kidding there's a lot more you
can do so we have our commands we just
did all that write all this crazy tick
marks and wildcards and all this stuff
well what if we just said let me treat
the entire command as a single string
and then invoke it that means I've got
the entire command as a string so I can
do crazy string manipulation on the
whole thing like maybe we'll just
reverse the entire command and on the
command line it's in Reverse but then
the memory it riri verses it and we
invoke it you can also put garbage
delimiters just all throughout the
command and use the split command to
basically pull out those delimiter so
you can use replace operations to
replace the delimiter zuv nothing you
can then just do sheriff concatenation
to basically chop up and reorder your
command into a lot of pieces so these
are some options that again are gonna
evade the command line stuff
but it's going to be reassembled for for
everything in script block log so script
block logs you're gonna have it all put
back together which is really really
nice so would it suck if someone wrote a
tool it did all the stuff automatically
as defenders we probably hate the person
who did that right so unfortunately this
is what I got myself into last year and
our releases tool called invoke
obfuscation that basically took all this
research that I did and automated the
office Gatien of PowerShell code any
arbitrary command or script you feed in
it'll basically give you the whole slew
of options of what you want to office
gate so in this case we take the exact
same one-liner download cradle that we
just walk through then at a push of a
button we can have it for do something
like this which is going through and
reordering all the components and
invoking it with the invocation
operators and stuff like that but then
we can take that and say let me treat
the whole thing as a string and do
something crazier like this and just
reorder the whole command as a string
now I put this flag up here because a
couple months ago we saw a PT 32 which
is a Vietnamese threat group using using
my tool to do their nefarious activity
and they actually wrapped their commands
in like a lot of layers like at least
five or six layers of this like string
manipulation stuff so I get a lot of
dirty looks in the office when those
samples come in and they just kind of
slide that over my way for me to go and
decode so people say you should eat your
own dog food I do a lot and the dog food
doesn't taste that good anymore so hold
the tomatoes then earlier this year a
released in vote Cradle crafter which is
not taking any arbitrary code in it's
basically saying feed me or remote URI
and any post kind of cradle commands you
want to run and then let me show you
some really weird cradle syntaxes you
can use that maybe the defenders aren't
looking for and that hopefully defenders
will use to start looking for them and
so anyways we take that same URI if it
legit and we can produce something like
this looks totally different than in BO
coffee station there's no tick marks
it's basically doing like method and
member and command let enumeration to
basically produce strings like download
string out of this like crazy just long
and nasty nasty command so then you do
something like this and just say well
who needs alphanumeric so I'll just use
special characters now I got to say the
the guy who came from with this concept
is a Japanese researcher who in 2010
wrote hello world and PowerShell with
nothing but special characters
the twitter handle is muda muda Gucci
and it's just a fascinating blog post
google translate it if you don't speak
Japanese because I don't but basically
took three steps into taking special
characters and coming up with any
arbitrary PowerShell code it's a really
beautiful idea and this produces not
beautiful code but at the end of the day
it's a ton of variables that are all
stored in dollar sign curly braces
because when you put curly braces you
can put special characters as variable
names so you could also put whitespace
as the character names and get something
like this and I was talking with Casey
Smith or subti early this year and he
said oh that reminds me of whitespace
encoding and I said I don't know what
that is and you got to tell me about it
and so he said oh yeah you just take
whitespace and tabs and basically do
that for the encoding and stuff like oh
sweet and so I wrote this and so this is
that same command where the whole
command is either in white spaces
delimited by tabs or tabs delimited by
white spaces do you have the stub
decoder at the end now for both of these
options again it is completely
reassembled in script lock logs you
don't need anything fancy to detect this
in script lock logs because it all comes
back together magically it's a really
beautiful example of the power of script
block logs but let's say you don't have
to get block logs then maybe you're
looking at me and saying wow I really
feel like there's no hope here what
could we possibly do so this is kind of
the turning of the tides of this talk
hopefully hopefully all the depressing
stuff is out and like let's talk about
some good news for defenders right so
let's try to do a little science now I'm
not a data scientist and nor do I try to
pretend to be one but there's some
simple statistical analysis techniques
that we can perhaps apply to this
problem area and get some good results
out of so as a human if we look at this
code no one in there no one here would
look at this code and say yep let's let
that right on through my environment
like totally okay to run that as humans
we can look at this and say this code is
not well so how might we tell a computer
to figure that out so one of the first
things last year almost exactly a year
ago it was a couple weeks after our
released invocation at Derby con Lee
Holmes wrote a blog post called
detecting more office gated PowerShell
and he actually referenced this these
examples in the blog post and he did
something really really cool
which actually started this this entire
conversation with me and Lee Holmes
about what other ideas could we apply to
detect this kind of stuff and led to
this collaboration which is kind of
funny looking back on so anyways he took
all the powershell scripts off of posh
code org which is 3400 scripts at the
time and he basically did character
frequency analysis on all of them and so
on the right is the average of all the
posh code scripts which as you'd expect
powershell the language itself is
English and so you'd expect the English
characters to kind of match like English
you know like grammar instruction or
like on stuff so we see ETA this is the
most common that makes up you know 20%
of all the PowerShell scripts the first
special character we see is the dollar
sign at 3% on average the 3% of any
powershell script on this site is a
dollar sign now you look on the left
there it's insane 20% is is tick marks
8% from all this stuff and then over
here I always say it's all special
characters it looks really really
different so again we can look at that
and say okay yeah these are really
different but how do we tell computer to
do that so this is where we get a little
nerdy here for a second
talk about cosine similarity now I'm not
this math whiz person so if you're not
please don't check out when should I
make this fun and really exciting but
basically the concept is if you have two
points two coordinates to make a line
right you have line a and you have line
B and they have angles right and so
cosine similarly basically saying what
these lines to be very similar because
the angles between them are zero but if
you have 90 degrees that's like dead
different right so we can actually
extend this idea beyond two coordinate
lines to three coordinate lines four
coordinate lines maybe 26 coordinate
lines for all the Alpha characters so
that's that's what Lee did in this blog
post he basically said okay why don't I
apply this cosine similarity to
technique and then apply that to all the
scripts in posh code and what you'll see
is that almost all the scripts are
really really close to the value of one
so I 95 percent symbol or 97 percent
similar but then we have our two samples
at the bottom which are 37% similar and
15% similar now if we took all the codes
on posh code and do the scatter chart
we'll see most of them are right up
there at one
really really similar to each other but
then you have all these really randos
just falling out at the bottom and so we
can do is take 3400 scripts and
immediately just say let's look at
everything below 80% and that's like 30
scripts so this is great on on just you
know 3400 scripts but as Lee and I start
through this research we said we need a
lot of data we need as much data as we
possibly get our hands on so a year and
a half ago Microsoft put out this
contest called underhanded PowerShell
basically inviting people from the
community to basically submit obtuse and
often skated PowerShell to evade certain
checks so that was a little bit of data
but then we we really wanted a huge
corpus of data so we start with
underhand PowerShell data github posh
got all this stuff but the important
thing to keep in mind for us is that Lee
and I felt it was really important to
highlight that you can actually gather
all this data and be really polite in
the process and what do I mean by that
well Lee wrote the script to basically
scrape github and all the blue portions
are the actual pieces of code that are
scraped and github and all the red
portions are a hundred percent Canadian
because Lee Holmes is Canadian and he's
the nicest person you've ever met and
it's just like throttling and all this
great stuff so he basically was he was
basically scraping for like a month he
looked at the crater to get hub ID and
said I there's 10 million IDs this
should take us a month or something like
that and so anyway it's getting close to
a month his uh his scripts are still
running and he sees 10 million ID 11
million 12 million he's like wait a
second and went back and double-checked
it was a hundred million in github he's
like oh my gosh the clocks a-tickin like
how are we gonna get this data and so
apparently the most polite thing you can
do is just ask the great folks at github
hey would you mind telling us what all
the PowerShell projects are and zipping
those up for us and a lunch break they
went and did just that so kudos to
github for getting us that data this is
every single contributor in github that
has ever submitted a PowerShell script
as of a couple months ago I just want to
ask is anyone in here ever submitted a
PowerShell script to github or TechNet
or any these places can you just raise
your hand real quick awesome thank you
very much because like you actually are
part of this research your name is on
the slide your name is buried in the
code in some interesting places but this
wouldn't be possible without all the
open-source PowerShell scripts that are
out there so seriously thank you very
much I don't read these right now if we
have time at the end we'll go through
that so we got a lot of scripts right
now when we have a lot of scripts we
have to do something with it cuz it'd be
irresponsible not to right so now if you
start looking through all these scripts
you're gonna find some weird shenanigans
out there and one of the ones I'd like
to highlight was just a really sad one
remove games that ps1 someone wrote this
to go through and kill games running
process even nuke the directory noise
sad major buzzkill but in all
seriousness we got a lot of scripts how
many four hundred and eight thousand
scripts over 28,000 authors and the fun
thing that we did people like to think
that hacking is like really cool mr.
robot yeah it's really fun like wear a
hoodie at the end of the day what we had
to do was we had to manually label 7,000
scripts which meant that on the weekends
you know sit in front of the computer
and notepad would pop up and you scroll
through the script and be like yep that
one looks pretty office gated let's mark
those off you skated next please and go
through and do that 7,000 times that's
not fun now why in the world would we do
that one reason they said that someone
else wouldn't have to so they could just
use the label and we did but if you
think back here on this approach of
character frequency if we looked at
everything under 80% then we could say
okay this was pretty good most of what
it was under 80% was office gated right
what we don't know is what about are
there any office gated scripts above
that 80% mark and short of looking at
all 3400 options when it comes to
actually trying to think differently
about this and applying some different
techniques we need to actually have
labeled data so that we know at the end
of the day did we detect all the things
that we labeled as bad I'm going to keep
you on Ryan Cobb put out a blog post
basically taking taking some of these
ideas and applying it and basically
showing that as you as you start to
creep up and look at higher and higher
percentages you're gonna deal with more
false positives but that's where you're
gonna find some more of the wins some
more of the obviously hated scripts that
are more similar than not so how does
this character frequency analysis scored
the two things to look at here are
precision and recall and it's 89 percent
and 37 percent so precision means let's
say we have a hundred thousand
PowerShell scripts right and 10 percent
10 thousand of those are bad their
office gated now if we ran if we run
this tool and it says ok these are the
thousand scripts out of the whole
hundred thousand that are office gated
let's say every single one at return it
was correct its precision would be a
hundred percent so basically every time
this model says it's bad it's bad but it
missed 90% of them out there that would
be a really low recall score it'd be a
ten percent recall score so in this case
ninety percent precision is pretty good
but 37 percent recall means it barely
got over a third of the office SCADA
scripts out there so we need something
better so surely we can do better so how
might we do better
well PowerShell there's a lot more
features in the data science community
information retrieval community they
would say these characters counts and
frequencies are features so PowerShell
when it looks at itself it basically
sees I know that this is this command
line I'm calling a generic I know that
these are the left parenthesis right
parenthesis and this is an object all
this kind of stuff but in PowerShell 3
and later what became exposed to anyone
is what's called an AST or the abstract
syntax tree which basically looks like
this so not only does PowerShell is able
to tokenize each piece of the command
but it actually knows the relationship
of those commands now why is this matter
for us this allows us had to get insane
features and really focus in because you
could say ok character frequency makes
sense you can have really obfuscated
stuff of always tic marks and have your
evil code and then you can literally
just copy and paste the entire work of
Shakespeare and then that's going to
really throw off your overall you know
character frequency analysis because
it's going to look like normal English
right well that's the whole point why
don't we drill down and start to piece
and start to gather features from each
kind of command letour each kind of
token so that we have to force someone
to basically put in bad data in every
single place that we're looking there's
a great tool there called a ast Explorer
which is just a little GUI or you can
basically paste in any kind of code you
want and explore kind of how the ast
structure is so with this we were able
to extract things like distribution of
ast types so again out of the whole
script let's say 90% of this entire
script is nothing but commandlets or
strings or arrays or stuff like that so
we did just a straight-up distribution
of those types assignment binary
invocation operators we did an array
size range again a lot of arrays aren't
that big but if you have rays of like
thousands of characters maybe that shell
code that's kind of odd right and then
for every kind of AST type again
commandlets string method all the stuff
function comments we basically did
character frequency on each of those
individually as well as the entire
script itself so we did character
frequency we also did things like
entropy we did the length maximum medium
mode range average white space density
character casing again randomized casing
and a lot of frameworks if you see 50 50
uppercase lowercase that's randomized
casing because typically it's gonna be
like 12 or something all these different
things and we basically push them all
together so that for any input
PowerShell command or script we get
almost 5000 features there's a lot more
than just the alpha numerics right and
so we were really excited about this
spend a lot of time just getting as many
features and possibly could never once
did we say this feature is bad or this
feature isn't we just said I just want
the data blue neurons crap what we're
gonna do with 5,000 features all right
like how do we actually you know make
meaningful use of this data so basically
we have here is that of these 5000
features some of these features matter a
lot more than others and instead of us
going through and figuring out which one
matters more than the other we used a
little thing called logistic regression
so basically you have the coloring is a
little bit unfortunate but basically you
have a logit function to say like again
if you have like thousands of
Commandments in in in one script but
only like ten comments like you can't
deal with the range like that so we use
something called a logit function to
basically bring all the values between 0
and 1 and kind of smush it down on this
plot and then we use linear regression
so what does that look like basically we
go through and we take all 5,000
features and we have a weight that
weight is basically saying feature 1 is
this important or feature 2 is this not
important or feature 558 is this
important and so for every single input
script or command we extract all 5,000
features and then for each feature we
multiply it by its weight to say how
important are you we then add up all
those results and then if it's over a
certain point then it's octave skated if
it's below a certain point it's not
obfuscated so now again it comes back to
well how do we decide the values of the
weights how important is one feature
over the other we let the model tell us
that I want to mean by that is we take
that labeled data you know 7,000 scripts
and we basically through thousands of
iterations send it through and say ok
pull all the features and we start with
all the weights being exactly the same
everything on a level playing field and
it goes through and it pulls out all the
features does although multiplications
and it says are you over one or are you
less than one are you off you skated or
not it makes that decision and then it
says okay so that this is labeled data I
happen to know whether I was right or
not now whenever it was right it's all
good but whenever it was wrong it looks
and says okay what weights contributed
the most to me being wrong about this
and then adjust those the most either up
or down and then the weights that were
released it adjusts those the least and
so it keeps kind of tuning and tweaking
each thing through thousands and
thousands of thousands of iterations and
as you can kind of see in this
concentric circle what kinda gets closer
and closer to the truth as it moves all
these weights up and down so how does
this actually work at the end of the day
we'll gain remember our cosine
similarity we had 89% precision and
recall is 37% now for anyone who's not a
blue team err in the house this next
slide is our equivalent of getting da so
we're gonna get really excited about
this so just let you in on this our
model performed at 96 percent precision
in 94 percent recall which we were
really excited about and false positives
were 0.01 so this model is literally ten
times better at finding off you ciated
code with half the false positives so
we're really really excited about this
now you may step back and say okay what
about what about sketchy stuff right
like occupation there's kind of a
spectrum right like something to be
really really off the skated like the
thing on the left whether it's just all
special characters but then there can be
some other things where it's like I
don't think that's bad but can't want a
second look so we actually went back and
kind of labeled things as like sketchy
and if you think about from this way
it's like if you had the world's best in
turn this in turn would be the one to go
around and say hey I don't think this is
bad but I'd appreciate it if you took a
second look that's kind of the approach
that we took and so if we start labeling
sketchy stuff and we'll actually see
here is that overall it performed at 88
and 89 percent so basically it was wrong
a lot but it actually captured 97
percent of the evil that was out there
as opposed to the 94 so what that means
is that if you want like the super high
confidence of the stuff that was labeled
is really really obfuscated then you're
gonna get that 94 percent 95 percent and
then the tool that's basically the
default it goes for high confidence
first but then if you want to cast a
wider net and say yeah I'm okay to get
some sketchy stuff as well I'm willing
to weed through some false positives and
find some more stuff that maybe I'm
missing in the other model then you can
kind of do that wider net approach so
what about other algorithms so again not
being a data science person with this
labeled data set you can take this and
plug it into any kind of like machine
learning studio that you want so Lee Hom
spent a little bit of time doing this
and testing out tons of other algorithms
to say like did our approach actually
fare well against all the others and it
actually did it was ended up being
almost tied with one of the other ones
but just a little bit better and so
again you don't have to have some fancy
studio like this to do what we're doing
we actually did all this by hand and
it's all out there open source on github
for anyone to be able to take that same
data and do cool stuff with it so a
quick demo of the tool so there's three
parts of the tool this first one
literally has nothing to do with finding
evil it's just all about ASCII art
because he doesn't like ASCII art so
it's colored ASCII art it's just doing
like a quick little demo of like here's
the command here's some of the kind of
extractions of feature extractions that
we do over 5,000 features less than 300
milliseconds for much powershell scripts
blah blah blah
and here's the interactive menu here so
basically the things to keep in mind are
you have some options here one is
tutorial which is a glorified colored
readme well she doesn't like colored
read Me's right so if you don't really
read me on github
you just do tutorial fun facts again we
spent a ton of time going through a ton
of data like 4 gigs uncompressed
PowerShell scripts like it is a lot of
data and there's a lot of fun things
that you'll learn about that data and so
there's some fun facts in there some
random phone backs ASCII art and you go
through that much data there's some
really creative people out there who are
way more artistic than me so we just
went and kind of you know wrote some
URLs to go through and find an ASCII art
stuff I spent an entire weekend doing
nothing like like on my exercise bike at
my gym like going through ASCII art like
I feels like you're such a nerd
so anyways there's random samplings I
asked you Arthur you can check out you
can also do a fun set of quotes and then
also credit so again every single of
github contributor for any PowerShell
project as of a couple months ago your
name is in here and I'll go and randomly
come display hey thanks to these 10
contributors and there's also a sub list
in there of like our favorite like
to contributor names because there's
some really creative contributor names
so some fun stuff in there so now if you
actually want to find evil just throw
that out the window and then get to the
really good stuff which there's two
components here one is reassembling
scripts out of script block logs
somewhere I'll talk about how PowerShell
5 is really awesome and you have these
CID 4104 vents well they're really
verbose right and so if you enabled it
some environments people are saying well
we can't possibly index all this data
into our sim and it's like that's
understandable it's a lot of data so how
can we meaning meaningful use of it
today well if you enable that logging
you can either acquire the raw EVT X
files or if you get one event we include
a lot of ingestion options so basically
we'll take the full event log and pipe
it into this function and it'll
basically go and reassemble the script
out of the script block log says if you
have a really long script then it can be
spread across hundreds of script block
logs and this will reassemble that for
you and it turns it all in PowerShell
objects which is nice so you have
PowerShell scripts now either command
line from whatever sources you have
maybe you have a directory of scripts
you've pulled out you know off the wire
other things or you go out and you query
your event logs and you reassemble all
the scripts and now you have it in
memory so the last piece is pushing it
through the magic which is measure rvo
obfuscation and here we are chewing
through 39 scripts right here in
labeling it as off the skated or not
obfuscated and again this is basically
taking all the scripts its extracting
5000 features multiplying multiplying
the 5000 against the weights adding them
up saying are you office gated or not
and then coming back with the full
results of the script saying true or
false is this off you skated it gives
the full time of how much it took to
extract the features measure the
features all this stuff and then also
all 5,000 features are listed in that
object for every single core soul so you
have everything at your disposal do you
want to dump at the disk or do whatever
else you want to start finding off the
skated code immediately now keep in mind
this does not find bad code for say this
is office caddy code there is still a
very really important role for looking
for indicators of compromise in whatever
frameworks that you're seeing out there
so I think it's important to add this as
a supplement so we're looking for these
known bad syntaxes or module logs or
other things like that and then for
everything else that we're possibly
missing just run this against it and see
what it comes up with
this is the very last thing I'll say is
that Lee and I we really wanted this
tool to be used by anyone we want anyone
to after the whole really discouraging
first part of this talk from defensive
perspective they'll say yes like there's
a tool we can actually start using today
and to be able to go back to your
organization's and say to your manager
hey we really need to get the powershell
5 and they say why and say well there's
crazy off you station you can do write
and say ok what would we do with all
that data we can't index it we don't
have to like if you have a syslog server
just anything you can just dump this
data to and then point this tool to it
then you can actually start detecting
this for zero dollars out of your pocket
and with that being said we want this to
be as user friendly as possible from an
operational perspective not just for the
research community or anything like that
because we are operational security
practitioners so that means is that if
you're using this in your organization
and as stuff comes back and it gets
flagged it's off to skate it you can say
ok this actually this isn't obfuscated
this is good I never want to see this
again and you can basically whitelist
that and so we have a couple options you
can basically drop scripts into a
whitelist directory it'll hash those and
then never alert on this exact hashes
again you can also write less based on
strings or regex matching which you want
to be a little careful with so you're
not too open with it but again we wanted
it to be really user friendly but kind
of operationalize this in your
environment so with that being said you
can get the code it's on my github you
can also it's also hosted in the
PowerShell gallery which means on any
power shell prompt you can just type
install - module revoke - office keishon
and have it up and running within 30
seconds finding office gated PowerShell
and in the tutorial if you if you follow
on github it will take you to tutorial I
actually included some EVT X Files and
some other files on there so actually
all the sample commands in this tutorial
are actually running against like real
data that we produced and it's not it's
not actually malicious but actual office
gated data so you can actually see right
away how it works and kind of the speed
at which it works in conjunction with
this research Lee and I at at black hat
and DEF CON released this white paper
which is hosted on the fire I've logged
there which is everything I just said
but without having to hear me say it
it's all written there's less jokes
let's be honest so so you can take your
pick there and then a couple references
like into some of the previous tools of
power shut off the station some of the
vlogs
about detecting it and then again the
last last one here PowerShell hearts the
blue team by Microsoft is you've not
heard that blog it's a blog post in
white paper that is just a phenomenal
overview of all the insanely awesome
preventive and detection based the
capabilities that Microsoft has put in
the PowerShell over the past several
years and it's just really really cool
so that being said that is my in the end
of my talk so thank you very very much
for listening
so I think we have five minutes or so
for questions so yes so if we say of all
the things that flag is office skated
from our corpus and what was almost yep
Oh most of it actually wasn't a lot of
the stuff was off he skated was like
code golf competitions and stuff like
that there's a lot of there's a lot of
the same stuff like if you just like
search through the corpus which the
corpus is available also we we made that
public if you just search for things
like invoke mimikatz just the way that
github starts to fork repos and there's
like everyone has their own copy of it
and so some stuff was off you skated
that way we did see some PowerShell ISE
steroids which is probably one of the
original PowerShell office caters which
they weren't that they were doing it
more for like IP protection but we do
see some of that data but but in in the
end this is looking at data that people
have uploaded to public sources so not
we didn't find anything it was like
groundbreaking this is really really bad
but I've definitely used it on several
engagements at man dia and it's been
really cool to see it find some stuff
that that we had some of the stuff we'd
found through other means but it was
cool to see this model at work against
just like massive datasets so really
good question yes
character talent by just attaching like
Shakespeare to it hmm so what happens if
you attach a sufficient amount of
well-structured well you know PowerShell
code and you have a small amount inside
you know yeah something yeah yeah really
good question so the question was in in
the character frequency analysis if you
have evil code and have all
Shakespeare's works and could you could
actually kind of counter that and it
would all holistically look good
well could you basically take with this
model take a really small piece of evil
off you skated code and have just
massive amounts of full code that's not
evil yeah that would be that would be
about the best approach to breaking it
other than the other concept is why
don't I minimally obfuscate it and you
don't need a thousand tick marks like if
you know exactly what defenders are
keying off of you don't have to put tick
marks or obviously ate those small
pieces a really good project that was
just released two weeks ago at Derby con
by Ryan Cobb he's the guy who basically
put together obfuscated Empire and he
really still called PS am Z which uses a
MSI or the anti-malware scan interface
to basically identify AV vendors that
are using a MSI to inspect PowerShell
and actually see what portions of the
script of keying off of so that you can
basically drill down and find of this
huge script here are the five pieces
that are part of the signature that this
AV vendor has and those just off you
skate those and he actually uses invoke
obfuscation to do just that is there
it's a really really cool idea super
smart dude so definitely a talk worth
checking out in terms of like evading
the detection now at the end of the day
you might think well that's kind of
stupid for you to say like here's
exactly how to evade this thing well I
have some amount of humility and realize
that like this is only so much and we're
really impressed by the results but at
the end of the day all it means is that
as we find in the wild or come up with
our own examples that bypass this
literally the only thing we have to do
is just label those is off you skated or
not add it into the back into the data
set and literally hit a button to
retrain the model go get a cup of coffee
in five minutes there's a new weighted
vector that we can plug in so yeah yeah
but but the exciting thing is that
anyone in the community can do that so
it is people find different models or
different vectors that make more sense
like hopefully they show that back out
with the community say hey this actually
works better than what these guys
with so that's our hope that real data
scientists will go and do some cool
stuff with our people who aren't data
scientists and started to take this data
and play around with it and not scrape
github for like a month and a half so
but really good question yes it was
definitely my code yeah yeah kind of a
PG 32 using off you see a PowerShell
it's it was pretty pretty evident to me
pretty quickly that it was my code so
it's kind of a that was the first time
I'd seen an apt group using my tool
which is kind of a happy sad moment but
I don't know unfortunately there's no
way to give this stuff out to only the
good guys but uh but yeah that I think
the most responsible thing is sharing as
openly as we can of the community and
saying like be aware this is a thing how
do we come together to detect it and
this was really my best attempt at an
answer to say like open source what can
people take how can people take hundreds
of hours of mine lee's research built
other people's research and use it
immediately to help better protect
themselves but be a really good question
any other questions
awesome thank you again very very much
[Applause]