the besides DC 2017 videos are brought
to you by threat quotient introducing
the industry's first threat intelligence
platform designed to enable threat
operations and management and data tribe
a new kind of startup studio co building
the next generation of commercial cyber
security analytics and big data product
companies my name is Gabriel Ryan I'm US
penetration tester at Gotham digital
science we're like Aeons security
consulting arm I guess I could call it
that
anyone here from the Northern Virginia
yeah
no I'm like really happy to be here
because like my first security job was
actually in Northern Virginia so I'm
pretty thrilled I don't miss the traffic
though you know but yeah so a couple new
things in this presentation we're gonna
be talking about two new types of
wireless technique we're going to talk
about hostile portal attacks which is a
way of grabbing Active Directory
credentials without having direct
network access and we're also going to
talk about indirect Wireless pivots
which is a way of using rogue ap attacks
to bypass port based access control
mechanisms on wireless networks so
before we go into any of this we have to
take like an obligatory look at wpa2 EAP
and no discussion about wpa2 EAP is
really complete without talking about
rogue ap attacks which is the means that
you typically use to steal credentials
for these kinds of networks so Rogan
Pete sacs are the real ones the bread
and butter of modern wireless networks
you can use it for stealthy man the
middle attacks you know stealing radius
creds as we've said all kinds of really
cool stuff and the simplest that this
the simplest example of how to do a
rogue ap attacker the simple simplest
rogue ap a check out there is something
called the evil tone attack just to use
an analogy actually first given to me by
that guy right there who got me into
wireless big round of applause for that
guy okay
sorry Scott so it's a good analogy of
like you know how evil twin attacks work
is let's say that you have an open
network and we're gonna call this DEFCON
open because it's probably the most
secure network in existence and
everything yeah so you have these these
four devices and they're associated with
this network if you were to spin up your
own wireless hotspot right and you were
to give this hotspot the same network
name SSID and channel as the one that
you're attacking how would these devices
be able to tell the difference between
these two these two access points well
the truth is that they wouldn't be able
to and as long as you're able to provide
a better signal-to-noise ratio that is
your signal strength is is better than
the other one these devices will
actually drop their connections and
associate with you so that's that's the
fundamental you know rogue access point
attack that pretty much everything else
is based off of our spans off of so
these attacks I mean they're not
anything that they've been around for
like a really really long time the first
one you know they started emerge around
2002 the first documentation that I
could find was the wireless LAN security
fact by CW Klaus that starts talking
about evil twin attacks about a year
later you have a asleep released by Josh
right which is a total expands off of
that 2004 you actually see the
implementation of a karma attack by Dino
Diaz oviya and Shane McCauley
four years after that you have free
radius wpe which is actually Josh
frightened Brandon Tana woods figured
out how to use his attacks to steal
credentials from radius networks
welcomewelcome grabbed a seed and you
know by 2014 karma attacks had actually
stopped being relays effectives that
used to be so two researchers from from
South Africa Dom whitey de Villiers came
up with the improved karma attacks you
know released a tool called mana that
actually mean I made these attack very
very very effective
once again and you know very recently
the guy who wrote Wi-Fi Fisher came up
with a lure ten attack which exploits
Windows Wi-Fi sense to you know a whole
new way of doing this so as you can see
I mean is this is actually a very
there's a pretty rich history of of
using these kinds of attacks rogue ap
attacks are they primarily are used to
feel like one of two functions the roles
that they fall into are either man the
middle attacks which you can use to
steal credentials for things or they're
used to breach WPA or wpa2 networks the
ones that use the EAP so in this talk
we're going to something a little bit
different we're gonna talk about rogue
ap attacks as a means of lateral
movement
so before we can continue we also should
talk about you know how would you use a
rogue s1 attack to breach at WPI 2 EAP
network so anyone here actually know how
EAP works ok awesome great so logically
we're gonna start out with kind of a
logical high look high level look at how
EAP works right we're looking at EAP
peep and EAP TLS specifically so
logically the the way that you aap works
it it it's a transaction that occurs
between a client the client and the
authentication server so the first thing
happens to the client that's like your
wireless device your laptop or whatever
it's gonna send an authentication
request to the authentication server the
authentication server is going to
respond with an x.509 certificate and
it's going to send the client
now that the reason why it's doing this
is it needs to establish the client that
it can be trusted otherwise the client
doesn't know who it's actually
attempting to authenticate with so at
this time at this point the client then
either accepts or rejects the
certificate if it accepts the
certificate it means it trusts the
authentication server and secured
tunnels establish between the client and
the authentication server so once that
secure tile is established we move on
from from the outer authentication which
is where we were at before and then we
now start begin what's called the inter
authentication process which is this is
actually where you know credentials are
entered and you know you enter in your
username and password and that stuff
gets sent to the authentication server
we'll look more at how that works in a
second but that authentication that
inter authentication is going to occur
through this secure tunnel and the
reason why you need that secure tunnels
that remember that you know EAP is the
method as the authentication mechanism
that we're using to provide access to
the WPA capabilities of the network so
until this entire process is finished
this WPA network is not actually
operating as a WPA net network you don't
get that WPA until after this process
succeeds so this entire this entire
transactions happening over open Wi-Fi
so without the secure tunnel and it's
hacker could actually sniff this the
inter authentication process offline and
derive the password that way and
actually legolas implementations of EAP
were highly susceptible to this think
like EAP md5 just pretty prevalent you
know like ten years ago so when I
mentioned that there was actually you
know two parties involved this
transaction that's a bit of an
understatement and there's actually
three the the
being the authenticator so we talked
about the client device the technical
name for that's the supplicant that's
that's that's your devices connect to
the network and you have your
authentication server and this is the
radius Center that's handling this
transaction but in the middle here
there's something else and that's your
access point the access point we refer
to it as an Authenticator if you look at
the RFC's that's the name that's used
and and the job of the Authenticator the
access point is to kind of act as a
mediator between the client device in
the authentication server and the reason
why we need this is because this the
supplicants peeking over layer two and
the authentication server only speaks
over layer seven using the radiance
protocol so you need this this access
point in the middle to act as an
intermediary now remember that this
access point until the process is
finished is is acting as an open access
point right so what this means is that
remember how we talked about how open
access points are susceptible to evil
twin attacks another rogue access point
attacks so what that means is that
because until this process is completed
you know that this access point the
Authenticator here is also susceptible
to those very same attacks so what you
can do as an attacker is impersonate a
wpa2 EAP network and and enforce clients
to attempt to authenticate with you and
if you're using a p-p-poor EP of TTLs as
your outer authentication mechanisms
then you're going to have a situation
where you can force clients to connect
to you force them to authenticate with
your own rogue radius server and you
know hopefully what that will get you as
an MS chappie to challenge and response
which you can then use to derive radius
passwords or radius and T password
hashes which are password equivalent so
this attack that I'm just describing was
was first described by Brad and Tonto in
2008 and to make it even worse actually
as anyone here familiar with ms Chafee -
okay out of you - who raise your hands
how many people think that ms Jeffy - is
amazing yeah I see some some pretty yeah
like no no no okay so yeah I'm just
happy to of the problem is that you know
a P P for example it this outer
authentication protocol it's bad enough
that you can force stuff to connect to
using a row of AP attack but the inner
the inner authentication mechanism
that's used typically is mschap e2 and
there are a couple ways of cracking
Emma's Chaffey to the traditional way is
that you take that EAP challenge a
response that you
that you've captured and you just can
you know iterally you know perform a
dictionary attack can take the password
and the challenge and then try to you
know combine them to create a message
happy to response you try these
sequentially over and over again until
you find the right password that's a
dictionary attack
unfortunately the success rate of this
attack is inversely proportional to the
strength of the password save a really
complex password you're gonna the more
complex that password the more you're
going to get diminishing returns
fortunately or unfortunately depending
on your perspective 2012 couple
researchers named Moxie Marlinspike and
David Holton came up with a
divide-and-conquer attack that can just
completely bury MS Chaffee - it turns
out that they discovered the MS Chaffee
2 uses it uses it basically it's
basically 3ds encryption so if you're
not familiar with what that means
3ds you can actually break it down into
a single des of encryption which is only
56 bits ntlm v1 actually has the same
problem and because you can reduce it to
this this this very very small 56 bits
of encryption you can actually recover
that pass for equivalent NT hash that we
mentioned earlier you know within 24
hours using that using a proper FPGA
based cracking rig with a 1 percent
success rate so it's very very very
crackable so just a quick demo of how
this attack works you know right right
now from the attackers perspective you'd
first create a cert which is what you're
seeing here and this is just a simple
self-signed cert and once you create
that certificate yeah
you then create the the the evil twin of
the network that you're targeting I'm
gonna kind of fast forward through that
a little bit and you're going to get a
client associating so here you see like
the the client associating with your
network and this is what you see on the
attackers perspective you know you'd see
the the username the challenge response
and that would all be sent to you as the
client device attempts to authenticate
with you you know from there the
dictionary attack what it would look
like using a asleep would be this the
the divide and conquer is a bit
complicated so I'm not really showing it
here but that's that's pretty much what
you'd see and you see we were able to
recover a password that way so the
mitigation for this was what's
introduced about ten years ago as well
this was in 2008 there was an RFC 5216 a
new form of EAP was released called EAP
TLS and EB EAP TLS uses mutual certain
certificate based authentication you
know for its outer authentication layer
so because of this this this this use of
client-side certificates it pretty much
stops rogue ap attacks dead in their
tracks that the problem with EAP TLS is
that it's also like really really
difficult to integrate any any network
administrators out there know network
administrators Wow okay so well from the
perspective of a network administrator
that the difficulty is that EAP TLS is
really can be really difficult to
implement you have to you know have an
internal CA that you set up you have to
have a certificate place on every single
device that you wanna be able to connect
to your network and and you know all of
this essentially creates a classic
security versus convenience scenario
where you're forced to to to choose
between an authentication mechanism
that's very very difficult to implement
or also or use a very insecure
authentication mechanism the form of EAP
P but P TLS so you know this creates a
market gap where you know products you
know that you have people essentially
the scripts of market gap for products
that can be used to compensate for the
security issues found at EPP you need to
be TLS but are also easy to employ and
easy to use I know so the current trend
that we see a lot is instead of focusing
on breach at prevention which would be
preventing you know attackers from
accessing the network in the first place
you instead see a focus on on containing
breaches that that occur once the
attacker is on the network and that's
what we're trying to address here is
whether or not this this strategy
actually works and before continue have
a little cartoon for you
okay it's a little let's read some
foreshadowing of what lies ahead so the
most popular way by far of addressing
the problem of breach containment is to
use an AK mechanism to distinguish
between you know authorized and
unauthorised endpoints as they're added
to the network so the idea here is a new
endpoint is added to the network
aka a new device connects to the
wireless network the nack identifies
whether this new endpoint is authorized
to be there or if it's not authorized to
be there if it's not authorized you know
some kind of restrictions placed on the
device usually place in a quarantine
VLAN where I can't really touch anything
there are two ways you know historically
we've had two ways of doing this you
have agent basin acts and you have agent
list necks so agent basin acts it's it's
the kind of the way that works is that
you have a software component called an
agent that's installed on every single
authorized endpoint on network and these
agents communicate with the brain of the
neck and report back information about
both the internals of the device as well
as you know external information as well
so this is really really effective
unfortunately now you you're in another
situation where you have to have a piece
of software living on every single
device on the network and this makes it
you know pretty much just as impractical
as eap-tls and on the other side the
spectrum you have agent listen acts
agent listen acts they use combinations
like passive fingerprinting active
scanning you know a traffic analysis
stuff like that and the idea here is is
to completely take a completely external
approach to identifying endpoints
however the problem with this is that
you have no way to identify the
internals or examine the internals of
network components so you can easily
bypass these just by finding an
authorized device to masquerade as so I
mean this kind of leads us back to the
same problem we looked at before you
have a recurring dilemma in security
versus in practicality you know you have
on one side the spectrum you have these
highly effective solutions in the form
of agent basin acts and also like very
easy deploy but also less than effective
solutions in the form of agent listen
acts so this leads to another market gap
right where there's a huge demand for a
solution that can offer deep
interrogation capabilities that you find
with like an agent based knack but
without all that additional overhead so
I mean this has led to the rise of the
next-generation neck these are actually
pretty interesting
there there are a lot of really
interesting solutions to them there's
there's one in mind that I thought was
like a really interesting approach but
also just at the same time really just
kind of drives the point home as to why
you know this this
isn't like an easy easy paradox to
bridge unfortunately no I actually tried
to I actually tried to borrow one from
work to bring here and do a demo with so
I opened up a ticket of course you know
that didn't really go as I probably
should've expected that but
interestingly enough also illegal kind
of reached out to me just like you you
got to keep this vendor neutral so I'm
like okay so in the interest of being
vendor neutral we're going to refer this
hardware vendor as vendor a and if
you're really curious I'm sure you can
find a bunch of products that kind of
match the description on Google but a
really good example this is vendor a
vendor a uses WMI to interrogate new
devices as they're added to the network
and and by doing this it's able to
perform those deep internal checks
without using an agent and you know the
way that does this is Anna Kate's over
SMB using a single administrative
service account so device it's added it
authenticates with the device using the
service account or attempts to and then
at that point once it's authenticated
with this device it uses some some
pretty deep administrative privileges to
look at the internals of the device and
examine how it works the problem with
this is it creates a single well anyone
anyone see a problem this yet yeah yeah
responder so you have a single point of
failure you have a device that's a you
know attendeth on okay authenticate with
everything that's added to the network
using the special service account and
this service account has access to
nearly everything on the network
typically it has DEA privileges actually
which is really scary so you have this
device that although it's able to do
these deep checks relatively easily it's
also sending god mode hashes to anything
that you add to the network so of course
you know the the first risk that comes
to mind is is using you know something
like impacted or responder to perform
S&B relay attacks where just add
something the network wait for this
thing to authenticate with you really
the authentication attempt is something
else and pivot into it and actually you
don't need a man in the middle there
because the nak applies is trying out
thank you with you of course you can
mitigate this fairly easily by enabling
SMB signing although it's worth
mentioning the s and B sign dates
usually it's disabled by default on
everything about the domain controller
but this doesn't really address the
issue of hashes being sent directly to
untrusted endpoints so I mean it's
interesting that this matter actually
offers a piece of software that you can
install on every single thing on the
network to kind of address this issue
this is starting to sound a lot like an
agent again
and considering that the chief selling
point of this thing is that no agent is
required I feel like we're back to
square one again
and you know once again I'm not really
like I you know I think I think you know
most I don't think that this particular
solution is like you know better or
worse than any of the other well what's
it called next generation acts out there
I just I think it's a really really good
example of how there really is no magic
bullet in this in the situation you
can't really always have security with
convenience and and especially when
you're talking about access control or
authorization or authentication I think
it's actually a total paradox so kind of
going back to wireless in general
another really interesting wireless
security control that you see a lot is
client isolation and Athiya you know the
idea behind client isolation is that you
prevent wireless devices from
communicating with one another you
usually use this as a security control
typical use case would be like an open
network like the hotel here for example
you may notice that you cannot ping
other laptops that are associated with
the network and there's a reason for
that the idea is to keep people from
attacking each other once they're on the
network so the way the 802 dot 11 is
supposed to work is that the AP is
supposed to mediate all communication on
the network right so in theory if this
guy down here that can you guys see my
mouse moving around cool in theory the
way that's supposed to work is if this
guy here is trying to communicate with
this guy the AP can just intercept the
packet and drop and say no you can't do
that but the problem with this is that
you know client isolation really is a
logical control is not a physical
control so back in 2005 the late Cedric
blancher awesome research from
forcellino longer with us he posed a
question how do you prevent radio
transceivers from communicating with one
another and the answer was you can't so
he introduced this tool called Wi-Fi tap
which was released by Cedric Blanchard
2005 later revived by Oliver Lavery of
Gotham digital science it's actually way
before my time but the idea is that why
fight actually Wi-Fi tap actually reads
packets from the victim to the AP using
a Wi-Fi interface in monitor mode and it
gives you a ton tap device that's
bridged to this modern mode interface
and lets you interact with that monitor
mode interface and what this allows you
to do it allows you to inject responses
to packets as if they came from the AP
so I mean this allows you to do two
things I mean one it actually lets you
interact with devices that are associate
up with a wireless network without
actually being associated with that
wireless network yourself and for
more it actually lets you bypass client
isolation and I think I cover this stuff
okay so there are some later tools that
do even more cool stuff so ayrton ng you
can do the same attack with WEP tkip ton
ng this is also part of the aircraft
suite you can you can inject you know
this pack injection stuff but with WPA 1
wpa2
there are some attacks that that
theoretical attacks anyways that really
have been implemented that theoretically
are able to you're able to do this with
wpa2
whole 196 comes to mind it's worth
mentioning that most of these are purely
theoretical and actually haven't
contested and are really up to
considerable debate but for the sake of
being thorough I just kind of throw them
in there but I mean here's a quick demo
of Wi-Fi tap in general if you look at
the top right we're actually going to
create an access point just using so
we've created here an open access point
with the SSID example Wi-Fi and we're
going to connect to it from our host
operating system this is a VM and this
is a second VM and this is our host
right here in the bottom right so we're
going to connect to example Wi-Fi from
our from our host operating system and
then if we go down here we're just going
to send a bunch of ICMP packets for us
and five ICMP packets to our AP from our
host operating system and you notice
that we send five ICMP packets and we
receive five responses that's expected
so now we're gonna do is we're going to
start up a modified version of Wi-Fi tap
called Wi-Fi ping which is actually a
really you know cool way of like
demonstrating how this works and what
Wi-Fi does is anytime it sees an ICMP
requests it injects an ICMP response and
and it so we're gonna do that from the
attackers virtual machine over here it
says this terminal you see here so we're
gonna start up Wi-Fi ping and Wi-Fi ping
is now running and we're going to once
again sent five ICMP packets but notice
that instead of receiving five ICMP
responses we see ten ICMP responses and
that's because we're injecting them over
from this thing and that just kind of
demonstrates you know just the very
simple
wireless client isolation bypass so food
for thought we've been you know so far
like I think a lot of the conversation
is really focused around you know
whether or not an app can be used to
stop direct attack from an attacker
who's gained access to a wireless
network but I you know what if we're
missing the point here
you know network access control isn't
the only problem when containing
wireless breaches you know if you think
about the role of nack in a wireless
network it's being used to prevent
attackers from accessing sensitive
resources after a breach occurs you know
so when an authorized endpoints detected
you take one of one of two possible
actions you know either it place the
endpoint in quarantine or you block the
port completely so what this is is that
when you're violating access control
policies you're causing the nack to
impose some kind of restriction in a
wired network that's the physical
restriction but in a wireless network
this can only be a logical restriction
as we just saw with with Wi-Fi tap more
than that later so I want you to imagine
a pretty typical scenario if you're if
you're incorporating the wireless into
you know your Red Team engagement or
your pen test right you're attacking the
wireless network and this here this
particular wireless network is is used
to access sensitive resources in other
words a legitimate user could get on
this wireless network and from there
access stuff like you know production
databases the domain controller
eventually have that kind of access it's
not just used as a straight pipe out to
the Internet so assume you've already
breached the perimeter unfortunately
you've been placed as the attacker on a
quarantine VLAN by the snack appliance
it's just kind of here's the neck here
you are on this quarantine VLAN over on
the restricted VLAN there's a bunch of
sensitive resource and that's ultimately
what you want to get access to because
you know if you can't get access to that
you really haven't demonstrated anything
in the first place fortunately for you
you know that you have at least one
victim device on this restrictive VLAN
because you would have had to have
compromised you would have had to use
the Rove AP attack against this victim
device in the first place to get
Radiesse credentials that would get you
onto this network so the question here
is how do we get out how do we get from
this quarantine VLAN over to this
restricted VLAN or over here where we
can actually get all the goodies like
sensitive resources so you know anybody
here every user spotter before okay yeah
everyone so for those of you who do not
know one we have to go over a couple
things that we're gonna like incorporate
into this attack that we're gonna use to
perform this this pivot we're talking
about the first is element RM betina's
poisoning so in case they're aware the
way that NetBIOS name resolution works
is that first you're gonna check the
look that when a computer tries to
resolve something using resolve a
hostname using a NetBIOS name
solution it first checks its local cash
if that doesn't work it's gonna check
its lmhosts file if that doesn't work
it's going to attempt to use local DNS
and if that fails we're gonna fall back
to two closely related protocols that
pretty much behave the same way element
RMB T&S and the way that that works is
element art meatiness is going to send a
broadcast request out to the entire
subnet so the way that does this if you
can think of two computers named Allison
Lee Roy Lee Rose a file server and Alice
wants to request a file from Lee Roy but
Alice does not know Leroy's IP Alice
will first attempt to work through those
first those those first NetBIOS name
resolution steps that we talked about
before but suppose that fails at this
point alice is gonna make a broadcast
request to the entire subnet using
element r mb t and s and every computer
on Alice's subnets going to receive this
request and what happens next really
depends on the honor system the ideas
that only Leroy will respond to this
broadcast request and and and provide
Alice with with an IP unfortunately you
know there's no honor among thieves you
know if we're an attacker and we're
around the subnet we can simply listen
for these broadcast requests and and and
respond to all of them and if Alice
receives two responses it's only the
first ones can be considered valid so
this creates a race condition that can
be exploited to trick Alice the victim
into sending traffic to the attacker so
quick timing pretty pretty widely widely
available tool called responder by
Laurence Joffe and you see here we have
a bunch of rogue servers here with an
HTTP server HTTP server SMB server these
are all listening for authentication
attempts and we have here our poisoners
we have our element RM between s
poisoners up there as well and they're
running and we have our victim machine
over on the right so the victim machine
is going to attempt to access it's gonna
attempt to map a non-existent share or
an SMB share our non-existent host right
and what that's going to do is because
the host doesn't actually exist it's
going to force the fallback to element R
and B T and s so allow us to attack it
so we put in this non-existent host name
as well as well as an SMB share and
there we hash is on the left because it
we were able to poison
requests and forces try to authenticate
with us so we're about 5% for a little
escape attempt here but there's
something else you have to cover as well
the other thing we need to cover is
redirect SMB so anybody familiar with
redirect SMB okay this guy obviously
obviously uses all the things cuz so
redirect SMB essentially the idea is
that you you force a victim to visit an
HTTP endpoint and this HTTP endpoint
corresponds to an HTTP server that you
control this HTTP server does one thing
and one thing only and that's redirect
all HTTP requests to an SMB share
because you can do that so what'll
happen is the the the victim will click
this link their browser will go to your
your your rogue HTTP server via rogue
HTTP server will redirect that browser
to an SMB share that you on a server
that you control the browser will then
be forced to authenticate with your
rogue SMB server and you get hashes that
way so this is pretty cool it also
requires social engineering because you
have to click if the force a user or
coerce the user some way to click this
link so this is we're gonna start
talking about new stuff the first thing
we tackle get introduced is the hostile
portal attack and it's essentially a
combination of the stuff we just talked
about and it's a means of kind of
leverage that the leveraging the stuff
to steal ad credit from wireless network
without network access so have you guys
seen something like this lately the
captive portal yeah they're pretty cool
right so a captive portal it's used to
restrict access to an open Wi-Fi network
and the way that they usually work is
that you know there was you know that
you typically have a specially
configured DNS server that's running
there was all resolves all DNS queries
to the captive portal and and also all
DNS traffic will be redirected to the
cafe traffic captive portal so that the
the user cannot just manually specify
their own DNS server in addition to that
if you really want be nasty you can also
redirect all HTTP traffic to the the
server that's that's hosting this
captive portal login page so the net
effect is no matter where you try to
navigate to you're just redirected to
this login page so a hostel portal tag
kind of expands on this right it's based
on the both the redirect s and B and
also like a captive portal technique and
it is that you first force a victim to
connect to you using rogue ap attack but
then what you do is you simply redirect
all HTTP traffic
to an SMB share on your machine and you
run a rogue SMB server in the background
so the what happens is that the user is
forced to connect to you but instead of
being redirected to a captive portal
there they're forced to redirect to your
rogue SMB server and what happens is
then they're forced authentic cute with
you and they give you hashes so that's
it's a really fast way to grab hashes in
addition in case that you know that they
just have to be idle at the time you can
also poison elvenar and every TNS in the
background so you can you can also
attack them that way as well
simultaneously so a quick demo of how
this would work we have here where this
is this machine here is our legitimate
network and our our victim is down low
in the bottom right and is associated
with this legitimate network this is an
open network we're going to talk about
how to do this with EAP people Network
syn a second but there's a couple more
steps involve it doing so and over here
we have the attacker the first thing the
attacker is going to do is use some D
off packets to force this victim to roam
over to the the attackers rogue access
point now the victim in the bottom right
is going to open up ie and the second
that this it tries to set start sending
HTTP traffic you end up with hashes
which is what you see here actually
really interesting thing about IE right
is that when you type stuff in the
address bar it doesn't autocomplete
thing which sends an HTTP request so
every time we type a new letter and here
we're actually receiving the hashes over
and over again so good job ie so yeah
when you you know in most cases we also
need to talk about how to do this with a
WPA EAP network because in order to kind
of tie this to the scenario we were
talking about addressing earlier we need
to be able to use this with networks
that use apt TLS or eep eep eep
this actually is significantly harder
because both of these use mschap e to as
an internal authentication mechanism and
you know what this means is what I mean
by mutual authentication mechanism eken
ism is that the radius server must
actually prove knowledge of the client
devices password for the internal
dedication attempt to succeed you know
so previously you know we were able to
demonstrate that you can force a victim
to associate with you an attempt to
authenticate with you right and it will
go through all the steps of the
authentication process to the point
where you actually have an MS happy to
challenge a response which you can crack
offline
to derive radius credentials
unfortunately what's gonna happen at the
very end of that process is that you as
the attacker you're you as the
authentication server need to then
authenticate back with the client and
demonstrate the client that you also
know the clients radius password and if
you can't do that the authentication
intent is gonna fail so I mean this is
something that we really need to
overcome because pretty much any
interesting rogue ap attack that you
want to do aside from simply stealing
radius credentials you're going to need
a full Association from those clients
that are connecting to you now there are
a couple ways of doing this the there
already exist I mean for weak rated
scree Angeles you can use something
called Auto crack and AD this is a
technique that was developed by Dominic
white and named de Villiers in the same
talk where they improved karma tax 2014
and that'll work for weak radius creds
for stronger radius creds remember that
we can crack Emma Chaffee to challenge
and responses relatively quickly so of
course you could just crack them offline
come back and finish the attack once you
have valid radius credentials let's talk
about both both of these so the very end
of the MS Chaffee to challenge
Emma's chavvy to authentication process
the victim is going to send a challenge
response by the way this overhears the
victim this overhears hostapd hopes to
hostapd is the is that is essentially
what you use as a radius server whenever
you're you're performing this kind of
attack so the first thing is gonna
happen the very end of the Emma Chaffee
to authentication process is that the
victim is going to send a challenge
response and that's the thing that you
used to crack the the radius creds to to
your radius server which is hostapd
hostapd at that point is going to
attempt to load the victim's password
from this thing called the EAP user
filing EAP user files essentially a
primitive database that's implemented
using a text file that has information
about you know you've different users
and how they can authenticate and you
know what their passwords are etcetera
so it's going to temp to load that
password and then from there it's going
to use that password to construct an
authentication response that is sent
along with the authentication success
method message to the victim of course
if you don't already have the user's
password or password hash or NT password
hashes I say you're not going to be able
to accurately construct this
authentication response so this this
part of the process here is going to
fail and they're not good and the
authentication attempts going to fail
so the way that you get around this
using auto crack and AD is auto crack
and AD the way that it works is that the
second you receive the challenge
response you actually modify hostapd so
that instead of immediately loading the
password from the AP user file you
instead shoot off the challenge
challenge and response off to a remote
cracking rig somewhere which presumably
is equipped to crack these passwords
relatively quickly so you've essentially
make an API call to your cracking rig
the cracking rig at this point cracks
these radius that limits a fee to
challenge a response to get an NT
password hash and then you just append
that that NT password hash or password
to the end of the EAP user file at that
point you continue with this with this
image a fee to authentication process by
loading the the newly appended password
from the EAP user file use it to
construct the authentication response
and send that with the authenticated
authentication success message off to
the victim so that can work with with
weak passwords and it could take
anywhere between a few seconds or it
could take a couple tries because really
boils down to can you crack it in time
before this authentication attempt times
out but for well it's a relatively weak
passwords this should work but you know
between like four or five tries for
stronger for stronger passwords for
stronger ADA's passwords you you you
aren't gonna be able to do this because
you're not going to crack it in time but
remember that the with the
divide-and-conquer technique you have a
24 hour maximum the amount of time if
you're using FPGA based hardware to
crack these to crack these credentials
so here's a demonstration of how you
just incorporate the the the auto crack
and add technique it looks a lot like
what we did before you know we first
forced the that's gonna take a couple
tries to force the the the victim over
here to associate with the attacker to
authenticate with the attacker and you
see here this time the the victim is
being you know prompted with this this
certificate warning because we've we've
given them an invalid certificate but
we've gotten them to associate with us
and as before the second they opened up
by e
HTTP traffic is sent we're able to
redirect that to our SMB server and we
get their hat their password hashes that
way so what this gets you is lost in
lots of ntlm hashes
get really similar results to what you
get with element Arnav 18s poisoning
there a few key advantages here for one
thing you don't need to reckon at work
action so you don't have to be like on
the network in order to do this the
other thing is that you're not limited
to just attacking a local subnet you get
everything that's connected to wireless
so that's that that's pretty important
and and and and most important it's not
a passive attack you're not waiting for
broadcasts or a request to appear on a
local subnet you're actually making this
happen so back to our scenario we can we
can use this technique that we just
talked about the hostile portal we could
build off of that too to do something
called an indirect Wireless pivot and
that's a way of using rogue ap attacks
to bypass port based access control
mechanisms so we mentioned here that
we're stuck on our quarantine VLAN and
we want to get over to this restricted
VLAN and be able to access these
sensitive resources here and we have a
victim device that that is on the
restricted VLAN as well and we have this
knack that is kind of preventing us from
doing that so the first step that we can
do we could first force these a rogue a
P attack well actually assume that we
have two network interfaces first of all
our first interface has an IP address on
this quarantine VLAN the second
interface is free to perform more
attacks so we're gonna use the second
wireless interface to force this victim
device over to our over to our own
network can we control using a rogue ap
attack at this point the particular
rogue ap attack we do is we'd use a
hostile portal attack and that would
allow us to redirect their HTTP traffic
to an SMB share that we control and that
as before we will demonstrate this this
will allow us to obtain their ntlm
hashes which we can crack offline right
at this point we continue attack where
we left off we might have to repeat the
step where we get them to connect to us
once we've cracked their ntlm hashes and
at this point we're able to use that
that access to place a time payload like
a scheduled task or something like that
on the victim
we then kill a rogue ap this allows the
victim to re associate with the wireless
network that they were on previously
now this victim despite the fact despite
the fact that we've we've exploited it
it is still an authorized device so the
nack mechanism here moves it to the
restricted VLAN at this point we rate we
wait for that that that scheduled attack
task to execute that gives us a reverse
shell to our interface that's honor on
the quarantine VLAN and allows us to
pivot on to the restorative VLAN through
the the authorized device so that's
that's a simple indirect wireless
but there's a better person doing this
if you can pull it off so suppose you
have two victims of Isis and an account
that can be used to access both you
could then force both of these devices
to associate with you and you know as
before you use the hostile portal to get
them to send you ntlm hashes at this
point though instead of simply capturing
hashes we're going to relay that
authentication attempt using SNP relay
attack from one victim to the other this
will allow you to instantaneously place
a time payload on on one of the victims
you let the the victims reassociate with
the target Network as before they're
moved back to the restrictive VLAN
because they're still authorized devices
and as before we wait for the reverse
shell so quick demo of what this would
look like we have two we have Leroy and
Jenkins our victim devices here
Leroy's in the top right Jenkins is in
the is in the top left here we have our
attacker anybody ever use Empire you
again so we have we have a Empire
instance running here remember using
Empire for to manage our payloads we're
going to be using impact it to do our
SMB relay attack and we're going to be
using a pamorah to do our Rove ap attack
and over here we have our legitimate
access point that these two the victim
devices are connected to and I'm gonna
come out fast for this so we have to
listener set up and we also have our SMB
sort relay server running there so we're
gonna start a recipe really it's really
servers the first thing we're gonna do
is we're gonna pass initial powershell
payload to our SMB relay server that's
gonna execute when we first perform the
SMB relay attack when they put when they
connect to us and then we're gonna start
a Pam or here and then you as before
we're gonna send some D off packets to
these two devices to get them to Rome
from from the legitimate access point
over to our rogue access point so we're
gonna do that really fast and it's kind
of lagging there but wait for it
there you go okay so that gets us one
device associated with us all right step
two we want to repeat that with the
second victim device Leeroy all right
now we have Leroy's associated with us
as well at this point we need to pull
off yes and B relay attack right so
we're going to to first start RS and B
well actually we're first going to need
to obtain the IP address of one of these
devices that's associated us output that
we see here copy it over to our SMB
relay server here and we're going to
paste it in there start the SMB relay
server now for demonstrative purposes
we're going to start we're going to
start generating some HTTP traffic on
one of these these target endpoints so
we do that here simply by just you know
typing stuff in the in the browser like
we saw before and you see some activity
there
that's the SMB relay server doing its
thing that performing SMB relay attack
and what you should see in about 40
seconds or so in Empire is an empire
agent connecting back to our Empire
instance and that will give us our
initial shell and there you go initial
agent from 10.0.0.0 now active we now
interact with that agent and at this
point we have if you look here I'm going
to actually fast forward a bit as you
can see here we now have NCI authority
system privileges on Jenkins which is
this this victim right here so at this
point both of these devices are still
associate with a rogue access point
attack but we've used an SMB relay
attacked to obtain a shell on this guy
right here on Jenkins so we're gonna use
that initial shell to place a scheduled
task on Jenkins that is going to connect
back to our first interface which is
currently associate with a target
network and it's going to do that after
you know like a set period of a few
minutes so we're gonna do that really
fast I'm gonna kind of speed through
that
and at that point now we we just we just
kill our rogue ap and you'll notice here
that in our and our legitimate AP that
the the victim devices are reso sheeting
with us so we've lost our initial shell
but and and and when these devices are
no longer directly connected to us
they're back on the target network and
now we just wait for the scheduled tasks
to execute the payload and connect back
to us so something really interesting
happened when I was actually recording
this demo video and in that I actually
you know forgot to do the thing in in in
VMware or you connect the virtual
network interface to your to your to
your box to the attacker machine so you
know initially what happen is that the
the the time payload or the amount of
that delay finished and I was like okay
so where's the you know where's the
shell I don't know what's going on here
and then I realized that I'd forgotten
to to connect a thing so I was
originally going to to refilm this and
restart the demo from scratch but
something really interesting happened
which is that you know it turns out I'd
actually set 120 retries on this agent
that to connect back so this thing would
120 times attempt to keep connecting
back to that listener so what ended up
happening was and if you can kind of see
here I'm gonna get to the point where I
reconnect it and you see here I hit the
back button oh yeah as soon as I did
that I just got the connection anyways
so I thought I'd leave that in there
because it was kind of cool and it kind
of you know at this point we actually
have as soon as I reconnect to the USB
interface you know within seconds I had
that that refers connection I thought
I'd leave that in there cuz it's kind of
cool and proves a point about you know
well-written malware and well-written
implants which is that you know even if
you can enter a situation where you
can't get a reverse connection
immediately you know you can still write
something that just keeps attempting to
in various ways until it finally
connects back to you so that's an
indirect wireless pivot I mean the
equivalent technique of doing this on a
wired network would be simply unplugging
an authorized device from from a switch
or something like that and then
connecting it unto a connecting it to a
hostile network on which you can attack
it and and and what this void Emin
straits is that port based access
controls you know that they rely on the
assumption that the physical layer can
be trusted in a wireless network on the
other hand
the means through which you can trust
the integrity the physical layer is wpa2
EAP so if you can't trust your EAP
implementation an attacker can freely
control the physical layer using rogue
access point attacks this kind of you
know makes the point of whether nak
works or not kind of moot because you
know if the attacker can control the
physical layer port based nak mechanisms
are actually rendered useless so what
this demonstrates is that port basin act
mechanisms they don't effectively
mitigate the risk presented by weak WPA
to implement EAP implementations and
also they demonstrate the ADI port based
and act mechanisms to a wireless network
it does not make the use of the apt TLS
or a PP any listen to any less
inappropriate if the networking
questions use to grant access to
sensitive information I'm gonna you know
before we kind of wrap this up I'm gonna
make like one last stitch kind of like
you know plug for EAP TLS which is that
it's it's actually not as bad as it used
to be I mean you can use group policy to
configure 802 dot 1 X on clients that
MIT that makes this a lot easier than it
used to be and your best option for
rolling out EAP TLS let's just use a
private CA and to leverage Active
Directory as much as possible to to
deploy EAP TLS if you're if you're
dealing with an MDM or I'm sorry if
you're dealing with a bring your own
device situation I mean you can just you
distribute that server server to clients
using either an MDM solution or a really
streamlined BYOD onboarding solution and
you can actually use let's encrypt for
that as well although it's worth
mentioning that even the folks that
let's encrypt have stated this as far
from the best option out there so just
to close this up just because wireless
and wired networks do not operate just
because they operate similarly at the
logical level and and that's you know it
on purpose right you know you don't want
to have to be able to observe the
differences between using Ethernet or a
wireless network when you're using the
network because that's kind of why we
have that layer of abstraction but just
because these things worked some early
at the logic level does not mean they
work the same way at the physical level
so as a community we should really
question whether it's truly a sound
business decision to neglect EAP TLS in
favor more reactive approach that
focuses on access control and threat
containment and finally last but not not
least most importantly actually the
needs for convenience and security are
often at odds with one another so
maintain a healthy skepticism towards
solutions that prom
both and that's it Thanks
any questions sure yeah yeah well
hostapd does actually which is the
radius server that you'd use to perform
the attack as for an individual radius
implementations they may not work that
way but I know hostapd uses the EPS or
file yeah so yeah you'd get you'd get a
prompt the user would get a prompt so
yeah well that's that's what you're
banking on the problem is that you're
placing you're placing the burden on to
the user to reject that that prompt and
you know with an organization of like
200 to 300 people I mean I don't know
man
think about your workplace do you trust
everyone not to click that prompt what's
up
true but that that rules out BYOD as
well what's up you would need that's a
good question
so effort for that particular attack you
would need the the necessary privileges
to one be able to access the device in
the first place you'd also have to have
at least like local admin on that device
because you'd need to be able to do
something like you know create a
schedule tasks to make that then connect
back to you in the first place so you
would need you know some level
administrative access in order to make
that work if you're
you could probably automate that using
the Empire API I have not done that but
it can be done
realistically though I mean you'd want
to automate it as fast as possible so I
mean that that's doing it like over like
a few minutes which is decent but of
course there's room for like taking it
beyond a proof of concept stage and
actually making it happen lightning fast
just ideally what you'd want something
else that's worth mentioning though you
know how we used to schedule tasks in
order to get the reverse shell to to
execute well that might not always be
the best way to do it because if you're
talking about like a realistic scenario
you'd want something that doesn't
necessarily touch disk so a better way
to do it
do this would actually be to have
something that lives completely in
memory and is maybe it's more
event-driven so it listens for like a
network change so it just is someone
logging or am i back on the network and
then it would shoot the the reverse
shell which doesn't have to be reversed
shell back to the first interface I mean
you could actually just do an outbound
connection it's something else you could
just have it autonomously start doing
enough situational awareness move see
I'm trying to figure out there a lot of
different ways of doing it but that's
just like an easy straightforward way to
just kind of explain it so that's kind
of why did it that way anything else
sure
if you have if you have certificates on
both ends that that mitigates this issue
that's the aptl s so that that's how you
the problem is that like people you know
organizations they they often tend to
balk at the idea of rolling outside like
that unfortunately but yeah that's
that's I think what I'm trying to push
for is using that more I've seen it
twice this past year which is not great
but actually the first time I saw it I
was this here I was thrilled actually
went up and shook the guy's hand because
I was like it's like someone's actually
doing this Wow
but then again remember I work primarily
with clients like in the finance sector
like in the North East corridor area so
it this may be different for like if
you're working like in medical or DoD
you might seem different statistics so
yeah that's just my own personal
experiences with that anyone else
No all right well thank you