thank you
um so I'm actually going to talk about
PHP exploits but the most important part
is it's binary exploits and these are
remote binary exploits so this is pretty
hard to do in PHP so that's why it's
pretty interesting I hope and I will
illustrate with like one zero day maybe
two if we have time but probably only
one
so a little bit about our company we are
a French offensive security company we
do a lot of stuff we have two technical
blogs first one is more about kerneland
system the other one is more about web
exploitation it's ambionics.io blog
well PHP and I have been filling with
PHP for most of my life I found quite a
few rces on many like 100 cms's super
Magento Symphony larva stuff like this
but I've also done binary exploitation
and why would you do binary expectation
on PHP well if there is no vulnerability
at some point you have to look into the
core and try and find vulnerabilities
there and there's one also another use
that is sandbox escapes so sunbox Escape
basically allows you to access to the
process running PHP so you're not
running PHP anymore you're running like
like a machine instructions and you have
access to the main process memory so
what can you do with this well generally
the worker that runs PHP is going to be
connected to a main process that will
run as root and so if you can find the
bug that allows you to access to the
worker process and then a bug that
allows you to talk to the main process
and get some kind of memory corruption
you might be able to get a local route
exploits such as the one that I found
like three years ago on Apache and
another one that is basically the same
on PHP fpm that allows you as well to
get Roots I am also the maintainer of
PHP GC sorry which is basically why so
serial but for PHP box
first a little bit of introduction for
the bugs that you can find in PHP
as you all know PHP security is pretty
approximative like this is actually true
I will let you figure out why it's a
hash and a float and it's true
there are a lot of bugs also that you
can find in a PHP bug tracker and they
are some of them are still in patch for
like 10 years the reason is they don't
really care if the bug is exploitable
only locally what they care about are
remote remotely exploitable bugs
so obviously we get a lot of sandbox
Escape bugs but we have also almost zero
remote exploit remote binary export box
so we will try and figure out why and
what we can look at in the php's code to
find bugs that you can explore remotely
so what kind of bugs can you find in
php1 PHP is a weekly type scripting
language so every time they use
something they have to type check it so
check the type of the Bible and then
reference it as well if something is
used at two places in PHP you have to
have a refund at two otherwise you might
delete it well when it's still being
used so you might have type confusion
box use after free box and it's pretty
easy to exploit locally because you're
just writing PHP code right so it's
basically the same as JavaScript Runner
bug you just write JavaScript and you
get
you can set them for your box so for
instance do some kind of e-passash Eep
layout then you can trigger your bug so
for instance create an object and then
trigger the buggy method on this subject
and then you can use the bug that is for
instance use the fact that the EP is
connected to I don't know get some kind
of read primitive or write primitive and
then you could get called execution from
this but this is all doable because you
are writing PHP code remotely you are
not writing PHP code you're just using
code from someone else
so obviously it gets pretty much harder
there's one very difficult thing with
this is that for each request PHP will
create a brand new if allocate your
input so get post cookies stuff like
this and then they will run the code
that you want to run and then it will
discard the Heap entirely so that means
that if you get some kind of bugs like
for instance used after free if you
don't exploit it in the same request
it's going to be gone forever so you
have to exploit everything in one
request so that's pretty hard there's
also the ID that
we are pretty Limited in size because
https won't allow you to send like
gigabytes of data usually and you also
have limited types you can attend
integers you can send floats you can
only send basically strings and arrays
um
there's also obviously since it's a
binary bug you have to beat aslr and Pi
a pi PSI and there's only one thing
going for us it is that crashes are
pretty much okay as I said generally PHP
you're gonna have a main process that
runs that runs as roots and workers if a
worker was crashing PHP would just
respawn it and this way you wouldn't
really care if you crush the process
when you are exploiting also that means
that if you get the aslr randomization
or the buy randomization from one worker
you're gonna have it for the other
workers as well
so to illustrate a little bit uh if you
have uh we will exploit uh generally
you're going to interact like tons of
times with the server you might set up
the memory first then get some kind of
leak then use this leak to set up the
memory again use another bug to uh
trigger a memory option and then use
this memory corruption in PHP one
request get a shell that's it
so to me it comes down to picking the
right targets you're not going to try
and look for any kind of function you
want a function that's going to be used
a function where you can control some
parameter usually and you're going to
find a function also that after you've
triggered a bug you can use the bug so
okay I got memory corruption what can I
do with it in the same request
so usually the best function for this is
unserialized which is php's
digitalization function it allows you to
interact with PHP several time in one
request for instance here I have an
array of filaments and in this array I
have an object which contains an
attribute it could contain like 50
attributes and then there is another
element that is string so you can easily
see that if you have access to
internalize as an attacker you can
create any kind of a player that you
want then create any kind of object then
trigger for instance the bug of on one
of these objects and then use the bug
afterwards with other array elements so
it comes down to as I said here interact
with PHP several times but only during
one request
so and cellulitis I mean it's pretty
well documented I won't talk about this
one
my idea was to use a database driver
functions when PHP connects to the
database it will First Connect and then
it will send several queries and then
the database is going to send the data
back so that's a way to interact with
PHP several times but only during one
request so that's pretty good for us so
that's a way to potentially have a
trigger so find a bug and then use the
bug by sending query results
so I actually released two bucks
um the first one I'm gonna talk about uh
way more the second one maybe if we have
time the second one doesn't matter too
much actually because I couldn't find
any uh known CMS or framework that was
using this function it's pretty old
sadly because it's actually a really
funny bug but it's useless so the first
one is more important it actually
happens when PHP sends its password to a
database and you you will get a buffer
overflow in the Eep and that will affect
basically any kind of database
management system such as admin or PHP
my admin any kind of share those thing
also utility you would get the bug here
so before we talk about the bugs I'm
going to have to explain a little bit
how it works in php's internals so don't
worry it's going to be really simple
we're going to talk about like only what
we need and actually PHP is not that
hard of an interpreter to understand the
allocator is really easy so it's going
to be I think a breeze for you to
understand
so obviously when you create a PHP
variable you have to store it as a c
variable
it is done using a Zeva structure so la
Luca talked a bit about it but that
value is simply a type so any pfp type
is possible array string object any kind
of simple type as well ins for instance
and then there is another structure that
actually defines the type so for Strings
you can have a Zen string arrays and
array etc etc well
um
usually when PHP is going to use the
variable it's going to always verify the
type before otherwise you might send a
wrong type and PHP is going to use it
instead and you might get a bug so it
uses it verifies the type and then if
they reference the internal object and
then uses the corresponding structure we
don't really care about that boss we're
gonna care about the string and then
arrays that's the only two thing that we
can send so that's pretty good for us we
cannot create objects by sending remote
requests that would be too easy so we
are only going to talk about these two
what you have to keep in mind is that
these two are generally going to be
allocated on the Eep which we're going
to talk about later but those advers are
not allocated on the if so we don't
really care about them
so first then string so this is actually
not really a structure but a header I
will explain why
um so the first thing that you get in
this structure is uh the GC which
contains the Rev count and some Flags
then you're going to have a hash value
we don't really care about this one then
the length of the string so if a string
has a length of 100 is going to be
stopped 100 and immediately after you
have the buffer of the Swing so it's not
the pointer to a buffer it's the buffer
straight up so when PHP allocates the
string well I'm gonna go here
um when tsp look at the string it will
just allocate enough size for these
three plus the size for the buffer and
then find a null byte right so it's not
a pointer to some other buffer somewhere
else in memory it's just straight up the
buffer
so obviously as an attacker what we care
about is exploiting the length if we can
change the length of a string
artificially well that means that PHP is
going to think that the string has a
different length that it really has so
if we can make PHP think that the string
is U is huge when PHP displays the
string is is going to actually display
things that come after the string in
memory so you might get a memory leak
the other thing that we care about is
the way to store PHP arrays so it's
basically the same as the python dict uh
basically a hash map we don't really
care about the structure too much it's a
pretty complex but what we care about is
the GC which is the same as in the Zen
swing first element is a GC then there's
the pointer to a key value purpose we
don't really care and then there's this
speed instructor it is a function
pointer so a c function pointer and it
is called every time you remove an
element from an array so here I have an
array with three elements if I unset the
first one it's going to go play this
tractor on this Z value set value that
contains one obviously as an attacker if
we can control this well that means that
when array gets destruct uh PD structure
is going to be called and if we can
control this we can basically do a stack
pivot or just execute any kind of
function so we we control PC so we might
get called execution from this
so now you have enough information to
understand a local PHP exploit it's very
simple
you use a bug to change the size of a
Zen swing this way the string is way
bigger than it should be then you simply
use PHP standard array notation on the
string to read or write memory so you
get basically read write over the whole
heap using one bug so it's pretty nice
and from this you can create lots of
xender rays so you just Spam the
creation of arrays and so in the mirror
way you're going to be able to see open
Destructor from the previous director
you can find the program's Base address
so Pi is useless and then you can
replace it with any kind of function you
want and get called execution from this
then if you want to execute the
structure you just have to unset the
array or unset an element in the array
and you get your execution super easy
but it's for local exploits there's
actually better ways to do this now but
that's like the simplest example on what
you can do with a local box so I chose
to explain this one instead
so to understand remote exploits however
we have to talk about the if so
a little bit
so the Eep you have two main functions
as usual one to allocate so I want like
n bytes you use email log it returns a
pointer to a chunk that is at least of
size n
and when you don't need the chunk
anymore you just go E3 and it just
removes it so how is it done in PHP well
um generally you're gonna have a heap of
two megabytes split in pages of orix
thousand so for
40086 in a decimal and that gives you
like five 512 pages on your Eep the
first page it contains if metadata so
you can't really use it but the rest is
used for storage and in a page you can
find chunks of the same size a chunk is
a fixed size memory region so a fixed
size buffer and it could be of size 8 16
24 etc etc up until 3772.
when you want to allocate more than 3072
bytes the buffer is going to be directly
stored on contiguous pages
so how does the allocation of the
allocation work it's very very easy for
each chunk of some size you have a
linked list that contains the chunks
that are free so for instance we have
been zero that contains chunks of size 8
being 1 for chunks of size 16
etc etc up until 3072. what happens when
we call E3 so we have a pointer that we
don't need anymore so how is PHP going
to put it in the right bin well it will
just find out which page the pointer is
in then deduce the chunk size from the
IP metadata you will read the metadata
and see what is the chunk size for this
page then it will just add the pointer
at the head of the corresponding bin
when we do email log PHP is going to do
the opposite for instance if we need 14
bytes it's going to pick a bin so the
bin is going to be bin 1 because it's 16
bytes it's gonna then take the first
element from the bin and return it right
fairly easy
evidently if there are no elements in
the bin PHP has to do something else PHP
has to find a page that is not used so
it will use the eat metadata to find the
page that is still not used and it will
create new free chunks in the page and
add them to the bin
so to illustrate a little bit on the
left we have the the Eep with the pages
and let's say for instance page 10
contains chunks of size of X100 and we
have this bin originally uh chunks of
size 0x100 are stored in B9
um so if we have this bin originally and
we free an element it's going to be put
at the beginning of the bin right and if
we allocate elements they're going to be
taken from the first uh elements of the
list so from the head that's it that's
how phpc works
so now you have enough to understand the
bug and how we can exploit it
so what is mysqlnd first mysqnd is php's
a client driver so this is the code that
is going to use to connect to the mySQL
database and run queries it's not using
any native MySQL stuff they all coded it
by themselves like it's been done by PHP
devs so evidently it's pretty horrible
and uh like there were so many bugs I
tried to fuzz it and it was like
permanently crashing I couldn't reach
anything useful so I was trying to patch
to patch the code to reach something
useful but I couldn't so I was like
it I'm gonna delete the code and that's
why I did so
the bag is simple when you connect to a
database with a clear text password so
sorry when you connect to database the
database can tell you he wants you to
authenticate with some method or some
other and it might ask you to
authenticate with your clear text
password so
the idea is that PHP has to send the
packet with a header which is a MySQL ND
adder and the password right the thing
is PHP on the allocate set of size for
the password
so the mng email log here is simply
malloc they try to allocate the side of
the password but they actually need the
size of the password plus this but they
don't so when they do the main copy
afterwards the main copy is going to
overflow or four bytes out of the buffer
so to exploit this you need to find a
way to make PHP connect to some kind of
database that you control effect
database the effect database is going to
ask for PHP for the clear text password
and then you send like huge a huge
string here and it will trigger the bug
so the target for today is going to be
adminer it's basically the same as php9
my admin sorry it's a way to manage your
databases generally the thing is like
some kind of system mean wants to use a
adminer because it wants to check his
database so it you plot it like on the
main on the Webroot and then he forgets
about it so what you have to do when you
do some kind of pen test on PHP just add
slash adminar.php and you might find one
and you might be able to expect this
back afterwards so this is the perfect
Target for us because we can force PHP
to connecting to a server that we
control with the username that we want
and obviously the password that we want
when we are connected afterwards admin
is able to run requests to import a
database stuff or export database stuff
so it's a perfect Target for us
so now what can we do with debug so we
need an allocation that is bigger than
one page because otherwise PHP won't
allocate or buffer but then afterwards
we can overflow of four bytes so we get
a four bytes overflow onto the next PHP
page
so
generally what you want to do is all
right structures that are already
existing but four bytes in Zen string or
then the array is useless because this
is only the Rev count you could exploit
this but it's really hard so my ID was
to Simply overwrite the next pointer of
a free chunk if a chunk is free that
means that it is in a bin so a free list
and so that means that it points to
another chunk so there is a pointer here
that you can partially override with
four bytes
so when you get to do this then you can
change the linked list of a bin so that
means that you can make the the bin
Point somewhere else if you can do this
that means that when you allocate you
can make PHP allocate somewhere else and
obviously that means so more for PHP
because you wouldn't be able normally to
do this
so how do we allocate well simply since
we are connecting to a server that we
control we can just send arbitrary query
results and so we send results that have
the same size as the chunks in the bin
and that allows us to allocate
um afterwards it's basically going to be
the same as before you try and find a
way to corrupt the length of a Zen
string and from this you might get color
execution as we'll see it's a little bit
harder but not too hot
so the thing is we can
trigger a bug it's simply by using
adminer and it will immediately connect
to the database and send the password
and so we get the buffer overflow and
then we can use the bug because we can
send arbitrary query results and
allocate whatever we want the thing is
we don't have like the Eep setup we
don't have the layout that we need to
exploit so how do we get the E player
that we need only using data that comes
before so that means HTTP input well
usually it can be it can be done pretty
easily as you all know you can send
strings to PHP like using the core
listing or post data but you can also
send arrays so you have arbitrary then
string or then the right creation before
the switch the script runs but there's
also one thing that is very very useful
it is that you can actually free some
value before it's being used to do so
you send the key a key twice and when
the second key comes in It's Gonna free
the first value here so that means that
you can before the script Branch
allocate anything on the Heap and then
free anything on the Heap not anything
but basically anything so generally that
means that you can do any kind of Eep
layout that you want so that's a perfect
setup before we trigger our back
quick example for you to understand the
rest if you want to create 100 chunks of
size 0x100 and we want to free one in
the middle so how do we do this well we
send strings of size Ox E7 why because
as I said before then swing has a header
size of ox18 because there are three
elements of of three keywords and one
final little bytes so if you do the
addition you you get actually 100 and so
you want a render chunks so you send an
array with 100 times Ox E7 strings of
size oxe7 and then afterwards you want
to free one in the middle so you just
redefine the array value here and that
works
so now what can we do we can set up the
hip using get them post which is nice we
can then trigger the bug by connecting
to A rod MySQL server and then we can
use the bug by sending arbitrary query
results to a PHP so that means other
than swing allocations so that means
that we might be able to control a free
list so we are pretty close to getting
close execution
there's one thing though we don't know
the eslr we don't know Pi so we could
maybe override some pointer but we don't
even know where we are pointing there's
a randomization in the addresses
so the first thing that we are going to
do is do a Eep setup that works well for
us so the IDE is that we are going to
have two empty pages here these pages
are going to receive afterwards the
buffer in which we will have the
Overflow so the buffer will overflow
into the Red Zone here and the Red Zone
contains three chunks that's exactly
what we wanted because we want to
overflow this a pointer to a next chunk
in addition to this
we want a huge region which is one
megabyte in size the ID is that we want
to override this with overflow and make
it Point here
this way we then can control completely
the free list and get some kind of uh
like region where we can do whatever we
want basically the problem with this is
that as I said before aslr so this is
completely random so how do we know that
we are indeed pointing here well
since huge is actually well huge uh we
don't really care about the lower bytes
what we care about first are those by
controlling this we can ensure that we
are pointing here
so it's only 4096 possibilities so
that's brute possible Right but there's
one thing how do we know that the
pointer that we corrupted is actually
pointing here well to do this we can try
every address twice
the first time we fill this region with
zeros
if we manage to override the pointer and
make it Point here we have this free
list okay so an address that we changed
pointing to nil so that's a valid free
list because new means no no elements so
when we allocate strings afterwards PHP
will not crash
if we actually fill the region with ffff
well the free list is going to look like
this and that means PHP will crash so we
test each of those twice once with zeros
here once with FF here and this way we
can have a different Behavior with the
same address so that means that we are
Indian pointing at the right position
well that's only like one and a half
bytes so we need a few more to beat aslr
uh there's nibos four and five we are
which are on the right here on the
address and to to find them out we can
simply apply dichotomy so on the top we
put zeros on the bottom FF and we just
do the export again does it crash if it
crashes it's on the bottom if it doesn't
it's on the top you repeat this and at
some point you are very like you are
very certain of where you points in this
memory region so that's really good
there's Global bite though which is byte
5 since we have an overflow of four
bytes we can't modify by five luckily
since we are pointing to a memory region
that we control we can fake a pointer
here and only have two 56 possibilities
to try and determine the last byte of
aslr
so we do this until we get no crash and
at some point we have beaten a SLR
completely and we control some free
lists so this is basically ideal exploit
conditions because now what we need to
do is simply create a free list that has
two chunks that overlap once we have
this we allocate the Chunk on the bottom
and then we allocate the Chunk on the
top since the Chunk on the top is bigger
than where it should it's going to
overflow into this chunk and this way
you're going to be able to change the
length of this trunk of this string if
we change the length of this string that
means that when PHP displays it it's
going to actually display the old memory
that comes afterwards and we get a heap
leak
well it's basically done at this point
because if you get a hip leak you can
create lots of arrays remotely using get
and post as I said before and that means
that when you get the Eep leak when you
view the data you're gonna find the
address of some bit Destructor if you
find the address of a pet instructor
that means that you have beaten Pi
because it actually points to the
program men's address
and since you have the program's main
address you can just change the
structure using again the free list that
you control so you might make a send
array on a Zen swing overlap as we did
for two Zen strings and this way you can
override the descriptor and if you can
avoid the restrictor you can change the
address of the function that is executed
when the array gets destroyed and the
array evidently gets destroyed after the
end of the request
so now you get code execution
you probably expect a demo now but
actually there was some kind of patch
that the exploits
so I actually wanted to report it after
like a few months and I realized like
like two days before PHP changed the
code responsible for Clear text
authentication it wasn't related to this
bug but they just wanted to add a null
byte at the end of the medical password
so my expert didn't work anymore
the idea which they exploit here is that
you have to control the last byte
because you won't bite 4 to be console
and if they have a new batch here well
by far by four sorry it's not controlled
anymore and so the expert doesn't work
which is actually a good thing because I
was pretty stupid with my first
exploitation you can do way better and
this is why I'm gonna show here
so
as I said you have a four bytes overflow
but the buffer that gets overflown from
is actually page aligned so if you
create a password which has the size Ox
2000 minus three and you add the four
bytes of overflow you actually get only
one byte of overflow on the next page so
you get a way better primitive a one
byte before buffer is really nice it's
basically a new Love by one uh in the if
uh obviously
we have to explore differently but we
are going to do this it's not too hard
um so the idea is the same as before we
want to overwrite a next pointer so that
we can control some kind of free list
and make it allocate wherever we want I
chose this chunk size is not too
important but for instance if you choose
chunk size of ox 100 every chunk is
going to be aligned with Ox 100 so
you're always going to have zero zero
zero zero zero zero and so your null
bytes of by one is absolutely absolutely
useless in here if you have write this
byte with the zero zero obviously it
doesn't change anything if we override
this one with zero zero it actually
points here so you have some kind of
circular pointering so it's a pretty
awful tool to debug and to to exploit
this one we actually have the same it
actually points to the first chunk here
this one we don't really care about this
one we care about so with this one if we
override with zero zero it will actually
point after this one but before this one
and it will actually overlap with this
one
so our idea here is to overwrite the
pointer that ends with one c0 and make
it actually point to one zero zero this
way it points right before 150 and we
can do the same expertise before the
same export as before is we have two
chunks that actually overlap so we
create a string in the first one and
then we create another string in the
second one and they will overlap so you
can control the header of the first one
so now it's a completely new exploit so
you have to keep in mind we don't have
aslr we don't have Pi anymore we're
starting we are starting from a scratch
so the ID
is to have basically the same if setup
but we don't need huge anymore we cannot
point to it so the green region is gone
and we instead of having a ox4 400 sorry
chunks we are actually using a chunks of
size Ox 70. so basically the same as
before not too hard to do
the problem is we are very interested in
this address here because we will
overflow one byte in this address so
this address really needs to be 1c0 if
it is 70 we're actually going to have a
circular one if it is e0 it's going to
be a circular pointering as well so we
don't want this we actually want this
one to be one c0 so we need to know what
Chunk we are overwriting right we have
sent lots of chunks and feed them all
but we want to know which Chunk we are
overwriting so to do this
basically set up before we do trial on
enter error so we we free every variable
that we send but one so if the variable
is here for instance
we will overflow of four bytes here and
PHP will crash when he wants to allocate
because the free list is
but here
if we actually have uh or or chunk that
is kept allocated on the top we will
overflow only in rev count and if we
overflow in your account it's gonna not
gonna break PHP so it's going to work so
that's a way of finding out which uh
pointer which Chunk we are overwriting
obviously you might suggest using
dichotomy the problem is that if you use
the economy you're going to send data of
different sizes if you send data
different sizes PHP is going to allocate
them differently if if they allocate it
differently all this is going to be
completely changed and you're going to
mess up everything here it's actually
like I'm saying this is easy but it's
actually hell like but at some point
when you have something that works it
usually works everywhere but before this
you have to basically do try on error
until it works out
um so now we have the chunk that we want
we didn't do too many requests to get it
so it's not that expensive and
now the ID is that we want c0 here 2.2
C4 because this is the address we want
to overwrite okay and before this we
actually want 150
to be allocated because once we have
overflow down this is going to be one
zero zero approximately here and then
it's going to overflow into this but to
referring to this we want to have this
already allocated
so that means that we have a free list
that first allocates this and then
allocates uh this and right after this
it's not too hard to do generally by
just sending get and post variables and
freeing them then allocating them again
you can get some kind of if setup that
is not too hard it's actually good
because we actually know the address of
uh well we know the last bytes of c0 so
we know the bytes of the others so it's
not too hard to do I won't take too much
to explain this one so this is the setup
phase now for new exploit we want this
kind of free list in PHP before we
connect to the database right and once
we have this we can trigger the bug so
one bytes before overflow this becomes
one zero zero now we have to change the
overlap
when we allocate this one is going to be
allocated first and then at some point
this one is going to be allocated and
we're going to have to change that
overlap
so now it's pretty easy to exploit it's
very close as before the different thing
though is that we need to beat aslr we
still haven't talked about aslr well in
here there should be a pointer to the
next chunk that is free well
the thing is since we have moved the
pointer that pointed here to here
in here you still have a dangling
pointer so when you do
the the corruption on the Zen swing what
you're going to see
is actually first a pointer to the next
chunk and using the pointer to an
exchange you can obviously deduce aslr
and so you don't care about ASL anymore
so then basically the same as before we
allocate we get effects and swing then
we get effects and array and we get the
address of the main program using the
restrictor which is always going to
point to the main program and so that
means because execution remotely uh
using an adminer
so now it's demo time hopefully it's
gonna work
sorry
10 seconds
10 seconds demo
one two
you need the mic you need the mic ah yes
right this is Amina there isn't the CSS
or anything because I just messed up the
setup but we don't recover but the CSS
do we and
I need to put what
I might help you
oh yeah but okay I need to to get this
going anyways
so
uh there's that media there's an exploit
the exploit is
very simple
so it looks for a chunk uh the thing
that we are overwriting then it will
leak memory uh
get the address of an array and then you
get code execution and to prove this I
created a file here on the right route
but I could do basically anything I have
access to the process memory
so I was too long ago time to finish
time to finish okay well whatever uh I
had the conclusion with basically PHP
sucks and you could fight bugs but uh
[Applause]
okay we we have time for one question be
lucky to the to be the guy to ask a
question
somebody raise your hand
s okay
so I will have a quick question what is
the impact of the exploit or many
systems can be asked do you think it's
dangerous whatever you think about that
take the mic please Charlie we found you
can find a lot of admin
instances and there are also other
things that are vulnerable that you
didn't talk about it but yeah yeah it's
it's pretty useful okay useful but you
have to have someone that up in
the beginning because adminar shouldn't
be on a website that is publicly
accessible okay
thank you so much some announcement
about flora and thanks again Charles