awesome thank you so much so hi
everybody thank you so much for coming
today today we're going to tell you a
little bit about the evolution of a
ransomware group from Darkseid to black
matter to Alpha
so I'm Lindsay K I'm senior director of
the advanced reversing malware
operations Eric Constance group The
Record future
um by trading my malware analyst or
reverse engineer hi I'm James Niven also
with the recorded future and I'm a
principal threat researcher and prior to
threat intelligence I was a red teamer
for offensive security and crowdstrike
So today we're going to discuss a
ransomware group and how they Rebrand
and change throughout their entire
history whether it be from law
enforcement pressure internal Fallout or
technical flaws in their lockers or
malware campaign along the way we'll see
how they can be tracked and what they
modify today we're going to be
discussing specifically darkseid's
transition to black matter and then a
more currently Alpha
so discovery of black matter well we
were in the right place of the right
time to kind of find them so dark sided
attacked Colonial pipeline in May May 6
2021 caused a lot of problems in the U.S
gas stations were shut down people were
trying to get gas
they had decryption issues uh earlier in
their Campaign which you could see on
the screenshot on the right uh
bitdefender found a decryption flaw in
their locker so dark side Isle of the
picture for now and there's only really
one Locker that has an esxi Locker
available and that's Revo so Revel takes
on most of their Affiliates and most of
the people associated with Darkseid at
the time so Revo had a similar downfall
where they attacked a Brazilian company
but has a large presence the U.S JBS
food groups and that caused a lot of
attention and eventually led to their
downfall as well so with Regal and dark
side out of the picture there was no
good Linux and esxi Locker for the
ransomware community to to have
so this is a screenshot from exploit and
exploit is a is one of the two primary
fun or primary forums where ransomware
operators and and uh malicious actors
will communicate is largely Russia it's
primarily russian-based there's English
speakers on there as well and on this
forum is where a lot of the negotiations
of uh selling tools buying things
joining programs goes and after the
Forum the initial communication on the
Forum it'll go through secondary
platforms such as telegram jabber talks
and other ways that they will
communicate so an interesting thing
about this screenshot is you can see
it's only one post from this actor the
way to mitigate or way to uh prove you
have reputation and you're actually in
this game is either reputation or your
Bitcoin deposit they've got a four
Bitcoin deposit with one post so he's
saying I'm serious and what he's asking
for are essentially
um Network accesses so your initial
access is whether it be vpns or RDP or
or any slew of those and he doesn't
actually say that they are talking about
ransomware or wanting you to join a
ransomware group because after the
attacks we talked about previously
darkseid's uh Colonial pipeline attack
ransomware or foreign administrators
really kind of clamp down on the use of
the word ransomware or any kind of
direct association with it on the forums
and fear that they would get shut down
as well
so once you get into the black matter
program this is the first thing you see
as an affiliate and it essentially
highlights the the goods and the the
goods of the program so in this
screenshot you can see they took a
notice from rivo Dark Side lockpit took
the best features of those improved on
it they're saying that they tested their
panel for all your web vulnerabilities
they tested their decrypter or so they
think
um they tested on the different versions
of Windows Linux es6i Nas
um later on different different os's
and it's essentially the saying this is
why you chose our program
so on the left you can see the
screenshot of darkseid's panel this and
on the right is black matter and this
panel is kind of the home home page for
a ransomware operator there's a lot of
places you can navigate from this panel
but the some of the most interesting
ones are you can go talk to the victim
directly you can change prices in
Bitcoin or enable Monero you can
send notes to an administrator of the
ransomware group to say I don't want to
talk to this victim or I need extra help
to talk to this victim and a multitude
of other things and the most interesting
one I think everyone's interested is in
the ability to build the malware itself
in the top middle screenshot or the
screenshot you can see the ability to
generate exe elf uh Powershell and and
other builds of the ransomware and with
that I'll hand it over to Lindsay to
kind of go into the malware itself
awesome thank you James so at the outset
of our work on this we got access to two
variants so one for Windows and one
targeting Linux and esxi you can see an
example of the windows Ransom note on
the top right just to give you an idea
what that looks like so the windows
ransomware actually had several
different anti-reverse engineering and
anti-analysis capabilities so nothing
you know wildly insurmountable but
definitely more than nothing
comparatively the Linux and es6i1 was
substantially more straightforward to
reverse engineer so it included things
like function names which you can see a
couple of examples so those of you who
do reverse engineering this is like gold
right so you can see all the function
names kind of what everything does makes
it extremely easy and it contained the
configuration file with a bunch of
information about like configuration
values of malware in a DI obfuscated
format which also much easier
so a couple of these techniques however
actually made the malware somewhat more
signature and easy to track which if
you're a threat researcher this is also
great so the cryptographic routines that
they use to actually encrypt the
victim's files we'll talk a little bit
more about those later but the
combination was somewhat unique
um the string obfuscation mechanism so
generally ransomware will have encrypted
or obfuscated strings in some way and
generally what you see is that the
mechanism that they use is fairly unique
to the family or variant
um black matter was no exception it was
extremely simple so you can see an
example of this kind of first round of
the string obfuscation magnet I guess
the obfuscation function in the top
right we'll dive more into that key
initialization function soon
additionally the function call
obfuscation so this wasn't something
that I had seen before
um so a normal function call you can see
on the bottom but what black matter did
was they made static reverse engineering
a little bit more complicated so instead
of just kind of doing a call directly to
the address what they did was they took
a magic number so 22065 fed and then
export it with another value and then
would jump to that address so when
you're statically reverse engineering it
you kind of have to figure out like okay
where in memory is everything which
makes it a little bit slower
um Dynamic much easier
um and kind of on this subject are the
magic numbers so each build had its own
magic number in this first build it was
22065 fed and it made several different
appearances throughout the code
so we released a report containing a
string decrypter and sumiara rules for
both versions and then magically new
versions of the ransomware started
appearing specifically the windows
ransomware so some of them had very
simple changes so that magic X or k
varied per build and then others had
very substantially more complex features
so things like new features and other
changes we'll talk about so you can see
an example of that key initialization
function from that first version
numbered 1.2 extremely simple in
subsequent versions they made the string
decryption substantially more
complicated so you can see an example of
how that function evolved in subsequent
versions
ultimately during the time that black
matter was active we never did see
another Linux or esxi build not entirely
sure why there you go
and then ultimately over the several
months that they were active they
released six different versions so
numbered between 1.2 and 3.0 of their
malware between July and September
so let's talk about a couple of the
future editions that we observed during
these summer months so first one of them
is printing the note on Ransom note on
local printers so other than like the
entertainment factor of seeing Ransom
note kind of spit out from your office's
printer one of the things that companies
want to do when they get attacked by
ransomware is keep it extremely quiet so
it's much harder to ignore these rants
notes coming out of printers than it is
to have you know somebody with you know
a ransom note on their screen so this
draws attention of the employees and I
mean it's also somewhat entertaining for
the actor I'm sure
adding the addition to encrypt
additional file types so specifically
some of the Microsoft Exchange files
which we'll look at soon so as you can
imagine attracting Affiliates to the
ransomware program it's a business right
so being able to support as many
different type types of file encrypt as
many things as you can do as much damage
is something that the program wants to
be able to do
next um you can see an example of the
Builder on the right so the black matter
affiliate panel and what this allows you
to do is when you build a copy of the
ransomware that you will later deploy
you can choose different configuration
values so one of the things that they
added eventually was the ability to
identify specific computers not to
encrypt
then the implementation of their
cryptographic algorithm did evolve over
time so how they were actually
encrypting the files and then the
ability to check for large files and
encrypt them differently so when you
want to encrypt everybody's stuff you
want to do it as fast as possible before
the system administrators and the
Defenders figure out what you're doing
and are able to stop it so as you can
imagine large files take a longer time
to encrypt so what you want to do is be
able to speed that up however you can so
they'll do things like sometimes we see
villain encrypt the first I guess couple
megabytes of the file or they'll
incrementally encrypt but that is
definitely a feature that they did add
over time oh
so let's look at a couple of some of
these features and how they evolved over
time so on the left what you can see is
an example of the first version of their
printer function so effectively what it
does is it looks for the printer on the
system and if it is not the PDF virtual
printer it'll print
so over time in starting in version 2.0
and above they added a couple of other
printers to also ignore so other virtual
printers that you may be familiar with
so sharfax filex PS port and Port prompt
and one thing I want to point out is
unlike the word PDF and ASCII you're not
seeing any of those file names so
another thing that they did was they
have a fairly custom kind of string
hatching algorithm so
effectively what it does is it will take
a hash of the printer that it's looking
at and then compare it to any of those
known hashes and if it's one of those
does not print to it so this was
something that I guess it just makes
reverse engineering a little bit more
complicated nothing is surmountable but
um it also is something that we'll talk
a little bit about
um other appearances of it later
so looking at the ability to the add the
exchange files you can see on the left
so here's part of the function where it
looks for and traverses the Microsoft
Exchange file path
um to start finding kind of where all
those files are if they're on the system
and what you might also notice is that
you don't actually see the strings
um you can see I've made a comment of
what they actually are but here's
another appearance of that magical x-ray
value so pretty simple like stack string
going on and xor with a magical value
here and then just makes reverse
engineering again a little more
complicated
um then on the right you can see it also
looking for the large file check so it's
looking for a couple different file
extensions so mbb MDF edu and accdb and
then it will handle the encryption of
those files differently
so again here is another appearance of
that string hashing algorithm just to
make it more complicated
so some researchers at nzsoft came out
saying that one thing that they've
noticed is that previously a group
called Darkseid had a fairly unique
combination of encryption algorithms for
encrypting files and what they noticed
is that this custom salsa 20 Matrix
was something that previously they had
only seen unique to dark side now is
making an appearance in black matter
so let's look at what this looks like so
you can see a couple screenshots of both
of these so on the top you can see the
random buffer initialization function
followed by the RSA 1024 encryption that
was used by Darkside and then on the
bottom you can see black matters
implementation of that same thing so
this is kind of what they were talking
about and then you can see
how they implemented that random buffer
initialization so
I guess effectively they are different
and how they did it but the Salient
point is the same so that was kind of
interesting
so MZ soft also found another fun and
exciting feature so remember that James
had noted that Darkseid previously had
decryption issues so one of the things
that they noticed is that for some
versions of the black matter ransomware
there was another decryption issue here
so the issue was that victims did not
have to pay for the key in order to have
their files decrypted so MZ soft in the
background was reaching out to these
victims helping them decrypt their files
so they don't have to pay the ransom
so after some time this came to light
and the threat actor found out and then
they fixed that specific issue sometime
around September 21 2021 so can't really
speak to this specific issue with
cryptographic code but you can
definitely see some slight changes in
the key initialization code and some of
the actual crypto code itself over the
different versions so
um while it's
well it's not necessarily like I guess
the specific issue is the thing it's
kind of interesting to notice that it
did evolve over time so you can see a
couple of different examples there
and with that I'm going to hand it over
to James tell you about their downfall
so as we've talked dark side now black
miter have decryption issues with their
locker this specific chat was a large
agricultural firm and if you read the
chat I I suggest you do there's some
interesting things there
um you'll there's essentially the sisa
was involved in the background MZ soft
was involved in the background other
firms and everything were there and
after this the the chat kind of went
downhill very fast and there was a bunch
of either security researchers other
actors who know who's who it was but if
you had the URL to this chat you could
join in the chat and have fun and fun
happened and then after this dark side
or black matter kind of shut this chat
down talk to the victim specifically and
said here's the new URL for your chat
and then with that they had to put the
victim had to put in the domain
controller names the domain admins and
chat access codes and we'll discuss the
chat access codes in more detail later
so decryption issues chat hijacking
losing millions of dollars by decrypting
behind the scenes with the victims black
matter was kind of fed up so they said
we're going to shut it down and they
claimed it was due to law enforcement
pressure and 48 hours after this post
they turned the infrastructure off and
handed out the keys for Affiliates to
give to the victims or do the
negotiations elsewhere
so it sounds like it's over for black
matter not quite one of our colleagues
did an interview with a a new
up-and-coming group called Alpha and in
this part of the interview you'll notice
that Alpha is is answering a question
about the chat hijacking and also the
decryption issues so that's interesting
and it's it's wondering why they're
talking about this thing specifically so
Affiliates had moved from black matter
to now Alpha and we'll talk about Alpha
here in a few
so if you're trying to go into the alpha
program you essentially would reach out
as we saw earlier that black matter post
on exploit you would do the same thing
and they would say here's the rules so
here's what our locker does here's how
much you get paid you can get starting
out eighty percent you do a lot of
victims you get 90 percent and and those
kind of things what our locker has these
exci functionality Nas Synology Linux
windows and each one of these things
they kind of point out a a group that
they're saying what they did better for
and the one on the bottom right is the
one that's kind of we're going to key in
on so they say hello Dark Side about
this and this is essentially saying that
people that have access to virustotal
can download the decrypt or download the
the locker as the victim posted run it
and get the ransom note and then jump
into the chat and monitor it and that's
essentially how you would monitor those
chats and figure out who the victim was
and that's where the access codes come
into play
so a way to await black matter and Alpha
kind of advertise to different people
how to get into the program where the
program exists is through a jabber
service
um on exploit and essentially you pay a
few hundred dollars and you can have
exploit broadcast this message to every
single user on the server and what this
message says is we have Linux es6i
capabilities we have a talks ID or talk
about the specific percentages your get
and also the jabber ID and the thread
that's kind of for the recruiting thread
so once you get into the alpha program
as you saw previously it's a it's a new
panel this panel will kind of highlight
and regurgitate what I just said about
the the esxi and the the percentages
and what's new about Alpha so with their
decryption issues they kind of said we
are really messing up somewhere and we
think it's our our develop our locker
developers so they scratched them and
they've found somebody else to develop
their locker and they completely rewrote
their Locker in Rust they completely
redid their panel and you can see it's
very different visually and they
implemented this access code so the way
they did this was essentially there's an
access key that's required to run beside
the locker itself the threat actor will
run the locker.exe and then enter this
access code and this access code
generates the correct landing page and
you'll see in the top screenshot that's
the note the victim would have and the
bottom screenshot is the the one the
affiliate would have so that he can
enter the right code this uh
ransomware group also has better support
so it's quicker to talk to an admin to
file bugs or just ask for help for
negotiations has a built-in Bitcoin
mixer and it has a new feature that
Lindsay's going to discuss here in a
second that allows you to obfuscate your
ransomware better
cool so the way that Alpha Morph uh the
service for obvious getting your
ransomware was advertised at the outset
was it helps you evade AV detection so
there really is no great AV for Linux so
I was very curious to see what exactly
this intake and they promised a couple
things so obfuscated strings as well as
a lot of garbage code insertion so
looking at the ransomware with the morph
obfuscation applied I didn't see any
actual string obfuscation but there were
a couple of interesting things that I
noticed in the 64-bit morph obfuscated
samples so previously what they had was
no function names they had removed them
but what it now seemed to have is if
you're familiar with name angling what
appeared to be now name mangled versions
of the original function names versus
the unobfuscated ones with the scrub
names so you can see on the right a
couple examples of what these uh name
angle looking function names look like
so you can very clearly see the word
Locker so for the ransomware in these
and in the x86 samples you can see a
couple of these kind of like similar
I guess they mangled versions of the
exported x80 of the exported variable
names so that was particularly
interesting and on the left what you can
see is what it was before the morph
obfuscation happened so does not
entirely sure what the point of that was
um but eventually they actually
abandoned this so now they only have a
Windows version
speaking of the windows version so as
promised there were actually obfuscated
strings now in the windows ransomware it
was extremely simple though it was a
random one bite xor using these randomly
generated functions to decode them so
you can see an example
um on the left of what this looked like
so you can see the obvious created
string and then the obvious the
de-obfuscation function so really the
only Salient point of this function with
the garbage code inserted is the X
worrying of each byte with the value 8
and the fact that it's a loop so um just
gives you kind of an example of what the
random garbage code insertion looks like
and we'll look at two versions compared
to each other as well
so one thing was that so first of all
these rust builds were extremely big of
the ransomware so they were the
unobfuscated ones are about three Megs
each now with the obfuscation apply
they're about 14. so over four times
bigger and the largest increases that we
saw were in the text data and relocation
sections so you can kind of see there
what that looks like
so comparing two versions of morph
obfuscated Windows ransomware you can as
a human very clearly see that these are
the same code
um what the garbage code insertion
really does appear to be is a bunch of
global values where they do random
mathematical operations on them
um doesn't have any actual effect on how
the code functions or really how
anything works but this just kind of
gives you an example of what they mean
by that garbage code insertion obviously
as a human this doesn't really make it
much harder
not really sure how well it really also
helps you evade AV in long term
so the story continues the cat and mouse
game has existed for years and it will
continue to exist for forever
um this three shot in the top left is
curb Zone security article
um alluding to this specific person on
GitHub being the developer of the new
Russ ransomware the screenshot on the
right is uh FBI and C sub both release
iocs and ttps associated with with Alpha
and the most interesting one on this
deck is uh the bottom one so this is
from Conti's blog and what they're
saying here is that Conti or the alpha
and lock bit are scammers more or less
and what they mean by that is as we
talked about the ability for an
affiliate to reach out to administrator
or someone else to handle the
negotiation they're saying that as we
saw with Regal that the administrators
would take over an Affiliates chat so
essentially if you're the victim and you
wanted to get decrypted you could jump
into this chat say I need I want to pay
but the administrators of the rats would
take that and move it to another chat so
the affiliate would would not see any
communication while they handled on the
side and got all the money from it so
with that we appreciate you attending
our talk and if there's any questions
Now's the Time
so we got time for a couple of questions
uh I know there are questions on Discord
if someone can relate them to me that
would be perfect
at least I I will start with one
question at the beginning of your talk
uh you mentioned the colonial pipeline
attack or incident and I think it was in
Europe are not necessarily
aware of that incident or that much
aware would you mind just putting
explain it a bit what happened at that
time yeah so it's essentially a large
pipeline that's it runs across America
that handles all the gas and it was
brought to the news and everybody that
saw the the regular everyday news didn't
unders they may not understand what
ransomware is but they know that their
their gas could be affected so
essentially everybody went to go get gas
and started filling up plastic bags or
whatever else to get gas because they
thought that well it did it kind of
halted that that pipeline's ability to
move gas
uh do we have any okay I'm coming up
[Music]
okay thank you for your talk
what's up with them today are they still
active yeah yeah they're they're alive
and thriving as you could say and they
didn't Rebrand or anything they're right
now they're Alpha okay
thank you some of the Affiliates from
black matter and dark side whatever they
want to call them they move they're
they're interspersed throughout when
when Black matter was down some of them
went to concier some of the more current
ones so
but the core people are still there
any other question
I think there might be some disown
Discord I guess
do I have them over there I'm sorry
uh
if someone could relate them to me in
case I don't have them right now
um okay so we're gonna be thank you
again for coming over and uh thank you
for that talk
[Applause]