uh well hello my name is Sarah
melbaghawi and I'm an offensive
developer at Hexum but this doesn't
matter much because we're going to talk
about fighting games
um so this product is for all the
fighting games nerds and mechanical
keyboard fans as you'll see
first off
there are common fight scene controller
issues so like you know your average
artistic or your mix Box Etc
the Pokemon point is they're all bulky
they're very bulky and they're very hard
to carry if you are restricted on space
like you have a small bag or something
like that and with the case of lever
Architects uh they're too too noisy I
got yelled at for that
so I won't choose one again
and mix boxes are like better in some
way because they do less noise but
they're way too bulky and that's also an
issue when you want it to be portable
and maybe carry it at events Etc you
won't have to prepare a single luggage
for that
so I found the fightboard MX that's made
by one single guy and he'll say he sells
it on Etsy it's a very great controller
don't get me wrong but it has some cons
like it's very expensive you have to pay
170 Euros to get a chip to France and in
a complete State because you can buy it
without switches and keycaps
uh it's uh it uses a closed firmware
made by the same guy and uh you don't
have access to the 3D models and PCB
and it also uses a kind of wimpy
microcontroller it's a derivative of the
Arduino micro if I'm correct
so not good I mean it's good but not on
this point
so I made this one uh actually but the
one you see on the picture is the first
prototype that I've made
um as a software developer I've learned
a lot with electronics doing that and it
uses a Raspberry Pi Pico and an open
source firmware the gp24c Community
Edition firmware you can make it by
yourself because all of the files are
available on GitHub uh it means like you
have the Gerber files all the PCB files
basically the casing and also the
firmware so you can build one yourself
and I'll also create an Etsy shop but it
will be way cheaper than the fightboard
MX because I don't see why it's so
expensive
and that's the end