with that said i
am very very excited to actually be uh
introducing our next speaker
i'm excited to be introducing her for a
couple of reasons number one she's
someone who i used to call
a colleague and that is a good thing uh
she's actually still at this
organization we used to work together
we've worked investigations together and
i've had the privilege of being on the
phone with
very very important people asking very
demanding questions and
my being able to say my colleague mary
here has the answer to that and that was
a
good highlight of my career for a period
in time um
mary's also someone who interestingly
enough i
i keep running into at uh interesting
locations
so um i ran into mary at a conference in
arizona
last year uh we run into a lot of sans
events and that kind of stuff
and then there's just times where things
pop up and i'll be like
i think that's mary and i will end up
saying hey and seeing what's going on so
it's
one of those awesome um sans folks who
i have the wonderful privilege of
calling a friend calling a colleague
having done work with and i also have to
add in that when it comes to
research mary is by far a
very very formidable force she
does not let any topic of interest go
unresearched
unfounded and undocumented and some of
mary's blog post which i highly
recommend a lot of you check out
and this is kind of setting the stage
for what i'm expecting from today's talk
uh are just so in-depth and informative
that you walk away from that being like
i didn't expect to learn this much but
oh my gosh i need to go
and research like this person does so
with that said we're going to go ahead
and marry i'm going to go ahead and get
you started feel free to take as much
time as you'd like
no worries we do have a break schedule
right after this so if you run a little
bit over we've got room
if you finish right on time that's fine
not a problem at all but without further
ado ladies and gentlemen when scp yeah
you know me
i i wanted to be careful about how
excited i got about this title because i
really wanted to you know
shout it out in the way it should be
pronounced um mary degrazia from another
forensics blog
mary glad to have you here ah thank you
so much matt and today i am so excited
to be talking about when scp yeah you
know me
and today we're gonna go ahead and do
this in the theme of the 90s right
2020 has been crazy so i just kind of
wanted to look back
on to a fonder time in my life the uh
90s and ah yes the 90s who
who doesn't love the 90s so one of these
pictures
is me i'm looking at my my hallway now
so
if you have an idea or you think you
might know which one of these uh
permed 90s is me um
take a guess and i will let you know a
little bit of background information
about myself i'm an associate managing
director
at troll cyber security and there i work
a lot
of you know digital forensics and
incident response cases
i've been in the it industry now for
about
20 years and then specializing in defer
for about the last
10. i'm also a science instructor where
i
get to teach windows forensic analysis
so i see
we have ones ones okay guess what i'm
actually number two
uh that was my prom picture just totally
rocking
the 90s hair uh number one i have no
idea who that is random person on the
internet when you google you know 90s
permed hair and number three this is
actually someone
from one of my favorite movies legally
blonde
okay so moving on in to
win scp so when we think about networks
getting compromised and attackers moving
throughout the
environment what we see a lot of times
is the usage of rdp
so with rdp you know
we get a lot of really cool artifacts we
get event log
entries the terminal services local
session
manager event log ids like 21 letting us
know there was
a log in we get the 4624 entries
type 10. when we think about lateral
movement in the environment and we want
to know what an attacker has
done what you know folders have they
accessed where have they
traversed throughout the environment we
have artifacts like shelby's
shell banks can show us you know what
they may have access while they were on
that system we can get things like
link files and jump lists all these
things
go towards helping us determine lateral
movements so any guesses on what a
movie this is from i think it's a little
bit before the 90s but i just felt like
you know we had to give a shout out to
this
one of the reasons i really like this
scene
in war games is they actually kind of
get in through this obscure
back door and it's not actually right to
the main uh system it's like this old
system they kind of forgot about and i'm
like wow
uh watching this many many years later
i'm like that actually rings
really true to home the same techniques
they were using you know back in the 80s
uh is still something that we see to
date which i thought was kind of cool
so but we're not talking about rdp today
we are talking about
when scp so with win scp
i'm going to focus on the portable
version of winscp
now if you go to the download page for
winscp
the first program you're going to
encounter is you know the windows
installer with the windows installer we
get some registry entries where it
stores information
but what we're seeing at pool and what
i'm seeing in my investigations
is when scp portable so with the
portable version you know they just
download a zip file and everything
is unzipped and it's contained right
there so it's not
making entries in uh you know the
typical program files directory
it's not storing its entries in the
registry it's in a different location
which we'll talk about
in a little bit so what is when scp
how is it different than rdp so when a
cp
uses ssh to make the connections okay
and when it does this it gives a little
bit of a different interface
when we think about rdp you know you're
logging in
to essentially the user's desktop your
presenter
their desktop whatever it looks like and
interacting with it and just like you're
almost sitting down in front of the
computer
well when a cp gives the attacker an
ability
to browse folders on a remote system now
this remote system
can be one that's inside the network or
it could be one that is
external so we have two different uh
tracks that we're going here when we
think about an
attacker connecting externally this is
going to
be where we start thinking about data
exfiltration
when we think about internally we start
to think about
lateral movement within the environment
very similar to rdp
some things that they can do with when
scp might surprise you too
right here we have a find files so they
can
actually use winscp to run searches now
traditionally if we think about an
attacker using
rdp to run searches they'll be using the
windows
interface to do this so we get entries
like the word
wheel query where we can see what
searches they've run
but if they start running their searches
through when scp
we lose that visibility because they're
outside
of that windows framework if you will
they also have the ability to download
files so right here you know
if they find a folder they like they can
download that onto
the host system or they can go the other
way so exfiltration
you know they can take data from that
system and pass it on
out to an external system
um so now we start thinking they're
using winscp
they're not interacting with the windows
explorer
shell which means we lose shell banks
we also lose that 4624 event id
10 because they're not connecting in
through rdp and
um you know the local session uh
managers well
we're losing those terminal services
entries so
um so now we think about this mechanism
where the attackers
can move laterally throughout the
environment using one scp
so you might be thinking hey well with
rdp the reason why they're using rdp
is because it's built in natively to
the windows operating system but
you know with win scp now they have to
set up a client to
receive those connections and guess what
um starting with windows uh we now
uh have basically an ssh
client that can be installed on the
system
with one simple powershell command line
so when we work our cases and especially
when we talk about ransomware cases
we see something that attackers are
using called
and i like to call them prepper scripts
um they can be power shell scripts they
can be
batch files but basically they kind of
get the environment
ready to push out ransomware and one of
the things that these prepper scripts do
um so the update was windows 10 1809
which i believe
was the fall the fall edition
um when this was pushed out
so with this version uh basically you
can run this powershell command
and boom you get an open ssh server and
what uh this can be done now said in
these prepper scripts instead of
um pushing out or opening up rdp and
enabling the firewall rule
and now you can just use the powershell
command and you can
instantly install this ssh server there
are two things in the background that
windows does
when you install it this way one it
automatically does the firewall rule two
it
automatically adds in an open ssh user
uh so this makes it relatively easy to
set up
an ssh client within the environment
very similar to how we've seen rdp
in the past once that's been done they
just start up the service and
bonus points that they want to throw to
set
service and let's start up automatically
so you know
it can certify the reboot so you know
one line to get that client installed
and a couple more to start it up
and then additional one for persistent
mechanism so you know if an attacker is
compromised the network this is pretty
trivial
for them to kind of prep the environment
and get it ready
to begin using uh something like when
scp
to start traversing throughout and doing
that lateral movement
within the environment okay so
who remembers this guy right uh who is
this
map something i think so here we have
max he's our attacker
and now that he's got win scp he can
move laterally throughout the
environment using one scp
and possibly fly underneath the radar
for threat hunters that
might be looking for lateral movement
via
rdp uh so now our attacker can move
laterally
uh they've got this set up uh but what
can we find
associated with when scp what kind of
artifacts
uh as threat hunters um are we gonna
have a visibility into
and i'll be going into each one of these
during this presentation
okay one we can get a byte count of data
transferred which is really cool
with the newer operating systems there's
this artifact called the shrum
and the shrum records network activities
so now we can actually get a byte count
in between these two systems uh data
that's transferred back and forth which
can give us some visibility into
possibly
how much data has been uh transferred
and we're going to get systems connected
to
uh remote directories access uh change
directory history which is really cool
we can actually see a folders that have
been traversed through so when we start
thinking
that we've lost this visibility with
shell banks we can get some of this
by some logging that occurs with win scp
we can see the user account that was
used for the connection so now
when we think about our threat heading
we will know okay this account has been
compromised we need to go take a look at
the
activity associated with this account
and see where else within the
environment it has
logged into so that we can know where we
need to expand our scope
we can see the last folder open we'll
talk about some event log entries that
can be used to hunt for
and we also get things like the last
execution date first execution date
this will give us an idea of the time
frame that when
scp was being utilized you know were
they using this for a day were they
using this for a week
or have we they've been in the
environment you know for six
months doing whatever they want and then
we
might be able to get some visibility on
the files copy there is no log per se of
files copied
but there are some artifacts that are
that you can kind of use to make this
determination although that one
not my favorite artifact to rely on all
right so
the usual suspects you know one about
program execution uh you know you're
gonna have your normal things
have your prefetch file indicating and
ran your users
uh your created and your modified data
and i'm gonna spend a lot of time
talking
about those um but i'm really going to
focus on
is the star of the show the win scp
dot ini file okay
so with the winning cp.ini file uh one
of the coolest artifacts that we're
going to
find is called the cd cache now the
winscp.ini file
is just a plain text and each
and it has a header that has a bracket
on each side so the first one we're
going to take a look at
is the configuration cd cache
this will contain the user name that is
used to connect
into the system as well as the ip
address
so by looking at this when scp.ini
file we can immediately get visibility
into what accounts have been compromised
and what other systems we need to take
a look at to see um you know where we
need to expand the scope what other
systems have they connected to
did they connect into that finance
system that has
you know all of the w-2s on it and the
hr
information we see that so many times in
ransomware cases
they pull this information back and you
know they want to use that
if you're able to restore from your
backups well now they're going to
blackmail you because they have
all this personal information so we
really want to get an idea of what
systems they have connected to
and this includes you know possibly an
external system so we might be able to
make a determination
or be aware of the fact that there was
exfiltration that happened
um so an example of what this looks like
is uh right here so here we have um the
account it support
and it was used to connect into this ip
address
um this hex right here is what
makes up the cd cache so you can use
something like cyber chef
or whatever is your favorite programming
tool to
convert that and once you convert it you
get basically a little
mru of directories that have been
traversed
into uh using the cd or you know
the change directory command so right
here you can see
uh the attacker was on one system and
they were browsing folders on
another system and looking for some
secret information
uh this can also if they are accessing
their system
outside of the network so we can see
some really interesting things
we might get ability into staging
folders
and they've exfiltrated out data onto
their remote systems
in fact i was working a case once where
we actually saw you know another
company's
name here than the client that we
currently have
so this kind of gave indication that you
know this attacker was using the
external
system not to exfiltrate our clients
data
but another company well because we did
not break
the name at all okay so
moving on from the cd cache we have the
configuration interface commander
local panel this will contain the last
path
browse to on the host machine but it
does not indicate that anything was
saved there
so this is basically the next time a
user starts to win a cp
it's going to remember that was the
directory that they were working
so that you know they keep on browsing
through folders um when i use winning
p to um you know connect into my
raspberry pi
i tend to keep like all my python
scripts in one directory
and then i use them to transfer back and
forth it's really nice because i don't
have to sit there and click through and
browse through all my directories
so this is basically what uh oh my
goodness someone just posted a picture
of a
cd a cd case right okay
this is great i think i moved last year
or no two years ago
and i actually went through and i had to
clean out um all my cds i was like
really am i really gonna use that old
copy of windows 98 for something um
funny story i actually did when i first
started my career
um i had to load up a windows 98 and i
put the cd in
and it spun up and it shattered into
like a million pieces i don't know what
happened if the
cd was uh old or if it was unbalanced
but all of a sudden i heard this like
bam what was that and my cd was in a
million pieces it was so old
so i figured i should throw them all out
okay so this is our local panel
that can give us some visibility onto
the host machine
what they may have been doing on it so
in this particular example with the
local panel
we have a directory here called recon
tools so
in this particular instance what the
attacker has done is actually
they're working on the host machine with
the win scp they've got some staging
tools there
and as they're doing their lateral
movement with nscp
in the environment they're pulling their
tools from their host machine
and they're putting them on the remote
machine that they're connecting into
so in this ini file you know after they
leave and after they're done they may
delete this
recon tools folder so we may not have
known it was there but by looking at the
dot ini
file uh you know we might find evidence
of that which is really cool
um and then the other way we think you
know lateral movement moving around
within the environment
it can also be related to exfiltration
they might have names of systems there
that they were pulling data back
uh to organize all of their data with
okay
so another really cool one
the local target configuration history
local target
now this one it is only created if a
file or folder
is saved on the host so when we start
thinking about this this is
where we think about staging for
exfiltration
so up to this point in time we have
evidence that they've browsed at certain
locations
on systems but if they actually take a
file
and they save it back now we're going to
get this local target so this
is kind of our evidence that okay
there's something more going on than
just browsing
they're pulling back data from systems
they could be staging it for
exfiltration or vice versa
this might be evidence that they're
bringing in tools from an external
server and saving them on the system
okay moving on this is an example of
what this looks like
um now what's kind of interesting um you
know did some testing on this
and the results were kind of mixed it
may only capture the first session
information
so it might only capture the first time
that they've been saving files this is
one of those artifacts where
um i just couldn't really find some
consistency with it i need to go back i
need to do some more testing and figure
out
why things happened a certain way but
you know at least
it's something right that we can work
with here so this is going to be
underneath your configuration history
local target and just some examples you
know of some folders and files that were
saved here
okay so remote target configuration
history remote target
files were uploaded to this directory
from the host machine
to the remote system so going the other
way now
once again may only capture the first
session copy information
uh here we get an mru list so zero is
going to be
the most recent so what's kind of fun
about this
is you know you kind of start getting
visibility into what the attacker
remote might look like right if i see
something like a root
here um this is a good chance that this
is a linux system that they might be
using and then once again i might get
visibility
uh by looking at these remote targets
what systems they've compromised in the
environment you know they might have
domain controller one there domain
controller two
file share one file share two so in the
remote target i can check this variable
and that will give me some ideas of you
know what they've uh
compromised so once again when we start
talking about evidence of exfiltration
which is always one of those things
that can be really hard to prove
definitively
this helps to give us pieces of that
puzzle
to put together and say you know i'm
seeing when it's cp being used you know
i'm seeing a remote target access i can
see the attacker
you know accessing a remote machine i
can see that they access these ten
machines
uh in the network and these are all the
folders that they visited
uh kind of starts to paint a grim
picture right but
you know it can help answer some of
these questions that we may have lost
visibility into
earlier okay so the configuration
history mask
now i talked earlier about the ability
of the attacker
to search for files uh without within
the systems
so they can use you know this file mask
to do it maybe they're looking for some
interesting
um you know files named ssn or w2
and believe it or not people call
password files
password so uh that's a really common
one right there is to see searches ran
for password
so there this is stored in the ini file
so this is kind of equivalent to
our word will query right we can see
the keywords that were used to run
searches which once
again is really cool we kind of get this
peek into
you know what was their intent when they
were in the environment were they just
looking for passwords
or are they looking for financial data
are they looking for very specific
uh you know intellectual property you
know what what kind of information are
we going to find here
that they could be searching for um
another interesting thing is and it's
not something i really dive into here
but using scp you can actually double
click on and edit a file
so a lot of times i use it just if i
want to do something quick instead of
logging in through like putty and
running nano
and editing a file i can do it right
through when sap for a simple
text file now it doesn't have a complex
viewer you know like for word documents
and pdf files but it's great just to
quickly view
um text files so that's just something
else to be aware of you know after they
run a fine
they could double click on a text file
open it up
and take a view of it right so excellent
this gives us uh some visibility like i
said into intent motivation
what it is that they can be doing on the
network
okay so uh in addition to
um these file masks that are used we
also
have a section that will let us know the
location
of where these searches were ran so the
configuration history
remote directory so now we have the
keywords we also know some locations
where they may have been
ran we can go check those locations to
see
what it is the attacker may have found
when they were running those searches
so when we start thinking legally from
the perspective of
notification um is this going to require
us to notify anybody are we going to
have to let this employee know that they
need to go and change
all of their passwords for their you
know personal accounts
things of that nature this is going to
give us some visibility
into folders that the attacker
ran the searches on which is really cool
here's an example of what this looks
like so obviously you know they were
running searches here
in the hr documents and then at the root
of the documents folder so i don't know
if you've been noticing that throughout
this presentation i have been giving
another 90s flashback
uh to some usernames crash override
and acid burn uh does anybody recognize
what movie those names are from
hackers right daniel very good hackers
movie
it was another movie i went back and
watched recently and really
enjoyed it okay when is cp
timestamp so the timestamps of these
files are pretty interesting the winning
cp.ini
file actually does not exist in that
portable
until the first time that you run win
scp so when you run
win scp it creates this when sap
ini file so that's going to give you
your visibility into the first time
that when scp runs a lot of times when
files are unzipped we get uh
you know kind of this wonkiness that
happens with time stamps
uh you know they will carry over create
a date modified date sometimes and we
don't actually know but
because the when scp-2ini file is not
created until the first time it runs
we get some nice visibility into that
the winsc peta ini
is also last modified or updated
each time when a cp closes because it's
saving out
all those preferences for the user so
you know this is great
because if we talk about and we're asked
okay how long was one of cp running on
the system
how many times did they use it you know
what kind of data
did they access what kind of systems
they access
just by this one scp folder we can
answer a lot of those questions
um so if we take the created date and
that modified date
we can then pair that with the prefetch
file and on
um newer windows systems with a prefetch
file
you're going to get additional time
stamps up to eight of them in that
prefetch so now if we look at that
prefetch
we could possibly get you know different
timestamps that we can go look at on the
system
uh that we know the attacker was there
and was using
win scp okay um so
that is all the default stuff that win
scp saves
uh thankfully for us without even asking
the user right this one is
being created in the background my user
kind of has no idea that this is going
on
uh they do or they are presented uh
when they exit win scp with the option
to
save a workspace so if the attacker is
like sure yeah save my workspace you're
going to have an additional entry in
there
called sessions with the workspace name
now this is the default one you know
very highly doubt the attacker is going
to be like just see my workplaces the
hacking workspace
but if they do you're going to get lucky
you're going to have some information in
there as well
host name username local directory
remote directory all saved underneath
that particular workspace
but the really cool thing is you could
get a password too
so if they save uh their workspace to
their external system and a password
you might actually uh get the password
um i have a link here at the bottom it's
cut off on my screen i hope you can see
it but it actually
walks through the the process of how you
can decode this password
so now you could potentially have an ip
address of an external system
or you know if you're wondering what
password was compromised
in your environment and what user
account this can give you that
visibility there which is kind of a
really fun thing
okay so here we're talking about the
shrum database so uh this is where we
can see
the bytes received and the bytes sent
while the application was being used um
so for bytes received where when scp is
being written
in the shrimp database you can pull out
you can see right here it was the wcp
application
and how many bytes received and bytes
spent
occurred during these time frames so
just uh for this example i had sorted by
bytes received this was the largest that
came up to the top
so this is a great place to get
visibility into you know
how much data was it was it games of
data was it just you know maze of data
what was it um and then on the flip side
we have sent so on the system that was
connected into and you can see the
application here doesn't say
when scp but it's the ssh um
demian right here that did that related
to
the system profile okay
so now that we kind of have this
overview of what is it that we can learn
with the winscp
it is time to hunt does anybody
recognize what this shot is from
right here um another 90s era movie
a great movie um predator
yes i love predator one of those great
movies so now that we have an idea of
what when is cp the artifacts that
leaves behind we're going to talk about
how you can look for this within your
environment how you can hunt for it
how you can be on the lookout for it so
whether you want to just make sure
nothing untoward is going on or if
you've already suffered
a breach and you want to you know find
out and figure out what happens so right
here
um i have an example of this is always
hard for me to pronounce
velociraptor so this is a great
edm solution free that you could push
out in your environment and this is just
an example of how you could leverage
this this particular one to hunt for
this win
scp ini file now
with scp to ionize you know this should
be very low fidelity within typical
networks
not a lot you know if you have a windows
environment you're really not going to
be seeing
a lot of when scp usage this is
just not something that typical end
users are using and probably not
something admins are using
unless they're connecting into a linux
system uh so if we
search for this when a cp.ini file
very very um you know
the results are going to be very
targeted because not only is it tied to
win scp but it's also tied to the
portable version
which i mentioned you have to go through
these extra steps download
most people that use win scp are going
to be installing it into the programs
directory
using the inspector right here i'm just
using the file finder
right there that's built into
velociraptor and i've just said go ahead
and look for windows cp to ini
on the c drive and and that's going to
give me that visibility into locating
those systems
where witness cp has been ran as long as
that hasn't been deleted
so let's talk about the event logs that
you can set triggers for
we do get a 4624 but interestingly
enough it's tied to
a login type file we also get an account
name of sshd
this number right here this 1860 appears
to be random based
on my testing so you know you might need
a little bit of a regular expression to
find this here
domain virtual users and then of course
this process
sshd.exe
okay the corresponding four six three
four as well with that
um there is an open ssh log okay so this
is probably where you're gonna go for
your big win
um it's gonna have an event id for and
it's gonna say it accepted the password
for the account name
from an ip address on the port ssh
now if you have cis mod configured in
the environment which i highly recommend
you do
it's going to tell you that you know you
have a network connection was detected
and once again give you that source and
destination ip for ssh
if they use powershell to install it
like i said at the beginning
just that example where they can use one
command you're going to get a 4104
entry that you can hunt for which is the
installation of that and then the
corresponding
7040 which is tied to the installation
of that service
and a registry key i'll be talking about
that in uh
pretty quickly here so here's just an
example of sysmon um
the information that it can give you uh
once again this is logging that is not
by default and something that has to be
pushed out
within the environment but you get some
great information with
the sysmon entry so with the witness cp
installer
you get a bunch of registry keys that
are installed so instead of using the
portable now we're talking about the
installer
and basically you're going to find the
same information
but underneath this key martin
[Music]
okay martin so look for martin right
here i'm not going to try and pronounce
that correctly that last one
so you're going to give this one a cp
key you can see right here we got the cd
hash
uh the history so a lot of the same
information
once again you can use an edm solution
to hunt for this
we have our mt user and we're just going
to look for this cd cache key right here
and the martin key and it's going to
have that information right there for us
we can see we've got the root and the ip
address so these
are ways you know you can use carbon
black whatever tool it is you want in a
similar fashion
to hunt for these and what's really nice
like i said they're low fidelity you're
not going to get a lot of crazy hits
that you have to filter
through on these okay so that concludes
the presentation uh it is now time for
the q a
i will be hanging out in the hallway i
know we're writing
the time here uh if you have any
questions please feel free
to um hit me up in the hallway or
through twitter or
however else you can find me thank you