well hey with that said
uh what i what i'd like to do is i'm
gonna go ahead and get our
our next speaker lined up um it is
someone who it's funny phil you you gave
us a good introduction talking about
regex's
and uh how your regexes usually lean to
lead to um kicking screaming and crying
which is a very similar situation for me
and to be completely frank with you one
of the things that i find myself
constantly trouble uh stumbling and over
and trembling about
is powershell and powershell obfuscation
and
um our next speaker joe petrowski has
actually decided you know what
matt why are you going the long run hard
way about this why don't you take the
smart way by just applying linear
regression towards it
and as soon as i said this read this
topic i was like oh my gosh we have to
have this because this is a common
problem that i think
incident responders and threat hunters
everywhere face number one and number
two what a novel way to approach
this so without any further delay joe
petrovsky he is here to talk to us about
hunting powershell obfuscation with
linear regression
and just a reminder everyone hop into
the
slack and keep your comments and
questions flowing so that way we can uh
get some some stuff out of joe but joe
on to you take it away we're looking
forward to it all right thanks so much
matt
uh thanks everyone for attending today
uh thanks so much to sans for having me
uh in particular to jen for kind of
being my handler and walking me through
this whole thing so thank you for your
help
uh and we're gonna talk about some cool
stuff today so i'm really enjoying the
threading summit 2020 so far
and uh let's just keep this rolling so
uh let's see here next slide
here we go so um here's what we'll be
talking about a little bit today so i'll
quickly introduce myself and then i'll
kind of get into
like what it is specifically that we're
trying to look for here
and we're going to find some patterns
that show up and in relationships that
you can find in the kinds of powershell
evil commands that we're going to be
looking for here and then we're going to
do some applied statistics stuff to go
try to find that evil stuff so
uh that's what we'll be doing here for
the next little bit so here's me
um been doing blue team stuff for about
16 or so years the past like 10 or 11 in
instant response and threat hunting i
worked for target with you've seen
already a bunch of my amazing colleagues
already
so i get to do really cool stuff with
david and fred and kat
all the time and so my job is pretty
awesome um
next year will be my six-year service
anniversary with the company already so
i don't know quite where that went but
uh yeah that's me
so um enough of that let's get into what
we're talking about
so if you're wondering whether this is
applicable or not like really don't take
my word for it if you just
literally google obfuscated powershell
you'll get like pages and pages of stuff
so
tooling articles about it things you can
do with it
whatever like that there's really not
much of a barrier to entry here if you
want to use these things for malicious
purposes
so this is something like we as threat
hunters should kind of have in the back
of our minds and kind of be thinking
about right we should be looking for
this kind of stuff this is applicable to
us
so then what specifically are we going
to be looking for well let's
think about this a little bit we're
looking for powershell commands
that have been doctored up in such a way
that you can't tell what they do right
so and why would you do that
it's to defer people to do stuff like
reverse engineering
incident response threat hunting or
whatever and why would you try to throw
them off your trailer well it's because
you're
probably trying to do something evil
with it
so what is our goal in looking for this
it's gonna be so i'm gonna say that
we're not
really necessarily at least trying to
build static detection for obfuscation
um the reason being is is because
there's
pretty much as many ways as you can
obfuscate something in powershell like
you're really only limited to your
imagination and the depth of your
depravity really so
there's not really going to be a way to
really detect all that or really get
detection for the results these commands
instead what we really want to do
is just figure out all the powershell
that's being run at scale across
wherever your enterprise is
and then boil that down into something
that you can say like okay if there's
obfuscated evil things
it's most likely to be in this
manageable subset so that's what we're
trying to look for
this is a big data set reduction
exercise
okay let's look at some examples so here
is a powershell command so
in the absence of any other kind of
context or knowledge
you can read this and go okay well
there's some plain text variable
definitions here
there's like a plain text verb uh
there's some concatenate okay
it looks like they're building a user
prompt right so this is a powershell
command that you can kind of tell
it's fairly self-explanatory what this
is doing i would consider this to be
something
normal benign and non-obfuscated on the
other hand
so here's something else so here's
another powershell command
and i have no idea what this is and
that's really the whole point
there's like some sort of encoded mess
at the bottom of this here there's like
a mixed case command up at the top here
um i have no idea what this is and i
know all i really know is if i saw this
in my real world environment it's it's
time to roll heavy on this
and the blue team is going to burn this
with the sacred cleansing fire right so
this is obfuscated the intent of doing
this is to make it sure that someone
who's looking at this doesn't know what
it is
so let's look for let's figure out what
specifically we want to look for
so i also get to work with paul nelson
who really kind of gave me this like
cool piece of advice that really stands
the test of time don't try to identify
what that obfuscated command does
don't try to detect what it does instead
just identify that as obfuscated in the
first place just go find the obfuscation
and that in and of itself is enough to
make us go okay now my suspicion is
raised i probably need to go
look at this much more closely and we
might have a problem going on here
so let's talk about how we're going to
start actually hunting this so there's
going to be some prerequisites before we
can get this off the ground
so job one is we've got to make sure
that we're
we've got some sort of endpoint logging
going on and like i realized that
budgeting and bandwidth and that kind of
stuff is this real thing is really
concerned
i will submit to everybody that if
you're really serious about doing
hunting on your endpoints
you got to get logs off your endpoints
in this particular case there's
a few different options excuse me for
logging powershell
uh sysmon event id1 is pretty good i in
this case i actually used event id 800
which captures a bunch of good stuff
like the the full powershell command
plus any switches running it so that
pretty much is really
what i wanted here so if you are logging
these things off your endpoints then you
need a place to
collect them all into essential logging
repository thing
and a place to search that so i'm not
gonna you know sell or recommend any
tools here
if you've rolled your own if you're
using something like elk if you're
paying for a tool like splunk
whatever use something that works and
whatever's in your budget that's my
favorite kind of tool right so
do it works for you once you've got this
stuff in your central searchable
collection point
then we're going to need some sort of
analysis package for this thing a data
analysis package and a
plotting plotting graphing visualization
mechanism
so again here you use what tools you
like use what tools you work in this
case i use the jupyter notebook as my
analysis engine
so if you're not familiar with that it's
it's a wonderful beautiful thing you can
think of it as kind of like a
a live dewy kernel for for python that
lets you kind of do stuff on the fly and
change things on the fly
um and when you're good at trial and
error like me it's super useful
um you'll need a data analysis package i
use pandas
uh and in fact specifically i was using
the windows anaconda distribution which
has a lot of different ones so i use
pandas in this case but
if you're more familiar with r or
something like that go nuts and then
you'll need a way of visualizing all
this stuff so there's different
visualization packages i use plotly
express again due to simplicity
uh total cost of that whole analysis
package is zero dollars that's another
reason why
i picked what i did
so let's talk about what we're going to
be assuming here if we're going to be
looking for evil powershell there's
probably going to be some similar
consistent
themes that are going to come up here so
if it's evil and obfuscated it's
probably going to run fairly early in
the kill chain
so like for instance if you saw chris
and john's talk yesterday
where they went from initial fish all
the way to domain admin all the way to
soda nikiti tragedy right so there was a
lot of powershell in there
where's the obfuscated stuff though it
was fairly early in kill chain
so it was like within the first couple
phases of the attack
that's where you saw that
it's probably going to be run directly
from a shell right so we're talking
about an adversary who's gotten probably
initial foothold
someplace probably on a popped endpoint
or something that effect
they're operating only in memory and the
real pros will continue to probably
operate only in memory memory so they
don't want to drop anything to disk
so we're not going to be looking for a
dropped ps1 script file on disk some
place so this is run really only from
the shell
and that fell off the bottom of the
screen probably under a user context
right so early in
the attack life cycle here we're talking
about adversaries who probably haven't
been able to elevate privileges yet so
maybe they popped a user who does have
some elevated privileges
but they're not no main admin yet so in
other words when we're finding this
stuff
all is not yet lost right they haven't
completed mission yet however
time is of the essence so we got to move
on this
okay how we going to collect this data
so what i did in order to collect the
corpus of data to begin hunting on so
look for something like this here's sort
of like a pseudo search
but collect this over some period of
time from across your enterprise from as
much as you can get and deduplicate it
so in order to get event id 800
and come up with a regex for whatever
users look like in your environment
and then exclude anything that runs off
a ps1 or a script file right so in other
words these are powershell
native commands run from the shell log
into event id
800 and run by something under a user
context
so when i did this um the the total
cardinality of stuff i ran this
for about three weeks across my entire
enterprise and
like just got as much powershell as i
could possibly get my hands on total
cardinality that was pretty big right it
says about 30 million things
but we're going to actually visualize
this in a scatter plot which means we're
going to want to deduplicate it
the reason being is because when you
scatter plot non-deduplicated
stuff your the data points just kind of
stack on top of one another
and it doesn't give you any additional
information so you might as well just
operate on unique data so that's what we
want here
and when i boiled that down and
deduplicated i like i dropped about
three orders of magnitude i was down to
about 7000 things that was kind of cool
which kind of makes sense right so most
of the stuff you're going to find is
automated script things that run across
your environment maybe multiple times
per day by admin type
things right so your mileage is
obviously going to vary depending on the
size of your enterprise but that's
you know a fairly big data reduction
just like that
and then what i did is i took that
corpus of data and intentionally stuck
some some things in there so
fred and i were playing with a bunch of
different obfuscation tools he was
messing around with
daniel bohanian's invoke obfuscation uh
stuff which is super cool like if you
ever messed around with that go check it
out
um but fred had this like giant body of
things that he obfuscated with this tool
and he just gave me a bunch of them
so i picked six of those at random and
just appended them to the end of my data
set just so that i knew
that i had some needles to find in a
haystack right
so here's the patterns that we're gonna
be looking for here if we're gonna try
to find obfuscated stuff in that mess
if you think about what obfuscated
commands have in common
they've got a couple things going on
here so there's going to be some sort of
encoding mechanism in there that turns
whatever the plain text that would have
been in that powershell command
into illegible stuff and then of course
that you know way to turn that illegible
stuff back into something that will
actually run right so both of those
things are going to be present in that
command
which means that the length that command
is probably going to be getting longer
and longer because it has to include
both of those things
so let's sort of use this to our
advantage here
if you think about it the longer the
command you're looking at is
the more things that you're going to
find as far as character types
those numbers are also going to increase
as the size of the command increases as
well
and we'd probably roughly intuitively
expect this relationship to be linear so
in other words the longer command
is the more letters you're going to have
in it the more digits you're going to
have in it the more special characters
you're going to have in it etc
so that should make intuitive sense so
then the question becomes like okay well
if we're going to use that relationship
to go find obfuscation
which one should we go after well
there's a bunch of options that we've
got here
so we can look for things like i don't
know dollar signs right which denote
powershell variables
we can look for string literals you know
quote marks double quote marks
uh grouping characters you know switches
between uppercase and lowercase and then
actually like fred gave me the good
ideas like why not just look for letters
and digits
okay cool so let's check that out um and
we'll have kind of like a bake off here
and see like which one of these best
explains our data
so we need to figure out actually a
quantitative way to figure out well
which of those is best right so we can
eyeball it but we can actually
get this quantified and get some numbers
on it so you can measure the strength of
the relationship between your observed
data
and what you'd expect it to be so in
other words if we expect this data to be
linear
then there is a line that most closely
fits the observed data
and the process of finding that line is
what we call linear regression right so
it's
it's the technique for taking your
observed data graphing it
and then finding the line that most
explains or best fits that data
a linear regression has a property you
know without getting into too much stats
here
called the r squared statistic which is
basically the
the amount of variation that you found
in your data that can be explained by
the regression line that you just drew
in other words
it's a measure of how closely that line
fits the observed data
on a scale of zero to one zero meaning
it's it's basically not
a fit at all and one meaning it very
closely and tightly
explains the data that you're actually
looking at here so what we're trying to
do is find the r square statistic
be a measure of how much your observed
data differs from what you'd expect and
the
expected stuff is what you'd find along
that line
okay so back to my initial question here
we've got some options here on which
character we want to do a regression on
well let's just do a linear regression
on each of those options here and see
which one has the highest r squared
value so that's really going to be
our best fit to the data and most
closely explains it so
okay let's do a basically a scatter plot
between the length of the command
and the count of things like dollar
signs and grouping characters and
letters and numbers etc and which one
works best
well it's actually this one right over
here so what it wound up being
is is the just alpha characters counts
of letters are most closely related to
the length of the command
um so i tried a whole bunch of them here
there's there's a couple other decision
options here
um you have an option for something
called a multiple regressions in other
words using
multiple independent variables to
explain the dependent variable in this
case it just wasn't needed
um the the r squared value for just
count of alpha was so high that was like
well
that's really all i'm going to need
right here since that's what we can go
forward with
and if you think about this a little bit
like if you kind of step back and you
can probably say like actually yeah that
makes sense
um if you're looking at a big corpus of
powershell commands running across your
environment
it's probably mostly non obfuscated
right and in best case it's completely
not obfuscated you didn't find any evil
in there so you would expect that to be
mostly things
that are human readable were written in
such a way that they could be understood
and it's going to be in this case mostly
letters that kind of makes sense
so if you define very normal normal
powershell commands as they're not
obfuscated and are mostly letters and
you can human read it
then what that means is we can find the
opposite of that and that's what we're
looking for
as an anomaly we're trying to find
things that aren't mostly letters
and therefore are mostly likely to be
obfuscated
so that's what we're going after right
now
so when you do linear regression on any
really any analysis package you'll get a
bunch of information about that
regression
it's called you might have heard of it
as like anova or analysis of variance
or regression statistics or something
like that um this is what you get out of
pandas
so a couple things jump out here so the
first thing in the top right is the
actual r squared
value for that linear regression and on
a scale of zero to one this is like you
know nine six five that's about as cl as
high as you can really
get in the real world and then if you
remember
like what the graph of a line looks like
so you go back to like eighth grade
algebra it's like y equals the slope of
the line times
x plus the y intercept like y equals mx
plus b um that's really what we're
finding right here and you said like
yeah what am i ever going to use at well
today's the day right um so here are
those things down here where the arrows
are pointing to so there's actually the
y-intercept and slope of the regression
so
we're pretty confident that the
regression line that explains this data
is going to be about y equals 0.855 x
minus 10.
um there's some additional cool
regression data over or metadata
the p of t values is basically an
explanation of like
what is the chance that this data is was
just really by chance and that there
isn't actually a relationship between
these two variables
and zero right so there's there's
actually really no chance
that there is no relationship between
these two variables so this is a really
good linear regression and this is going
to be useful for us
so let's scatter apply it finally um so
here is the initial scatter plot of the
length of all the commands i found
and the count of the letters in all of
those commands and of course what she
jumps out at you right away is two
things so one there's a couple things
way off the end of the chart here
and the rest is way over there you know
clustered around the origin
so maybe let's let's zoom in on that a
little bit um
so this is actually really what most of
the data looks like it's fairly
clustered really tightly
around that regression line which is
what we expect uh and it looks like we
can really start using this
now to find anomalies
okay so if we now know what our graph
looks like we can now
use that to find outliers so we got to
define like okay if we think
this is what our data looks like when
visualized what are things that would
look abnormal
based on that visualization so if we say
that things that are really close to
that regression line are what we would
expect
right that means that the farther you
get from that regression line that's the
most likely to be things that we
wouldn't expect in other words
that's probably where obfuscation is
going to live if it exists
and i also threw kind of just a hard um
length
cap on this thing when i was looking at
all my data i really didn't find
any more than a couple instances of a
command that were longer than 250
characters
so i just had a hard threshold here and
said anything longer than that i want to
know about
so then what i did was i try to find
define a range around that regression
line to say okay outside of this range
this is what i'm going to define as an
outlier and this is what i want to know
about
and in my coda i did that with a with a
variable so i could
control the width of that band so you
can kind of doctor this up to
as you need it so if you make this range
wider
um this will reduce your false positive
rate but it might result in you missing
things that you would have wanted to
find
if you make it narrower you're probably
going to be more likely to find anything
that there is defined at a trade-off of
having more false positives so kind of
set this
where it works for you and you can kind
of play around with it a little bit
so when you graph it with um a band
defined it looks a little something like
this so i
set this to i believe like 23 times the
confidence interval for what the slope
of that line was
and you can pretty clearly see like okay
most of the stuff is inside those two
red lines and there's some stuff
outside it those look like they probably
should be something i want to know about
um doing it this way returned about
eight and a half percent of the initial
data set is things that were defined as
outliers
so cool that's a much more manageable
number like i would want to look at 7
000 things with my eyes because my
attention span isn't that long but like
600 things i can probably do that
right
so what i did is i simply spit all that
stuff out to csv and started looking
through it and sure enough i had
originally seated six intentionally
obfuscated commands
in this data set and i got all six of
them so really um i got a zero percent
false negative rate i did find
everything that i needed to find
there were quite a few things that wound
up looking you know fairly weird right
but
they were they wanted being benign human
readable things that i could explain
away
um so that resultant set of stuff is is
enough for a human to go
process so again i couldn't really
automate this away this is really not
high fidelity enough for static
detection
but it wound up being a really great
hunting exercise and super useful so
i think i got a good win out of this one
so one of the reasons i really like this
kind of investigation here
um is because it wound up like it wanted
being the simplest and most elegant
solution was the most effective thing
i didn't need to train some sort of
complex algorithm here like i didn't
need to do anything really ridiculous it
was really
sort of like fairly basic statistics
stuff gave me the best results
and not only that but it was really the
simplest regression i could do on the
simplest
use case that i could come up with was
the most effective thing so
this is i think a really effective way
of finding things that are
um powershell commands running your
environment that are the most
likely to be obfuscated and the most
likely to be suspicious
and this is a repeatable analysis so
this can be iterated we can do this
again and again
and this can be shared with people and
that's what i'm what i really want to do
today
so really this is where i say like okay
everybody else please take it from here
um this will eventually be on github.com
target unfortunately the approval
process for doing that took longer than
the time delta between when i wrote this
talk and today um so it'll eventually be
there however what i will do is i will
post my analysis notebook in my hallway
chat after when i'm done here so
whoever wants it please grab it and go
try this all right so i would love to
hear back from everyone next week next
month next year
and tell me like yeah joe like i tried
this in my environment and
it worked i found some stuff and i
investigated in this like this is real
world and it works
so i would love to hear back from this
please go check my code try it
you know when i get it up on github
semi-pr is like let's let's talk about
this and make this a cool thing that we
can share
so um i would love to hear that and
that's really all i got that's my time
thank you all for your attendance today
thank you so much to sans uh and on a
personal note
um please be safe and healthy out there
you know things get scary
take care of yourselves take care of
your families however you defend family
and thank you very much
you