and with that
i would like to introduce david bianco
who's going to be giving our
second keynote of the summit here um
david is somebody who i've known for a
number of years had the great
opportunity to work with in a few
different capacities
um he is uh working with with the target
company
which we heard some folks yesterday
david is also somebody that
he will probably not like that i say
this but um i kind of
have always seen him as kind of the
the godfather of threat hunting if you
will um and that's a
meant in the absolute highest highest
regard
um it's really cool to have his
perspective and expertise as he's going
to be teaching friends it's 572 next
week with the the summit event
um and when i got to sit in the class
when david was was uh
teaching uh one of the trial runs i
learned a whole lot more about my own
material which was really kind of
awesome
just to hear his perspective on it so um
that all said
this talk is going to be really good
because it's going to talk about how we
become better as
a community as an industry and
i really want you to just kind of put
that email away whatever it might be i
know it's early in the morning um just
really pay attention to this because
this is going to be something that
you're going to need
to hear you're going to need to absorb
and you're going to really need to think
a lot about before
you can take this out into your to your
workplace and apply it because
this is going to be a uh a very
continuous process and i don't want to
steal too much away from
what david's going to present but um
that all being said david thank you so
much for
taking your time with us today and
sharing this and uh i am
happy to turn this over to you sir and
uh
good luck with the other presentation
well good morning everyone welcome to
day two
uh before i get started i just wanna do
uh i just wanna say thanks to everyone
who spoke yesterday
and and also to those of you who are
speaking
later today the threat hunting summit is
like
it's one of my favorite conferences
every year as i i really just
love learning from other hunters so
thanks to all the speakers
i also want to say thanks to the sand
staff because they do an incredible
amount of work to make all this possible
so thank you very much
giving a keynote is well it's a big
honor but it's
it's more a big responsibility
i'm supposed to not only wake you up
first thing in the morning but
also set a tone for the day
i think the best keynotes are also in
some way
inspirational they look at a problem and
they make you want to be part of the
solution
they make you want to do something
better
to be better
i spend a fair amount of time trying to
make security better
it's something i think about a lot i do
what i can both at a macro level by
publishing things like the hunting
maturity model and the pyramid of pain
and also at the micro level by
lending encouragement or guidance or
advice to people
who are just trying to get better at
security
maybe even just trying to get their
first job in the field like honestly a
lot of it is just me trying to be a good
human
but as it turns out being a good human
is a great way to make things better for
everyone
they say a rising tide lifts all boats
on the surface you might think the
infosec tide is already pretty high
and there are many more open jobs than
experienced people to fill them so
it's kind of a candidate's market most
people working in the field are paid
pretty well
and every day we get new and interesting
problems to work on
so most of us are never bored at work
not all is well in the infosec harbor
though
getting your first job in security is
hard because everyone wants experienced
or senior candidates instead of
training up entry level job seekers
we're subject to high levels of stress
and burnout
perhaps most importantly many of our
industry's lifeblood communications
platforms
often feel like cesspools of
gatekeeping and toxic negativity
security can't be kind of an unwelcome
or even hostile field for some people
but i'm not here to talk about how we
should hire more entry-level candidates
though
hit me up in my slack channel later if
you want to talk more about that
i'm also not here to talk about stress
and burnout
there have been a number of really good
articles and presentations
and initiatives that address that in the
last couple of years and do it way
better than i can
i am here to talk about how we can
reshape our professional community to
create a more diverse
inclusive space where we can all bring
our best ideas find help and inspiration
when we need it and then
encourage professional growth not just
for ourselves
but for those around us too that
might sound like a tall order and it is
but we can do it
the good news is there are three simple
steps that we can start doing today
that i think will raise the tide for
everyone in security
and we do need that tide raised if
you're like me you probably depend on
social platforms like twitter to keep up
with current events and security
i follow a ton of people uh it's how i
find out about new attack
techniques i need to be able to detect i
read about the results of new research i
just connect with friends and colleagues
in the industry
i mean it's it's not the sole source of
any of my security information
but twitter is usually one of the most
up-to-date sources and
usually also the most convenient to
access
but for something so critical to our
profession
twitter is kind of a rough neighborhood
this tweet here is just like one example
of the kind of
pernicious gatekeeping that you might
find cropping up
in the middle of nearly any thread on
any platform not just twitter
the cyber security community does not
need people like this he says well read
that tweet closely
like what he's really saying is i am not
willing to put up with beginners
people who studied hard to learn the
basics of their intended new job and
just
lack experience
almost every week i see some kind of
article saying we're not even
able to supply enough security people to
f to fill our existing positions
and the demand keeps increasing so if
you're discouraging beginners
you're actually making the problem worse
not better
and by the way if you are a beginner
just let me tell you he is dead wrong i
know it's harder right now to get
started than it should be
but we absolutely do need you
now this was a screenshot retweet by gab
smash who has
previously i stated publicly that she
didn't come into the field via
a technical path but so i i know or at
least i hope she's being sarcastic here
with her shocked face emoji but
imagine what it must be like to be a
student or a career changer reading that
original tweet
like here's someone inside the industry
telling you
not only that you don't belong but that
you'll
never belong because he doesn't want you
working
and gaining the experience he says that
you need in order to work in the first
place
here's another example of the kind of
junk you can find
every day in our supposedly professional
community
to me the original tweet here just shows
that
not only has the person in question
struck
probably an appropriate work-life
balance but has apparently
also been forced to defend it in a
fairly blunt manner but
you know what she's a woman therefore mr
wall here
has apparently decided that because
she's not at everyone's beck and call 24
hours a day seven days a week
she somehow deserves that unjust pay
disparity that she's probably being
forced to endure
this is unadulterated sexism
straightforward and
unapologetic
speaking of unapologetic i
barely even know what to say about this
one it's a flat
out negation of the need for inclusivity
and security
like i'm just aghast
this last example targeted my friend
jackie who goes by find evil on twitter
for some reason she's been the target of
persistent harassment by the operator of
this twitter account
which by the way named for one of the
most racist misogynistic groups of
homophobes
in insecurity i guess
because she's a woman of color who dares
to be good at hunting bad guys
and she has opinions
here they're publishing a photo of her
home
that's her home they did stop short of
publishing her actual address but
this is a classic intimidation technique
and an implicit threat
that they may choose to dox her whenever
they feel like it in the future
they're basically saying i know where
you sleep i know where your
kids sleep now fortunately jackie
happens to work for the biden harris
campaign so when twitter initially
refused to take action
vice.com published a story the headline
read
twitter is letting people threaten joe
biden's cyber security expert
twitter was eventually shamed into
shutting down the account so on one hand
that's good
it's resolved for now on the other hand
though
it's a shame that it took some major
media attention which is
not something most of us can easily get
and don't
don't even get me started about the fact
that just having your twitter account
suspended is essentially getting away
with this type of
threatening behavior without any real
consequence
these tweets make me angry
and i'm not trying to pick on twitter
here because i see this behavior
everywhere that we
as a profession get together even in
some
in-person events all this makes me angry
maybe right now you're a little bit
angry too
let's look at some calming boats
while we're de-stressing let's talk
about what we
can do to fight the types of behaviors
we just saw
i'll say it up front this is not a
problem that we can solve with
technology
i know that as technologists that's
often our first impulse
certainly social media giants like
twitter
and facebook are investing heavily in
technological solutions and hoping
they'll work but
despite the fact that the problem is
often
expressed through technology it's not
really a fundamentally
technological problem it's actually a
human
problem and therefore we require a human
solution
and i say solution but i don't mean that
we can
actually solve the problem entirely and
prevent people from behaving
reprehensibly
that's impossible but what we can do
what we each can do is take steps to
actively raise the level of discourse
wherever we gather
in person and online
and i do mean actively most of us
are really are good people but being a
good person
isn't always obvious to others
especially
if you're a silent witness to this kind
of heinousness
if you want to create a more inclusive
environment where everyone can
contribute and feel safe doing so we
have to not just be
good humans but we have to actively be
good humans
we have to look for opportunities to
reach out to others to support them to
encourage them
to help them so what does being an
actively good human look like well
i can't give you a full answer because
there's just so many ways you could go
about it
making a list of them all wouldn't be
that useful anyway
but there are three things i'd like to
see
all of us do even some things that we
can do
today that i think can help create a sea
change in our professional community and
the way we sometimes treat others in it
with all the negativity already out
there we need to start
by looking for ways to bring positivity
with us
into our professional lives it's like
ideally
we've been we've been looking for ways
to do this all the time but
i wanted to give you three concrete
steps so i just chose one example here
it's one of my favorite ways to build
others up though and that's just
finding a way to say thank you
we all have people who've helped us on
our security journey
they could be a professor a co-worker a
mentor
an open source tool developer or just
someone who's work that you admire
it could be that person's job their side
hustle
or something that they do just because
whoever they are and whatever they did
for you
helping others is the sort of thing we
need to promote so why not
reach out to them and let them know what
they
or their work has meant to you send them
an email or a tweet or
introduce yourself at a conference or
come up with your own way
it doesn't really take that much and a
little encouragement goes a very long
way
reaching out one-on-one in private is
great
but if you think it might be appropriate
doing it publicly has the added benefit
of demonstrating to others that
this is a thing that we do in our
community we build each other up
it contributes some real positivity in
what
can sometimes be a very negative space
i'll have a little bit more to say on
that later
they say never ask someone to do
something that you wouldn't do yourself
so i'd like to take a few minutes
to say a public thank you to someone
who's had a huge influence on my career
even though he may not have realized it
at the time
some of you may know richard baitlich
and many more of you probably know of
him
he's a thought leader but in the best
sense of the world because
it worked because even though he didn't
invent the concept of network security
monitoring
he probably did more than any other
person to promote
and to popularize it he's also just a
great human
who even if he disagrees with you will
do so in such a way as to be
both firm and yet civil at the same time
which can be a real trick sometimes
i first met richard that's met in quotes
because it was only online
shortly after i was assigned to review
his book the dao of network security
monitoring back in 2004
i'd been doing intrusion detection for a
little while and when i read the nsm
approach for the first time it just made
so much sense i had to try it right away
richard wrote about squeal an open
source nsm solution so that's where i
started getting it all set up though
proved a lot easier said than done and
richard and the other members of the
squeal project team were
very helpful and generous with their
time while i was trying to figure it out
i eventually joined this wheel team
myself where i had the chance to work
with
richard some more because of that a few
years later he invited me to come work
with him
when he was the director of general
electric cert
i remember telling my wife oh there's no
way i can say no to richard he just
invited me to work for him
richard has been a professional role
model for me and i can't
begin to count the number of times that
i've watched what
he did in a certain situation and then
later tried to copy him when i found
myself
in a similar place in my mind there's a
meandering but
very clear path in my career between
meeting him
and being here today as a keynote
speaker
so thank you richard you really helped
me a lot
and i don't know if you knew it at the
time but i'm very happy to be able to
tell the world just how much you helped
me today
being an actively good human of course
means that you have to put yourself out
there that's the active part you have to
participate in the community you have to
contribute in some way after all
can't be actively good without being
active right
you probably know the concept of paying
it forward and that's a big part of what
this is all about
we just talked about recognizing those
who have helped you along
so isn't the next logical step to do
what you can do
to return the favor by helping others
how you help that's up to you no one can
tell you the right way to do it it could
be as simple as engaging people in the
community
on twitter or in person if you're
comfortable with that you know asking
questions
answering them for others even just
sharing your opinions and observations
on professional matters in a respectful
way of course
if you learn a new skill or you come up
with a cool new hunting technique like
we're seeing here at the summit
please share it a blog post explaining
it to all the rest of us can be
extremely helpful
you might even come up here on stage
next year or at some other conference
and walk us through it in person
no matter who you are or where you are
in your security journey you do have
skills and experience
that the rest of us could benefit from
they don't even have to be
quote hard tech skills i mean that is my
specialty but
here i am talking to a technical
audience about something important that
has
absolutely nothing to do with technology
by sharing what we're good at with
others we not
are we're not only helping everyone else
grow but we're helping to drown out
those negative voices we're
amplifying the signal and making it ring
out over that toxic background noise
but it's not just about amplifying the
signal i already talked about how
important it is to call out the people
who have helped or influenced you on
your way up
by sharing what you're good at you're
opening yourself up to the possibility
of being one of those influencers
someone else is out there learning from
you maybe changing the way they think
about something for the better
maybe using a tool you wrote to
improve security or make their job
easier
better yet maybe they're even taking
what you did
and building on it with appropriate
credit to you
of course and then putting that back out
there for everyone
else to take advantage of the fact is
when you make a contribution to the
infosec community
you can't really know and probably will
never know the full effect of that
contribution
because your innovations fuel other
people's innovations
which go on to fuel other innovations
etc
they call it the virtuous cycle because
it repeats itself
over and over potentially making big
things happen
from what might have been of even a very
small beginning
last month i was a volunteer for the
career village with another conference
the diana initiative
i hope most of you have heard of it by
now probably some of you have attended
or maybe even volunteered there too
the diana initiative is specifically
organized around
themes of inclusion and diversity in the
infosec field
it's an event for everyone though it
does emphasize the fact that
members of underrepresented groups have
places in security
that we have a responsibility to provide
a level playing field
so everyone can compete on equal footing
and that all of us
should be given the same opportunities
to develop and advance
this year i think it was a little bit
over 1700 people who registered for the
diana initiative which is fantastic
but do you know how it started
started with just a small group of women
who met in a food court during defcon in
2015.
they got to talking and had an idea
about how great it would be to have an
event where they could get together and
share their experiences
working in infosec and where they could
monitor or excuse me mentor and support
other women
the next year and 2016 tierracon
became an official defcon event they had
panels workshops social events
and then the year after that in 2017 it
became a full-fledged conference in its
own right
it ran concurrently with defcon and
that's also when they changed their name
to the diana initiative
so for about the past five years they've
been enabling and advancing security
careers for
everyone with an emphasis on everyone
the ideas from that food court in 2015
hatched into a full-fledged event
supporting providing opportunities to a
diverse
group of practitioners and potential
practitioners
and they're in turn bringing their fresh
perspectives and
inspiring new ideas and getting involved
themselves to help others
i think this is a great idea a great
example of that virtuous cycle
in action
as i was preparing for this talk one of
the things i wanted to do was watch some
examples of
inspiring talks my favorite was a
2016 commencement speech that matt damon
gave to the graduating class at mit
in that talk he quotes some advice that
he was given
by former president bill clinton
president clinton's words were so much
better than the ones i wrote for this
slide
that um i decided to steal them
yes i stole them so i'm quoting matt
damon
quoting bill clinton when i say that the
final point
in my three-point action plan for
raising the tide in security
is this turn toward the problems
what does it mean to turn toward the
problems
well it's not enough to just recognize
that there are significant roadblocks
for people trying to get their first
jobs or
that actually want to participate in our
industry it's
it's not enough to deplore the pervasive
hostility and discrimination that some
people face
every day based on their gender or the
color of their skin or
whatever other kind of arbitrary out
group classification
other people impose on them it's not
enough to just
call out these problems like i did at
the beginning of this talk
we have to actually take some positive
steps to remove
those roadblocks to counter that
negativity
to boost the visibility and provide
equal opportunities for the people
affected the most
by the darker aspects of our
professional community
now how you do this again that's another
one of those things that's up to you
and it's probably going to be different
for everyone so for myself i started
at my day job at target and and even
before that
i try to think of my role in more than
just technical terms
it's not just my job to hunt threats
but it's it's also my job to lift up the
people around me
near the end of last year i committed to
my teammates that i would do a joint
conference presentation with each one of
them
i didn't quite succeed but i certainly
didn't fail
either those of you who attended last
year might have seen me up here on stage
with cat self
talking about how we revamped our
hunting program
and although i'm not actually presenting
with them this year you'll notice a
strong target contingent
among the summit speakers yesterday and
another coming up today with one of my
teammates
i've been trying to ramp up my efforts
outside my day job too
i've done a few rounds of mentoring
monday on twitter
for example where i invited basically
anyone to hit me up for career advice
and i still do by the way so dm me if i
can help you
i'm volunteering with the def con blue
team villages meet a mentor program
where we get matched up with mentees for
a longer
deeper longer term arrangement than we
can really do
during most twitter conversations
and i already mentioned of course that i
worked the defcon initiatives career
village this year
i'm not saying that you have to do the
same things
that i'm doing what works for me may
may not work for you but i know there is
something you can do
even if it's just finding the people who
are being targeted on twitter
and letting them know that you saw it
and you care
even that simple thing can mean a lot
and men i'm sorry to be the one to tell
you this but a disproportionate amount
of this burden
falls on us now that's partly
because we're typically among the least
vulnerable and therefore the most well
placed
to speak up and have an impact
but i'm sad to say it's mostly because
our fellow men are usually the ones to
blame for a lot of this bad behavior in
the first place
they need to see from everyone but
especially from other men
that what they're doing is unacceptable
and will no longer be silently tolerated
it's important that we not only hold
that attitude but
also that we demonstrate it in person
and online
because aside from the chance to change
behaviors on an individual level acting
on your beliefs in a public setting
normalizes those beliefs just a tiny bit
each time but when we're all doing it
those tiny bits add up
and it might not take as many of us as
you'd think to raise the tide
there was a 2018 survey by
dr damon sintola a professor in the
annenberg school for communication at
the university of pennsylvania
who found that in any given group once
about a quarter of them
of the members committed to a change the
rest of the group
followed and the change became the
group's new
normal now his his experiment
had random groups of volunteers who were
asked to look at pictures of different
people
or objects and agree on a name for those
people or objects
and that turned out to be fairly quick
and straightforward
once the group agreed on the name the re
researchers introduced activist groups
of different sizes to try to
convince the community to change that
name to something else
and what they found was that when the
activists made up at least
25 percent of the group they were able
to change the names for everyone
of course 25 percent of the information
security community is a lot
but keep in mind that the researchers
weren't saying that you absolutely
require the entire 25 percent in order
to make any change at
all think of it more like an upper bound
and if there's an upper bound then is
there a lower bound
another study this time from dr erica
chinowith as a public policy professor
at harvard
used real incidents from recent history
to examine the role of non-violent civil
disobedience in societal change and she
found something fascinating
no movement involving at least 3.5
percent of the group population
failed to be successful certainly
movements with
lower population could be and were
successful
but once they hit that magic number of
3.5 percent
change was virtually assured
now why is that well in part i think
because people like to back a winner dr
chenoweth said and i quote
the visibility of civil resistance
actions
allows them to attract more active and
diverse participation from the
ambivalent people
end quote in other words it's important
for us
not only to disapprove
of the attitudes and behaviors that are
holding our industry back
but to demonstrate our disapproval
publicly in order to attract more people
to our cause if you're thinking that the
difference between
3.5 percent and 25 percent seems pretty
big
you're right on the one hand we can
think of these as
lower and upper bounds for the number of
people we might need
out there taking positive action it's a
perfectly valid interpretation of what
might seem like
conflicting data points but i wonder if
these two data points really do conflict
so dr chenoweth says that the visibility
of the actions was an important factor
in
recruiting uncommitted people to the
movements
maybe and i think even likely
a smaller number of people who care and
show that they care on a regular basis
can convince enough other people to do
the same until we reach that 25
tipping point maybe that initial number
can be as small as the number of people
who are watching this talk today either
live or later on recorded
all right we've covered a lot of ground
so
let me sum up try to make this simple
i'm asking just
three things from each of you starting
today
first let's commit to fighting
negativity by generating positivity in
our professional discourse
one great way to do this not the only
way but one great way to do this is to
show your gratitude to those
who have helped you along or influenced
your career or even just made your job
somehow easier
especially if you are willing to do it
publicly
we have a break coming up right after
i'm done talking
so you know what would be really great
what if everyone listening right now
took just
a couple of minutes of that break to
send an email a text a tweet
whatever to someone who helped you give
them a sincere
thank you in public if possible
i guarantee it'll make their day and
you'll feel great
knowing that you contributed a little
positivity today
next let's find ways to pay it forward
by getting involved in the community
everyone's involvement will look
different
and that's great you might offer your
thoughts in a blog post or a tweet you
might teach workshops at conferences
uh you might do some volunteer work for
an organization
that you believe in whatever works for
you
put something out there that others can
be
by or build on remember even the
smallest contributions now can be the
start of something big
and finally let's remember that
identifying a problem
is not enough to actually solve it when
we see
something wrong we need to ask ourselves
what we can do to make things better
even
just a little better and then do it
now i know my simple three-point plan is
just that
it's simple you might be looking at it
and saying david this
is this is naive this is
never going to work i don't know it's
not a full solution
it's not a full solution by any means
but i think of it as a
good base it's like a set of tools that
we can use
to help us start building the other
tools that we
need to solve these problems so i hope
you'll join me in looking for and
taking those chances to raise up
those around you together i know that we
absolutely
can raise the tide for everyone in
security
thank you
you