um well i'm really excited for this next
introduction and the next talk
um introducing ashley pearson uh who is
going to be talking about
the the place in the overall information
security
cyber life cycle where threat hunting
fits
really talking specifically from a sock
point of view um ashley and i had a
chance to
chat dm back and forth a little bit here
uh before the talk
came to realize well first of all um she
is a threat hunter with the air force
down in san antonio
and came to realize that in each of our
non-intersecting air force careers we
were both actually assigned
at different times to the same small
communication squadron in northern
california
which is kind of cool so we've got a
little bit of ninth com legacy there
which is very cool but
this talk is going to be really relevant
for us because a lot of times on the
dfir side
you know we kind of get these these
blinders on and don't really think about
that big picture
and think about where uh you know where
our
work product goes and where our sourcing
or our tip comes from so to speak
i know ashley's going to touch a little
bit on that and um if you give me one
more northern california metaphor uh
from back at beale air force base
instead of us looking at this down at
the the low in the weeds level where we
often are on a daily basis
she's going to bring it back up to the
70 000 feet or higher
perspective that the u2 would bring and
uh i'm really looking forward to that so
that said uh welcome ashley we're glad
to have you and uh
incredibly excited for your talk go
ahead hey everyone like phil just
mentioned
my name is ashley and i work as a threat
hunter at the
air force commuter computer emergency
response team
i'm really looking forward today to
talking to you guys about the security
operations center and where threat
hunting fits into that picture it's
something i'm really passionate about
i've ranted enough about it at work so i
figured why not make it into a talk
right those always make the best things
to talk about
just to get into it first and a little
bit about me so you guys know who i am
and where i'm coming from
like phil mentioned i did work at ninth
com at beale air force base kind of in
the middle of nowhere northern
california
as a server admin i started
my air force career eight years ago and
for the first half of it
i was kind of a jack-of-all-trades
server admin i did a little bit of
everything i did ticket jockey work at
the help desk i did
server administration a little bit of
vulnerability management and firewall
management along the way
and then about halfway through my career
i decided to switch things up a little
bit and swap over to what is known in
the air force as
cyber warfare operations which is mostly
cyber security uh kind of in a general
sense to translate it for you guys
i've worked in a sock for the last three
years
for the last year specifically i've been
a dedicated threat hunter so i've kind
of done a little bit of everything in
the security operations center before
moving
to dedicated threat hunting full-time
i do have my twitter handle up there if
you guys want to follow me i do
have a very new blog it's only got a
couple of posts but i'm hoping it's
something to keep up while i
keep delving into the cyber security
realm i've been super excited because
there's so much to learn in cyber
security so i've been kind of pokemon
collecting certs there down at the
bottom
going to school taking classes reading a
bunch of white papers taking as much
training as possible because i'm just
really excited to learn about all the
things that defer in general has to
offer
so just to go over kind of what i want
to talk about today since i am taking it
back
up to that 10 000 foot view
the overall question is how do you
integrate threat hunting which is
relatively new function within a
security operations center with some of
the more traditional
or pre-established processes or roles
right so i'm going to start by just
going over some of those functions and
roles so we're kind of all on the same
page since i kind of have to translate
from you know the military jargon to the
more commercial sector stuff
then i'll kind of go over the culture
shift that needs to happen to really
make sure that your threat hunting
function is going to be successful and
that your operations the whole is going
to be successful
i'll go into what threat hunting is
maybe what some threat hunters might
look like in your organization so you
can identify them a little bit better
how to mature those operations and then
ultimately i'm going to go over where
threat hunting
fits into that picture and how you can
use that
to leverage the abilities that threat
hunting can provide to illuminate some
security blind spots that you might have
in your organization
so i'm sure when we think of a
traditional sock we all kind of have a
slightly different picture so i put up
here some of the functions that i think
of and i think of these
as functions that the sock performs
right instead of tying them
specifically to roles because i'm sure a
lot of us work in organizations where
just because you're working in a role
doesn't mean that's the only thing that
you perform some people are
hat swappers i think nicole mentioned
that earlier where she
wears one hat for half of her day and
then she takes it off and wears another
one
so i like to think of these more as role
agnostic and kind of focus on
exactly what the function's providing to
you and i'm sure a lot of us are going
to have the same ideas here
vulnerability assessments are really
common the network security monitoring
for a sock detection engineering or
forensics
and then we get into the analyst years
here you know you have your traditional
tier one analyst working the seam alerts
that come through
tier two being your traditional incident
response and then tier three if you have
it your smes your advanced incident
response
that kind of thing and i know i
mentioned earlier
that i moved over to the sock a couple
years ago
and while i was there i kind of wandered
around for my first
i would say year and a half kind of
bouncing around trying to figure out
exactly
where my expertise might fit in and lend
its hand to within the organization
so i've spent a lot more time working
through the analyst tiers than i have
these other secondary positions that
perform those functions and what i
noticed while i was working that
position is
the way that these functions come
together to work in your sock
are really going to depend on the people
the processes and the technology
those are going to have such a huge
impact on what roles you have who's
performing those roles
the tool sets that are available for
those functions to really shine in your
organization
but then the other thing that i noticed
is that a lot of these roles if you
think about them at their core
operate on more of a firefighting level
uh you're
responding to alerts that are generated
in your organization
you're performing these functions in
reaction to either
your ids or ips your seam
or even external agency notifications
which i know are still very common these
days
but the thing is that's not necessarily
a bad security posture to have
we just want to try to shift from a more
reactive posture
to a more proactive one so if you think
of your typical
tiered analysts right your incident
responders
a lot of those guys are going to be
performing their function in response to
atomic indicators of compromise and it's
going to be very
trigger based like i said you have a
firewall alert that has fired or a seam
alert that comes through that your tier
1 analyst is going to touch
and it's going to be something that's
already known to them like this is a
known bad
file or ip address or domain and they're
going to respond in performance and
response actions to that
whereas we want to start looking at how
to detect
activity that's tool agnostic we want to
start looking at indicators of attack
and this is actually something that
crowdstrike has defined that i really
like to use when i
teach new threat hunters that come to
the section or talk to even my own
bosses in the organization
and these indicators of attack have us
focus on detecting the
intent of what an attacker is trying to
accomplish versus just the tool sets
that they use to accomplish these
actions on object
objectives you're more concerned with
the steps that they're performing
within the execution of the cyberkill
chain rather than
again flagging on memicats.exe or
evil.exe right and
these require no advanced knowledge of
indicators of compromise
so you're not sitting around at this
point
waiting for someone to notify you of
something bad happening within your
network
you are going out and finding things
that are one
very relevant to your own environment
and that are happening right now so
instead of taking indicators of
compromise and parsing them down
two things that might be relevant to
your environment you're really going
about it proactively and trying to find
these things yourself
and of course i feel like you can't talk
about threat hunting without at some
point bringing up david bianco's pyramid
of pain
i personally just to get these concepts
in my head
i divide the pyramid of pain in half for
me the bottom half of the pyramid of
pain really deals with
and explains those indicators of
compromise in a very easy to digest
manner
he labels them you know domain addresses
ip addresses hash values those types of
things
are very easy for you to implement in
your environment when you're looking at
detection logic to create
but i also want to spin it around a
little bit and think about it
from the adversaries perspective as well
if you have malicious domain names ip
addresses and hashes they're going to be
very easy for you to just plug directly
into
your ids or ips or any of your other
alerting devices
in your environment right but they're
also very easy for the adversary to
change
should you alert on them if you flag a
bad domain name it's very very easy for
them to just swap it over to a new one
register something new
if you pop an ip address how easy is it
for them to just spin up a new cloud
instance with a different ip address it
is almost laughably easy for them to
change those things too
but once we get over to that proactive
side and we start focusing on the top
half of the pyramid of pain there
it's much more difficult for you to
create detection logic around these
things but it's also
going to be much harder for them to
quickly change to keep evading detection
with your environment
and that's exactly why we want to start
focusing on the upper half of the
pyramid of pain
if you pop a ttp a tool
or any of the hosts or network artifacts
that they're leaving behind while moving
around in your environment
it's going to take them much longer to
recover from that detection than it is
if you just focus solely on the bottom
half of the pyramid of pain here
and i want to make a special note too
that transitioning from reactive to
proactive can be very slow it's not
going to be
a snap of the fingers alright boys we're
proactive now this is happening
sometimes it can be really difficult and
it's very easy to fall back
into relying on those known indicators
compromise i talked about before so
sometimes it can be a bit difficult
but what you want to ask yourself is so
how do we start climbing this pyramid
and get away from
solely focusing on the indicators
compromise and move more towards the top
half of the pyramid rate
and the answer is threat hunting i
realize i'm biased in saying this
because i do
really enjoy threat hunting but threat
hunting really lives
in the top half of that pyramid of pain
they are
as a function providing internal
notification of malicious behavior
they're not just saying hey i found
memecats.exe that's already going to be
detected by
the ids or ips or av that you have in
your environment they're going out there
and finding these things
based on the behaviors without again
without that
notification of the malicious behavior
happening in your environment and that's
very very valuable to you
and i know the typical definition of
threat hunting that you're going to hear
i'm
a lot of people have touched on it today
as well threat hunting is really
an iterative approach and it's
hypothesis driven so you're saying
this malicious behavior is happening in
this manner and this is how i'm going to
find it and i'm going to prove or
disprove that
and that's kind of a widely accepted
definition but there are still a lot of
misconceptions the biggest one being
that threat hunting is synonymous with
what functions a tier 3 incident
responder can provide to you
that's not necessarily incorrect again
it's going to depend on the people
processes that you have in your
environment that are going to shape this
but they really do provide two different
sides
of the story to you your tier three
instant responder is going to be just as
smart
just as knowledgeable but they're still
focused on that reactive
like waiting for a trigger to happen
before operating whereas whoever's
fulfilling this threat hunting function
is going to
again go find their own alerts to work
the sex the successes are just going to
be dependent on the culture and
personalities that you have fulfilling
this function in the long run
so you really want to make sure that you
have the right people fulfilling this
function in your organization
and with that comes some expectation
management
and this isn't just management's
expectation of the people fulfilling the
threat hunting function this really is
also the threat hunters having realistic
expectations for themselves right
you're not always going to find bad when
you perform a threat hunt and that's
okay
and this is very different from some of
those traditional sock functions that we
talked about because
if you work traditional incident
response you have an alert
you work that from cradle to grave and
then you have expected outcomes and
things that are going to come from that
whereas sometimes these threat hunts
just aren't going to be producing things
to work from
and that's definitely a hard pill to
swallow and that's probably the hardest
part of that culture shift that i talked
about which is why it can
sometimes take a little bit longer to
implement in the long run
so if everyone could just keep in mind
while they're performing this
or managing their throat hunters this
quote from captain picard
it is possible to commit no mistakes and
still lose
that is not weakness that is life and
this
you really need to take this to heart
when you're threat hunting you can plan
for weeks or months sometimes
the perfect hunt you can analyze all the
data sources that you're going to need
or what you're going to look for
and sometimes you're just not going to
find it and that's okay and it shouldn't
discourage you
in the long run and managers as well it
shouldn't
discourage you from supporting your
threat hunting function
because they're not meeting a 100
success rate in the long run
now if you're meeting if you're never
finding anything that's when you need to
go back to the drawing board and make
sure that you take the time
to learn from some of these mistakes and
that's how we get into
how to perform threat hunting now if you
look at some of the talks earlier if
you're able to attend them
regardless of organization mitre target
even nicole touched on it when she was
going through her brief earlier
these are going to vary from
organization to organization some people
have a very very detailed methodology in
the way that they perform
threat hunting but the
commonality between all of those things
is
really for general steps and this is the
squirrel model as well which is why i
like it because it leaves a lot of room
for interpretation
but generally speaking when you're
threat hunting you're going to start
with a hypothesis
again you're going to say hey i think
this activity is happening
in this manner and here's how i'm going
to find it you're going to perform your
investigation
and either prove or disprove that
hypothesis
and then that's eventually going to lead
to the discovery of new
tactics or activity within your
environment
and then it's going to enrich analytics
within your environment
and there's a kind of a hidden step here
that's
inferred from the informant and rich
analytic step
but it's that feedback part of this loop
that's really important to focus on
and i really want to focus on that one
for just a minute
the hypothesis generation the technique
discovery
and the patterns and ttps that you're
going to find
are very important but you're never
going to mature your threat hunting
operations unless you really take the
time
to learn from some of the mistakes that
you might have made you need to sit down
and ask yourself
sometimes some really difficult
questions did we find this if yes can we
create detection logic from it can we
work with the detection engineers here
and maybe detect this in the future so
we don't have to perform
manual hunt did we not find anything and
is that a limitation on skill set or
knowledge base and what can we do to
remedy that
or is this a tool set or a data set
limitation
and those are going to be harder to
remediate in the long run but they're
still very important questions to ask
because your threat hunts are really not
going to improve
unless you sit down and take recovery
time after to ask yourself these
questions
and as far as the signatures go for
creating detection logic
sometimes you're going to be able to
create detection logic even though
you're performing your threat hunts
based off of
behavioral detection you're still going
to be able to parse out a lot of those
indicators of compromise because those
are still valuable you're still going to
be able to find
the domains and hashes that you can
blacklist or whitelist or
in your environment but a lot of this is
going to be
organization specific and it's still
important to recognize like hey can we
implement this or is this going to have
to be manually repeated every you know
couple weeks or a couple months again
that's going to depend on the people
fulfilling this function but this is a
really really important step that
doesn't get highlighted enough and it's
really crucial to improving yourselves
in the long run
and that improvement shouldn't just die
within the threat hunting section your
threat hunts really need to start tying
into
some of the other functions within the
organization right
you can see here in this graphic you
perform a threat hunt
and that's going to have incoming
intelligence or
other sources of information you're
going to generate the hypothesis you're
going to perform the hunt
you're going to perform the
investigation and from that
you're going to get new iocs new ttps
new indicators of attack that can
immediately be
passed over to your detection
engineering function
to create and validate new signatures
and then those signatures are
immediately going to
feed directly into the alerts and
incidents that your incident response
chain is going to be working
and that's going to lead to more
resolved incidents it's going to improve
your detection time in the long run
all of those things feed directly into
some of the other positions within the
security operations center
and even if you're not finding the exact
iocs or
indicators of attack that you're working
on you're still going to be able to find
sometimes some
potentially malicious samples of
executables or binaries within your
environment
now if your threat hunters can perform
basic analysis that's fine and some
organizations don't have a
dedicated forensics area but if those
malware samples are analyzed or reversed
in any way that's going to generate
more indicators compromise and that
whole section of this
chart right here is really organization
specific immediately
it's not hey we found this intelligence
and this might pertain to our
environment but we're not sure so we're
going to have to do some research
no this was found in your environment
operating so you know that this is
very relevant to your environment and
you can cut down on some time
between identifying these samples and
extracting new iocs to then feed right
back into the incident response chain in
the long run
the nice thing about threat hunting is
it's not disrupting any of the existing
functions within the security operations
center it kind of fits
directly before some of them because
it's a more proactive approach
so it complements a lot of the things
that are already there which is
wonderful and makes it far easier to
implement
each time you run through the threat
hunting maturity or the feedback
or feed those threat hunt results into
the other areas of your security
operations center
you're going to start shrinking the gaps
in your detection capabilities
i mentioned earlier that one of the
biggest benefits that the threat hunting
function provides to you
is identifying gaps that you have
they're looking for
activity and actors and behavior that
have not alerted any of the other
detection capabilities you have in the
mesh that's created your security
enclave
so some of those at the beginning you
might find are very big gaps and very
scary gaps but over time if you start
taking the things that your threat
hunters are telling you to heart and
fixing
and taking the time to look at that
feedback loop and take a look at your
environment and say
can we find this if we can
that's great but how do we fix it how do
we learn from this how do we grow as an
organization then you're going to
immediately start improving your
security posture and close all of the
security gaps that we mentioned
the ultimate goals from shrinking all of
these
security gaps in the long run is to
lower the average dwell time of
attackers in your environment
there are a bunch of reports that come
out that the dwell time of actors
within any environment is astronomically
long it's like
a scary number like days and weeks and
months sometimes or years even you'll
see stories come out saying
this activity was occurring for years
and no one knew about it and it could
have very well been prevented had they
implemented a proactive approach to it
so once you start getting after that
type of behavior you're immediately
going to start lowering the dwell time
of malicious activity in your
environment
you're also going to start imposing cost
on any of the adversaries if you start
looking at
again the top half of that pyramid of
pain from david bianco
you immediately start tagging and
flagging on some of their harded to
change
indicators of attack which is going to
take them much longer to recover from
than if you
purely rely on the vendor signatures
that are string matching on some of
those easier things
from the bottom half of the pyramid of
pain and you don't want to make this
easy for them
don't make it easy for adversaries to
hide in your network you want to impose
as much cost as possible
in the long run on them make them change
their tools make them change the way
they behave
make them so worried that they're going
to leave something behind in your
environment that you're going to catch
that they're not going to be able to
hide any longer that's really the
biggest goal from threat hunting
is they shouldn't feel safe you should
be operating
under the assumed breach mindset where
something bad is happening environment
in my environment and i just haven't
found it yet and you want them to also
be thinking
they know that i'm here so i have to be
very careful what i'm doing and take
longer to complete my actions on
objective and you really want to make
sure that they're the ones who are
worried and that you're not worried that
you just haven't found them yet
so in conclusion the right people and
the right processes can easily make this
happen in your
organization once you get management
buy-off
and start seeing the value that a
proactive mindset can really provide to
your organization in the long run
you'll start immediately closing those
gaps
and even some of the more difficult
things if it takes a bit longer that's
okay because you're still improving your
security posture in the long run
and with that i leave you with a meme
and i ask if anyone has any questions