um
so i'm excited to introduce uh jason
kierstead who is coming to us from ibm
and what i was most interested in about
this submission was not
just the concept of a platypus which
let's face it i mean that's
going to get attention when when you see
that come up in your your cfp
submissions but was actually his role um
an architect of threat management
and he's as i said at ibm and managing
for the threat life cycle is something
that a lot of us don't think of
at first when we think of threat hunting
because you think of threat hunting as
the activity that
we're going to do going out and
searching for
uh activity or artifacts and logs or any
other art evidence
however threat management brings this
into a much broader picture
so i'm really excited to hear this talk
specifically because we're talking about
data modeling information modeling here
talking about
how to deal with the threat as an entity
instead of the hunt
as just an activity so um with that all
said i'm very excited to
turn this over to uh to jason and uh
excited to
hear more about the platypus as well so
take it away sir
okay uh thanks a lot phil um my name's
uh jason kirsten
uh widely known in some communities as
jk um
i'm the cto of threat management for ibm
security as well mentioned and i helped
drive the
the technical direction of our whole
portfolio in threat detection and
response
i'm also the co-chair of the open cyber
security alliance project governing
board
and first i want to thank you guys all
for taking a few minutes of your day to
listen to me ramble on about information
modeling
um what is it exactly why should you
care about it
uh common challenges that i see
associated with it
and i hope to share a few ideas on how
to overcome some of those challenges
a couple of the different angles that
i'm going to talk about
may not necessarily be new news to some
folks but i can tell you from my
experience
dealing with fortune 100 class
organizations all over the place that
there is still a very long journey ahead
in this specific space
around information modeling if we want
to get things to where
i believe we need them to be in the
industry and along the way we'll learn a
little bit about biology perhaps as well
and
platypus and whatnot although i want to
make it very clear everyone i don't
claim to be
a biologist by any in any sense of the
word
so i want to start this talk off
with uh quote that i really like
it's called there is no ai without ia
and in in this context ia stands for
information architecture number
different people have said this over the
years but the earliest reference i could
ever find to this is by an ai expert his
name is seth earley
and he said this in 2016. what this
quote is referring to
is the importance of having a
well-defined information architecture if
you ever want to be able to do
something as complicated as machine
learning it's not an optional step
i'd argue when you're trying to develop
machine learning and it's also not an
optional step if you want to do anything
advanced in cyber security
why it's pretty simple you can't teach
something that you don't already
understand yourself
and that holds as much truth as much
from machines as it does for people
and this whole idea of understanding
your data understanding what it looks
like what it feels like what it smells
like
is really fundamental to building a
cyber security information architecture
so just let's let's set some table
stakes first
what is an information architecture jk
what are you talking about
in short information architecture it's
the design
and organization of information so that
it can reliably support
things like findability usability
analytics takes into account
data curation validating the data
in some cases not really relevant for
cyber security but it takes an account
translation
normalizing the data cleansing the data
without a proper information
architecture around your data
it tends to not look the same it can be
stored in different places
different apis to query it there's
different models of the data
it becomes very hard to work with and
things like building
analytics and machine learning on top of
that data gets very difficult
so my question is does this sound
familiar
to you because it to me this is the
world that we live in
every day in cyber security operations
we run into this stuff when we're
ingesting data when we're correlating it
when we're hunting
when we're responding to incidents
because none of the tools in our huge
arsenal
they don't tend to speak the same
language the log sources don't tend to
look the same
the analytics don't work from tool to
tool everyone's speaking a different
language
and it's the root pro it's one of the
root problems of a lot of challenges in
cyber security
it's why extracting you know real
actionable value from something like a
large sim or data lake can be so hard
it's why analysts you know who's become
an expert in one tool chain
can't necessarily easily port those
skills over to another which then plays
into
you know we hear a lot about this
mythical
well depending on who you talk to
mythical cyber security data
cyber security skills gap um this is a
big part of it
right when your skills are not easily
portable from tool to tool
and from employer to employer
it makes the overall talent pool a lot a
lot smaller
so i want to start this
um with a better understanding of
of how information architectures work by
tying it to an information architecture
that
i think many would be at least somewhat
perfectly familiar with
and that's taxonomy and biology
taxonomy is basically the science of
creating an ia
for all life on earth why do we need
a taxonomy for life why was this thing
ever developed it's simple really
as humans we really really really like
to group things to explain them to each
other
uh in fact this whole science of
taxonomy it's
it's been referred to before the world's
oldest profession apparently by
people who aren't familiar with the
other world's oldest profession
but the point is we've been doing this
for a millennia um
modern taxonomy however it traces back
to about 1735 by the swedish botanist
named carl
linnius developed it so i want you to
think about how important taxonomy is
to um to this area of science
imagine you went to an island that
discovered a new creature
and you had to describe that creature to
someone if you didn't have taxonomy if
you didn't have a common way to
to talk about what that animal's
characteristics are
the whole conversation would become
extremely challenging and that's why
information architecture is so important
if you don't have a roughly agreed upon
information architecture
it's not possible to have proper
communications
now i'm not going to spend an inordinate
amount of time on
on this whole idea of biology and
taxonomy in this talk so
so don't don't be worried too much here
um but on the left
you can see the rough um hierarchy of
taxonomy with
groupings that you're probably at least
peripherally familiar with
um note earlier however that i said
rough
agreement on information architecture
and
the reason that that's important is
because
even in an incredibly mature domain like
biology
something that's been around for
hundreds of years as i said two specs
70-35
um there's still today a continual
evolutionist information architecture
multiple taxonomies can often be in use
by subsets
of this community until over time the
architectures come to a consensus and
start to converge
below you can see a rough timeline i
created
by doing some research around this these
are
at the domain and kingdom level what you
see here in the slide
that's the absolute bottom level of the
pre previous pyramid on
um so you know think about how
interesting this is that you know
we're still trying to sort out hundreds
and hundreds of years after the science
was created
what the most basic high-level groupings
of life should be
um and that's because we're constantly
learning and discovering new features
of microorganisms and whatnot i find
this whole thing
fascinating but i can already kind of
hear what you guys are thinking
you know thanks a lot dr science but you
know what on earth does all this have to
do with threat hunting and cyber
security
um so
i'll tell you what it has to do with
cyber security it's because when we're
hunting
and when we're developing detections we
really want to detect
things not strings um
and and i love this this quote this idea
of things not strings and we're going to
come back to this
a couple of different times um so
we just spent a bunch of time talking
about these information models what they
are
and now i'm going to tell you why
they're vital in cyber security
first of all let's talk about the
normalization of data
why is normalizing data important well
i talked about this a little bit when i
was talking about information
architectures but to recap
first of all there's no widely adopted
standard
for security event logging nothing
that you know nada i've been at the
focus of this whole area of the industry
for about 15 years and i can tell you
we're barely further ahead today than we
were even 15 years ago
it's still the total wild west why
why is this it's a combination of
different factors there's a lack of
market pressure
there's developer complacency and a
bunch of other things that play
but there's there's a silver lining here
and that's
uh cloud cloud is helping a little bit
um because of um
when you build detections against the
cloud
the major cloud vendors are somewhat
normalizing that data because so many
things are built on top of their apis
um so that's you know a little bit of uh
a cost right you're we're coming to
normalization but it's at the cost of
over
centralization
second point here and it contradicts the
first a little bit
and that's that public cloud vendors
can't
and likely will never agree on what
their data should look like when you
pull it out of them
um their platform specific security
tools that they build against these
clouds they don't tend to agree on data
formats and what the data coming out of
them is supposed to look like and it's
unlikely they'll ever agree because
frankly there's little
pressure in the marketplace for them to
do this
uh as such you've kind of got this
situation where you've got momentum
towards the marked improvement like i
talked about before
but it's at the cost of this known
ceiling on how well this is ever going
to end up
because they're you know those three to
four major public cloud vendors
are unlikely to produce um
another reason that this is important is
some cost and existing and detection
analytics so
when you've sent spent a lot of time
money and effort building detections
that's a sunk cost that you don't want
to waste
and finally you know we all have to
recognize
that this same cyber security startup
culture that rewards the churning out of
innovation
all the time it doesn't necessarily
weigh
enough on long-term supportability
um and things like using existing data
models to make sure that your tools work
properly with all the others
so why is normalizing
data something that you would need when
you're developing
hunts and detections first there's
extensibility if you build your
detections and analytics
on a normalized data model it's a lot
easier to combine and mix those
detections into new ones
because all the detections share the
same underlying data model
second is this idea of portability and
reuse
the ability to have your detections and
skills be able to move from data
to data source and tool to tool it's
incredibly valuable and can save you a
lot of time when you're doing
investigations
this also plays into the earlier skills
gap area that we mentioned earlier and
widening that talent pool
finally uh we've got collaboration um
thankfully we're starting to see an
incredibly increased movement around
community development of detections
um you know i can't be more pleased that
we're finally starting to see this after
a lot of years
collaboration around analytics and
detections however it's it's really
difficult
if everyone in a certain community
aren't speaking the same language
because they're not using the same tools
and then the same tool chain and their
data looks different
so that that can sometimes lead to folks
not being able to
equally participate um because
the they don't use the same data models
and the power of the crowd is then
diminished
in that case
so all that sounds great interesting
this is a really important thing to do
but
i'll tell you it's it's a lot easier
said than done
in practice there's many real world
challenges that you're going to face
in this whole area of trying to align
your data to an information architecture
so let's start going over those and
we'll start with
some of the basics first of all
if you're going to try to align to a
data model which one
should you be trying to align to there
are a lot of different information
models that exist in cyber security
some of them are here on the slide but
there's actually a lot more than these
and each one of these is a data model
that you can map your data to and from
in order to normalize it
why do so many of these exist well
you know i'm sure people are familiar
with this xkdcd
xkcd comic which i uh you know i pull
out
very often um this whole one about the
standards and how they proliferate but
in all seriousness
you know we we could participate all day
about
how we got to this place and why we
continue to have new
and more models and can't get to a
consensus but the fact is
all these models are out there and they
are popular in their own domains and
they have very important use cases
so they're not going anywhere anywhere
anytime soon
there's not going to be like this
massive consolidation of data models
it's just a pipe dream so getting back
to the question
how do you choose um
first of all we're i'm not going to
spend
a lot of time going through all the
minutia comparing and contrasting all of
these models
i was originally thinking about doing
some of that in this talk but then i
realized i only have 25 minutes
and that would probably take us all day
so instead i want to talk more at a high
level about
how to choose a model that you want to
map your data to
and what things you got to think about
first
do you have any influence at all on the
source data
you know i i still run across people who
don't necessarily
realize this that
it is possible to change the output
formats and data models of
many different cyber security tools and
if you have the ability to influence
that inside your environment
if you can ask them to change the the
data format
on these these these devices and these
sensors before it gets to you
it can be incredibly useful and
incredibly powerful to
to exert some of that influence and
achieve that alignment
the second thing to think about is what
is your tool chain
um does your tool chain work best with a
preferred data model
i'm going to pick an elastic search here
for a second because
it's an extremely popular open source
tool
in this community and elastic last year
released this ecs data model which is
incredibly powerful
um yet you know i still don't see
a huge uptake of it in the cyber
security community and this is something
i'd really like to see
more threat hunters and more folks who
are standing up
elk stacks take a much closer look at
you know people are still somewhat
blindly throwing all their data in an
elastic search and then trying to
extract value out of it on the other
side and if a little bit of effort can
be spent
on that data curation in advance to map
it to something like ecs you can reap
enormous rewards from it
second thing to think about is what are
your use cases
the best the best path and model
on how you should do things for
real-time detections it might not be
what you want to do for threat hunting
um one thing i'd caution though is that
when you're when you're
looking at all this stuff keep in mind
that if you start at one
you're probably going to end up wanting
to use this data for the other use case
so really from the start if at all
possible you should be trying to
take into account both real-time
detection and instant response and
threat hunting when you're doing this
exercise
um what's the level of expertise in your
organization
if everyone on your team is a wizard
with cim then
not using that as your standard model
you know obviously doesn't make a lot of
sense because you know it's it's
gonna be a huge lift for you to go and
and retrain
you know a whole steward of people um
what are your use cases um finally
you know back to the power of the crowd
are there communities
that your team is involved with that you
plan to leverage
if those communities exist where's their
expertise what models
are most popular in that community um
this is something that's very important
do you have existing content in
or analytics you want to leverage or do
you plan to
you know mainly base this around a
community
so let's pivot back a little bit to the
whole biology
point and you know this is i hope a
little bit of a fun exercise that
illustrates the second challenge you're
going to face on this journey
um this is a picture of the platypus so
if you think back to our earlier
conversation on taxonomy
how do you think the platypus ends up
getting classified
it's it's a mammal right it's obviously
a mammal it is fur it produces milk
weight
maybe it's a bird after all birds lay
eggs they have
bill wait wait a second he's got
poisonous spikes
and he has an electrosensory system
those are those are typically
uh characteristics of a reptile um
you know how was it classified when it
was first discovered
it's totally non-obvious what this
animal should be
and the only real solution to try to
figure out what it is is to
model all of its attributes according to
your taxonomy model and see where it
falls according to your information
architecture
you can't just take like a wild swag at
it and expect it
to come out with good results um so what
does this have to do with threat hunting
and by the way for anyone
actually interested that class was is a
mammal
um so what does this have to do with
threat hunting so
hopefully you know a lot of folks will
recognize what this is in the screen
this is just a typical uh microsoft
sysmon events that's pretty obvious
um my question's a little bit more
fundamental than that though
how do you model this data and to be
clear you know this is nothing
interesting this is just this this month
i grabbed from a quick google query to
build this presentation
it's nothing exciting but
what is this the the answer is
it's not any one type of data it has
lots of different features
it's an endpoint log it's a log of
process activity
it's a network flow it's also a file
record
it's all these things at the same time
what it isn't
however is windows event id3
and you know technically it is windows
event id3
um but that is actually the most
unimportant piece of data here
despite the fact that map
detecting and searching based on windows
event id it's one of the most commonly
referenced things when people are
talking about detections
and investigations you know oh you want
to go and look for this
activity you're looking for windows
event 285 or whatever
um remember earlier when i mentioned we
want to find
things not strings and this is why this
conversation is important
and it's really the crux of this this
entire
talk um if we're doing threat hunting
looking for things like say specific
windows event ids and i don't want to
focus too much on one of those id but
there's there's a number of different
things
of this nature if we're looking for if
we're looking for
not the data that's in the record but
we're looking for the record itself
then we've lost all of the benefits of
modeling the data in the first place
suppose for a second that this ttp
whatever whatever's going on the sysmon
event this ttp
had been involved in a virtual machine
and it was recorded by a cloud workload
protection solution
instead of sysmon and you got the data
that way you've got the same process
that's doing the same things
it's aggressing to the same network
location but because it's not coming
from sysmon anymore
the data is going to look very different
and if you had built a bunch of
detections or hunts
around the sysmon event none of them are
going to pick that up
just because you're now getting that
information from a different tool
um and that's that's really the crux of
this
when we talk about things not strings um
you know you really want to be looking
for the data as modeled
not the raw data itself
um it does not do to leave
a live dragon out of its calc out of
your calculations
if you live near him what does this
quote mean it means that
factoring in a highly probable future
scenario
even if that scenario isn't really
assured is something that's very purging
to do
in other words take a beat to plan ahead
when you're building your detections
when you're working on your hunting
playbooks
take some time try to build those things
around a well-defined data model instead
of the raw data if at all possible
if you can do that over time it's going
to re you're going to read major
dividends
in your environment um
finally a couple of best practice
guidelines some of these things are a
little bit basic
and some people in this talk may have
heard these things a million times but
on the other hand you know
as i mentioned at the beginning this i
still see in
in fortune 100 stuff level organizations
there's so many people still struggling
with some of these basics so
i don't mind repeating them first of all
try to make your detections generic look
for the ttps if you can
don't look just at the iocs um
i another way to talk about this is look
for the payload not the envelope
it's another way to say the the whole
thing's not strings conversation
we want to look for that actual model
data not the envelope it's been
delivered in
look for threat signals not os signals
what do i mean by this
you know ttps increasingly you can
figure out ways to do this that are
platform at os
agnostic and you know while this is a
little bit more rare
um that that a given ttp can
you know cross os boundaries as we
migrate to increasingly virtual
environments and our applications are
all delivered to us via the cloud
um you know or we're as an example right
now with covid there's there's an
enormous uptake in remote work and
remotely delivered applications that are
running on
single purpose vms and shipped off to
the endpoints
so as you start to get look in this
world
you know it's going to become more and
more important because
the ways that you get visibility in
these environments are very different
and if you're doing things with blinders
on
trying to build things with platform
specific use cases it can really limit
your
your whole visibility uh finally you
know
test test test this is always a best
practice for pretty much anything you
ever do
in a technical area um but you know
echo it again for detections you have to
test this whole test detections like
crazy
and then again you know planning ahead
um taking shortcuts in this area
you know it usually ends up you having
to go back
and redo it later at some point in time
either as you grow or as you onboard
new tools or what have you so and and
you know and some of this data you you
want to keep it for a long time
right so having to go back and remodel
that data is painful
so what's the next frontier um before i
wrap this up
i want to outline something that i see
as
as the future and that's not just the
common data model the common hunting and
analytics languages themselves
why why do we need this it's it's the
same reasons that we're looking at
common information architectures
um you know lack of of folks that have
the right skills you know this enormous
volume of data
that's coming out of the cloud this this
need for collaboration
around detections and analytics in the
community
being able to detect things and write
hunting playbooks and express
complex analytics in one open source
language that you could then use on any
different cyber security tool chain
that's now a world where you can have
ultimate reuse and ultimate community
collaboration
because everyone can start cooperating
on next level detections and next level
use cases um without worrying about
whether or not
this this complicated query that is
going to work in this sim or the other
sim or this
xdr tool or you know against this data
that's running in this elasticsearch
cluster
the this kind of may sound a little bit
too good to be true but
i don't believe that it is we're very
rapidly approaching this case there's a
lot of momentum
in the space and there's some exciting
things that are going
on in this area um and i you know i
strongly
uh implore everyone you know take a look
at what it's out there what's going on
because it's very exciting
um to close i'm going to
leave you with a few different resources
you can draw on if this whole
topic was interesting to you if you want
to dive into the space
more first i recommend checking out you
know uncoded i o and the sigma project
that you know some folks earlier today
we're talking with sigma if you're not
familiar with it it's a very powerful
tool in this domain
um it although it maps a little bit more
into the detection space you can
actually also use it when you're hunting
next i'd be remiss if i didn't call out
our own
stick shifter project in the open cyber
security alliance
stix shifter is trying to solve for a
lot of these same challenges that i
outlined in this presentation
and it's trying to do that by giving
getting into a place that you don't have
to worry so much
about the data model you ingest because
it's up leveling that problem up to the
analytics layer
i also mentioned elastic common schema
if you're
using elasticsearch in your organization
um in any way and you're not using
elastic common schema
you know you don't know what you're
missing so take a look at that
finally check out the miter car project
cars
for folks who don't know stands for
cyber analytics repository
um this is an effort by mitre to build
one of their own aforementioned
communities
for detections um and car actually has
its own data model as well
although a lot of the detections in that
community um
also have mappings to other data models
not just car
and with that um i'm going to wrap
um and thank you very much for taking
the time i hope you
enjoyed me pontificating about data
modeling with platypuses and a bunch of
other stuff
um if you have any questions or want to
follow up on this topic or anything else
i'm very easy to find on twitter and
linkedin
and i'm going to be in the slack channel
here for a little while as well