okay let's go ahead and get started I'd
like to welcome you to the github
tutorial
I'm Carolyn Donahue I'm with the ietf
education team
I'd like to seems a bit echoey doesn't
it oh you can't hear me now you can hear
me okay folks in the back can you hear
me
a bit better oh so I just need to be
louder okay so we can cut this part out
at the video anyway I'm Carolyn Donahue
with the ietf education team I'd like to
welcome you to the tutorial I'd also
like there's going to be a survey link
in there
I'd really appreciate any survey results
that you have any any thoughts you have
on the tutorial itself additional
tutorials that could possibly be offered
and the other thing is the edgy team is
actually looking for additional help and
additional resources so if you are
willing to a help provide any tutorials
or be helped Shepherd other tutorials or
do other work associated with the ietf
like helping organize the ietf education
materials on the website or on the wiki
there's just a long list of
opportunities and we would love to have
you with that I'd like to introduce Mike
Bishop and he'll be talking to you about
the github all right yes all right
is that better all right just have to
eat the mic so my name is Mike Bishop
hopefully those closed captions are not
too distracting and might be helpful for
someone and it miss transcribes anything
like my name we can laugh at it we're
talking about
the tools that are available for using
markdown and github to keep track of you
internet graphs so we'll be looking at
basic concepts you know we'll be looking
at basic concepts around markdown get
the template and how you use github and
CI systems to tie all those together I'm
not going to go into as much detail on
the markdown because Dan I already did a
session on that and the previous time
slot but if I can just get a show of
hands how many people are already using
markdown to write their graphs fair
number and who's familiar with git
whether an ID context or not most people
I will skim that section very quickly
then and do you use github already for
things similar number okay
so we'll focus mostly on how to get
things set up and not as much on the
tools themselves but I will still take a
quick look around how the different
working groups are using things so
things were not focusing on the XML RFC
v3 not diving into that very much
there's an excellent talk about that
previous time slot but most of this is
going to output be two for the time
being and you're also shielded from the
exact version of the output I don't want
to get into the details of whether
working group should use github there's
a working group later this week on the
best practices if they're going to and
you know the pronunciation of the boss
that did not intend to form a working
group and did let's sleep Evelyn so I
think the best tagline for using
markdown it is certainly less cryptic
than XML it's intended to be something
that somebody can read through and it's
easily consumable in the base text
format but then we have tools that can
take that text format and spit out nice
easy work with HTML that's convenient
for reading and the text format that we
all know and perhaps love the front
helps generate all the boilerplate and
this is the same thing that you would
find at a beginning of an XML document
produced XML RFC basically grab somebody
else's document and adapt accordingly I
would not try and know what all the
different things are that you have to
put up here to have a beginning document
there are a couple different ways that
you can do references this was alluded
to in the previous session you can be
very explicit and write it out yourself
and this is Gamal as one comment noted
you have to get the spacing exactly
right if you're going to do it that way
but each document has a normative and an
informative section at the beginning or
you can explicitly list out the
documents and just let it pull from the
database of all the RFC's all the
internet drafts
yes good so I really don't have a good
way to adjust the lighting but the
slides are posted online and yes so the
comment was that it is hard to read some
of the text that's up there probably
because the lights are shining on the
screen so you can take the you can put
the naiton number of the RFC and just
let it pull in and populate that from
the online database or what you can do
is just do the inline references and not
even mention anything up front but when
you need to make a reference to a
document then you just put the two curly
braces with normative or informative
exclamation mark for a normative
question mark for an informative
reference the other nice thing about
that is that you can give a different
name to that reference so
I want to call RFC 7540 hgp to instead
of always referencing by number I think
that makes for a nicer output and all of
these things are supported by the XML
but you can use crammed down and
markdown formats to lead into it so just
skimming through here within the middle
and the back sections you used the
hashes to do level top level second
level third level headings if you go
past third level you can get really deep
but anything below third level doesn't
show in the table of contents you can do
cross references either two sections or
figures by putting the anchor tag so you
just indicate the anchor that was
provided with the section and if there
isn't one that's put when the section
was declared then it just takes the
title and it converts that so you can
see the the third level heading I didn't
give it an anchor tag and it just takes
the text of the title drawings and
tables again I would suggest grab an
example document and the ones from quick
are a good instance of that but all of
those are supported by crammed down in
the markdown format and will turn into
nice tables both in the HTML and in the
text output as far as get looks like
most people are familiar with it so
let's just skip through there
we have commits that are snapshots at
different points branches and tags so
the idea is we have these tools that let
you start with markdown and use cramdown
or in mark or some other options to turn
into XML and then you can take XML tar
FC that can give you the HTML output the
text output you can use PostScript to
turn text into PDF and those are all
great as standalone tools that you can
use
but when you want to tie them together
there's a tool called the ID template
that you can get from github that just
wraps them all up and uses a git repo
and fundamentally the ID template is the
hideously complex set of make files that
tie all of this together and let you
take a document and have it spit out all
the right things I don't know how well
I'm going to be able to eat the mic over
here
so since there was a question on how
well we could see earlier are you able
to see see that as well.all right-it are
you able to see there's the mic on or do
I just need to be even closer okay so
what we have in this repo is just a
markdown file that has an existing
internet draft in it so the tools that
are there build on make so that if I run
make it's going to go and download all
the necessary references and spit out
now we have the HTML on the text version
so if I go pull that up
so it generates all the boilerplate here
that you would want
so if I wanted to go and make a change
to this document let's say I wanted to
add some text and when I add the
boilerplate from RFC 69 19 to define the
terms must but we know you vote should
consider all those other terms that we
aren't officially supposed to use but
use all time and then I will do
so I'll try and commit that and it's
good to tell me that I actually made a
reference to 69 1999 and it will refuse
to let me commit it because I'm making a
reference to an RFC that doesn't exist
so one nice feature here is that it will
actually send if you check the document
when you try and commit it so I'll fix
that and go back and now if I cam in it
it's in the repo it's there and so that
that lets you get different outputs and
you have the check before you go in
other things that you can do just from
the local repo if I tell it make diff
then if I had RFC DIF installed sorry
then it would build the output of the
comparison from the last time the draft
was submitted to the current state of
the repo and if you're trying to run
everything locally make submit it says
it doesn't need to
okay well apparently we didn't make
enough sacrifices the demo gods
what makes admit does is it builds the
XML and the text versions that you would
need to upload to the data tracker when
you are ready to submit the document so
looking at github people are probably
familiar with what what github offers
it's essentially a hosted git repository
and then a set of workflow tools so the
way the quick working group has been
using that
the renown we have a readme file that
lists all the documents and this is
actually auto-generated by the ID
template that for each document you get
a link to the editors copy which is a
live reflection of what is currently in
the repo we use the issue tracker we use
pull requests to we use pull requests to
manage text that people would like to
bring into the documents who are not the
editors so the way we have it set up the
editors are the ones who have write
access and then anybody else can clone
the repo and propose changes so if I
wanted to go in and take a change I'm
actually not going to go into how to use
up because most people said they were
familiar with that but the process when
you start hooking github in along with
circle CI that's when you get really
nice automation around all of these
things so you have your local copy of
the ID template and you're making edits
and each time you can build it it'll do
us enemy check and produce the local
HTML and text that you're interested in
when you're ready to push that to github
fun other people can see the markdown
changes that you've made
but github enables change triggers so
external tools can observe when
something changes and their repository
and so if you set up a trigger with
circle CI or Travis which are both
supported CI mechanisms then you can
have them run their own container with a
copy of the ID template and what they
will build they'll take the documents
push it back to the gh-pages branch and
that's how you get that editors copy
there
anybody with a web browser can go and
see those documents so what that
actually builds so the GHP just gets
published on github IL and the name of
the repo now quick actually has it set
up to redirect to a particular domain
name but that the generic form is your
github username dot github ah and dot io
/ repo name and the ID template will
build for the master branch at the top
and then for every branch it will show
you all the built documents of the
current state of that branch the other
thing that can happen on CI is that can
respond to tags and the repo so if you
tag a particular document as being that
version zero zeros your a one whatever
your next version is then it will
actually take the document once it's
built and it can upload it to the data
track alright and it can upload it to
the data tracker and so your actual
workflow when you're ready to submit
your document is simply build it tag it
and push the tags and then you get the
email that asks whether you in fact were
the one who submitted that document and
if you want to approve it for
publication so this can help take out a
lot of your interaction with the data
tracker and just get the publication
directly from the command line where
you're already working on the document
so when you're trying to set up a repo
from scratch a lot of this is really
convenient once you get it running but
the difficult piece is getting
bootstrapped trying to take an empty
repo
get it set up the the ID template setup
script is quite good about telling you
when you haven't done something
correctly but when I was getting started
with it I would often just do a loop of
run set up it'll tell me oh you haven't
done this yet and then I need to go fix
it fix it there are some setup scripts
that rich sauce has written that are
intended to help help you get the repo
set up in the first place so it will
create an account on github for a
working group and it will let a working
group or an individual with an existing
account set up a new repo but it still
comes out as an empty repo you can
upload a upload a template to it so what
I'm going to do now is just walk through
taking taking an empty github repo and
you can either use the script to create
it
you can use the script to create it or
you can do it directly on God so I'm
gonna say I want a new repository and
sure fantastic dirty and just take the
name of it offers so right now we have
an empty repository and then I'm going
to come to the command line and do the
basic setup so the first thing you do is
clone it down
and before anything else happens you
need to put a very basic version of the
draft so Rich's script would populate
this with a with a template that has no
content for purposes of this in this
demo I'm going to copy the change that
we did from the DNS service draft so
so the setup is first you have to have
already committed and pushed so get push
just interact with the remote repository
- yes just a question is the fantastic
journey the working group in this case
it's just the repository for the
document so one of the things that we'll
be discussing in the get working group
for best practices is whether you should
have a single repo for all the documents
like we've mostly done with clique or
whether it's better to have individual
repos per document I have mostly done
one large repo but I know the tls
working group has a separate repository
for document and either one works
functionally it's a quick one the
template can handle having multiple
drafts present so it will build each
draft that it lines so I push that and
then if we're going to set up the
template
so the IV template itself is on github
it's under Martin Thompson's account and
the URLs and the slides so you clone it
down into the rectory called Lib and it
contains the setup script so you run
make and point it to that setup location
and then what the template is going to
do is first check that your draft
actually is present and build and has
already been pushed up to github so it
wants to make sure you have a a good
link and then it will start populating a
readme file that contains the name of
your draft and tells people what working
group its affiliated with Tulse then the
discussion should happen on the reading
on the mailing list it populates a
contributing contributing document that
points them to the note well and just
helps to solve the issue of how do
people who do drive by contributions on
github know that they need to comply
with the note well and the IP are
policies of that and it helps populate
the things that you need in the repo so
at the end of that set up if we look at
the commits we see that the setup script
added a new commit that creates all
these files and it added a gh-pages
branch which is where the built
documents created by the change nun by
the CI the continuous integration are
going to live but if we go back to our
github repo all this lives if we look at
the gh-pages branch what we'll actually
find is even though the index.html file
is there it's empty
so that relies on getting things set up
in the change at non continuous
integration system so once you've
created the repository you need to go to
circle CI until it that it should
actually be building from that repo so
you tell it to add project you find your
new repo and it'll try to walk you
through creating the dot circle CI
config mo that's actually already added
by the template so when you run the
setup script that's created for you you
can just say start buildin so at that
point
Oh
and then what I missed
it created the it created the commit on
my local repo but I never pushed that to
get up
so if I come back here now that I've
pushed it well fine then you'll see that
it's populated the readme file with name
of draft the links to them where the
editors copier is going to be the
contributing guidelines will show up
here for anyone who is interested now we
should be able to see yes it does run
and so what this is going to do is every
time you push to the repo it will build
the documents and if the documents don't
build correctly than circle will send
you so that is a convenient way to keep
them keep track particularly if you have
lots of people collaborating on a
working group repo that if somebody
breaks the build you find out about it
so let's say well before we get to that
there is one thing that's still missing
though if we go to the gh pages
it doesn't actually push back because
circle needs permission to do that so
you set that out you'd be going to
github settings and they hide it under
developer settings to get the access to
its an access token there's something
that is not your password that can be
used to talk to github on your behalf
so you'll create one with whatever
permissions you want the only permission
that it requires the only permission
that's required for the CI system is
public repos so long as it's not
actually hidden then you take that
change okay and you'll come to come over
to circle
so that in the settings for each project
that goes in as environment now since I
already have it set up I will go to a
different repo and copy it over the name
of the name of the variable is gh token
and you paste end the token that you got
from get out the other the other place
where those tokens are useful is you'll
need them at the command line to
interact with get up if you have to
factor off the setup with your main
account you can create a token using
two-factor all and then use that token
as the password for a tool that can't
interact with the - then - vector what
so now that the token is there any time
I have adult on out and I'm just gonna
restart the same build it will not only
build the documents cloning
so now it's going to push it back
so if you look at the commit history
first thing it's going to show you is
with each commit so you know when CI
tries to build it even if it doesn't
have the token and that will report back
to github whether that version in that
commit was able to build successful so
you can easily see this one it wasn't
able to build then we pushed it after
setting up the ID template and you get
the green checkmark and every time you
introduce a commit it's going to add a
new commit to the gh-pages branch with
that version of the dolt documents
committed by the ID bot and this is what
gives you a banana all
we go over here and now it has built the
index page with the HTML version and the
text version when you're ready to submit
you do an imitated tag I don't even
remember what version of the graph this
is actually on but I'm not gonna let the
submission go through anyway one thing
to note is that in order for circle to
do this and do the auto submission to
the data tracker it has to be an
annotated tag which means you have to
give it a message to go with the tag but
the actual content of that message
doesn't matter at all so you have to
pass something it will fail if you don't
or rather it will bring up the editor
and ask you to type it so if I create
the tag and now I push the tags up to
github
you go and take another look encircled
you'll see that that tag is also
something that it will build on and the
last step we're gonna just build is that
it's going to use curl to upload it to
the data tracker which will generate an
email to all the listed authors and I've
already told Ben that you should not
respond to any emails from the day
detector about this draft today and I'm
going to cancel the submission when I
get the email that assumes that I guess
on the fast version that when the data
tracker doesn't reject it so the last
step is part of the build process you
can see the upload to data tracker and
it's looking for a 200 ok coming back
and if it doesn't get a success on the
submission then what it will do is email
me that the built failed on that tag to
say it couldn't it couldn't submit to
the data tracker you may need to do that
so to recap how we do that setup first
you need all the local tools you have to
have get and make for the template to
work XML RFC depends on Python from down
RFC two-six two-nine requires roogie and
those can be installed with their
appropriate handlers actually apt is
able to take all of these directly so if
you just go and ask for those four you
can get more current versions of XML by
RFC off of the pipe I installer and
cramdown can come off of rubygems on the
cloud side you need to create your repo
either script or manually and you need
access tokens to give to circle and then
on circle you need to set it up to
follow the repo and you need to have the
access token in the environment
variables if you want it to actually
populate back to the repo on your path
so full disclosure while I have made
some contributions to the IV template
I'm not the one who wrote it
that would be Martin Thompson so if this
looks like a tool that will make
authoring internet graphs easier for you
I would say buy him drink I have found
it to be a lot simpler than trying to
mess with the XML which I did at the
beginning of my time and the IETF but at
this point I am marked down for
basically everything mostly for
reviewing the slides later I've got some
basic like what community would use and
get for different tasks and that is the
end of whatever we're a lot we're way
under time because I skimmed through the
things that look like most people were
familiar with but if there's anything
that you want me to go back and go into
more detail on I'm happy to do that
happy to stick around the news or
questions
and the deafening silence in the room is
either okay Sebastian go ahead hi mark
expert village I was wondering if
dissipating threat commitment to github
versus other farms that doesn't get my
work out there um
github is what we have primarily used I
believe I believe that it would work
with any remote git repository so long
as it can integrate with circle but I
don't actually know how reliant circle
is on using github and not the other
versions and then Vidia I also saw that
their support for Travis yes it is still
present and supported but I'm not sure
whether the newer features like auto
submitting to the data tracker are
supported and Travis or not okay thank
you we know we have experienced that
circle is more reliable for building
things and also it passes more
information into the environment of the
build that the template is able to pull
on if you open up some of the make file
scripts they're part of the template you
can see comments like if this is Travis
this is not populated we have to attempt
to guess it yeah rich so Travis might
also be on its way in decline because
most of the staff has been fired
I imagine that doesn't help actually on
that I could continue yeah please the
the reason I asked about github and I
mentioned it lab as well is because a
good lab it could be self hosted and it
wouldn't be on you know startups going
out of business or things like that
I mean had the Microsoft owning github
is pretty reassuring
I guess in the long run but for some of
the other tools that are related to it
it might make sense for the IDF tools to
also be open-source and be able to be
self hosted by by authors yeah so a lot
of that discussion is likely to happen
in the get working group later this week
their Charter is to come up with best
practices for get the git and github use
at the IETF we're chartered to focus
specifically on github but the question
of whether any of the tools need to be
self hosted and managed by the IETF even
if there are third-party at once is
definitely going to come up
any other questions
okay well I will stick around for a
while if anybody wants to ask anything
not at the microphone otherwise thank
you for coming
[Applause]