okay changing the subject to our
favorite protocol I got the t-shirt and
everything same thing applies guys this
is the first time I do this it is
working progress is also the type of
content that we are going to put in the
public domain and you guys saw the test
audience this time it's about the Netcom
protocol all right same thing here this
presentation uses in this case actually
a set of common kind of network oriented
tasks that people that run networks do
to walk you through the features of the
Netcom protocol so you'll see a
commonality here that we wanted to try
to do presentations or tutorials that
are just not going through or if these
top to bottom that actually tie it into
a useful narrative or a useful set of
activities and after this presentation
which I think will be a little shorter
than the yang one unless you really
hammer on with questions you will know
how to get configuration from Netcom you
know how to actually configure things
with net cough and you will understand
how Netcom transactions work I told you
about there's about Yang and it's even
more important here I'm not covering
everything that the net comforta Cole
can do it's actually large chunks that
we just don't have time for I believe
that the full blown version of this
presentation will be only order four
hours when we strive for completeness so
take this as kind of an intro for those
of you who haven't heard this before and
there's quite a bit of other types of
presentation material and tutorial
material available including of course
all the way back to the source the RFC
net course of course is a protocol it's
been around for a while now as any good
protocol it's based on a couple of
layers I cannot spend too much time with
this but some of the terminology here is
important on the bottom we have secure
transport very very important right but
we didn't want to build the net that
protocol explicitly towards any
particular transport right we had a
couple of requirements on useful
transports and then produce what we call
transport bindings
the majority of the net conf
implementations that I've seen in the
world today uses SSH so most of the
implementations today is actually
traveling over SSH but that doesn't mean
that it's inextricably linked with SSH
in any way shape or form especially in
the beginning we had grand plans about
soap and beep and all kinds of things we
may see or we will actually I think we
will see TLS coming
but for now most of the actual deployed
equipment runs over SSH then we have a
messages layer so this is let's call it
the envelope it's the RPC RPC reply
style messaging that you've seen before
you will see already here hopefully that
this is actually the on the wire
encoding for Netcom phys XML all right
but that doesn't mean that you guys need
to know XML there's a lot of nice
libraries and there's also or another
net conf like protocol called rest conf
in the making and will probably extend
their tutorial too to add that to where
we have JSON but for net conf
we use XML so you have the messages
layer or PC an RPC reply then we have
operations so net confess a protocol and
this makes it vastly different from
things like soap from things like HTTP
from things like beep we actually
describe a set of base operations so we
go far up the stack compared to many
other things so the next time people ask
you why don't why do we use net conf why
don't we use just use rest you can tell
them because net confit is a full
semantic stack with operations in it
rest is an architectural principle you
can probably implement net comp like
behavior using rest but it's not in rest
itself on the top we have content this
is of course where yang comes in right
when we actually published the net comp
RFC the first thing that we heard back
was nothing right because what's the fun
of a protocol when you don't know what
you're manipulating right so of course
the fun starts with the content in that
comms case it's the configuration data
and also the notification data we won't
talk about notifications today but the
configuration data and of course that's
what we
created yang for to describe the same
tax structure and semantics of the
content that travels in at calm a core
principle of net comp that it also makes
it vastly different than many other
so-called protocols is that we have a
concept of data stores I'm trying to use
data stores when I can not databases we
have a concept of data stores there's
three of them this far we'll talk about
capabilities so this would this denotes
a capability which means that it's
optional but let's talk about all three
of them of course the running data store
is what reflects what the box is doing
right now what that actually means in a
router switch or base station depends a
little bit on the vendor right it may
take time for your newly changed
configuration to actually happen on the
firmware but it's the representation of
what the books thinks is it's complete
and active configuration we have a start
up data store that's a pretty obvious
thing usually when you want to snapshot
or you say that this looks like a good
configuration to have when I come up
again you copy the content of you're
running into the start up data store so
the next time your books cold or warm
boots it's going to read the startup
configuration a key thing that makes
Netcom perhaps a little bit more
interested depending on your leanings is
the candidate data store I think of it
as a scratch pad it's a global scratch
pad but it's where you actually start
editing your configuration and the cool
thing here is that with the candidate
data store you can pre validate we'll
get to that but you can pre validate the
configuration without affecting the
running data store in a well implemented
system and of course the communications
between candidate and running is that
when you're happy with your candidate
and we'll talk about these in more
detail you do what we call a commit
commit means take the content of
candidate and make it running very
painful to implement for those of you
who knows and of course you can go the
other way around so when you start
afresh you start a new session you
usually start by copying you're running
into your candidate you manipulate that
till you're done and then you commit ok
it's important to have these kind of
concepts in your head to really
understand why that conf may
make sense for you or not there's
nothing particularly strange with a
basic napkin session like most are PC
based stateful protocols that go through
kind of three main phases we start a
session by exchanging what's called
hello messages we'll look at example of
this their cool thing here is that the
hello messages gives you capabilities
exchange which is also a little a little
novell a little new I think for for
network management protocols then you go
on your merry way you perform usually
one or more operations to rate first not
conquest much just one question the data
store is on the server or the client
that that is a fantastic question it is
on the server really important so this
these three would be implemented in your
favorite router vendor okay and another
question is it part of next gulf to
discover the capabilities of the server
for example absolutely so that's what's
gonna happen in the first phase here we
do a very thorough capabilities
publishing or exposure so yeah I'll show
you examples so you perform a set of
operations or series of operations until
you're happy and then you end your
session of course the well-behaved
client would do a closed session the
less well behaved client will do a kill
session and the really rude would just
tear down the transport just kill SSH it
kind of has the same effect so here we
go with the capabilities right for every
new session the client starts with
sending a hello the client actually
sends capabilities if it wants to it
doesn't make much sense actually in the
real world but you can send things like
what net conversion to support the
server then responds this is a very I
don't have time to show you running code
but this is a very small response this
is usually fairly large what this server
tells the client here is that it
supports net call base protocol 1.1 so
the client knows that all the mandatory
capabilities or the mandatory functions
in napkins is supported by the server
it also says that actually I have
writable running you can write straight
into my running data store and I have a
candidate so this implementation
actually has two of the three data
stores that I showed you on the previous
slide now the client knows right down
here and for further study the server
also says these are the yang modules
that I support think about that for a
while that's pretty cool
including the revision and how to how to
actually get a hold of it this means
that you can always query a router for
the exact contract language like
definition of the data set that you can
manipulate on it this has been sorely
lacking in the industry for a long long
while and before we move on I'm gonna
bring - yes features and deviations are
the exchange in the capabilities
features yes deviations are in the yang
files that you that you look in okay
well they are you see this is great
they're also okay so the actual editor
of the RFC said yes
they're also advertised so both
deviations and features that was close
thank you should prob'ly put that in the
example okay some terminology so this is
XML heavy but bear with me okay so in
net comp lingo you remember this this is
the RPC envelope here are our operations
so in this case we use the get operation
it's a basic Netcom operation operations
have parameters in this case we use a
filter we'll make an example of this but
I just want to point out the lingo
parameters may have attributes so we're
gonna use a specific type or filter in
this case so operations parameters and
attributes
so the first completely set up question
is how do I get all configuration and
operational data day to day question
right to do this we're going to use two
different operations and this is also
where net conf is a little bit different
than other protocols we make a strong
difference between the get operation
that actually returns everything both
configuration operational data so if you
wanna if you wanna if you want to have
fun you can take any big router that
supports net Commodore get on route and
watch it slowly keel over it's a very
very heavy operation for most current
implementations because that means it
needs to snapshot all counters
everything in its entire system it's
comparable to a single single call
snmpwalk for the entire mid-set okay so
don't do it yet until they got their
coding in in order the gap config
operation only actually only fetches the
configuration so this is probably more
useful typical use would be a backup
actually the semantics of this is such
that you're supposed to be able to say
get config get the data put it to the
side and at any point in time later as
long as the router or the books runs the
same yang models you're supposed to be
able to just dump it back so we can we
can say it's reliable backup and restore
much different from the way we've done
it with CL is an SNMP okay so here's an
example
all RPC messages have an ID we actually
use the base net conf namespace or
namespaces is is all over the place here
nothing strange to do a gift
there's no parameters to get which means
you're doing the thing you shouldn't be
doing and you get an entire set of data
returned in a data envelope okay
very straightforward a more realistic
get response actually this comes out of
our previous example is this but it's
it's a very made-up - it's as if this
box only has two interfaces and only
running ipv6 but as you can see this
data then it's the same that we looked
at for the example in yang maybe the
things to think of here is that this is
where you start seeing the namespaces
right this is the namespace from the
yang module for the AF types this is the
ITF IP namespace and so forth okay so of
course our eager network person wants to
know how to filter data instead of just
get everything right so both they get or
and the gate config operations have a
filter parameter there are two types of
filters there is a simple subtree filter
which I believe is actually mandatory so
it's a way of pointing out this is the
path to which I want to see everything
below that for the more adventurous
implementers you can also have filter
type X path and that puts you in a whole
different situation X path as you guys
know is a whole query language you can
do all kinds of cool stuff with
existence tests and counters and all
kinds of things but sub-tree is
mandatory so in this case we're going to
use a filter to select the particular
sub tree and only get that so here we go
we send the following message because we
want to see just the interfaces list so
we have a gift we have the parameter
filter type sub tree and what we're
saying here is that we only want to see
what's under interfaces okay this is the
if you like the sub tree criteria I
should probably make it into one element
and here's the response message and it
throws back at me that based on the
filter from this namespace here is the
only interface that I have it's called
eth0
and if we do the relief you'll get some
more data so in this case that the full
or the deep response actually also
includes of course everything that's
under each h0 okay okay
so that's that about getting get config
and filtering now how do we manipulate
configuration so in this case again
we're gonna borrow from a previous
example gonna enable and configure ipv6
addresses for the interface to new
operations here edit config is the big
tool to actually manipulate data on
boxes so we're going to edit data for
content but you guys now know that
there's three data stores so we may need
a target parameter to specify which data
store am i manipulating at this point
and if we are manipulating the candidate
you guys remember that we need to also
use the commit operation to take what's
running in the candidate and make it
running so what like almost like a
general example of edit config is this
right it's an RPC it's its own base
operation you point out the target and
then you send the config subtree that
you want to apply to the target so
here's the actual payload to do what we
did as an example in the previous in the
yang session so edit config target
running right so no candidate just no
candidate subtleties just straight into
running we know what we're doing config
envelope and in this case we know that
what we are going to change is in the
interfaces subtree and this is the this
is the namespace for that on our
interface for this to be actually valid
of course we need to send the key so we
need to say that for this member of this
tree eth0 make it enabled okay so this
is the edit config content to do or we
mentioned the yang module
but that's too easy for our adventurous
programmer here he wants to use she
wants to use edit config on candidates
first of all as I said you have to check
the fact that the book supports the
candidate capabilities you have to look
in the hello message to see thus these
books actually support candidate if it
does here's what you need to do first of
all it's good form to clear out the
candidate as I said the candidate is
global there may be lingering data in it
that someone else didn't clean up after
them you edit the candidates so it looks
like the way you want it to and then you
commit it again which means that you
move the content of it into the running
data store yes I do how do you deal with
race conditions for that you take looks
and we'll get to that in five slides
good to people just running up that far
maybe I'll make just a small note sit on
your hands race conditions later delete
config the parameter is target and
candidate we do edit config with the
target candidate new configuration and
we commit that's the very short one yes
sorry question pauses I had a
configuration so but not yours either
configuration to configure the
configuration to total servers do I need
a tool you look at config first because
we added a configuration maybe does the
configuration of the server may be
changed so better I need a tool first
cattle coming Edition and as an added to
the server I think it's safe to say that
in most real implementations you would
do I get confused this is the
implementation I need yes exactly so in
but in realistic systems we have we
found the boundary of the protocol - we
needed some mechanism for Tocantins that
has a consistence of the configuration
between the client and the server a good
implementation would provide that yes
but actually from the kind of Netcom
from yank perspective we are more
concerned about the consistency on the
server ok see what I mean see
well so can I do anything like wild
cards so on the previous slide could I
do like interface star and a vote drew
or do I have so I glance over and say in
sub-tree you can't with XPath you can go
crazy on it yeah so here's the edit
config our first step in that 3-step
thing so we had any confident and elates
saying content that you saw before and
then we commit that's that's the basic
difference and the commit step if I
didn't mention that before is of course
a transaction so when the box returns
that your commit was successful it is
supposed to be successfully running in
running if something happens while
applying it you should have your
candidate intact and you can use other
things like validate or change what you
have any candidate and retry okay now
three slides that's what it was
locking I don't want others to change
the configuration while I'm editing it
right you don't want you don't want bad
fall outs from race conditions we will
use a couple of new things actually
we're getting closer to another full set
of operations that will give you
two-phase commit like transactionality
the new operation here is that we will
use a locking operation you've seen
delete now you have you haven't seen any
config you've seen edit config you've
seen commit and then of course to close
it off we will unlock the databases that
we needed so here we go a good gentlemen
will then log in or in the first thing
to do in the session is to look so we
have a target here of course you don't
want to lock the entire thing in this
case we're gonna lock the running now
next question from you guys will be fine
grained looking and no there is no finer
grain locking down on a database level
don't give me that look
say something huh in the base protocol
there are extensions but in the base
protocol good point
delete the target candidate so we clear
that out do the edit config on the
candidate it committed then we unlock it
shouldn't say free should say unlock
here we go yes another question can you
make can you serve commit it and then
require that you approve it sometime
after that kind of like junipers you
know commit on a config three more
slides you you you will find that
juniper did have quite a say in the
creation of the Netcom vertical
validation and rollback in this case we
will use a new operation called validate
so we will validate the content of a
datastore which means that you will ask
the system to do whatever it can in the
back end to make sure that first of all
it complies with the yang but may be oh
there are also other stuff right is the
temperature in the chasis such that you
can do this change and then we're going
to use something called a confirmed
commit now that's a that's a that's a
hint
that's called confirm commit confirm
commit is a particular type of commit
there are two new parameters that we're
going to talk about here one is a
persist parameter to specify a commit
identifier so a unique identifier for a
particular commit like you can use later
and the other one is a confirmed timeout
so what confirm timeout means is that
unless you're back to confirm the
confirmed commit or we call a confirming
commit the box itself will roll back
okay so if that times out the box will
roll back itself you can also cancel
commits by identifying your commit using
the persist parameter
the validation step because we've
already done the Edit candidate here
looks like this so this is the way of
asking the box take a look at what I
have in candidate and the way you feel
about things right now is this valid
according to yang and according to your
running state if this is okay then you
can proceed to the commit state and
here's the confirmed commit so the new
things here are the parameters we have
the confirmed element we are sure that
you know if something goes wrong inside
of the next ten seconds it needs to roll
back if it survives 10 seconds we're
fine
this would have saved me in 1998 from
taking out half of Sweden for example by
mistyping AC else and locking myself out
of some core routers because had I done
this with a conference I'm out I
couldn't come back and confirm the
commit so it would have rolled back and
saved me a crazy car ride and in this
case we also send the persist ID and
here's what the confirming commit looks
like it's a commit like any else but you
just you send there persists parameter
here so that means that you can forget
about the timer you're now can can't
forget that state and you're running
okay we're getting closer to the final
crescendo here is configuring multiple
devices so in this case our network
engineer wants to configure multiple
devices at once and rollback everything
if anything fails right so yeah you set
up a VPN if anything fails on any of the
participating boxes you want all of them
to reliably come back to where they were
before I started meddling with them same
steps as in the previous example but
we'll do it in parallel with one stop
along the way so this allows for two
phase commit transactions over network
devices given of course that devices do
work actually has the capabilities that
is required for all these steps great um
when a failure occur can you can you
have that from a different channel and
send oh I notice a failure and
notice there is a failure or ooh so
let's say you have an alarm system on
the side that suddenly gets a trap
rather the year they would need to be
some sort of a channel between that
alarm system and whatever client is
actually doing it see what I mean
there's no way for you as a third party
to come in and say stop what you're
doing okay unless you know of the
transaction ID actually then you go in
and say yeah it gets intricate okay so
here's the preparer face for you for the
people with some database background so
three devices right step one prepared
and prepare this case means that you
look everything clear the candidate edit
the candidate and then you validates all
right so now you know that the content
that you have in the candidates is
validated by the books so that's a
traditional preparer face all the
subscribers or all the members in the
transaction have said what you're
telling me looks good okay if any of the
devices here say well Act you just gave
me garbled inputs you can just mm to the
candidate and unlock the data store and
go back and think about what happens
okay so nothing has actually been done
to the running data store yet but again
the devices have told you that what
you're asking me to do looks reasonable
and then you commit then you probably do
a confirm commit here because of course
while the data that you send to the box
will be semantically it's syntactically
and structurally valid it may be wrong
right you may have the wrong bgp
parameter so your neighbor doesn't come
up you may have the wrong VPN endpoints
so there's no data flowing right so
between the step of a commit and a
confirming commit you can go ahead and
do whatever burn in or feature tests
that you that you need so you will have
a timeout that is appropriate for
whatever you're going to do and if any
of those fails if something you know
there's no there's no Carrier Ethernet
that the inter inter frame delay is too
high so that's not gonna work all you
have to do is well if you're rude
you can just kill the session because a
killed session on a confirm or come it
actually means roll back and you just
kill the sessions or close the sessions
on all devices and they will reliably
roll back so you're back to where you
were if they all work then you can
reliably just confirm the commits and
then unlock the data store so this will
formally protect you from the common
mistakes that we all do in the sense
that it provides two phase commit based
transactions any questions did you catch
that I looked unsure when I said that
because I'm not sure after persist I'm
not so sure if you have an open session
with the outstanding commit you kill the
session just the Box rollback yes the
question is does it unlock so if you
just went ahead you've locked it right
you did this commit something failed and
you said just kill the session well
you're certain if you're sitting there
with lock it also releases locking it
does okay I had that one I was very
unsure about thank you guys
any other questions because this is my
last slide before I conclude that you
know everything about net conf this is
probably more of a deviation but what
about how does that conf interact with
other elements which may configure a
switch right because I have controllers
which manipulate ARP tables and if
you're telling me that I have to lock
something and then wait for that yeah
that is a universally challenging thing
and it's not new for net conf
or for yang for that matter it's a tough
thang but what kiri diese don't use
anything else it depends on so either
from from observation because the
company that I work for use to cell
navcom service into people running or
building network equipment there are two
kind of ways of going about it the one
is to take the step and say look the
Netcom server actually owns the data
right so everything that happens to that
data mean needs to be conforming with
yang
that's what cleanslate implementations
to put it mildly right when you have a
green field the other one is to actually
try and separate them based on what is
is that you want to do so you have
napkin for certain things and then you
have the others for other things and you
hope that there's no interaction between
them yeah because the the Netcom for
everything won't apply because it seems
the time scale is very human operator
focused right so you won't get a turn
around fast enough so an example for net
call for for so an example I have is
that we have software which effectively
manipulates the art table based on local
health checks I'm not going to do the
entire time frame of streaming something
up centrally to then have something like
that yeah
so what you would normally do that's a
good that's a good one so would you
would normally do is actually declare
that operational so you wouldn't even
meddle with that through net confident
it's gonna mean yeah record-holder
similar thing with routes we have static
routes which are done through net cons
and BGP routes that are not done through
net cons and you know exactly what you
said time scales it's dynamic and so on
and they're separate so I don't know if
you'd call the BGP routes operational
you can read them but but you definitely
don't configure them any routes that you
configure are static routes at least
this is how we work so there is also
another working group called the ITRs
working group interface rewriting system
and their intent is to support ephemeral
configuration with a very high rate of
change so it's sort of a short circuit
through the net comp path but is still
yang model data yeah it's a third type
right config non config operational and
ephemeral yeah it might be appropriate
as a sort of an concluding remark is
that again and thank you for patients
this is a pretty basic and
straightforward tutorial style
presentation so don't take away from
this that we're not doing other things
we are doing a whole lot of other things
in the ITF both around protocol
development
and certainly around the yang language
itself and modules so this is this is
the entry level welcome to NAV configure
and kind of kind of presentation and of
course you are all now able to obtain
configuration configure network devices
and explain to someone how Netcom
transactions work how am I on time yeah
officially dangerous you can now shoot
yourself in the foot using two-phase
commits if there's no other questions
thank you guys that's it for this time
and no wait here's what want to do
here's what we want to do we want to
send the link to the evaluation don't we
for the EDD you team there is really
there is one yes yes um how do we do
that
it's pretty pointless to put it up on
the projector there is an evaluation
link on the agenda for this item please
again the the the the usefulness for me
is if you guys rip into what I just did
and help me make this much better so I
can iterate over the content many many
many times
go ahead and do we have your style heal
your slides available they would be good
one they will be available at the same
place that the evaluation link is a good
one yes very nice well setup thank you
sir
okay if nothing else thank you everybody
thanks for coming