Oh
ah
this is going on yes okay I'm gonna go
ahead and get started my name is Alice
Russo I work for the RFC production
Center I'm living in Seattle but I work
for AMS which is based in fremont
california this tutorial is to talk
about the options and specifically we go
over XML to RFC Andonov edit in more
detail also briefed intros to a couple
of the option other options one is
crammed down RFC 26 29 which uses
markdown to create a text output or xml
output if you're used to working on wiki
pages you might be happiest with that
option and licks to RFC which relies on
licks which I understand is popular in
academia academia and there will be time
for questions also if you have any
questions along the way or you don't
understand what I said I spoke too
quickly then feel free to ask a question
in the in the middle as well so just to
get a general feel for what tools people
are already familiar with can you raise
your hand if you've used XML to RFC to
create an internet draft before great
and raise your hand if you have XML RFC
installed on your machine you run it
locally as opposed to on the online
converter okay so about half of people
using XML RFC heaven so locally how
about Enroth edit has anyone ever used
in rough edit to make an internet draft
mm-hmm
one person and then getting a feel for
the these other two cramdown RFC 2629
anybody use that how about pan dock to
RFC it's another mark down option that's
not on this nope how about licks to RFC
which is listed there nope okay I'd say
XML the RFC is really popular from what
we're seeing in terms of I only see the
internet drafts that are approved for
publication as rfcs but a lot of people
are using XML to RFC how they actually
get to that XML file their various paths
some of which I'll talk about today so
basically this is geared for at the
beginning of your process so this slides
from Scott Radnor's newcomer tutorial
but before it even goes to the working
group you're working on your draft it's
a good time to choose your authoring
tool and some people don't choose and
then later they have co-authors who say
oh I'd really like to do this in XML RFC
or that whatever their favorite oh
that's one of the other ones I didn't
ask that is the word template has anyone
used the microsoft word template to
create an internet dressed okay a couple
um so you know you don't have to stick
with the same authoring tool through
this whole process and but it helps if
you choose at the beginning when your
authoring your internet draft something
that works for you so you can focus on
the content and less so on the
formatting so going through some of the
options here Enroth edit is using an
inner off source file and the tool
credit is Stefan Sanderson and this is
the website where it's available you can
you install it as a GUI that's a
side-by-side you see the inner off on
one side and a text output on the other
side it starts off with a template for
an internet draft it has easy reference
creation meaning you put in
RFC number and it just pops in the
reference information automatically
creates your table of contents talk
stands for table of contents and in
brief you edit within the application
I'd say this is a pretty easy one for
someone who's scared of XML and doesn't
want to do microsoft word in turn off
that it's pretty quick quick to start
XML to RFC is one that most people a lot
of people in the room were already
familiar with you can install it or you
can just run it in the web converter i
recommend the web converter for a lot of
people because it's always going to be
up to date the template for the ID there
are lots of them available from the
tools i HAF torg site and for narf see
at our site and this is probably the
most comprehensive reference creation
that you have because it's not just
RFC's is also internet-drafts and then
there's citation library for I Triple E
references and i'll be going into more
detail on this but also for other stos
documents not necessarily as up-to-date
as is useful but it's a good starting
point the table of contents is created
automatically you can edit in your
favorite editor and then run the
converter there is a v2 the if you
install it locally it has a GUI see and
you can theoretically edit in there but
it's pretty lightweight um the word
template relies on Microsoft Word and
it's written up completely in RFC 53 85
um you run in your own copy of word
there is a template to start with it's
not quite as easy for making references
and you do have to run a perl script
after you use a special template with
special margins set etc then you run a
perl script to get the plain text output
yes
so the question is I'm just saying the
question into the mic the question is
what operating systems do these run on
so right word wherever you have word
installed the XML tharp see there's a
Windows package and a Mac package I'm
not actually sure how it works for
others and then in Rafah edit definitely
has a mac package I think well look at
the site later in the tutorial so it's
worth going to check this huh so looking
at some of the other options the one on
the Left cramdown RFC 2069 and the one
on the right Pam tarp see are both
marked down so that's you know the rich
text basically that you use to create a
wiki page very similar cram down it has
a github page also there was a tutorial
at IHF 92 that went into the details of
crammed down and i'll be going over more
detail in this tutorial but basically
the file that you create is mark down
but also some yeah mille which is a
subset of JSON and you run the converter
and you can get an xml file that you
then feed to xml to RFC to get your
plain text the licks to RFC also has a
github page and all of these do because
their work in progress to a certain
extent yeah it the converter relies on
various software for liquor RFC that you
have to have installed so it's worth
going to read the documentation to see
if it's something that you already
already have you probably know if you
already use latex or licks that you
would like this one pan dr. RFC's
written up in RFC 7328 it's fairly
similar to to cram down RFC 26 29 in
terms of the mark
but they made different decisions about
how to handle internet-draft specific
things like references and figures and
tables it references within the document
okay so I'm going to go into more detail
on and off edit it's what you see is
what you get it's a side-by-side view
you download it it has spell checker
built in a template built in it gets
updated um why would you choose it
because it's an easy way to make an
internet draft that's going to be
accepted by I Dean it's it automatically
does some of the things for you
generating the references from RFC ref
text that's a plain text file provided
by the RFC editor so it's going to be up
to date with the right format and also
the most recently published RFC's it's
pretty straightforward you could provide
also the in Raphael sure if your
document was accepted for publication
approved for publication as an RFC you
could provide in Raphael to the RFC
editor and we would use it we edit in
raw files and we're edit XML files
during the publication process that said
you don't have to have a source file to
provide if your documents approved we
will create a source file if you for
example edited plain text from scratch
or used microsoft word template so quick
start with in roth edit you download you
install and you say new draft from
template it builds the reference list
automatically it's the same file that I
mentioned and there's the preloaded
template which you can also just
download if you want it if you for
example you want to run in Roth on the
command line basically in Roth markup is
simplistic and makes text output there's
another in Roth template available from
the RC editor site and I meant to say
the being these slides are available
from our theatre org ford / materi
ford / the name of this tutorial
basically but i'll put the i can put the
link up later it's also available from
the edgy team wiki pages so this in roth
basics the commands i'll start with a
period it's very basic and is that
interoffice developed decades ago so you
tell it exactly how much you want to
indent you tell it if you want text to
be wrapped or not wrapped line breaks
and page breaks and keeping lines
together it's all very explicit so to
contrast with xml RFC you wouldn't be
worrying about things like this with xml
RFC it's going to choose for you how
many spaces to indent and depending on
what element you used it'll choose when
to wrap the text but if you're already
familiar with this it's not too
complicated this is a screenshot of the
automated table of contents so you're
not trying to pull that together as
mentioned the reference insertion is
pretty straightforward and you can even
give the references different labels you
know some people like to label the
reference i could v2 instead of the RFC
number and it has that functionality and
then my recommendation here for if
you're inserting references to other
sources like internet-drafts or non rfcs
then i would recommend copying and
pasting them from existing documents
rather than typing them from scratch but
basically you're just putting an indent
command before each one so this is the
screenshot of the managed reference list
you can see at the top there's it's in
an inner off comment that's a ghosted
out so it's hard to see it on this slide
but basically as the author you just put
in a list of numbers of RFC numbers
optional labels and then it the pro in
turn off edits creating everything below
the yellow arrow so it's automatically
creating the reference entry
which is nice another reason you might
choose and Ralph edit is if you're
starting with an internet draft that
someone you don't have a source file for
because you can take an existing
internet draft in plain text and feed it
to enter off edit and it will try to
convert it to enter off as assuming that
internet draft that you started with is
in I'd units formed it'll succeed and
then you'll have a source file to start
with so that would be i'd say the quick
and easy way to get to a source file as
opposed to if you're starting with a an
internet draft and you want to make an
XML file there's not a really viable
text to XML tool that exists currently
so it's more of a manual process and
i'll talk more about that later there's
also some integration with the ITF tools
diff service so you can see the changes
in post URL this is the automated diff
generation you can tell it's relying on
RFC diff which does the side by side
diffs and there's more functionality and
inner off edit some of its on this slide
so I was going to demo this but I think
for the sake of moving forward basically
like I said the text to enter off demo
would be that you feed it a plain text
file and it will try to create a source
file front from there any questions
about Enroth edit before I move on to
XML to RFC okay so this is the one that
there's the most familiarity in the room
but feel free to stop me if you have a
question it converts your xml source
file into text HTML in raw fun paginate
text or expanded XML and so you can
create an internet draft that's in the
right format also the RFC editor can use
it change a few attributes and it
creates an RFC
it's available from XML trfc that i HAF
torgue which used to be XML that
resource said org but the I think that's
a redirect in place so why would you
choose this similar reasons as in Roth
edit this one has the advantage that you
would get HTML output or even PDF and
then also exchanging the source file
with authors is more useful if you have
if everyone likes to use XML and you can
you know theoretically put metadata in
it at this point the XML files that are
uploaded to the ID submission tool there
is no automatic metadata just extraction
but in theory you could say okay how
many of the XML files in the ID
repository contain XYZ you know element
and we will take your xml file another
reason is looking toward the future you
may be aware that the RFC series editor
named Heather Flanagan has been working
on an effort to change the format of
RFC's so this doesn't affect you as an
author of an internet draft it's just to
be aware that in the future instead of
publishing only plaintext RFC's there
will be at HTML output PDF output with
nice links this is different from the
HTML versions of RFC's available from
tools that I GF network which you may be
familiar with for more information about
what the RSC is doing take a look at the
RSC format FAQ this is slated for
upcoming years so maybe we would see
this in a year and draft hoffman xml RFC
is defining a new vocabulary for xml RFC
in order to add some of the
functionality needed for the new output
formats so in theory if you're choosing
to use xml RFC today then in a couple
years if you wanted to use your source
file you would have XML RFC v3 available
and a converter from v2 to v3
vocabulary so that your file would make
the new pretty output that's going to be
available some people are excited about
this format effort also because it will
allow non-ascii characters for example
in your name so back to v2 this tool was
rewritten from scratch if you're
familiar with the old XML tariff see
that it's now written it's been you know
more maintained it is stricter when you
run the converter you might be seeing
errors that you didn't see a while ago
XML to RFC at IHS or giz the mailing
list and people just send questions
there and there's also an f eight sorry
this is the link to the reporting bugs
if you're having problems with you too
but I'd say most of the bugs for you to
our ironed out works works well so for
initial setup you have some choices if
you want to use the tool on the web or
install it if you want to use the
citation libraries as they're available
online or maintain your own copy and
edit you know whatever editor you'd like
to edit XML in so if you just want to
get started as quickly as possible just
use the online converter use the
citation libraries that are available
online use your favorite text editor
edit the raw XML as opposed to you know
some people want to use XML mind and
then have special configuration you're
welcome to do that but this is the quick
start also the template so the templates
are available here for a generic draf
i'd recommend the draft davies template
bear which has some instructions in
comments and then if you're writing a
mid which is a specific kind of document
there's also a special template that for
writing a mid available there are some
other options for creating an xml file
so the ID creation wizard kind of lets
you fill out a form on the web and then
it creates the xml file for like your
author element and title basically the
the starting front matter it takes care
of it for you so if I were starting with
a text file that I had no source file
for and I wanted to create
internet-draft I might just start with
this ID wizard because you could copy
and paste from your existing draft and
it would just get you started with it a
nice template with your author elements
and all that also the markdown tools
will create xml files so crammed down
our panda RFC as well as looks RFC
create xml files that you then could
feed to XML to RFC just some basics for
XML the elements are nested have opened
and closed tags excuse me that
attributes have quoted values case
sensitive replace certain characters
that you don't want the XML parser to
parse like your left hand sign or an
ampersand if you're putting in a big
I'll talk about this more but you're
putting in a chunk of XML into your
internet draft then you want to use see
data a special tag for the figure
artwork so it tells it not to parse that
so you don't have to replace all the
characters this authoring document has
more XML basics so the document
structure is basically a front middle
and back this slide doesn't have the
open and close elements for each of
those but it's you know open front close
front open middle vazhno etc it's kind
of counterintuitive and that the author
information goes at the beginning of the
xml file and we're all used to seeing
the author information at the end of the
output at the end of the internet draft
the tricky part the reason that it's
hard to build a text to XML converter
for use with XML photo use with XML RFC
is in the middle in your sections when
you actually get into the
meat of your document putting in figures
or tables or even lists nested lists
it's tricky to automate some of that
especially complicated tables so if
you're creating an internet draft you
want to make an author element for
yourself as I mentioned the IID wizard
can make that easy T tags go around
every paragraph figure artwork both
elements go around each figure and when
you want to cite a reference you've put
in an xref xref standing for crossref
it's a little confusing because xref is
not only for in-text citations it's also
xref if you want to say see section 9
you would also use extra target equals
and you will give given an identifier to
section 9 and tell put that as the
target yep the drawing meaning like how
to create ascii art okay so the question
is am I going to talk about drawing tips
or how to create figure artwork so
because as mentioned because output is
plain text a lot of people have fancy
ascii art in there internet-drafts I
don't really dive into that in in this
tutorial my primary recommendation for
getting ascii art into your source file
is to go and look at another internet
draft or RFC where you like what they've
done and start with that as your
I agree so he said it would be good to
know which ones are good examples to
follow and which aren't I've actually
been thinking about that lately in terms
of saying some specific RFC numbers that
might be good examples for bid diagrams
or flow charts that could be good
starting points yes tamashii Curtis net
I have a question can i put figure into
paragraph I mean figure inside of D or
outside I actually think the DTD lets
you do either one um but I don't
remember off the top of my head but if
you it's not going to affect your
spacing like if you close the tea close
your paragraph and you put in the figure
it's not gonna give you extra white
space so I I think you close the tea and
then open your figure generally okay
thank you yep would it be possible to
become a copy of your presentation yes
the slides are currently available let
me see if I can show where they are
thank you ah they're not so I thought
they were tools underscore IDs
underscore FCS underscore 94 PDF ah I
see what I see what materials page you
were referring to
ok and
hmm so this page it's on tools that ITF
torg group ed wiki tutorial by IDF has
all the tutorials and the one that I was
recommending before is this mark down in
the am old tutorial that's crammed down
the one that I mentioned earlier but i
recommend the edgy wiki for finding
finding to pass tutorials ok i'm going
back to slides no problem so one
question comes up a lot for people
working on XML Darcy's what am I
supposed to do with the IPR attribute so
generally trust 2009 02 is the most
commonly used one then this pre 53 78
trust 2009 02 is the one that adds an
extra paragraph that has to do basically
with if your text relies on old RFC's
and I recommend looking at the FAQ
available from trustee aye GA org and
all the license and foes on that site
this is an empty author block I wouldn't
recommend starting with an empty author
block in philly and then so much as i
mentioned that ID wizard kind of you
just fill in a form with your name and
then it spits it out with your
information all in the right places if
you're using lists and ID's definitely
seem to have a lot of lists these are
the styles that are available so empty
is simply indentation you have numbers
letters symbols is to get the bulleted
list which in ASCII comes out the top
level bullet is an O lowercase o but you
can actually control user
instruction that's what the p.i RFC text
lists symbols you can control what the
bullets are hanging gets used a lot for
definitions and then format % d is an
example of how you could do a customized
list so it'll let you do % d 4 digit % c
for character % I if you're doing Roman
numerals and you could change it like if
you wanted to say rec one rec to rec 3
you can do format wreck % d and then
it'll make it the list like that so that
the example I was just talking about for
customized lists it's you're a big fan
of parentheses you can do that so this I
mentioned earlier see data so in a
figure artwork it won't parse the
content if you put in this see data
especially useful if you're trying to
put XML or HTML into your draft because
you don't have to replace all the angle
brackets so references is usually the
sticking point as I mentioned there are
citation libraries and they have names
that you can expect so for RFC's it's
always RFC capitalized and a four digit
identifier and for internet-drafts it
always starts with I hyphen D and when
you don't include a version number it it
chooses the most recent one so this is a
screenshot from XML trfc webpage so if
you scroll down on that page below the
converter it lists the citation
libraries that are available and some
people maintain a copy locally but
there's no need to do that in the sense
that if you're using the online
converter it recognizes the names and it
will pull the reference information from
these libraries so as mentioned there's
RFC an internet draft
and then there's w3c documents jsf which
is like XMPP the jabber documents freak
3gpp documents and then miscellaneous
has a big mix of different SEOs and
they're not very up-to-date there is a
new one which is bib XML 6 which has I
Tripoli documents in it so that the
content of that directory actually has
been updated so you may find it has the
more recent I Tripoli document you want
to reference so one of the tricky parts
of the XML RFC is that there are
different ways to get the references to
do what you want the short way is just
using and include it's relying on an RFC
specific processing instruction so some
people don't don't like it the long way
is that you define an entity at the top
and then you call the entity in the
references section and the really long
way would be that you copy and paste in
the holding of the complete reference
element which you need to do if you're
referencing something that's not
available in the in the citation
libraries sorry okay so the point
they're making it works offline so if
you're relying on the citation libraries
and you don't have a copy of them on
your machine then it's nice to have the
complete reference in there if you're
trying to get output from XML RFC while
you're offline right so it's just it's a
sync problem right because as you know
internet-drafts often get replaced so
what was on version 05 when you wrote
your you reference version 05 of an
internet draft and then I you know a
month later it could be on version 10
um or other SD owes documents obviously
change change over time so the downside
of doing number three is that you're
basically hard coding all the content of
the reference into your document and
some references are a moving target so
this is an example of the short way you
just put the include into the reference
section and you get this text output
based on the reference elements that are
in the citation library this is an
example of the long way at the top of
the document you have these entities
it's helpful if you're starting with a
template so you know what to put in
there and then in the references section
you use the ampersand and the really
long way is to put in the whole
reference element so for RFC 2119 it
doesn't really make sense to put in the
whole reference because it's an easy one
to use the citation library for but if
you wanted to reference a Wikipedia page
or something you know you're gonna have
to make a reference from scratch so this
is a template for a reference from
scratch you um the DTD does require the
date element but it can be empty so you
can have an empty date element in there
another trick with the reference from
scratch is let's say you're citing
another stos document and you want the
organization to be listed as the author
you leave the author attributes empty so
initial surname full name blank and then
you put organization you put in the
right now that organization element is
empty but you put in a content there and
then it will list that organization as
the author cuz thats helpful in that you
don't have to hack the author attributes
to try to get the output you want so for
reference tags some people like to use
one instead of RFC 2119 you know one two
three numeric or
Frances you can control that with a
processing instruction called sim refs
so if you set sim refs equal to no sim
means symbolic then you would get the
the numbers and also some people like to
get use the names instead of the RFC
numbers like mentioned I could be too
this is a one of the downfalls I think
of XML Tower of cv2 is in order to do
that you actually have to put the whole
reference complete reference element
into the document and then change the
anchor whereas when we were talking
about in roth edit it was easy you just
put the label next to the number and it
generated the right thing also once you
change the anchor to I could be two then
every time you want to cite that
document in the body you know within the
body of your document you need to have
xref target equals I could be too
because you've renamed it okay going
into the table structure in XML Darcy
it's called text table it does not have
as much functionality as an HTML table
obviously it's pretty pretty basic
that's why I put the little white box in
the bottom that says figure artwork
elements are another option so basically
if you want to do anything fancy with
the table like you want to have to row
you know combined rose or component
behind columns you have to make it
yourself meaning it's basically ascii
art table and you put it into a figure
artwork text table works well for
straightforward tables some tips I
recommend using X rough for references
instead of typing in square brackets
into your the body of your document that
would similarly for section references
you don't want to say see section 9 you
want to say see xref target equals I
Anna considerations and for lists you
want to use the list element don't put
the list in as a figure and do the
indentation yourself the beauty of the
list element is that it'll line
everything up nicely and it does nested
lists just fine so some people with v2
are seeing errors like the DTD errors
that they hadn't seen before because V
one was more forgiving for example list
is not nested in T and it gives you a
message about the DTD so the solution is
you have to put a tee tag around the
whole list or simply leave a preceding
paragraph open um similarly ampersands
it used to do like a best-effort thing
and it would not complain but now it
complains so XML parts entity ref no
name it's basically you have an
ampersand in your text you need to
replace it with the entity for an
ampersand people used to working with
xml probably don't find it that tricky
but then you can put your xml file to
work you can exchange it with your
co-authors there's the ability to put
just a normal xml comment inside of the
xml file or you could use the see refs
functionality there's a something called
a CRF element and it lets you put
comments in line you can upload your xml
file to the submission tool when you
post your draft you can send your xml
file as mentioned to the RFC editor when
your documents approved will already
have it if you uploaded it to submission
tool some people like to read the HTML
output of their of their xml file and
join rescue made an xslt that lets you
have nice HTML this is where you can go
for more information about it it's
within the browser as opposed to getting
the HTML output from XML tarp see where
you feed it the xml file and say you
want the HTML output then it runs and
gives you HTML this is just within the
browser so if your document is approved
for publication and we're going to
receive your xml file we find it helpful
if you consolidate your ex
into one file for example some people
use local citation libraries run the
file using XML to RFC as available
online then we know it runs with the
current version of X melt RFC and if
you're using processing instructions
that are local or specific to alternate
XML converters they will be ignored by
XML Darcy so some of what you expected
and output might not be there one
problem people run into with XML Darcy
is white space how do I control the
white space within my a document how do
I get blank lines between list items or
compress the text so there are no blank
lines so there's a processing
instruction compact and there's also a
sub compact compact equals yes will not
start each main section on a new page
which in the opinion of the RFC etter is
good subcompact equals no puts one blank
line between each list item and then V
space is an element that's kind of a
hack that forces blank lines or even can
just force a line break but hopefully
you can just set compact equals yes and
subcompact deals no and you'll be happy
with output but if you're not you can
turn them on and off within the document
and compact also affects the text table
output so some people like their tables
to have a blank line between each row
and compact actually you have to set
compact equal to no there's lots more
functionality and i recommend the faq
that's the last link is also linked to
from the main page i wrote it so that's
part of why i recommend it but also it's
some of the common things that people
run into so I
I think I'll just do the middle of these
demos so this is what the I don't know
if I can be of my display to do the
right thing for this this is the
converter form so you can see the
options you have there basically if you
if your goal is to upload your internet
draft you want it set to plain text and
file this RFC markup option is the
script fit if you ever look at the tools
ITF torg HTML it has the links it's I
haven't actually tried that out but that
would give you an HTML output with with
links and then scrolling down on this
page as I mentioned is the list of the
citation libraries if you're looking for
that and I thought there was a link to
the wizard on this page but there's not
so it's X melt RFC hyphen wizard so this
is the one I mentioned a couple of times
just for it's basically like making your
own template instead of starting with a
template you know you fill out this form
and then farther down on the page it's
creating the xml file so it won't help
you with tricky things like tables or
lists but it will help you get that
frontmatter going so personally I edit
my xml file in Emacs and then I convert
using XML Darcy and its installed on the
command line
which there's not much to demo there
just creates your txt file okay going
over them mark down one of the markdown
options so this tool is created by
carsten bormann as mentioned the link to
his slides are their slides RFC dot
space was his tutorial that goes into
details so I've just picked a few
highlights from his tutorial to give you
a taste for what his tools like in case
you wanna if it's appealing to you um
basically you feed a markdown file to
his tool it creates XML and then you
feed that XML to XML RFC which you could
either do on the command line or do I'm
using the online converter so why would
you choose this tool as Hugh describes
its distraction-free writing so you can
focus on the content the QuickStart
guide is used gem to install his tool
and pip to install XML RFC then you edit
your mark down in your favorite editor
or a specific markdown editor like Mac
down or markdown pad and this is what it
kind of looks like if you've edited a
wiki page it's very similar where I
think it gets a little clunky is the
table I mean you could argue the tables
also clunky writing in XML directly
where it says code block or just indent
by greater than 4 so there's four
Tilda's in a row there and that's
basically going to create a figure
artwork in the xml output and then every
time you want to cite a document you use
curly braces and that's going to be the
equivalent of like extra target equals
blah and then as mentioned some portion
of the document is in y amal which does
not look like mark down so the
references section itself and also the
author information and the document
metadata like its title etc would be
more
this format check out his tutorial
slides there's also a side-by-side
converter that's a work in progress so
you have the mark down on the left and
your text output on the right so that's
the drafter so some people is anyone
ever used drafter before it's been
around a while okay so this is a new
version of drafters is a tool by richard
barnes it's not complete but it it'll do
the basics and it's relying on cram down
so kind of just gives you an interface a
wet a web accessible interface to the
markdown converter also if you go to
drafter j/s it'll give you a starter
template which you can also get from the
cram down page so finally looking
briefly at licks to RFC this is nique
nico nico williams tool and he is not a
fan of xml so he made these slides and
um apparently this for some people likes
this is something they're already
familiar with and this is an easy way to
get an xml file and you use licks which
is available on linux and as mentioned
mostly used in academia free stable easy
to use a complete internet-draft can be
written with no xml it does all the
functionality we've talked about and it
does let you rely on the citation
library and you can get HTML plain text
or xml to feed xml dark sea so this site
for that i had the URL at the beginning
of the
presentation that I do not have it on
this slide and there it is licks org as
though that's for the format nevermind
that's not his um there's a github page
for licks to RFC so finally beyond
creating internet-draft there are lots
of other tools that are available
especially from tools that ITF gorg so
just to give you a general idea under
search and view documents ITF doc
fetches something install for your in
Firefox that lets you have a search bar
for our seed internet-drafts they're a
bunch of different options for diff
tools if you like side by side dips or
you like in line diffs or you need to
change the color of the diffs it lets
you do all that and the daily dose is
automatically created a list of links
relevant new ITF information the working
groups a lot of working groups have
wikis on tools that ITF torg the email
aliases have actually been switched over
to the main idea better work so from the
data tracker pages what i mean by an
email alias is that if you know that you
need to email all the relevant people
for a specific internet draft and ask
them you know hey do you have a source
file or make comments on their draft
they have set up these email at aliases
that are basically like the drafts name
at ITF torque but it dash all usually
but or if you want to email the working
group chairs you can put the working
group acronym dash WG arrow sorry dash
chairs at ITF that org but from the data
tracker pages it'll show you the what
those aliases are and they can be useful
for communicating with the right people
they're also a demand RSS feeds
available like keeping up with the most
recently published RFC's or
internet-drafts also all the as you may
know since you're at the meeting their
various
tools for helping to follow the ITF
meeting and um also formal language
checking for example if you have a B and
F in your document there's an a B and F
parts are available nib review tools so
as mentioned XML to RFC list is a really
good place to go if you have a question
like why isn't my xml file running the
RFC editor is here this week will be at
a desk monday through thursday near
registration and we're good for
questions like what tool should i start
with or how do i get the source file for
this old RFC that i'm working on the
best document for or um various other
who should I talk to about something
we're welcome you know you're welcome to
come and ask us and there is a short
survey available um surveymonkey com and
ready for any questions okay well ended
an hour early so um if you want to bring
if you have a problem with an xml file
something you want me to look at welcome
to bring it up here and i highly
recommend attending another tutorial
there's internationalization tutorial if
you're dealing at all with that in your
working group at three o'clock or you
could go catch the second half of the
newcomers there's also newcomers in
japanese going on right now so yeah
enjoy your ID chip meeting
you