beyond you you want to know how to
compile correctly your yang models thank
you hi good afternoon my name is Raja
vodka and in this part of the tutorial I
would like to talk more about practical
things about the steps that you probably
want to do with your yang modules and
especially if you are preparing these
modules for publication in idea of
standards so if you do all the steps and
the compilation will be okay then I know
I will be happy I guess otherwise you
will you know
Harris you to make it compile properly
because that's quite important of course
if people publish in Internet drafts and
modules that don't compile it very
helpful anyway as before if you have any
questions or comments please feel free
to interrupt me anytime and ask good so
these are the steps I would like to
cover this is actually an abridged
version of a tutorial that's available
at the end wiki and that web version has
some some some more information more
details and also covers other steps so
maybe you really want to go to that page
and try some things yourself and if you
want to really try something you need
some software to be installed so
primarily it's it's being that's all
it's about and then there are other
open-source tools that you probably want
to make things happen
primarily it is with XML to library with
its tools
this package is mostly part of base
operating systems or it can be easily
installed and then there are some
optional parts I recommend to use Java
based tools Jing and Trang written by
James Clark and you can download them
from that URL and of course you need a
good editor too especially if you want
to edit xml then I would although I must
admit I am biased being an MX user for
the last 25 years maybe but really
believe me I think that at least in the
open source area and especially for
editing XML Emacs is by far the best
tool you can get there are other
commercial editors like oxygen that
might be helpful as well but I have not
used them so I can only talk about in X
essentially and because I am a Mac user
I use comics on OS X which works fine
alright
yes just a quick comment there's a
number of open-source projects coming on
to do WYSIWYG sort of young editors web
based and also Eclipse plugins and
things like that we should collect these
together and have them posted I may be
young again central or something yes of
course about I'm sort of hardcore
old-fashioned UNIX users so we prefer to
know tools so that's a good point I've
been trying we've been on a couple of
tools to yangsun trouble so we really
want to collect all of these you've got
the question all the time so there are
tools to produce young mothers but also
libraries so if you know of of any that
are not on the yang central let us know
it's a right for everybody right
now a few works about her peeing peeing
is an open source to working in in
peyten most of it was written by Martin
miracle with contributions from myself
and a few other people and for some for
some steps and it's some accessibility
stylesheets for example are part of
being p.m. distribution so but you also
want to use this XSLT processor and some
some tools are also written in shell
scripts so Pyong is written in in Titan
we have been trying to support both
Titan 2 and Titan 3 versions and it's
really painful I can tell you especially
because we also want to support older
python 2 versions and it's becoming more
and more complicated and I don't like
this part actually very much anyway
theoretically you should be able to use
paying with both fighting - and Python 3
peeing is extensible via plugins a
number of plugins is already available
and you can write your own plugins if
you want and I think as a part of the
hackathon maybe some new plugins have
been written I don't know and so this is
quite useful and I will show you a
selection of the plugins that are
available now and that are part of PM
distribution being is under active
development
fortunately the last stable version is
quite recent so most plugins are already
in that stable version otherwise usually
you can get the most recent plugins bug
fixes and so on from the github page
can question is that stable version
using a gang 1.1 yet no we have we have
a branch on github which is which is
supposed to contain yang 1.1 changes but
it's it's not very comprehensive so far
so you cannot expect really to validate
in one I think that again I want that
one branch already and I was so the
follow-up question is to know when that
branch might more like when would it
become comprehensive enough because as a
draft author I'm having issues
validating my documents and Benoit is
you know a place runs you know
evaluation tests all mine are failing
but only because that are using yang
window on yes I know that's a
shortcoming but we have to discuss this
with Martin and of course it's it's open
source so we just have other things to
do and but of course we're going to do
that part as well as soon as possible
but depends on many things actually
anyway the last table version is one
point six you have discovered a buck so
that you cannot use unicode as part of
all this I mean non ASCII characters
currently so probably there will soon be
a 1.6 1.1 version but anyway this new
version is installable via the standard
titan packaging tool tip and if you if
you have an older version I would
recommend you to install that this new
version because it has other nice
features like bash completion and so on
UNIX manual pages are part of PM
distribution so you can find
most information about command line or
all information about command line
parameters from those men you apply
pages so in particular those tool tools
that I'm going to cover are described in
manual pages so here is a selection of
interesting plugins that are part of
Penn distribution most of them just
produce a specific output and these
plugins these output plugins are
selected via the dash F command line
switch and each of the plugins usually
has a number of its specific command
line parameters and options so idea of
draft points point of view let's say fan
you know new to writing a draft which
are all the tools that too much too much
of information I'm trying to see what is
the most learned information what I am
going to cover really the basic steps
you you want to do with such such
internet or with such a yang module
this is just for for information for you
to see what you can do with the angle
route kind of different outputs you can
generate so I'm not going to I'm not
complaining about this I'm trying to you
know see which is more alluring for me
from my point of view I think that you
will be I go to see it in in the
following slides probably what you
really wants to do but anyway so I don't
know whether Carl covered the fact that
we also have an xml-based syntax for for
yang modules no you didn't so I'm going
to tell you that what all those curly
braces and so on they are they so called
the yang syntax but you can also use an
alternative and equivalent XML based
syntax which is
in and so two plugins to output begins
NPN just convert between each other then
you can generate this dog schemas and I
will talk about that later
actually this is now not current
information and the access debugging has
been removed from version 1.6 because it
was it has been incomplete and
deprecated for a long time and people
just got confused although they asked
users that want to use access D for some
strange reason but it's not available in
NPN anymore tree plug-in is very useful
I will talk about that later then there
are some plugins for producing UML stuff
and there is another even more special
plug-in that can used B output then can
be used as input to a software which is
called OmniGraffle for it's only for for
Mac and iPad users what apparently it
produces very nice picture so it might
be interesting to know about that and
then there are some other plugins for
producing HTML input for browsers
different thought J's tree and height of
tree and then there are plugins that
allow for converting between XML and
JSON encoding of instance documents I
will also briefly mentioned Alice's done
and then there is also another
relatively new plug-in that enables
German generation of sample instance
documents in XML so much stuff maybe
some more
bodies are those data in my opinion the
most interesting and important
well ITF is just command lines which
isn't it so it depends yeah I I will I
will actually mention that so first of
all you need to have some editor to
produce yang module as I told you I'm a
Mac user I don't want to get into some
religious wars but let me just mention
that you you can also use VI or win
using syntax file that's available from
that URL but as I said Emacs has very
advanced and XML mode that enables
editing XML in in a very efficient and
user-friendly way so in fact all my yang
mode use I have written so far almost I
write them as XML in the in syntax and
then I convert them to the yang syntax
for publishing internet draft of
Costco's
that's more readable but the source
format for me is XML some people think
that this is a bit weird so I'm not
going to recommend it to you in any way
but if you are interested in that there
is some H wiki page I wrote that gives
you some background and some reasons why
I'm doing this strength thing and of
course we need a real-life example as
Skaro hat mpls so I chose and this is
also in the web version of this tutorial
I chose Turing machine that we all know
and love and these young modules are
also
in PNG distribution in that directory
and for those who are really into fun
there are the crate he wrote Turing
machines simulator that can be managed
by a net confusing these this beta model
I think it's quite interestingly we used
it in another tutorials somewhere and I
think it was really quite useful so this
is an URL where you can find that Turing
machine simulator written in C and using
some net conf libraries that you also
need to install anyway so here are the
very essential steps that probably
everybody has to do before publishing
yang module in an internal draft so
first of all you have to check the yang
module for for correctly this is done
easily by using PN without any other
command-line options just like that and
if this check reveals any any errors
problem then you have to go back to the
editor and correct them of course
otherwise then you can move further and
then use that so I don't know if you
want to call it a plug-in or something
but it it you meant like producing the
the canonical ordering of as the plugin
okay alright so anyway just terminology
right yes my point was that plugins can
do more than just output translation
they can add command line parameters
they can do validation and so on okay so
in any case if you use that - - IETF
option stricter strict rules will be
used for checking your module so in
particular you have to have your your
yang statements in a very particular
order that's defined in RFC 6020 and in
the internet graph that defines the Eng
1.1 and other things that are not needed
in general but it is required because of
the rules from RFC 687 that essentially
this check with that does dies - ITF
will not show any errors and so please
do that before you publish your draft
and then of course if you want to see
what the beta model looks like and also
this is an information that should be
included in in an internet draft because
that's very useful as an overview of a
beta model content it's very useful to
you that 3 output again that gives you
some tree based representation of the
data model I will show you how it looks
like on the next slide and Carlo already
had some examples there are some symbols
used in that tree view that may need
some explanation so you can get this by
using that tree help option and if you
if we use it on that Turing machine
module it will show this output so as
you can see in the Turing machine data
model we have some
some state they tell that are marked
with our oh and it falls essentially the
Turing machine definition so we have
state and the state of the Turing
machine head position and then
representation of the tape then we also
have a configuration that basically
describes the transition function for
the Turing machine and then we also have
an RPC for a Turing machine which
enables you to initialize and start the
computation and the parameter there is
the input of it means the initial
content of the tape and there is also
one notification the Turing machine is
supposed to send this notification as
soon as the computation holds and if it
also sends as a parameter the state in
which the Turing machine has ended up
right so the main point of doing this is
to have all errors that a young beta
model can cover that means read only
state data read write configuration data
are pcs and notifications if I'm not
mistaken we advised the people who
produce draft to put the three in the
draft that's correct yes that's what I
said yeah it's really it's really useful
and if you that please also include some
explanation of the tree symbols because
that's useful you can find some template
for such a section in the existing graph
so just copy and paste this into your
draft and tau about
validation so it's also useful if you
include some some example of a
configuration in your draft and again
it's very useful if you do include this
this information to have an information
that's correct and that's valid
unfortunately it happens every once in a
while that if I try to validate those
examples they just do not are invalid so
this can just confuse people so again
it's important if you include such
examples to perform validation in
pairing this validation of instance data
can be done using or in xml but I will
tell you how to do it Jason as well
later so it's done using so-called
distal schemas and I don't want to go
into details about this digital family
of schemas because it requires some XML
background but it's an international
standard and it's a coordinated set of
schemas that essentially replace w3c
schema language and add some more
possibilities for validating semantics
rules and so on so we decided to use
these schemas for validating XML and
various standard mapping of young data
models to business chemos these are
described in RFC 6110 and the point of
and it's implemented at peeing peeing in
that bsdl plugging and this plugin
actually produces free schemas that are
part of the digital standard it's relax
ng schema that's used for checking
grammar the schema itself and data types
that Carl talks both
and then another schema is about
semantic constraints which is schema
Tron another well-known XML schema
language and then third part that not
that's not very common so far is used
for adding defaults to the instant
document I will again explain why this
is necessary and how it works on on the
next slide you can produce all three
schemas by using that yang to digital
tool this is actually a UNIX shell
script and I wrote it in order to
provide an example how to use these dis
da schemas in in validating tool in fact
it turns out that it's useful in and by
itself it's okay to use it for
validating but if you want to write a
tool that also does some validation
please don't put any execs and calling
shells and and using this shell script
this is not not very good just look into
the shell script and replicate all those
steps using some library function calls
and and so on this is for example what's
done in lipid conf library so this shell
script tool can be really effectively
used from a command line like this so we
can produce these free schemas like this
so you have to specify the target but
you want to generate the schemas for
that means in our case we want to
generate the schema for configuration
right and here you can see the three
schemas are stored are saved in files
and then I names are here on the right
and so if we generate these schemas we
can use
then for for editing a configuration for
sample example of configuration let's
say but in order to save some typing we
can also use another a yang plug-in
which is called sample XML skeleton for
producing a skeleton instance document
which takes the data model and then puts
an instance instance of every node
that's found in that data model into the
the XML document but then this skeleton
the human has to be edited usually it's
not valid because for example for every
choice that's in the data model you will
have all cases that are part of the
choice included in that instance
document so usually in to remove all
cases but one from the instance document
in order to make it Valley but anyway
it's just a technical point if you edit
this sample skeleton you can also use
emacs for example for on the file
validation of this for the an external
mode by the way you need to convert be
the relax and G schema to so-called
compact syntax if you want to do that
and then if you load that into the MX it
will validate the instance document on
the fly using that relax ng schema and
now we can do all steps of validating
the instance document using yang to this
dual script this can be done for our
Turing machine model as follows
so here are the arrows and the
annotations explain what the
command-line parameters are about so
- as tells the tool to use the pre
generated schemas rather than generate
them anew which takes some time then
- J tells the tool to use that Jing Java
based validator if you don't use this -
J the script uses the usual XML lint
that's part of the lip XML suite
but in my experience this XML lint it
works fine but the problem with it is
that it it's error messages are really
horrible and they don't tell you
anything about what's really happening
what's wrong with the document whereas
Jing is really very very much focused
and tells you exactly what you need to
change in order to make the document
well it's rare comment using this every
time and then you have to provide the
base name like the tool needs to find
beef 3 schema files so you need to give
some some information about the name of
these schema files and then you provide
an instance XML document that you want
to validate and that's all and you can
see that the validation is done in three
steps
it essentially means in every step one
of the schemas relax ng DSR L and schema
Tron is used and in this case no errors
are found if there are some errors in
the document you will see some error
messages that may help you to locate the
source of the problem ok so here is a
picture which explains what's really
going on so and this
exactly follows the procedure how young
when instance document is supposed to be
validated against young data model so in
this case we first have to check the
structure the schema itself the grammar
of the document and data types and this
is water relax ng schema does really
well so that the first step and then
before we can check the semantic
constraints we have to fill in all
defaults that may be missing in the
instance document because that the rule
of of yang that all the default have to
be provided before the semantic
constraints are checked and that cement
so this is what the DSR L schema
provides so this step is done and the
initial XML document is changed so that
all defaults are present in the new
document and this new document is then
checked for all the semantic rules that
are written in the data model are then
checked using the schema from schema so
in in effect this covers all all
validity constraints that can be
expressed in yang with some very minor
exception that I do not discuss here so
that's also the reason why it was not
very avoid it was not actually possible
to use XML schema because XML schema
only would could only cover the first
part on the left and there is no
official way you can actually use also
schema to run with XML schema but that's
not that's not official that just some
in official extension of XML schema and
so that's why we decided to use that as
deal and schema languages any questions
all this validation I know it's a bit
technical so you may want to look into
the web version of this tutorial but
this is how it is supposed to work and
we can also then use the same procedure
for validating what we did previously
was validation of configuration here the
config target but we can use it for
other document types other instance
documents for example on a notification
for the Turing machine we have one
notification and then notification can
look like this for example and we can
validate this XML instance document in
the same way just using another target
but that's indicated with that - T
parameter and it says that the schema
should be for notification this time and
so as you can see the yang to this
discret produces three new schemas that
can be used for validating notifications
and this time it does the validation at
the same time so again no errors are
found and the validation procedure is
exactly the same as before and now the
last part I want to talk about is
converting XML instances to Jason and
vice-versa Carl told you and maybe this
will be part of the next edition of this
tutorial that there is a new protocol
that's an alternative to net conf it's
called rest conf and apart from other
changes it also allows for using Jason
instead or along with XML
for sending data back and forth between
the client and server so Jason is an
optional media typing in Raskin and
tieng also provides some means for
converting for actually doing a schema
based conversion between XML and Jason
that's quite important you cannot use
any of the shelf XML to JSON object
Jason to XML converter because there is
quite a lot of information in the yang
data model that has to be taken into
account in order to really produce valid
results so for example it's important
that numbers from XML are converted to
Jason numbers and not to Jason strings
and so on so peeing helps with this and
the way how this is implemented is that
peeing can or Jason Jason XSL plugin can
use can be used for producing an
accessibility stylesheet and as soon as
you have this accessibility stylesheet
you can use it for converting any
external instance it means
configurations the data notifications
our PC contents you can convert them
from XML to Jason and I think this is
quite useful for them for example if you
need to perform this conversion in the
device it's not necessary to have Python
installed installed on the device so you
can just produce this accessibility
stylesheet offline then install it and
this XSLT stylesheet only changes if the
data model is changed so as soon as as
long as your device uses the same data
model you can use this accessibility
style sheet for Corvette converting
external to Jason
just by using any available of the shelf
XSLT processor so then of course the
accessibility processor is applied to
and the stylesheet is applied to an XML
instance document in the usual way so
for example if you use that ubiquitous
XSLT proc processor it's done like this
and as I said the same things stylesheet
covers all document types and by the way
PN also as J talks plugging that does
the opposite conversion and for example
this can be useful for validating JSON
data I have been using it quite
regularly for validating JSON data it's
seems a bit complicated so you need to
convert Jason first to XML in order to
be very able to validate that XML using
that bsdl procedure that I explained but
it's - in my experience it works quite
finite and it is doable so unless we
have some JSON schema implemented this
is what Cal wants to do this is as far
as I know the only way available in
open-source tools how we can validate
jason documented against en data model
and to conclude this is just a list of
other resources that you might want to
comes out so it's not working group
pages where you can find
yes questions link away from University
and I used to have P warnings when I
used validations is that my models is
too large lots of definitions just
wondering is that some kind of
suggestions from the ITF that I should
not to make the module very large
because actually I'm doing the yaw
models for dhcpv6
is lots of work very large model so I
just considering whether I have to
submit submit the model into small sub
modules but actually I have never met
this wording like beta model to large I
can offend Martin Martin who should know
maybe if you can send us really what the
warning where maybe it's just related to
do long line so something like that but
it just says I have lots of definitions
those definitions not the file size it's
the size not the sub size of the file
that's real strange because I'm not
aware of any arbitrary limits that you
can have for the depths of the hierarchy
for example things like that so you know
for issues that are found and you should
post the issue to the github tracker the
P and github trackers so that then it
would be great usually such bucks that
are reported on the github they are
dealt with
yes dv6
yes I found that is there is no warnings
just you know a just but I don't know
it's a couple of weeks ago if you use
p.m. with really huge beta models and we
had some to test it can take some time
that's true it it's not terribly fast
but for normal life they come all that
should work just fine and really there
are no limits concerning the number of
definitions or the depths of the
hierarchy or things like that so sorry
Jason here are you you might have met it
mention at the beginning I'm sorry if I
missed it but are your slides posted
somewhere there's a lot of good links
and games the same as the first part of
the tutorial
they will be available on the ITF I do
pages or okay well there's me on the
meeting materials pages just there's a
link for meeting materials people may go
levain there so this might be useful to
stick them on there right they will be
on the edu web page now there will be in
multiple places like yang central and
the yang doctors home page was a
linguist yes a lot of not confront yang
relative information is in the on the
net consent route pages that are
maintained one by nd Biermann then PN
McKay apart from this tutorial the
extended version of it
it also constant contains other
tutorials and other materials and more
stuff is also available on the yang
central site where you can also download
some other tools for working with Yin
documents so any more questions right
got a question do we have people here
that are working with different SDOs
okay there is something that I would
like you to mention Martin in the latest
version of Pahang 1.6 there is like an
extra option that we could use because
normally is going to complain that you
don't use like an ITF - prefix right so
if you come from I Triple E for example
you can put like a - a triple e it won't
not campaign about that so I just wanted
to change the ITF option into as do
something that well there is a new
option it's so I so we had this - - ITF
option that checks the rules in the yang
guidelines document 60 87 and it also
checks that module name begins with I
ITF and it checks that the name XML
namespace is one of the
by their faces so I changed that plug in
so that now there are two different
options one is called - does lint and it
just checks all the generic
recommendations from RFC sixty eight
seven but it does not check you know the
name of the module must start with IETF
and so on so if you if you want to check
for the guidelines for a module that is
not an IDF module might be vendor
specific also you can use the limped
option to behind it's gonna check all
the recommendations and guidelines and
one last thing as well on this interest
do because I'm receiving more and more
requests from different se owes who want
to do like yang models and that's
perfectly fine is good news we have in
the latest guidelines for writing yang
models RFC sixty eighty seven bits we've
gots a couple of extra sections for
different as dioz please review this
just to see if it makes sense right if
we're missing anything that will be key
but a triple e m EF BB F okay so if
there are no more questions thank you
very much for attention and I think now
we will continue thank you thank you for
your help so now what we have is what's
called a yang editing device session
this is for the people who have like
yang models and we have the available
some available yang doctors here so what
I plan to do is if you want to discuss
one of your yang models
we just take a few minutes here to write
your model and we're going to divide the
forces that you've got and you can have
maybe 15 minutes with the yang doctors
for all the questions that were not
answered either in the peeing session or
in the yang session before so who has
got like yang data models that you won't
discuss 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 all right you
please come here we're going to write
them down we want to get the best yang
doctor for you depending on a technology
etc and then we're going to assign one
to you and we'll just reshuffle the
chairs or whatever and you'll work in
your corner on on that yang model and
for the mythical guys I mean this is
where we could stop the recording thanks