[Music]
welcome back everyone our next speaker
creates streamlined natural interfaces
that span the divide between human and
machine among her recent projects you'll
find Soto which is a wearable courted
keyboard that works with Bluetooth
Bluetooth Bluetooth devices like
smartphones and tablets her educational
background includes Yale and brown she
was published at both and she's been
extensively published in BuzzFeed
covering topics like human machine
interaction and how technology is
received in our society and its role
today we draw on her expertise to learn
about how using biomimicry can unlock
the illusion of human elements within
robots and machines please welcome to
the hackaday super conference stage
christine Sunu hi everybody
so I'm Christine and I'd like it if
before we started this talk everybody
could get up please stand up just
everybody stand up shake it out you know
wave your arms around high-five your
neighbor I just want you to feel for a
second
what a cool and streamlined an
incredibly complex machine your own body
is just feel yourself being alive for a
second because that's really what this
talk is gonna be about it is about being
alive and The effect of that on how we
design Hardware so I am much like you a
generalist in this awesome endless
learning of electronics and making so I
previously ran the developer community
at particle and then I worked on weird
open-source robots at BuzzFeed and I
currently do random product work and I
post tutorials and electronics and
design at hack pretty calm and most of
my work focuses on emotive interactivity
in physical and digital objects which
means really I work on getting people to
feel living emotions
about an alive objects and that may be
oh no it's fine yeah
and whether that's like an app or a
hardware product or a robot pet and one
of the shortcuts to getting a user to
feel deep emotions whether that's
attachment care joy or even sometimes
fear is to use biomimicry I know I'm the
worst so we do see biomimicry in tech
news all the time these days right like
a lot of technologists will focus on
biomimicry because it offers these
amazing creative solutions to heart
problems but of course there's another
much simpler reason to use it uh which
is that biomimicry is fun and funny and
crazy and super weird and it makes us
feel something right that other more
typical robots don't necessarily do I
mean let's face it this is much funnier
than this and this is much cuter than
this although this is cool and this is
way more terrifying than this just at a
baseline
I mean look we're humans right we've
evolved to deal with other living things
you know so when machines decide to
imitate these living things it makes us
feel these feelings that we usually
reserved for our animal and insect and
human friends and that can make us react
much more strongly and emotionally to a
robotic stimulus the power of these
emotions that we feel when we see
something we think is alive it can be
overwhelming I was talking about emotive
biomimicry a couple months ago at an
event in San Francisco and I had this
little bot and I carried her around the
whole time while I discussed with
people how you think your robot being
alive right and then at the end this
little day what we feel when we see him
that's too deep programming I'm really
uncomfortable watching him be in pain
and I think it's a good question to ask
whether we're ever gonna be able to see
something that appears alive and feel
nothing to watch it struggle and feel
nothing to watch it die and feel nothing
living things need other living things
and we are alive aren't we okay so I'm
pretty sure that they yeah I am pretty
sure that they added the applause at the
end there because I thought that I
walked off the stage too
shocked gasping followed by total
silence people were really affected by
the worm getting killed on stage even
though I told them it was a robot the
entire talk was about the illusion they
were experiencing at that moment and I
had the words this is a robot projected
on the screen behind me like there was a
cognitive scientist who came out to me
after the talk and told me that even
though she knew everything I was doing
she still cried when I snapped the word
in worm in half cried which goes to show
that uh human emotions are very powerful
and making your users feel something can
be a very very powerful thing
I mean feelings are important right
feelings guide the perception of your
product they guide clicks on buttons
such as subscribe and like and Add to
Cart they guide user experience and
biomimicry is a really powerful shortcut
to feelings so it becomes really useful
in product design or even in weekend
hacking projects I mean if I'm building
something for myself I'm much more
likely to do a task if I feel generally
good when you know I accomplish this
task or bad when I don't
and feelings are important just largely
right they can make an uncomfortable bot
feel more comfortable that can make an
unprecedented new technology just slide
into your life like you never know you
lived without it so the question isn't
will by adding biomimicry to my hacker
product make people feel something about
it and make it more usable the question
is how do I do it effectively and how do
I get the feeling and the experience
that I want my users to have the answer
has a lot to do with the factors that go
into the human perception of life as
well as a lot of the physical
associations with the appearance and the
texture and the movement and there's
also this other issue which is that you
know in the at the end of the day a
robot is a robot no matter how alive it
seems no matter how attached we are we
already knew that and recognizing the
fact that you know all your users will
know that your robot is a robot actually
is quite an important part of designing
a good interface but let's start with
this the inside not just of your robot
but of your users minds which is kind of
crazy and can be like much more
important in fact your users are human
and if you understand the way that
humans perceive life and the way that
humans use empathy it's going to be much
easier to get people really attached to
your bot or your app or your interface
so I'm gonna go over this a little bit
on the quicker side the talk where I
broke the worm in half was like all
about this so you can always look that
up later and then be mad at me for
breaking the worm I'm sorry but the the
bottom line is living things need right
we need food we need water we need a big
box of resistors from Aliexpress and we
also need other living things
we have societies based around our need
for each other to be near each other to
fight and conquer each other to help and
love and care for each other so we are
constantly on the lookout for other
living things and whether they're likely
to help us or hurt us so when we're
looking for life we're often looking for
something that seems like us
and that usually means something that
has evidence of need-need starts with
purpose so I have to start with that
when I design these robots like us a
lifelike robot should be happy when it
fulfills its purpose or upset when it
can't and you should be able to see that
every time you interact with it so the
firm's purpose was to not die while
being crushed on stage at a conference
um and if it started failing to fulfill
its purpose it would act really
uncomfortable
it was very consistent in its struggle
and in struggling more to show that it
was in greater danger and this alone was
actually pretty convincing to people but
as you can imagine if something were to
react the same way every time we would
start classifying it as not really alive
you know you start to see like the hand
and the puppet making all the motions
and you're like no that's not really a
thing and this starts to be a point
about emotion because a lot of times our
emotions can feel like totally random to
us so if you're building an emotional
robot that humans are gonna relate to
you kind of have to recreate the sense
of randomness and emotions that humans
actually feel I mean we're not only
experiencing this one reaction every
time something bad happens right
like sometimes we're gonna be like
frustrated and that's okay so sometimes
we're gonna be skeptical or like
frustrated or angry or just like really
sad right like when something bad
happens you have a varying number of
reactions that really can be based on so
so so many factors so recreating that is
actually really important and what's
especially good is if you can recreate
these random reactions that are highly
convincing consistent in their reactions
but unpredictable in the range of
emotions and that is possible
particularly when your bot is really
simple so when it was uncomfortable the
firmware would twitch really
unpredictably although the speed and
amplitude of the anim
were correlated to the discomfort it was
not possible for me to predict like the
actual number of twitches or the way
that it twitched because that was kind
of based on random noise so while you
could sense the discomfort increased
while you know you squeezed him for
longer you really had no sense that he
was gonna do like the same motion over
and over and it got to be really
convincing to the point that like I as a
person who wrote the code was really
uncomfortable watching it which is a
good sign that you're probably doing the
emotional randomness right and making a
robot that appears to have needs and
appears to have randomness in this way
is really effective especially when you
couple it you know with really what I'm
about to talk about next because there's
a lot that goes into the external part
of biomimicry that takes these
psychological elements and solidifies
them so in terms of outward appearance I
find that it's better to mimic
combinations of creatures rather than a
specific critter because when you use
the appearance of an own life-form you
can create these expectations that are
really hard to fulfill I like the
strategy of hand picking associations
with existing creatures whether they're
real or fictional and putting them
together into a critter that optimally
represents what you want your audience
to feel about it so you can go really
simple like in the case of this tail
pillow from Japan that I'm sure a lot of
you have seen it expresses emotions just
with the movement of the tail this very
familiar animal emotion and that can be
really effective and you know again
simple you can also go big and try to
mix a lot of emotions together a lot of
associations together in this case we
get this big mess of like slightly alien
cuteness but associations are a
double-edged sword because people will
draw associations for things that you
didn't really mean to put in or you know
that you didn't really think about that
hard so you can get very close to all of
these cute things and then with like a
single hardware choice ruin all the work
that you did to take the exterior in the
first place you know associations serve
to support the story of your bot should
make people feel good should it scare
them shouldn't scare these people but
not these people you know you got a
handpick the right
ones and then throw out the ones you
don't want this is a really careful game
that you have to play so texture becomes
a really important part of this as well
I'm not talking about just like the
outside like what you covered it with
right because something can look really
soft outside and nice and that doesn't
necessarily mean it feels right when you
squeeze it or hug it if you can feel a
big box of electronics inside even the
most charming crater is gonna go from
magic to robotic in the span of a single
hug if you've got something that's meant
to be hugged you should be able to hug
it and if it's meant to seem alive it
should feel alive when you hug it and a
lot of times this means not only
calibrating the associations with the
appearance of the bots but also making
layers of biome and making elements so
that when you touch it squeeze it and
interact with it it really feels real
the inside matters the skeleton that you
create can be felt and when you make
layers an actual imitation of biology it
can make your critter look and feel
really right so this is burbles the
starfish cat from my starfish cat human
discomfort experiment some of you met
burbles here at super con las year the
deal with burbles is you know you you
pet him and he starts to meow and he
reaches for you with like his cute
little kitty claws he does like kneading
motion the cats do then you pick him up
and you put him on your body and he
looks for bare skin using the IR
thermometers on his base and then
suckles you with a terrifying mouth that
contains a gross pneumatic motor that I
bought from China so burbles was meant
to feel like unnerving ly alive right I
think I'm trying to max people out in
the simultaneous pity and discomfort so
I had to layer in a structure that would
like protect his insides while also
feeling pretty biological and muscular
and of course if you're trying to
imitate biological layers it really does
help to do biological layers so this is
the structure that I was using this is a
layered structure with cartilaginous
bones that are made from flecks PLA like
in a circle and are contained in this
like stringy wire wrap muscle which is
like spongy and feels kind of like an
actual you know interstitial and then
the thin layer of subcutaneous silicone
that feels more like skin and it ends in
this fluffy pedable exterior that's made
from feathery yarn so it's seamless so
you end up with this very you know
convincing fluffy thing that feels
bright when you squish it and the effect
of these layers so profound to see
because it made people react really
strongly to holding burbles whether that
meant that they thought it was really
cute or they thought it was really
horrifying or they thought the first one
and then the second one really fast
which is usually what happened and you
know so people would hug him and compare
him to like their dogs and animals but
like regardless they were kind of
thinking he was a little alive and the
same thing kind of happens with the fur
worm like okay it's very spooky to see
this without skin it's not cute but you
know what isn't cute when it's just a
skeleton the movements that I put into
the worm were made much more realistic
because of the skeleton underneath it it
also made it a lot stronger so it made
something that would move and break in a
lifelike way so it was predictable in a
way that you would expect living things
to be predictable not in the things that
not in the way that you would expect
robots to be predictable you know and
while we're on the topic there let's
talk about motion because motion is a
huge part of life and if we don't get
the motion right we're not really gonna
get you know the illusion of life right
here either because a real looking robot
with like halting expressions or
unpredictable movement I think you have
to it it's gonna put us squarely in the
uncanny valley and it's like generally
super creepy robots are binary and
binary motion where you're going from
like 0 to 100 pretty fast
you know it's seen as starkly robotic
you have no movement and then you have
movement you have resting
- like well-thought-out predetermined
action pretty immediately and animals
don't do that because we don't do the
predetermined action thing quite so well
as a robot you know we're not sure and
so we need to be safe so we often
accelerate into motion
we often kind of weave around
the right kind of motion we're often
clumsy there's more mistakes we use
motion as a modem for expression which
is something that robots typically don't
do we portray our emotions with the and
our uncertainty with the speed and
acceleration of our movement so you know
if you want to trick somebody into
thinking something is alive you've got
to get away from this and go towards
this I mean this is about acceleration
adding a really particular acceleration
profile can create something that feels
evocative playful expressive and even
you know alive and this specific robot
is programmed for like a very specific
expression and acceleration right but
even on a small scale acceleration can
make a big difference in the perception
of life so when building one of my BOTS
I did this experiment where I had these
two servos next to each other and one
was doing this like you know binary
motion that was just like on/off and the
other ones doing this slowly
accelerating thing and one of my lab
mates said that to her one of those seem
pretty typical as robots went but she
was pretty sure that the other one was
gonna kill her in her sleep and could I
please keep it away from her desk so
motion really matters both in the
instant perception of life and in the
creation of these robotic expressions
that can feel really lifelike okay so
that's pretty much gonna take care of
like a few of the basics on how you make
something appear life like using
biomimicry and human factors but when
we're building lifelike interfaces we
have to consider that in the end a robot
is a robot and that is a fundamentally
different relationship than that between
humans and living things and that's
actually kind of great and not a
disadvantage at all as long as you
account for it that's the key look no
matter what we do to make a robot more
lifelike it's always gonna be a robot we
know it's a robot we built it consumer
so it's a robot they took it out of the
box and powered it on so you know the
relationship between humans and cats
from the get-go is going to be
fundamentally different than the
relationship between humans and cat
robots so when you're designing a robot
that imitates a known form of life
you should always ask yourself what is
the thing that's important about the
alive version of this and how is the
robot version going to be different and
this may seem like an obvious set of
questions to ask but it's actually
surprising how often these questions get
left behind or addressed impartially
when they're addressed well we notice we
buy the products we use them we think
about them all the time the Amazon echo
for example it had some biomat making
elements but you know the the creators
of the echo obviously understood that
the echo is as different from an actual
executive assistant as a bicycle is from
a horse they didn't try to make the
Amazon echo do absolutely everything
that an EI would you because like you
know why would you try to do that it's a
completely different object the on a
live version is completely different in
the way we perceive relate to and use it
and if you didn't account for design and
account for the fact that you were going
to think it's a robot in the design and
the documentation and the usability
right that result in pretty poor
products and kind of confused users but
if you accept on the other hand that a
robot is a robot you can sometimes even
avoid the uncanny valley entirely and
open up these avenues for usability that
become really popular and like really
useful to humans so let's figure out
that to kind of illustrate this point
I'd like to close the talk with a case
study on robot pets so I often find
myself building these like
semi-realistic robot critters in my
basement like you do so I have some
thoughts about you know kind of and
opinions about like how much they should
cost and what kind of design you should
get for that price and some of you
probably guessed that this is what I'm
about to talk about there has already
been some backlash about Sony's new AIBO
this is a $1700 robotic revival of the
old toys of the early 2000s so the new
AIBO is said to learn with a cloud-based
brain so by uploading your floor plan
and more to Sony services it can learn
to navigate your house and develop a
unique personality which by the way will
run you about $25 a month and the
American tech audience seems like
understandably disinterested in this
like cuz automatic uploads of your house
and more to the cloud sounds like could
be uncomfortable and maybe even
dangerous like subject to surveillance
or unsafe data storage or unsafe
you know privacy I don't know for most
honestly the price tag is also just too
high for what you're getting but I'd
like to kind of examine what went into
the creation of the I bow I would guess
that if I asked the designers of the
modern Ivo these questions I would get
something like these answers right like
that the important parts of having a job
involve the interaction and the playing
and the movements that indicate
affection and that a robot dog is
distinguished from a regular dog by its
greater ease of use I would also expect
a third answer that goes something like
stop asking me these questions Christine
we're just trying to sell the cloud
service and you're asking too many
questions
but in any case I don't think that these
answers are necessarily incorrect I
don't think they're necessarily
incorrect from a business perspective
but from a user's perspective they are
rather incomplete and I think that you
know I'm glad I'm here at this
conference so I think that as we can
hackers and fast thinkers and like
hardware heroes we can do a lot better
so let's redesign the modern robot pet
around truer more accurate reasons for
having a pet all right so with pets
right like bonding often comes as a
result of Karen work the joy you feel
when your dog finally learns to sit and
stay is amplified because of all this
work that you put into helping that dog
learn that trick and in the process of
training the dog you developed this
whole bond with the animal right buying
the sit stay trick from the AppStore
doesn't really have the same effect
and even outside of the emotional
bonding a lot of folks keep dogs not in
spite of but because they require work
to maintain you know like parents who
get family dogs to teach children
responsibility young couples who get
dogs as a practice run before having a
kid I'm like in the age bracket where
everybody's doing that right now so you
know a dog that you don't have to work
for not only loses a lot of the
emotional impact of a regular dog but it
also kind of defeats some of the purpose
for a lot of people getting a dog in the
first place so you know in light of that
I say that we strike this earlier goal
and with the understanding of the
importance of work in owning pets as a
part of the relationship that a human
has with a pet let's make a better one
cuz look robot pets can be so much more
than just pets um since people are gonna
perceive it as a robot right let's stop
pretending that it's only gonna be a dog
like robots are awesome let's just lean
into that I love robots okay so but our
robot dog so this is what you know you
can imagine like our robot dog should
add a minimum yes provide the sense of
therapeutic bonding that people get from
like the mutual companionship of having
a dog and it can do that through a lot
of the biomimicry that we talked about
already just through some of these
factors looking at the way that it
interacts with the humans and its
appearance and the way it feels but look
a robot is also an object of work right
if you or I were to buy a robot dog
chances are we do it because we're gonna
hack on it on the weekends and the
popularity of the original AIBO among
researchers in the past wasn't really a
surprise because it was like some of the
coolest open hardware that you could get
at that time modern robot pets
hypothetically could give us some of the
feedback of an organic pet right like
some of this feeling of bonding to it
and companionship but at the same time
being one that we can upgrade and work
on and personalize which is sort of like
you know the non-biological equivalent
of training your dog like you put the
work into it you upgrade it and you know
it learns and that to me sounds a lot
better than a robot that restricts all
of its potential to pretend to be like
this low-tech meat dog oh could look
like a pet that you work to upgrade
right is both the pet of the future and
the pet of the past like we haven't
actually changed the thing that makes
the dog feel really important to us
we're just accounted for the fact that
it's now also a robot which like we
should account for so and of course if
you're skeptical that people will bond
with an object by working on it I would
encourage you to consider how you feel
about your weekend projects you know
your hacks or how people feel about
their cars or how people feel about
their gardens or how kids feel about
their Legos when they've built something
or their sketch books or their blocks
right working on objects gives us this
profound sense of accomplishment and it
also gives us this very unique bond to
the object itself and so working on
robot pets
actually could give us this deep bond to
the creature that already exhibits
pretty good therapeutic biomimicry right
so like we have the bond to it as an
animal and now we have the bond to it as
an object of work as a robot so I
haven't really yet seen the raw head of
the future but you know I think that we
can all agree that when it comes it's
gonna be like totally dope because we're
in an era where makers are everywhere
and stem has become this essential and
highly necessary part of Education so
well-designed robot paths which are open
and have the potential for this endless
customization could play a really huge
role in synthesizing technology with
play with curation with creation and
with care
I mean look dogs used to perform all
these essential functions for humans
right like herding and hunting and again
I don't necessarily want to change that
I just want to account for the fact that
now it's a robot - so robot pets by the
same measure should perform a bunch of
easy tasks that a robot could do you
know or they should contain helpful
technology like a reading light or a hot
spot or a temperature sensor or a
weather display and ideally you know you
as the user should be able to work on
these functions yourself as a part of
the responsibility of taking care of and
upgrading your pet just you know phrases
of the future uh-huh and that way each
robot pet actually becomes that unique
and one-of-a-kind critter that we really
look at and hope for when we get a dog
right that like each puppy ages into
this unique and one-of-a-kind dog and
each robot pet that you start with as
you build on it and hack on it and you
know turn it into really your own thing
becomes a unique and one-of-a-kind
animal as well um so I could actually
just literally talk about this all day
but I won't oh but if you really want to
know about robot pet design hypothetical
advantages of a bespoke robot familiar
etc or anything about the biomimicry
principles that we talked about how it
applies not just to little robots but
how it applies to apps how it applies to
interfaces how it applies to everything
come talk to me come see me after the
talk I'm around I'd love to talk to you
you can also reach me here this is my
email this is me on Twitter that's my
website so cool and that's it thank you
everyone