[Music]
hello testing hi take two hi welcome
back
I'd like to introduce our next speaker
she is a CEO of Bantam Tools which was
formerly known as other machine company
maker of the awesome prototyping tool we
all know of the other mill the machine
was recently acquired by former MakerBot
CEO and co-founder Bre Pettis danielle
has a degree in chemical engineering
from MIT and a PhD in material science
and engineering from UT Austin please
give a warm welcome to the hackaday
super conference stage dr. Daniel Apple
Stone hello everybody I was here a
couple years ago it's really awesome to
be back here again because it means my
company didn't die in hardware
I've been running a hardware business
for the past five years as she mentioned
it was a it has a new owner now which is
good for R&D and if you're like me you
think about how your work and what you
do everyday fits in with the rest of the
world and what's going on and how maybe
the things that you do might benefit
society I think about that all the time
I hope you think about that too and
judging some of the a kadai Prize
entries I'd know that there's there's a
lot of people thinking about how to
improve the situation for others so this
talk is about how I think the hacker
community and maker community and R&D
focused community can help us build the
work force of 2030 we're in this strange
paradox at the moment where a lot of the
country feels like this they feel like
they read articles about automation and
there's a pressure of I had this job I
maybe have been working it in ten years
and it's going to go away sometime soon
and there's a lot of tension around that
but the paradox comes in and that
actually with the baby boomer retirement
a lot of folks in many
our retiring and automation is
eliminating the lower-skilled jobs and
creating millions of jobs that are
slightly higher in skill level so this
fact that I present up here that came
from a Deloitte study it's two million
the the net job change from automation
over the 10 over the next ten years is
actually that there will be two million
unfilled jobs that we won't have enough
people with enough skill to take these
jobs and part of why this happened was
because we got rid of shop class and
there wasn't a path into using your
hands and building and manufacturing
fell out of favor and I got involved and
my company to to build desktop sized
robots for milling and cutting and
really they're just small scale
manufacturing robots and part of the
reason was well let's let's refocus our
efforts on chop class but I think we
have to do more than just that so here's
the state of manufacturing I was really
surprised to to discover these facts
when I started digging that US
manufacturing is still the largest in
the world that it's twelve percent of
our GDP as manufacturing nine percent of
everybody with a job in this country is
in manufacturing and the weirdest part
is that there's already over half a
million unfilled manufacturing jobs all
across the country and they pay really
well so it doesn't make sense to me this
thing doesn't add up
because I have a lot of you know friends
who are who are struggling and kind of
service industry jobs and they're trying
to figure out how do I get these
manufacturing jobs how do i how do i
step into these open positions and
actually get the skills that i need so i
faced this problem as an employer and we
manufacture our hardware it's a if you
if you know what a CNC machine is if you
don't you should look it up they're
great
so it's a it's a 17 pound high precision
super R'lyeh
Boal CNC machine a lot of people use it
for prototyping aluminum and electronics
we assemble that machine in Berkeley we
use components that are manufactured
most of them 80% manufactured in the
United States and if you're in the Bay
Area don't think about that as a
manufacturing job type of place and in
fact there were not a lot of people
around us that were trained to do
manufacturing jobs and when I think
about the big picture of 2 million jobs
over 10 years and then translate that to
a very small scale of like what did we
experience as a company when we were
trying to hire manufacturers and we only
had to hire a couple dozen to do
manufacturing there was only one thing
that worked for us and oh by the way
this is the we make we used to be called
other machine company with the other
mill we change it to Bantam Tools
because well this name I got to choose
and this was small powerful machines and
the Bantam is a small powerful rooster
so it made a lot of sense to me Oh
PCB prototyping aluminum parts yes so
this is how we did it we hired people
who were traditionally non-technical
people but who were scrappy enough to go
get themselves some technical skills
this is Emily
she's our product manager she took she
was an acupuncturist but went to tech
shop and took a bunch every class at
tech shop and then heard about our
company and decided hey you know what I
think I might be able to do that and she
started assembling machines with us so
you know not a traditional technical
person getting her own kind of exposure
to these skills and then coming to us
and she's been really incredible this is
Owen kind of the same story he went to
school for videography but he found
Adafruit online and I started doing
tinkering he wanted to be an inventor he
started looking at Instructables and
just putting things together and it was
the same type of thing like a person who
would not be a traditional manufacturer
getting exposure on their own on their
own time and building themselves
as a technical person who could who
could help out in manufacturing quality
control same thing happened with Beth
who was an architect who had ran a
Kickstarter campaign and realized how I
made this one thing maybe I could make
many of these maybe I'll get into
manufacturing and she joined our team I
could go on and on this is Devin
he worked at Home Depot same thing
learning electronics he got into IT and
decided you know I want to build things
with my hands I'm tired of my job where
I don't get to build things and this is
this is amber she worked at the zoo she
was really into spreadsheets she thought
maybe she would be good at quality
control and she joined our team as well
and when I thought about how do we solve
this bigger problem with manufacturing
and all these unfilled jobs when we have
all of these really capable people
I just turned inward and I thought okay
maybe the key is let's get a lot more
people who are not traditional people
exposed to robots and manufacturing
because really robots are the future of
manufacturing I think that's pretty
pretty much inevitable but everyday
people don't have a lot of exposure to
robots so this is the challenge because
I'm an operator and I like running
businesses I think about what is the
what is the way that I could possibly
solve that and I thought ten years two
million jobs
that's roughly 200,000 jobs a year
200,000 people that I need to place in
jobs a year over the next decade well
how do I even get though get people who
don't know they're interested in
manufacturing even to the like to the
door of the place to apply for a
manufacturing job and I thought about
libraries part of the reason is a lot of
the places that use our machine because
it's small and can go anywhere that'll
use it in a library and so the challenge
really that I'm kind of putting forth
that I'm going around the country a lot
talking about this in all kinds of
places is if all you did was have a
thousand libraries that exposed 200
people a year for the next decade to
these technical skills and like robots
and making and cutting and
and soldering and things like that there
would be so much more people that would
even be even be aware that they could
have a technical job and I think there's
probably a lot of people in the room I
don't know everybody here but there's a
lot of people that I do know that taught
themselves things on their own and I
really think that if you put a
makerspace in a library you can't really
expect just library staff to do it I
think it's up to all of us to volunteer
in our communities and be more involved
and get people more excited about
technical skills and so that's that's
the challenge that I am personally
taking up and looking for people of
course to join me this is my mantra so I
don't have a lot of proof that this
works there's there's one library that
I've been following pretty closely the
Chicago Chicago Public Library system
I've trained thousands of people of year
a year to use you know 3d printers and
laser cutters and everything and it's
really the most basic stuff just hand
skills and the goal isn't to train
someone to be a robot operator out of
factory before they ever get there it's
just to get people inspired to take on
these super high-paying jobs that have a
future and are probably in a field that
they have never even considered before
and so my approach is give everyone
robots whether it's Girl Scouts or
engineers in schools or whatever this is
the this is the kind of effect that
we're already seeing for when we put
these robots people don't even know that
they're robots it could be a 2d shape
cutter but the idea is to try to lower
the barrier and really increase access
because the fact is if you don't look
like the people who are in the shop you
won't ever go into the shop and I fit in
just fine in a hackerspace I wear this
dress and everybody's like of course she
belongs here you know no big deal
but that's a privilege that I have and
not everybody has that and so this is
really why I'm advocating for widespread
exposure to robots in libraries and you
might think that it's you know that this
is kind of like a fringy idea but in
fact this is the whole reason that I
started this company in the first place
we were
tasked by DARPA and a government grant
to build small-scale manufacturing
robots that could go into classrooms
that could go into libraries because
they saw and it was actually a study
there was a study about what is the
biggest threat to national security in
the next 20 years it's just not having
enough technical people not having
enough people to operate the
infrastructure for the company or for
the company for the country
and and so they tasked us with with
developing these tools one we we
developed was a reciprocating exacto
knives blade for cutting cardboard
because that was cheap one was a milling
machine and and in this came from some
very forward-thinking people in
government what happened is eventually
we ended up just taking those prototypes
and forming a company but I think we now
have all the elements that we need we
have to create a space where people can
get access anybody can get access in
public libraries are a great place for
that the cost of the machines is pretty
low the cost of materials is pretty low
and what I see is there's this key part
that's been missing from the maker
movement if I have one judgement among
the maker movement it's that there
wasn't a light shining that we're all
pointing towards and for me that light
is getting non-technical people to learn
technical skills and actually open doors
for themselves and and the people around
them in terms of employment so that's
the purpose part that I really I think
is coming in too you know there's a lot
of momentum around it even I think it
was last month
Google pledged a billion dollars towards
educating people into tech fields I
think that a lot of people are now
taking notice but it's really up to
folks like us on the ground to make
moves and we will be the people who are
actually introducing a lot of people to
their first soldering job and their
first robot and their first 2d shape
cutter Cricut or whatever it is and now
is a great time to do it like I said the
hardware's cheap the soft
where is cheap or free and now more
space is becoming available I have been
to I went to Indiana and North Carolina
and in the Bay Area and here and talking
about the same thing what I see now as
opposed to five years ago his people are
understanding that this is important and
schools traditional schools are not
going to be able to keep up with this
demand for workers so they're thinking
about alternatives I'm thinking about
alternatives which is let's put in
expensive hardware and software use
inexpensive software and allocate space
towards this because it's actually
really important for our future and this
is the thing that was the most
surprising that I found through all of
my research which which is it's actually
an investment in our economy our future
the future of this country
and and actually I'm not particularly
like made in America focused I'm more
like make it locally like wherever you
are if you can have more things made
where you are that's better it doesn't
matter to meet where it is but there's
this factor which is if you invest in
this and you invest in creating this
workforce and you invest in creating
facilities you actually get more than
you put in which is really important so
what you can do is you can contact me
and say hey I want to get involved
connect me with a library that's psyched
to do this work or how do I participate
what is like the right content that I
need to put out there there's a lot
there's virtually nothing that's being
done in that to answer that one specific
question which is how do we take what we
know about making and exposing people to
these skills and getting them a job or
getting them like to even think that
they could have a job that's the missing
link and so if you have ideas about that
you should share them with me stories
share them with me it's really important
to elevate the stories of success and to
find out what patterns there might be
and I'm really interested in in what is
the answer what is the key to taking all
the things that we do in hacking and
making and fabricating and prototyping
and having it translate for a lot of
people into
a new future for themselves in their
family to be quite honest so you can
email me I'll put you in contact with
people these are some references that I
had talked about the manufacturing all
the manufacturing stats and the study
you can read a ton about it I had no
idea in fact how important manufacturing
was to to what we do in the United
States and to put the perspective of two
million unfilled manufacturing jobs or
to put some perspective around two
million unfilled manufacturing jobs
that's as if you took all of the
manufacturing jobs in California and all
of the manufacturing jobs in Texas which
are the top two states for manufacturing
and you just stopped you just left them
unfilled and if you go to Indiana and
you talk to the to the factory managers
like I have you'll see that this is
already a problem it's already half a
million and it's only growing so time to
get to work everybody and and feel free
to reach out to me and share your ideas
I think this is a really important
problem to work on I think that people
who are non-traditional explorers of
technology like we are are well
positioned to address it Thanks
[Applause]