so hi everyone my name is ish enzo from
university of michigan today i'm happy
to present this drawing collaboration
with carnegie mellon university on
website privacy choices so privacy
choices are mandated by regulations over
the world from the European Union to the
United States
the three most commonly mandated types
are opt outs for email communications
opt outs for targeted advertising and
choices for data deletion do users care
about privacy the answer is obviously
yes in 2016 pure national survey 65% of
respondents that is very important to
them to control what information is
collected about them 86% reported taking
steps to remove or mask their digital
footprints ranging from clearing cookies
to delete in post on social media our
privacy choice is usable the answer is
unfortunately no as reflected by prior
research which were conducted as either
large-scale measurement analysis or
small-scale user studies based on a
limited set of tools or websites our
studies is in the middle in terms of
method as a manual in-depth counting
analysis of privacy choices on 150
websites we chose to focus on email
communications targeted ads opt outs and
data deletion choices as this are the
most mandated three types of by
regulation we're interested in knowing
how this mandated privacy choices are
provided in practice specifically what
choices related to email communications
targeted advertising and data dilution
do websites offer and second how our
websites presenting these privacy
choices to their visitors and what are
the potential usability issues for each
web set we went through different places
to check the process of privacy choices
first we'll go to the home page observe
it has any cookie notices or link to
privacy choices after that we created a
user account using a provided name and
no address third we go through the
websites privacy policy and find
description of privacy choices in text
and force we repeat the same procedure
for account settings while going through
each website we filed out an analysis
template including 82 questions to
standardize the data recording
procedures examples of questions include
location such as where's their choice is
located as privacy policy account
settings or other places level of detail
such as for an email opt out as a
describe what specific types of
communication that can be opted out the
third one is link availability do they
use one or multiple links and do all
links lead to the relevant page
interaction path how many user actions
are required to exercise their choice we
randomly sample 150 web sites from the
Lexus top global top 10 key sites as of
March 2018 particularly we stratify the
sample based on site traffic with 50
sites from the top middle and button
tiers respectively this is to understand
the potential influence from website
popularity we analyzed all 150 web sites
between April and October 2018
half of them were double coated with a
high internal reliability most of our
analyzed web sites are registered in the
US while Europe was the second host area
notably because our analysis was
conducted using u.s. IP addresses the
results we observed only reflect the
state's quote for us-based users so what
do we find for website privacy choices
and will a structure our key findings
around three aspects their presence on
different websites how they were
described and potential usability issues
first an encouraging finding is that
privacy choices were commonly offered
across top middle and low traffic tiers
when looking at this graph you notice
most of the sites that use email
communications or targeted advertising
provided a respect
tip up towel mechanism and this lack of
Troyes problem occurs slightly more
severely for data deletion other types
of opt-out we observed which are less
common are those for web analytic
services third-party sharing on earth do
not track request and opt outs for
cookies in looking at the location of
privacy choices either in account
settings privacy policy or more than one
location we notice for email
communication opt outs intended to
appear at multiple places
comparatively presence of targeted ads
opt outs and data deletion choices were
more centralized toward privacy policies
the location distribution patterns are
quite similar for websites with
top-middle or traffic or pattern traffic
moving on to a description of privacy
choices problems start to emerge first
it's a websites described as privacy
choices with very poor readability
looking at this flash King cake rate
level scores for tax in privacy policy
that describes this choices they all had
a mean around 13 this means on average
comprehending attacks were required the
audience to have university level
reading abilities interestingly
understanding the privacy policy tax in
general is slightly easier but still not
ideal as comparison materials addressed
to the general public a suggested to aim
for a score between seven and nine
another problem regarding a tax
description is the lack of consensus in
the wordings used to present privacy
choices taking the headers the headings
of the sections that described as
privacy choices as an example we noticed
that some terms were evenly distributed
such as your choice for all three types
however there are unique terms for
certain types of choices such as opt-out
for email communication third party for
targeted ads and you're right for data
deletion and furthermore no single and
grande occurred in more than twenty of
our analyzed policies this lack of
consistency across websites
make it hard for users to locate choices
in privacy policies here's a snapshot of
the headings for data dilution choices
companies like parks and Netflix had a
relatively simple such as your choice
and data subjects rights other companies
would use longer and more concrete
headings such as Lincoln's
rise to access and control your personal
data and Facebook's how can I manage or
delete information about me moreover
ambiguity exists regarding what actually
happened when a choice is exercised
among the 80 sites that mentions trying
to advertising in their privacy policy
50% did not describe the opt-out would
stop tracking entirely or not and 90% in
a specified whether the opt-out applied
to across multiple browsers or devices
the same ambiguity issues exists for
data deletion choices among the 108
websites offering data deletion
mechanisms 83% did not describe a time
frame one that when the account will be
permanently deleted for usability we
also found severe issues that could
likely make this privacy choices
difficult or impossible to use starting
from requiring too many user actions we
counted user actions as clicks hovers
checkboxes and forum views we counted
the user actions required to exercise
the choice from the home page just for
the shortest path and the number is 5.3
for email opt outs and data deletion
choices and 3.2 for targeted ads opt out
notice that this is just for the
shortest path and it's conducted by
researchers who are experienced and know
where to go to to find these choices an
average first-time user is likely to
spend more time as struggles in figuring
out the right path
here's an example on New York Times
which we should clarify is just you okay
here's the video which is valid uses to
illustrate larger issues instead of
targeting any specific companies here it
can takes up to 38 user access to
complete a data deletion request form
starting from finding the right link to
the form in privacy policy select
deleted as a type of request scroll down
and select the right product or service
from the list of 22 up options then the
user also needs to fill out name email
address country etc plus for checkboxes
and the resep recapture at the end of
this very lengthy process
additionally confusion may occur why
website when websites have multiple
links leading to different opt-out tools
for the same purpose take Twitter's
targeted ads up now for example first in
the account settings you can find the
opt-out provided by Twitter itself if
you navigate to the about Us page
it also shows up top provided by DAA and
then I as well as Google for its web
analytics if you go to Twitter's privacy
policy only the one provided by Twitter
and naa will show up here
all of this links to multiple opt-out
tools
spanning across multiple pages may cause
confusion about which tool should be
prioritized and what their differences
are lastly we know that several poor
design choices that may impact usability
here's an example from Amazon to opt out
of email communications your first
encounter a list of 69 check boxes for
different categories then at the very
very end of the list you'll notice an
opt-out of all check box titled do not
send me any marketing communications and
you'll need to remember to click the
Update button to make sure the choice is
exercised
well this opt-out for all button is now
visible on top a first-time user may be
scared away immediately just because
they think they need to uncheck all 16
eye boxes and the process is too
and hassle so after hearing so many
issues you may wonder how do we improve
website privacy choices we summarize our
recommendations based on the interaction
cycle which divides human interaction
with systems into four stages planning
translation physical action and
assessment I will next highlight one key
recommendation for each stage but feel
free to refer to our paper for more
details for the planning stage to help
users find a specific privacy choices
more easily a starting point can be
standardized in section headings in
privacy policies one example how this
can work is the model privacy notice
form that US financial institutions are
suggested to use for compliance with the
GLBA
though this might not be perfect exactly
a good initiative and research have
shown that this can contribute to lower
ambiguity in privacy policies for the
translation stage to help users plan now
the actions to exercise the choice more
efforts should be put to simplify the
process of learning of those in cases
where websites provides links to
multiple targeted ads opt-out such as
Twitter user can really benefit from a
single interface such as our privacy
Center that unifies multiple choice
mechanisms for the same purpose if this
is not technically feasible whether both
a website should at least provide
adequate explanation of what the
differences are between multiple opt-out
tools and which one should be
prioritized for the physical action
stage to help users exercise the choice
better and intuitive step is to reduce
the number of required actions in the
New York Times example there should be
an option to delete user account from
all services well if the user really
wants to do it just for Selective
Service they should at least be able to
do it in one single form in formats such
as the list of checkboxes instead of the
current drop-down list and finally many
of the form fields can be eliminated so
that a only asked users to provide
minimal information that's necessary to
perform this data deletion request
and similarly for the Amazons cased the
up dog our button should really be
placed at the top of the page rather
than at the button two of why the cases
where the users waste their time on
checking our boxes or even giving up opt
in now because the process looks too
complicated at the first glance it's
conceivable that many companies may
deliberately making this privacy choices
unusable for their visitors and in this
case it's regulators responsibility to
combat such dark patterns previous cases
exist such as a ruling by the French
Data Protection Authority on Google for
failing to provide notice in an easily
accessible form and fell into the obtain
users valid consent to data processing
for a personalization and similarly for
FTC's recent following on Facebook for
the assessment stage to help users
better evaluate the outcomes of
exercising privacy choices we can start
by providing more detailed explanation
for choice outcomes this means to
something like this choice will only
apply to the specific browser or device
from which you opt out as in the example
of dailymotion or we will delete your
full profile within 90 days as in the
example of github so in summary today I
present our study on website privacy
choices which are prevalent but still
severe issues existing regards their
description and usability we call for a
joint effort between companies and
regulators to ensure usability of
privacy choices thank you all for
listening to my presentation my name is
Ian zofran University of Michigan and
the happy to take any questions
[Applause]
thank you folks to come to the center
bikes with questions
there aren't any questions yet I have a
question you showed in the beginning
there's a bunch of different regulatory
requirements um what are your thoughts
on the ways usable ways to combine all
the different regulatory requirements in
a usable way especially around things
like standardizing language and stuff
like that so yeah thank you that's a
great question I feel a way to combine
regulations together is to make sure the
regulations stipulate specific
requirements so a counter example which
I can think of is in gdpr when it says
using clear and plain language for
either things like data breach
notifications or privacy policies it
doesn't really tell how to achieve that
all clear and plain language and so I
feel as a starting point if you want to
establish specific requirements in the
regulations that can be a good point to
really tell companies how to achieve the
things we want you to achieve
- I'm Cory Ferris from Carnegie Mellon
it's a nice to see you again at Supes
congratulations on this I'm curious have
you guys reached out to the companies
involved in the study to get to notify
them and maybe get their feedback oh we
haven't done so so far about to my
knowledge our team is working on an
update which hopefully can be published
on media and in that way attract more
attention for companies you notice there
are changes to be made thank you
University really great presentation I
was curious
given that this kind of scenario
involves different stakeholders which
includes the companies and the
regulators but also the users so how
important do you think is the user input
in in creating more accessible and more
usable privacy policies and interfaces
um - main user input is extremely
important and that's like approach
called user centric privacy design that
takes user input into the cycle of
designing and implementing privacy
choices
especially I think if it's just
companies working with regulators and
stimulates specific things to be done
with it
they don't necessarily take the insight
from known tech savvy users and
especially for experts like a security
and privacy we know all those things but
we are already familiar in the field for
such a long time so maybe we need
fresher perspective from the users to
make sure they are actually usable for
them hi thank you i'm pilar from
1password
and i was wondering if you have stumbled
upon this service that we've seen a lot
of basically you are social privacy
conscious that you allow this
third-party company will read and write
access to your email and they just
machine-gun every company they can think
of with billion requests and the person
doesn't even know who's getting the
deletion request so we have to be a lot
more careful with actually enacting it
but have you seen anything about this
service or bad side effects of it so
that will be a service that perform data
deletion request in representative of
you every company they have I may have
heard of this service I don't I haven't
used this kind of service before oh I
cannot speak for their practice about
how shady or how pervasive they are in
performing this I think the intention is
good but if a user one should use that
make sure you read their privacy
policies terms and conditions and that's
not enough I think there should also be
like regulations or some kind of
supervision on this type of service to
make sure even though the purpose of
school they are not invading users
privacy none either intentional or
unintentional way
thank you
[Applause]