thank you so today I'll present the work
I did together with Malika Maya
fishing certificates and I want to start
by ya answering the question why would
we even look at certificates and the
reason is that we've seen a steady
increase of websites that are using
HTTPS up to 90 percent of page loads are
using HTTPS in some regions of the world
and phishing websites going along with
this trend we've seen a rapid
development of phishing websites that
are using HTTPS in the last years and up
to a 60 percent according to this record
mm-hmm and looking at this data we were
wondering what kind of certificates are
phishing websites using and can we use
the information included in the
certificates to learn something about
the attacker or maybe detect better
detect phishing websites maybe in an
automated setting or a user education
setting and yeah these are the questions
that I'll be talking about in this in
this talk but first make sure that we
are on the same page recording some
terms I think all of you are familiar
with what phishing is I've just included
this slide so that the yet the terms
I'll be using are clear when I'm talking
about phishing there are three actors
involved the victim the attacker and the
target and the target has some website
that is copied by the attacker who then
sends a link to the fake website to the
user who probably clicks on it and
enters their credentials and yeah in
this talk we are going to look at the
website of the attacker and specifically
there are certificates so what kind of
information can we find in a certificate
there are several types of certificates
they can be roughly divided into into
three types the first is called the main
bullet validated certificate and this
type of certificate only includes
information on the domain name
of the subject so this is the most basic
type and it can be verified
automatically as this for example done
by the issuer let's encrypt however CES
also have the ability to verify more
about the subject than just ownership of
the domain and this could result in an
organization validated certificate you
can see that in this case not only is
information about the domain including
the certificate but also an organization
name in the attribute organizational
attribute of the certificate
however the URL bar even though yeah
there are differences in the
certificates usually does not make
differences between these two types
there is however a third type that is
called extended validation and yeah to
grant an extended validation certificate
ACA has to follow a very strict process
which is at least currently and in some
browsers displayed differently in the
euro and as you can imagine the more
information we can find in a certificate
the more we can yeah argue about this
certificates so in following we are
going to see what we found we were
mainly concerned with two research
questions the first is are there general
difference between certificates of
fishing and Pinay on websites so for
these we looked at the tool and data
sets and we're finding out for example
all fishing websites using let's
equipped while none of the benign what's
do mmm for the second question we
include some additional context and
we're trying to find out if the fishing
websites are able to replicate
information of the certificate of the
targets and here at the core of both of
these questions is a comparison between
fishing and benign certificates so I
will now explain how we how we collected
those certificates
yeah we started by creating two data
sets benign and phishing and both data
sets originate from
yeah the certificates were extracted
from here else and pb9 URLs were
collected from Alexa these are the top
50,000 lists on the Alexa app list and
the fishing data set was created by a
curing fish tank and we collected more
than 30,000 fishing URLs from this
website over a period of 53 days yeah
after extracting the URLs we were yeah
we collected the certificates and this
was done in the same way for both both
datasets and we collected more than
43,000 benign and more than 25,000
fishing certificates from these women
removed several and duplicate
certificates and we were also decided to
focus only on valid certificates I'm
sorry we moved invalid certificates as
well and ended up with a data set that
contained almost 40,000 benign and
almost 10,000 phishing valid
certificates so we can already say that
just looking at a warning and deciding
that a phishing website must be the one
that has a warning with the HTTP invalid
it's no longer the case hmm so starting
from these collected certificates we
then extracted features that we wanted
to look at a little more closely and
yeah and did the analysis and I will now
present the results I'll start with the
with some general differences mmm so
there was the first research question
and the first thing I want to show you
is the distribution of radiation types
so this represents in a way the
information that is included in the
information in the certificates of the
different data sets and we can see here
on the Saiga
the percentages of organization
validated extent validated and domain
validated certificates and we can see
that the percentages in the benign
dataset for ovn TV are much higher then
in the fishing data set however there
are some organization validated and even
some extended validated certificates in
the fishing data set just as a small
aside on the extent of vacation part
because that might surprise some we were
sampling some of these certificates and
we did not find any conventional fishing
website on these websites instead there
were some false positives in the fish
tank data set we also found some
apparent miss classifications and lastly
websites that returned error pages for
the URLs so it might be that fishing was
hosted on these services but the website
was cleaned but yeah the main thing we
can see from this figure is that a large
majority of websites in the benign and
the phishing case are using domain
validated certificates and so we were
trying to find out if we can find any
other differences in the certificates
that might be helpful to differentiate
the two so for this we looked at the at
the issue us since certificates from the
same issue at tend to be very similar so
two certificates issued by let's encrypt
typically have the same policies and
even very similar algorithms in key
sizes and again we found some
substantial overlap between the two yeah
as you might have noticed this is the
distribution of the five more five must
come fishing issuers and indeed let's
encrypt is the most popular issue of
phishing websites however it is also
very popular in the benign data set yeah
and from this we do the conclusion that
in a general case it might not be
possible
to decide if a certificate is belongs to
a phishing website or benign website you
can see this if you have let's encrypt
certificate and yeah the tool let's
encrypt certificates one is benign one
is phishing the only way they might
differentiate is the the domain name and
this can be almost freely chosen by the
attacker so that was the first research
question let me go on to the second
research question and here again we were
trying to compare the target certificate
to the certificates of phishing websites
that attacked this particular target and
we created a table for this and I'm
going to explain it and the example of
paper which was the most popular target
of phishing attacks in our data set so
that's why it's ranked 1 the target name
is paper we had more than 10 more than
1000 Malay certificates of phishing
websites that target paper so it's quite
a lot hmm and the main thing we found is
that the organization part of the
certificate is not at all recreated so
paper actually uses an extended
validation certificate so the
certificate does include information on
the organization however none of the
phishing websites was able to or maybe
even tried to recreate this information
just as a comparison there were 84
phishing websites that had papers or the
name people as they're in their URL or
the domain name part of the uvula and
this was the not the exception but
rather the majority of the targets we
looked at followed a similar pattern so
the organization's did not match and
there were varying amounts of
you are matches there were however some
exceptions to this namely these three
targets had phishing websites that were
able to recreate organization
information the interesting part of this
is that all of these websites phishing
websites that created the organization
were hosted on the target sound
infrastructure so these services or
targets offer services where users or
customers can upload their own content
and the content is then protected with
the certificate of the target and in
such a case the organization and
actually your l-pod would also be appear
to be valid and the less since we only
saw the same issuer in only phishing
websites that were hosted on benign
infrastructure so to speak we can see
that are we rather did not see any
evidence of attack has actively
replicating the information that can be
found in certificates
however yeah and the abuse of target
infrastructure is possible so that's
what we found for for the two research
questions now if you wanted to actually
use certificates for fishing in tection
in practice there's two some open
questions that I will be talking about
now the first obviously is the
discriminative power we've seen that
there are lots of benign websites that
do not have an external validation or
organization validation certificate and
in such a case we really don't have much
information to go by and I'm not saying
that everyone should know switch to
another certificate that would not
really be practical since they usually
cost much more and yeah might be harder
to automate but it is a factor we would
have to consider if we are were trying
to implement
phishing detections based on
certificates as for the second question
we've seen that none of the information
was recreated at the current time we
might ask the question what about the
future is it possible that attack us
would start replicating certificate
information and yeah this is basically
comes down to the question do we have to
trust the CAS not to include stuff in
the certificate that is not correct or
that might be misleading they saw over a
project that tries to answer this which
is the certificate transparency project
that's basically a public and verifiable
lock that includes all valid
certificates and it's mainly currently
mainly used to detect issuance of
certificates for domain names that they
should not have been issued for however
it could in theory be extended to also
include other certificate information
yeah lastly if we were to look at
actually implementing phishing
attraction based on certificates we
would also have to deal with some other
problems for example TLS interception if
the certificate exchange is intercepted
by a third party as is for example the
case with some antivirus products or has
even been shortly the case on a national
scale yeah we might not get the
information out of the certificate that
we are interested in in with with these
problems and open questions I'd like to
conclude the talk we've seen that it is
very hard to differ
to differentiate in general between
benign and fishing's certificates might
even be impossible however we did not
find any evidence that attackers are
actively replicating
contents of their targets certificate
and yeah as often questions that I very
gladly extend to the audience
maybe certificates can be used in the
future for automated detection or user
detection I'm interested yeah and what
you think on that and with that thank
you for attention do we have any
questions hi I am Jim Fenton did you
make any you mentioned the the sites
that were hosted on the target zone
infrastructure yes did you do anything
to distinguish the cases where the
Fisher had actually obtained a
certificate as a you know perhaps with a
deceptive domain name in order to make
it look likely or verses other cases
where the attacker might have just
simply found a site that they could
break into and and and host the phishing
page off of yeah we we labeled the data
as by that top targets by using the the
fishtank entries and if I say that the
target was not replicated I mean that it
was not replicated by any of the
phishing websites that had the target
label in the data set does that answer
the question
yeah I'm not sure I quite understood but
I question was I'm wondering in how many
how many of those cases you think that
the attacker actually had to go out and
obtain a certificate oh yeah use one
that was on an on a site or yeah in that
case I would say the zero that is pretty
much the point yes
[Laughter]
hello Jeffrey Goldberg from 1password
I've seen a fair amount of research
which I wasn't able to find right now on
the non effectiveness of EB certificates
yeah and users have just wondering okay
you're obviously familiar with it if you
comment on how that might connect to
your research and possible
recommendations yeah I think this is a
very recent and ongoing discussion and
really kind of had to comment on
personally we we did not find any
concrete evidence that external
radiation certificates were abused there
was some evidence that might point to
compromise of extended validation
websites yeah I am honestly not sure
what else to say
do you you mentioned that or you showed
in your graph there are some issues that
are very more common on phishing
websites like yeah it was something like
that
is that an issue known to these
companies or did you contact them I'm
not sure if they are aware of this fact
I think this evens out if we move away a
little from the top fifty thousand of
the Alexa list and move toward less less
popular website so to speak yeah we also
looked at a at the data set that was not
the top fifty thousand and the issue of
were a little more similar to the fish
in case I just fill in for that last
question let's encrypt or the e FF which
is behind let's encrypt is well aware
that the paid certificate authorities
are very much advertising this fact yes
they're all aware okay if we don't have
any more questions let's think this
speaker again
[Music]