hello everyone I'm Molly ha I'm a PhD
student at University of North Carolina
and Charlotte and today I'm going to
present or a study on end-user
perceptions of a smart home device
manufacturer data practices and relevant
wrists so a smart home market is growing
very fast people are getting more
interested in having internet connected
devices in their home for increased
conveniences or increased security and
safety and in just last one year the
smart home market grown 12% only in US
and expected to be a forty billion
dollar business by 2020 and a lot of
people in u.s. has two or more smart
home devices in their house so with the
prevalence of these devices also counts
many security and privacy risks because
these devices are actually automatically
collecting a lot of potentially private
information about its users and because
data is important both tech companies
and malicious parties are getting
interested in these smart home devices
and we are seeing more and more attack
on a smart home and IOT devices
regularly nowadays so there are some
papers who looked at security and
privacy in his smartphone from end users
perspective for instance Jeff Janet L
conducted an interview study and found
that even expert users have incomplete
trade model of security and privacy
recently smart home and instead of
sharing a common set of concerns
it is often limited and varied among the
participants there are another study who
investigated 11 mostly technical users
focusing on their perception of specific
data collection entities and found that
users comfort on sharing their data
depend on the benefit they get from the
device and their trust on those entities
however none of the previous work looked
that what the current users of these
smart devices think about what happening
with their data and what is their
concerns and comfort in with these data
collection and users and how that is
affecting their behavior security and
privacy protection behavior also the
earlier state is mostly concentrated on
expert users who installed an automated
a smart home devices in their house but
not on the incidental users who were not
involved in the installation and
automation but use these devices in a
regular basis so in this study we
decided to get a more detail and
holistic understanding of both expert
and non-expert users perception of very
smart device manufacturer data practices
more specifically what data do they
think this is martim devices collect
where the data is stored who can accept
that that data how that data is used and
how that perception is shaping their
security and privacy concerns in smart
home and how that is affecting their
security and privacy actions to protect
their data so to answer these questions
we conducted a semi-structured interview
with 23 participants
it was a phone interview which lasted of
on average one hour we recruited
participants from I have two related
online forums from Reddit and we
recruited participants who has at least
three types of smart home devices
because we wanted people who have
experience interacting with different
types of devices so which I to recruit a
balanced sample of participants in terms
of both age gender different technical
background and also people who are its
purchasers in involved in installation
and automation and also people who just
use the devices as incidental users
so our participants had a lot of
different devices and they use the
smartphone devices mainly for automating
their household remotely sensing and
controlling the devices and increasing
security and safety of their house in
some way some of the participants also
mentioned we use these devices for
saving energy and help with household
chores most of the participants had some
central controls controller set of four
extends either yzma things or a smart
voice assistant and for many of our
participants voice was the main method
of interaction so as one of the goal of
our study was to understand what people
think about the data we conducted a
drawing exercise where we asked
participant how the thing the data is
flowing in the air a smart home so we
found that users mental model depended
on their technical background and their
interaction with different devices so
participant who had advanced mental
model he had a more detailed
understanding of their smart home all of
those participants who had advanced
mental model know about the cloud and
the role of cloud in device interaction
they know that data goes back and forth
between the devices and the cloud when
the interaction happens in contrast
people who have service-oriented model
was mainly consists of how they control
the device that they control these
devices with its devices so that that's
how the data flows some of them
mentioned cloud but none of them has a
good idea of the role of cloud in device
interaction so after that we in our in
the rest of our study we asked
participants not a manufacturer data
practices so we found that the depth of
people understanding of their smart home
didn't actually affect their perception
or understanding of his smart home
device manufacturer data practices for
instance users perception of data
collection depended on the type of the
device and their interaction with
the device or 30 letter app for instance
the people who has video doorbell all of
them knew that the video doorbell is
collecting video but none of them
mention that the app may be collecting
the location when they are accessing the
video all of their participants knew
that their interaction and users may be
collected by the device manufacturers
but again they were not really concerned
so we look more specifically at audio
and video data because they normally
seemed as more sensitive and the video
was still considered very sensitive by
our participants but our participants
found practices to be become comfortable
around those devices for instance one of
our participants said he just turn on
the recording when he's not home or some
said that they only used a video in
video camera in live streaming mode so
none of the video gets recorded our
participants also mentioned that
sensitive information can be inferred
from from the data these devices are
collecting and that information can be
used for building advertising model for
them and target for targeted advertising
but they are not very concerned
they say that targeted advertising
becomes so common our kind of integral
part of their life that they think that
is kind of a cost of using the Internet
our participants also mentioned that the
companies collect these data to improve
the product for example if there is a
hero if something is not working the
company collected data and use that data
to resolve the problem and also they say
that they use the data to identify users
need to develop new product our
participants know that device
manufacturer shared their devices with
third-party advertisers but they are not
really sure the extent of data that
being shared so some things that only
the demographic data is being shared
some things that only small companies
share the data big companies don't share
the data they collect the data from
small companies
our participant mentioned that their
data is going to be device manufacturer
server of the cloud and some of them
also mentioned that the device
manufacturers may not have enough
protection in place in the cloud and
they were also not sure about how long
the data will be stored most of them
think that the data will be installed
indefinitely and many of our
participants also were not aware of the
security and privacy controls that are
available in many of the smart home
devices and that makes our participants
uncomfortable for instance one of our
participants didn't want elect Eco in
her house because she thought that there
is no option to check the audio
recordings and remove that data and that
make had uncomfortable that he want to
remove she wanted to remove the device
from her house after learning about
their perception of device manufacturer
data practices we asked them what what
can happen to them based on what is
happening to their data so the
participant mostly said that yes there
can be a data breach in the cloud and
their data can be hacked some also said
that the device can be hacked and
remotely controlled by the adversary
some more also said that there can be
improper sharing between between
different companies and as a consequence
their physical security can be hampered
there can be more risk of identity theft
some advanced participants also
mentioned that with these data the
companies can some way manipulate their
decision or perception of things and
some also mention discomfort around the
civilians especially around the devices
that collect audio and video data our
advanced
identified more treads but again only a
few were really concerned so instead of
they're not really concerned they
actually to conduct some protective
measures so for many of our participants
say it like they sell self-censored
themselves in some way around the
devices so for instance turn the turn of
the device when they don't use the
device or do not use certain device
functionality or just would fake data in
their account and some also say they
change their behavior around these
devices many of our participants use
technical based practices that they know
from other computing context for example
they say that they use a strong password
and two-factor authentication some of
our expert participants said that they
install some kind of tool to protect
their data for instance two of our
expert participants mentioned that they
installed a local server and customized
the devices to work with the server so
their data do not go outside in the
internet but most majority of our
participants said they either use some
technical mitigations or changing their
behavior in some way around that devices
- as a protective measure and also
mentioned that they are not really
concerned about the threats and
mentioned the number of reasons why they
are not concerned so one of the reason
is they say that there is no way other
than accepting these trade-offs if they
want to use that device they have to
accept the risks some also say that they
trust that the manufacturer will not
misuse their data because because it
will be financially it will it will
damage their reputation and not be
financially very profitable some was
very optimistic that they will never be
a target because they are not solvent
enough and some judges theories by how
expose they already are so they say that
there is already enough in
formation about me in the internet so
adding in new smart home devices will
not increase my risk of identity theft
some trusted that there is strict
regulatory body who will look over their
data and make sure that the companies
are not misusing their data and some
expert participant mentioned the
difficulty of implementing protective
actions like as like implementing a
local server and sometimes and that cost
of creative action is so high it's often
overrun the limited concern of the
participant so from our study we learn
that users perceptions of device
manufacturer data practices is is not
much different from their perception of
Internet and these knowledge also don't
affect their security and privacy we
have aired any smart home for instance
our expert participants did know about
more threats and more protective
measures but still they didn't actually
implement it instead if they are
protected via via depend on their own
biases and they're concerned with
general internet users our participants
conscious concerns were thought was also
paradoxical for instance they knew that
these devices are collecting data
sensitivity data can be inferred the
companies may not have enough protection
in the cloud or there may not be in
Africa Latorre bodies but again when we
ask them why they are not concerned they
are kind of backing it up with the fact
that the trusted company will not misses
their data there
there are come regulatory bodies who
will look over their data and this can
be explained by learned helplessness
where people ignore negative outcome
because they don't have control and many
of our participant explicitly say they
don't have any controls once the data
get into the device it's out of out of
their hand so they use different coping
mechanism
so data don't get into the device in the
first place
for many of our participants the
estimated risk from these devices was
also very low because for instance they
know that there can be their physical
security can be hampered but they
thought that there will never be a good
target they know that there can be
identity theft but they thought that
there is already enough information in
the internet so if someone wants to
target me the information is already out
there even the people who had a victim
of identity theft told that they have
enough protection in their financial
account so they're good so they don't
understand the breadth of the risks that
can come from it smartphone devices and
lastly the lack of awareness of divert
level controls actually impede users and
make the participants more uncomfortable
and from our interview it was appeared
that if they knew about these controls
their protective Vav arm agent in some
way so these underscored the importance
of more studies to examine the nudges
that drive users especially the norm
Staller of these devices towards the
security and privacy controls that is
already available with the devices
so with that I'll finish my talk and
happy to answer your question some time
for questions hi so I'm a yonathan
Zanger I am at Houma but I actually used
to had infra and privacy for the Google
assistants so thank you very much for
this talk I had a question about the
interpretation of this data you are
saying how people are making fairly low
estimates of the risk and that they're
ignoring certain types of hazard and so
on how do we tell whether when we're
looking at this we're seeing at user fat
security fatigue or privacy fatigue
versus people actually making fairly
sophisticated risk/reward trade-offs
because in the same interviews you are
talking about looking at this data it
also looked like people had pretty
complex understandings of where their
data was how it could potentially be
used and had actually been making
decisions deliberately how do we know
what's the right way to read this so so
that was one of the interesting findings
we had from our data that yes we thought
that people don't know anything so maybe
that's why they are not doing anything
but actually people know that okay they
have complex model that yes that is
happening to my data
yes sensitive information can be
inferred from my data you still they
don't think that that can directly
affect them because they don't think
them as a potential victim or potential
target for of whatever data that are
available and but it sounded like they
were in numerating various ways it could
affect them what it sounded like they
were enumerated risk of identity theft
physical security yes
yeah they worried about like as I said
they all read about identity theft but
again they have multiple of our
participants said they already have
protection of their final data financial
data so they thought that okay that will
be enough like if someone want to break
into my back account then I I would know
but they know about the risks but they
also have reasons that why I'm not I I
will not be concerned
okay thank you so you mentioned that
many of your participants were not aware
of privacy controls that some of these
devices had and you also said that some
of them had wrong mental models of
either the protections or the
regulations that were in place and you
mentioned notches at the end so I was
just wondering if you thought more about
how you could people help have more
accurate mental models so make them
aware of privacy controls that might be
useful to them
so if people know about the privacy
controls from my experience with the my
participants I think it it will be
helpful for them because many of our
participants when I told them that this
is actually available like with these
device and then they told me that if I
would know that I would I would remove
my video I would I would look at the
audio recordings and delete it and may
not be this much uncomfortable like one
of our participants actually remove
tannest camera for her house at some
point because she got really
uncomfortable with that device so I
think if if people know about these
controls they that would help them get
more comfortable around these devices
and use more private privacy protective
behaviors and do you have any ideas how
we could make that happen beyond you
going and visiting every user of a
device so that's that's another problem
because the ecosystem is very complex so
each people have different types of
devices and different devices has
different types of policies provide
different types of controls so at the
future stay for our study right now we
are investigating what are the controls
that are available in different set of
set of devices and what people's
perception of those controls how people
use those controls and what their needs
so it's kind of a futuristic okay sounds
great thank you let's thank our speaker
[Applause]