hello everyone my name is Abdul Majeed
our Kotani I'm a business student from
UNC Charlotte
I'll present my paper on sharing and the
privacy concerns of users variable
fitness devices so wearable fitness
devices are one of the most adopted IOT
devices and it is the top-selling
devices in market reports estimates that
reports estimate that more than 70% of
the devices of the variables that would
be sold in 2020 are fitness trackers and
smart watches which also include or
provide fitness tracking capability
these devices sense and collect a
variety of data like heart rate calories
step count location among gathers many
of the wearable fitness surfaces enable
users to share their data with other
individuals and with organizations so
user users can share their data within
the device military and social circles
or externally on social media and
external online health and fitness
platforms
however sharing since the activity data
can expose users to several risk for
example when a user share data such as
step count or distance routes can be
used to pinpoint user home address or
other sensitive locations such as
military sites there is also a concern
that fitness tracker data can be used by
third parties such as insurance
companies can be used for other purposes
to increase for example by the insurance
companies to increase consumers coverage
rates or by employers to basely share
their promotion decisions based on an
employee health status so these are some
examples and there are different other
scenarios where users data can be at
risk a previous work on sharing and
privacy of fresno state examines user
motivations users shared their data in
order to stay accountable and to get
social support and to compete with
others and there has been extensive work
on sharing activity data on social media
and workplaces so users wanted to access
larger number of audiences by sharing
their data on social media and to
promote their physical activity within
the work place environment privacy
concerns were also examined and they
found that users do not find the data
from activity trackers sensitive but
they are concerned about other data
collected by these devices like location
and they are also concerned about
unintended use and lack of control over
their data other all studies also
examined the privacy policies of
wearable fitness companies and they
found that some of the policies some of
the companies did not comply with the
existing regulations regarding data
practices users have also a limited
knowledge about those practices
according to another study so far
previous studies examined the sharing
and privacy primarily on social media
and in the workplace in workplaces
focusing on users goals and their
perceptions we wanted to we wanted to
have a broader view of all forms of
sharing so we wanted to examine in our
study we wanted to examine sharing as
one important aspect of privacy
therefore our goals in this study were
to understand how long-term users of
fitness trackers share their data and
what privacy decisions they make when
they share data with different audiences
and with different organizations so you
conducted semi-structured interview with
users of fitness trackers
in order to get insights about their
actual sharing behaviors we restricted
participation to people who have three
months at least three months of a device
used and who shared some information we
advertised our study and relevant online
forums and we interviewed 30
participants 15 beers and 15 females
they came they came from different
backgrounds and from different from
different educational backgrounds and
their age ranged from 20 to 51 they also
utilized a variety of fitness trackers
including wrists devices such as Fitbit
smart rings just a swab and among other
devices the interview questions were
structured into three parts the first
part focused on the general usage of a
device by the participants and the
second part we asked them about their
sharing practices we'll ask them
questions such as with whom they share
their information and in what platforms
and why in the last parts of the
interview you ask them about the
prophecy concerns we asked them how they
think their information can be misused
and what they do to manage their
information we trust the inductive
coding to analyze the interview
transcripts so moving into the results
the first part of the result is about
general usage so similar to previous
studies findings we found that users
utilize their participants utilize the
trackers for several purposes mainly to
track their activity and to stay
accountable however we found a
considerable number of people in our
study share their data with with
caregivers for medical reasons for
example we have fun participant she has
sleep apnea and she used her device to
track hair sleep another participant has
had back surgery and she used the device
to track her standing and walking after
the surgery most of the participants use
their devices all times others be
during workouts so prior to starting our
study we assumed that sharing platforms
and backed users behaviors however we
found that platforms had less to do with
users behaviors than they're sharing
goals and related audiences so our study
presents a set of sharing goals
audiences and specific practices from
participant free services we identified
six category or the recipients of their
data friends family strangers physicians
and center programs and co-workers some
participants utilized multiple patterns
based on their goals so starting with
the friends the majority of participants
shared their data with friends so they
share their data in order to stay
accountable and to compete with their
B's and to to brag about achievements
they said they share basic data with
their friends such as tip count they are
unwilling to share body weight and other
data that might impact them because they
are concerned about their friends
judgments of their lack of activities
especially those who may not have time
to exercise also participants who share
their data friends prefer to share their
data on social media channels like
Facebook and Twitter however a few
raised concerns about sharing their
their data on those cells because those
channels they said they have different
networks of connection and sometimes it
may not be ever ready to share activity
data with different networks of
connections like professionals the
second category of the recipients are
family as family so participants
mentioned that they share their data
with family in order to have their
family maintain healthy lifestyle and to
also help themselves
had a lifestyle so they said they felt
comfortable sharing everything with
their family because they felt
responsible to toward their family and
to share any experience with a good or
bad with their family members then you
try simple techniques to share their
data so just by talking or by showing
family member their data in the device
the third category of the recipients are
strangers so about the servants share
their data with strangers in order to
get advice regarding some health goals
like losing weight so they utilize the
device built in social circles or online
fitness and health communities we ask
them if they are okay to share their
data with unknown people and they said
they are okay because they do not expect
harm from people having same goals as
themselves others were not concerned
because they use fake information in
their profiles and all of the
participants mention that they do not
share location data because they are
concerned about their safety we were
surprised by the number of people who
share their data with caregivers so we
have about six or seven participants
share their data with caregivers as I
mentioned they share the data in order
to track some medical conditions or to
track their vital signs so they say they
said they they are okay and they are
comfortable sharing or friendly with
their doctors and they make sure to
record everything precisely because they
think it's good for their to hold their
health to merge their information
accurately with accurate information
however some are frustrated when
frustrated with the current way they
utilize to share their data because they
compiled data manually and checked with
the doctors and they wish to have
somewhat emitted way to share their data
with with their physicians some of the
participants also share their data with
financial incentive programs so they
share their data in order to receive
some incentives like discount on the
purchases from a pharmacy or discount
and the insurance so they connect their
data with those parties those parties
will pull out their data from their
fitness trackers mainly step counts and
to admit that they their main goal for
sharing their activity data is to to
receive the incentive we also ask them
if they are comfortable and they said
they are ok because it just counts and
the step count are harmless step count
is harmless only one participant
mentioned he is concerned about abusing
his data by the insurance company in the
future but he considered himself healthy
now and he's not concerned right now the
last category of the recipients of users
data are co-workers so similar to
previous studies findings we found that
some some users share their data with
co-workers so sharing with co-workers is
more friendly competition and
participants find it an opportunity to
to increase their physical activity some
of the co-workers may not been
personally known to the user but they
say it again at step count and it is
harmless
the last part so first you ask
participants about the prophecy concerns
they said they are not concerned because
they do not consider they did not
consider activity data sensitive
comparing comparing to other data such
as financial data rather they are mostly
concerned about self presentation and
social norms were sharing their data so
they said they make sure to boast
information that
confirm with sharing common sharing
norms and they do not share information
that might impact their image in front
of their peers so they make sure to post
something that can communicate positive
image about their health and with his
life all the few people had concerns
about reusing by their data merely by
insurers and by marketers we also asked
them what they do to manage their
prophecy and the most of them said that
they do not take any action to to manage
their information because again they do
not consider their this this data as
sensitive a few people mentioned that it
allows some strategies certain
techniques like providing minimal
information or providing fake
information in their profiles somewhere
was somewhere where we're not aware
about their privacy settings so we asked
them to go over their profiles and some
of them discovered that the other files
were actually public so in summary our
such our study suggests that users of
fitness trackers do not consider
activity data especially steep count as
sensitive as a result they do not take
any action to protect their information
however experimental research showed
that highly private information can be
can be draw it from activity data that
users generally consider less concerning
or less sensitive rather the disclosure
decisions are impacted by the benefits
such as the incentives or sharing with
doctors we've seen the measure of Milly
with the adductors for the sake of their
health and - they may disclose more
information to receive
incentives they are also there the
scores of decisions are also impacted by
social norms and audiences social norms
of the audience and the prod are our
platforms so based on our results we
recommend the set of design implications
first to design controls and features
around common goals and buttons so users
should be able to customize their
profiles based on and on the audience
and in their goals and features should
reflect common sharing norms there
should be also some methods to enable
users to connect their self tracking
data with their caregivers and finally
privacy not just tonnage users about
their sharing practices and to remind
them to revisit their controls from time
to time now I will leave you with this
set of sharing buttons that we found and
if you have any question happy to answer
thank you if you have questions please
come to the microphone hey Dan cons like
Cornell and asset so I don't know if
there's gonna be so much a question as a
comment it'd be interesting to know how
people the part of decisions in
particular maybe wonder how the
recipients of this information thought
about the sharing cuz they're gonna sort
of work in the past about how doctors
may not really be able to make sense of
tracking data and so be really
interesting to see sort of the flip side
of this where you look not just at the
sharers but the people who they're
sharing to and sort of what kind of
responses and values they can give back
to people can you be the customer it's
not I said it's not a question I'm Koka
meant that you know you're talking about
the sharing but exclusively from the
sharers point of view right okay it
would be really interesting to
understand and this sort of contextual
integrity framework that you posed in
the paper
about sharing you know how recipients
point of view around the sharing and how
sort of the bigger interaction wins that
may have some real insight into the
kinds of controls and nudges that might
be yes interesting yes one of my future
plans is to study what study users and
doctors collaboration so I aim to you
know conduct user study with also
doctors to ask them about the reception
so this one of my blends so interesting
right now you know I get from Latrobe
University in Australia I say thanks for
the interesting talk I was wondering
about you talked about people when they
child informations actually they'd
really don't see the sensitivity notes
of that data shouting through all these
that the devices and were you able to
develop a kind of a threat model
understanding how the attackers could
leverage their tax through inviting a
previously of people its plaintiff
identify where the attackers couldn't
sneak into the systems through inviting
people surprise kind of things yeah I
did not think about this but I think yes
you're right if we like make some
experiment with users and telling them
that we will collect some personal data
from them they might be they might
reveal a different behavior so yeah this
is something interesting too I was that
a question for you so you talked a lot
about how what people's preferences and
considerations were in sharing data with
other people mm-hm and it was kind of
heartening to see that actually reason
about why they're sharing data and why
then what data they might not want to
share did you learn anything about how
they feel about the fitness tracking
companies having that data as well
did not examine the company's user
perception about their companies but
yeah some of them were concerned about
the marketers and about insurance
companies so these have some doubts that
their information might go to third
parties great thank you let's thank our
speaker
[Applause]