hi everyone my name is Nicola Pattanayak
I am a PhD student from the University
of Bristol the area of my the area of my
research focuses on the development of
novel programming abstractions to
improve the usability of security api's
however first I need to understand what
the problem is and as a first step
towards finding out I ran the study
titled
usability smells and analysis of
developers struggle with crypto
libraries along with Joseph Hart and a
waste Rashid so I'm going to quickly go
through some definitions as these terms
are very frequently used in my study so
firstly what is a cryptographic library
a cryptographic library is quite simply
a toolkit of operations that a developer
a developer can use to implement
cryptographic algorithms and features to
better secure their application now what
is a smell a smell is a structure in the
code that indicates a violation of a
design principle and overall it
negatively impacts the quality of the
design so we're going to talk about the
differences between code smells and
usability smells now so code smells are
indicators that a piece of software code
may be of a lower quality than desired
so code SMO signifies that while a piece
of code may not be broken it is in
violation of a design principle and
therefore may be fragile and prone to
failure following the idea of code smell
we have a usability smell so the idea
here is that a usability smell is an
indicator that an interface may be
difficult to use for its intended users
so developers struggle with programming
interfaces in the same way that users
may struggle with user interfaces ok so
an example of a code smell is Fowler's
shotgun surgery so the idea here is
basically save a developer wants to make
a change
they've made the intended change to a
certain class right but they may also
need to make other smaller changes to
the surrounding classes as well now the
issue
when they need to keep track of all
these changes and in doing so they may
miss out an important change so what the
codes most signifies is that if the code
smells of shotgun surgery the code may
pass all the tests you run it through
however the smell suggests that there's
a deeper issue within the code structure
which you need to have a look at okay so
let's talk about what the the problem is
so cryptographic api's are hard to use
many studies have highlighted
recommendations guidelines and
principles to suggest how to improve the
usability of crypto API s but we need to
ask question if these usability
recommendations we need to ask whether
if the usability recommendations are not
being implemented so how can you tell
when such usability recommendations are
not being implemented okay so the idea
here is basically to make developers
understand the importance of usability
smarts and understand the mistakes they
make while designing with the library
what principles they may have overlooked
and what principles they need to address
in order to successfully address the
usability smells that come along with it
so developers may know the principles
however they may not be aware of the
usability smell that come along with it
so in this paper we focus on 10
usability principles defined by
Greenland Smith and in this paper we
focus on two key questions the first
being what are the issues developers
face when they use in crypto libraries
and what are the tell-tale signs that
one of the 10 usability principles is
being violated
ok so Green Smith wrote this great paper
so basically they got a list of
usability guidelines based off API for
API usability and reworked it to address
crypto API but are the green and Smith
principles right
okay so here are the ten green smith
principles one important point to note
here is that the principles themselves
are written in a positive manner
now what I mean by this is if we take
abstract for example this is considered
their golden rule so the idea here is
that you integrate the cryptographic
functionality with like a standard API
so that the developer doesn't need to
interact with the crypto cryptographic
API in the first place now you can tell
by the framing of that statement that
it's it's it's written in a positive
manner right so how can we spot when
green and Smith principles are not being
followed and what are the issues
developers face and all the issues
developers face fixable with the
principles they suggest and how can we
tell when developers are struggling with
a cryptographic library ok so we started
off with 2491 questions and we ran a
thematic analysis on them to define the
recurring issues developers face and
from this we arrived at 16 usability
issues so these issues basically
captured the the the core issue
developers face when they're asking
these these questions we categorize
these 16 usability usability issues into
seven themes so in the paper I go into
more detail as in the examples and how
these these issues manifest in questions
now the relationship between the
usability issues and the ten green and
Smith principles allow us to identify
the for usability smells so the smell
themselves are indicative of the
principles that are not being observed
basically okay so in order to identify
the developer struggle we analyzed 2491
Stack Overflow questions and we examined
them from a range of seven different
crypto libraries
now these crypto libraries themselves
cover a vast number of languages and use
cases so open SSL lip sodium and NEC own
they come from
bouncy castle comes from Java s JCL
crypto GS come from JavaScript and PI
crypto comes some Python within that you
can see from the chart that most of the
questions yet they come under open ssl
but there are other differences so for
example open ssl is considered a low
level crypto API what this means is it's
very detailed and usually the developers
use it have a high level of expertise
when it comes to cryptography on the
other hand you have live sodium which
claims to be usable now when you look at
the the way lib sodium is structured
it's a highly abstracted crypto API so
we go into more detail here okay so
let's look at a few of the questions and
see how the issue is manifest within the
questions themselves okay yeah okay so
the the developer states that they wish
to use a same function which is
supported by the library however the
developer says that they cannot find the
relevant information associated with
function and therefore you know that
they don't know what to do next
so that's pretty much the question so so
this type of issue
moves on to missing documentation so so
so this is how it it's it's classified
right in this example the developer has
used the library but but they failed
right this is quite common they would
they would post the code on Stack
Overflow and quite simply ask what's
gone wrong here so as a result the
answers usually give the same code back
but with the amendment made in the
correction so this would come under
what's gone wrong here ok so these types
of questions they raise the question of
appropriateness right so the developer
usually has like a task or a project in
mind right and they want to know which
library if there's more than one library
would be most appropriate to use for the
project they have in mind or say if
they've already selected library within
that library say if there's more than
one
function that achieved the same output
which function is most appropriate for
the project they have in mind so this
type of question comes under should I
use this okay so okay these types of
questions here there were many instances
where the developers struggled with
using functions from library quite
simply due to the fact that they have a
lack of knowledge of fundamental
cryptography so here the the developer
sets out just to create their own
certificate however they don't
understand the difference between a
trusted certificate that's created by a
certificate authority that's been
verified versus an untrusted certificate
which they've created themselves so this
comes under lack of knowledge okay so
all right these these questions also
comment the example I think I can
explain here is say for developers use
openness or several years right they've
done countless projects on it and they
understand how open SSL works their
mental model has now been structured to
how open SSL has basically been
structured right but let's say if
they're going to start this new project
where they're gonna have to use MTU
crypto which is Python library right so
basically they're they have this mental
model of how open SSL works right and
they're trying to recreate the same
functionality in a different library
empty crypto right which may have a
different different structure different
model right so the questions they raise
is basically asking how they can use the
mental model they have of open SSL the
one they've borrowed and use it to use a
new library so these types of issues
come in the borrowed mental models right
okay these types of questions so there
are many okay so the developer is
basically struggling to integrate the
library with other platforms and
possibly other libraries themselves
right so in this example they're trying
to encrypt using open SSL but decrypt
using another tool so these types of
questions come under compatibility issue
okay there were many questions so like
that look look like this develop a
stroke on the very first step of using a
crypto library and that step is quite
simply building the crypto library and
running the tests now these types of
issues come in a build issue just to
just give an example 18% of the OpenSSL
of the questions that came under open
ssl were attributed to build issues okay
so here's like the overall mapping of
basically how what the usability issues
to developers face
I covered like one from each category
okay so everything highlighted in red
are there 16 years ability issues the
ones highlighted in blue are the themes
the usability issues have been
categorized into so just just to give
overview usage issues so this is quite
simply the developer asking questions
about usage so they may ask questions
without appropriateness or quite simply
how to use this system issues this is
this comes from Bill diffusers and
performance issues not knowing what to
do and this comes from maybe the develop
having a lack of knowledge which may
lead on to passing the buck nothing if
it can do so this raises the question of
the ability of the crypto library so you
may have like an unsupported feature or
the developer may have to use poor
mental model missing information comes
from missing documentation may be a lack
of example codes or quite simply a
clarity of documentation programming is
hard comes from abstraction issues
what's gone wrong here an API misuse
issues across time and space covers
compatibility issues and deprecated
features okay so this table here shows
the relationship between the usability
issues and the ten green and Smith
principles now if you remember earlier
we made the point that the ten green
Smith principles are written in a
positive manner right so in contrast the
usability issues are written in
negative manner so the way you can
understand this is safer developer fails
to fully implement a user usability
principle we might expect to see
questions that show the developer
struggling with one of the usability
issues we identified so yeah based off
that relationship we can we came up with
for usability smells now three of which
the first three are covered quite nicely
by the grayness math principles however
the final one not so well we're going to
go through the usability smells and
basically look into them more more
detail okay neither super sleuth so
basically the user needs to be a super
sleuth in order to find the relevant
resources they need to correctly use a
function from the library confusion
range this usually takes place before
the tasks so the developer may be
struggling as to how to use the library
or again raise questions of
appropriateness now needs postmortem
this usually takes place after the task
has been completed so the developers use
the crypto library but something has
gone wrong now the developer needs to
figure out whether there's some type of
issue they caused or whether the issue
is associated with the library itself
okay doesn't play well with others so
this is the issue this is the usability
smell that's not very well covered by
the greenness principles now the issues
that play here are build a shoe
compatibility issue and performance
issues now we did find a bit of a
relationship between the builders and
the temple in sports however performance
issues are not covered by the ten by the
ten years of usability principles by
Greene and Smith okay
so this table shows the prevalence of
the usability issues against the crypto
API is now I know you can see this
there's only the three crypto libraries
here organized to sell bounce castle and
pipe repair
that's quite simply because they had the
most number of questions associated with
them I can go into more detail if need
be okay so in conclusion green and Smith
principles are basically correct we
shouldn't ignore build issues and yeah
the next time you use a crypto library
have a sniff thank you for your time
[Applause]
thank you very much for that this is
something that's very we're consumers of
research like this this is important
stuff I'm a little bit if I understood
correctly under usage you had both
appropriateness and how to use and for
me or at least my suspicion is that this
is where you where you actually have
huge problems and I'd love to see these
teased outs so for example if somebody
asks how do I use rot13 to encode UT
Unicode to encrypt Unicode the correct
answer is don't and you know I mean I
could come up with more plausible things
but I wanted to give an example for non
cryptographers and so because that I
believe is actually where I suspect the
developers make mistakes in
appropriateness and so I'd love to see
that teased out and wondering if you
have any plans to look at that yeah well
in the paper we do talk about the future
work and how we should probably focus on
how the usability issues come to be and
exactly what the issues how the
developer gets to that stage in the
first place so I'm sure we'll be
covering that at some point Thanks
question hello Thanks I'm a lobbyist hey
thanks again for this
presentation actually got a chance to
read your paper on the flight in I was
wondering and maybe I missed this I was
wondering if you had a chance to look at
github issues and see if there was any
correlation between the types of
questions and some of the issues that
developers ran into and see if there was
any correlation between the Stack
Overflow questions that you analyzed no
I mean like initially we were looking at
where we're gonna get a scrape all these
questions from I did suggest github at
one point but there's like tens of
thousands of questions to look through
we looked at Stack Overflow because the
questions are framed in such a way that
the developer is asking the type of
question where you can find like the
issues the developers are actually
facing with github it's the questions
that they're of a different type they're
structured in such a way that you you
won't really be finding the issues
developers have using the library they
may point out like like generally like
system issues or something like that
but I guess that's that's something we
can you know have a have a look at Becky
thanks for your question yeah hi Chris
long next century so you alluded to this
in your talk so maybe there's the answer
in the paper but one of the issues is
you know different libraries are
different sizes and different levels of
detail and to cap you know debris of
complexity so you would expect that
libraries that are more detailed and
powerful might be might at least require
you to read more documentation to
understand how to use and mean so is
there or how do you address that or do
you see that as an issue is like trying
to analyze the data and maybe modulate
for that somehow well so are you trying
to say that safe and novel sorry a new
developer like a novice came and started
using these slide please how would they
go about using it is that it's not the
question
sort of well if somebody has if there
are lots of questions about a library it
could be I guess maybe it's related to
documentation because it could be that
the documentation is bad or it could be
that they just didn't read the
documentation
so is it I mean I don't write here you
got to avoid blaming the user except
that sometimes they do deserve it
so I know you're right yeah yeah you're
right okay so passing the book it's one
of the issues that I I didn't cover
during this this presentation so
basically what this means is the user
has asked a question right now if you do
a simple search of what the the the
question is in the library's
documentation it comes up as like the
first result right it's super easy to
find if you can do it right so what
results from this is basically the user
has delegated the question into the
Stack Overflow community instead of
going and reading the library
documentation so that quite that stems
down to passing the buck basically yeah
but in terms of documentation the
libraries the quality of documentation
ranges from library to library I guess
it's more for open SSL they may they do
cover a lot of the functions but if you
look at s JCL for example if you
literally go into the the library
documentation they have the function
then the only other resource they have
is the source code so in terms of
documentation there's no example codes
there's no like actual sentences so I'm
guessing you need to be a really you
need to have a high level of expertise
to use something like that
okay thanks let's make this the final
question thanks very much for the study
really enjoyed the presentation this is
a an issue that we deal with an industry
a lot actually main question was did you
find any correlation between say results
of static analysis tools run on these
libraries and the detected usability
smells yeah thanks for the question so
static analysis is a section I will be
looking at in my PhD at some point for
now III just try to answer the very
simple question of what developers are
struggling with when they use in crypto
API is
Thanks okay thanks we time everyone
[Applause]