right so before I start I should mention
that the real solution to dealing with
malicious traffic is to be prepared for
malicious traffic in in particular you
should build your links and your in your
server capacity in a way that allows you
to absorb attacks but in the mean time
because things in the physical world
take money and time to change you need
better tools a little bit about dying as
we have about 20 data centers in five
continents our main business is DNS
services also email and internet
intelligence and we use anycast a lot
and some of you may know that we
sometimes get some DDoS attacks so
responding to malicious traffic the old
way or the default way is first you need
to determine which sites are under
attack
then you determine the router names
those sites then you SSH into the each
router you hopefully type in your ACL in
a text editor and you copy/paste it and
rinse lather repeat you do that
hopefully the same way everywhere you
don't make any mistakes any typos and
you pray and of course it's how you feel
when you're doing that because you're
under attack and it's very frustrating
so obviously you're not as fast as you
want to be you always make typos always
you forget one router or you log into
the wrong router and
and you have problems with cleaning up
later because you left the ACL in some
place and then you forgot about it or if
you have automation like we do your ACL
gets rewritten before even the attack is
over so it's just a big mess obviously
there are better ways and we have this
tool that talked about in other
presentations and it's a continuous
integration approach to configuration
management and it works great except
that it's really not built for
emergencies it's more for configurations
that are supposed to be permanent so the
approval phase and the testing phase and
all that is a bit too much when when
you're under attack and under a lot of
stress so it's not the best answer I
mean you could say actually actually you
just use templates and generate the
configs and push them with danceable but
still that's not the fastest way the way
we deal when when with an attack when we
need to filter something somewhere is
now through a chat bot we use slack so
someone on the NOC Channel is aware of
what's going on they know what they need
to filter and they type in some things
in this slack channel it's a lot shorter
and more concise than what you would
have to do at the CLI and you only do it
once and while you're doing it everyone
everyone is watching what you're doing
because you're doing it on the slap on
the slack Channel and so you type that
commit and sit back and relax and you
watch your counter graphs to see how
much you are filtering and that happens
very very fast so even the sloth from
Zootopia would do it fast enough so what
is flowspec
because that's where I'm going flowspec
is a standard it's been around I think
from 2009 there's an RFC that you should
read about it it allows you to specify
not route but filter specifications or
ACLs basically and based on those ACLs
you can you have the option to do
several operations on those packets that
match the ACL you can discard them you
can apply a rate limit you can redirect
the packets to a different routing
instance etc it's very cool so we
thought okay let's let's build something
with flow spec that we can use quickly
and so we've used Excel BGP everybody
probably knows what that is it's a BGP
tool that is open source it's great we
use it for other things and we thought
well let's just put an API in front of
it make sure that the API allows us to
specify these filtering rules and put
some persisted in some storage so we can
save them and then we have that exit bgp
instance talked to every edge router in
our network and then that opens up a lot
of possibility so with an API as you
know you can do many things you can talk
to it directly from a command line or
you can tie it to a chat bot or you can
build a web a web page that talks to the
API if you're brave enough you can even
tie it to your net flow collection and
if you are very sure about what patterns
you are encountering that makes sense
and you want to block then you can set
some triggers that talk to that API and
actually block things for you so in our
case we built it we put the API server
in one of our core sites we bit just
configured
appearing with that API server from
every router and you can actually also
do redundancy very very easily by just
placing the same thing in a different
core site or this different part of your
network and use Redis replication to to
exchange the the data and just peer with
the other one at the same time from
every router and it would look something
like that
right very simple so going into detail
if you haven't seen except PGP
configuration this this is probably very
intuitive doesn't need a lot of
explanation you define a template that
you can reuse more easily and you in the
template you put all the common
parameters that you're going to reuse in
your neighbor definitions and then of
course you're gonna define all your
neighbors and inherit from that template
and here's the fun part about xwp
you can define a process you give that
process a name that makes sense to you
and that process runs a piece of code in
this case it's Python it's a Python
piece of code and you define the encoder
as JSON which means that you're going to
be exchanging JSON what that does is the
Excel PGP demon will run this
application and the application it will
be mostly receiving the standard output
from that application and taking it in
and passing that data to the BGP engine
from the other side and I'm just giving
a Juno's example but it could as well be
another render very similar just a bgp
peering it's an external peering in this
case local address P Ras neighbor and
notice that this is a multi hop session
the reason for that is our network is a
bunch of islands we don't run ibgp in
between our edge sites and our core
sites or anywhere actually so the the
easier the easiest way to implement this
was to just put the API thing in one
place and make it just peer doing multi
healthy BGP peering the part at the
bottom that says no validate if you've
read the RFC it'll make sense but if you
haven't very quickly there's there are
some mechanisms defined in the standard
that tried to protect the receiver of
the flow spec in a way that doesn't
compromise someone else's routes or
someone else's traffic and for example
if you're a service provider you would
probably want to only accept flowspec
definition that matches a route that
that same peer is sending you in our
case that that's that doesn't apply so
we use an no validate option but you do
have the option to specify a policy so
you can do anything with that some
options for example you can limit the
amount of flow spec entries that you
accept or you can limit the prefix
length that you are able to accept that
you want to accept and the application
itself is simple it's a little bit of
Python using the flask framework it's a
web framework you can use for api's or
for anything really the persistence
layer we chose Redis because it's simple
as fast it's well-known and it allows
for replication and then there's a
simple reverse proxy so we can do SSL
Certificates and authentication now
going more in depth into how the read
the REST API works there are these
resources so as you know a REST API it's
probably everybody should know what
by now but in case you don't a rest api
is based on resources and in those
resources you can execute operations and
those are usually post delete or put so
you can create new resources delete
resources or modify resources the
resources that we created were three
very simple flows which are the
specifications for those ACLs and they
actually can represent more than one
flowspec you'll see how then there are
sites because we didn't want to have to
type all the neighbors in our commands
we created this mapping between sites
and routers so it's easier to just say
apply this to NJ NYC instead of saying
you know router 1 blah blah blah blah
blah and then there's a refresh resource
which has to do with the fact that if if
the X of GP demon goes down or the if
one of the routers reboot that session
is re-established and maybe if you're
what's it called the let me go back did
I miss that
[Music]
the timer what's a good they're graceful
restart saying sheesh my memory great is
if graceful restart has expired
then you need a way to refresh that
route that not that route that flowspec
definition and that allows you to send
it to all the routers affected by that
by that rule the flow resource is a
n-tuple thing with all the possible
parameters for matching the packets we
did not include all the possibilities
there are more like packet lengths and
ICMP code and a bunch of little details
that we thought well we'll start simple
and then add on so these are the
parameters in the flow resource it has a
name
we usually named it after the incident
that's going on the neighbors can be
sites or routers the operation is you're
either announcing or withdrawing you
have source IPS and/or destination IP
protocol source and destination port
expressions and those are based on the
RFC syntax and optionally a rate so by
default we discard packets but if we
pass the rate option then the packets
are rate limited this is an example
using curl so speaking directly to the
API from a command line the header says
content type is Jason the operation is
post so we're creating a new resource
and you'll a flow resource we name it
example flow it has a list of neighbors
sike one protocols TCP to source IPS and
one destination IP and then the ports
are port 80 and port 443 and a rate once
the flow is created you can query the
API and see that everything you passed
it is there and you can see in nice JSON
output and this is what exit vgp receive
so once the the flow the flows back
the flow resource is stored in Redis
then it is converted to this JSON format
that except EGP understands and you'll
notice here that it creates two flow
spective definitions one per source
because the standard says that you can
only have one source and one destination
so the code is smart enough to separate
it into two and that is passed on to
excel bgp notice that here we are
telling XIV GP which neighbors are
supposed to receive the announcement so
in some cases you don't want to send the
I mean because we specified the site
previously that means that we don't want
that rule to go everywhere we want it to
go to a specific router so in this case
the routers are these two and that is a
great feature
I mean xwp and then in Juno's you can
actually see when that flow spec is
received you can see that the filter is
created and like any other filter you
can look at counters packets and bytes
that are discarded or that match the
rule so so far so good we have the API
it's working now how do we use it I
noticed this trend that operators really
like chat BOTS because it has many
advantages and so in this case this chat
bot is our interface between the people
that are on the slack Channel and the
API it's more human oriented it adds
some help output so if you forget the
syntax and of course you forget the
syntax every time you need the help so
you say you remind me please how am i
specify a flow it has a dry run feature
which is cool you can see what you're
doing get some validation before you
actually commit everyone in the team can
see what it's happening I think that's
the main that's the main benefit before
chat chat ops we were used to typing
things on the command line and then
posting it on the chat so everybody knew
what we were doing but that's
steps this is one and the cool thing is
with the same chatbot you can talk to
different ApS and do different things
and in fact that's that's what we do and
when you when we ask the people who are
at the forefront of dealing with these
issues they were quite happy the
response was good experience was between
febrile I we used it about 150 times and
this is a informal count based on search
which means that we were you know using
it quite a bit
no more CLI typos the the reaction time
is reduced significantly I mean I'm
talking about from going from 15 minutes
to under a minute in reaction time we
because we name those those flow records
after the incident which is tracked in a
different application then when that
incident is closed you can actually
delete the the record from from your API
and I did an informal poll on the chat
you know how much faster do do you think
you can deploy a packet filtering now
compared to before and everybody agreed
that it was a lot faster which is good I
mean we had some challenges
except PGP is great and is very feature
full but you know as someone who
maintains open source I know it's hard
to maintain documentation so sometimes
it was a little hard to figure out how
things were supposed to work but we
figured it out at the time the multiple
neighbor functionality wasn't there so
we had to do a lot of reading code and
we noticed that it was actually
implemented in the master branch so
there was code and he worked so we were
able to use it I think by now the the
latest release includes that that
feature so that's great one thing that
we haven't tackled is a pv6 and that's
unfortunate but
it requires Juno's newer than or more
recent than 16 1 and that's not always
possible so it's something that we will
definitely tackle when we can before
taking questions I wanted to mention and
thank Jeremy dubbings bachlin who helped
me a great deal with the API
implementation and Johnny Gregg's who
basically took the the task of
developing a chat bot and so both both
of them did a great job and we have
quite a bit of time for questions maybe
some closing remarks before I forget
this isn't rocket rocket science I'm
sure some other people have done this
internally I but I really wanted to show
how it's possible it's not hard and I
gave you all the hints you know all the
the hardest parts which were ok let's
figure out the syntax that we need to
pass on to accept BGP I figured it out
for you so you're welcome
hopefully this will help others
implement something like it and and
benefit from it Michael Michael Sinatra
yes very interesting what you're doing
mmm sorry for my froggy throat are you
what kinds of security implications are
there in this setup I'm thinking in
terms of like how do your operators
authenticate the slack to make sure that
it's actually the person who's
authorized to be doing this
yeah great question two-factor on slack
or anything like that yes right great
question so we run slack internally
first of all so it's not going out in
the Internet and we do use two FA and
the chat bot also checks that only
people from the NOC are able to use it
that actually answered my next question
which is what do you do if somebody's
dossing slack but yeah I actually don't
even have ax
to the mod of course I have access to
the to the real server so I can I could
circumvent that but it's pretty tight
yes
so Erin Finney with open X question is
what are you using for your DDoS
detection right now what tools and do
you have any plans to integrate those
into this for orchestration we use a lot
of tools but we we use a lot of NetFlow
so we have a lot of nice dashboards and
and searches we use elastic search to
store our flow data and we've created
triggers that very quickly tell us that
a particular IP is sending too many
packets or a particular IP of ours is
receiving too many packets and so we
detect attacks pretty quickly we have
not tagged that to a direct action
because we I think we're not there yet
but also because our knock is you know
they're very quick in deciding and
running tools so it hasn't been a big
priority but it could it could be done
do you currently have 24-hour not
covering this and then what's the what's
your average time from the start of an
event until you actually detect it and
make an action on it it's much better
now I can tell you then
I don't know years ago I don't know I
don't have the data I mean I would have
to ask people from the NOC but I do know
that it's way faster because we're
better at using tools and developing
tools now fair enough
thanks a lot thank you all right thanks
so much
[Applause]