hi I'm Jacob Heights from Cisco I have
another
you for the Rutley no protection k what
is a rat leak if you're an AAS and you
receiver out from one other a s and you
send it to the other a s and neither
side is paying you then you're leaking
the route so that's basically a rattly
why does anyone care other than the a s
that's actually doing the leaking and
that is because the a s that's doing the
leaking usually is a small customer
errors and he has very small pipes and
if you send the whole internet to him
he's going to drop it all so that's why
you care what did I write there about
that okay so the concept of this one is
that suppose customer a s 3 there has to
transits to transit providers a s 1 and
a is 2 now he sent a route and in that
route he puts the community that says my
transit are a s 1 and a is 2 so that now
a s 1 will receive Iraq through the
other way from a s 2 now he looks at the
community that he already got and says
yes yes to either transit so ok that
route is not a leak now a is 3 sins the
route to a s for as he normally would
but a s for sins it onto a s 1 but a s
one already has that community from the
other route that says a S 4 is not a
transit so now that so now a s 1 can see
well i received it from a is 4 but a s
for was not a transit so that must be a
leak
that's the idea right now to encode this
I've decided to do that in in BGP and to
encode it on each route Indies
individually and the reason for that is
that you may be sending certain routes
to certain trains its and other routes
to different transits there are some CD
ends around that will censor will have
lots and lots of transit spot they send
a single route to each transit but not
to any of the others so the relationship
the trains that PA customer relationship
is different for different routes so I
put the put the information on to the
route themselves also in different
locations in different regions of the
world you might have different transits
so you want to do that you want to send
the route in those locations with those
transits and in other locations with
other transit or not transits no so I
have found that the large community is a
convenient place to put that information
so that's what I chose to do so in the
in the large community again we have
three 32-bit fields so I've chosen to
use the first eight the first field is
to be a the well-known number to say
this large community indicates route
leak protection and then the other two
is the nominating a s in the nominated a
s so the nominating a s is the one who
says these are my transits
now if an AAS does not have any transits
then he puts in he nominates as number
zero as being my transit that is to
distinguish those cases that do not send
anything
and those aliases that have no transits
I so what do we got D so that's just a
detail there which I mean let me just
three that ok next one ah yes there are
sometimes sometimes an AAS will split
the prefix in seeing split prefixes to
to a content provider perhaps in order
to do the traffic engineering to say I
want parts of my network to come through
here and other parts of my network to
come through there and so they split the
prefix and send it to the content
provider now when the content provider
leaks those more specifics out to the
internet then all the sudden they just
draw all the traffic for that and they
drop right which happened in Japan a
month and a half ago I think so
so my answers for that one is to put
another route leak protection community
in that says this is a transit for all
of the more specific routes to this
realm ok so so now we have two of them
we have on Isis these are my transits
for this route and the other one this is
these are my transits for all of the
more specific routes of this realm the
ones with the longer net masks
okay so how do you find a leak now so 64
500 sins sins two of these it says so
along the top here we have nominated is
64 500 my transit is six four five oh
one and another one this is my transit
is six four five oh two now on this same
route he also gets another one from that
guy on right 501 and 501 has no trains
it's so he just since the one this is my
transit is zero so these are the are
lp's they're 502 has received from
wherever it's receiving them from now
now we get a route let's get the red one
at the bottom so 64 500 sins off to the
left to 504 who sends it up to 502 so
502 gets an AAS path in that his path is
500 for 500 so he's going to look at 64
500 says do I have any our LPS 464 500
yes I do that's the first two there and
is 64 504 is that in a list of transits
no it's not there we have 501 we have
502 but we don't have 504 so 504 is a
leak because it cannot follow from 500
there are some other proposals in the
ITF had affixes one of them is to put a
bit into in in band into the actual
route that is leaking now that requires
the AAS that's leaking to pass that bit
through and as some of you may know
there's no such thing as a transitive
attribute in a BGP anymore
because some years ago there was a few
bugs where routers crashed because they
had unknown attributes sent and then we
all went and put this protection in so
they can drop unknown attributes and so
a lot of people drop unknown attributes
so transitive attributes get dropped
unknown transitive attributes get
dropped so so for this proposal the
leaking AAS does not need to pass
anything doesn't need not need to
upgrade any code now a Tijuana transit
or any trains that can sell this brat
leak protection to its customer the
customer puts a community that was a
part of mist this is a way to to do this
with a regular community the regular
community is smaller so you can't put
all the information in in a regular
community you can only say this one is
my transit but he has to be 16-bit yes
so in that case the customer writes into
a community these are my transits and
then the ISPs will pass that along
amongst each other
okay okay I have the route service in
there the IXP right server the route
server does not put it's a scene into
the area's path so there's no way to
check whether the route server leaked
anything now route server does not
actually need to have any trends that or
peer or customer type of relationship
with any of its clients because it
doesn't put it say a scene into the
area's part the actual
IXP route server clients themselves have
relationships amongst themselves only
right what are they the the ISP can sell
AR out leak protection to the customers
without having to rely on other a SS to
cooperate because it's only sees through
them the leaking is does not have to
cooperate okay okay now I have a few
more examples here so what's this one
this is a typical Valley leak so a
Swanson's route to its customer its
customer is Jill home it seems it's
other home and because the route leak
protection is passed through between
peer ISPs the the receiving I speak and
detect that and detect that here we go
is a swine has no trains it since its
sister a ste I have no transit but we
got a route from a s1 through is 3 so
that's detected is a leak ok here is
here is one that could be seen as a leak
here we say is fine not a salon I don't
have any transits nice in said to his
peer but he's Pearson's the route to the
customer the customer season a is path
right where it appears that a is to is
transiting for a s1 so that could be a
leak
however the route was received from a
transit itself therefore it's not a leak
so that's part of the rule if you
receive it from a transit
these are lp's don't matter this one's
probably pretty similar to the first one
a swim to Tijuana he's got no transit
since today is too but these two seems
to appear and again from the ROP we can
see they used to it's not a transit
therefore it's a lake okay this one is
again so a s2 is originating or passing
on a customer rock he sees my transit is
a s1 he also sends it to appear and the
P is supposed to actually only send to a
customer but he seems it up to the
transit so again we see the a s path
with three after food but the arrow keys
there's not list three is being a
transit so it's detected okay this was
the most specific that I was talking
about so a is true appears with the
content provider a is three he has a
route 10 double colon slash 12 so that
is
mm he's aggregated route defines his
total network and he sends that to the
internet but he splits that prefix to 10
double : 13 and 18 double : / 13 so that
to split the prefix because he wants
part of the traffic from a is 3 to come
across the top and other parts of the
traffic to come across the bottom so
that's how he achieves that but now a3
leaks one or both of those more
specifics to the internet again now with
the covering route lake protection a
swan came detect that there should be no
trains it's for any any more specifics
of 10 double : 12 okay this is this is
another one but the the RLP the route
leak protection community originates it
is - it goes to the tier 1 provider as1
now he is one he shares it with a s4 and
they trust each other to do that so a is
40 takes the lake because a s3 is not a
transit so so this is the case where the
rat-like protection community is shared
with with a tier 2 provider transits
share the our route lake protection so
this is the this is the case I see I
would imagine mostly would happen there
the
Tiye one provider receives it from its
customer they send it to all of the
appears and that's as far as as it goes
in most cases so we can detect that is a
s2 is originating it sends rattly
protection up to its transit but it
sends the route across to its peer it's
it's P Lakes up and that the tier ones
have shared the relic protection so a s4
knows about it
and as for knows knows about who its
transits are from a s1 and it receives
the route from a s3 it receives a leak
from a is three so I think that's the
biggest point here is that the route
leak protection community travels across
the top and the leaks travel in a
different place along the bottom okay
this is the example about the route
servers the route service cannot have
any relationships with its with its
clients you see here s1 is a provider to
a is to but he is three is a customer of
a is two so for that to occur
there is no possible relationship that a
is - you can't have with the ixp in
order to make those other relationships
work right now here I invented some
configuration for i/o a six-hour
so the way that this would work in the
software is that the software would
match the relic protection communities
against any received routes and then
mark mark any received routes a with a
validity bit that you can test in the
route policy ye if not accepting
forwarded RL please then you delete
these large communities the the rattling
protection communities should really
only be receive from your direct
neighbor so your diff your direct
neighbor your customer tells you who his
transits are who these other transits
are anything further away is maybe not
trustworthy I think perhaps the tier 1
ISPs could trust their peers with this
information but too much further it's
not effective anyway and they you can't
trust in a s10 hops away so you would
put that statement there delete large
community in that the 41 0 0 1 0 0 1 0 0
that is the well-known number and then
you'll put the word not PRA s that means
that if that next number is not your
peer it would delete that community and
the star means anything for the next one
the example here is if the a s path
validity which is that bit thing the
software sets is leaked then set your
local preference you could do other
things you could drop it or you could
just make it totally invalid
sort of like a next top that's
unreachable and then on the outbound
neighbor outbound you put if you're not
sending any if you're not forwarding any
our LPS that you receive then you just
put that so you delete you delete them
and you put your own arrow keys in like
this and you put additive whoop selling
backwards this is pretty much the same
this is one with na s it does have
transit providers and so the top part of
that is the same yeah at the bottom part
is say set large community these are my
two transit providers I am 64 500 and my
providers are 64 501 and 6-4 502 so I
had those two large communities like
with the one before this guy has no
transit providers so he sets large
community with a zero to say that he has
none okay so this one this one is just
for a customer who's requesting route
leak protection for his routes so he's
just on his neighbor out policy he just
is set these communities so this is one
for just sitting community set large
community will be the same as the bottom
one here sick community is that one that
but that only works for 16-bit races and
it cannot be passed on to your neighbors
and this was
this is automating the peer locking
concept that job Snider's it provided
some time ago and you know got an ATF
draft yeah
Oh as of as a as a follow-on from jobs
talk today we are very interested in
knowing what what your thoughts are on
on the things that job wants I think in
particular that one about the iOS
causing the route leaks if you want that
or if you don't want that there's a lot
of Cisco people doing Brownian motion
around here so if you bump into one let
us know questions Jeff Houston a peening
look at when you have a hammer
everything is not a nail yeah you have
to exercise discretion and this strikes
me as a remarkably complicated approach
to a really simple environment as a BGP
speaker in a routing system all I want
to do is not lose money and preferably
I'd like to make money I pay money to
transits customers pay me money so this
is really simple called valley free
routing what I learn from customers
I send to everyone because I get money
from customers what I learned from
transits I only send to customers cuz I
pay money to those transits and I'm not
going to give everyone a free ride and
what I learned from peers I only send to
customers this only needs one bit
it's called the up bit right you with me
so far
yeah yeah we've seen you out there when
I learned it from a peer I clear the up
bit because it's gone sideways all
when I learn it from a transit I clear
the up bit when I learn it from a
customer I set the up bit when the up it
set I only send that upwards that's all
you need
so this seems an incredibly complicated
approach to what is a really simple
control problem
don't send what you learn from transits
or peers to other transits or peers
that's really what you're trying to say
here tell that to the linking I assets
right I do that that's a remarkably
complicated approach to a very simple
problem that you can do with a much
smaller community than what you're doing
here so there are other proposals in the
ITF this is not the only one yeah and if
this is a surrogate IETF BGP meeting
then I'm gonna say the same thing here
as I would say there I just don't
understand why it needs this level of
complexity for a remarkably simple
problem that we've been living with for
the last 20 years
thanks senator microphone please be
quick Leopold and got three minutes for
three comments thank you for the talk
Jacob I think you goofed slightly and
saying you want to strip out everything
except the pier is is communities
because in your drawings you show that
the our LPS have to be passed along so
that the RLP for this a s goes through
this s and over this one so he can make
the decision that that's not a valid
path way if you're dropping the are LPS
that are not from your puree s he'd
never get the are LP from the guy down
here so just just as a pointer I think
you don't want to strip the not puree s
our LPS otherwise it only protects your
people you're talking to and doesn't
protect against that third hop rot leak
the one other piece to this is how do
you make sure that the person who's
leaking isn't accidentally rewriting the
community and putting a community on
that says oh this is a valid transit
pathway okay so so I had some more to
the rules there which a deep detail in
the in the draft and that is if I get an
I forget an RL piece it directly from my
neighbor then
Trump's all of the others so you have a
hierarchy of yeah on it thank you sure
Provo Google Matt hit my forte right
question but the other comment is merely
for the oh one version of the draft I'd
suggest changing the order of the
elements what how you write that so it's
consistent with 74/54 and put my AAS
first the way we did with the overall
large communities no no in in the large
communities you put my a is first right
but that is an indication of what the
rest of them are right I was just
meaning that um
74/54 recommends that you only pay
attention to stuff with your es and then
regarding security against people
sending you signaling data that you
don't want them to send so you the order
of operations within that RFC recommends
you only pay attention to stuff received
with my a s first and then don't strip
anything else because if we do it the
other way than we may have to update
okay well this one is to be a well-known
large community that where the first
number indicates that it is a well-known
large community and we know what to do
with it so Ruettiger were very much out
of time I take this is getting in the
hallway conversation so the last
question is that thanks Sarah Mike I
just want to point a little bit I'm from
Moscow XP and we already implement a lot
of communities and the now most of
platforms most of vendors faced with the
problems that it became to grow amount
of the community that it's assigned to
one prefix with this complicated
approach you just extend this problem
too much and now we also in several acts
peace limiting amount of communities in
the prefix so it could be just ripped in
case if it could be too much so
it's not I think it's not a good
solution for for that okay yeah he put
some more communities into the route and
it provides the service see all right
Thank You Jacob thank you everyone
[Applause]