so anyway hi Dave Duncan again chair of
the election committee we're going to go
through a series of questions for the
candidates all of these questions came
from our community members some of them
are verbatim some of them are
concatenated versions of multiple
questions that were all thematically
similar what we're going to do is each
candidate is going to have three minutes
to give an introduction they should tell
you who they are why they want to serve
on the nine on board and whatever else
they want to tell you in that three
minutes I'm going to run through a
series of five questions each candidate
will have one minute to answer those
questions I'm not rude Elmo maybe I am
but I'm not purposely trying to be rude
I will be keeping them to time on those
questions because we really don't have a
lot of time and we have as you can see a
lot of candidates so with that I would
like to invite Paul to kick it off so
what happens when I sit in the middle so
just a couple notes obviously I Know Who
I am
I'm Paul Emmons and right now I serve as
the executive director for ninja acts
and we operate five community-based
internet exchanges here in the United
States I got started in this business
when I was about 15 years old I left
this business but in telecommunications
basically I start putting in phone
systems for friends and relatives and
that kind of morphed into a
long-distance business and then I
graduated high school so I had to find
something else to do and ended up both
the resale the facilities based
long-distance industry for a number of
years and had operation in Arizona and
California and did consulting for folks
in Puerto Rico Hawaii and throughout the
US and about that time something called
the internet came along
I remember the first day I we got our 56
kilobits circuit from crl along with the
five or six thousand dollar month bill
and we basically started using it for
for email and fun things like gopher and
ever since then been in and out of as
entrepreneur different businesses
basically doing with operating Internet
and networks
and that's also gotten into the paging
and cellular and fixed wireless parts of
the business so my background the last
couple years ago last couple years has
focused on the i-x communities and also
on the fixed wireless portions of
operations and I feel that coming in
here as a board candidate I can offer a
different point of view than look at the
CDN and some of the larger corporate
networks because pretty much everywhere
I work for has been a small or a new
entrant coming into the business so I'm
used to being an entrepreneur and a
gorilla so with that I'd you know love
your support and I joy helping out the
community
I guess one other thing would be I was
also the program director for the
Education Committee and that come from
my parents of teachers my grandparents
are teachers and my sister's a teacher
and that's always something that I've
enjoyed with the community helping learn
and expose people to to new technologies
and new techniques so thank you very
much thank you Steve Feldman
hi I'm Steve Feldman currently employed
by CBS Interactive I'm also on chair of
the ad hoc committee for naina on the
road currently I've been around that up
since the beginning now number one from
notes care so before there I miss some
aspects of the original fifty person
meetings that we had in a university
environment but I've also been thrilled
to see the growth and expansion of our
industry and of nanog over the years
since then I want to see us continue to
thrive but I also don't want to see us
lose focus on the original educational
mission that we had we need to have
balance going forward as we have in the
past yeah sorry for the reading this
we've done really well financially since
becoming independent in 2011 I think it
was we need to continue to ensure that
we have sufficient reserves to whether
or downturn which I think we need to
assume is inevitable we can be happy if
it doesn't happen but it does we want to
be prepared but we also need to be able
to continue investing in programs
educational outreach things like that
without breaking the bank the other
thing I want to mention was if you look
at the current composition of the board
we have two leaving this year
two more leaving next year I think
they're termed out and then when the
following year we're also going to have
a new executive director in the near
future so I think it's important that
somebody there be some one with history
the organization who remembers the past
and that will help compliment board of
new people who can help us move toward
the future so thank you for listening I
hope you'll vote for me but even if not
please consider who the candidates are
and who you think will work together to
move down on forward thinking thanks
Steve Susan for tea
I'm a Susan Forney and I'm currently
employed by the Markley group where I am
the or at lead the network engineering
team I'm a network engineer and I've
worked for the Boeing Company and
Microsoft before coming to the Marketing
Group I was at Microsoft for about 15
years
I didn't really have any prepared
remarks because I didn't want to have to
try and read them up here with my
glasses on so I decided I just treat it
like you'd been walking up three o'clock
in the morning the networks broke and go
so basically what I would like to do for
for Nana is continue to create the the
type of community it has provided it's
unique in its mission for being able to
be a forum and a community for all of
the network professionals in the in
North America and then and also we reach
out to our internationals I would like
to see us continue to to grow and
develop and maintain that because there
really isn't anything else like that I
started coming to Nanog I think was like
nano 25 so it's been a long time ago and
I haven't attended every single one or
since then but I thought that Nana was a
very important organization and it was
really critical to the industry to be
able to maintain this you know level of
community and communication and figuring
out what we're going to do with the
internet as an industry because at the
end of the day we're the ones that drive
it and we're the ones that build it so
if I'm elected to the board besides
making the Express online shorter I
would like to focus on just creating the
type of organization that speaks the
membership and keeps moving forward and
keeps it growing and keeps it vital and
that in the future as well as it has
been in the past
Thank You Susan will address the
espresso thing later if we have time
Eve thanks David hi I'm Eve gorilla kiss
from Cisco Systems I work and the
Optical be you doing product marketing I
am NOT a network engineer and I think
for that reason I bring a bit of
diversity to the board but I really
believe that diversity is not just about
gender or race diversity is really how
you solve problems and how you work with
people to solve problems I think overall
it's working with different people and
understanding what they're doing is
really important and this is a really
special group of people here at nanog I
mean everybody here loves to solve
problems so we're all in this together
so let me give you an example of
diversity in the sense of where I've
bent because I don't expect everyone to
repeat BIOS I was an industry analyst
for nine years so I got to work with a
lot of telecom companies I got to hear
their whole pitches a lot of the
that they deal out and so I understand
sort of you know the whole cycle of
what's going on there and I can address
that if there's anybody that has
questions on this but overall there's a
lot of things that can be done there and
you have to understand that like a
company in Alabama is going to address
their vision very differently than a
start-up say in Israel and so how people
solve those problems are really very
different and I'm pretty good at being
flexible and working with different
types of communities with over that I've
also worked over 10 years as a product
line manager in routing and switching
Bay Networks well fleed Nortel and some
optical startups and obviously optical
and Cisco right now I really work in a
very hub-and-spoke type of way so I
gather information I pull it in I do a
lot of research on it I analyze it and
then sort of disseminate it so that's
really the way that
I sort of work so the real question is
what skills do I bring to the board
which is really important one is the
ability to listen I really like to
listen to the kernels of problems and
work on those and research them and then
figure out what we can really do about
that so that's really one thing that I
really liked I solved a huge problem and
one of my first companies Thinking
Machines if you remember them as first
parallel processing computable company
and I listen to everybody there and the
answers were out there believe it or not
it was just that I had to go through and
research it and go through the process
of proving everything else until we
found the solution and then enabled it
so it's pretty cool thing to do
virtually you're out of time okay just
one last thing I have a lot of
experience on OSA in committees Sean
thank you Dave so my name is Sean
Kennedy I'm a network engineer and a
manager and I'm a long time attendee but
what I think's more important is more
recent experiences with Nanog and I took
some time off while Merritt was managing
the NOC and that was valuable and when I
came back it was largely for work
purposes but I've got involved and
become more engaged for more personal
motivations and so the first one is I've
continued to meet new people learn new
ideas even this weekend with the
hackathon with the tutorial I picked up
new ideas from Brandon Bennett listening
to him explaining go and some of the
ideas of what he had implemented as far
as a BGP controller secondly with the
nanog membership taking over the
organization I feel a sense of ownership
and that drove me to volunteer for the
organization
I actually was nominated for the board
of directors a while back and didn't
feel that I had the qualifications so I
volunteered for the program committee
and I've solicited ideas new content for
the program
I helped grow Nanog on the road and was
one of the people that helped bring the
hackathons to the program and I think
that's been valuable not only in
increasing the content and valuable to
the paying attendees but also growing
our community and making it more diverse
secondly as a committee leader I've
listened to the members and tried to be
their funnel to the board and in a
couple of things to mention the meeting
maker that was launched at this meeting
in what became the women at technologies
lunch are the product of ideas from one
of the program committee members and so
why I can't take credit for her ideas I
listen once you propose them discuss
them with her and made sure the board
heard them and the board acted so I'll
be that type of leader if you elect me
to the board secondly I think engagement
of the membership is extremely important
we can address some of the issues and
challenges that are facing simply by
doing that outreach doing that
engagement whether it's two speakers
committee members new attendees students
so on but there may be things that are
outside the expertise or maybe from the
inside we can't see them and so I'll
talk with the board about are there
things happening in the community or the
things that the members are raising that
we should seek outside help whether its
culture whether its diversity whether
its growth the organization another
thing is to make the organization more
diverse something important it is to
encourage the good people who we have
this community to participate show them
the value that instead of taking their
spare time and spending it on a CCIE lab
they could volunteer for nanak they
could speak in a nog and they could be
on this panel of distinguished people
for the board so there are a lot of good
candidates up here I would appreciate
your vote but please choose wisely thank
you
[Applause]
Tina hi I'm Tina Morris I've been in
this industry for quite a few years now
starting in the Navy going through small
operators and then cable ISPs and now
Amazon Web Services where I manage
strategic planning for ipv4 and ipv6
deployments across in entire Amazon
organization I started coming to Dan now
it's about nine years ago actually as
part of just because they were
co-located with Arin meetings which I
was going to for the IP resources found
more than I expected at Nanog found us
it's community training networking
that's been incredibly valuable I would
like a chance to give back to the
organization a bit of what I've received
from it and I feel that I have always
had unique roles where I've had to build
consensus and manage people that do not
actually report to me and get things
done in organizations in ways that are
not traditional those skills can kind of
be valuable here I currently also serve
on the air and Advisory Council I've
been doing that for four years the vice
chair at this point in time I serve on
the fellowship committee trying to bring
new membership in just something that
Nanog also needs bringing new and
diverse people from different
communities different points of view and
not only bringing them in for their
first meeting but keeping them coming
back through maybe continuing education
and different opportunities that would
be good for the community also helping
people justify attendance at the meeting
the program committee can't always get
the agenda out in time but maybe
trainings and pre-written letters and
things like that of justification to
help people get to the meetings so that
we can encourage newcomers to become
members and
just grow the community and increase the
networking so I would love your vote and
I'd love a chance to serve on wards
Thank You Tina Ron Ripley good afternoon
thank you for your time
my name is Ron Ripley I am Canadian like
the only one here I am currently the
manager of an IP and optical networking
engineering team at Schott
communications in Calgary Shaw is
Canada's largest cable operator or
second largest cable operator with
approximately two and a half million
subscribers that stretch from Thunder
Bay Ontario to Victoria British Columbia
that in itself is a challenge in terms
of optical networking and diversity in
terms of routing my team provides
engineering and architecture solutions
for production international network and
the internet backbone and our optical
network including peering transit
backbone and enabling services such as
content delivery networks IP video voice
and mobility in addition we architect
and operate multiple data centers that
exist across Canada for non
customer-facing applications as well as
our content delivery networks my team
continues to innovate and effectively
scale large national networks to
accommodate rapid subscriber growth
while being mindful of spending the
capital that were given and operating
costs I've been in the industry for
about 23 years starting with the birth
of Canada's second largest Internet
backbone I worked to provide design
engineering operations and long-term
strategy for its evolution I've spent
many years in the vendor community as a
systems engineer and a trusted advisor
for some of North America's largest
telephone companies and cable operators
during that time I've supported those
companies and achieving their business
objectives and their technical
requirements to maximize their revenue
stream and lower their operating
expenses such as building services such
as TV internet high-speed Internet and
voice and services like that I grew up
in this field I've had a passion for
networking and jumped right in after
high school so I didn't have the
education that was required so I
go to the San Diego State University and
challenge The Bachelor of Science degree
and was awarded an equivalency degree in
Bachelor of Science for electrical
engineering I have been at nano only for
about three years I've attended
regularly with the exception of one
meeting I've grown to love the community
and the networking that makes possible
here for me to interact with just about
every content delivery company on the
planet as a board member my goals are to
participate in evolving the bylaws that
make nano big community into membership
and and drive to an autonomous group
promote education programs through the
college immersion programs and encourage
innovative programs such as our
hackathons which are widely exciting
participate and listen to the Nano of
membership and engage all board meetings
I offer the Canadian spin to some of the
challenges that occur in building
operating and operating networks
coast-to-coast and I look forward to
participating on the board if elected
thank you thank you okay so there were
two other candidates Paul Fischetti and
blanking on the other name sorry yes
neither could be with us they also
didn't submit a statement so what is on
the website is what's the most
information that we have on both of them
so what we're gonna do is move into the
actual Q&A session as I mentioned the
first question we have was directed
specifically at Susan foreign issues
provided it in advance relating to a
couple of people had brought up whether
or not there was a potential conflict
given that she works today with a board
member of Patrick Gilmore
so specifically Susan perceived conflict
has been identified between yourself and
Patrick Gilmore giving me work for the
same employer Patrick is on the board
today can you clarify your professional
relationship and explain whether or not
you would consider it an issue to vote
against him on a contentious issue
related to nanog okay so sorry when I
first heard this question the first
thing that went through my mind was
how does anybody think I could work for
three years with Patrick Gilmore and
never have a difference of opinion I
wish I could comment on that and you
know it is true I've had differences of
opinion with Patrick before but the
first thing you should know about my
role at Markley is I do not report to
Patrick Gilmore we report up through
different management's and hit the the
1-over manager for me is a peer of
Patrick so I I don't have like a direct
reporting relationship or a you know
have to you know fear you know what my
boss is going to think if I if I don't
agree with him but I guess the other
thing I would say is that you know I'm
not afraid to make a decision if I think
it's the right thing and vote in a
certain way or or argue for a certain
point you know whether or not people
agree with me because sometimes you are
the only person in the room that's right
and you've got to be have the conviction
to stand up for that and then at the end
of the day if you don't get your way or
you don't agree then you have to have
enough mutual respect for each other to
be able to understand that you know
that's the decision was made and move on
and I you know honestly believe that
Patrick is that kind of person and I can
tell you that I am that kind of person
too so I don't I don't see any problem
okay thank you all right we'll go
straight into the next question which
will be posed to everyone on the panel
here
what was your friend as I mentioned
earlier you have one minute to answer
these questions each what was your most
memorable Nanog meeting or moment and
why and start with you again Susan okay
okay
I think my most memorable nanog moment
was when Doug Wilson joined the touring
Microsoft and he had been in Excel
communications and we went to the
peering Botha and everybody submits a
slide to the peering buff so that you
know they can introduce themselves and
when Doug came up instead of Doug's
slide there someone put up the blue
screen of death and then queued the Star
Wars Darth Vader theme so that was my
most memorable moment at nanog and it
showed me that the Internet is a really
fun place
and maybe you really want to come back
cool even sure I have to say it not that
I participate in the Burning Man event
but the Burning Man presentation was
absolutely fascinating I thought that
was really interesting and how they had
set up a whole communications system and
I think that something like that for
disasters and what we're seeing in
Puerto Rico would be really really
helpful to focus on and some of the
upcoming downs okay Shawn so I'll talk
about an experience that was with an ad
hoc mailing list and it's a little bit
of a old time insider thing but it talks
about community and and so on and it
happens to be Patrick Gilmore of my
first introduction Patrick Gilmore was
he I believe he was working for a
company and a hosting company they may
have gone out of business and I he
didn't have a job but he offered to find
homes for his customers while the power
was still on and try to reproduce within
the data center and get them new
services so we went out and said hey
that's an interesting person let's try
to bring him in for an interview and
invited Patrick flew them to BBN and
Patrick showed up but so the first thing
I want to tell you is I don't plan to
work for you but you offer to bring me
to Boston and I couldn't refuse so I
came Paul okay I won't do any Patrick
info other than the time last time I
think we're in San Francisco where I got
appendicitis I will skip that what is
the most exciting but I just really like
the first guy nog I went to for the full
nanog was in Albuquerque I think was
like number 19 and I remember getting
there and those days we started on a
Sunday and basically getting there like
five minutes before whatever
presentation was was going to go on
and it might have been a buff I don't
really quite remember I just got em BRR
that like during that entire that entire
three days there in Albuquerque that I
was with people that were excited to
learn and and be a community together
and like I said that was the first one I
was out the entire time and since then
I've been coming back as often as I can
Thank You Tina for me one of the most
memorable was a couple meetings ago when
there is that massive DNS outage and
watching everybody come together in the
break areas giving up brooms for four
people to work that already checked out
their hotel suites helping each other
different companies all coming together
to to get through a very serious network
outage that happened during a meeting
and it was really cool to see everybody
work together hmm that was exactly what
I was going to say however I think that
the nanog for me was I do believe it was
again surrounding an outage which was an
elevator issue that kind of I'm not sure
which now that was but the elevators are
out and there was a blue screen on the
panels and the elevators and you know
the other part about nanog for me was
the first one I was at where I got an
opportunity to meet some of the the
people that shaped the way that content
is delivered around this country and it
was you know one of those aha moments
and finally figured out how to deal with
some of these large content providers
Steve a couple but for me my favorite I
think was way back in the early days I
was working for M FS and one of my
primary jobs was to get up in front of
them I got it says it apologized so one
of those meetings I decided I was gonna
wear a target so I had a target printed
up and wore down my shirt and while I
was speaking Shawn Doran was pointing a
laser pointer at the target and but what
struck home was at that point we were
community at as long as we work together
to solve problems didn't try lying to
each other or waving away issues we
could actually as a community work
together to make things better thank you
all right you guys are doing great on
time so keep it
all right the next question is this one
you might actually need your full minute
for if elected what kind of programs
would we work on to address diversity
and inclusion within our community and
if you have the time can you articulate
any specific programs or initiatives
that you've worked on to expand
diversity with another organization
we'll work backwards from Steve because
I think you repeat it okay you reread
the question
all right so if elected what kind of
programs would you work on to address
diversity and inclusion within our
community and can you articulate any
specific programs or initiatives that
you've worked on to expand diversity
within another organization so if you
look around the room you'll see that
most of us look a lot like me with gray
hair and gray beards and we need to fix
that no question I think we can solve
that to an extent by recruiting
volunteers from the broader community
but I think we really have to go is the
pipeline inbound and that is finding
students finding young engineers who can
come into the organization and breathe
new life into it and I'm not talking
about just gender or just race or
anything like that it's a whole breadth
of different backgrounds that we need
more of coming into the organization
that we make what will help us around at
it in the future so I think the the
biggest important one for me is women
and technology and I look around the
building that I work in and I count five
women that work in an engineering
building of about 1100 people and I've
worked closely with the universities in
Calgary and making sure that from a
co-op student perspective that we bring
not only women but people of all diverse
backgrounds mostly on their their merit
of engineering and their desire to want
to be in this industry and we promote
not only women in technology but just
about everybody that wants to to get a
hold of this technology moving forward
okay so diversity is obviously important
I've always been in a male-dominated
field it's always been a challenge I've
served on the women and cable board of
directors for Florida when I was a part
of the cable industry and one of the
focuses was you know just bringing
bringing more women into tech obviously
diversity is also small operators other
parts of the industry other there's so
many things that it covers but this is
an intimidating organization whether we
want to be welcoming or not it doesn't
always come across that way so I think
more investment in mentorship programs
and ways to give people access and feel
a way to start out for newcomers more
trainings more starter one-on-one
courses or 101 courses and offer ways
for people to become part of the
community and a less intimidating format
would be helpful oh I think that by
utilizing the Nanog on the road program
and also maybe looking at additional
educational opportunities is a good way
to bring in other ethnicities and women
into our community in a manner that's
yeah like Tina said about 1,300 people
large and where you can spend a lot a
lot more of one-on-one time with with
those people as well like in the on the
roads there's no cost for that and so
it's a lot easier to get employers to
allow people to go to those to go to
those events and so I see that as a way
that we can help bring in both more more
women and both and and other people in
operations into this organization Shaun
so I mean I think our culture today is
important and in its welcoming but
intimidating and there's very much a
place for a lot that happens some of the
geek humor and presentations and so on
we let our engineers present things that
they wouldn't go and present at PTC that
you wouldn't talk about with your
manager
a review meeting and so on so that
that's important as are the socials but
we do have to engage other members of
the community and we may need help from
outside so as as far as experience with
diversity I was one of the founding
board members of the Brazilian women's
group which obviously I'm not a
presenting women and but they had to go
outside their organization to look at
how to structure their meetings how to
structure their outreach to the
community and so on so I think there's a
lot of value in what we do today and
there's some changes that we may need to
make so first of all the board has to
engage the membership and not just on
mailing lists we can't have a
constructive discussion unfortunately
you're always on mailing this close your
thought sure I mean I I'm welcomed ideas
and and I'd love to talk about this
further and I think the members
breakfast firs is the right place for
members to talk to the board about it
make sure I came up with an idea a
couple of days ago and maybe I'm sure
somebody else has done this before but I
was thinking it would be really cool to
go to some of the sponsors at Nanog and
ask them for ten or fifteen thousand
dollars each
especially the big routing guys who have
a lot of money and put that towards
scholarships for people to come and tend
to Nanog because I think with everything
in this industry you have to start
really young and we have to start
training people really young the number
of women that are in computer science
classes actually according to Melissa
Gates was about 25 percent when she was
in college and it's actually down to
about 15% now so we have to get women in
colleges much more involved on I'd like
to see scholarships that don't go in
that way and I think it's certainly
possible this is the type of thing that
I think I'm really good at it's getting
people to donate money and and figure
out a good scholarship program I also
think that and I've mentioned this a
couple times before but there was a
Harvard Business School study that
that women often drop out of tech
because they're not properly mentored I
have to tell you a lot of what I have to
cut you off but just to be fair
okay don't want to be mentored by women
they want to be mentored by men I have
I'd like the other people on the board
or candidates here I think that that
it's not just about including women it's
about including other ethnicities
because you know it's it's a it's a
large community and you have to make
everybody feel welcome and I think
that's really important I think that you
know making people feel part of the
community and encouraging them to come
back and encouraging their them to
express their thoughts and to be you
know respectful when people are trying
to do that is the kind of thing that
helps us encourage that diversity and
encourage that thought to come forward
so that we you know that we have that as
far as things that I've done for you
know diversity when I was at Microsoft I
developed a program called mentor rings
where I figured out a way to get
director-level women in touch with other
women you know lower level women in a
mentoring program so they would have
access to him because the directors
didn't have time to mentor these women
individually so by creating these groups
and setting this up I expanded the
amount of women who could get mentorship
in that company and it was a was saying
it's really important to have and some
of my mentors in that in that program
were men very many of you know I'm gonna
cut you off but thank you next question
and we'll go back the other way if
that's okay with everyone there's been
some chatter on the mailing list about
the community being and turn off to new
members some might say that it's cliquey
do you agree with this loaded question I
guess and if so what would you do as a
new board member to attempt to change
this perception Susan could serve you
that's okay so actually I kind of think
it is I think that I was very lucky when
I started coming to Nana because I came
with people like you know Matt PTAC and
Doug Wilson who knew everybody
and introduced me and helped to
integrate me into the community and I do
that today I try to read I try to sit at
tables where you know even before I
bring for board never every now like I
go to I try to sit at tables where I
don't know anybody and I try to talk to
people about what they do
and I try to tell them what Nanog is if
they do if they're newcomers and try to
encourage the community to get bigger
and try to encourage them to come back
and and participate and I think you know
one person makes a difference and I
think that's a really great way to do it
look people get clicky it's a natural
side effect of behavioral psychology the
fact of the matter is I think you're
right Jimmy Alban and dougie if you sit
at a table with either of them we'll
introduce you to practically everybody
in this organization and I found an
overwhelming warmth and wonderfulness
amongst everybody here I continue to
come back you know to every Nanog and
see everybody and feel like I can talk
to everybody about anything and learn
from this community I have learned so
much I just learned a whole bunch of
stuff from dougie this morning about
DDoS attacks so it's amazing sure so we
have a fairly large community
particularly in the general session and
on the mailing list and there are some
strong voices but one of the ways to
address that is to provide other forums
that sort of split up the groups such as
Paul mentioned then on down the road
we've had a lot of those and those are
smaller forums and they welcome newer
members the newcomer lunch obviously
does that the hackathons I think have
been a big help you bring people with
different experiences and expertise and
let them run wild there basically and
then the last thing is just the
membership themselves can change his
culture I mean we own nanog it's a
membership organization so step out of
your clicks welcome newcomers don't just
wait for the board to mentor mentor new
people mentor newcomers get people to
join the committee's Oh
we have a hard time come with something
original but I yes it's it's clicky and
I think I once a year tried to bring at
least one of my clients who's never been
been to nanog and tried to introduce
them to as many people and honestly they
just feel overwhelmed with a lot of
times and I think whatever we can do to
help the the new people coming in feel
more welcome whether it's more you know
breakout type of sessions might be a
little bit more helpful but I think it's
really just everybody in the
organization trying to make the the
newcomers feel welcome I think that
would go go very far yes as you said it
most things but said already but yes it
is clicky it's also there's business
meetings going on in the hallways too
sometimes you approach somebody and
they're in the middle of the discussion
and you feel as though you were shunned
when it was just the bad timing so as a
whole we should all make a point to find
those people again and have that
conversation later so they don't feel
put off I think a formal mentorship
program for newcomers would be a very
valuable asset and to take it seriously
and make sure that people that person
meets at least 10 new people at the
meeting that they're comfortable with
approaching at the next meeting and then
your circle just gets larger and larger
each time but if we don't actively
involve these newcomers they're not
gonna make those relationships that make
the say a warm and welcoming environment
completely agree I think the formal
mentorship program is something that we
at my organization do on a regular basis
and bring new people in and give them
somebody or a group of people that can
specifically mentor those in the area of
their expertise so a formal mentorship
program we need to step out of our
comfort zone as being members and go out
of our way to help members that are not
there or on the fence of becoming a
member and help bring them by helping
them mentor or everybody I think that's
it is cliquey but it is also there's a
way out of it with with with a
mentorship program I agree with that
I'm not gonna disagree with anything
anybody said I'm a registered introvert
so it's hard for me sometimes to get out
and do what I need to do to meet people
one idea Paul briefly mentioned which I
think might help a lot is expanding the
breakout sessions back from to where it
was a few years ago where we had boss
for different subjects right now we sort
of have peering and everything else I'd
like to see more specialized areas in
breakouts where smaller groups can get
together and talk about things in a
somewhat less formal manner okay
somewhat thematically on that it's not
my timer here several wants and
long-standing community members also
commonly known as grey beards have
expressed discontent they refer to
themselves as a grave here in the
question with the present direction of
Nanog arguing it has become a trade show
how do you perceive the direction of Na
Nog and what if anything needs to change
under your tenure and will come back the
other way so that you don't have to use
the unoriginal answer Steve that's fine
and I noticed he give to the gray beard
first that was not on par with so they
have an absolute point the I think I
have seen the evolution of Nana from
like I said it was 50 people in a
university auditorium to 1300 people
here today I think there is danger of us
becoming too much of a trade show and
not enough of a conference anymore we
haven't crossed that line and I think
we're ways away from it but I think if
we're not careful at some point we're
gonna cross it without realizing it and
it'll be really hard to go back and I
think there are things we can do like
expanding educational outreach types of
things on the roads my previous boff
idea to help alleviate some of that and
get back to probably the right mixture
of commercialism versus learning about
stuff in the ball
I agree I think it 90% of this should be
about people bringing their ideas
forward in a environment that's
welcoming to them 10% probably or even
less should be about the vendors base
and the vendor communities trying to
sell you something every day I get at
least four of those every you know a
couple hours in the morning here for me
I think you know there's a there's a
form to have in this room we he'll who
stabbed ender night here at least once
at nanog which is which is probably
sufficient for you know the vendors to
to come and show their things but we do
need to make sure that we're not getting
into that tradeshow space and and that's
probably I think closer than you might
think
overall I really appreciate the way
vendors have been kept out of
presentations and advertisement in this
room and thinks to that effect however
my email has definitely increased on
people trying to sell me things
affiliated with my registration at Nanog
so I think it's an a it's a tricky
balance you need sponsorship but you
also need attendees to be here for
education and things like that so I
think as long as we continue to put our
focus towards education bringing new
people in young people and and and keep
the focus there and keep it away from
the intention is to grow new quality
members the future of our industry our
companies but not so much money and
attendance just for the sake of
attendance oh the last tune an ounce or
so I just felt like I'm coming for
meetings outside of the room because
everyone wants to have you know have a
15 or 30 minute meeting so this time I
purposely said yeah I'll meet with you
anytime on Sunday or I'll meet with you
anytime in the evenings but I really
don't want to be pulled away from the
actual conference and in my case I'm
paying for the conference myself and so
you know if there's a session that I'm
not particularly interested in let's say
I I don't
need to go there's no one over over
giving me oversight asking me to go
essentially so I can suck I make my own
schedule so I've kind of felt like I
said I felt torn recently because got
customers or operators they're winding
schedule meetings and I'd really like to
kind of see you know maybe an
encouragement to try to do some of that
stuff away from the away from the
conference time I know that that's that
could be really hard to do but I got a
someone who I've been trying to go hold
up and sup a meeting with for a couple
months now and the time that they wanted
to have a meeting is right now thanks
Paul Sean so I mean there's always been
people pushing their ideas at regional
texts and nanog and so on and I mean
some of the motivations that you come or
not just about the technology when I
first came to regional text I wanted new
code from Tony Lee from my router I
wanted to know why the net edge at Mae
East was shredding my ATM packets and
our ATM was shredding my packets and and
so on but there today there's a lot of
good content I wish we could keep the
people that have the experience more
around more and let them meet newcomers
so an example Vint Cerf came and spoke
in Washington and one great moment in
Nanak he jumped up in the middle of
somebody's presentation walked up to the
podium and instead of asking his
question from a microphone he asked it
at the podium and the presenter was a
little surprised but but actually
enjoyed it and then Vint gave his talk
and afterwards he stood around and took
selfies with the graduate students that
were part of the NCI environment so I
wish that first as jack waters it was
here today could have stayed longer and
other people from the industry to meet
some the newcomers and we could
facilitate that perhaps with the
additional lunches and break outs make
sure I think the program committee has
done a great job of keeping a lot of the
vendor stuff out of the basic subject
matter
for most of the nanos I really do I do
not want to see this turn into a trade
show by any means the intimacy here the
ability to talk very freely about what
we're doing in the networks is I think
priceless so I would not like to see
that changed as Tina said it's a fine
balance between getting the money from
the sponsors and straight arming them a
little bit I feel very comfortable if I
got on the board that I'm very good at
straight arming and yet getting money
out of them I pretty much agree with
that every everyone else has said here I
think it's really important to maintain
Nanog as the you know the community of
people who run the internet you know a
really good example of why that's
important is when the and you know
initial arguments and and debates about
net neutrality we're going on and we
actually had the people from the you
know the government here the FCC here
talking about that stuff and listening
to our opinions and you know and
actually making a difference in how
things work and you know if Nana doesn't
maintain that posture then it's gonna
become ineffective and we're gonna lose
a really you know important valuable
tool so like everybody else I you know
would like to preserve that all right so
now this is the last question I'm gonna
give you 75 seconds each because we've
got a little bit of time and it's a
three parter well three parter for you
one question in 18 parts now so what do
you feel are the top three priorities
that the Nanog organization needs to
focus on over the course in the next few
years and how would your experience or
skillset contribute to successfully
executing on those priorities you can
choose if you want to answer three or
one or two or ten anyway so we'll go
back the other way
starting with you Susan okay I think
that you know pretty much we've talked
about most of the things that I would
like to focus on and that is just you
know continuing with the building of the
community continuing to keep the nanog
focus being on you know people who are
in networks and the industry and and
what it does best and trying to reach
out a little bit more to in
new members and you know like they said
before you know maybe have a little bit
more of a younger population and engage
the people who are gonna build the
networks tomorrow and want them to be a
part of this community too those are the
things I would like to you know focus on
if I'm here I have a long history of
just doing that kind of thing on my own
I I work on those things you know
especially for the outreach when I come
to the meetings and I I would continue
to do that as a board member and try to
organize events so that we could be more
effective at that I think that there
that nanog is it a little bit of a
crossroads right now and I think it's
probably really important to get a lot
of feedback from the general public and
I think it's really important that the
public feels comfortable and not
intimidated to talk about what it is is
that's important to them so I would try
to have a less intimidating atmosphere
and do all the things that we've talked
about not have it be a tradeshow reach
out to many more people and a diverse or
group of people and keep it the essence
of what Nanog is as Nanog Shawn so Nanog
is incorporated as a membership
organization with an educational purpose
so first of all maintaining the
independence of the program committee so
the board shouldn't interfere in the
program committee they do appoint the
members of that but then they let the
committee self organize it solicit the
content and so on so that that must
continue that's important and we must
remain an educational organization and
not a trade show secondly I think
culture and outreach is important and
that's not only maintaining some of the
history Steve talked about our history I
talked a little bit about just being a
safe space for for engineers and others
and we need to be more inclusive so
that's second important and lastly
financial that the questions this time
have largely been about culture whereas
the last election it was
largely about financial and and today
the organization is on solid financial
footing it's making investment of its
cash reserves but we do need to be
careful Indian issues that we take and
so the board should be responsible with
the organization's money yeah I would
like to see that our three time of year
meeting just be the most effective and
inclusive as we can possibly do which
doesn't always necessary work together
but I in some of the other things we've
talked about about having other like
breakout type sessions I think that
would go to a long way for these three
meetings but I also see that the
education whether we do education series
or kind of a more formalized or planned
out arc of educational educational
programming that can be they can be
counted on to occur that can be planned
and you mean I people come to this man
AAG be might be able to come to one next
you know the summer one or the winter
one but having a national schedule that
can span a course of a couple nan dogs
out there I think would be very very
helpful
and then lastly like Shawn and some
others have said on the the neon dog on
the road I I see that where we're as the
best way for us to get other operators
involved we've got we're doing that but
we do like about four or five millimeter
I'd like to see see more if you know if
possible and you know the the other the
other aspect on time that's right
no problem thanks yeah as pretty much
every base saying is more education
continued education immersion of new
people to the community bring in the the
junior network engineers get them coming
not just the top level people and just
bring that new that new group of people
and I've done a lot of work with the
Aaron fellowship committee
to get people in from other other groups
other communities the Caribbean
specifically for Aaron is a challenge
and just trying to build those
relationships and bring people back is
an important thing and that's one of the
things I would focus on as board member
great thanks
I think education as everybody said here
is absolutely critical to the survival
I've I've taken groups from co-op
students from many education
sorry many universities and colleges
throughout Canada and have gone on my
way to make sure that these people get
an opportunity to understand what this
network is and what a network is because
most of them have this aspiration of
becoming a network engineer but when you
ask them if they know what a network is
they really can't tell you so I think
helping them understand the fundamentals
and the basics of what it is and helping
these people grow through engineering
and becoming who we are here today and
and those top tier people the 20 leaves
and the Shawn doors of the world you
know helping that group get to that
point I think is very key thanks Steve
so I see two big challenges among the
various ones worth mentioning here the
external one is what everyone's been
talking about rebus all-time is bringing
in the newcomers extending our outreach
to things beyond just the conference or
trade show or whatever we're calling it
to make sure the new people know about
us and want to participate I can't
really add to the equator idea so for it
already today the other challenge I see
is more internal and that touched on
that briefly in my opening statement and
that is there's going to be quite a bit
of turnover fairly soon as board members
rotate out and especially as Betty
retires and we hire a new executive
director we need to make sure that that
transition is seamless that we end up
not breaking things as we move forward I
believe I'm in a position to help that
with my previous experience on the board
one of my big roles in the past was to
act as kind of a facilitator and
consensus builder even when we disagreed
we could discuss rationally and come up
with what we considered to be the right
answer for various problems and that's
how we got where we are today so if you
choose to realize me then that's what
I'll do
thanks Steve all right so now we're
going to lightning round it we have
about a little more than 15 minutes left
I'd like to invite any community members
who want to ask a question you are free
I would prefer if you asked aimed at the
whole panel and not just at any specific
person and I will give everyone 45
seconds to answer that Patrick Patrick
Gilmore Berkeley group I'm surprised no
one else wants to ask questions don't
you guys want to know what new board
members think about things all right so
we talked a lot about community and what
it means to be nanog and stuff and
that's very very important but as a
board member you have some other
responsibilities who here has actually
read the website where we list off the
responsibilities of what an ad-hoc board
member is required to do all right well
you raise your hands I'm not sure I
believe you
so how a simple question could you each
list one thing that was on the website
Wow okay Patrick
we'll start middle out for this one just
to be fair we'll start with Paul pretty
sure there's something about yeah
financial or fiduciary responsibility in
there so which way do you want to go
I'll go to Shawn I ending board meetings
attending a minimum of nanog meetings in
person Tina like that's right ooh
the I know now seven bullet points just
wanted to confirm that all right does
anyone want to just volunteer one
instead of I think there was the word
home on there somewhere
yes of course there was attending Nanog
meetings at least two it at three in the
year I mean I've read the basic
requirements I thought the division
between the PC committee and the board
committee was pretty interesting that's
what I know anyone else want to add one
steal all of it I don't have a memorized
but video a fiduciary duty is the
important one we have a responsibility
as board members to ensure the health of
the organization going forward and not
just enrich ourselves in whatever way
possible
okay Tony and then Joe Tony Tony Talbert
Comcast what can people tell me about
their experience with to me one of the
most important things at least right now
is hi is hiring and guiding the new
executive director so what can you tell
me about experience relevant experience
that you have that you can bring to bear
start with Eve I don't have a lot of
experience hiring executive directors
I'll be very honest about that I think I
can do a good job interviewing
I would work with the current board
members to help make that decision but
let's go to Tina again not also I don't
have a lot of experience specifically
hiring people like that but I do have
experience working with a lot of people
in that kind of role and know what my
expectations would be and also kind of
shaping the direction of an organization
so I would apply that and hopefully lean
on other board members as well to make
that decision Steve I actually do have
experience higher heat executive
director I was on the search committee
when we hired Betty a large part of the
job is figuring out what you want the
executive director to be what the role
should be in defining it so that when
you actually start bringing in
candidates you are measuring the
candidate against what you want the
person to be you need somebody who's
going to fit with the organization's
goals
who's going to complement us rather than
work against us that should go without
saying obviously but it's needs to be
done with you Ron yeah so again I don't
have a lot of experience in hiring
executive management I do have a lot of
experience in hiring and network
architects and senior principal
engineers but I would defer and work
with the rest of the Nano board to to
work with what's best for the for for
that position Susan when I was at
Microsoft
you know I participated in hiring a
executive level director and general
manager type of people and what Steve is
saying about job search in in those
types of situations is exactly right if
you don't know what you want you're not
going to get it so you have to figure
out what you're going to want first and
then once you consider what it is that
you're looking for then you have to be
very careful to make sure that you
interview the people and figure out
whether or not they have those
requirements and so that's what I would
do
Paul and then Shawn I've had the
experience I guess twice of being an
organization and being
the committee to interview new executive
directors and it's not easy and it
wasn't fun but in one case we found the
perfect person and I think in another
case just through the patience of it we
were able to find a really good match as
well so I I know going into it that it
may not be very easy it may not be very
comfortable but it's very critical that
you get the right person in their trunk
so I think in any hiring situation you
really need to manage the recruiters
provide them with good information look
at the candidates in resumes that they
provide you give them feedback interview
candidates individually as a team and
discuss the results and then revise the
search if there's obviously something we
need to complete so we can't dally doing
that but it you do need to be thorough
secondly it I hope I have worked closely
with Betty and I have a fair amount of
operational knowledge of the
conference's itself for putting it on so
I think I can help
at least with that and there's still
board members with a lot of experience
with the financial part of the
organization that can help mentor a new
executive director so I'm hopeful we'll
find a good candidate and do a good job
of mentoring and making that transition
smooth thank you from Joe you're not
matt matt PTAC Yahoo so at a not too
long ago
Nanuk member breakfast bit of a
bombshell was dropped about a increase
in the fee structure without a whole lot
of warning now as potential board
members in theory you're answerable to
the membership in the community here
what are you going to propose to do to
make sure that the lines of
communication between the board and the
membership of the community stay open
and clear so that when decisions like
that are being made the community is
aware of it coming ahead of time and has
a chance to provide input more than just
pass the microphone around over the bait
and after the citizens already been made
thank you mm-hmm okay so so we can get
through the last question 30 seconds on
this one start with Tina I believe any
proposed field P structure changes
should be circulated to the community
well in advance of the actual vote to
move them forward I think that's the
most transparent possible way to do it
and the logic behind it should be shared
as well Sean so I mean I think obviously
I've mentioned the the members breakfast
and because it's breakfast I mean
Bacon's been a draw for for getting the
members there on time but a lot of the
discussions sometimes resolves around
that in ancillary issues and there I
mean we obviously do have Finance
responsibilities need to communicate
that but the board needs to find ways to
talk to the community and it's in that
room at breakfast it's outside that room
engaging members of the community but
you do have to make a decision so
communicate what you're working on
discuss it thoroughly document the
minutes and make the decision and
obviously then I had the same fee for
many years so it perhaps is not
unreasonable just there may have been a
better way to address raising the fees
thanks Sean Steve yeah I think that
decision could have been communicated
differently and with more advanced
warning and not an over breakfast there
are certainly some things that the
boards they have to do where you just
make the decision and do it like hiring
executive director
perhaps but fee structure it should be
one of those they should have been
advanced discussion so that it didn't
come as a shock to people and it was
what should have been announced more in
advance I think but you're up one time
sorry I started at 2 seconds late Ron I
think that it definitely needed to be
communicated in multiple ways one of
them is a mailing list because you know
that's just a way to get to mass people
but unfortunately not everybody reads
every single email that they get so not
everyone is going to be aware of that so
we need to do that in conjunction with
sending out emailing and
making sure that you're also getting
that communication done at these
breakfasts and and well in advance Eve I
think that there are many companies
right now that are really clamping back
on travel and being very careful how
money is being spent and I think the
reality of that is very serious and I
think it may or may not affect the
attendance going forward and so I think
we have to be very cognizant of that
that a lot of us in senior positions are
can easily travel and don't have to get
the okays which is partly why I think a
sponsorship program that not only pays
for travel by the tendance it would be
good Susan you know obviously the the
fees you know the P issue has had that
ship has sailed but to prevent stuff
like that from happening in the future
probably a really good idea would be
just to distribute the things that we're
going to be discussed at these meetings
so that everyone would know and they
could you know give everybody a chance
to approach their board members or email
the email the board and let them know
what their opinion was and then perhaps
we could avoid situations like this in
the future and then really finally Paul
yeah I think that having the most
abounded as possible yeah like everyone
said yeah how the agenda and having a
chance to know about it yeah not at
breakfast but way beforehand is item EU
is the only way you know only way to
operate it with transparency thank you
and then final question my name is Rudy
Daniel I'm from the Caribbean
I'm a first-time attendee so thank you
for the opportunities to attend then on
the internet being a multi-stakeholder
bottom-up governance process how would
you what specific policies would you
promote to ensure that we move on in the
development of that bottom-up governance
process instead of
returning to the hierarchical vertical
process that we all are very accustomed
to we will start with when I spoke I
think there's things that our community
can do with you know with respect to
informing government policymakers but
you know the reality of it is that we're
dealing a world where we have both a
Content side of the business and the
eyeball side of the business and as I
expected I see that all the time I think
that you know from the standpoint of
different regulations within you know
certain regions decreases the
availability of the Internet to some
populations and I think that there's
things that we can do as an organization
on our reach basis to to help those
communities and by the way you have 45
seconds to answer this Steve so with the
caveat that we're not an Internet
Governance organization there's
obviously there are things that we can
do to help we can co-op encourage
cooperation and communication between
the various stakeholders on a technical
basis and as we saw with some of the FCC
stuff that can actually help inform
policy by the people who actually do
make it made things more open and better
for everyone
Ron I'm gonna just completely agree with
what Steve said Susan yeah I think that
I think we're all in the same page here
and it's you know in order to make this
work we just have to continue to be the
organization that you know is
representative of the the Internet
profession so that we can you know
approach people and have an influence
and have an impact even I completely
agree I don't really don't have them
where to add than that it's
so I think growing are the knowledge of
our members and making that available to
policy makers we had at lunch with the
FCC three senior technical members of
the FCC working on policy office of the
CTO and they came in talked to our
members told our members how to engage
not only the FCC but other parts of the
US government and out of that we talked
with the FCC and they said hey we
mentioned in on the road and that we
done one in North Virginia and they said
why don't you bring one in Washington DC
for the federal government so that's
something that the program committee has
been talking about with Betty for 2018
and lastly I mean we give space to
community I X's through our IRS like
Aaron to come speak and bring issues of
Internet governance on the program and I
think we should continue that thanks Ron
Tina um I believe that would we have
situations like this with the FCC and
all that you can invite that community
into this community to learn more and
build bridges as well we've done a lot
of that in the Aaron community with law
enforcement we've had a lot of problems
that have been brought forth and a lot
of engagement with law enforcement has
hopefully kept us out of the government
interfering with the internet more than
they already do and so anything we can
do to help with that is obviously good I
got everyone right okay so with that
that's our last question I want to thank
all of our candidates for coming up here
and sharing all of their opinions on
things hopefully it's informed you for
who you choose to vote for I'm assuming
they'll be around over the next couple
days I'm like anyone's planning on
leaving but you should find them the
halls if you want to find out more I
apologize again for any of the questions
I cut them off for they might be able to
expand on that but yeah with that thank
you
after this I can step away if you're
like after this for those of you who are
in the appearing community there's the
peering coordination forum Sean I
believe that's it right that's the only
content left tonight before the social
and then the social starts at 7:00 is
that correct
7:37 awesome thank you but where's the
parent so there's the peering you I was
gonna give a reminder you put him out
over here so Regency Ballroom - does
that sound right yeah that sounds right
I think that's where the lunch was okay
okay so hearing coordination forum
Regency Ballroom - for the next couple
hours after that the social at 7:00 at
San Pedro square market yeah it's it's
walkable less than 10 min walk perfect
couple of the reminders before everyone
runs first of all please fill out the
survey that's how the program committee
figures out what what works what doesn't
and how to make this place better and
obviously it's time to vote if you are
not a member
I'm told that as long as you remember by
9:00 a.m. Wednesday you can vote that's
correct
so please do and that's it thank you
thank you