hi everyone are you ready for this to be
over
or do you just love being here with me
so much thank you thank you well I'll be
quick I have with me Dave Temkin the
2016 no I'm 17 now 2017 board chair and
Patrick Gilmore who is going to be the
next board vice chair excuse me vice
chair of our board so they're gonna join
us and Orion I'm sorry that information
will be shared an email but Ryan
Donnelly wasn't able to join us today
but he is the board chair coming up the
next one so with that Dave and Ryan are
going to answer any questions and talk
about the elections should we go there
but what I thought I would do is my
usual part of the closing is to give you
a sample of some of the early comments
that we're getting in the survey data
look took an otherwise boring but an
important topic and find a way to make
it interesting doesn't that say a lot
about this community and what we talked
about here so I found some of these
comments really enlightening and I hope
that if you haven't completed your
survey you do so that URL is there we
hold the surveys open for a couple more
weeks we'll send you some reminders it's
really important data because it helps
us helps me and the staff do space
planning do we write size space did it
work for you didn't it it's also
important feedback for the program
program committee and there as they're
looking at content does is it relevant
did you like the speakers that they
brought in and does the meeting format
work we talked a little bit earlier this
week about some buffs some changes in
the program and this is the time to tell
us in writing what you think again thank
you to all of our connectivity and host
and premium sponsors they do a lot of
the heavy lifting financially for us
here at nano again we really appreciate
them
it's amazing now it's two slides but
these are the individual sponsors that
have either sponsored it breakfasts
lunch during the breaks baring gear the
list is growing and so I hope that you
all found found value in their purses
participation statistics I always look
at these because it kind of tells us
what we're doing as a community and
where we're going
largest meeting ever 1319 so you again
tapped my prediction my prediction was
twelve forty four maybe so it's amazing
really amazing and we all fit the member
registrations up so a lot of our members
joined us here at the nanog meeting and
student registration that number is
growing a little not as much as I would
like to see but the unique data point
about student registration is we did
have one individual for my high school
we actually had a high school student
here so I thought it's pretty cool we
had 22 speakers we had college version
students here and I thought that's
fantastic that they all participated as
well
female attendance is up a little bit but
of course the meeting is bigger count
her country's in attendance right around
33 to 39 so we're right where we have
been I thought the interesting point was
that Juniper Networks topped the list
with attendance and this is always a
little busy but I think I put in bold so
I could read it hopefully you can as
well when we when I talk I should say we
but when I talk I don't want to be for
you about Nia nog and the type of folks
you are that come here it's interesting
the top two and you you kind of self
define this for me but it is an Internet
service provider base either through
equipment or the traditional I'm
building a pipe providing connectivity
and so and and routing out with a
network operator so that is who we've
been it's who we are you just change a
little bit in terms of attendance
special thanks to all of you
Nanog happens because you come to these
meetings and I really appreciate we all
do that you find a value and where we
plan them and you come three times a
year I value the membership we just had
elections and many of you took the
process serious and I hope that you find
value to the board of directors and the
communities that we have we couldn't we
couldn't do this without community
engagement the sponsors staff and
Valerie at the back table could everyone
give them a hand
they have been working really hard this
summer trying to find new venues we're
doing site selection for the next two
years so they've been really busy with
that and producing this meeting
supporting everyone so thank you Lisa
Volpe she helped put on that fantastic
social everyone go last night did a
great job really appreciate our work it
makes it possible for us to bring
something like that social event to all
of you our contractors Alisa the guys
from line speed Cascadian they do the
net cast serious and our network team a
lot of these folks do repetitive work
but it's important work because it's not
in the way of what you need to do is
just there so I appreciate it and the
Hamilton group they're the ladies out
front make sure that you have badges who
get checked in you have coffee and
they're all listed there and in case you
don't know them by name Kristin Perry
Sabrina and Tessa they're just amazing
to work with save-the-dates
I want you all to mark them on your
calendars here we come Atlanta in
February
next June is Denver and guess what next
June is anyone guess we'll be
twenty-five years old you're right
Patrick
and then we go to Vancouver our trip
back to Canada anyone who's interested
also an important item there and when we
go to Vancouver we do not have a host
yet so if you're interested in that
meeting touch me I'll tell you what the
benefits are
I'm the road meeting we have wonderful
round out this year we're going to Fort
Lauderdale it'll be warm I hope I was
freezing all week long timeline for the
committee nominations as we round out
our election process so we have the
board in October and we do the program
committee at our February meeting the
pages outline of the dates are there and
the web pages in the timeline but the
coffin nominations and how many
positions and all of that will be about
January 3rd or excuse me that the
information will be out to you before
but we actually start on January 3rd and
we try to appoint the new committee by
February so the new program committee
will be producing your June meeting
conference timeline it's really
important to start thinking about
presenting in Atlanta now the staff are
busy updating the call presentation the
registration information so the sooner
we get some good material in the sooner
it'll be that we can produce an agenda
so Shawn wants me to remind everyone
think about the content that you didn't
see here that you would like to see or
if you've got something new and great to
present it'll be the tool be open and
they'll be ready to accept probably
tomorrow I'm not expecting the same
crunch on the hotel room block but I'm
watching it closely so I would suggest
if you're planning and going to Atlanta
as is always the case
register your room with that set I can't
wait for Atlanta to see all of you again
if you can make it to Nia on the road in
Fort Lauderdale that would be great
otherwise welcome to Nanak 72 and I can
consider this meeting closed nothing any
questions
Oh somebody folks thanks for everybody
for attending the few you stuck around I
just want to thank Sean Kennedy first of
all congratulate him on his new
servitude to the board
but yeah but more so I want to thank him
for his tireless tireless service as the
PC chair and previously as a PC member I
mean he's really shown a tremendous
amount of heart and commitment to the
organization he works you guys have no
idea how many hours he works not just
putting the PC meetings together but the
amount of time he's also spent doing
nanog on the road for many many years it
was really an honor to work on him as
vice-chair so Shawn congratulations and
thank you very much I'm told that there
is a pizza party somewhere here a little
social event that Aaron is hosting
you're all welcome to join it's going on
tonight if you're staying over for the
Aaron meeting I'll see you tomorrow
otherwise Atlanta here we come
[Applause]