so hi I'm CK I work for carmine last
year talked about in the lightening
torque how someone took over my Facebook
account and posted cat pictures we're
not doing that today today we talk about
the worst kept secret for the last year
also known as ICN or as other people
said what is Jared doing the whole day
let's see if we find out a short recap
as you might know or not
well Akamai is a highly distributed
platform right near CDN 130 countries
all of that kind of stuff and what we
told you guys for all these years is
that we act on Islands so all the
clusters we build our Islands they are
not they don't have a backbone we put a
certain amount of servers either on it
or at ni X depending on how many we need
for that particular region to serve the
eyeballs and then this is a standalone
cluster sometimes we had situations
where clusters for various purposes were
actually in the same data center so you
had a row with 10 racks of servers and
there might have been two or three
different clusters for different
purposes but they never talk to each
other whenever the clusters actually
either would have to talk back to the
mothership for monitoring or billing
purposes or to fill the cache with the
content in the first place
then they used the internet so we gave
them transit and this is how they talk
to each other over the time depending on
the products we had we had actually more
and more clusters talking to each other
we call that mattress traffic and that
traffic was growing as you all know when
you use transit extensively then you
might run into things where your ISP has
come boning issues he filters or to
provide a steep here each other so the
mid crest traffic we had when they had a
talk to each other or for the Cashville
was actually often or once in a while
impacted by these problems as we all
know them also an interesting point is
if you actually have clusters which want
to now talk to each other
then you when you use the internet then
you have exactly the features that like
everyone else
so latency MTU or you know if you
provide the highest ipv6 or not the one
you're using all that actually tells you
how many features you have and what you
can do with the clusters because you're
not in control over it so what did we do
well label the backbone so the IC n
stands for intercity network and it
connects Akamai deployments together so
this is for the Midwest traffic I talked
about when they have to talk to each
other usually these are clusters which I
had I access or you know in carry
neutral data center this is not the ones
you have in your network so we didn't go
to your data center and connect them
secretly then we started to connect them
together with the ICN this is not very
different than you know what a Facebook
Microsoft Google did with their own
backbone for their own purpose to
transport own traffic between your own
equipment so as we have more and more
services and where it makes sense
this ICN will then also transport
various other kind of traffic's between
our own infrastructure
what will it not do well we are not
building a isp transit network so the
idea is not to sell transit any kind of
layer 3 layer 2 VPNs or you know what
our classical telco and isp product so
this is not the point the idea is also
not to compete with the partners in the
PS we have so we are a CDN that part
hasn't changed we also have no ambitions
to become a Tier one and who ever
thought about that they can sell by
voice minutes from us next month it's
also not happening so why did we build
it actually it was the other way around
I like in the last 5 or 10 years the
question was usually why do you not have
one and one of the main reasons was that
the platform was really very distributed
and we didn't had a computer platform
per se like one of the others I
mentioned before so the traffic came
usually from the
server to one of the clusters and then
was sent out to the iPods so it Nate
never really sends from a financial or
technical perspective to actually build
one with the increased madras traffic
this has changed so one of the biggest
reasons was financial reasons we had
actually cases where we delivered a bit
and before it was going over boundaries
of transit where we paid for five or six
times bounced between different clusters
before it was sent out at the end so now
when you can deliberate yourself you can
see how you not just have an impact on
the performance but certainly also on
the cost it turns out when you're
actually having a backbone and you start
talking about it internally in the
company then everyone figures out that
they have used for it so more and more
departments actually figure out that
this is a great idea and to what they
want to do with it so you get actually
more and more traffic on that it also
helps with traffic you localization for
end-users and now as we can have an
impact on the cash fill we can actually
optimize it because now we can pick up
the traffic ourselves and transport it
for the clusters which are connected to
the caches there are a couple of
benefits for you for the ones which have
a cluster an A&P and unlit cluster in
their network then now some of the cash
flow could instead of by a transit if
you pee with us come from the ICN
network and the other big part is for
the people who peered with us and this
is probably the biggest difference
usually you transported it to the
cluster where we then have sent out the
traffic right so the transport was on
your backbone now as we can peer in
various cities in various locations we
can actually pick it up where you source
it where your data center is where the
origin is and then transport it for the
ones which are connected to the backbone
ourselves to that so you get rid of the
traffic much earlier
that's how it looks like so technically
speaking they're actually three
backbones on the left side the us the
nine metro areas which you might know in
Europe it's currently four cities and in
Asia if you actually want to call it a
backbone it's a City link between Tokyo
and Osaka this part is already online
so it actually transports traffic since
two months and as time goes we will add
more and more cities and upgrade these
locations before the first question
comes what is the speed and what is the
bandwidth so we decided to actually not
even bother with ten gigs and started to
with hundred gigs straightaway so all of
these links are hundred gigs want
multiple in the future we have multiple
faces two of them are interesting to
point out here so face number one was
the mid crest traffic I talked about the
clusters which talk to each other and
then you get the cost in the performance
parts so that part is complete what we
are now doing is we actually will add
two pea rings to it and help that we get
the origin fetches instead of Maya
transit or why are their various peering
nodes which we had in the past but where
they were not connected on the ICN and
then transported we will hope in 2018
depending on what the traffic levels are
starting to connect the three continents
most likely Europe and the u.s. first
because that's where the bigger traffic
levels are and then as traffic grows do
the usual stuff and with updates between
the existing cities and the cities you
have seen we're just the start so we
will add as soon as it makes sense more
and more cities especially Europe you
can imagine that we will not just be
limited to the four have shown so and
with that you might have a rough idea
what Jared was doing in the last couple
of months or the rest of the team for
that sake here we go
hello hi how are you I just shared our
map with you because we got one tier you
forgot us but Dave Temkin Netflix it's
interesting I sent this to my boss who
involved in a fight when we first
started building our backbone around
basically we were told from way up high
actually there was a specific quote when
I came back to Netflix which was Temkin
doesn't think he's building a network
does he and of course now we do have a
global backbone my boss said it best
though and it's earlier today the reason
why we have to do this really is because
the Internet is a concept not a thing
and that at the end of the day if you
need to operate a global network like
Akamai does like Netflix does you can't
have all of those features and reliably
know that they will exist across the
entirety of the internet and so to your
point I think that's you know I think
what you're doing is absolutely the
right answer but you if you're operating
content delivery network and you need
those kinds of localization features I
don't want to worry about moving traffic
say from the u.s. to Tokyo yeah building
a network is absolutely the right way to
go Thanks
good thanks a lot
[Applause]