all right so this weekend we held our
third hackathon
we continued a tradition of having a
tutorial first and then a hackathon to
allow more time for hacking we held the
tutorial on Saturday night it was a
tutorial called let's build a BGP
traffic controller and go by Brandon
Bennett and a special thanks for him for
coming in on a Saturday night he flew in
just to give that presentation I think
we had as much as 40 people in the room
here on Saturday and it was a really
good presentation for the hackathon we
had 80 individuals registered we had
some folks on the waiting list and we
accepted all the waiting list attendees
that showed up but we may have to think
about a better way to handle the
registration numbers but initially the
room was thought to hold 75 we were able
to accommodate 80 and we'd like to
continue doing this make sure we have
enough space so now every time that
staff comes to new a hotel or other
venue they scope out whether there's
space available on the weekend to have a
hackathon this weekend we also had DNS o
Ark and we're competing with five
weddings in this hotel so it was a very
difficult job for the staff to get that
room but they got a room that held 80
individuals that resulted in roughly
twelve groups of which 10 got far enough
that they presented a prototype in our
forum and then today as soon as TJ and I
wrap up we're gonna have the winner
presentation and at 3:30 this afternoon
we have two more presentations for the
first two runners-up I just wanted to
say now is the time for you to hack your
network in this conference played a
valuable role in making sure that we had
access to the routers to the command
line and that we weren't forced to go
through gooeys OSS systems and so on but
we're now past that you can program your
network you can hack your network you
can write code that runs on your network
if you like and on top of that there's a
lot of virtualized and lab environments
that even run on your
own laptop that can allow you to do that
development without breaking the network
because as we all know 3 o'clock the
morning you don't have to fix something
so tested in the lab first develop in in
a test environment and then deploy it if
you get a chance later look at the
slides there's a couple of suggestions
here for how you get started and still
even at Nanak 71 even though the
hackathon is over we do have relevant
presentations that are coming up and
there are a number of tutorials that
have been given in the past that you can
access on the website there's also a
Facebook group full of supportive people
if you want to get started in hacking
and so if you're interested find one of
the folks up here one of the runner-up
presenters we did have students old
timers new timers everything in between
hacking at the hackathon so if you want
to get started now is the time all right
thanks Sean so as you mentioned I'm TJ
from Facebook this is the second
hackathon we third actually second in a
row hackathon we sponsored last time we
were focused on peering automation it
seems like the right forum for that this
time we went a little bit different we
wanted to try some sort of you know
egress or dynamic traffic controller so
branded tailored his a tutorial on the
night before focused on some of that we
kind of broke it into three separate
problems you have the problem of
collecting the data from the network or
devices you have the business logic or
decision side of it and then you have
how are you going to influence that
traffic so we kind of presented that
about a week before the hack started we
started up an ideas pad where people
could contribute their ideas throughout
random things when we kicked off the
hackathon people came up and pitched her
ideas and then we ended up creating as
Sean mentioned about ten groups so at
the end of it these are the ten groups
that we had so we had cough FA Kafka
hack Overflow the scope creeps the
injectors streamers go jet yourself the
down timers everyday I'm pullin flow
symmetry and go fail hard
so here we have the winners so beside us
they'll present after the down timers
they came in first
we have Kofi fake Africa his first
runner-up and hack Overflow as second
runner-up you'll see way down at the
bottom go fail hard as last that was my
group it was pretty awesome so I suggest
if you didn't come to the hack you
should come check it out we have people
that are experienced people that have
never done anything before the tutorial
that Brandon walked through kinda took
you from little to no experience on how
to you know get started with the go
programming language but you could use
Perl Python C++ jet it doesn't really
matter come to the tutorial and learn I
will probably do similar formats in the
future and then come to the hackathon
and come hang out it's all about meeting
people and learning a skill so thank you
for everybody that participated and I
hope to see you all there
alright thank you
and now our winners of the hackathon
that down timers hi I'm Colin McIntosh
Erin atach and we worked on maintenance
traffic controller as our project for
the Nanog 71 hackathon so a little bit
of background before we get started we
all get too many maintenance
notifications we have a lot of peers
they do a lot of maintenance it can be
very hard to track all of these
maintenance notifications and when you
have a lot of external connections and
circuits it can be a real pain to manage
the downtime and communication around
these so we set forth with the plan to
improve the communication and the
notifications themselves so a little bit
of what we worked on at the last nanog
hackathon which led into this at the
previous Nanog hackathon we worked on a
project that allowed us to read partner
maintance notification emails it was
very simple we just read emails from an
IMAP folder we tried to identify which
of those emails are maintance
notifications there's an existing
maintenance notification be cop standard
that has some header
in in ICS attachment that we can use to
identify maintenance notifications so we
look for those first if we couldn't find
it we then fell back to some naive reg X
parsing which was just some simple reg X
strings that pull out start time end
time circuit ID and some other small
details about the maintenance event and
then once we have all these events we
bundle them together put them in a
schedule as well as Google Calendar so
then Aaron will talk about what we
worked on during this hackathon so as
the thing as the theme was a traffic
controller this year we implemented
traffic off the network links during
planned maintenance we used identified
circuit IDs to match with the device and
the peering session and then created a
schedule off of the emails of the
peering sessions that are going to be
turned down and when to turn them down
and back up and then created a daemon
that watches the schedule and shifts
traffic before and after the maintenance
so a little bit about how the project
works overall so the first two pieces
that you see there are receiving the
email from partners and parsing them out
like I said that was what we worked on
at the previous hackathon the
continuation of it was focusing on the
schedule of maintance events and then
the Python process that we're calling
maintenance traffic controller the
Python process pulls the events out of
the schedule and combines it with data
in our circuits database for the purpose
of this hackathon we just made a mock
circuits database and then we chose to
use napalm and some Jinja - scripts to
actually kick off the traffic shifting
the benefit and I guess real reason why
we chose to use napalm and Jinja is
everyone has their own flavor of their
network and everyone has their own
preference for how they would shift
traffic off of links so we didn't want
to give a you know one-size-fits-all
solution for shifting traffic so the
Jinja - templates really allow everyone
to implement their own version of
traffic shifting so the controller that
we worked on this time as I mentioned it
matches information from the emails to
circuit IDs in the database once we have
that information we can identify the
device that the circuit is on the
interface it's connected to the peer the
session and any other information that
we need to actually
traffic the controller will then watch
the schedule it will look for events
that are about to go into their
maintenance period for our purposes we
set it to about five minutes before the
maintenance start time so about five
minutes before the maintenance starts it
will go and kick off the script that
will shift traffic off of that link
controller will then sit there it'll
keep watching and it will wait until the
event is has reached its end time once
it reaches the end time it will
disengage maitenance mode which is our
way of saying it'll just run the script
of that shifts traffic back on a blank
so a little bit about traffic shifting
so currently as we know network
operators are going to shift traffic and
all the different ways that they
specifically want to for the purpose of
the hackathon we implemented two ways
into the Jinja two templates that we
created we created for three different
vendors Juno's Cisco IOS and Cisco IOS
XR specifically we implemented two
different types of traffic engineering
denial or ASP pending so if a B G B P R
is going to have a maintenance window we
imported a specific deny all on in and
out so you can keep the pairing session
active but no traffic is leaving or
entering the network and if you do not
necessarily want to completely block off
the Paris traffic and let's say
hypothetically you only have two peers
so you still want to keep even though
that peer is going to be going into
maintenance active for traffic you can
just do some traffic engineering to
essentially set it at a lower
bgp preference or path selection so
specifically we implemented a s path
depending on the outbound policy and
inbound we set the local preferir a
little so there for BGP path selection
will prefer other routes but if need be
the peer that is in maintenance will
still be accessible for traffic so like
we said these were just some examples
that we put together there are many many
options and it's very easy to write your
own templates for this so we're not
going to do a live demo because it's not
actually very interesting to watch so I
included some output from our logs from
the controller as it's running so in
this log you can see the the controller
starts a scheduler that goes and watches
the actual
of events it'll start ticking through
it'll once it sees an event that starts
soon in this example we actually load it
in a mock event that was starting soon
it will go and do its work to engage
maintenance mode so in this case it went
and engaged maintenance mode on a lab
switch it'll then check for events that
have recently ended and pulled and
pulled them out of maintenance mode in
this case had we didn't wait around for
the maintenance of fake me and Stan but
had we done that you you would have seen
it disengagement and smote on that
switch so yep so possible future work
for the project checking the link for
BGP status before we actually turn the
link back up if need be support more
writing protocols than BGP such as OSPF
and eius eius and any other specific
routing protocols the network operators
desire enabling maintenance mode and
alerting system like Nagios which
several people use to suppress alerts
yes so the other things that are really
important to this that we actually still
need to focus on a lot because this is
an ongoing project that we've been
working on over multiple nanog is we
need to actually get people vendors
partners peers to support the xm8 note
headers in the ICS attachments this
makes it much easier to actually consume
these maintenance notifications in a
more standardized way so we're not
trying to parse out human readable text
and in addition to that there's still a
lot of work that needs to be done on the
maintenance
in addition to the amazing amount of
work that has already been done so Eric
is going to talk about some of the work
that the maintenance hackathon and some
of the stuff we're gonna do in the
future
also all the code that we did for this
hackathon is already up on github if you
want to check it out you can also send
us an email if you have any questions
Eric thank you Colin so some of the work
that we've been doing lately in support
of all this convoluted to this is really
about trying to establish some standards
to support an omission of medians
notifications we've seen organizations
that have implemented regex parsing to
parse their notifications they often
continue to spend Facebook's a great
example hundreds of hours a month
dealing with situations where those
notifications don't don't parse so
lately I've been working a lot with Todd
Parker at twitch and as well as Ryan
Gunther Todd's been a huge proponent of
all this and a lot of what I'm talking
about today is due to his hard work so
again just to restate our goals we're
trying to establish some conventions for
a format immediate certification is
really in to enable machine personal
content support to win an automation and
the goal is to save time all of our time
is precious and then also reduce the
chance of human error computers can do
things like convert time zones from one
region to another much easier and more
reliably than then people can we want to
preserve human face and content there's
a lot of value in the mainus
notifications we've all developed over
the years so really the standard is
about adding additional content that's
formatted alongside the Edition edition
or alongside the human face and content
that's already present and we want this
to really be general enough for any
service it's not just about network
services although it obviously can be
used for that so we divided the project
into three large phases the first is a
draft of standard that's pretty much
complete second is to develop
implementations and a tour the adopters
in implanting the standard today we have
libraries and Python and go and Jade our
from face book has been a fantastic
supporter of the project and developing
the the go library recently and once we
have enough operational experience from
all this and we feel we have a solid
standard and place them and move on to
publishing that and getting broad
adoption across the industry thanks to
the advocacy efforts that we've been
engaged in we have some great early
adopters so level-3 Thalia and Zao have
committed to implementing these
standards we're helping them through
that process working with them to get
this implemented in a development
capacity so they can do some trial runs
and eventually move on to production I'm
hoping to see more of you participate
here we'd like to get additional names
on these lists and help you move through
the process we're looking for people in
pretty much every area of the industry
carriers ISPs IX operators if you're a
programmer either in one of these
organizations or outside we need your
skills to help contribute to the project
improve our libraries work on additional
tooling that
people are doing around this and get
this adopted if you have any interest in
any of this feel free to reach out to
one of us we're happy to help answer
questions and support you we have a
bunch of information that's available as
well so please let us know if there's
any interest and we're happy to help you
however we can to implement these
standards thank you alright thank you
and congratulations to the three of you
on a great project