alright so next we're going to learn
about bgp innovations for operation
hi everyone I am job Snider's I
volunteer for appearing to be OpenBSD NL
MOC and in my spare time I work for NTT
and today I would like to share with you
an update on what has happened in the
last 12 months in the ITF world for a
number of years there was a somewhat a
bit of stagnation from the operator
perspective there was a bunch of
features that we would like to have but
didn't get for some reason and a lot of
those gaps have been closed in the last
12 months and therefore I would like to
get everybody up to speed on that so we
refer to this as the battle of
operations not all of the RFC's were
created with with the usual friendly
atmosphere that is at the ITF some of
this was done with pitchforks and
flamethrowers but in the end we came out
on top and that's the good news a bit of
background on how bgp developments
actually works
there is IDF many of you have heard of
this the internet Engineering Task Force
and within that standards body there are
many working groups and each working
group is responsible for a problem space
or a protocol specification and in the
case of BGP is actually split up over
two working groups there is IDR which
owns the protocol itself
it stands for inter domain routing and
then there is Gro which are the users of
the protocol and there's an interesting
feedback loop between protocol designers
and users of the protocol and I think
this is a very healthy situation and
other protocols should perhaps copy the
approach because it's always good to
have a sort of advisory board on what
direction the protocol is taking so in
the last 12 months several RFC
have been published and some of them are
still in flight as internet drafts
that's a status before they become
official so to speak and in this
presentation we'll go over five aspects
of that should you be interested in
participating in this type of work I
strongly recommend that the only reason
we got this for is because of operator
involvement hundreds of people showed up
and voice their concerns and or called
their account managers this was a group
effort
and that works if you involve yourself
with the standards body so at a very
minimum I would recommend to join the
grow working group because that's where
we as network operators hang out and get
to chime in on with our opinions so the
agenda for today this this is a bit of a
weird presentation because it's not one
gigantic presentation on a singular
topic it secretly is is five lightning
talks and with some of the topics you've
already hurt me at a previous nano or
perhaps a right meeting other topics may
be new to you so if you doze off don't
doze off for longer than ten minutes
because then I'll be on the next topic
it also means that feel free to
interrupt me at any time if you have a
question don't wait till the ends
because everybody will have forgotten
what we were talking about just come to
the mic and we'll all go through
questions as we cover the topics so the
agenda starts with some security
innovations safety things we did in the
BGP protocol management of your network
coordination between organizations
facilitated by BGP and then final ins
finally some performance improvements
that will reduce packet loss during
certain events in your network
all right the first one the concept of
black holing may be familiar to many of
you and it remains to be a crucial tool
in today's operations all too often the
economics don't work out to keep a
victim of a DDoS attack online at all
cost and you have to sometimes make the
heart and difficult choice of
sacrificing one IP addresses reach
ability in favor of the rest of your
customers and the way a DDoS attack
works is that you are overwhelmed you're
flooded with traffic that you did not
ask for did not request it comes in to
your edge and the edge congest soar
applications congest so to improve this
the operational handling of this type of
problem
many years ago black holing was
described as a good mechanism where you
can signal to adjacent networks I don't
want to receive traffic for this
destination IP address stop sending me
traffic and by doing that you can
alleviate the pressure on your edge
network but every provider had different
bgp communities to accomplish this and
this means that for every partner that
you're interacting with you have to
coordinate with them
what is the bgp community that is used
to signal this no longer so we now have
an RFC that describes a standardized
black hole community this black hole
community is 6 5 5 3 5 :
6 6 6 this is a community that has been
assigned by iana for the purpose of
signalling to adjacent networks I don't
want to receive traffic for the
destination described in this PHP update
you put that community on the
announcement after you've detected that
an attack is ongoing and when the attack
subsides you you remove the community
and you return to normal operations
another advantage of this welcomed
community when we started this work
there was no outlook on a community
solution for 32-bit ASNs so fairly
two-bit is piece using 32-bit a essence
had trouble assigning communities for
this function and that's why the
well-known 16-bit community is useful
particularly in that context there are
some considerations when it comes to
this community it is up to you to either
honor or ignore the meaning of this
community and usually this is driven by
the commercial relation you have with
the adjacent network for instance if the
adjacent network is a bilateral peering
partner you may not feel inclined to
facilitate the partner with this feature
however if it's a customer than their
relation you may want to consider
offering your customer the black holding
mechanism so nothing in this earth sea
forces you to implement black holing
it's just if you use black holing you
may also use this well-known community
you must agree between the two networks
to use black holing and if you're not
offering black holing you should strip
the community on-site so on sessions
where entity is not offering black
holing we will strip this community to
reduce the impact it may have further
down the line if you do black holing
always add a no expert community it
rarely is helpful if such routes
propagate any further than the direct
adjacent networks and if the adjacent
network also wants to do request black
holing from its
jacent networks they should regenerate
the route and inserted themselves into
the adjacent network so make sure that
you limit the scope of propagation by
using no expert in combination with the
well-known black hole community and
another safety trick so to speak is to
make sure that you only accept this
feature on the most specific routes
generally speaking slash thirty twos or
/ 128 do not propagate very far on the
internet most people have boundary
filters which only allow up to say / 24
so by requesting people to use the most
specific route if they are black holing
we further reduce the chances of it
propagating two places it shouldn't we
have a question Patrick Gilmore markley
group I'm interrupting you as you
requested can I make a suggestion to
additional bullet point on your usage
guidelines you should make sure that the
person advertising the network
advertising the black hole route
actually owns that 30 to 128 so they
don't black hole somebody else that is
an excellent point
after this RFC was published we've seen
various deployments we've seen
deployments which aligns with the text
as specified in RFC where we we
explicitly state make sure the network
is authorized to announce this route to
you but we've seen some deployments
where this advice unfortunately was
ignored Patrick thank you for reminding
of the as of this make sure you base the
filters of IRR or rpki or a combination
or somehow a mechanism where you
explicitly agree with the adjacent
network that they have authorization to
insert black holes it's be a real shame
if you start black holing your
competitors oh actually we had a whole
dedicated slide
I am sorry I cannot see the next slide
so I have to go from memory of another
aspect is the black hole community in
itself it's just a number there is no
BGP implementation out there that
automatically starts black holing if
they see this community you have to
explicitly configure your border routers
to set the next hop to something that
goes down the sink so there is no magic
here it's just a mutually agreed number
that represents a certain feature that
we all understand as black holing all
right that brings us to a slightly
different topic well before I continue
there's another question a job this is a
huge in open networks I was just curious
instead of using this black hole
community there has been another
standard called flow spec where you can
specify various more filtering actions
like limit the traffic rate or sample
and you don't have this validation
problem there because the standard
itself makes sure that the person who is
telling you about rejecting a particular
rejecting traffic for a particular
destination gets validated Oh
we are the unicast routes that have been
that have come in thank you for that
contribution
I feel flowspec and black holing not as
mutual mutually exclusive
there are different products in
different context the validation aspect
with flowspec happens at a different
stage because I still need to filter out
what I want to accept from an adjacent
network or not so I need to build the
authorized whitelist anyway you're right
that there are some additional
mechanisms in place to ensure that it
affects a particular comb through the
network so it may alleviate one type of
problem a little bit but it may
introduce other types of problems as
well because
filtering the actions on flowspec
announcements is not always
straightforward on all implementations
so and another aspect is flowspec this
trick black holing we can implement it
on the oldest of iOS boxes so it's a
really low common denominator it's a
very basic tool it is a crude tool
because we're throwing away all traffic
but it may be better than having no tool
and from that perspective I would like
to popularize the idea that black holing
is a basic feature but if you can do
more or if you can have more involved
participation with your customers and
partners sure flowspec is absolutely on
the table as one of the mechanisms thank
you
next topic
safety RC a 2 1 - this represents a
route leak and we got tired of those
there were a number of implementations
out there that under certain
circumstances would expose default
behavior that was less optimal for say
everyone and we set out to try and
define behavior that is more aligned
with internet operations rather than
throwing a dice and picking that as a
default so what we do in this RFC is we
define that on an e bgp session if no
policy is associated with the particular
session you should not accept routes you
should not announce routes and this
default ensures that if you're halfway
for your configuration or there are
unintended consequences of the way your
configuration management system pushed
something out or there could be all
kinds of reasons why you have no policy
on Annie BGP session while in reality
you need to have some kind of safety
mechanism there this
RFC defines for the first time what the
default behavior should be if there is
no policy associated and this was a very
tricky one because it goes counter to
years of operational experience that we
have in the sense that we are used to
certain behavior maybe not happy with it
and now we have a definition of what the
desired default behavior is but that
road is not trivial because there are a
lot of BGP speakers out there that
adhere to more promiscuous standards so
opponents argue we can never change
defaults fortunately we know this is not
true defaults are changed all the time
it's just a matter of energy and cost
expenditure so some defaults are hard to
chase but we can never not change them
people argue that changing default
behavior may break people's operations
because they are relying on the behavior
that was unspecified but we also see
that the lack of a proper default
behavior which is a safe safety
mechanism where we don't announce or
don't accept routes lack of that
behavior also breaks things so it's a
bit of a balance thing that had to be
figured out what is more important and I
would argue that the default free zone
is something all of us share and
incidents in the default free zone not
only affect your own operations but you
can negatively affect the networks
around you and a shared resource similar
to the environments should take priority
so I'm going to spend some time on being
sure that you memorize this piece
because some opponents argued that
customers do not read release notes and
they do not read the Nanuk mailing list
and they do not attend Nanak's so that
put the onus on us to make sure that you
have this message in mind and that you
are informed of this new aspect of BGP
so let's look at an old situation where
I will not name out a particular vendor
but if you look at this configuration
what will happen this is what is
technically called it will cause a
lateral AAS to a s to a s leak because
the clouds image in the middle that had
those five lines of configuration
because that's the minimum amount of
lines needed to get HP sessions up and
running how it interprets that piece of
configuration is that it will accept
everything from a s 6 4 5 5 5 in the
upper left corner admit that to its
local rip and it will also advertise
everything because it was not configured
to do otherwise and this type of
situation happens all too often
unfortunately and it negatively affects
all three of the a s ends in this image
all three of them will be routing
through links that are too small or
increase the latency this this happens
daily so what are see a 2 1 2 does it
adds airbags to this situation the
specification says if there is no policy
associated with the neighbor do not
announce or accept routes and because
this is this must be built into the
router the parallel with airbags is
appropriate because this is a built-in
safety mechanism to protect you from
harm so po
our C status is that implicitly secretly
under the hood there is a route map
application if nothing else was
specified if you explicitly specify
accept all routes or announce all routes
that's good because you made a conscious
choice I want to announce everything and
you'll make it easy for your colleagues
or contractors because if they read the
running configuration they see oh here
we explicitly intended to announce all
routes unfortunately after publication
of an RFC there is no immediate update
of all software worldwide so there's a
bit of a way to go another advantage of
this specification is that it unifies
the behavior between platforms we've
seen variants where for instance the
platform will not accept routes but will
announce everything we've seen variants
where it will only announce routes that
originate within the AAS but nothing
else or it will announce everything but
not accept everything it's a bit of a
mess so to speak and I think we as
operators will benefit from unify
behavior across multiple vendors and
last but not least as I mentioned before
the default free zone is a shared
resource and this type of approach helps
protect that there's a small list of bgp
implementations that are widely used but
are unfortunately no longer compliant
with the core bgp specification and we
need to do some work we need to ask our
vendors for this specific feature we
need to demand that the default behavior
should be safe behavior rather than
opportunistic behavior we're keeping
track on the get up page of the
developments that we see in this space
this will take a number of years I
imagine but without your help it will be
very hard to get this RFC
as production code yo man P tech Yahoo
quick question you're saying is to
protect the default free zone which I
totally respect is this going to have a
knob that's turn Honorable awful for
labs and other environments that aren't
touching the default free zone or is
this just across the board everywhere
doesn't matter where in the network it
is we have to protect the default free
zone and even if you never touch it hi
Jared Montz from NTT so Matt I've got
I've got it I've got uh 15 years 17
years
hi Jared Moss from Akamai it takes me a
little while to remember this now I can
be sufficiently embarrassed for the rest
of the meeting so yeah so Matt this was
a common refrain that came up you know
in in some of the discussions and for
example in iOS X are you can simply
emulate the iOS classic configuration
mode by configuring something called I
think it was like ebgp unsafe default or
something like that where it explicitly
says hey I'm doing this unsafe thing for
the lab and with pretty much all the
vendors moving to like a ztp type
environment or capabilities it would
totally be easy and feasible for you to
ztp that into your lab environment
because as we all know we automate our
labs and nobody uses VI or notepad.exe
is your Sdn controller so you know as
part of this you know I my
recommendation is that people you know
look at this as something because you
really you know we'd no longer configure
open relays you know and IP directed
broadcast that was used in Smurf attacks
was the default for a very long time and
this type of a change I think is long
overdue to secure the routing ecosystem
to go and say please behave in the safe
way because the lack of an atomic based
configuration model by some of the
vendors goes in referee you know that
they're listed you know really it harms
all of us by having it do this thing
without you intending it to do it and
it's it's very
dangerous and it's something I'm very
concerned about myself personally but
like with directed broadcasts you notice
there was a a explicit config knob
associated with that that could be
flipped so to that point the RFC does
mention so the RC is structured as
following it says you must not accept or
announce prefixes if this is the
situation but vendors may provide a knob
to turn this off so one is a requirement
and the other one is a optional
suggestion to the vendors like well of
course you can provide a single button
to turn this off but at least that
button will be explicitly visible in the
running config and that to me is a big
benefit because if I'm grabbing through
convicts I can see which ones are
operating in secure or insecure mode and
further to that point if if you start
shipping if you're a vendor you start
shipping boxes that have a dip switch on
the front that you know allows you to do
in secure mode great that's compliant
with this RFC if we make it into a DHCP
boot option where it says boots with
insecure default mode that's fine
but the default if I just unpack a box
and put it into the network the default
should be safe so please reach out to
your vendors on this one more questions
Jillian Goodwin Google did you also look
at encouraging vendors to not Auto
accept when a rap falls through
particularly with say change policies
you know style you can end up with an
era where you miss a policy of the end
and suddenly announce half a global
table that's a good question
we briefly thought about it to give
guidance on what's a policy construct
should look like and whether a default
permits or default and I should be done
but as we went along this simple thing
simple in words but not in execution was
already quite complicated and not all
the vendors share the same apps
concepts of policies or chains or a
language construct so it's I mean I
would love to see a few clothes
situation where you don't have a full
fruit that is open and you start
accepting but rather something else but
that that is really hard to standardize
on thank you but to your point I would
recommend that from this day onwards you
assume that the routers behave in a
certain way and that you make sure that
you are never relying on implicit
behavior of the Box in in any context
regardless of this particular RFC but
relying on undocumented or poorly
documented or changeable defaults where
they could change from release to
release may not be the right thing to do
an explicit configuration will
facilitate your operations specifically
in this regard so if you notice that you
have ebgp sessions in your network and
there's no policy associated with them
an example could be where you are
feeding a lookingglass
for instance the route fuse or right
bris you may have taken a shortcut and
just not configured policy and it will
barf out everything at nose look for
those instances in your network and
amend them so that you explicitly tell
it to announce everything to such
looking-glasses check release notes read
them read the documentation because
somewhere in the future your vendor may
start agreeing with the RFC and if
you're not looking out for that
particular topic you and you're not
testing and you're upgrading all your
routers at the same time without Cannery
then you may be in for a unpleasant
surprise but of course many of us at
least check if the software boots so I'm
sure there will be no trouble in that
regard it's it's probably not covered by
the RFC which by the way I supported Don
Smith CenturyLink
do we get some kind of a screen that
says default behavior is now don't
advertise and don't accept
I hate implicit rules you mentioned the
word implicit I hate implicit rules I
want to see it and they can fig
someplace so I want the default to be do
not accept star do not send star I'd
like to see that in the configuration
that's actually for the vendors out
there cisco juniper acceptor yeah if a
vendor is in a position to make implicit
behavior explicitly visible that's great
not all vendors have this so in some of
the bgp implementations run off a text
file with others it's sort of a shell
into a database construct where that may
be easier but talk to your vendors and
if you if you tell them I want this
behavior and I also have some
suggestions on how I want things to look
I think they would appreciate that
management's next topic next lightning
talk and we're perfectly on time so this
is going well many of you have heard
about large communities but since we
have a ton of newcomers to stay no it is
critical to make sure that everybody
receives this information a bit of
backgrounds about ten years ago 32-bit
asns were specified because we knew that
we'd run out of 16-bit asns at some
point and if we look at the current
growth trajectory of the default free
zone
they are currently 55 thousands ish asns
in the default free zone theoretically
you can have around 65 thousands ASNs if
you use 16-bit integers so it is clear
that something is too small somewhere
and this this was identified people
start working on it and now we have
4-byte asn the RER started allocating
networks numbers from this extended
space from the 32-bit space in 2007 and
with most areas there is no
difference between 16-bit and 32-bit
asns however in the 32-bit is an RFC it
was specified Oh folks keep in mind
there will be a problem with bgp
communities and I think people felt
proud that they had explicitly specified
that in RFC S there were still a to-do
item
unfortunately that to-do item was not
successfully followed up on in the
subsequent ten years and this led to a
sort of emergency situation where we saw
32 the pool of 16-bit SNS depleting the
pleading depleting uptake of 32-bit a
SNS and no Universal BGP community
framework to coordinate with in neural
network or between networks so something
larger was needed and the picture on the
screen kind of demonstrates the design
philosophy behind large communities we
really wanted it to look smell taste
feel like 16 the the regular classic
communities but just larger that's it
and all the characteristics that we are
used to and love in normal communities
should be replicated to large
communities and that was resolved by RFC
8:09 - called the BGP large community
attributes this was done in a very high
paced philosophy philosophy the the
first internet draft was published in
September 2016
and in February 2017 it was an official
RFC and that is incredible for ITF work
usually our seas take 2 or 3 years to to
mature and in this instance we did it in
six or seven months and I'm very
grateful for that because there was
urgency we were running out of space in
some areas and it takes year
to deploy technology like this if we
look at entities network it may take up
to 12 months before a given edge router
receives a software refresh and it does
take some of the vendors between 12 and
18 months to develop the software that I
was gonna load in that instance and then
if you tacked that on the two to three
years in ITF you're looking at five year
time spans and that would have run well
into the depletion of 16-bit asns so the
fact that many people recognized this
and stood up and helped progress this
through the standards body is
appreciated and this includes the
participation from the vendors that are
also fast tracking this particular
feature we kind of think that 2018 will
be the year of large communities and the
reason is that then most of the
well-known vendors will have implemented
support and put out public releases of
software that can use large communities
there's a ton of resources available at
large bgp communities net that's where
we track presentations software examples
implementation status anything related
to this feature there is also a
companion document who are fc8
one-nine-five this companion documents
to the official specification provides
you with numerous examples of how you
could use large communities in your
network and you'll find that a lot of
things are much simpler now that we have
more number space compared to what we
have with classic communities this is a
long list iris has been planning this
brocade Ethan is planning to support
this iOS XE is slated for June 2018 XR
is probably coming later this year
Juno's already is shipping software with
large communities
support all of the open-source projects
that talk bgp have been patched by
volunteers to support large communities
so we're looking the the outlook is
extremely positive because with the
thing like communities you want in to
interrupt between networks that's where
we use it is a demarcation point the
ebgp sessions where we signal to other
networks this is what I want I want
different traffic engineering I want
prepending so it is really important
that all vendors support this otherwise
we cannot deliver our products but we're
looking really good on that not only the
BGP implementations themselves needed
patching but there's a whole ecosystem
around BGP that also needed to be
upgraded we took care of this and you
can think of things like TCP dump or tea
shark or PM acct or MRT parts or
Wireshark all these things that we use
to either analyze traffic flowing
through our network or our debug bgp
packets flowing through our networks had
to be patched and that's been done any
questions on large communities
specifically everybody good to go the
next one is the topic of coordination
between administrative entities
otherwise known as I have my network you
have your network and sometimes we need
to coordinate or cooperate on how we run
things communication in this problem
space can be really challenging we all
know the example where somebody emails
to the internet exchange technical
mailing list I will do maintenance and
then two other people reply what's the
circuit ID five mill robots start
opening tickets on everybody's behalf
and it sits and you're like but I don't
even peer with you
this is annoying and it's very hard to
optimize on that because what other
option do you have other than to
broadcast
if you cannot narrow cast we tried
different methods of communication here
I'm using a bunch of / 24 sand flapping
them so that in ripes BGP analyzes to an
image was instantiated but this this
took 5 months to generate and it's not a
viable way to communicate therefore we
now have the BGP administrative shutdown
communication the coordination problem
is that when I tear down a BGP session
you as the person on the other side of
the session may not know why I am
tearing down the session is it because
I'm doing maintenance is it because you
didn't pay the bills is it is there some
other reason is there a network problem
this is hard to figure out from the
syslog message itself so the solution to
this is that you can now embed a small
message in the BGP sees notification BGP
message it's kind of confusing
everything in BGP is called message and
depending on the context it may be the
outer packets or something within it but
the point is when I tear down a session
I can now associate text with the fact
with the event that it was being torn
down and that information is locked in
your syslog messages can be up to 128
bytes utf-8 is supported so you can send
emojis over BGP now
yeah we we did it but you're laughing
the reality of it is that there are more
characters out there than just seven
bits clean ASCII a large portion of this
world does not speak English and they
use different character sets to
communicate with each other so from that
perspective that we want something to
operate on a global skill for everyone
on this planet utf-8 is the only valid
option in a context like this you'll see
this more and more in ITF where if
there's text involved utf-8 is mandatory
usage guidelines you can send a
administrative shutdown or an
administrative reset those are two bgp
events that you're all familiar with and
with these you can for instance include
a reference to a ticket number or a
phone number or an email address or just
a short message I'm going away for 30
minutes see you later on the receiving
site you should try and capture these
syslog messages into your NMS if you
have a place where you a great things
and perhaps you can do lookups for the
ticket IDs and I see all too often that
that entity initiates maintenance we
shut down bgp sessions and our customer
calls us say hey why is the bgp session
that we sent you the notification two or
three weeks ago oh yeah you're right I'm
sorry and if we have the reference
tickets or ticket ID in that syslog
message we can encourage people to
search in their mailbox or other central
tracking system and they'll be like the
system maintenance as announced one or
two weeks ago I'm gonna ignore this for
a while but if it's still down after
five hours or whatever time period then
I'll start calling the NOC and I really
hope that the shut down communication
mechanism will greatly reduce the
chatter that we have between all of our
NOx
so this is an example from open Beach PD
on OpenBSD there's BGP control which is
the binary to instruct the daemon to do
things you type in which PC TL neighbour
IP address down that will so standard
and now as an additional feature we can
add a sentence to that command that says
we're upgrading be right back on the
receiving side in syslog you see that
the session goes down and what the
reason is the session went down and
these are tightly coupled to each other
so that makes it easier for parsing
there are a number of implementations on
their way in the open source world were
slightly ahead of the traditional
vendors but I've heard interest being
extra expressed from from the the big
ones that they would also want to
implement this so I don't have a time
frame but this is one of those RFC's
where you should really ask your account
team I want that feature please
implement it if all of us ask it will be
done in no time if there's only a few of
us asking even if we're big companies it
will not get the priority I would like
it to have quick question maybe haka
whoo so you're sending 8-bit data across
from another network to yours piping
that Indus syslog it's going through
syslog have you don't need
interoperability to make sure that you
can't pass random binary strings into
your syslog daemon this way not really
so we could be opening up an interesting
security hole here is what you're saying
no I don't think so there are many
libraries out there even for crazy
languages like C that will help you
sanitize unquantified data there's for
instance vis which will force a octal
representation of strange things and
that so a lot of these problems have
been tackled in syslog itself and since
we're just passing on a set of bytes
to the syslog existing infrastructure
that problem should be mitigated already
because we have been doing syslog for a
number of years another trick is the the
shutdown communication is not
null-terminated there's an explicit
length field so you as an implementer
you know exactly what you're getting and
if it's garbage you just ignore it and
if all the things line up you you pass
it on to your syslog infrastructure okay
the explicitly it does help thank you
now on a slightly different topic called
performance there's two subtopics one is
graceful shutdown and the other is
called bgp session calling and I now
realize after 12 months of ITF work that
we should not perhaps called everything
shutdown because it's confusing but this
is what we have to work with bgp session
calling is a BCP a best current practice
documents and this means that by
specifying it as a BCP you can include
references in your art piece or in your
appearing agreements where you tell
networks this is a oprah's operational
procedure and i would like you to follow
it or even better you can tell your
customers
I am compliant with this specific
describes operational procedure and
within the BCP documents there are two
types of maintenance there is
maintenance that I as the administrator
of a BGP speaker initiate that's called
voluntary shutdown or there is
maintenance that the internet exchange
points or the layer 2 provider between
me and other people is undertaking
if you do voluntary shutdown there's a
number of things you can do you can
first drain the traffic you can when
you've drained the traffic you can use
the beach be shut down communication to
signal why you are shutting down you can
use graceful HP session shut down to
make the training of the traffic
smoother let's all nice and many of us
are properly shutting down sessions
before yanking cables but a more
challenging one is the one in the case
of an internet exchange there is no
signaling mechanism from a complex
switched layer to fabric to the higher
layer that is the BGP session but as
with engineering we often see a bit of
duct tape is good enough some smart
folks figured out hey why don't we
disrupt the BGP sessions crossing a
particular switched fabric and that will
cause rerouting which is exactly what we
want because we want to drain traffic
and that is called involuntary shutdown
someone else is disrupting your BGP
session to protect you from the negative
effects of the maintenance they are
planning to that point with graceful
shutdown if you shut down a BGP session
you risk a little bit of black holing
and this can happen because BGP routers
tell each other their best path and up
until that point if they send a withdraw
then other BGP speakers may do best path
calculation and then you get back a best
path and that propagates to the edge
router that initially received the
withdraw and in that small time period
there may be no route to the destination
so if we walk through this with the
image on the lower bottom you see a
yellow circle and that represents my
autonomous system number and it's just
one router the upper three blue balls
are
your autonomous system number and in the
middle you have a route reflector IFA
session with both your border routers
and if I want to shut down one of those
two sessions and I type in shut down and
this will cause the border router on
your site to generate a withdrawal
message internally and redistribute that
to the ibgp sessions from that moment on
it no longer has a route for the
prefixes I was announcing over that
session the withdraw reaches the route
reflector the route reflector realizes
it has a alternative path and it sends
back this is the new best path up until
that point there was no route on that
one edge router so it was black holing
traffic so that is not ideal I'm
assuming that if we have bgp sessions
with each other it is because we want to
exchange traffic it's not because we
want to drop traffic and there's
fortunately a cute little trick called
graceful shutdown that can mitigate this
particular failure scenario what happens
with graceful shutdown is that before I
actually terminate the BGP session I
tack all my announcements with a
well-known community called the graceful
shutdown community and this is a
indicator to your border routers that
the path they received will be going
away soon of course routers many of them
have no concept of time but what happens
is when they see that well-known
community they can lower the local
preference and signal to the rest of the
network apparently something is going to
happen to this prefix so I it's
undesirable but even when it's
undesirable and it has local preference
zero attached as attribute it is still
in the fit and you're still forwarding
packets so there is no outage the bgp
update reaches the route reflector
if that well-known community to signal
it's going to shut down and the lower
local preference and the route reflector
does its best path selection and will
signal back a path with the normal local
preference the alternative path the
moment that alternative path is offered
to the edge router where I'm going to
shut down the BGP session you'll you can
hit lessly install that prefix in your
fit you change the pointer out you start
forwarding packets in in that direction
now and there is no outage for anybody
involved then you actually shut down the
BGP session and you do your maintenance
the well-known community is 6 5 5 3 5 :
zero and I would like to recommend
everybody to start looking into this
mechanism to make maintenance a bit more
smooth the guidelines the nice thing
about this approach is that we can
implement it on every platform on the
planet all BGP speakers or at least
everything that was produced in the last
10 years or so support bgp communities
they support matching on a bgp community
and then setting attributes to specific
values so what it boils down to is if
you see a prefix with that well-known
community over an e bgp session lower
the local preference to zero that's it
that way you support receiving graceful
shutdown on the sending side of things
so for the person that is initiating the
maintenance and wants to guide traffic
away what you should do is you should
change your routing policy to add that
well-known community 200 announcements
you tag the announcements you receive
with a low local preference so you start
draining in both directions you wait a
period of time it could be 5 it could be
10 minutes it depends a little bit on
your hardware
and then you shut down the session and
you can normalize the situation there is
no guidance on how long you have to wait
I recommend that you just look at the
traffic and when it reaches a certain
low point then you're like okay I'm
calling it let's do it because an MX ad
will convert slower than say a nice Avex
20/20 and with this mechanism the cool
thing is that it doesn't really matter
how fast they are converging because Oh
BGP speaking elements are allowed a
chance to convert without packet loss
what this looks like in configuration
examples on the upper left side there's
iOS X R there is a policy that you
associate with ebgp sessions and you
would just simply match if this
community is present lower local
preference to zero on the Arista Brocade
iOS quagga FRR site you can use route
maps and in route maps matching on a
community and setting a local preference
is very easy for a Nokia we have an
example as well so you can see we can
implement this on virtually every
platform that we are using to run the
internet today so to summarize if you
see the graceful shutdown signal that
bgp community it is basically a
broadcast of saying this path should be
undesirable it's going away we're gonna
yank the cable so stop using this path
and this will initiate an advanced
sequence of events there's a ton of
science
why this works the way it works but the
end result is that you can seamlessly
switch to an alternative path without
disrupting the traffic between your two
a SMS there's a number of networks that
support this already today
NTT GTT github Norden escola clue MCO
bit and I think this group of networks
that support receiving shut down
communication shut
graceful Shelton community will increase
as we go ask your transit providers ask
your peering partners to implement those
two lines of configuration dumb question
would it be good to put a no export or
no advertise along with that it's not a
dumb question well it's it's a good
question because there is a group
there's a school of thought that no
export is a way of gracefully draining
the traffic but the strange thing that
happens with no expert is that the whiff
drop doesn't happen on the border
between you and me it happens on the
border further away and I've even less
visibility into that so a customer of
NTT may say stop exporting this route
and that generates withdrawals on all
ebgp sessions towards the rest of the
world and those withdrawals are what is
hurting because the withdrawal will need
to propagate up to a speaker that has an
alternative path then the alternative
path has to propagate back to the node
that received the withdraw and in that
time period in traffic so no export is
not beneficial in this context I think
the question was about the security
reporter let's continue networks and to
prevent propagation of the g-shot across
the end is border just saying to your
neighbor and don't propagate this father
but it's kind of done automatically
because local preference zero means that
it's not it's not selected if there is
any better path so it's containment
Walker enemy and to that contribution I
think it is beneficial if the community
propagates across multiple a SMS because
my ASM may not have a better path but my
Pearson
may have a better path and the moment
they realized that the path through
entity is not desirable anymore they may
tell entity a better path and up until
that point we may not have had that
alternative path but because of allowing
this to propagate across multiple agents
we increase the chances of finding an
alternative path from the security
perspective all this is is just a
standard traffic engineering bgp
community that lowers the local
preference almost every transit provider
already offers this today the only
difference is that I also asked peering
partners which you would normally not
grant any traffic engineering features
to allow me to do graceful maintenance
and that goes back to the point where if
we're having an bgp session with each
other i think it's because we want to
forward traffic and not blackhole it so
please allow me to use graceful graceful
shutdown community on your network as
well I take a bite from Cisco so it's
either you probably propagate the
withdraw or you propagate the tisha
t-shirts better to propagate yes
withdrawals mad G shots good withdraw go
after that right anyway where are we now
so the the bgp session calling where we
do involuntary maintenance has a
slightly different mode of operation
it's less graceful but it is what it is
with equipment signaling mechanisms that
we have today but imagine there is a
layer to switch and you and I are both
connected to the layer to switch and the
layer to switch is actually multiple
layer 2 switches connected to each other
forming a switched fabric if the link
goes down on my site because that switch
is being upgraded you will not see a
link down event on your side because
your
into a different switch and that port is
going to remain up we be waiting for a
BGP timeout to happen which can be up to
say 180 seconds and during those 180
seconds your router is sending traffic
across a layer to fabric that is black
holding it one way to mitigate this
would be that everybody reads all the
maintenance announcements from their
internet exchange points and interprets
them correctly but as we've come to
learn this is not realistic
there's too much communication already
it is very hard to communicate to all
affected parties when something is going
to happen and also have them act on that
notification so a layer to fabric
operator can be more proactive in that
regard and a trick that was developed on
loan app and internet exchange in London
is called calling where you insert a
combined layer 2 layer 3 layer 4 ACL in
the switch platform that only effects
bgp traffic that originates from the
peering LAN prefix is on port 179 and is
destined for appearing for IPS within
the peering line prefix if you kill that
traffic after 180 seconds the bgp
sessions all timed out but meanwhile
normal traffic you know our VoIP or
gaming our YouTube the cats that is
still forwarding so from the routers
perspective we see the neighbor
disappearing and timing out but in
reality the data plane is still doing a
useful job for all of us and this is a
really cheap trick to ensure that
maintenance on infinite exchange points
is less disruptive than it needs to be
of course there you there's also other
approaches some internet exchanges have
photonic switches and they before doing
maintenance flip you over to a backup
switch I'm sure that in the world there
are different ways of mitigating this
type of problem
in a general use case where an internet
exchange is across multiple layer 2
switches this is a really good trick to
prevent black holing your internet
exchange participants traffic so will
you go shopping around for internet
exchanges make sure to ask them whether
they support bgp session calling and if
they don't ask them why not be sure as
an internet exchange operator to only
affect traffic from and to the peering
LAN prefix on TCP port 179 any other
traffic is not yours to touch so if you
do a blanket drop of port 1 7 9 you may
also be killing bgp sessions that are
not related to the internet exchange
itself but our for instance spam
blacklist distribution lists or BGP
Looking Glass sessions or what not so
it's really important that you confine
this action to something that is
actually part of your infrastructure
make sure that you apply this for both
v4 and v6 you you can observe after
you've applied the ACL weather traffic
is actually draining if it's not
training double check your config and if
you see a draining wait until you see it
hit a certain low point there is no
predicting how long that takes but in
the case of low net we see between 5 and
10 minutes but it of course depends on
the hardware capabilities of all the
internet exchange participants when
you're done with your maintenance remove
the ACL the sessions come back up and
all packets were saved I have three more
slides but no time so I'm gonna go
quickly through this and hope the PC
doesn't drag me off the stage shipping
now graceful shutdown you can implement
this on your network today you don't
need to wait for your vendor just change
your route
policies allow o eb TP peers to signal
you that they are going to shut down
that one is easy session calling because
we're recycling existing tools on modern
devices you can implement that procedure
easily if you're running modern
equipment the black hole community is
also shipping today because it's just a
well-known community
what's partially available is large PHP
communities there we still need to keep
encouraging bgp vendors to implement
this the shut down communication should
also be on your list of things to ask
from your vendors and the ebgp secure
defaults are CA two one two is also only
partially available today so the call to
action is ask your vendors for these
free RFC's folk with your wallets but
the more people ask the easier this
becomes and then there's listen to
either rich customers or a lot of tiny
ones and we all of us together can be
that second group to make sure that we
have good BGP operational tools that's
it for today
[Applause]
if you have questions I'm here to a
first day see you later