my name is bart stump we talk about uh
talk is just scraping by privacy
implications of mining the internet and
kind of digging through and seeing what
we all leave out there so
we'll start who am i um
a lot of you may know me a lot of you
may not uh i am a father twin boys 13
year old boys weed outside a lot
i have a new puppy through the pandemic
who didn't get one
i'm also one of two black hat knock
leads with grifter you guys may know
that guy
defcon goon
involved with dc 801.81 labs i've been
m.i.a a little bit the last year or two
but that'll get back into it and then
a senior security consultant for optiv
by day
so again the internet and privacy on
what we're going to talk about what that
looks like
how often do we think that we have any
semblance of privacy on the internet
oftentimes a lot of people think that
they do and just the people that i've
talked to
but i think in in most cases
the the assumption should be that there
there is no such thing as privacy on the
internet um
that data's out there again having 13
year old twin boys it's very apt for me
at the moment
i'm trying to to make sure that they're
aware of
the implications of what they may say as
a teenager on social media and the
internet
as has become adults and we'll talk
about that a little bit
again in some cases i believe some
people have a false sense of security or
privacy excuse me based on
certain sites that they're at they
didn't do anything wrong
you've heard those terms all before
uh again we need to assume that that
data also exists forever so
again if you put it on the internet you
say something that you didn't
necessarily
mean or was in the heat of the moment
can certainly come back to bite you
and we've we've got some apt examples
that i want to talk about a little bit
before we kind of get into what the
project is that i'm looking at
a few of you may have heard in the news
recently don't know if you're
sports people
but john gruden
is the
head coach of the oakland raiders
well i guess it's las vegas raiders now
they've been
what that reset they have been
doing some some investigations on
another nfl team
based on some some issues that were
there and they were digging through
emails to find implications of
workplace let's get this started back up
now that reset
there we go so workplace misconduct with
uh was the washington redskins
washington football team
digging through those emails
they found emails from the
owner which is not the owner excuse me
was the president of the washington
football team was a good friend of john
gruden that had been sending emails back
and forth
for about 11 years now um they went up
until about three years ago when uh
bruce allen was fired
but it's one of those things the
interesting uh
it was done and gone 11 years ago
another thing that i'd say about this is
a i don't i don't condone any of this
it's certainly examples of where things
come back to bite you i'm not saying
what he didn't or what he did was was
right by any means
but but the fact that something from 11
years ago in an investigation that had
nothing to do with him comes up is just
kind of again an example of what we're
trying to talk about as far as privacy
and those implications
on the internet again
certainly would not condone what he was
saying or did
some interesting thoughts about it is
that at the time when when most of this
happened he was not employed by the nfl
um
and then another
kind of dumb idea i guess a thought that
he he did he used his personal email but
he was sending it to um an nfl email
address so obviously they can go back
look at all of that and go through it
the interesting piece to this um
is that there are some people that may
have
an invested uh reason to to kind of
flame another coach in that sense so the
owner of the
washington football team is under fire
for a lot of other things
and there's there's some some finger
pointing going on right now as to how
the the leak even happened of those
emails
again the idea that something like this
would happen in a private
these air quotes private conversation is
kind of
another quick example here um laramie
tunsil another nfl example um
in 2016 he was projected to be the
number one overall draft pick in the nfl
so at this time still you know young 20s
or a teenager um
literally
the night before the uh draft
um
there was a video that was released on
his twitter page of him
smoking a bong uh on a gas mask so
uh he went from the projected number one
overall pick to number 13 which lost him
i mean that doesn't sound awful in the
grand scheme of things he's still
playing he's still making millions of
dollars
but at the time he lost an estimated 10
to 12 million dollars just in that that
pick so again
the interesting thing was in the
conversation
uh was that it was from his twitter
account
there's there's been a few stories about
what happened and how it may have
happened that it was a
business associate or somebody else that
was promised things that once he went to
the nfl he'd hired hired an agent and
that person was not getting
the money that they were promised so i
think it's one of those things that
again even when there's people that you
trust there's things out there that had
access to his twitter and actually
releasing it on his own
social media was obviously a big deal
the interesting piece about this is that
as they talked about a little bit that
he accepted money from his college coach
um
again don't necessarily condone things
but the way that this happened he was he
had never
done media interviews at college
and then basically right after he was
drafted and everything had gone down
for whatever reason they explained a
whole bunch of things basically his
college coach wasn't there his family
wasn't there his agent wasn't there he
was basically the draft alone after all
that came out
and was giving
media interviews basically
never talking to anybody never knowing
how to kind of address that and was
basically spilling the beans to other
things and again all of this
for something that that basically blows
up online
last example here justine sacco this
one's again a little different not
necessarily the time frame that it came
to to pop up later
but this one was again just kind of the
power of the internet i guess you could
say
um so justine sacco was a 30 year old
director of corporate communications iec
which owns a bunch of different brands
she was on a flight from
london to cape town
had 170 twitter followers and decided to
say some stupid stuff
um
during that 11 hour flight uh she
decided that she would
go to sleep and when she landed and
turned on her phone
um it it exploded basically she was the
number one worldwide trend on twitter
there was a
hashtag when does justine land
basically following her to try and flame
her she was fired the next day she still
has a job
has gotten another job i guess they
would say so again it's one of those
things that it's
to a professional athlete a professional
coach somebody that's done that made
millions of dollars john gruden probably
never has a career again he'll write off
into the sunset happily with his
millions and and have not much issue
somebody to this extent though the other
side of that
excuse me
again has a job did just fine and didn't
really help herself uh in any way shape
or form but just talking about again the
power of the internet somebody gets a
hold of that a few retweets it gets to
somebody a little more popular and it's
it's just a wave um there are certainly
some conversations about
how twitter justice uh kind of becomes
a uh
terrible word i guess in this sense some
people have compared it to common day
lynching whatever that is it's an
interesting concept the the psychology
of it i guess
when somebody does something bad and
kind of the piling on and people losing
their jobs and obviously affecting their
lives
so
a little bit of story time
and i like gifts so we'll always have a
good gift um so i want to kind of dig
into a little bit of what the project
idea was some quick examples of just
privacy and what we're looking at i kind
of talked about what we're uh
what we're looking at here
so
the original project idea as as most
terrible ideas that i have
it all started by talking to grifter
we have
we have plenty of conversations uh but
we were actually digging through this
day uh just our random conversation and
and looking through some uh some jail
photos some mug shots of um
a prior
co-worker um
some interesting conversations uh and
and again just as we're doing things we
have we have our conversation and then
adhd brains uh take over um terrible
ideas ensue
and
this all kind of
came together and
as you'll see here shortly a not so
great idea that at least
started this all so uh we as we were
scrolling through we saw some
maybe
attractive people some other not so
attractive people uh and it reminded me
of an old site
um
[Laughter]
hot or not was uh if you don't remember
it was was you just kind of no were they
hot or not really it was it was it was i
don't know the original tinder but you
didn't get to date him afterwards i
guess
um
and again so i had been looking for some
ideas to to do some web scraping kind of
start a project and have something to
play with um
without digging in anything and anybody
can go back and look i'm sure i have i
have had a mug shot on the internet
before it's not very nice when you're
searching for yourself and something
like that comes up the worst part of
your life
when you've done other things right
you've done successful things you're
going to go look for a job and somebody
searches that that's the first thing
that pops up
we had some conversation around that um
this particular individual that we were
looking at uh doesn't have that uh same
it was it was pretty bad i said so uh
we started coming up with names and what
we would call a project to do some web
scraping on jail photos and kind of
point a uh
point of spotlight we'll say on to some
of the issues with mugshots being out
there before someone's convicted
like i said terrible ideas so please
don't judge right um we did come up with
a name it was
it was pretty bad so how to rot we had
we talked about some awful ideas to kind
of scrape pull web pages or pull uh
booking photos
and then take said ad money and possibly
put it on someone's books after that it
was also march there were some brackets
talked about and some some terrible
ideas but basically pointing spotlight
on some of the privacy implications
somebody has a bad day gets arrested or
even
falsely arrested there's been plenty of
that and stuff still lives out there
again forever on the internet
um so again we had talked about this
obviously knew that there would be some
not so happy people will you say uh so
so this wasn't necessarily the idea that
that took hold um
but this is kind of what started it so
so to let you know uh and ps
it's always grifter
um so how did we get to st con so
forwarding a little bit from that
conversation neil and i were talking
again um and and kind of trying to make
sure that i could uh i wanted to get a
project going and for some motivation um
so i called our fearless leader and
honest
because they're pretty awesome um
bugged pope see uh to see if there was
still
a slot to speak this year and
stuck myself in there for
quote unquote motivation
anybody ever given a talk before you've
done a project and committed yourself
and that's how you do it
so then i started to do the research um
so starting this year uh this this
conversation that that grifter and i had
was probably
a year year and a half ago
speaking of pope this was right after
black hat uh give myself a few months to
do that i could at least come up with a
you know proof of concept of what i was
trying to do
as i went through and started digging
through
um some jail photos
there was some issues that i ran into
specifically here in utah
they changed the laws this year so
there's actually some really good stuff
that comes out of this it kind of threw
my project into the
the dirt and hotter raw was probably
like i said a bad idea anyways
but
really quick some of the laws that were
changed and just discussed this really
quick in utah and there's some some
other states that have changed some
things so house bill 228 this year was
passed and it was
it restricted the
distribution of jail photos
so more so than just someone's
past
or or worse moment being out there on
the internet
there was a publish for pay websites uh
business that was kind of
taking off apparently so basically
people
um
sites would would scrape these photos
and then and list them on their own site
and then force people to pay them in
order to remove them from said site or
delete them
that obviously is pretty much just
straight extortion became an issue so
they wanted to change the laws around it
the reason i have the other one listed
isn't necessarily anything to do with
jail photos i was doing a whole bunch of
reading on this and and getting through
the the bill a little bit um
there was concern from media and other
people um
about restricting access to jail photos
so what they did and kind of as a
compromise
and their house bill 249 was passed that
basically allows um
you to search the exchange database is
what it's called not that exchange it's
the letter x
but that is a database that the state of
utah uses
attorneys
anybody in that attorneys lawyers judges
have access to this we have to pay a
monthly fee and it's pretty expensive i
think it's a couple hundred bucks but
basically you can search somebody and
you can find
convictions speeding tickets
bankruptcies divorces you know
everything that we have in the in the
state database on someone
so as kind of a compromise in some ways
to the jail photos
a companies can or excuse me media can
still access those they just have to
request them they're not just posted on
a clear text website by a sheriff
so it's a little at least a little more
clean in that sense but basically they
they made them
sign a form saying that it wouldn't be
published on a
publish for pay site the interesting
thing about this and just a quick side
note again as i was reading through this
a little bit we don't want people to be
extorted the laws were changed for a
reason there's some some interesting
stuff there but there is uh
in reading through the law and what they
did
those sites can still exist
whether or not they charge people is is
where it becomes an issue to remove to
remove mug shots
in the in the bill there's a excerpt
that says
so basically
if if you're not guilty and there's a
mug shot on this site you can request to
remove it they have to do it within
seven days
you can't be charged anything otherwise
they're held accountable and there's
fines and a legal recourse there
however
if you were guilty uh of that
charge on that mug shot when you request
they only have they only have to take 30
days as opposed to seven and they can
still charge you just not a fee in an
amount greater than 50 dollars so
the state made some interesting changes
but they still allowed them to kind of
exist which that's what lobbying exists
for i guess right somebody knew somebody
is what that tells me uh but i think the
the the contrast there of the two bills
allowing access to search exchange which
uh their other point to that was for
um
vetting people on dating apps or other
people you may meet in today's day and
age we've heard plenty of stories
you meet some random person and it
doesn't necessarily
end well
so there are some other states since
2013 apparently that have changed the
laws i read 18 states had changed the
law since 2013 um
however i only found 15. apparently it's
not as trivial as you'd think to search
uh different types of laws that way and
obviously the language in all of them is
different what they may be focusing on
or hidden in another bill so
that's what i found
there's plenty of others that are wide
open you go look at alabama and florida
and it's definitely not pretty um
they're still all there that kind of
stuff is it still exists so again it's
out there um
kind of nice to see some of that changed
uh for a privacy sense all right so we
ran into that speed bump
so we had to get back to more research
and development at this point
um so to touch on the project again a
little bit what i was trying to do
this was again to force myself back into
python a little bit i've learned it i
tell people 10 different times you know
if you use it
don't use it use it don't use it you
kind of learn it go back
i don't use it on a daily basis haven't
needed it that much
in my career
when i've used it i've uh
learned what i needed to and gone from
there so it's something that i've wanted
to kind of get back into and have you
know a
not expertise in but at least a little
more proficiency
after finding the issues with the
the laws and the the mugshots being
changed um development and kind of still
learning python if you will to get into
this uh it got pretty tight so talk to
actually somebody else about possibly
coding some of the project for me
helping out there and kind of doing it
in a modular state
that didn't necessarily work out kept
doing some more research
and found an interesting tool called
octoparse
i'm still going to be building a tool
for this and we'll talk about that again
in a second but i kind of wanted to
touch on octopus a little bit was an
interesting tool
um that i think deserves a little bit of
a shout out so it's basically a web
scraping tool for non-technical people
and businesses so
um
i paid i think 90 a month for the the
basic one you can get it a little
cheaper than that i think for even less
searches or scrapes if you will but
basically the idea and what they did was
they built these templates for web
scraping for let's say online businesses
that are getting reviews or comments and
that type of thing
you can schedule those scrapes to happen
they can run from their cloud machines
they can dump the uh the results into an
excel spreadsheet or a database uh so
you can then obviously manipulate and go
through that data as needed so
certainly an interesting tool uh and
then the other thing that i thought was
interesting that they did have was
some social media scrapes so you could
go back and pull
all the tweets from a certain person so
again
from an employer perspective it's a
pretty cool idea if you're hiring
somebody to be able to go back and look
at exactly what we're talking about
octoparse i think like i said deserves a
little bit of a shout out there i was
playing with that trying to get some
ideas uh with that and
uh maltego basically to dig into
kind of what became the the bigger
project here so
that bigger project uh
we decided it's going to be canceled bot
so the idea here and
terminology or whatever uh
is is interesting that the whole cancel
culture is kind of what i'm talking
about
again not
i don't condone don't don't agree with a
lot of the things that the examples that
i gave and there's plenty of people out
there that deserve to be canceled if you
will
there's a lot of issues though with
other people that again when the twitter
mob the internet mob come up and
somebody's passed
let it be the past i'd say
if i was a teenager and had
the internet and cell phones the way
that people do these days it would it
would probably not be a good thing for
me either we all learn
we learn from our mistakes and hopefully
grow
hopefully grow so the idea here
wouldn't be to build a tool that would
go find those things to then
create the twitter mob or or flame
anybody it would be more of an idea to
see what you have that's out there
publicly that you can go through and dig
into your own public presence there are
some other ideas that again i'll talk
about
in talking to some other people about
this project kind of came up that i
think would be great to kind of to kind
of go with this
but what's the idea and kind of the base
idea of cancelbot so i'd like to be able
to
provide target information
name email phone number any combination
of that
and then
have it pull and provide back public
profiles off of uh common social media
uh
linkedin github even sometimes facebook
twitter
instagram the obvious ones
once we do that we can go through and
find
public posts now in some cases this is
going to be an issue obviously
from a public perspective i'll dig into
it a little bit and see what we can get
if you're logged in have an account
and and dig in a little bit deeper on
anybody but a lot of times if you've if
you've
sanitized your your public presence
that's hopefully not there
just in searches
once we pull those posts we can search
all existing posts for given keywords or
phrases
[Music]
that's not necessarily going to cut it
in a lot of cases uh i've i've thought
about some other ideas whether it's
natural language processing or anything
else again just some ideas to play with
some some projects and and technology
here to get some other things going um
an idea that i had there though is we
could also ask microsoft for their
racist twitter bot that was also uh
already pretty uh
apt in in
talking in a in a racist tone and
understanding what that would look like
that was an interesting concept of what
ai can do and and what the internet can
do to it so again um
an interesting story there but uh if
there was something that could
genuinely uh do some natural language
processing to kind of review those old
posts
again some of the other stuff that i was
doing already was digging into
maltego and some other ocean tools
as far as what those would look like the
the transforms for the
malteco social media stuff for a lot of
times cost prohibitive
and require subscriptions so there was a
little bit of limitation there in
digging into
just social media so digging into other
ocean tools and some other possibilities
there
are certainly some of the ideas here
and then
some of that other work that i was
talking about some ideas that have kind
of come from cancer and talking to other
people and starting to to work on this a
little bit
[Music]
so a few weeks ago i was talking to my
therapist
it's 2021 we should all be doing that
anyways
and she actually had some some
interesting ideas uh
in telling her what i was talking about
she said that she has
clients and such that are
abuse stalking issues anything else like
that that that maybe x's are are pulling
things online or um in a lot of cases
the the things that she described were
likely just
bad password use and and shared
passwords that you used with an x they
knew how to get into accounts and do
other things from there but again some
ideas on how to help protect yourself
for uh quote-unquote muggle
or non-technical person other people
um
an idea from that again i'll touch on a
little bit kids
again having 13 year old boys starting
to talk about social media it's it's
it's certainly a conversation to see
what that looks like
trafficking exploitation keywords so
again searching and helping find anybody
else that's in issues that they use
those tools to find
trafficking victims anyway so
if we could use that and automate
anything to help those people that
search for
exploited people
that'd be awesome as well so there's
there's common places that they search
common keywords uh stuff like that if
you could provide that let it help uh
kind of go through that that would be a
great idea
then again what my therapist talked
about she talked about providing some of
this information so i talked about
maybe doing a video or a blog post to
some of that kind of help provide a
sanitization if you will of your online
presence and helping
other people kind of understand what
that looks like
again if we put this into a
web tool and let them search for their
own presence and see what they find
this could certainly as anything in our
industry used be used in a bad way
if if somebody wanted to
but again to be able to provide that to
people that don't necessarily know how
to do all this or or couldn't easily um
search all the info is is kind of what
we're going for and then lastly uh again
info for parents teenagers anything else
that we can do to help that way again
providing information into what their
public presence looks like seeing if
there's anything
that they're
missing if you will
back to the exploitation trafficking
from a teenage level and what that
becomes
there's some some terrible stories there
that i've i've heard and won't
necessarily dig into but anything that
we can do to help these are some ideas
uh that that i've kind of gotten as i've
been digging through this
don't necessarily have anything
technical thanks to timelines and
we will be digging in and having a lot
more conversation here shortly about
what that will look like but
for now that's that's what i've got and
kind of what i've dug through so any
questions
of course
mm-hmm
so the question is the the pay for
publish for pay sites and and the states
that have outlawed that and if it covers
the other sites the other states so
everything that i've read there's
the laws don't apply in those states so
they're still charging if people want to
remove that so obviously again it's a
full exploitation
like you're just exploiting people at
that point but it's definitely
an issue
elsewhere in the country at this point
so
i wouldn't say that we're always the
first to do good things but but we're
one of the first this time
awesome thanks guys
[Applause]