all right so
paulo kung fu um this is a rinse and
repeat talk i did three years ago about
palo alto we're going to talk a lot
about um how to take and use a dark net
and we'll talk about what that means but
first of all my name is jeremy cox if
you don't know me i'm super tech guy i'm
the director of technology or the cto
for washington county school district
um
supertechguy.com is where you're going
to find this training at the end i have
not posted it there yet it will be there
uh probably tonight
so if you want the slides you'll find
them there at supertechguy.com slash
training
and all of the slides for every
presentation i've done
here at sync con are on there up to
the ones that i couldn't remember um
which are a very very long time ago so
in this presentation we're going to
examine how to leverage a portion of
your address space on your network to
monitor and mitigate attacks
we'll discuss custom logging from the
palo alto firewall
to a linux log server
we will discuss creating custom
dashboards so that you can view these
logs and we'll also discuss how to turn
those logs into a list of ip addresses
and then take
and
import those i p addresses as dynamic
lists into the palo alto
and then using them to block traffic
from those addresses so the idea being
is that we're going to teach you how to
automate blocking on your palo based on
a set of criteria that you make and the
beauty of this is you don't need any of
the custom subscriptions to do this if
you have a palo alto firewall
you can do this
regardless of what subscription you have
um the technologies we're going to use
in this are the palo alto firewall
obviously
syslog ng is the logging choice that i
use it's not the one you have to use
but apache php and basically something
that linux on that side is probably
going to be your best choice
it may work on others but today i'm
going to show you how to do it with
those
and
so the question is what is a dark knit
now that we're not going to confuse this
by the tor network or the dark net
a dark net is basically a section of
address space on your network that has
nothing on it preferably something that
has never had anything on it that won't
ever have anything on it that you have
no dns records that it will ever point
to it or have ever pointed to it and no
servers on it no references in any way
and probably
you
the idea is to have something a space
some address space
that
there's no good reason for anyone ever
being there okay
so
what we're going to do with it is we're
going to catch those automated scans so
somebody comes in and they
end map
and use nmap and then scan your network
there's a couple of different ways that
can happen right you can go forward to
backwards backwards to forwards or
random
randoms kind of hard to catch in any
reasonable amount of time but if they go
forwards or backwards
then the idea is you could catch them
quicker than maybe they get to some of
the the internal stuff that you may not
want them to see okay
so
the way you build a net is first you're
going to determine how large of a dark
net space to build um
depending on how big of a network you're
working with um
you may be able to work with just a
single slash 24
if you're talking about a really large
network you may want to do some more of
that um
though basically it's whatever you have
to spare
and how do you build it out well
the idea is to build it out in such a
way that you're going to see the traffic
coming in but there's another
interesting thing that happens is maybe
you have somebody who's scanning
internally on your network so you may
also want to consider
building it out in private space on your
network
now usually what i when i look at it i
say okay
i'm gonna when i've designed mine i
thought okay well maybe i'll put my a
dark net right in the at the beginning
of my network a dark net at the end of
my network and what the heck let's put
one right in the smack dab middle okay
it's kind of a guessing game there's no
right or wrong way to do it it's just
strategy how do you think you're going
to be able to catch someone scanning
your network
so
there's not really a wrong way to do
this it's just okay if i'm seeing scans
on my network where am i probably going
to see them first
okay
um what if your address space is not
contiguous
a lot of you are going to run into this
problem hey we got a bunch of address
space but it's all over the board
really just design it whatever you think
is the best thing for you
however you think it's going to use it
best but even if you have non-contiguous
public address space you're probably
using contiguous private address space
in your network so utilize that be smart
about how you build those out plan it
wisely
so the very first thing that we're going
to talk about is what to do for part one
you're going to create a dark net zone
in the palo alto now for those of you
who use the pallos you know that
there's lots of zone capabilities within
the palos to define and you can create
rules based on those zones
now in this case we want its own
specified zone we're going to call it
dart net
and then we're going to tie it to a
specific interface
and basically give an address to it and
now you may tie it to multiple
interfaces right and give it multiple
addresses
but ultimately
we're going to tie it to that interface
or we might create multiple interfaces
that are tied to that same zone however
you want to do it there's like i said
there's not a lot of wrong ways to do
this
the idea is the same
then you're going to want to create a
syslog server profile once you've
created that syslog server profile it
allows you to push the data the logs in
a very particular format so we can say
hey i want a custom log format that
looks like
this
so
you can say i've got
a threat and if you're using threat
subscription you could do something like
this and use the threat if not if you
don't have any subscriptions usually
basically you're looking at traffic
right so you're going to say scan from
source to destination
and then we want the protocol the port
and the application if there's an
application detected by the palo
okay now this is really crucial because
building it in a format that both you
can parse
and both looks good on a dashboard can
be very helpful to you as you're looking
at these logs okay
all right and you want to make sure that
it's not just pushing it in its normal
format because
one it might be more difficult to parse
it gives you a lot more information you
probably need
and two it doesn't look pretty on a nice
dashboard unless you reformat do a whole
lot of more work so you could do it that
way but you're going to have to spend a
lot more time on it
so
once again
in real big letters we're in in the
traffic we're going to say scan from
dollar sign src
two dollar sign dst
and then i just put a a bar in there
protocol
destination port and application
now like i said all of these slides are
going to be on my website so you don't
have to take pictures if you don't want
to it'll be easy to find to follow from
that point
so at that point you're going to create
your own custom log forwarding you're
going to create a log forwarding profile
that says hey i i have this log
forwarding profile that we're going to
later attach
that's going to reference
that
the syslog server profile that you
created earlier
okay
once that your is done
very at the very very end you're going
to want to create a policy
that goes in and says at the very end of
your trap at the end of your policies
you're going to say we're going to catch
every all the traffic that hits those
dark nets scanners before it's allowed
so we're going to let everything through
that's already explicitly allowed and
then anything else which there should be
any openings to your dart net
we're going to create a policy we're
going to call it darkness scanners we're
going to say okay if it comes from the
outside or if you're working with a
firewall on the inside you may want to
say you know if it's coming and it's
hitting the 192 or 192
or 10 or any of the private address
space you may change this but right now
we're working with public address space
so we know it's probably going to come
from the outside you could also say
you could say it comes from any zone
that way if it comes from the inside or
the outside it's going to catch this
rule okay in this case i said outside
but it could be any of those zones so
um and then the most important part is
it's going to the zone darknet
so we go to actions we're going to deny
it we automatically are going to deny it
we don't want it to do anything
but then that's where we go in we set
our log forwarding to that dark net
scanner to that log forwarding profile
so now any bit of traffic that comes
into the palo
tries to hit
that network
it's immediately going to say okay
you get pushed over to this log
forwarding profile that gets pushed to
this syslog server that we've built for
this purpose
or even a regular syslog server that you
use by your organization and you've
created a rule that it funnels that log
into a file
so this is what it looks like in syslog
ng
so right now
in syslog ng you should be getting logs
that look something like this
scan from
um
where it's coming from where it's going
what type of traffic is it udp
is it tcp what port
and what application if the pallow
detected it now in most of these cases
the palo is not going to detect the
application because it needs to see the
handshake so you're not going to see
that a lot
because in most cases it has to actually
see the handshake um so we're going to
create a filter
that's going to send all those logs into
one file because otherwise it's going to
say it's stuffed in syslog ng in your
regular log file and mixed with
everything else so we're going to create
a source that's based on udp
and then a destination
which is the file darknet.log
okay
and we're going to grant it owner root
and group wwe data and we'll tell you
i'll show you why it's important that we
actually give it to the web user
later
then we're going to create a filter
basically we're going to say if it comes
from that firewall you can do this now
if it's not the only thing you have
coming from that firewall you may want
to do something more like what you have
at the bottom which basically says if it
comes from this firewall and it says
scan from or message threat from which
is why we created that custom language
in the log forwarding
then we're going to stuff it into that
particular darknet log
okay we tie it all together with a log
declaration which is darknet log um we
do your source the filter and the
destination and in the end you should
have a file show up that looks like that
that says dartnet.log
okay
and then of course you want to set up
log rotate otherwise that log will
become insanely large and fill up your
firewall so when you're done when you're
seeing the log rotates you should see
something like this
and based off of
excuse me
based off this script that we've set
here to do a log rotate i'm showing only
14 days now you could do more than that
if you wanted to the challenge is
depending on how many
how many things you have funneled into
this how many i p addresses are actually
scanning you each day which are probably
if you're like me a whole heck of a lot
then this is going to be a lot of
addresses and your palo is probably not
going to be able to handle 14 days worth
of addresses okay you're probably only
looking at a couple days worth of
addresses and maybe some for historical
purposes
so you'll see 14 days worth of logs
and this is what we would do on the
apache side
and i don't know why that slide is in
there
at all
okay
if you go to um supertechguy.com
training
you'll also find this log
dash.tar.gz file
which contains the code
okay that basically gives you a
dashboard that looks just like that
okay
so that you can put this up on a screen
and show exactly what's happening on
your network in our case we actually
took and we have some other dashboards
that are above this and down below it
just scrolls through and shows us who's
currently attacking us or scanning us
now the cool thing is that you can also
funnel back
from your other file walls as they
detect these attacks
you can funnel back those same exact
um syslog packets back into that same
dark net file and then you'll also see
which ones are actually getting blocked
as they're coming through so you see the
scan come through and then you see it
getting blocked later on
okay so this is the particular file um
that we've got that basically is going
to go through and create a
list that you can then take
off of that dark net log okay i know
this is kind of rough
it's a lot of technical detail
you're going to take that dart net log
and then you're going to push it into a
file a text file then the palo alto can
actually understand because the palo
looks at when you're going to create a
dynamic list
you're going to say okay
a dynamic list is basically a text file
of ip addresses that's all it is
but if you try to feed that dark net log
into it it's not going to have a clue
what to do
you need a list of just the ip addresses
that are in
that log
and then unique ones you don't want it
to repeat
you want the palo to do more work than
it needs to do okay so the idea is
you're gonna say okay on page now the
beauty of this is it allows you to do
multiple days worth of logs so say you
want to take
and
i want to see yesterday's logs and i
want to import those also into the palo
and use it to block tuesday's worth of
logs okay
you can do that
so the idea is you go and you say okay
this is php code that will go in and
basically run the the script pass
through
run the the command pass through which
is going to cat basically whatever it
sees on the command line it's just going
to pass it back to to apache to ph
through php
whatever that output is so in this case
we're going to cat
uh
varlog.net.log and then we're going to
pipe it to a program called awk now awk
will take and filter it in a specific
way and in this particular case awk is
looking at it and saying okay i want to
print field number seven
okay
and i want to print
a slash 32 at the end so basically what
we're doing is we're saying field number
seven happens to be the ip address where
the attack or the scan is coming from
okay and a slash 32 is what paulo is
expecting because it has to see it in a
cider format okay you can't just feed an
ip address there you've got to actually
feed a cider formatted network address
this happens to be a network of one okay
then we're gonna sort it in order
all right so we have all the ip
addresses sorted in order and then we're
going to run unique
which is going to take and limit it down
to just 100 just the unique ip addresses
in that list
does that make sense
so ultimately what you'll get
is something that looks like this
okay
and you'll see just the unique ib
addresses that have actually scanned
your dark net once you have that list
then there's a lot of power that comes
with that now you'll notice that the
other ones if it's page one it says go
to dart net log dot one and if it's
something else
then go to dark night dog dot and then
dollar sign page so whatever that is
whatever page you're asking for dot gz
and you notice
everything past that is going to be gz
and it's going to be gc compressed
okay
so you got to use z cat instead of this
cat
all right so that's why that that script
looks the way it does
you're going to get a list that looks
like this
and then you're going to go back to the
palo
and what you're going to do on the palo
and you can do this on all of the
firewalls in your organization this is
the beauty behind it
is that within
whatever you set as your repeat which in
my case i set it for five minutes
so somebody comes in they scan one of
these dark net addresses
within five minutes that ip address is
blocked on every single firewall in my
organization done
automated complete
okay
all right so we're going to create an ip
list an external dynamic list
and it's an ip list and then we're going
to point it directly the source
directly at that page that we just
created okay
now in this case i'm actually it's a php
script but it shows up as a text file
when it gets pulled and then i want to
pull it every five minutes
okay
and then i'm going to take those
dynamic lists and i'll maybe create
another one so for instance i'm going to
have one that's going to be
current which is what's happening today
one that's going to be what happened
yesterday and one that's going to be
what happened to the day before and you
can do as many as
these as you want to up to the point
that you have to look at
how many external dynamic lists or how
many ip addresses can your palo handle
in external dynamic lists
because there is a limitation
and you can't do 30 days worth you can
probably only get away with a few days
worth okay
and basically that first one we know the
current one
we know we want to pull that up every
five minutes and refresh it the other
ones we know we only need to pull it
once that day because it's not going to
change what happened yesterday
okay but the beauty behind this is now
we know that
we've got three days worth of blocks so
you scan our network okay you're going
to be blocked for at least three days
in this case
you may configure your firewall
differently and maybe do more than three
days or less depending on what your
constraints are
okay now we're going to create that
other syslog profile that i talked about
these are the blocked attacks
all right
so this we're going to go in we're going
to create the exact same thing send it
to the exact same server except this
time
in the traffic log i'm going to say
attack has now been blocked
from source to destination using this
protocol this port
and this application and then i like to
at the end reference where is this block
actually coming from because we have
other ways that we pull blocks from that
are automated
and
dart net's just one of them so in this
case i put drk at the end so i know this
is what why this attack was blocked what
actually blocked it so if i ever need to
go back and say why is some traffic not
working i can look through this log file
and say oh that's why it's not working
okay
and then we're going to create that
custom log forwarding once again
tie it back to that blocked attack
and
set that up
and then we're going to create a block
based on those lists now this would go
at the very very beginning of your
firewall that you're going to say hey i
want to block darkneck scanners if
you're using panorama it makes it really
easy just to push this all out as a the
very very beginning of your lists
on all of your access lists for your
rules you can set up a rule that will
just go out to everything on your
network
okay
and then you're going to reference
anytime it comes from these sources and
it comes from any interface any zone to
any of those source addresses those
external dynamic lists that we just
created
okay
and then we're going to take at the end
we're going to say we're going to deny
it again and we're going to do a log
forwarding to a blocked attack
and that's all it is
so
i covered that in 20 minutes
and maybe i went way too fast but let me
tell you the rundown of this
we've been running this the last time i
did this presentation
three years ago
we had been running it for about a year
we had no issues
we've now been running it for four years
we've still had no issues
none i haven't had
except for
when i've had people get curious
and start to play
on my network i have never seen
legitimate traffic blocked by this
which tells me something
because that was one of the biggest
things that we were concerned about and
it's probably one of the biggest things
in your mind okay so if i set an
automated blocking to a darknet based
off of
traffic that hits the dark net what is
that going to break
this is the thing is
nobody should ever be talking to that
space like i said you want to build this
space in such a way that nothing's ever
been on it nothing's pointed at it
there's no reason for anyone to ever be
there and as long as you can do that and
you have the capability the capability
to do that you should have no issues
with this now
is that a guarantee no nothing's
guaranteed but i can tell you that we've
had great success with it and the beauty
behind it is we look at this traffic
every day
and we go okay there just goes
you see somebody come in and start
scanning the network and then suddenly
it's all blocked and it's blocked for
three days
okay and do we know that it's definitely
blocked attacks
or stops somebody from hacking on a
network i don't know
but it's just one more thing right it's
one more thing
so what questions do you guys have and
then i'll go down and you guys can call
it a day because
you probably want to go get your
families and or if you're coming to
family night or not
yes so if you go to supertechguy.com you
go to training all the slides will be
there i'll get those posted tonight
along with the code so i'll make the
code download downloadable and you can
get that and implement it
and play with it
oh
enough that you it takes a while to
scroll scroll through the page
okay let's just say it's a lot i i
haven't actually
i haven't actually counted them
you know for a very very long time and i
could possibly
get in and count it at this point but
let's just say
it's a crazy amount
there's a hand back here somewhere yeah
so the syslog server profile it's
pointing at a linux box that's running
syslog ng
and so we use i that that's the one i'm
most familiar with um these instructions
should work just fine on for syslog ng
to set it up
you could use other syslog servers and
be just fine that's just the one i like
the most
yeah
um for the dashboard it's just it's just
apache php
that refreshes it's got some it's now
built into it that has some auto refresh
right in right in the code it's not
doing it i think we did
i think it's running ajax now at this
point to be honest with you but yeah
it's just apache php it ends up on a big
tv on the wall
yes
oh absolutely if you if you threw some
some udp traffic at it and did something
like that yeah you might have something
like that happen in fact we talked about
this very thing last time so yes is that
a possibility absolutely
absolutely i mean with any of these
types of things anything automated
you're going to run into those types of
challenges right
especially if somebody figures out where
the crap you put that
right
so it just opens up a can of worms
and if that happens if we're gonna have
to deal with it absolutely
with what
we do
yep we do i'm not saying that you should
use this in in in lieu of anything else
it's just one more thing
one more thing to add to it
yeah
do you tell them where your dark
dark zone is
well actually
trying to remember if we ever set up
some i think we might have set up some
custom
allow rule or something i i think we did
run into that one time but at the
beginning the answer was no we didn't
but i do believe we did run into that
because they did do they started doing
some funky scanning at one point i do
remember that now
like i said it's been three years since
i gave this presentation so
yes
most of that does yes but we have had
some internal scanners that have gotten
hit by the private space
not not very often
it's rare
yeah i mean i've got a i have a massive
network
um
it's it's probably the biggest network
in southern utah but
it's it's rare
okay yeah
yes we do have some exceptions so any we
do have some exceptions that are allowed
through that that automatically do not
get
um whammied
yeah
they could be either way i think the way
we actually that the code that i gave
you is probably an old version of the
code i'm thinking it's in the code if i
remember right
but you could do it either way you could
you could say
yeah
you could make exceptions write in the
rule if you wanted to even so
yeah
usually scans are done continuously
there are
nmap does have some flags that you can
say scan this at random that's really
hard to catch
um in any
reasonable period of time
but usually if somebody if you've just
got a script kitty going through or just
somebody's just lazily scanning your
network is contiguous
so front back
something in the middle
you know something like that
it you just kind of plan accordingly
does that
help okay
how quick does that happen um it doesn't
take very long we just have to go in and
make an exception for it
we can have it done in about
30 seconds or so
and then we usually take that exception
off afterwards or
assuming that it's not going to happen
again if it's something that's
reoccurring we can leave it in
anything else
okay thank you very much
[Applause]