who am i uh my name is neil weiler in
the information security community i'm
better known as grifter um
by day i am the global lead of active
threat assessments for ibm x-force
or i have been for a couple of days
i just started with ibm x force in that
role for the last six years i've been a
principal threat hunter at rsa
by night i run all the technical
operations for the black hat security
briefings i'm one of the main organizers
of defcon i'm on the review boards for
black hat and defcon i've written some
books i speak all over the world yay
mommy's proud um so
uh like i said 90 minutes worth of
content so let's roll
so we're going to talk about hunting
right so let's start out with what
hunting is um and i've got a nice shiny
definition here that just says hunting
is proactively searching through data in
order to detect threats which have
evaded traditional security measures and
that's a great definition if you're
explaining what hunting is to somebody
who
doesn't you know understand what
information security is or um you're
just trying to kind of give them the the
blandest possible way of describing what
you do
some what what hunting really is though
is just doing ir without knowing that
you're owned right we do a lot of the
same things it's investigatory like we
go in and check things out we do a lot
of the same processes it's ir
when you're not sure if an attacker is
there sometimes it leads to finding an
attacker
sometimes it leads to hours of you just
clicking around on stuff
and we'll get into that a little bit
hunting itself is it's important to
point out is human driven this is not a
piece of software this is someone with a
set of skills
that is going in and using those skills
to try to detect an attacker persisting
within the environment
despite
what
you see on expo floors of places like
rsa conference or black hat this is not
something that
you can just fire off a piece of
software or put another box in your
environment and just expect it to do it
for you
hunting requires people
it's proactive not reactive right so
we're deciding i'm gonna go look before
we get some alert or incident that comes
into our queue so we're gonna go look
first and and
find out if somebody is there it's
better not to wait when you're playing
hide and seek go seek
and it's iterative right it's not random
it should be a repeatable process
something that we're able to do over and
over again so if we find something
that's interesting or a certain type of
data that's interesting what we want to
be able to do is find that type of
information again
that allows us to make our hunts
repeatable to document things to hand
those off to maybe junior hunters or
other hunters that you can say like hey
i found interesting stuff it also means
that maybe we create an automation
playbook or another alert or something
like that
you know those are things that we can
gain throughout our hunt
but let's talk about what threat hunting
isn't right it's not hitting ctrl f and
just putting in an ioc right we're not
just going and looking for the next
file hash or
uh you know ip address host name that
kind of thing that's not hunting that's
just um
you know googling or i think we're
supposed to say duck now right right
okay yeah ducking
so
um
it's not automated so again despite what
you see on the banners and the shiny
displays on expo floors that security
conferences everywhere hunting is not
automated
it is someone going through and doing a
process or following a framework or just
following a hunch it's not something
that you just go
do it and it goes off and does that for
you there are aspects of hunting that
can be automated you can create reports
things like that but hunting itself
isn't automated it's also not new
hunting itself or threat hunting as a
term you know is less than 10 years old
it sounds really cool and it's fun to
put on a business card but in reality
we've been doing these things in
incident response forever right if
you've ever taken a bunch of domains and
dumped them into excel or something and
then stack counted them and been like oh
this only shows up a couple of times
across the whole organization i'm going
to take a look at what that is that's
threat hunting so you have been doing
this
it's also not wizardry
right
having somebody who is a generalist who
understands a lot of operating systems a
lot of protocols different things that
they can go and investigate about is
fantastic but even if you have a junior
analyst or somebody who's new
all of us have a specific bias right
there's some part of technology or part
of security that we are better at than
other parts so take your hunt your
junior analyst or your junior hunters
and point them at that thing right if
you have that like sadist within your
organization just loves dns like
point them at dns it's usually dns right
so now it's always dns
why do we want to hunt well
we're hunting because we're looking for
undetected threats we're looking for the
things that the blinky boxes and the
shiny things we buy from vendors aren't
finding we want to find those undetected
threats because it reduces the dwell
time that attackers get to hang out
within our environment and that
is the goal right we don't want to be
that company who's on the news after a
breach and they're like and evidence
shows they were in there for seven years
right you know that's
no thank you
um you're also going to learn your
environment better than you ever have
before and for me i think this is the
biggest hidden return on investment of
hunting is that you'll start to
understand things like why did we create
our golden images this way why
do we use these protocols why do we not
use these protocols why did the network
team configure things like this or
segment this like this
it helps you understand the way that
your organization is structured and when
you have that understanding it gives you
a huge advantage over an attacker and i
can tell you as somebody who lived on
the red team side of the house for for
many years that if an attacker gains
access to your environment the first
thing that they're going to do is learn
everything that they can about your
environment so you should do that first
it's also just going to help you improve
your organizational posture overall
you're
not always going to find exfiltration to
china or some
russian organized crime group right
and that's good
we don't want to find that i'm going to
go do a hunt today
dear god no like you know no you want to
go and do your hunts and do them
repeatedly every day go out and try to
find something interesting you're not
always going to find exfiltration to
china but what you will find are gaps in
the way that your security is set up
misconfigurations
that exist within the environment
and you'll find them before an attacker
does right and what that means is you
can go and fix those things before they
become a problem before they become a
foothold or an enabler of compromise for
your organization so you're reducing
your overall attack surface
and finally
why hunt well just makes your analyst
better it allows you to instead of
sitting there
taking
incident after incident out of a queue
i've been in that role before it is soul
crushing right you're just like oh let
me make sure the mitigation worked it
did and here are my notes and good right
like
it allows you to take the knowledge that
you gain from doing things like this
coming to a conference reading all the
books the training classes that you've
gone to and decide what you're going to
go look for decide what you think is the
thing that is actually going to matter
to the organization and spend your time
there and when you do that you do two
things one you're focused on something
that you care about and two it's just
plain good for morale right so
allow yourself to be the investigator
you were told you were going to be when
you got onto the blue team side of the
house
documentation yay let's talk about
documentation um everybody's favorite
topic
honestly uh you gotta write stuff down
um if you're not writing it down it
might as well not have happened you
wanna do this for two reasons one
it allows you to show management the
value and the time that you're spending
hunting you can say this is the reason
that we spend this time doing this is
because i was able to find these gaps in
our infrastructure i was able to find
these vulnerabilities
and that allows you more time or to
become a full-time hunter or hire a
full-time hunter expand that hunting
program
so what you're going to want to write
down are things like gaps identify so
gaps in logging any vulnerabilities
issues that you came across and how they
were resolved so as you find things and
you escalate them up to different parts
of i.t or the organization
follow up with them make sure that those
gaps were closed otherwise what was the
point
so follow those things to resolution
the hypothesis that you came up with
when you started to hunt so if you said
what am i going to go hunt for today and
you're like well let me put myself in
the attacker mindset if it was me and i
was going to attack our organization
how would i try to exfiltrate data from
our environment
i'm going to go look there right write
down what you were hunting for what gave
you the idea to go look there and what
did you do
right you want to make sure that you are
laying out how you spent that time
and of course any new alerts that you
come up with so if you do find something
find a new indicator of compromise find
something that you can create a rule on
or
an additional analytical path for your
you know automation solution or
something write those things down and
and of course anything you discover find
a compromised host find an attacker
persisting in the environment write it
down again
two reasons for this one get more time
to hunt
hire another full-time employee to hunt
whatever it is
but also because the end of year
performance review is going to show up
and selfishly you'll have a bunch of
really cool stuff that you can put on
there where you're like i found this i
found this i closed these gaps i was
able to detect these compromised hosts
those are really good things for that
end of year review so good for the
organization uh good for you because
you'll get additional help within your
stock and hopefully some more time to
hunt or additional hunters but also good
to get that
that stellar raise every year right
all right so let's talk about the data
um from a data set standpoint we start
out with logs right the gold standard
for decades and the gold standard for
decades to come i'm sure
logs
storage is cheap log everything so i put
on here collect logs from key areas
those key areas are everything
if it creates a log log it write it to
disk i don't necessarily mean put it in
your sim right because that's expensive
depending on which solution you bought
right so
but i do mean keep the logs
even if you don't look at your logs and
please
please look at your logs
but even if you don't look at your logs
if you experience a breach and you're
able to have an ir team come in and you
should have an ir team come in even if
you have your own if this is the whole
like don't do your own defense even if
you're a lawyer type of thing like uh
bring in a second set of eyes so when
another team comes in an ir team comes
in they're able to look at all of that
log data they're going to love you
you're going to be in a much better
situation so if it creates a log
log it
network side of the house
i love the network side of the house i
i would just let p caps wash over me all
day if i could i know that
that makes me super weird but i said
everybody has their thing for you it's
dns for you you just like the you know
minutiae of different operating systems
for me
pcaps
so
on the network side of the house all
your network data understand what your
ingress and egress points are right so
how does data flow into and flow out of
your environment
where is data leaving as important when
you're trying to understand how an
attacker is going to move the crown
jewels out if they
ever do get in
understand your subnet roles how your
network is segmented how do you carve
things up right what can talk to what
those are important things to understand
and a huge one is establishing
directionality
not everybody follows rfc 1918 there's a
bunch of random ip addresses that are
within organizations what's important to
you is is that data flowing in is that
data flowing out or is that lateral
movement right is that just something
that's going on inside the network if i
go out on an engagement
usually the first half of the first day
is spent just understanding that how
does data move around this organization
and then i spend the next several days
just hunting but i need to know how that
date is flowing because some things you
might really care about if they're
coming in
and some things you won't care at all
and you know vice versa so
and for me full packet capture i told
you i love me some keycaps
full packet capture is huge if you don't
have full packet capture within your
organization go get it
full packet capture is the
i don't know if i should be insulted by
that ringtone that sounds like cricket
but i am
no uh so
full packet capture is essentially at
least to me i liken full packet capture
to video surveillance for your network
right and we wouldn't build a building
today and not put
video surveillance on the building right
well logs are great logs are you walking
up and badging in in the morning and you
get a log that says you know grifter
showed up today at 9 00 am
and it's like great there he is and
that's the information you have oh he
badged into this other room he came into
the sock
and that kind of stuff it's very limited
it tells you some things about what i
did but with full packet capture um it's
the same as video surveillance where
it's like is that actually grifter yes
it is oh he was carrying a box that had
these things in it
when he came in he left something from
that box and this pl in this room and
this room then he took things from those
rooms put them back in the box and left
the environment with full packet capture
that means that i understand oh this
person came into my environment with a
box of tools they put those tools here
they deployed that there when they left
they took these files and they put that
in the box and off they went right
what i can do is actually pull the
things out of the box take a look at
them see what they got so when you have
full packet capturing you're seeing
tools being deployed in your
organization or malware being deployed
in your organization and you can pull
that tool or piece of malware out of the
stream and throw it in a sandbox
and see what makes it tick
that's huge right or
if you are
unfortunately breached and somebody is
exfiltrating data from your environment
and you have full packet capture
you can pull the files out that they
took so you can say oh there's this you
know rar file over here full of weird
stuff
well now i'm gonna pull it out throw it
in a sandbox open it up and see what
they actually took and knowing what an
attacker took during a breach is the
difference between having to call a few
people
and
ending up on the news right legally
there are way different things that
happen depending on what somebody takes
from the environment so if you have the
ability to rebuild what was taken from
you in a breach that is invaluable
um
the organizations who don't do this and
then experience a breach understand how
valuable it is after the breach that's
normally when you will get the blank
check right you're trying to get spend
you're trying to get spend you're trying
to get additional head count can't get
it can't get it can't get it breached
let's go look at how many people we're
hiring oh we got this shiny thing i
don't even know what that box does but
it sure is pretty like
hopefully you don't have to get to that
point
get your full packet capture going and
understand what's actually happening on
your network and then of course endpoint
endpoint is where the rubber meets the
road right what did they actually do on
the host and so
make sure you're pulling all your pro
inventorying all your processes
scheduled tasks unexpected services i
know a lot of these things sound
foundational and they are
but the reality is the foundational
stuff is where we find bad
constantly and this is
across every organization we're not
talking about just mom and pop pizza
place over here we're talking fortune 10
the foundational stuff is what finds the
attackers okay
they will not burn a zero day if they
don't have to they will come at you and
find the path of least resistance and if
that makes them successful
then great they stop there they will
escalate to whatever level they need to
get to if you're specifically targeted
but by and large attackers will come at
you with whatever will work and is the
least amount of effort so we find these
things with foundational stuff and it
works
all right so mindset wise
um
threat hunting is really about
situational awareness it's about
understanding what normal is like on
your host or your network it's about
setting a baseline understanding what
the norms are and diffing against it
over and over and over again so you can
say okay this is what this should look
like so when something happens that is
an outlier or some type of anomaly it
will jump out it will stand out like a
sore thumb you'll be like that ain't
right i don't understand why that's
doing that that's a bump in traffic over
here that's a weird behavior that user
never connects to that thing over there
so
understand and set that baseline it's
important to note though that while
outliers are always interesting
they're not always evil
you're not always going to find that
russian organized crime group right but
sometimes you'll spend four to six hours
just digging in on something that you're
like oh what is this what is this what
is this and in the end it's just how a
certain protocol or operating system
works within your environment which is
just the way the communication takes
place between different parts of your
organization but you still learn
something and if you can put yourself in
that mindset that i don't care how this
ends but i'll learn something that you
will always enjoy the hunt
and i genuinely enjoy the hunt
um it's also important
to just leave your preconceived notions
at the door you don't want to start with
an ioc again what you want to start with
is a hypothesis a question how
is somebody going to come at me this is
where if you have
any offensive background red teaming pen
testing whatever it is
putting yourself in that attacker
mindset and saying what would i do to us
is going to be valuable so start out
with a question
you want to know what you
hope to find and then go out and look
for it but don't be discouraged if you
don't find it you want to stay flexible
um if you're in the middle of a hunt you
started with a hypothesis and you're
driving down the path to find out or
prove out that hypothesis and you
what i call see something shiny
and it gets your attention this is where
you want to embrace the adhd that is so
prevalent within our industry
if you see something shiny
full stop
what's that why did that get my
attention why did that stand out to me
these are the things that we want to
look at right
so
if you're in the middle of that path and
you're like i just i can't get derailed
open another tab and then see something
shiny open another tab open another tab
and your hunt's just not done until all
those tabs are closed
that's it
so prepare to pivot there's going to be
a lot of them
and this one for me is huge fine tools
that help you make sense of the data i
don't care whether those are bought from
a vendor i don't care whether those are
open source if you're a university and
you have a bunch of students you can
throw at managing some open source
projects so that your analyst can
actually use it instead of managing it
and using it because who's got the time
um
find the thing that works for you it
doesn't matter if you have the most
expensive shiniest dashboard crazy
whatever look at the pew pew pew
great
if your analysts hate it
if your hunters hate it
who cares how much it cost
what you need to do is consult your team
decide what the tools are that you want
to use what are the things that are
going to make you successful and use
those things
doesn't matter if it's vendor driven
doesn't matter if it's open source use
the thing that your analysts want to use
and size it appropriately if it's slow
ain't nobody hunting in there
and then again document everything and
write it down and please share it um
another thing in our industry that's
pretty prevalent is uh our imposter
syndrome if you need to write a white
paper if you want to give a talk at a
conference if you just want to send out
a tweet that says this thing helped me
share it
if it helps one person
fantastic but put the stuff that you're
learning out there
i talked about a hypothesis a way to
begin a hunt or decide
what that how that hunt should start
and here's a good way
to see that hypothesis right so
what you want to do is take a look at
your business your organization and
understand what it is that you actually
do what do we provide am i an
entertainment am i an energy sector uh
you know is am i financial health care
okay for me what are those applications
and assets that are related to my
industry that are the most risk for me
what are the things that are the
scariest what will put us on the news
all right understand that down to the
application and asset level
and once you've done that determine what
the probable attack vectors are going to
be to come at those
and then for each one of those what are
the potential techniques right what are
the artifacts that are going to be left
behind by those techniques and for those
artifacts what are the tools that apply
and when i say what tools apply again
two things one what are the tools that
create those artifacts what are the
attackers using and two what are the
tools that detect the artifacts that i'm
looking for
and then document it you can see a theme
here right document document write it
down
i know there's a lot of people out there
who think like oh you know like like
tribal knowledge sucks like if you are
in an organization you're like when i
leave everybody's going to be so sad
because there's going to be a vacuum and
i'm amazing whatever you suck as an
employee and your team should hate you
there's no pizza party for you when you
leave
write it down
yeah
okay
no pizza for that guy like the guy who
started clapping first is like yeah go
to hell rob like you know
so
um and then when you've determined what
those things are and what those probable
attacks are red team and blue team them
if you can right and so
what i mean here is emulate the most
likely attackers that target your
business right so if it's apt whatever
that it comes at your energy sector
business if you can't defend against the
most likely groups to target you
good luck
right but if you can you reduce your
risk dramatically
and then just do it over and over again
over and over again again another theme
do it again and again and again a good
place to go look for things like this
that that those ttps the tactics
techniques and procedures threat
intelligence that actually
matters right the way that attackers
conduct business and in some cases it is
literally business
understanding those ttps will help you
defend yourself for much longer than
blocking an ip address a hostname or you
know triggering on a file hash somewhere
so
the mitre attack framework is a great
place to go find that type of
intelligence
literally you can click on things like
i'm an entertainment and it's like these
apt groups hate you
or love you depending on how good your
defenses are
but the mitre attack framework is great
for that if you don't spend time in
mitre attack please spend more time
there
it is fantastic i am super nerdy so
sometimes i'll just go into mitre attack
and go down the wicky rabbit hole and
it's fun
because i'm a giant nerd
another thing
is that using miter attacking build
things like this which is a nice stop
light type matrix where you can say
i have these data sources for these
attack vectors and these techniques this
is the visibility i gain with the data
sources that i have so if we're looking
at web shells logs are okay but full
packet capture and endpoints are are
fantastic and netflow's useless to me
for web shells right and then go through
your organization and decide
where am i covered then you can take
this and deliver it up to management and
say here's where our gaps are
here are the groups that target us are
most likely to target us here's their
normal attack techniques
this is what they use to
you know come at us and we lack
visibility in these areas and so
hopefully that allows you to go back to
management and say give me additional
head count give me additional time to
hunt i need to buy the shiny thing i saw
at black hat
whatever it is we need more training we
need this
it gives you the ammunition to hopefully
get the things or the resources that you
need to be successful as a defender
another thing it does
is
that let's say you are breached
and they're like hey they call in the
cso and it's like it's time and time for
what time to be the chief information
scapegoat officer you're fired right and
you can be like well
that breach happened this way the attack
was done this way they used this
technique and if you remember back in
june i gave you this shiny stop light
type matrix they told you we had gaps in
these areas and all i needed was
additional headcount or maybe this other
product but you didn't give it to me
i'm going to go back to my desk
good luck with that
and then you go back to your desk and
you keep your job so
good to have stuff like this
now i mentioned red teaming and i want
to talk about it just real quick because
there is a difference between offensive
types of uh you know approaches
not everything is just red teaming or
not everything is pen testing right so
what are the differences well a
vulnerability scan is just a scan it's a
piece of software we set it and we let
it run and it pumps out a report you put
a logo on it you charge the company ten
thousand dollars no don't do that please
don't do that but there are plenty of
people out there doing that this is not
red teaming this is hitting go on a
piece of software
pen testing is a skilled individual who
goes in
and says okay i'm going to go try to
find vulnerabilities and when i find
them i'm going to exploit those things
and once i've exploited that i'm going
to try to see how much further i can get
and i'm going to do this over and over
and over again and see how many ways i
can find to get into the organization
how many different things i can exploit
and hopefully when they're done they
give you a report that tells you here's
your gaps close these up and they come
back in three months or six months and
hopefully you fix those things and they
just find new ways to crush your spirit
um
but it's a numbers game right
red teaming is a test of not just your
technology but also of your capability
to do detection with your people right
so red team should come in with a
specific goal they want to get to a
certain thing they're going to come in
still with stealth and look to meet that
goal by whatever means necessary as long
as the scope is correctly done
um and they should be using threat
intelligence to do that they should come
at you and say
here's the most likely way that you'll
be attacked we're going to emulate those
things
we'll see if you can do those and if you
can then we will adjust the next time we
come in and do it and we'll come at you
in a different way
that is how a red team exercise should
go it should be a group of skilled
individuals who are
pulling no punches and coming at you
emulating how you will most likely be
attacked um and and that should gain you
something it shouldn't just be you
getting punched in the face over and
over again
the f i will say here and this is just
uh you know the gospel according to
grifter
findings should be shared from the red
team to the blue team without any kind
of discipline and also without any kind
of the nonsense
frankly ego that seems to come
along with being on the offensive side
of house and again i
have been and am still contracted
sometimes to be that red team person so
um i get it like you know it's like i'm
an elite hacker pew pew pew and you're
like shut up tom like so
um
so you what you need is not it shouldn't
come across as ha ha we got you it
should be we're working together to make
sure that these things are are closed
right
and so
red teaming's a little bit different i
threw bug bounty programs in here and i
did that because i think that they're a
good um
it's a good way of getting some low cost
testing on different things but it can
be noisy right so
you want to be able to know whether or
not not what you're seeing is just a
bounty hunter looking for a bounty or
whether or not you have a legitimate
threat and sometimes
this can muddy the waters but i mean
someone might get a t-shirt so that's
dope
all right
we're going to talk about some some
practical hunting or things to go look
for i will say before i start that hunts
are
you want to start out and build
layers right there should be layers that
make you go oh this is a problem a lot
of the things that i'm about to talk
about are alertable they're things that
you can create alerts on
but um there some of them can be very
very noisy or loud alerts
if we were to um
to just like alert on every time a
process was created like forget it shut
us down like we're done right so um but
what you want to do is pair these things
together so if i'm looking at web
traffic and i see that i'm getting
traffic from a region i don't normally
do business with that it's a short user
agent string and they're posting to the
web server without ever doing a get
request those things are now interesting
because they're layered on top of each
other maybe somebody with a short user
agent string isn't something i care
about but when i have those other
factors i really start to care so um
like i said we'll talk about a few
things and some of you will go we
already do that good
all right
so yeah
check your logs for process creation
check your logs don't alert on process
creation that's insane
but check your logs for process creation
do those processes match the names of
your allowed software right um
are those things being kicked off by
executables that you actually know about
and want to be there
if you have the ability verify the file
hashes to known good executables has
something been changed what am i looking
at
and then for for this
this is true of network as well as on
the endpoint side of the house but
i look at a 24-hour window when i'm
doing a hunt and i do that because
i need something digestible right so
i'll look at the last 24 hours if i see
something interesting something odd
something shiny
i will then drill down my investigation
on that thing and then expand my window
so i'm like oh that was odd well let's
go look at that well let's see how many
times that's happened in the last three
days seven days 14 days or now i'm like
oh that's on this specific host or that
was done by this specific user well
let's go see what that user has done for
three days seven days 14 days a month
however much you know retention you've
got
so
hunt within a 24 hour window look for
something spooky
and then when you find that spooky
expand right it makes it just digestible
but you can look at a 24-hour window and
look at processes that are um
you know executed once or twice across
your entire organization like you're
like what is that why do these specific
endpoints have this thing going on we've
all done this in some way when we look
at the processes that are running on our
machines at home and we kind of go
crap what the hell is that
oh no then you go and
duck it
yes
so
so you go search for uh what is that
process is this related to malware and
i'm getting nervous
and then
when you've done that and you've done a
search maybe you're still not satisfied
so you grab a hash thrown in virustotal
you're like we're still good um or
you're still nervous you throw in a
sandbox and see what it does right so
that's what you want to do across your
organization look for the outliers if i
have ten thousand or a hundred thousand
endpoints but only
five of them have this particular
process running on them what is that why
do only five machines out of 10 000
running this thing and just understand
what's going on
and then you can always do like a report
to deliver something like this so you
can say like hey i want a report every
day that tells me the outlier processes
that happen across the organization and
then you just like look at those things
check those out hunt on those what's
happening there let me go expand the
hunt find out what's going on
um
look at you know parent process
relationships right so uh if command
odyssey is running from windward what's
uh
what's going on there man uh look for
stuff like that right svc host being
launched by anything other than
services.exe
processes that are missing company name
and product version so lazy
you know attackers who just aren't
aren't changing things again this stuff
sounds foundational because it is every
bullet point in here is something we
have found something on
and i'll share a story if i have even
remotely a moment at the end of this but
i'm still trying to
power through
look for processes with similar names to
legitimate processes and this is where
things like string similarity algorithms
are great where you can go in and say
show me processes that look like actual
known and good processes are they trying
to change something like having a
capital i instead of an l or a zero
instead of an o that kind of stuff right
um or just you know srvc host or
something like that right we want to
find outliers like that and then
processes that are just starting from
odd locations um scripting right this
should be something that when we start
adding things to an allow list we
understand who are users and what
departments are most often using
scripting if kevin in accounting is
suddenly doing a bunch of stuff in
powershell you're like what's going on
there brother
what you doing right you want to
understand who are the folks within the
organization who normally are
doing some type of scripting and if
something pops up that's odd we want to
look at that outlier or anomalous
behavior
if they're invoking
encoded commands what is it that they're
trying to hide and maybe nothing maybe
they just really like doing it i don't
know but but we want to look for things
where people are not you know encrypting
something but just encoding something
obfuscating or making it harder to see
what's actually going on and then again
just some advice use a naming convention
for your scripts right and then alert on
things that go outside of that naming
convention or or don't and just know
that your hunters and analysts when
they're looking and they see a script
that's been fired off somewhere and they
go that's not normal
putting small things into place like
just adding a naming convention to your
scripts can make a huge difference to
what's normal and not normal within the
org
users being added to privileged groups
know when it does this right and if they
don't have a schedule for doing it
please ask them to have one right if
they're like we only do that between
these hours and these hours on these
days and then if something happens
outside of those that's an outlier
that's an anomaly go look why is that
happening why is that taking place
and this one might seem odd but
collecting your bash history
across the org to a central location
this one is just if an attacker does get
into the environment um
watching them at a command line can give
you an indication of how skilled that
attacker is i think we've all
experienced this as well when you're in
a command line situation and someone
walks up and is looking over your
shoulder and you're like now i'm going
to put 3000 typos and forget all of the
commands and you're like why are you
judging me because i keep hitting
question mark right like stop like i
just want to be right
right so
understanding what the skill of the
attacker is but also i can tell you from
the um
offensive or red team side of the house
or pen testing side of the house
going and looking at the bash history to
see what a machine is used for is a good
way to understand what you've gotten
into it goes beyond just who am i right
like going in and looking at what the
last 50 commands that were executed on
that box in the first time you get into
it can give you a good indication about
what takes place on that machine so
attackers are looking at the bash
history you should too
and then look for things that are signs
of internal reconnaissance right so who
am i
you know just ipconfig normal stuff
again this is stuff we do all the time
because we're nerds and it's part of our
jobs but there's no scenario where
somebody in you know finance is like
should be messing around trying to
figure out uh you know what's going on
on their on the network or within their
environment and this holds true for you
know tools like nmap anything you'd find
in a kali distro right so look for
things that are normally run by it or
buy admins not run by
your average everyday employee
when you're looking for lateral movement
so new user and endpoint paris is
somebody logging into a machine they've
never logged into before why is kevin in
accounting logging into a machine in
research and development right that's
odd we want to pay attention to stuff
like that new endpoint endpoint pairs so
why is that machine
talking to this machine it's never
talked to before again outliers
anomalies take a look at things like
those
and then
somebody logging into a system and then
immediately using alternate credentials
another thing that might be normal for
us as administrators
or within the it organization but not
for normal users
and then of course to keep it gangster
any kind of log tampering somebody going
in and trying to corrupt or clear logs
when it comes to persistence you know
any changes to the registry this is true
for other things too where um
like local admin privileges or whatever
somebody's able to make changes to the
registry and they shouldn't we have done
uh audits of changes to registry and
found people who were put into the wrong
groups or given the wrong privileges on
devices or resources that they shouldn't
have been and again it's not
exfiltration to china but it is reducing
your attack surface because now you have
one less administrator out there right
look for scheduled task creation
people changing you know enabling or
disabling tasks what are those
any unknown or unapproved services
and then the indicator so nice we put it
in here twice users being added to
privileged groups again for persistence
so pay attention to things like that now
this one may seem odd but it is kind of
interesting and that is hints from your
antivirus most people deploy antivirus
and they just leave it right
but what's interesting about your
antivirus logs is understanding where
malware is being cleaned from
so if malware lands in an average
everyday user's download folder is
immediately found and cleaned
cool
if malware was cleaned off of a user's
machine but it was cleaned out of system
how'd that get there
right
even if it was cleaned
how did that get there
right so
pay attention to your antivirus logs
there's interesting stuff in there that
can clue you in that there is a problem
on that endpoint or with that user that
you need to be aware of that is odd
behavior
so if you see something like that what
has happened over the last three days
seven days what is this user what is
this machine doing
and then signs of known attacker tools
being uh
you know cleaned out of anywhere doesn't
matter i don't care if it's the download
folder or somewhere else if you're
seeing stuff like mimikatz being cleaned
off of something why the hell was that
there
right and if it did get cleaned off
great but what does that mean
after
you know uh after it's gone well it
means the attacker knows it got cleaned
off and so they're gonna try to come at
you a different way or they'll just
recompile something or whatever
so look for
signs of any known attacker tools and of
course any droppers as well type of
staging that might be going on so look
at your antivirus logs there's
interesting stuff in there
um
artifacts in shim cache and amcach i'm
huge on this if you are not hunting in
your shim cache and am cache you are
missing interesting stuff this is how
you understand what all your
applications are doing where they're
launching from all of that information
is in here please if you're not hunting
in your shim cache and am cache change
that make that a thing look for rename
tools somebody just changing the tools
that they're using or potentially
command line arguments that are being
executed by something that you would
know is normal on a different tool so
you're like that looks like port
forwarding and putty but that's not
putty doing it what is that right so
look for things like that
um on the you know http side of the
house the website house i mentioned this
earlier posts with no gets people don't
often post things to your web server
without asking for something first so
look for methods that are strange
short file name scripts are things that
are outside of your naming convention
attackers can sometimes be lazy
and they'll just you know put in a very
short or or a single letter as the
script or whatever that they're
deploying we find interesting stuff
there encoded query strings gone are
mostly the days of just finding cat etsy
password in in your address bar
but um now it's just a blob of base64.
why is there a blob of base64 in there
let me go take a look at what it is
and then low numbers of http headers
right so
when you send a request it sends a lot
of stuff it wants no content length the
type of the user agent string is what
browser you're using and like operating
system how am i supposed to format this
thing um you know what the person is
asking for what region they're coming
from what's the language i'm going to
deliver this all these different things
are put into
that request and response
if you're seeing six or less headers in
there that's weird we normally see eight
plus and sometimes an absurd number
right depending on what your what you're
looking at every once in a while you'll
see something where it's like two and
you're like what is that and it's like a
python script but you know because you
go look and you're like oh we're good
um so just pay attention to stuff like
that on the host side of thing anomalies
direct to ip is that any more
foundational could it get any more
foundational than that
direct ip is not how we communicate to
one another we don't say i found a super
dope website at
64.228.14. whatever we don't do that
right we give you a host name and so
direct ip communication happens between
machines or somebody who knows what's on
the other side
what is that communication why is it
happening create a feed of what those
ip addresses are actually tied to and
load that into your sim or whatever you
know tools that you're using to allow
you to understand oh this is what this
is
whenever you see it
and specifying a port number again we
are all huge nerds here so we do this
all the time and if you're running like
a nas at your house or a media server or
something you do this every day right
you're specifying the port number
but you know who's never done this my
dad
right
kevin in finance right so if we if we
see somebody doing oh this specific port
on this server what's on the other end
of that port we want to understand that
um strange or missing refers are you
seeing stuff coming from
places where you don't normally work or
sites that you have no connection to
if the content length is missing or
mismatched and we've seen this before
where an attacker wrote a tool and they
just put the content length was going to
be 40 96 60 every single time and it
wasn't so that mismatch in the content
length we were like
that well that breaks the rfc let's go
take a look at what it was and it was
just a you know an attacker's tool
they'd custom written themselves
old strange or short user agent strings
this is where you're looking for stuff
like mozilla with a zero all right if it
says mozilla five but it just says
mozilla five that ain't right it should
be really really long it tells you all
the things they need like the browser
needs to do to display the page
correctly so look for
you know user agent strings that are
weird sometimes attackers again are
super lazy or it's just some kid in
their parents basement in wyoming and so
they don't
they don't take the time to change the
username string of the tool that was
made to test environments right and
they're using it to attack with so if
you see those things you know they're
bad every time and if it's old then
maybe you just have old browsers kicking
around your organization that need to be
updated
you see like netscape navigator gold
um or something i heard my old people
chuckle
thanks old people you're not alone
um
all right on dns
uh dynamic dns so still used by command
control a lot right we see malware
that's communicating to dynamic dns
services and the services have made this
really easy for attackers because
they've created apis that allow them to
basically do domain generation
algorithms using these dynamic dns
services now dynamic dns is often used
sometimes just for connecting to a file
server or a media server or whatever and
so we find policy violation stuff in
organizations all the time where we just
have users connecting to some file
server or media server at home it's not
a
breach per se but it's not
allowed
so we want to look for stuff like that
but i mentioned dga
so what this is is essentially
it's kind of like having a two-factor
authentication like having a token
where i have some seed data and you know
that data too and so we know that every
60 seconds this number is going to
change well it's in this case it's just
every x amount of time this domain is
going to change and when it changes it's
going to change to this
so that
that domain can change and change and
change and that host changes every time
and it doesn't matter because the
command and control can still take place
they never lose communication from the
malware to the c2 server because it's
just rolling and rolling and rolling
which is why host names are terrible
threat intelligence
dns lookups to onion addresses or
browser processes that aren't tor trying
to connect to
onion addresses i know this sounds odd
but
this very well may be the first
indicator that you get that somebody was
hit with ransomware because they don't
know anything about it and freaking
kevin and finance is trying to go to a
dot onion address and because he doesn't
understand that he's got to do it a
certain way to to pay whatever the
ransom is so um sometimes like if you if
you see this this you should alert on um
immediately and then as far as dns
tunneling we look for a large number of
subdomains this is where
um an attacker is using really slow
basically exfiltration they're using a
couple of bytes and they send it out and
they change that sub domain and they're
basically encoding whatever it is
they're trying to get out and that
couple of bytes over and over and over
again they make the request they rebuild
on the other side and now they get
whatever it is they want it's absurd
as far as bandwidth wise but it works
especially if you don't detect it
a large number of a single sub domain
again command and control if we see
somebody who just repeatedly is hitting
a certain sub domain and it's only a
couple of
endpoints out of your entire
organization something you want to look
at
a high volume of no null or text records
more bandwidth for exfiltration but we
want to look for stuff like that or file
transfer just straight up file transfer
over dns
and now
you want to parse for file headers but
you also just want to be aware that this
will sometimes trip on zone transfers or
security vendors or antivirus vendors so
you'll see something that you'll say
okay
oh crap look there's a dns tunnel
somebody's trying to get files out over
dns and then you go look and you're like
oh
it's sofos right the thing about
antivirus and security vendors is that
they know about things like file
transfer over dns so if they want to get
something out of your organization guess
what they do
they use it right so but look for stuff
like that because it's not normal
when it comes to encrypted traffic um
you know it's encrypted right so it's
game over we just get rid of it right
throw it away
no
even if we're not saving the payload the
metadata involved in that is invaluable
so source and destination ips session
size and length there's things that we
can infer from that encrypted traffic
that having the metadata for it is
really useful
um we can use things like job3
where we can get a higher confidence
understanding of what the client server
communication is that's happening with
that encrypted traffic but honestly we
are at a point
where you know we're seeing
you know 50 plus 60 plus 70 plus 80
percent encrypted traffic not just um
like internal but external as well
at the black like a black hat we track
that as a stat how much traffic is
encrypted on the network and for a long
time it went up about five percent year
over year and it seems to have plateaued
between like 75 and 80 and it just stays
there um encrypted is great right as far
as we're all concerned encrypt
everything right but
as a defender it's really hard to defend
when you don't know what's flying around
your network so it's good to maybe start
looking at a decryption solution and
just a like piece of advice from me
some security vendors will come at you
and say hey we can do native decryption
maybe they can maybe you check a box and
now it starts doing that decryption
however the impact to whatever that
device is can be severe right so it's a
good idea to just check and see all
right is it worth it for me to go buy a
standalone decryption solution like go
get some gigamon solution that i can
have rather than tell this vendor's
device to start doing that decryption
for me and it ends up killing the
performance and i have to buy three
times as much now the vendor is going to
love that but you're not
so just make sure that you understand
what the impact is of doing that
decryption and look at a standalone
solution if you do and with that
i made it
all right so i i have a minute i told
you i would tell you a quick story about
something that it seems really benign or
not important at the beginning um but in
the end led to something very
interesting and that was um if you came
to the keynote yesterday you you met
james pope so pope and i worked together
at rsa as threat hunters
we went out into a
an incredibly large financial
organization all of you know this
organization
we went and sat in one of their sites
and there were 30 security people on the
floor that we were on on that site right
so not like a small
security team sometimes we would go in
and meet with security teams and we'd be
like well how many people are on your
team and we're in a conference room with
like four people and they're like this
is it and we're like what um but in this
case that wasn't that wasn't true we had
30 plus folks on that floor
we sat down with a couple
of people and said here's what we're
going to be doing this this and this
they said all right this guy's going to
sit next to you you know to to see what
you guys are doing
and we started describing hunting to him
and the kind of the process we go
through and the way that we do our hunts
and we were looking at all of their
network traffic and we said well what
we'll do is go in and look at a low
number of sessions because those are
outlier sessions and we want to see what
it is that's behind that
so we're like so for instance
i'm like
why don't we take a look at ftp
and he goes we don't use ftp
and i was like well i i assure you that
you do
because i can see it on the wire like
it's here in the full packet
and he's like
no we don't allow ftp and i'm like
well then this is a perfect place to
look because if you're saying that you
don't allow it this is good this is five
minutes into us sitting down with this
guy just talking about the hunt
so we're like well let's take a look we
open it up we look and we're like okay
every day at 1am
there is a file transfer to an ftp
server in russia and they're not even
trying to hide a straightup.ru
and we're like
is this normal and he's like
nope
or and we're like well what do you think
that is
and i'm like i'm not opening it because
i'm contracted to be here so i'm not
opening that and he's like
all right well i'll do it you know so we
pull the file out of the stream it's a
zip file we open it up and he starts to
open up the file and he
freaks out and he closes it he goes
oh
and we're like what and he's like you
didn't see that and i was like all right
just out of curiosity what did i
not see
and he's like that is every financial
transaction and trade that we've made in
the last 24 hours
and i was like
um
let me just see how long that's been
going on
six months of logs
six months
every 24 hours
ftp to russia not even trying to hide 30
security people on that floor but it's
ftp we don't use it
so we don't look
go look
because it's the things you think you're
not using that are going to bite you
thanks
[Applause]