they took this you'll see it with lpl
stuff they took it to a whole nother
level of amazingness with this top down
camera um
super legit i'm excited about it
so
oh they didn't mention compukid mike
made the defcon badge too right like
utah we bat way above our weight in the
infosec community so we're saying like
hey this is the cool badge at st con
that's the same badge maker makes a
defcon badge just saying
all right so this is me i'm james pope
everybody just calls me pope which was
nice and easy because i had a weird last
name no matter what hacker handle i
tried it just ended up with that
um it did get a little more complicated
because i got some brothers here with
the same last name they got to have
their own handle so i'm just still pope
i've been doing st con committee since
in the av did it with kevin howard
and uh i sit in the black cat and knock
as a team lead
so you'll find me there actually flying
out to europe in two weeks to do the
europe show i helped start and run with
a lot of really good folks dc435 which
is up in cache valley
also came from salt lake so dc801 i'm
never giving up ownership of that so i
participate in that and then i help
bryce coons run b-side salt lake as well
here in salt lake or
that way in salt lake
all right so when i was putting together
this talk
i went back and looked at all the past
talks i've done
and just from morbid curiosity i was
like what's the first talk i ever did on
infosec this is an actual slide deck
from it it was a security awareness
training talk i've taken out the org's
name that it worked for
but it was in movie theaters that'll be
prevalent as we start to go um and
i started like looking at all the
content that was in this slide deck and
it was things like fishing and spear
fishing things like patch management and
social engineering
and what i realized was
all the things that
are in that deck is the exact same
things today
right like i could almost get up not
that i mean we're all in security and
you don't want to sit through security
awareness training and you know people
in security
because that's not super fun because you
already know you're preaching to the
choir
but
it was it was a lot the same so i'm
looking back from a decade before and i
realize
we're just staring at ourselves right
like
this is literally the same things we're
talking about a year a decade later like
an entire decade
and
oh one caveat one caveat this part right
here i used to front load the front of
all of my presentations almost a third
of it just talking about why security
matters
this part has absolutely changed
i now have neighbors
six-year-old neighbors four-year-old all
my neighbors are coming over telling me
about hey
colonial pipeline got ransomware and gas
prices are going up or hey microsoft
helped me with support and i think i
lost 400
right
why security matters
is built in now everybody understands it
i still have conversations with people
about
things like
you know do i care if somebody has my
information we get into weird privacy
conversations that still happens but
this part has absolutely changed besides
that
we're still doing this we're staring at
ourselves from a decade later of a lot
of the same stuff and when i realized
that i actually got kind of depressed
about it
right i'm like this is my job this is
what i'm doing and we're still talking
about the same things and i legitimately
like it like it like bent my head right
i was like wrapped around like
just really like frustrated thinking
about all these scenarios of how are we
still going over the same things a
decade later
right
and
i started writing like a talk that was
like super negative
like all the ways you could get breached
like it started just spiraling in weird
directions and it was all just ended up
being more negative than positive like
turning into twitter right where it's
like
and and rightfully so security kind of
is that and it's actually the reason i
love it is there's always new things new
vulnerabilities but it's usually like if
you look at it from a peer defender side
it's like here's something else you have
to deal with you got to go patch
something else hey that you know you
thought it was just os now it's computer
chips you know now it's you know your
bios and all you know all these other
things new bypass today of microsoft
surface you know security right like
just new things over and over and over
and so yeah i was building out this
thing that wasn't like the most ideal it
was just more
negative than positive and that's not
something that i wanted to do
so
i thought like what what is the time in
my life
that correlated to this like i've had
situations like this before where i
started getting really negative about
things
and you know how did i break out of
those so to tell this whole story i
gotta start from the beginning and the
beginning is at one point in my life i
started this company and we did camera
security
right like we're installing camera
systems all over chicago to canada to
whatever we were just being shipped
around uh putting in cameras this is a
legit picture that is will on the top of
that ladder and he was up there for like
six hours
right like
yeah and my brother larry as well in
here and so we did these camera security
companies and part of that was it was
all just availability right i didn't
know anything about security i mean i
knew some things i'd installed some
systems but it it wasn't a thought it
was all availability i was completely
focused around availability and as such
we'd get a camera system installed and
then we would you know punch holes
through firewalls so that way we could
you know get an activex on internet
explorer 6 to
run it's not a joke that was a real
thing
we used to do that
right and so we would we we didn't care
about security we're just making things
work and that turned into all sorts of
other weird i.t things
when you help a customer is one thing
and you can log into their firewall
suddenly it's like oh could you do b c d
e f g and it turned into all sorts of it
things
racks and installing things and
whatever was needed we just started like
building that out helping people with
all their general i.t
part of that
i had a customer who said hey uh he
called me james so james my first name
hey james uh can we
do this pci compliance
that
the credit card brands are asking me to
do
and i was like i don't i don't know
anything about any of that
right
and he's like well can you look into it
sure so i go i go home and google's the
pc i i'm gonna call it duck it now we're
ducking it duck.go i went home and i
ducked it and uh
i
researched and saw what came with pci
and my immediate reaction was like no no
no no no
i don't do that pci this thing looks
like a dumpster fire is a mess i don't
want to touch it i don't want to do it
and
and he said okay fine sure
like a month later he came back and he's
like hey uh i really like your help with
this pci compliance and i was like
didn't you find somebody else i told you
i'm not qualified i don't understand it
i don't know anything about pci and it
looks like a mess and he's like
i really want you to do it
come to find out i had a really cheap
rate at the time i just didn't know it
was 35 an hour right like i didn't know
i didn't know um so i said all right
i'll greet you if you pay me to research
pci understand it and if i don't deliver
it properly i still get paid for the
hours on the research
fine okay so i spent a bunch of time uh
did doing pci we did a full i think was
like sac d
and we get through it and they bring an
external auditor and the external error
comes in and they look at everything and
they're like
all but this one thing you missed this
one thing part of that was policy
creation and other things but we did
this one thing and after that one thing
they cleared and passed through pci
compliance and my learning curve of
security went from punching holes in
firewalls for ie6 for activex to run
make sure you click allow you got to
click allow all the things
my learning curve is security started
shooting up and i started to catch this
little bit of bug of infosec
this little part of like
hey you know there's a whole other side
besides just availability
we should probably secure some things
right
and that led to me going to the company
i worked at
and saying like hey we
we take a lot of credit cards
we should be doing a lot of these things
at the time i don't know if it was
around the time it came out or maybe it
was before and i just got access to it
this thing called lucidchart that i
thought was like the most amazing thing
ever and so
um a little bit of this story will lead
to that what happened was i went to my
boss and i was like hey all these pci
compliance things and uh i was had him
on the phone call and he was like
i don't understand what you're saying
i don't understand either this much like
my reaction when i first looked at pci
like no
this is a mess
and he's like maybe you need to type it
up for me so i still have it i couldn't
it was all redacted when i tried to get
a screenshot of it but
an entire email talking about all the
things in pci that needed to get
accomplished and i ship it over to him
i'm really proud of this work
and he's like i don't understand any of
this right like this is still a mess and
so i had the idea let's take lucidchart
i'm going to make a flow chart this is
the actual flowchart i made in 2011.
the org name is blocked out i'm sure i
could do a better one today
but funny enough i had i had this whole
side of like is the company willing to
change if no status quo
and then a whole bunch of things over
here that were more i.t related
including like maybe legitimate windows
you know keys and stuff and then on the
left hand side was like pci compliance
and this is required and if you don't
you're going to pay fines and then i
looked at the stuff we were doing and
the stuff we weren't and i created like
this really short list of like
all right well maybe we need not default
credentials and maybe we actually need a
policy that says we're doing pci right
maybe we actually need to get some cisco
training because i don't know what i'm
doing on that right
um
different unique ids maybe we shouldn't
all log in with the same credentials so
i went through all of it and tried to
find the differences and listed it out
and at the end of the day i was like you
know i'm just going to list all the
references of pci at the bottom just so
that way i'm covered right so this is my
actual this is like a gif of me make of
bumping through it but this is like
legitimately and you'll even see like
the date stamp in the far right this is
2011 like a decade ago that's insanity
to me to think about
and so i delivered this
and it got forwarded up because people
actually understood big red things that
said required and large fines
right so i delivered it and it went all
the way up to the executives
and then i got in a lot of trouble
i got a lot of trouble at the time i was
like a director of operations running
movie theaters multiple locations and i
did i t i stood up some point of sale
systems like
and then obviously camera systems right
but i got a lot of trouble jump there's
people who are responsible for
it and it wasn't me
and they were not happy with this
right and instead of being like yeah we
should improve some of these things and
how do we work towards this they just
got told like no we're doing that
and
you're a young kid from utah and stay in
your lane essentially that's maybe my
interpretation of it those words weren't
exact but multiple calls where i was
wrong and they were right
even though i was like hey i'm
overseeing a lot of these buildings and
i guarantee we're not doing that anyway
regardless it got to a point where i was
like just just leave me alone i'm going
to keep around the theaters you guys do
whatever
i'm going to do that on the side
consulting
i think the laptop this is what i'm
talking too much
a single slide all right
so then i get a call
it's like a friday i remember i was like
in the theater tearing tickets and i get
a call and they're like do you know
what's going on with these buildings
and i'm like no i have no i have no idea
right that's not my building and they're
like uh they're saying we need a pfi
and my immediate response was oh you got
breached
and then attacks how did you know that
how did you know he got breached i'm
like well you said pfi that's a pci
forensic investigator you want to talk
about that learning curve of pca i got
nerdy like i've printed those things out
i was reading them i was living
breathing pci i was thinking maybe i
could make a lot of money charging 35 an
hour to do pci
right
i was reading so i knew exactly what pfi
meant and they're like okay well uh the
brands mastercard telling us we got to
get that we don't know what to do and
the links they sent us were the same
links that were in the bottom of your
flow chart
[Music]
and i was like yeah pci so i immediately
pivoted people covering my stuff and i
had to go hire uh ir team forensic team
that was you know certified we get on
site
and i'm meeting with these guys and you
know confirming the breach yep total
total breach just so you know because
i'm dirty and i like that stuff came in
through pc anywhere
remember that came in through pc and er
some default creds server
effect terminals
and uh the credit card swipes and
they're finally moving off we'll chat
about that in a minute um they're just
key loggers right it's a usb keylogger
literally if you open up notepad and
swipe your credit card just prints out
your credit card information
so
they were just every time you swiped a
card it was just saving it to a text
file called it was like something stupid
like one.txt or something and then it
was sending those all to the server the
server is batching them to an ftp server
like every hour like hey we want to make
sure we get this every hour send out
credit cards so confirm breach
and i get there and i'm chatting with
the guy and i you know i talk a lot
right so i was like earful of this guy
i'm like in his ear what's happening
what's this thing doing and by the end
of i hear him on the phone with his boss
in the other room's like like dude these
guys have it they they have he has the
freaking pci like printed out and he's
referencing things about it that i don't
even know right and so i was like okay
like my learning curve my little bit of
bug for ir and forensics all
shot up i then had to turn around and
secure that environment
and so i don't know if anybody's ever
got youtube certified that's where half
your screen on your laptop in the back
room is youtube and the other half's
your cisco terminal
and
you're trying things and then nmap to
validate it no that didn't work trying
things and then you learn the hard
lesson of what a running config and a
save config is
after you get it all working and you
reboot it for those who don't know and
you reboot your cisco device plug it or
otherwise and you lose everything you
did if you don't save it
learn that lesson so yeah learning curve
shot up everything goes up and it turns
into
securing the site becoming a director of
i.t moving out of operations going full
into it and start doing presentations
that are required by pci like why does
security matter internally it turns in
even bigger i start doing it for the
industry i start presenting for
movie theater other exhibitors and
you know people who make the content
going to industry events and i'm
presenting on security and not my words
because i'm a smart enough security
professional to never say these words
but other people's words
you have the most secure theater chain
in north america
and that was primarily because we were
not proactive we got breached right and
so then spend was there time was there
people were on board because we already
dealt with this pain and at the time
2011 breach
everybody cared
like like now i think if that happened i
don't think anybody would be like
whatever like another breach but we had
like 17 police precincts and government
agencies and it was in we had to keep
hard drives for seven years of every
terminal like that stuff is now just
like whatever new can pave it let's go
everybody's getting wrecked
right so it's completely changed but so
i start doing these presentations on why
security matters in the industry and uh
at big events
and that led to that you know initial
slide deck
also um i decided after like five
locations because there's like 17 or
something i'm like pci sucks right like
i know i like it and it's a big learning
curve but it's a lot of freaking work
like a sac d at the time like 265
questions or something insane
and
i found these loopholes called
end-to-end encryption and i was like
wait what is this thing and it's like 10
questions you have to answer these 10
questions every year and i'm like yeah
i'm doing that so we moved we moved
everything to these verifone units in
2011. like you know just now everybody's
like
put in the chip bbb we did that long ago
because i was like i'm tired of this and
i actually proved out an roi going to
that instead of doing pci sac d
so anyway we end up that's how it most
secured because even if we're completely
breached there's no credit cards they're
all encrypted and verifone has the other
end of that key right
anyway so i'm trudging through pci for
lots of years
like three or so and i was like i wonder
if there's other people doing these
things
it just literally had never dawned on me
so much work in front of me just plowing
through it i'm like are other people
doing security in pci i would like to
talk to some of them so i google it duck
duck it dang it i duck it and uh the hit
comes back with defcon right and i'm
like oh that sounds cool and it already
just passed i'm like oh and then i found
saint con i'm like oh st con it's coming
up in like two weeks in october in weber
and i'm like all right i'm gonna try to
go to this so i put this proposal my
glass i'd like to go to st con get some
training get better at pci things
and he's like yeah i don't really see
the value of that
so back and forth back and forth i think
they they did agree to like okay we'll
pay half your time you pay the other
half but all meals travel all's on you
your car's on you okay so i got like two
days paid to go to st con i think i
think that's right 2014.
so i show up and yeah i i missed the
very beginning
so i didn't know who troy was i missed
this entry keynote because i got late
got there late because i was doing a job
and
so i didn't know troy was and yeah i was
ranting about the av that wasn't the
smartest move but um
got stuck doing av
it's been fun it's actually been great
doing that but what i did who i did meet
in the lobby when i first showed up was
metacortex
and uh
danny and he was there with 801 labs and
he's talking about all the things that
801 labs is doing
and i didn't i didn't understand the
vision like he explained it and i'm like
i don't i don't know if that's for me
right and so i left and he was like i
made some counterpoints he's like yeah
that sounds good so then i went uh into
uh presentations and when i tell you
when i went to my first saint con it was
like i just like found family it was
kind of weird and i was like super
nerding out like super tech guys up
there doing a presentation on like ir
evidence and i'm taking like pictures of
his slides
nerdy miles on fishing and you know just
watching all the things they're doing
and i'm like documenting them i mean
aaron toppings on like the math of
passwords and i moved to a password card
then and i still use it like insane like
how much i was just trying to soak in i
still like all these google notes uh
from that first conference and pictures
from it
and then i went to metacortex's talk
and it went from like this this bug of
security of pci of things that i thought
interesting to
he pulled out a computer
turned up a can of compressed air froze
the ram
pulled it out and like dumped all the
memory out of clear text off a computer
it wasn't even running
and i was just like what in the freak
right like i i legitimately had never
seen anything any is so amazing
and so i came out of there and i was
like
wherever this guy is i need to go
so
i went 181 laps whatever that pitch was
before but show me that i'm going and it
went from like oh there's not just pci
but there's like attacks and all this
other weirdness and so freak so i went i
went to 801 labs i met troy there um
i didn't remember him too much from the
saint con as much but i met him there
he's teaching me how to paint a wall or
something he has a very fancy way to
paint a wall if you need how to paint a
wall
troy knows how to paint a wall
i did show him how to like make cables
and he didn't believe it this is just a
side i just remembered it um i was doing
some cat six cables because remember had
a company that we're doing all this
stupid cabling for two-piece and i was
like banging him out super fast and he's
like no way you can do it as good or
fast as me and i like wrecked him and
then he's like okay that's better uh
anyway after you get your street creds
make some weird cat6 cables
but
at 801 labs i met nemus there and i'm
going to his reverse engineering malware
classes and after sitting through six of
those uh i hate assembly i will never do
reverse engineering malware i'm glad
people do um i i learned that i don't
like it um i love nemas he's the best
but i hate assembly so reverse
engineering malware's out i met neil
there uh grifter
and uh they're like hey we're doing all
these fortinet aps we're flashing them
all for black hat and so i just sat
there and helped them flash fortinet aps
for like hours and they're like you
wanna you wanna go to black at
i'm like yeah that sounds cool but i'm
not paying no like thousands of dollars
to go to black hat
and they're like no you can come on the
knock team and
go for free and i'm like yeah let's go
so that's how i joined black hat got in
the black cat not just meeting them
there
and
lots of people started running dc 801
and getting presenters and i met a lot
of people doing that
so that's how i pivoted there
and
then it moved into becoming a defender
so i'm like okay i'm going to get out of
this director of i.t role and i'm going
to become a security defender this is a
game i used to love to play you know
defender
so playing defender
in security um handed lots of tools and
things that i'd use some parts of some
not others but just focus instead of
being like a small part of what you're
doing it's your whole job right you are
a defender go defend
and part of that i got handed a qualis
box
okay you got vulnerability management
cool that doesn't seem so hard
yeah the whole entire story is about
quality vulnerability management
it's a mess
like i go in there and look at it and
you have essentially two buckets the
bucket of the systems that are auto
patching
they're auto patching and the other
bucket and that other bucket is the
report that it got generated last week
is the same report that got generated a
year before except new vulnerabilities
are on it
right
and so i'm trying some things there i'm
you know sending out the auto emails
asking people to do stuff and it just
wasn't happening
right the same report the same thing
and i became really like frustrated
about it and there was other things but
like i got super like in a weird funk
and depressed like maybe i made the
wrong call maybe i shouldn't be in
full-time security maybe go back and
tear tickets at a movie theater i don't
know what i'm doing i'm not making any
progress i'm just bashing my head on
this wall and nothing's happening
we did some pen testing kind of felt
like a lot like that when you can't get
a foothold you're just
slamming your head against the wall the
entire time
and
after like few months i was you know
debating just calling that quits
and i just decided you know what i'm
just gonna hyper focus on vulnerability
management that's it it's the hardest
thing the part that i hate the most
i'm gonna just focus on that i'm gonna
see what i can do i'm just gonna change
my mindset about it i get to do this
instead of i have to do this i'm gonna
plow through on vulnerability management
so i did i created i call the fbi top 10
hit list
where i just said here's the top 10
vulnerabilities in the entire org
and that department owns one and that
department owns one and that department
owns one so i'm going to send a personal
email instead of the qualis report i'm
going to copy it out i'm going to paste
it why it matters what somebody can do
with that information
let me come and talk to you about it
afterwards blah blah blah send it over
some that gained traction some it didn't
someone just throw out calendar invites
conference room you
and i just show up sometimes they showed
up sometimes they didn't but
interestingly after a while
it started really gaining traction
people are showing up they're listening
to what i say they're like yeah that
sounds bad or we're coming up with
mitigations if you can't
and after a period of time months this
wasn't like
the next day
months
interestingly enough we're all rowing in
the same direction objectively by
reports we have improved security
posture the thing that i thought was the
hardest most frustrating became very
rewarding
building rapport with all these
departments that could care less they
were just like me just availability
punching holes in firewalls i don't care
i just need this to work
right my job is to make stuff work so
start talking to them building those
rapports and improving security and it
was very gratifying when it actually
happened
that led into i also find this weird ftp
traffic
and then that leads into okay what is
that and it's this camera system and
there's just this camera that's
legitimately doing the shadiest things
ever like full ftp and ssh and ssh ftp
out and it's just like this the most
amazing proxy for somebody that they've
just been using for we don't know as far
as back the logs went
and so that kind of caught me a little
bit of bug of like
going and looking and hunting like oh we
can just look through this data and find
interesting stuff
and so i pivoted to another job where
there's stuff in between but i'm cutting
to the chase for you on this we pivoted
to a job where we went and did a lot of
threat hunting and part of that i was a
sales engineer team who worked on uh
threat hunting
and i got to talk with giant giant orgs
and hunt through giant orgs data and
that was a lot of fun and we do stories
on that me and grifter have a ton of
stuff on those
and
you could easily tell the org who
was just trying to do a compliance
checkbox for the sake of it
or for h or sorry for insurance or for
compliance or some other reason or the
ones who actually cared
legitimately there was orgs where
yeah you put in the ids you racked it
you powered it on
okay how's it working how do you use it
oh we don't use it traffic actually
doesn't pass to the ids
so wait you bought a really expensive
ids and you're not passing any traffic
into it that's correct
why would you do that
oh because our compliance says we have
to have an ids
but it doesn't say it has to be used or
even monitoring traffic
this is this is stuff you find and see
if you're just trying to check a box you
can absolutely check a security box and
miss the whole point
and i've seen it
you can also do it for the right reasons
and when you talk to an org that was
doing it for the right reasons it was
super refreshing here's what we do and
we're trying to improve this posture and
here's our prioritization list and
here's what we're working on that gives
me like goosebumps i'm like oh like
i just love talking to you because you
care about security for the right
reasons when you're doing it just to
like i don't really want to deal with
this i'm just required to um
you might as well just not do it right
but part of that we're still dealing
with the same things these big orgs with
big security teams we're still talking
about
cis 20 or 18 now i guess we're calling
18 now cas 18 framework or whatever
framework you choose not discriminatory
um and the number one is inventory your
devices
well big words with big teams still
don't have this down
the ones who care and are really doing
it for the right reasons
have it down where it matters
i have my critical servers i know what
they are and if anything ever gets added
there i get a notification or alert on
it
maybe they don't care about the kiosk in
the lobby maybe they don't care about
guest wi-fi ceo's laptop yep cfos they
care about the critical assets but we're
still talking about these same things a
decade later same slide deck inventory
of devices we're spending time looking
at that local admin i remember going on
a circuit across utah talking about how
to remove local admin from your
environment
still a thing we're still talking about
this because it's hard security is hard
it's the part that makes it exciting and
fun it's also the part that gets you a
little bit depressed like ah
how did that ransomware spread oh yeah
they all had local admin cool
yep that makes sense um why does
somebody in finance need local admin i
don't know it's like the sister of the
owner and they just needed to have it
right
but we're still talking about these same
things
one more thing i wanted to note on a
story wise i was sitting here running av
and we had a keynote lost and my
favorite 2017 i think that's right
anyway i was just sitting sitting down
here i think it was actually on the
floor like by the camera and uh
he mentioned something like
just a single slide deck it was like a
single a single slide hey uh
sometimes when i'm doing pen tests
i checked for a cisco smart
vulnerability
and i remember pulling out my google uh
keep my notes and i wrote cisco
smartphone ability question mark
okay and then i forgot all about it for
like months
months later i was looking through my
notes go smartphone what is that start
researching it oh cisco says it's not a
vulnerability it's a feature cool all
right so not a vulnerability um are we
looking at the same thing yep we are
that's it all right well i'm gonna try
it grab a script
i run it against a cisco back end
switches and i get a full config i'm
like dang
maybe i'm in a privileged network though
so i spin up a vulture vps and one of
the shady vps is like 2.50 cents or
something it's a bit of a vulture vps
and
i do it again and i dump the config
again from a privileged network
completely external in la
the vulture one
and then i was like holy crap that's not
good so i'm like can we check the logs
and see if anybody's done this before
i come back yep besides my ip yep
somebody has dumped this config before
and that turned into
a full scale we gotta burn keys we gotta
burn creds there's automated tools that
are rolling these keys and creds and
part of that people were like this is
awesome and we're glad we found this but
then there's also like
freaking security
has given us so much work to do
right you've just saddled us with this
pile of work to do when we already have
our job and everything to do and now we
got to go do all these switches and all
these things
let alone some of those switches when
you update them remotely in the middle
of utah fall over
and that caused all sorts of other grief
and right i wasn't intending to cause
any grief
right that's not the intent
but the view of that some people were
very appreciative this is great we're
glad we found this we're glad somebody's
not in there we should definitely roll
this and others were like no
we'd rather not know
so
what does this all lead you i told you a
lot of stories let's see if we can
stitch them together
right sometimes what do we need in
security sometimes we just need buy-in
and spend time materials tooling
whatever that might be to move things
forward sometimes we need to listen
maybe there's just a keynote
maybe not me something maybe more wise
like lost who's up here with just a
little nugget of something that you're
like maybe you're going to sink on your
first time or your fifth time or
whatever and somebody just mentions
something and you just write it down
like what was that thing i'm gonna go
research it and pay a little more
attention to it sometimes it's go look
go hunt right you can assume you're
already compromised and how would
somebody do that and how would you do
that and go look for it do you even have
visibility to see
if that did happen
right do you even have a log that would
show you if somebody did that in that
scenario
where you know the cisco cisco did later
categorize that as a vulnerability they
did change it after that
but if in that scenario
do you even have a log that said
somebody did log in and try that before
or you just don't know
so go look right sometimes it's just
james pope with mental struggles of like
i'm in this job nothing changed at that
job the org didn't change the supervisor
didn't change money didn't change
nothing changed except my mindset
sometimes it's just your mind
sometimes you're just told to stay in
your lane right get out of my face
security
you're the no guys your job's just
coming here tell me what not to do i
just want to do my job right i'm
punching all through firewalls i'm doing
ie6 and activex we're doing this
and so what changed in some of these
scenarios one it took a breach
hopefully that's not needed
to get
hearts and minds moving in the right
direction
but it is a reality
and hopefully when org gets breached
they don't end up with this
baseline of comfortable again that they
forget that pain and have to go through
it again hopefully it doesn't take a
breach
sometimes it's just your mindset i'm
just going to call this a james pope one
this is the cycle i go through this is
what tied this whole talk together from
when i first thought about doing it was
like i got depressed
oh i've lived this before i've lived
these cycles sometimes it's just my
mindset i have the opportunity to be an
infosec
and to look at cool things and do cool
things i get to do that i can always go
back and tear tickets
right so i get to do this this is what i
choose to do sometimes there's real hard
work and sometimes it's mind-numbing
bashing your head on walls
sometimes it's just hunting i want to go
hunt through my traffic i'm the biggest
advocate of threat hunting it's a it's a
very sexy name that just means you just
look through a lot of data
and i talk classes on it lots of classes
on it and i do recommend everybody goes
in threat hunts even if you're not a
threat hunter because even if you're
brand new to an org it helps you
understand your org your posture what
you have where's my ingress egress
points where do things happen where's
the vrf where's how does the firewalls
block this traffic go hunt through your
traffic if you don't have time or your
boss will let you do it full time which
most won't
carve an hour on a friday i'm gonna go
hunt one hour on friday and just look
for it what's the worst case you find
weird stuff bad hygiene and uh well
hopefully it's not a full-on breach i
have plenty of stories of those for
another day but you find interesting
things and you come out a better
defender you should know your network
better than an attacker who lands on it
that should be their biggest
disadvantage when you first land on a
box or when i had a pen test and you
land on a box
you spend a lot of time trying to
understand who i am what privileges i
have what are the things i can talk to
security teams that's our biggest
advantage this is this subnet this is
what it can talk to here's the
privileges they have
what would i do with that escalade etc
validating going and checking for things
right going and looking for weird camera
systems um kind of part of hunting also
kind of part of the lost story of like
here's this thing it's a new
vulnerability well let's go see if that
impacts us
the qualis box doesn't tell us that that
exists because it wasn't a vulnerability
at the time
but here's red team that are using it
all day every day right
and then yes back to organizations if
you can do nothing else then
try to do security for the right reasons
even if it's hard even if you're like i
to know all my assets is daunting pope i
can't do it all
i get it right all i guessed wi-fi
you're probably never going to get there
but start with your critical what's the
most important thing to my organization
data ip
whatever that is
you should know what resides on those
things maybe it's a subnet maybe it's a
vlan maybe it's however you're logically
breaking that out
know what exists on those and if that
ever changes you should be notified when
that changes there are scripts to do
that there's tools to do that there's
free things to do that
right so some of that's hard phase one
start with whatever that first security
control is
okay so this is a tactic
ttp tactic techniques and protocol this
is a tactic that came up with somebody
else i don't know where i got it from
but this is something that i do
constantly i did it this week i did it
even way back when i was getting uh
depressed about the you know trying to
get vulnerability management improved
what i do is i even if i'm at night and
i can't think i'm thinking of something
i write it down and then i put them all
on a piece of paper i'm a little bit old
so sometimes i uh legal pad it i legal
pad out all the things that i have
problems with that i'm trying to improve
and then what i do is i cross off the
ones i cannot control
and this will vary by you your org
varies by me it varies by the situation
i'm dealing with
so maybe in this situation i have time
maybe some examples i have no time right
here's the things i can control i have
time i have the tooling
but in some situations maybe you have
manager buy-in or you don't sometimes
your manager's like i don't understand
what this is maybe you should make a
flow chart right and you make a
flowchart and lucidchart and send it to
them
most orgs deal with budget and time
in some form of those two sometimes both
some more get lucky enough to get both
some only get both when you get breached
those two are complicated people having
good people having good tools some tools
are free some tools are paid there's
various forms of that communication was
literally the one thing that i could
control in that scenario the
vulnerability scanner it was just the
way i was communicating nothing else
changed but my communication right
if you're james pope it's always mindset
you're training
your people's training around you
not just that that knowledge one right
there just showing up the same con and
somebody being like
there's more people here that do pci
than just you
and you can talk to them and gain other
insights of knowledge of things to try
or do there's a way to dump passwords
off of memory with a computer that's off
no idea right knowledge
anyway documentation is either like
somebody's let me down in the past or
it's me letting myself down in the
future because i don't document but
these are things cross out the things
you can't control and don't focus on
those focus on the ones you can control
and yeah if you're me it's pretty much
always this one this is the one that i
always can control and i always get i
get in cycles i'm not perfect cycles of
doing this right cycles of not doing
that right
so all right what what does this all
mean pope you've told us all this
stories and nonsense what does this mean
well first presentation was 2011.
here we are a decade later
21.
what i'm hoping is
we're not talking about the same things
again and that's a daunting task because
as i mentioned those things are hard
having an inventory of your assets is
hard removing local admin developers
security people hard complicated right
but what can we do in this scenario well
we can eat our own dog food
and we can cross out the things we can't
control
well i can't change this whole industry
but i can change myself i can come to st
con i can get knowledge information i
can write something down and go research
it later and try it in my org or take
whatever training i got and empower my
organization to make that better
but by making yourself better
you typically will make your department
better
you'll take a weird thing and suddenly
that part will grow
in some situations maybe that doesn't
right there's it's not always rosy and
perfect
sometimes you have to change orgs that
does exist as well but by making
yourself better you typically will
improve your department if nothing more
than your own contributions to that
department
by making your department or whatever
your security team or whatever it is
you're going to make your organization
better if nothing more than your yield
output you will make your organization
better and by making your organization
better we will make our industry better
it doesn't mean just like that
vulnerability management it doesn't mean
that a month later all the things are
patched
and we've made that objective
improvement
but over a period of nine months a year
it's measurable
you can actually look at and say because
we all started doing this thing maybe we
don't have to keep talking about the
same thing
i am not snow
if you didn't know sorry for the bait
and switch
we love snow we wish her
she recovers quickly and we get her back
and we'd love to have her here again
next year
but with that said
hopefully you got something out of this
maybe it would inspire you a little bit
to just like
i learned something saying khan i'm
gonna go try it at my org
i'm gonna try something and if you bash
your head on it
you might bash your head on it that's
security it's fun but it's frustrating
at times depending on your role
and we i don't know how much
we probably have like a little bit
if there are questions we can run a mic
to you if not we can end a little early
too
or yell out and somebody will run you a
mic
it's not the most questioned talk but
maybe there is some there's someone down
over there i see somebody
i didn't i didn't hear i'm sorry
you still have all the fortinet aps 801
labs
you can have them
uh i'm not here to vendor bash but we
definitely don't use those anymore
ask me afterwards when it's not being
recorded
we can chat further about that
any other questions
all right well if if anything else i
would say
you want to get to network and know
people
volunteered a security conference right
i showed up at first saintcon in 2014
helped running some pieces in 2015
and thankfully john's doing a much
better job of av than i did and really
cool stuff that look forward to seeing
when we get lpl up here thank you
everybody
you