my name is sean jackson
we're talking about incident response
the incident response process plan what
have you however want to say that
and i really do think it's not if
but when so what should you do now
because
if you are hacked if data is leaked if
malware is running rampant through your
environment
you probably have agreements in place
with your customers somewhere on some
level that says you
handle incidents responsibly
and you have a process and you generate
artifacts
and if you say that
and you don't do that
you're liable
and you can be sued your organization
can be sued
so find out what is in your sales orders
and your dpas and what it says you do
like if it says you notify customers
within 48 hours if there's been a breach
of their data and you don't
and they find out
they can sue you because it's in a
contract you guys agreed to it
so you got to know what is in your
contracts about incidents you've got to
prepare and know what to do
okay
i am sean jackson right now i am the
director of information security at
spiff we're based in sandy but we're
actually kind of global and
let's go back to the thing where i
freaked out because they're
distributed
on twitter my handle is tarkus if you're
in information security and not on
twitter get on twitter
twitter is where information security
happens and where
news happens before anywhere else
and i am a
giver of free hugs for most of my life i
have
unwittingly celebrated my own white
privilege and my own male privilege
and i recognize that now and
if you're
whatever color you are whatever gender
you are or feel you are i don't care
i'll give you a hug because i bet you
haven't been hugged enough
all right
okay we're gonna look at a huge priority
one incident
but i feel like every time i've given
this talk it's really boring
it could be me it could be the content
i'm not sure could be both
so i wanted to switch it up and we're
going to go
in reverse
i'm going to show you how this huge
priority one incident went so well
and then we'll talk about what we had to
do in the beginning to get there so
that's the tenant thing we're gonna go
backwards so we can go forwards
okay let's start it's all done
well good job you did a great job of
managing that incident that took months
and now you got a vacation and it's a
misnomer we don't get vacations
so sorry sorry to distract you there
and you didn't get a raise
post
incident the incident is over
so we have a postmortem meeting
we do not point fingers
at anyone
in the post-mortem meeting
this is not the time to say we got
hacked because that guy
you got hacked because something wasn't
working in your security posture
something wasn't working in your
controls
something wasn't working in policy
adhesion
the policy didn't have enough teeth
so maybe yeah that guy
he violated a policy he's going to be
fired
but you didn't get hacked because of him
he got hacked because the policy didn't
have enough teeth to stop him
something like that
it's not
the people's fault
it's your security posture's fault
in the post-mortem meeting you're
talking about the metrics you talked
about how long it took to discover you
were there's a an incident how long it
took to
make the team
mobilized how long it took to get to
where you uh restored stuff
how many people
the hours they were spending you you're
getting metrics on everything
because you don't want incidents to
happen but when they do you want to get
better
again going to your promotions and your
raises you want to get better at these
things because this is
this is the achilles heel to any
organization if they get hacked they
could go down
so you want to get good at this
protect that achilles heel
recovery before we had the postmortem we
restored all the machines
we we brought them the machines we said
this is the way you want it right this
way it's supposed to be okay we're ready
to go okay let's plug it in let's turn
it on it's yours
when you go when you restore you've got
to work with the device owner or the
system owner
and they need to sign off that it's all
good
that it's back where it should be
you can't just stand it up and go
ah
saturday night you okay finally we can
go home so you turn it in you stand up
you plug it in turn it on and they come
back and they say
where's the database
you say oh well yeah we reimaged the
machine um
okay well we can get the database well
i'm up
i'm live now because you plugged it in
and turned it on and there's no database
i've got a weekend full of customers
complaining what are you doing to me
you don't do that you say we think we're
ready could you please run your tests
and check to make sure this machine is
working just the way you want it
because we can tell it's not it's free
of of malware or whatever we
we know what it was we checked it was
infected it's not anymore can you please
check it
you like it
good we're done
now the management part
of incident management
when you're in the thick of it when
you're in the incident you're having
daily meetings
you're going to repeat ad nauseum
every day you're having a meeting
what's happening in that meeting
this is the daily schedule that i
recommend that i follow when i'm in in
an incident
nine a.m and sorry i try not to have a
lot of text on my slides but here here
we go
9 a.m
you have an informal update of
everything that happened
since you last met which was yesterday
afternoon
or overnight because sometimes you have
to work overnight that's going to be an
email it's not an in-person meeting it's
not a zoom meeting it's an email eleven
o'clock coordinator sit up or sync up
that is incident coordinator technical
coordinator and supporting coordinator
those are three individuals if you have
them in your staff
if you don't have the staff to have
those three leadership positions
you are all three
i'm sorry
i have been all three
if you have the staff then you have the
sync up at 11 o'clock and they talk
about
what happened what needs to happen today
what the long term what the short term
they have all those
those
discussions
they talk about is there anything we
need to decide
they don't make decisions
the
coordinator
the the the head incident management
person they make the decisions it's not
the sea level
the c level is going to be in those
meetings but they're not making the
decisions they can advise
but the incident coordinators make the
decisions
so if there's
decisions that need to be made they're
going to have a call
with everyone who is is making the
decision and they're going to put this
on a slide deck what the decision is
they're going to have inputs due at 3
30.
the statuses are due at four
from supporting technical coordinators
that is not decisions that is status
updates and then at 4 30 you have the
status report and if needed the decision
briefs to the instant commander
what are those slides what are those
decisions incidents
this is what a brief would look like
if you're having a malware outbreak
updates all the new things are in red
everything old is in black
so your eye can easily see what is new
by the way i have a copy of slide decks
for malware outbreak and for
decision briefs
on sked or shed
the schedule thing where all of our
schedules are
i put the slide decks there along with
my slide deck
because there's like emails you might
want to
copy
of when you send out the notices that's
happening so this is a brief this is a
status update this is what you see at 4
updates malware response assignments in
red black vulnerability threat
consequence updates previously assigned
task assumptions next steps and efforts
incident commander's input next stats
brief and execute
i colored this tuesday night so this is
not real this is not from a incident but
new things are red
old things are black
you want to be brief
you do not want people to have to read
these things when you're in it if you're
presenting do not read them
you the best status brief is when
someone looks at this and goes
all right next slide
okay next slide
all right next slide everyone have a
good day
that's the best status brief meeting you
can have
so that data should be
terse
brief
informative
just an update of what we're doing or
if it's a decision
you're going to say who the decision
maker is
what we're trying to solve why we need
to make the decision what would happen
if we didn't make the decision and who
is the decision coordinator
then you have another slide the
recommendation action to be taken what
you know
what you're assuming what are the pros
of making that decision the cons of not
making the decision and what would
happen if you're going to make the
decision
so every day during the incident you
have that meeting with that slide deck
where everyone who's involved as wants
to be can go and just see what's
happening this is not confidential to
the organization if you're working on
the team you should know these things
you should see it and you should not
raise questions in it
you raise questions out of it and you
have things to talk about in the morning
or the next day
so that's the daily schedule
9 am email
coordinator sync up
decision conference call inputs due for
decisions inputs for status report the
meeting 430 every day every day this is
how you repeat it and this is how you
make sure that action is happening
if it's not happening it'll show up
within 24 hours in this meeting
this is how you get everything moving
all the time you're working towards that
remediation and restoration of machines
being put back online
so you can have your vacation after your
post-mortem meeting
okay
this is the daily daily this is the
daily schedule there's a daily meeting
at 4 30. there's a daily email at nine
the email at nine is talking about what
happened last night what's going to
happen today and at 4 30 you talk about
what's happened today and what's going
to happen tonight
and what decisions can be made
that make sense
any questions
no question was that question
not a question
what's the hard part
this is
everything else you have to do this is
the containment the eradication and the
recovery and i'll show you a picture at
the very end about how containment
eradication recovery all point back to
the one before it and they all point
back to identification
you could be in an incident you've
identified the incident and you know
what machine is doing it and so you
start to contain it and you start to
eradicate you start looking at how did
they get in and then you see oh i've got
20 machines that have the same problem
you're back to discover so now you're
going to go back to discovery try to
contain those 20. and then while that's
happening now you see something else is
happening that wasn't the same as those
20 because they pivoted and they got
somewhere else you're playing
whack-a-mole but you keep going back to
discover once you're in discover you go
to containment eradication recovery
your primary efforts are on containment
if you know it's there
contain it
stop it from spreading
stop it from getting further into the
kernel stop it from
getting elevated access it them
whatever
stop it from getting worse contain it
and when you find out there's more
things contain it
your primary focus is containment
stop it from spreading
eradication that can be difficult
don't
don't be afraid to
to re-image
if you know what it is you know how it
got in there and you're able to contain
it
you might just want to re-image and get
it back up online because when it's down
you're not making money
and i know we all like our jobs
you don't have a job if your company's
not making money and if it's stopped
because of malware or data breach you're
not making money
you're
looking at a dead end
get it back online as soon as you can
there are there are so many talks you
can attend you can get sans training on
the on
on those things containment eradication
recovery i recommend you do
incident declaration
now we're back to the point where we
know we have an incident it is a big one
it's nasty it's priority one so everyone
on the uh
incident response call list has been
called
so
yes it is really happening
this is the email that i send out when i
know we have an incident
i will say it's a priority one a
priority two that's saying you are being
notified that a data compromise has
occurred
and our resources will be required to
support this incident
that is my email that says everyone that
has an instant response hat on your desk
put it on
we're going
i have a summary of it the justification
for priority one as opposed to priority
two
technical impact the business impact if
you can if you can't tell what the
technical impact is
you need you have a lot of homework
if you don't know what the business
impact is you have a lot of homework
when you know the technical impact and
the business impact every time you have
a conversation with someone in the
company they feel more comfortable
having you there
because you know
why security matters to the organization
a little side tangent
there is a university a stone's throw
from here that i understand if you get
your computer science degree
they're going to encourage you to turn
around and get your master's degree in
cyber security because when you get that
shiny diploma and you move the tassel
from one side to the other you'll get a
job for 80k
i'm sorry you're not
you've been trained but you have no
experience you're not worth 80k i'm
sorry they're lying to you and i think
they're just trying to get people to go
to their master's program
you need to have experience working in
the organization
talking with process owners
and
marketing people
engineering and
implementation and support and legal and
finance and sea levels
you need to know how the organization
makes money
what
what assets
marketing thinks is most important it
might not be the same ones you think are
important
since they're do they do the marketing
that brings the money which one is more
important
it's the one they value
at my last job i i got in with a
young
security guy who was there before me
and he had a list of all the uh risks
and i have a risk registry that uh that
i use anywhere i go that has five it's a
five by five registry
and the likelihood of something
happening i'm sorry we're way off of
incident we're in the homework
it is never going to happen in our
environment
it could happen one day in our
it might be happening in our environment
it probably is happening in our
environment or i know it's happening in
our environment
those the likelihood factors for my five
by five and the other five
is this has no effect on our customers
or the company
this has a slight effect we might have
to apologize to
less than 10 customers and we might have
a slight financial hiccup but it's
nothing to write home about
we've got to contact a lot of customers
and maybe some some
vendors and maybe some individual users
and this is going to take us six months
to recover financially
we've got public marketing statements we
need to say to the world we're
contacting the news
we might have talked to sec
we are in serious financial trouble it
might take a year or two to recover
financially and the worst is we are out
of business or everyone if there's a
customer has been exposed and is suing
us
so those are the five of how bad it
would be and there's my five of how
likely it is
and this
guy had this risk registry and he said
look at these risks i can't get them to
do anything they are critical
and i said how do they affect the
company
he said
well they don't i said yeah the cvss
score is is 10.
it's terrible
we have so many factors in the in in
place to mitigate this
how could it affect the the organization
he says
it couldn't like right so that puts it
in the top corner
stop sending the tickets stop loading
he's like but it's insecure
that i know
it's not an issue
it's not hurting the company you will
get no traction from anyone to fix that
because it doesn't affect the company
you just look like the squeaky wheel
so stop being the squeaky wheel don't
tell them to chase something that has no
value
find out what's of value to them
secure those and they'll be happy to fix
those things
so technical impact business impact you
need to know these things
coordination
conference call to be held at this is
the
question
whoever knows what they're doing most
i'm i'm sending this email
you guys are sending this email unless
there's someone who has more experience
with incident response than you do
if you have the most instant response
experience
take a look at my slide deck on the
schedule page because this email is in
that slide deck so you can copy this out
if you want
yes
the next email the next slide will show
you who gets the email
so the coordination conference calls me
held at it's probably going to be
in the next half hour or something or
people if you know
leadership is on vacation or out of the
office make it tomorrow
um doesn't mean don't start working on
it
send the email and start working on it
uh the date and the time it's been
announced the call number passcode the
incident coordinator
person of contact the approving manager
personal contact and then refer to the
following items or for additional
information you attach to this email the
first email you sent
the incident response plan
um
any documents that are related to it you
have in your your share their password
protected reply back to this email if
you want access to it
who gets that email
the cso the ceo the cto the vp or the
manager of security operations security
operations staff
the
computer incident response lead
legal forensics compliance vp or manager
of i.t operations i.t staff treasury and
cash management public affairs
the computer instant response
triage swat team investor relations
disaster recovery
and
up to you
corporate accounting if your socks
beholden
marketing and human resources
you might cc them
now for everyone in this room
maybe you don't have the cso
maybe you don't have a vp or a manager
of security operations maybe you're just
one of the staff maybe you don't have a
serp lead
i'm sorry but you're probably going to
become the serp lead because you're here
congratulations then i'm sorry
um
if you don't have those
things if all those hats have to go on
your head
wear them
don't complain just wear them
and fill the need as best you can
be honest about your limitations be
honest about your experience
be honest the only training you have was
a talk at st con
be honest
and try to wear those hats
but this is who gets that email
this is also the same group that gets
the first email which we'll talk about
in just a second
remember this is the email that says yes
we're having an incident
when you have the incident you might
have to release public facing documents
there should be a draft
approval and release process
drafting and approval should come from
you
from marketing from sea levels from
legal from
public relations from
developers from anyone who's who's
working on the incident or is being
activated and they know something
the only people who can talk about it
are public relations
that might be marketing if you don't
have marketing and public relations
if you don't have a second you don't
have to marketing and public relations
it's marketing
the only people who can talk about the
incident to anyone outside
is marketing
do not talk about what's happening to
anyone outside this is all
highly confidential
i would go so far to say don't tell your
significant other
just say one of those things at work
that's going to take me
all the time
is happening you grab your go bag and
your sleeping bag and your pillow
and you go back to work
so
a lot of people have influence that on
drafting and approval
the only releasers
are public relations or marketing
that clear any questions
okay
when you're executing the computer
instant response plan
there is a reviewing senior executive
before the talk we were doing an ama
i'm glad we have so much time
um
and someone said should sea levels be
there yes
there should be a c level who is
watching and aware of the entire process
unless you're the cso
that sea level is not going to be highly
involved
they want to know what's happening
but this is not their wheelhouse
this is not what they're good at
but they need to know what's happening
they can make advice they have credit
cards with big limits
if you need to
put people up in a hotel right across
the street
put them up
say we need to have we need people here
on site
but the floor is so hard can we please
get rooms at the hotel
and maybe people maybe have shifts
people are going over there sleeping
during the day coming at night
they have food they have you can get
credit cards with for food
cut back on the alcohol until the
meetings until the incident is managed
you want people focused anyway
incident
commander
again if if there's no one there better
than you at this that's you
you've got the
incident manager coordinator
technical action coordinator and
supporting actions coordinator
they're responsible for turnover
task management facilitation of the serp
the scribe and post incident tasks
that is mean they're going to do them
unless they don't have the staff if they
have the staff these are the people who
are going to have some of those hats
look at the description of these things
it might be technical people it might
not be technical people
it might be
marketing it might be implementation it
might be customer support it might be a
developer
they're probably going to be a security
champion they're going to be interested
in security things you want to encourage
that
technical action containment eradication
recovery that's usually going to be us
and our peers and people at your
organization and it might be a third
party you hire to come help
supporting actions external reporting
communications evidence management
liaison with police and legal oversight
although i'm saying
liaison with police is in supporting
actions
i kind of want to keep that myself
you should have the phone number for the
local fbi
organization the person who is in charge
of
hackers
and miscreant behavior
you want to have a relationship so no
matter where you go in your career you
know how to reach them and they know
where you are and they know what you do
and you know what your organization does
and who might be
targeting them you know look at the
mitre attack
framework and see who might be going
after you
maybe the fbi wants to know about that
so get the local
find out who in the local police is
responsible for for
uh hacking information or hacking
activities
get their information get the local fbi
and then take care of that relationship
and don't let someone else screw it up
and don't let someone else pooh-pooh it
and downplay it
when it comes to police and incident
management when you contact the police
if there's been criminal activity
from anyone could be from russia could
be from a co-worker could be from
someone in
their mom's basement in virginia
if it's criminal activity the police do
not have the same goal that you do
what's the goal the police have when
they know there's a criminal
catch the criminal what's your goal when
you've been breached
get back up and running
those two might be in conflict
they might want to gather your evidence
and make it not available for chain of
custody
makes it very hard to eradicate when you
can't when you don't have the machines
that were infected
so
talk to the police when you think you've
got it all taken care of or maybe you
have it all taken care of
then get all your evidence that you
collected make a copy
get the hashes give them the copies
and let them go catch the criminal
incident notification this is not the
declaration this is just the
notification
this is the email i send when i have
indicators of compromise
that are sufficient to think we have an
incident
now right there i'm saying a lot
you see things all the time at your job
that are weird
every time you see one
if you're anything like me you say is
this
something
or is it
a misunderstanding
is it a stupid process
is this
a bug is this a
flaw in the code
or is something really happening
so if you think something might be
happening but you don't know it's an
incident yet
and let me make clear
you don't know it's an incident so this
is going to tell you kind of where this
email comes in relation to the big one
this is the one that says something has
caught my eye
and it seems credible
so
if you had the hat mothballed under your
desk
just take it out and put it on top of
the desk you might be able to put it
back under the desk soon but get it out
you understand what i'm saying
if
the parties listed below are
investigating possible data compromise
the date and time incident coordinator
personal contact approving manager
source of detection or notification that
data is compromised best you can guess
compromise characteristics what does it
look like
what do you see what makes you think
it's something
what data has been encrypted what is the
technical impact if this is a thing what
would be the business impact if this was
a thing
the next steps you're going to take to
identify is it really an incident
confirm confirmation or denial of
compromise
is there is data out
or not
any obstacles
let's say there was a gas leak at the
data center and we can't get in
there's an obstacle
and then next update and means
what you might need
to get going if you don't have it
already
now is the time you need you might want
to contact a third party incident
response team
you might want to find out what they
charge
you might want to go buy
all the hard drives you might you think
you might need to do backups
and to do gathering you might want to
get all the cables you might want
crossover cables
you might want to get
vmware licenses
you might want to go buy quick go bags
for everyone that you don't already have
with flashlights and notepads and
cheap digital cameras and
gloves and hats because data centers are
cold
so
this is the
prime the pump email
that make if that makes sense
it's you don't want to send this email
too many times you really want to know
we're looking at something that is
really catching my attention and making
me worried
so all the daily fires that come up you
have to put out that's not this email
this email could become wolf
so make sure you have all the things
filled out really well
what would be the business impact if
this was a thing
what are the next steps what are the
characteristics of the compromise
why do you think it's a thing not just
it feels like it but why
what's the evidence that it might be a
thing
and that email will get everyone
it will prime the pump
get them thinking about it and they're
looking for that second email that says
yes we are an incident
we are in an incident get your hats on
drop everything else it's hitting the
fan
that goes to the exact same team
goes to everyone who needs to know who
needs to know
the prompt is being primed
so in your technical analysis that you
put in that first email you need to
answer these questions
what's been affected what data has been
compromised what level of privilege the
attacker gained how did they get access
what was exploited how widespread is the
vulnerability within the organization
were we able to detect it or did a third
party tell us
and what component of the information
security infrastructure failed to
prevent or detect this attack
that's the one you talk about the
post-mortem
still here you are not pointing fingers
you're not saying this person screwed up
this person clicked the link
no
your system allowed the link to get to
their email
that's what happened
it's not the people don't look at the
people like they're the problem
business impact analysis is the other
bullet point how is public safety
affected how many customers might be
affected by the incident what products
or services does this compromise affect
has the organization lost the ability to
control or record or measure or track
any amount of inventory products
cash or revenue
this one is
huge
are we losing money
are we losing data are we on paste bin
are our customers on paste bin
is there any indication this act will be
exploited for malicious or criminal
activity
so
could this be uh negligence
or is it malicious
and who currently knows about the
incident inside and outside if there's a
third party that told you if it was
krebs krebs knows and everyone who reads
his blog knows
now
before that email goes out is something
happening
the iocs oh
someone's clapping oh ten minutes okay
no
where do you find your iocs
from help desk
people go to help desk when something's
going weird
help desk will start to learn eventually
when they bring things to you and you
say oh that's not a thing but thanks for
telling me or holy cow that's a thing
let's go talk to them
they'll start to learn that pattern and
they'll stop coming to you ones that
aren't a thing
don't discourage them keep them coming
because they are the first
people who find out something's
happening
especially if crowdstrike's not catching
it
law enforcement they might tell you
a customer might complain
you might have someone saying i've got
to tell you about something
i found online
or the knock
or the sock
users reporting funny behavior again
that goes to the help desk or they might
slack you
or threat hunting
if you didn't hear grifter's talk
yesterday on threat hunting i'm so sorry
but you missed out on a free sans course
that talk was
one of the best three i've heard in all
my life going to all but all the cons
i've been to
so when they're on youtube if you didn't
see it go get go watch grifters talk on
threat hunting it was mind-blowing
i thought i knew about threat hunting
and i know nothing about threat hunting
after seeing his talk
and in two weeks i'm going to be a
master of threat hunting
because that talk it was fantastic
threat hunting is the best way to know
you have an incident without anyone else
finding out
be very quiet and find
look at the weird things and look over
time get all the logs get all the p caps
watch grifters talk
he told me about incident maybe he's in
the talk but i asked i talked to him at
length afterwards he talked about
there's one organization he went in and
and started doing some threat hunting
and they found four incidents
and there's a fifth one that was found
by a third party
but they found four that had been going
on for quite a while
through threat hunting and no one was
the wiser
threat hunting
but when you look at the knock on the
sock and the threat hunting
anyone else facing a problem with staff
i don't have a knock i don't have a sock
and i don't have anyone else doing
threat hunting
so i have job security
so now you got to figure out is this
really an incident we're talking about
what's the threshold for an incident and
this is important for legal
all of my dpas and my sales orders my
sos
say that we will let you know
we customers i will let customers know
if we have an incident that affects
their data within 24 hours of a
confirmed incident
and there's the catch
i'm saying it's a confirmed incident so
what constitutes an incident
for my organizations if any data is not
being controlled by us that's an
incident or
if i see the same bit of malware
on six different devices
within 24 hours
that's an incident
now i might have one type of malware on
one device and another type of malware
another device
that's not quite an incident that i need
to go tell my customers about
i have my work to do it might be an
incident it's gonna be priority two
so i need to do the work but i'm not
gonna tell the customers when it's
priority one
you're telling customers
so
pci says
you have an incident if you have full
magnetic stripe data or primary account
number and visa says
deliberate electronic attacks on the
communications or information processing
systems whether initiated by a
disgruntled employee a malicious
competitor or must guide a misguided
attacker or hacker intrusion into
computer system where unauthorized
disclosure modification or destruction
of cardhold data suspected this is for
pci if you are pci beholden yes
you need this is this what defines an
incident for you
fortunately for the last
two organizations i've been to we
we third partied all of our card
processing so that wasn't
for those that's not my marching orders
so i can say
if data is out there yes it's a priority
one
but if it's just one machine going
sideways or two machines going sideways
or five machines going sideways i don't
have to tell customers because my
lawyers say i don't have to
this sounds like a
like chicken scratch
but this is saving your customer
relations and the way you can do it is
by putting it on paper
put it in policies and say what an
incident is my incident response plan
has this
not this it says any data or
six instances of malware within 24 hours
the same malware
that's a priority one that i have to
tell customers
do that
save yourself some legal homework
oh
look i did more slides about this
pi data breach or malware outbreak
this is this is uh i copied and pasted
from my policy a malware outbreak is
defined as six or more malware incidents
occurring in 24-hour period involving
the same malware
so that's do i have to tell customers or
not if it's not that i'm not telling
customers might be an incident but i'm
not telling customers and let's be
honest if you have malware on two
machines you got an incident
okay
now we're at the beginning
we have no iocs we just got home from st
con and we're at the beginning
so now we prepare
from what we've talked about so far
do you get an idea of how you need to
prepare
you need to understand business impact
analysis
technical impact analysis
you need to know your physical inventory
your software inventory log aggregation
ids or ieps identity management computer
instant response plan meet and train
members of the serpent leadership
policies you train the staff on secure
practices you need good application
security you need good physical security
you need good network security you need
good vulnerability management sharpen
your axe come to saintcon go to blackhat
go to rsa go to defcon
go to if they're still holding them go
to utah sec meetings
sharpen your acts
get training get certified get better at
your job
incorporate lessons learned into the
serp anytime you have any kind of an
incident
what
allowed the incident to happen put that
back into your security posture fix that
hole
hire and retrain retrain the staff or
identify the vendors for an instant
response
find out who you're going to call if you
have an incident you need them to come
help you
and then threat hunt
again go watch grifter's talk learn how
to do good threat hunting
this i don't know if you've seen this
before but this is the incident
management life cycle
preparation is where you are today
prepare prepare prepare prepare
then you might identify something
then you declare you have a real
incident and you go to containment
and you might go back to identification
you might go down to containment and go
back to identification then you go to
containment and eradication you think
you're getting a handle on it turns out
you don't you have to go back to
identification back to containment back
down to eradication then you're going to
recovery turns out you didn't get it all
the way you go back to identification go
to containment you go to eradication
recovery and then you do lessons learned
and then you go back to preparation
the first two boxes that is your job
every single day am i right
preparation and identification
any questions
we've got three minutes i think
was it good seeing it backwards
i when i was thinking about i was like
oh that'd be really cool to see a good
process
so you can see what you have to do to
have that good process that's the tenant
thing
uh well
it is completely third partied and so if
they have a breach and they let us know
i can pass it straight through to my my
customers and say it's them
and any concerns
i'll say it's them and here's their
contact information for their instant
commander or coordinator talk to them
yes usually in the dpas
you'll you'll see you have to notify
them of anything that affects them that
you if you're if they're a sub
sub
controller
so you say yes this third party is
having a problem there's their contact
information
it's not us if there's anything we can
do to help you let me know and it might
be they say can you help us can you tell
us what's going on for security because
we don't have a security guy and you
know what you're talking about
it might be that
question
oh for anyone who didn't hear that he
was asking about third party credit card
processing if they get popped what do
you have to do she couldn't get that for
the answer
any other questions
really
ye that is so hard to say um
how long does it take you to contain it
how long does it take you to
recover
how bad is it
is it ransomware
can you decrypt it
are you get do you can you just wipe it
and restore from backups
well what if you didn't fix the hole and
they re-encrypt everything
you're not done
you gotta find how they got in stop them
contain it
so it's hard to say what an average time
is
you need to track that as part of your
metrics you talk about in your
post-mortem
and you talk about it so everyone knows
it took us this long to do this incident
it took this long to get to this point
this long to get that point this long to
get that point and you try to get better
and faster
so i'm sorry i don't have a really good
answer for what the average time would
be
there's no average incident
uh yes
ddos attacks can now be mitigated
through
like a waff
uh cloud flare akamai imperva google
armor
in addition to watching all the traffic
they're able to distribute your
application around their different nodes
and that is the best way to stop ddos
they might
like cloudflare will do things with
black hole in your old ip
giving you new ip really quickly and
propagating out dns
another question
go ahead
yeah
well your outside legal counsel isn't
security trained they're still going to
need your help
and you need them
if they are the legal counsel for your
organization they are the legal counsel
uh they need to be involved
they they're going to be part of writing
the the language in the contracts in the
dpa in the so
every attorney i've talked to when they
say
when are you going to notify them
i say we'll notify if it's a confirmed
breach
involving their data and they put that
in the contracts
and they say well what is a confirmed
breach and i said oh
loss of control of any data or six
malware incidents within 24 hour six of
the same malware within 24 hours
oh okay that's defined great
and then
you the attorney is there to make sure
that
you're safe the organization is safe
so involve them
any other questions
advice on getting your arms around
asset management
it's universal
especially today with
shipping devices around the world
um
uh
okay for apple
again i my last two jobs have been
almost all apple
i use jamf
and i buy my devices from third-party
sellers that can put the
jam number
in the sale
so when they open a device it enrolls
immediately into my mdm policies
and one of those is
who are you where are you
who do you belong to
so i can then have a database of all my
mac
users with pc i used in tune and now i'm
using another vendor
better cloud and they have they they
have a better solution than intune that
does the same thing for pc but it's not
as transparent as buy it from apple and
it's already installed
so i get the pc i install it then i ship
it
and that tracks all those devices
um
i can go to the it manager and they can
tell me about all their devices
the problem is
when marketing stands like up a new
domain
and you don't know about it so
you've really got to be on top of
all the things
it's hard and it is really
the primary
object of our job
another question
the ir analysts should be
they are now one of the iocs
they see the things and if they see
there is an incident they should let you
know
yesterday we had two incidents we
fixed them both
we had two events i should say we had
two events
and we localized it and we contained it
and eradicated it and fixed it and it
was good
that should be
reported in a ticketing system or
something where you can go back and see
how many times that happened
that might be indicative of a larger
problem that you're so close to the
trees you can't see the forest
yeah the the lines between
your information security analysts and
your incident response analysts are
blurred sometimes they're one of the
same and if you can separate them it's
still gonna be blurry
uh
i think it is what it is it's gonna be
blurry
sorry i'm not more helpful but
you want to have that interaction
because they see
the iocs
go ahead
you need a sass you need a dast
and you need something look at the apis
uh apis are the soft underbelly of all
applications and a lot of people think
there's no ui it can't be hacked
and that is so not true
if it talks to the internet it can be
hacked
and apis do nothing but connect they
gather data and they process and spit
back out
and people think oh you can't see it you
can't hack that oh my gosh
apis are the door into the database um
so
there are tools that i've been looking
at
i'm standing up appsec at our at my
organization and there's one that i
really really like at salt security
and that does a side car thing in
kubernetes
and watches all the apis that are both
documented and the ones that aren't
documented or the developers just trying
to get them to work
and i tell you when they get when the
developers are doing something just to
get it to work
they didn't secure it
um
does that answer your question
local admin
yep and they want local admin um
you need to have your good endpoint
detection
you need your good ids or ips
you need user analytics
you need
secure
access
because
we will not solve the problem
of them having local admin
they will have it
the
security
is there okay maybe you've heard me
speak before
why do you put brakes on a car
you put brakes on a car
not so you can stop
with brakes on a car she can go faster
if you don't have good brakes you are
not comfortable going faster
now if i'm going to secure a car
i could encase the tires in concrete
and chain them to a metal plate under
the under the ground
is the car functional as a car
no
so
the developers need local admin to do to
their to do their jobs
i can't take that away and be so
draconian to secure it
because they're going to complain
endlessly that i'm making their jobs
hard
i cannot make their jobs hard but i
can't have them be more of a whole so i
need to have more things in control on
their device
more things watching and more things
preventing
edr like i was saying earlier
crowdstrike is a response
if you can get something on there to
stop it from happening in the first
place
that's better
if you can have greater security at the
device
let the developers develop
and and they'll and they'll thank you
for letting them do their job and not
being the problem security that they
have to deal with every other place
they've been to
there is so often an adversarial
relationship between security and
everyone
we need to fix this
your job is not to make it harder at the
expense of the company being able to
make money
you need to help the company be more
secure doing what it does
let it do it
and do help it do it securely don't stop
it from doing what it does or you are
not an asset to the organization you are
a problem and you are checking a box
they know they have to have a security
guy hired but they hate the security
guys they've hired
don't be the thing they
hate another question
so i don't have you heard but he
he puts the developers on their own wild
west domain they can do anything it's
like a little kiddie pool
they can play around with that
yeah kitty pulled don't drink the water
any other questions
another one
yep
i've had that happen
and i've said i am so sorry but i'm
going to overnight a laptop to them
but i have shut that one off it can't
connect to the internet
it is
useless to them they're going to ship it
back to me and i'm going to look at it
and i'm going to work on it i'm going to
try to save all the data they had
i'll try to give it back to them but
they're going to have a new computer
it'll take a day
so
sorry but we're going to pay them for
one day vacation
local
come on in
come on in i got a laptop for you
you give me your old one i'll give you a
new one that's not infected
you're very welcome
so someone somewhere has accepted that
risk and that's when you go back to
legal
and you say i recommend that they use
our image devices with our security
tools because they're looking at our
data
if they don't want to do that i want
whoever owns that outsourced process
that they're going to be responsible if
something happens to those machines and
that data through those machines
they're responsible for that
not me
put that in writing have legal present
it to the person who owns it
and you're probably going to start
imaging their machines
because they don't want to own that
but you're saying yes you own this
and when you do that again
you're playing hardball
you're saying i need to have my borders
i need to secure what i can secure and i
can't let that be a
hole you can punch through my my
defenses
again
don't
hinder the ability for the company to
make money and to do what it does
if they can argue that they can't do
their job because of crowdstrike
find another vendor because that's not
true
where they say i don't want to have your
stuff on my machine it slows it down
say okay get a new machine
you want to work with our data
you're going to have our our software on
it
because we can't let you have that you
can't look at that data without being
secured
and get the lawyers do it
protect yourself make them responsible
and they'll fix it
another question we are so are over on
time but there's nothing coming after
this
okay
oh in the very back
yes the slides are on schedule on sked
i've posted them already
also i posted the two slide decks ones
for the briefings and one for for
decisions and there's more notes in
those slide decks you can see more of
what i'm talking about
this
i think it's going to be on youtube
no on sync con
and that's where i think you'll find
grifter's talk go find grifter's talk
it was amazeballs
all right thank you