glad you came to st conn
we're really excited to have you here
and i'm going to
introduce
our
committee chairperson
and
the founder of saintcon
troy jesup let's give a round of
applause everyone
thank you troy for all that you do to
make this conference as great as it is
we're really grateful
test one two i guess i can say thanks
for the thanks um
and
i really appreciate it it is i'm gonna
if you're okay i'm gonna remove the mask
we're gonna do the closing without it
kick him out kick him out
most of you are without it right now
because you're eating and that's cool
anyway and when you take that mask off
and throw it away after having it on
your face for a week
i just know that many of the committee
members
and many many of the other attendees of
the conference
are grateful that we've done everything
that we reasonably can to be safe while
we've been here so i hope that you felt
safe
and as a committee it's what we felt was
necessary to help people feel safe
enough to come out and be part of a live
event i don't have a slide for that
later so i figured i'd just mention that
right now so
welcome back to saint con this is
probably supposed to be a goodbye slide
at this point
but
we called it in real life because we
were already ready
to get back to real life
and have this conference in person and
so we think that it's been pretty
successful and we're going to talk about
a little a couple of aspects of it and
things and we hope that you feel the
same way
and let's get just right into it
first and foremost the lost and found
it's a really interesting thing that
happens at st con
as we get super excited about the things
that we're doing
and glasses and keys and coats and all
sorts of other things end up being
orphaned as part of saintcon and so i've
got a picture of a few things here
if any of those look familiar to you
they're currently i think still down at
the registration booth and it's
literally the last thing they're going
to put away
at the registration booth but what i
will say is that we're also sick and
tired of storing these things for year
after year after year
and so
as cool as these things look and
everything else we're not taking them
home with us and so
um i haven't talked to danny at the
venue
to see if maybe he'll keep him around so
people know they can come back and get
them i wouldn't necessarily even put
that responsibility on them but
if you recognize it that's where it's at
after today it might not exist
anymore but one important thing that we
found in lost and found
is a gigantic
sparrows lockpick kit
and i'm not going to show it to you up
here
so that you can come up and describe
what it is because
this is probably a very expensive kit so
if you're missing one please check your
bag and make sure you've got your really
cool large sparrows lock pick kit with
you
uh if you don't then i've got it up here
and you're welcome to take it home with
you this one won't get thrown away i
mean if it doesn't get claimed it will
probably end up being
the new lock pick
tools that we seem to go through every
single year because people sometimes
think that brute force is how you open a
lock
all right
the next thing we wanted to do is give
one last shout out to our incredible
sponsors
90 of them are probably not even here uh
anymore they've had booth time and face
time and other things with you but i do
want to make sure that we recognize them
one last time as we close this out by
just saying that
the sponsors are in part the reason why
we have cool things the badge that you
have around your neck the
cool ability to have so many different
mini badges and contests and events and
other things
get funded in part through
sponsors paying us
loads of money not really we're a cheap
conference from our first sponsor
but loads of money to come here and just
sit in a booth and be bored all day long
because most of the people are in
presentations and doing things that are
not necessarily sponsor focused and so
what i would say uh is that if you have
needs in any of these generalized spaces
and that there's a vendor that supports
our conference that's on this list that
you can do business with or refer
business to and other things we we
appreciate that we want them to feel
like they're getting their
balance or their money's worth as it
were uh in investing and helping us with
st con and so this is our list of
sponsors there's one logo that we
couldn't put up on here because of how
the graphic was there but red point
security was also included in our
vendors and sponsors we want to
recognize them as well
and then there's just the conference
hopefully
we
nailed it with the uh the aspect of
so many things so little time that was
kind of our sub theme for this year
we hope that you got super involved in
one thing or another during the
conference this year whether it was the
hackers challenge game which i know
personally a couple of people that
haven't slept
for four days
because they were super scared that just
maybe
zevlag or bash ninja would drop a new
challenge at three o'clock in the
morning for them to be working on
uh and it takes takes them a long time
to do that there's people that come just
to play that game uh during the
conference
and there's so many other aspects so
many other contests events and other
things that people were able to get in
involved in we hope that you went down a
rabbit hole somewhere maybe that's the
best way to put it
i hope you did even if that was the
presentations rabbit hole
and that you learned something and we
offered something at st khan that
increased your ability to make you a
better i.t or security professional in
your field and it's something you can
take back and tweak or just improve
security even if it's just a little bit
in your environment
so the conference
had so many different things
i probably should have been on this
slide for that whole last paragraph of
banter but these are
some of the many things that we had
available this year and we hope that you
got involved
in a few of them
i wanted to just get a little bit more
specific and talk about communities
if you walked around the expo space you
probably saw some of these communities
and i hope you had an opportunity to
interact with them some of them have had
well-developed
uh you know very polished offerings
even though it was their first year this
year
i was thoroughly impressed with with
with what logan was able to do with the
rfid and nfc village he did an
incredible job
[Applause]
and he deserves that praise
uh and but he did an incredible job and
i'll tell you what it's not like he's
the rfid nfc
guru that you
and he's he's only 14.
i don't is that true though no he looks
like he's 14.
um
in fact we were kind of joking the other
day sorry it's a real quick side change
he needs to grow a beard like compu kid
mic is what he needs to do
yeah
anyways
just to illustrate even just one of the
communities they did such a stellar job
even though it's their first year we
often have low expectations for a first
year because most people have no idea
what they're getting into when they want
to run a community or a contest with
saint kahn
but i was thoroughly impressed with that
iot community this was their first year
also
and were we were happy with what they
were able to provide and do
we're looking forward to what they're
going to do next year our lockpick
community is a very mature community
it's been at st con for a long time and
colin did an incredible job integrating
teaching showing demoing giving prizes
and everything else for our lockpick
community and so we appreciate his time
and effort in bringing that to saintcon
this year
the red team community yep yeah
the red team community was brought to us
by uh some of the folks at my current
my current job at the uetn
uh and so we're appreciative of them
bringing red team hardcore
capabilities to
to show you tools on how to pen test and
teach you how to use these things and
actually give you boxes and other things
to actually hack your first machine if
you've never done that before and so
we're appreciative of them and the
hardware hacking community or
yeah the hardware hacking community
jonathan did an incredible job there uh
and the st con widows for those of you
that's kind of the unsung heroes
oh i i'd love to give you a little just
a little bit more detail i think we've
talked about this before but we'll
capture it in yet another closing
ceremony that the saint con widows is a
club
in essence and what it is is it's all of
the spouses
of the committee members
that don't see
their other their significant others for
months
leading up to october
and so we call the them the saintcon
widows and then what they did is they
said the heck with this we're going to
organize our own thing
and so they did and that thing turned
into being our kids night event there's
a slide for that later that you can clap
for but they did an incredible job there
but our saintcon widows have now become
super involved so they can be involved
with their spouses while here and then
off to the side and i'm being
long-winded longer winner than i want to
be here
some of the external communities that
support and offer
staffing expertise capabilities and
other things we have the best security
community anywhere in the entire country
and it's made up of some of these folks
over here the dc435 folks which is a
relatively new group but they smash it
the dc 801 folks they've been involved
for a long time and they're the one you
know these are the folks that are
running these contests events villages
you know communities and everything else
and so we're really appreciative of them
and new this year was the women in cyber
security group and we want to continue
to make sure
that we encourage
[Applause]
females to enter into this field there
is not enough
of that here
anyways for contests there's a lot to
talk about in the way of contests and
we're going to get right into awards for
contests so
let's welcome to the stage our committee
member over contests
lean
[Applause]
i haven't presented so long i forgot how
bright it is up here
contests were amazing this year
always love to see what we can do uh
every year it's it's fun to say
you know i think you made it too
difficult um you probably should dial it
back a little bit it's like no no we got
this and then you all surprise the heck
out of me because it's like you actually
did the thing that we didn't think you
were going to do
and so we'll talk a little bit about
that so um
as we mentioned in the opening the vault
was canceled this year but we did still
have some
safe cracking going on so hopefully
everyone was able to get through and
experience that because that's really
cool it will be back next year so start
preparing
but the vault uh it's it's going to be
an amazing event next year so make sure
you come back and see it so
um i apologize that we couldn't get that
going this year but we have a lot of
contests and this is just uh some of the
the more official ones that we have
booth space for and as you know there's
a lot of contests throughout the con
just in general
um all over the place people are
creating their own contests all the time
so while uh this is um i guess the
pseudo-official list it's not the only
thing that goes on here so always keep
an eye out for that um
and one thing we're going to do because
we're going through awards real quick i
know a lot of people always ask hey i
need more information on these contests
it's intimidating we got a lot of
feedback this year like i kind of wanted
to try that but wasn't sure where to
even start so we're going to do some
hallway con talks
virtually after the con over the next
few weeks months i'm not going to
commit to a time but
you should see some content come out for
that so that way it's you know if you
haven't seen anything in los santos
before and what it's about let's let's
talk through that and
and you'll see some of that content
online so that way next year you can
come prepared because these are amazing
challenges that take a lot of time to
prepare a lot of thought goes into these
and we want to make sure everyone gets
to experience them
so let's first start with los santos 48
participants
this one was fun real quick primer on
this
the premise was you've been taken by the
cartel um and if you were a team there
were two of you one was thrown in the
traditional interrogation room and the
other one was thrown in storage because
there was just no room um but the person
in storage is drunk and so they're
wearing beer goggles um so they can't
see what's going on that's why it's uh
it's kind of funny to watch people uh
try and escape with beer goggles on so
you notice the vent in the floor there
that was for team participation to be
able to help each other escape
so if you can't see you could still at
least stick your arms through the vent
and have someone you know get you out of
your your restraints now the restraints
were zip ties really really difficult
zip ties and handcuffs and you were able
to choose either in front or behind
depending on the difficulty uh change
the the point structure so
lots of great participation
and if you didn't get to participate
just show up next year and start asking
how do you get into this how do you
break out of that and uh keane will
absolutely walk you through it
but you have to get restrained first
so the winners uh real quick um we had
two winners it was a single uh winner
and a pair winner so for the single um
we have austin j
who is the winner for the single run
congrats
um
i'll have all winners we'll meet over
here after as well but uh the only
person to
in handcuffs for the single to make it
out uh in in the time allotted uh for
the team we had chuck and amelia
and this should surprise no one
so um
was it two years running now three years
running i just keep it going so
great job everybody that was a great
event so definitely come out and check
that out next year scavenger hunt this
one was a new one this year
we had a lot of participation and some
really weird submissions um this was one
of the submissions
um anybody know what this is
billings microsystem 1980.
i'll be honest i wasn't born
boo hey hey
really cool submissions this year um so
definitely going to be expanding this if
you have ideas just start dropping them
in discord um but not things that you
own at your home because that's not fair
um so the winners for this one in third
place tfq
took home third
in second place we have professor
[Applause]
i'm sorry
it was really close but but you you know
you know hamster he's brutal
great job hamster congrats hamster for
that one so
uh scavenger hunt definitely a lot of
fun uh so we will be expanding that one
so come prepared and i think we're gonna
be doing a lot more pre-con there so i
apologize in advance
tamper evident uh this one's a fun one
every year because this comes out of
troy's brain
which we all know means that it's brutal
so
lots of uh of interesting challenges
here the the idea here is you're getting
a box with the tamper evidence seal and
it's got multiple layers of different
tamper evident challenges and you have
to get in all the way to the bottom and
this year was an sd card in the bottom
and read the sd card and get back out of
it without uh any
trace of you being in the box so
definitely difficult lots of different
ways to to bypass these temper evident
tags and stickers and and tape
always amazing to see people really get
creative with this and i think the
difficulty is actually scoring because
sometimes you can't tell how they got in
um so that's always fun but
this year
uh the winners
team amathia
[Applause]
did i leave it up there long enough for
you
you got it okay
uh that's and uh dc435
and i think it was just two this year
congrats
password cracking
anybody want to count how many that is
it's up there 50.
50 gpus this year um doing a lot of
crazy things we had 6000 passwords
this contest has been running for a
little while and it's always unique and
creative and we change it up every year
this year it was a mix of a lot of
different things memory dumps password
lists etc
so really creative it was an on-site
component so you were given access to
use these gpus so if you don't have a
cracking rig at your house for some
reason
then you were able to still participate
and that was the entire premise of the
community and and the contest was we
want to get more people involved engaged
and and realize how easy some of this
stuff is so a lot of a lot of
participation here
a lot of crazy things going on a little
side note um i think it's pronounced uh
the augie
augie file encryption is kind of a newer
file encryption standard right or final
groups and tool
that was cracked by three people here
this year so
very fascinating stuff again it's it's
one of those hey let's throw it in we
don't think anybody's going to get it
and you
get surprised no matter what every year
so we have a couple of different
winners here
we had an on-site version of this and an
off-site version of this so the off-site
winners
we had echo in third
apparently they didn't want to be named
and bastion first
and then the on-site winner
is the yushi goblins
and a surprise for this year is this is
for the winning team
fun little badge there
hacker's challenge i will not be
speaking about this because the man who
puts in so much time
deserves
much much time to talk through this this
is an amazing contest so please welcome
to the stage mr galvez
[Applause]
thank you for playing hacker challenge
this year
i love doing it for you and i'm glad
that you enjoy it so keep it up
this year's game rocked uh
nearly a full third of the conference
played in a meaningful way
like more than
one entry so that's awesome
thank you so this year's hackers
challenge was amazing um many of you
dedicated
your entire conference to it uh the
as was mentioned in uh the
a little bit earlier uh there were
definitely people that stayed up uh just
waiting to see my little icon and
discord to go to sleep so that they
could go to sleep
but we'll get started um
and introduce some of these winners
in third place we have a new entry that
i have not seen on the game board before
and that was lego clone good job
in second place a
return winner
factor
he blew out one of those most difficult
challenges but wasn't quite enough to
hold first place and our first place
winner
to a man that well deserves it and i
don't know if he got any sleep at all
this year was santiago
[Applause]
congratulations santi you will win the
hacker's challenge black badge and
this
amazing
hand-built trophy
for the hackers challenge black badge
winner
with the black badge the soul black
badge award at st con this year you will
be welcome back to saint con with free
entry for life and uh we oh awesome
thank you
santi good job
thank you everybody that played hackers
challenge
the game was amazing
here's the scoreboard for the top 15 and
the scoring chart you can see as they
battled back and forth for that first
place it was a fierce competition
and uh my hacker's jeopardy introduced
near the end of the game i gave a a fun
shake-up for those couple like four or
five thousand points um but thank you
for playing and uh the hacks challenge
game board will be live with everybody's
scores if you'd like to see where you
placed
[Applause]
all right it is he exits the stage give
zevlak one more round of applause for
his incredible effort
if your name is in the top eight
of this list
if you're in the top eight please make
sure that you see me afterwards
yeah we've got some special
um mini badges for the hackers challenge
that we did in the black badge motif it
doesn't mean the same thing as a black
badge but
it absolutely does give you something
unique for being
one of your top eight folks
all right
let's finish this or let's get this
across the finish line here let's talk
briefly about some of the saintcon
events
that we do here
during st con we want to make sure that
we bring
diverse
fun and interesting content
and so what we do through this
or through this
thing that we're trying to do i guess is
bring a couple of different
organizations together uh ideas thoughts
and this year what we decided to do
again
uh was our
or
excuse me i'm stammering a little bit
um is to do our family night activity
again and it was super well attended and
it gave all of you hopefully you took
advantage of it an opportunity to bring
your family your children to come and
teach them how to pick locks and to
solder and do all of the same things
that you're doing here but at that kid
level and the widows
rocked it and did an incredible job they
deserve a huge round of applause and if
katie is somewhere here
if she'll just stand up and get
recognized for her efforts in that too
[Applause]
it's absolutely something that you'll
see is a common occurring theme for many
years probably to come as long as the
widows are willing to put
in that time and effort to do it we'll
give them a break whenever they want i
mean they do so but other activities
that we had those of you that
participated and came over and just hung
out the hack in the box event this year
was absolutely lit we held it over
across the street instead of in an
airbnb clear across town and there was
lots of people over there
if you were over there in the evenings
you probably had a great opportunity to
sit down and talk face-to-face and maybe
even get drunk some of you with
lock-picking lawyer
and such great place yeah thank you
a great place to just get involved
get more or sorry meet other people
in the community and get involved with
our community a lot deeper the tinfoil
hat talks i don't even know if they
happened or not or if they're even a
thing but but somehow that's a thing
uh and then
the store uh this year we had no idea
i guess i didn't have any or much of an
idea
uh one of the things we always get asked
is hey can i take one of those hoodies
or can i buy one of those hoodies off of
you and
what we've always traditionally done
with our apparel is we use those as our
thank you gifts to our committee members
and staff members and other people that
put in a ton of time to help make the
conference work and i guess it was
always been an untapped
resource for us to maybe sell it to the
rest of the uh you know
attendees and such so this year i don't
have any official fun or numbers and
things like that but we've sold well
over eight to nine thousand dollars
worth of store merchandise which we had
no idea what happened
[Applause]
and so thank you for all of that
but what i would like to say along with
that is that you i hopeful i hope that
you found
that the prices and things that we were
charging in there were super reasonable
our goal at that store is not
to make any profit
uh so what you probably found is a
leashi tool that you can go buy on
lockpick lawyers covert instruments
sells for about 80 bucks and you were
probably paying 85
to help cover our shipping and some of
the logistics and other things just so
that we could take in sales tax and the
things that we need to do to be legal
and appropriate but we are not there to
make any profit it the saint councillor
will never be a profit center
uh for saintcon as long as i'm in charge
of saintcon
because we want to make sure that you
have access to the tools and other
things that you need
and that we just provide the opportunity
for you to get them conveniently while
you're here
last but not least
our leadership track how many of you
participated in one session or another
up there in that leadership track
okay that's a lot of hands we appreciate
that that the leadership track has kind
of taken on a life of its own sometimes
it's one of the toughest things for us
to coordinate with because it's
almost all completely done in a vacuum
by a different project manager and they
bring and they try and coordinate and
fit into how we do things at st com the
best they can but sometimes it's a
little bit rough but they do an
incredible job of bringing in good
content and speakers and things and they
do it fairly independent from the
conference
but they bring in these types of folks
to speak at that higher level that
executive level
in most cases
so that you feel comfortable for those
of you that want to to bring an
executive or your boss or somebody else
to saint con so they can see things
where they feel comfortable and where
they're going to feel community in that
leadership area and not necessarily have
to go down and pick locks and be like
i'm kind of bored this is dumb this is
your con thing not mine so
uh we're going to do leadership track
for at least another year
and next year the leadership track is
going to bring in some really big names
uh and so we'll we'll we'll release
details and information about that uh in
the coming weeks and months uh but uh
it's gonna be one of the places to be
next year for sure
but we have such great events and things
there
there's not a ton of them but there are
definitely those events
um
comment over here no
i thought i heard somebody say something
okay then uh let's get this across the
finish line here by talking a little
really quickly about man or mini badges
y'all kind of collected many badges i
hope
those are kind of becoming the olympic
pins of saintcon
and matt lorimer over the hardware
hacking community or the communities
and such only got to collect two he said
and and here's the here's kind of a
funny real quick side story is i
designed about 20 of the many badges
that are out there for you all i'm not
looking for praise there there's some of
them that i don't even have one of
because i gave every single one of them
away so
don't worry about me you don't have to
bring me one and and pity give me one
back i'll just order some more from
china and it doesn't matter when they
get here
because normally when we do order from
china we're really hoping uh that they
get here in time there were some that
slid in just right at the last minute
this year but we had a ton of mini
badges we hope you collected some of
these these are some of the more
official ones but this is not a complete
list and so hopefully you go home with
some really fun and interesting things
to explore and solder and and and put
together
and we're actually looking to inc or to
expand
many badges next year
if you haven't had an opportunity to
look on our youtube channel compu kid
mike but last year did an incredible
video or a training on how to build mini
badges
and i'll be very honest and say i mean i
said this in the earlier talk so if it's
repetitive i apologize but before this
year i had never designed a mini badge
in my life
and so if i can do it by watching a
couple of videos getting my youtube
university circuit and mini badge
or you yeah
you can too it is approachable it's not
super hard
and it just takes a little bit of
thought and a little bit of energy and
you can come up with some incredibly
cool designs and things i'm sure you
probably have oh wouldn't it be great if
i would love to see what that mini badge
looks like next year so please we this
is going to be a thing for
decades to come and we're encouraging
you to bring your own and do some
trading and use that as your your your
method of
introducing yourself to others and
trading pins and and building your
community
uh and then the last couple of things it
would not be appropriate for us to not
talk about the badge but i am not the
one who is qualified to do it so will
you welcome compukid mike to the stage
all right
coming up yeah uh professor plum if
you're here
and come up here
so i hope you all really like the badge
this year
um
so real quick did any of you guys finish
building the machine all the way
yeah awesome it's a good number of hands
well done
and i'd like to say a huge thank you to
professor plum and sodium hydrogen who
helped with coding this year it was a
huge help and we didn't have to reflash
badges this year
um and i need to thank all the people
who helped with assembly we spent days
and days long nights putting all these
together because they came in really
late
so thank you to everyone that helped
with that
the code for the badge is up on github
the link on the back of the badge works
now i made it not private anymore so you
can all see that
um
and i wanted to say thank you to all the
people who made many badges this year a
lot of people came up and brought me hey
i watched your video and made this mini
badge it was amazing thank you to
everyone who made their own
and
if any of you have not assembled your
mini badge
extender board here's a picture this is
how
it goes
yeah it kind of works if you put the
connectors on the back of the board but
not quite and there's some weird badges
you can do to do it but
yeah follow the silk screen on the board
did you guys want to say anything
no okay
and last thing i have a handful of laser
shark mini badges left come see me after
if you want one thanks
[Applause]
he does an amazing job and as we talked
about in our opening ceremonies
we are honored to have the same person
that is selected to do the illustrious
defcon badge
as part of saintcon in fact we had him
first
and i'll tell just a real quick story if
that's okay um not to extend time but uh
it was
we start planning for saint con in
january
on most years
uh january february time frame and i
think this last year was march
that i get this call from compukid mike
and he says hey by the way
we put in
a response to the call for badge makers
at def con and we've been selected
and uh
i i'm not sure if they even knew how big
of a deal that was
but
they've had a really super long year of
badge life
because they literally went from march
through august on defcon and then from
august through october on saint con and
they have literally not stopped
badging
and so
our deepest appreciation to your time i
know that that take took a lot of time
from their family
and
all of the other things that you should
and could be doing differently but we
are deeply honored to have you as part
of our community and to have you as part
of our bad or have you as our badge
maker and i think we've got him
committed to next year i probably would
be surprised if he's not
but i just wanted to make sure that the
applause that you got a moment ago is
echoed with my
uh sincere thank you
for all that you have done
[Applause]
all right we're almost across the finish
line here last few slides
it would i would be uh
yeah let's just say it would be silly
for me to not mention and talk about our
incredible keynotes this year
we felt like it was time
and well let me step back story time
again just for a moment
keynotes are something that sometimes we
at st con struggle with
we're this really cool community con
it's fun it's interesting and
ironically or maybe it's a good thing
saint kahn is somewhat well known in the
cyber security hacker community is a
conference that sort of exists and maybe
it's in utah
but when you call up somebody and you
say hey can you come keynote for us at
saintcon they're like
what is that
and so what i what i'll say is sometimes
we struggle in trying to tell our story
we don't bring in often big names
because we're this small con we don't
have a huge two hundred thousand dollar
keynote budget that we can pay
honorariums for and things
and so when we get to have an
opportunity like we did this year to
have somebody like the lock-picking
lawyer
come in and talk in fact i've got a
slide for this i should be talking about
during the slide but to have somebody
like the lock-picking lawyer come in
and
essentially donate a lot of his time and
energy and and expertise
to come here and do something that he's
not done at any conference ever before
uh and have him be here is a great honor
for us and we're scared to death on how
we
up it again next year
so what i'll say and kind of as we go
through and close this out
if you've got ideas and if you've got
connections
we're interested in in making sure that
we make those connections now we're
starting to get more and more
connections i mean many of us attend
defcon and black hat and we get some of
these connections but sometimes it's a
little bit tough but we were honored and
it was a great pleasure to have the
lockpicking lawyer with us this year uh
he's not here he left early this morning
maybe i mean he might still be in his
room
um but
and nobody here's the thing there are
now
way more people who knows what he looks
like
uh because he he he felt so comfortable
with us and our community
that he didn't feel like anonymity for
this group was an important thing and so
if you met or ran into him around the
conference he's extremely approachable
he'll talk to you about anything
but we got to sit down with him for
hours and hours at the heart or the hack
in the box event
and such so we are we extend our
appreciation to him hopefully you're
seeing us in in our closing ceremony uh
reference
uh lpl we appreciate you being here and
being part of our conference you're part
of our community forever uh and you're
welcome back anytime
[Applause]
and then we have james pope
our you know again a real quick story
time on this one i think i mentioned it
at least a bit in the opener
this was a keynote that was on par with
any other keynote that we've ever had at
saintcon but it was prepared a couple
hours before it was given
because we had snow who
unfortunately got sick and wasn't able
to attend but we felt like we couldn't
just do it with one keynote we had to
have a second one and james pope being
one of the smartest men i've ever known
in my life and a great friend and just
incredibly talented we lent or we leaned
on him just a little bit to go outside
of his element and to deliver a keynote
and he did it spot on where we
appreciate him being involved and being
one of our keynotes this year as well
lastly or we're really close to the
finish line by the way lastly we would
love to thank our venue now
the the interesting thing about the utah
valley convention center is just like
almost any other event that happens here
we end up paying money to be here
and such but we have never in all of our
uh
are
all over the state of utah'sness of this
conference
had such an accommodating
and overly excited group of people
than the utah valley convention center
they tell me all the time we really look
forward to your event each year this is
the funnest one that we do
it's got the coolest people the nicest
people
but at this point i want to say thank
you to them for their partnership with
us because when we offer drinks out here
for you all to just take when you need
one or want one
that doesn't come from
that comes from a partnership that we
have with the venue that's willing to
give those to us at a price that makes
it reasonable for us to be able to do it
it's something we've done traditionally
at st con for a long time they made it
possible and it's not just that but it's
so many other things they're so good to
work with so danny i don't know if
you're in the room or not but we
appreciate you and your staff
and providing this venue for us and
making us super comfortable in being
here
[Applause]
and if we grow too much and we start
doing way crazy hacker things let's talk
you know i'll try and smooth things over
as much as possible but we got such a
great group here and then lastly and
certainly not least
is we thank you the community
as i mentioned before we have the
coolest community of any
state region whatever here this
community you make it possible for us to
do something like this and it's you
and your involvement and your desire to
be here and to be part of our community
that keeps us wanting to do this year
over year running saint con isn't an
easy thing at all
but it it's something that we continue
to do because we know that our community
needs
wants and benefits from this conference
and so thank you to you for what you do
and being partici or participating in
our conference we will be back next year
um
so we're going to be back here probably
in october i'm not going to give you
dates yet because they're not finalized
but we'll be here in provo at least
another year
uh so and that's i think the end of the
slide deck so
thank you very much have a great rest of
your year and we'll see you on the next
one