[Music]
thank you and you're at the hose cloud
Society talk today and just want to talk
to you a little bit about how you can
expand access inside of cloud
environment on engagement and then also
like some mitigation steps for that so I
am right whom I currently work at
Adobe's and I run the red team they're
at Adobe's digital marketing business
unit they mostly focus on analytics as
product or website then I used to work
in the department defense and I used to
also work doing defense at Homeland
Security so right so cloud right it's a
nebulous term and hopefully by the end
of this talk it won't be so nebulous
anymore but he can't get quite diverse
quickly you know seems like you know
there's so much cloud now you know
there's one cloud provider or them
there's another cloud provider and then
there's another cloud provider there's
more cloud providers and I think the
only thing that's really guarantee is
that there's always going to be another
cloud provider coming out right so see
for the day right so while each cloud
provider has differences if you can
learn the general security concerns with
the setting up the infrastructure and
running infrastructure in these cloud
providers and then you just have to
learn the little nuances that are
different between the providers and I
know everyone talks about cloud talk
about brand-new everything's different
all your old problems go away and I love
the perspective that a lot of things can
be better right if applications are
written around it but I mean a lot of
things are like both like the way that
we've been operating the data centers
for
8.now so I just want to show you this is
kind of the old way it's very simple
probably not even accurate but you got a
developer you write code he checks it
into sound repo and then you have like
some physical server like a chainsaw and
then that's going to push this towed out
to the production servers whether that's
like a web server or a you know
something to research policy initiatives
there's not like that but oh yes I know
maybe you send your dildo there for this
like a standard build order now for
pushing code out for like a production
data center you with help from my dad
then you know you pretty much have that
same flow now in the cloud but you're
using services so you're not managing
the boxes and services to expand out and
down as needed to scale with your with
your application your product or
solution all those things so you can
still have developers pushing code to
github or some other code repo and
that's you know using some type of code
deploy service which then deployed out
you you know lambdas services in AWS
which are kind of like dynamic web
servers or computers to get spun up on
people across Web Services and then you
kind of have this storage in the cloud
area of that s3 bucket for Amazon where
like persistent data is going to be
stores all right so is that you know
family services don't have persist and
Forge so and these are all basically
just eight guys you're calling to
interact with these various services and
then you know you filled admin right so
in the old model you have an admin he
might though he might administrate like
an 80 boss or an LDAP server and then
all the rest of boxes and an enterprise
more or less trust a 80 or LDAP server
and so he's still able to get to all the
servers and admin these various now
individual servers propagated under
and in the new cloud environment still
have someone who has admin access it
might be the same developer right which
is also developing the code but instead
of you know logging into servers you
just logging into this web GUI
management console and from there he's
able to manage each of the services oh
so you know you feel if you combine that
developer and admin maybe like a DevOps
model there's no separation of duties
and you know he's able to kind of go
everywhere and touch everything right so
obviously you know this edge is
compromised and you know that they take
some theories
to talk about you know this isn't just
like figment of my imagination a
scenario I mean this is actual
intrusions that have happened and have
bankrupted company so the first thing is
there's a is a guy postings as Stack
Overflow asking I got a fifty thousand
dollar AWS bill what what should I do
now right so someone got ahold of some
of the secret he was using to manage to
date Amazon services this is decided to
spin up a bunch of additional servers
and racked up huge bill for them so you
know there is a he wasn't able to go
through a resolution processes Amazon do
it the bulk of the bill is apparel if
you're sloppy with your security what
happened to you and if you're running a
very large amount of servers leveraging
a lot of those services not even notice
[Music]
okay and then I think code bases is the
quintessential example what not to do in
the cloud base they built their entire
web application in Ian Amazon compacted
up to s3 bucket I've had ami images in
Amazon and an attacker was able to
compromise API keys that they were using
and they emailed them and said hey you
know if you don't pay up we're going to
just destroy you know your company they
weren't really detailed on how they're
going to do it but they did take up and
attackers went in and they deleted
and then they terminated all their money
servers the resources and it essentially
bankrupted the startup and one day right
so I mean this is like a real scenario
that could happen if you're not careful
with year you know you just set it up or
there's something else in in in a closet
Vidor okay so we're just going to talk
about initial access so in the cloud
providers there are secrets or API keys
and really you want to get your hands on
these atiq and there's many ways you can
do that I'm going to show you some
pretty I think they're amusing example
right but you know you could take the
traditional path of you know finding a
vulnerability on the server and packing
that server and finding the correct in
the file so you know the first thing is
people will actually mine through open
source
you
oh right jacket you know really all
you're going to do is like Xenophon you
you bunk you bought and installed AWS
tool and I'll put a copy of these slides
on SlideShare and I'll tweet out move to
them afterwards so that way you know you
want to write it down a little bit right
and you're just as pretty standard if
you admin AWS services you'll probably
Airy happy
goals at all and I'll just kind of show
you how to use them so s3 bucket this is
where you store files in Amazon so you
store like images just or static content
maybe you backup files maybe you create
your own like OS image then you upload
it to s3 and you could like watch it as
so any time you know you want persistent
long-term storage you might use an s3
bucket so so people actually host
websites straight off the s3 bucket and
if they do that you can actually just
you know team the domain and you'll see
in the response that comes back like hey
this is s3 - website and then it's going
to give you the region that it's in
Amazon's actually located good and
you're just going to want to make note
of that region information there's only
so many region about 12 inches right I
mean you could in future steps just get
pretty far region
but you know this is going to tell you
what to do okay today let's get me so
you know that's not even creepy happy I
just think the domain is all tied to the
next three so um so s3 bucket can be set
to be world readable which just
basically means like if we go to a
website and you see that index of and
just the field listing of all the files
in there there we you can set up your s3
bucket to be exactly like that and so if
that is the case you can actually just
use this
AWS s3 command and it will list back all
the files that are available then you
can try and download each file these
definitions
and if you browse to humming this world
you
all right so you got secrets you got
your box set up now you want to leverage
those actually be something useful
instead of AWS so the first thing I do
is I configure profiles for secrets
usually when I'm doing engagement and of
getting as much as a ginjury goes on and
get more and more secrets three to view
us as I'm more more successful so I just
Trent set up different profiles with
different names and that way can switch
between an easily track of what what
secrets I'm currently using so you just
from that yet of your computer command
to do that and then I usually just cat
that there's a dot 80 of us older who
has a user's home directory I usually
make sure it looks good at people Iraqi
you know also some time to read the
spaces around that equal sign so I can
keep them - tricky really quick okay so
this is kind of the Who am I put away
for for AWS so you somehow got these
secret you hack server you found them in
it open source repositories but you
don't really know these these are like
do they go on through or what to do or
which their business it again access so
you can just use this SKS get color
identification API call using command
line tool and if you get a little bit
information about whose equations are I
need to give you one want or I can you
just help back up right another
technique for finding out more
information about who you are is by
calling I am I am is user management
capability and secret natural
capabilities inside of AWS so you may or
may not have access to it I mean
realistically you should not probably
ever get access to that just hoping this
trivial but
even if it doesn't work it will air and
in the air it will tell you a little bit
of information about the users you're
currently running at so once you know
that the correct or right once you do
that STS identification call my first
thing I want to do is know am I being
log right there zombie laws I need to be
very cautions about every API man that i
issue and you know lest I get caught
right or deviation is over so it
you
just some logging off though we're not
being reported found the secret because
you're packing a server he's the local
source repository but now we just want
to make sure we don't think it's out all
right but I got two weeks left on this
engagement I just want to make sure that
I'll be kicked out or detectives before
it's over so that way I can you know
provide back a holistic picture to the
top somewhere closer very here in this
environment so I think this is a cool
technique you can actually if you have
an API you have secret cooking that use
for like API access you can actually get
a session token' say hey get session
token' and this will give you a
completely different set of tea tricks
that are good for 12 hours so then you
just set a cron job that gets to secret
every 12 like but not right like every
10 hours as long as you know this secret
this session secret seems to work then
you'll be here to get more and more
session features so there's like some
little nuances that they get annoying
with using this like a little bit more
difficult to set up and there is some um
you want restriction any data left you
can't do that the main super hand but
this session people it is I don't know
really how to view them but eight of us
and mock sure they are to vote maybe
there's a way to do like that now I'm
not really aware of it so yeah go ahead
the default is 12 I think you can go up
to 15 right you're on your issuance of
it and I just visit meatball you can
actually there's another switch that
suspect by the time that is good for and
there's documentation on it so you could
go larger I just didn't want to like if
there was a way to enumerate session
tokens which I'm not sure there I just
didn't want to stand out from anybody
else's session so good okay all right so
these is pretty stealthy and and then
you just kind of set it up in AWS file
similar to the way you set up a preview
secret but my names are slightly
different and then from then on you know
use that session token' profile and then
you can keep you interactive the
services no or the stable future another
way to persist is every user that's in
the console can have two AWS keep its
associated account so most users will
just issue one API secret and then
they'll continue to use that for local
operations and if they need something
that's more application specific they'll
create another account so just physics
of that API fault so you can actually
just go through list out all the users
if you have I am access and then pick a
user that you think is a good candidate
then add another session another secret
to that users and then by adding that
secret to the user you know hopefully
that will go unnoticed by the user not
people the parent in the web GUI I mean
if the user goes in I'll probably just
think they issued it and easily you can
also just rate up add another user
alright cool here I'm adding the user
and Ryan
every actor okay oh yeah I see you has a
get a user then you can add a key to the
user then you can add a password to the
user in this scenario then you can
actually log to that pretty web GUI so
there's really no reason any cousin
attackers can be honest man all right
cool so if you can get back to let's see
secret has access to s3 buckets and
usually what I'll do is I'll dive into
that three buckets and I'll try and find
more secrets right you can find more
secrets that have access to I am which
is like user management or have access
to to which is instant management
I collect and set up these servers in
the cloud then you can actually just
spin up a brand new server inside their
their VP C which is like their private
network and then you can just SSH into
your own server that's now running
inside their their environment then you
can do all your plastic you know pen
testing techniques from that server
right so why it wise is better right
because you know one you have full
control of that server that's inside
their private network now you can do it
as a school information that you want to
you can now access probably a lot more
services very accessible just like if
you were to get access to a server side
of data center you can now start hanging
up and probably find like on
authenticated reddit databases or other
like memcache servers things like that
whole wide range of services which a CL
group from the security groups from the
internet are probably denying but once
you're inside that trusted BCC and
inside that trust network you can now
start your packing in more and more
servers right and of course when you
hack another server you definitely go
and try and line through it to find more
secrets right so you kind of go fold it
right do traditional time testing you're
doing
AWS interactions and then you're just
kind of using each other to each other
in the loop and you know this will like
appear like a new instance is in their
list
so I mean you probably want to list the
instance
first and make sure there's a bunch in
the region everything if there's like
you know you know there's 20-plus
servers in the regen weekend up one more
I don't know like what difficulties that
Facebook and some of some of the AWS
account settings under certain sensors
right and then I just want to talk about
the metadata turbit I know this you know
they talked about before but something
that I often run into people and they
are unaware of
so there's actually an RFC it just
basically says for these cloud providers
there's a magic IP address 159 I can
address and based off of RFC you should
be able to be read as IP address only
from an instance that's running inside
the cloud provider and then get back
information about the incident so this
is crucial for a few reasons like one if
you ever get code execution on an
instant inside of AWS you definitely
want to queries and metadata service and
enumerate as much information as you can
out of it you can basically just do that
by making curl request right here's a
metadata service to some types of web
vulnerabilities if they are occurring on
an instance in and Amazon are needed to
be have their criticality used up right
so if you think you know do you kind of
like an open redirect on a web
application you get a web application to
make a call out on another IP address on
the internal network and then return
that result back to you you can actually
have it reach out and go to this 159 IP
address and then return back the results
of the metadata service to yourself very
infrequently but it is possible you
could find secrets actually stored the
committed a service which to turn you
back secret so
I shouldn't happen but there is like
some Federation data that can go into
instances and boost them up and climb
back data can be retrieved in the
metadata and it really deceive the
metadata survey labelled from any
instance you just curl the 159 Effie
dress and then get abused oh right pri
and then if you that works and you want
to go back to the documentation and just
pull list of all the URI and they can be
memory for each one of those pull back
all destinations but um but like I said
before metadata service is actually not
an am something there's like an RFC and
more cloud spiders like a sure aim
digital ocean and Google compute has
once you are actually trying to build a
similar text service so you get code
execution on any of those providers you
should be able to query that same 159
FPGA and then also gain some information
about the engine so the problem is
Amazon's implementation of it's much
more mature than other cloud providers
from my testing and Google's has a
little bit additional protection you
have to us by like a particular host a
nerd when you're pairing it so that
might give you some the web redirect
issues like you would be able to do it
through them but but yeah in a sure you
can query these two API calls is the
only two that I was able to find and it
gives you back some really limited data
not really soul but what is cool in
Azure is there's a W agent folder and in
Linux underbar live W agent if you go
into this directory you can get a lot of
information about the incident and
possibly then decreased access
additional resources inside of azure
and you have to be route on the instance
here we do this inside of Asher
so that's a little bit better than the
Enzo setup but it's definitely some key
gated amount of it
okay cool
so we got access to someone AWS now we
want to expand access right if we PSIM
you know we obviously we probably just
add a show user logins web GUI equal
there but you know a lot of times what
customers feel like ok great you got
access to that or like where's like push
the credit cards like where's the
production data how do you know how
would you go from that to see you
actually like all critical data right so
you can take snapshots with your servers
inside of AWS and if they've done this
previous and you're able to set up an EQ
image you can actually just mount those
a shot as another hard drive if you
mount them as a hard drive then you can
start mining through them for like you
know at stage private keys and finance
page private keys and you're inside that
BTC then you start education to the
boxers you'd be surprised hold off these
snapshots so there you got to be
thinking every Aldous comes back you
know physical file
you know files on disk and I mount those
and I read them and if so if I'm more
secrets or and I use those taxation of
offices access boxes totally shares one
and I just want to talk about a pretty
extreme technique I do not recommend
this and once you're in a desperate
scenario but is very attractive right so
I call this top part hard boot technique
alright so let's just say there's a
server in easy to you got root
credentials to AWS but you still can't
get inside the server right this is fun
up you can some big strategy that you
don't have access to right and those
aren't like retrieval
rest of it one thing you could do though
obviously this is get an effect
production is you can actually just get
access to manage it is that you can say
hey shut down the server when the server
shuts down you can actually mount the
pivot card drive from another ec2
instance then you can actually modify
that other other production servers hard
drives like address H key to the remote
to that servers are good instance and
then unmount it and then spin back up
the server right you know obviously this
is going to make this assignment very
angry if you're sitting down their
production servers but I mean unless
they're implementing some has a full
disk encryption at the cut like inside
the instance of a cloud provider which
everything done yet which probably
should need to stop this type thing and
the right you're going to be able now
activation as a production server and
pretty much access a walk X right so or
you know you could have pulled it off we
have the image right but relatively you
know want to heat the time that the
curve is off the lowest amount possible
if this not because that is right so
yeah it great
yeah can you create a snapshot so that
you don't have to do a hard vote right
oh I think my experience of that is you
can't create snapshots a public server
is shut down and then how hard they do a
snapshot but a good technique is to go
through em another technique I don't
know if I suppose we talked about or not
is actually a lot of people will create
am i right and you can actually share am
I to another Amazon account those an
attacker you just sign up for another
Amazon account you can actually go into
their images and share their instance
images with you and sometimes the image
will have you know secret surprise or
key sort in it and that will allow you
to you know access that type of data
which would be another technique
although a lot of times I see cloud
providers doing is the image ami just
has a bootstrap script the bootstrap
script
reaches out to like a salt or puppet
server it is enough salt and puppets
over kind of push all the secrets onto
it at that point
so you know sharing am I haven't works
great for me but you know definitely
exactly okay so I'm just going to talk
about mitigations for a second and then
I'm going to a question so right so you
know the biggest thing for me is just
single purpose secret right so if you
want a secret to access RDS a relational
database
you
the secret using the Bluth account
that's types that you want to create
another town and then login to another
town and then create secrets associated
that account at a bare minimum reasons
that you want to do this one route
secrets generally have access to do
everything inside your Amazon instance
so those get compromised they can do
anything
another tidbit about roof secrets is
there's a technique where you can
actually use these secrets to buy stuff
off amazon.com and fill it back to the
root secret credit card number so I mean
I haven't actually seen it like an
attacker do that but you know they don't
like just wasting your money on a tow us
they could actually physically ship
themselves off with it and then the
other thing is rotating secrets very
frequently right these are not things
that you know you want some static and
what they're forever like I said it's
not if it gets from Isaac when it's
gonna get compromised when that happens
how quick can I roll the keys and you
know how along with RT good or and then
another really big thing and there's a
lot of solutions now to actually do this
using you know puppet like a black box
like solution allows you to do this and
it's secret management right you don't
want your secret city in plain text
inside of your cozy goes like yet and
that's the end so you need to come up
with some type of software that's going
to have encrypted blob inside there and
those gets encrypted on the production
servers because you know developers will
eventually leave in a day or you know
will get access to code repo closed do
and if that has access to production
secrets and they know there's high
production environments people online
okay
that is a presentation so thanks for
coming out if does anyone have questions
ok I'll be up here if you guys have
questions or concerns or want to throw
stones I mean Roybal
thanks for coming out appreciate it