[Music]
okay well welcome to Lake City I am
thrilled to be back at b-sides I'm
actually a local here in Utah and I feel
very fortunate how many how many folks
are not from Utah on here
a handful cool no talk to some folks
from Vegas LA I know Leslie coming up
all the way from Chicago so great to
have you here I am always thrilled and
excited by our security community I'm
always amazed at what's been built out
here I'm I feel privileged to be invited
to be a part of that and I'd say really
the security key to me is kind of all of
you sitting in those seats so I just
want to thank you for doing such an
amazing job or for such a small area we
have an awesome community so awesome to
be here what I want to talk to you guys
about is a little bit of credentials and
it we've got a problem
we have a credential problem ladies and
gentlemen and I think you're all aware
that I think we you've been in security
community for any period of time you are
well aware that credentials are a
vulnerability
however I've got this sneaking suspicion
that most people in our field actually
don't know the extent of the problem
it's incredibly complex the windows
authentication system and I think
frankly it's almost too complex for
someone that doesn't dedicate a lot of
time to fully understand
I'll give you example I've done you know
over the last couple of years probably a
hundred plus interviews for folks on the
CrowdStrike team these are top tier
security professionals and I've walked
away from almost every single one of
those interviews largely with the the
sinking feeling that my god you know
this person really doesn't understand
credentials it's one of the common
questions I ask because I think it's so
important and very rarely will anyone
nail sometimes even the most simple
questions and that's a problem and this
is both red teamers and blue team's
amazing I expect kind of blue team or
sometimes we kind of get get our heads
down you know
kind of got our artifacts we look for I
was especially surprised of red teamers
not truly understanding what they're
constantly taking advantage of they
certainly know that they're stealing
tickets or tokens and they may be
reusing those in order to move to the
environment but commonly they don't know
why the tickets or tokens are there and
that's going to be a big problem because
we're going to see in this presentation
there's some good mitigations coming
Microsoft the sleeping giant has finally
woken up maybe and started to try to fix
some of these problems and we're going
to have some you know pen testers red
team is and hopefully attackers which
are going to start stumbling because
what their old-school techniques that
work every time all the sudden are going
to stop working with any luck right we
can only hope
but the idea this presentation is really
to kind of get us all up to speed on
credentials this is actually something I
sat down I was just so kind of down just
with with the level of kind of
understanding of this but I just sat
down and kind of wrote what we're about
to see actually this is a part of a
class that I co-author for sans is 508
instant response class and you guys will
be some of the first ones to get a look
at it and so I also wanted to get you to
the slides so you have kind of all the
the bulk behind it but we're going to
talk about credentials now think about
the common attack cycle I'm an instant
responder kind of bitrates I'm more blue
team and so I'm constantly looking at
what I call funnel points looking for
areas where I can actually sift that big
haystack and actually find where the
attackers are right hundreds of
thousands of endpoints where do I know
they're going to be what I know they're
going to do that I can learn to track
and in my experience or really in my
opinion probably credentials are the
most critical part of any attack I can't
think of anything more important and so
let's kind of go to the cycle a little
bit here yeah so an attack our first
gains a foothold on the network this is
almost never going to be the place they
want to end up unless they get
incredibly lucky they're going to have
goals that extend far beyond this first
foothold this first user workstation
we're going to have to somehow get
credentials where they can move around
that environment the great thing about
Windows is that everything is tied to an
account
to give you an example Computers
themself have accounts right registry
keys are tied to specific accounts right
everything so if you don't have
credentials you're stuck so very
commonly if they're already admins well
they're ready to rock and they can kind
of dump credentials if they're not admin
yet they're going to have to do some
sort of privilege escalation attack to
get there because one of the key
components of credentials and windows is
there's nothing native that can just
allow you to get them you're going to
have to use some sort of attack
technique some sort of tool and as we go
through these slides I'm going to try to
point out kind of the common tools that
we'll see attackers use all right so
they're going to dump their first set of
credentials now similar to the all the
data they want not being on this box
it's very unlikely that all the
credentials they want are going to be on
this initial box so they're going to
take whatever they gather here and with
any luck they're going to be able to
move laterally through the environment
they're going to start kind of expanding
their influence throughout the
environment now everywhere they go this
is very early in their tax cycle they're
going to as you might have guessed
dumped more credentials you're going to
see them over and over and over again
dumping credentials as they move through
the environment tramp I've seen
attackers send out a schedule task to
150 systems just to dump credentials
from every system and bring them back
the goal of course is that one of those
credentials is going to take them to the
next level and so they're going to
continue to dump credentials until they
achieve some sort of what I think
Microsoft nicely calls domain dominance
this means total ownage right once you
get domain admin now you have new unpaid
admins in your environment and you get
to deal with all the fun that comes
along with that and so this of course is
the the primary goal of the attackers
early attack cycle and eventually they
are going to get to a system where
they're going to achieve those it's
almost inevitable how many pin testers
do I have in here don't be shy I know
we've got you guys never want to
self-identify all right of my pen
testers when's the last time you did not
get domain admin the new one not get
domain admin in their last attack you
scoped was that the problem
so you didn't do ain't doing pen testing
in a Windows environment yes yeah it's
so funny I was talking to someone it was
actually a computer network exploitation
individual that actually was formerly at
the Fort Meade NSA and I was like ah
okay well tell me how you simply do your
attack so you can is specialize on in
UNIX systems you know what's your what's
your initial kind of entry point when
you get there well we first go to the
Windows Network and we gather
credentials there inevitably some of
those credentials we'll be able to reuse
in the Linux environment like that is
not very exciting right that is not what
I expected you to say right I want to
hear some ninja techniques you know kind
of attacking Linux so bottom line is are
eventually going to get their domain
admin and this is where they're finally
going to achieve their goals and in my
experience a dedicated attack group
likely achieving domain admin 24 to 48
hours into the into the attack but the
good news is the techniques that they're
using and what they're gathering a
relatively finite set so these are
things we can watch for these things we
can detect and if we get lucky and
detect it we are very early in the
attack cycle we can stop it well before
they can accomplish their goals all
right my pen testers
has anyone ever written a 140 character
pen test report anybody 200 characters
yeah anybody raise their hand I'm going
to switch over I'm moving to the red
team right but I will bet you your 50
page pen test report doesn't really say
much more than this typically all right
this is pretty much the way it always
goes right get an initial foothold spear
fish attack get access dump credentials
move around get domain admin and get
paid all right now there is some hope on
the horizon I will tell you and you
think about the XP timeframe total
security disaster all right there are
basically nothing stopping credential
attacks in that world we get the Windows
7 sort of not much we got user access
control which really just upset users
more than anything but not you know user
access control can frustrate some
firts to gain credentials you know the
whole idea of the UAC was being able to
have users run as admin but not allowing
kind of all their processes you know to
run as admin even even at that kind of
level so kind of restricting kind of
that lease privilege or enforcing lease
privilege
the fortunate thing UAC is not a
security boundary and if you do some
searching you'll see there are plenty of
UAC kind of attacks that allow kind of
easy in runs around it right but at
least causes attackers to work a little
harder to get that initial first kind of
admin rights to dump credentials
about the only other good thing that
came out of Windows 7 was something
called managed service accounts now
we'll come back to these but this was
the idea of recognized effective service
accounts are a huge liability in your
environment and managed service accounts
will basically allow you to
automatically set very complex passwords
on your service accounts and rotate
those right now it's I think every 30
days by default and this is all managed
to Active Directory the initial
implantation of it was totally kludgy
and almost impossible to use at scale
there's a new version called grouped
managed service accounts which came out
subsequently much better and much more
realistic so you'll see that's one of
the things that I'm going to point out
the in as one of the most important
things you start thinking about now
between Windows 7 and Windows 8 we had a
little thing called mini cats who sort
of that yeah thank you I know that
almost every in the room is heard about
you know some of the most evil kind of
malware we've seen in recent memory and
Mimi Katz did something that kind of
punched Microsoft in the face basically
did something that no one thought was
even possible which is start to pull out
things like clear text passwords
and so when Windows 8 really 8.1 rolled
out Microsoft finally you know kind of
woke up and said my god we've got to do
something about this this is insane
and so we get a lot of great mitigation
to come out in the 8.1 world right so
that idea of now the removal of those a
lot of those clear text passwords from
memory assuming that they're not added
back you know through some stupid
configuration the admin is done we get
some better account restrictions there's
a much easier way to restrict local
accounts from being all eldest indicate
over the network this is going to go
reduce the attack surface for things
like pass the hash tickets or sorry
that's the hash attacks and so this is a
this is a big win a really easy thing to
kind of get implemented protected
processes almost all of the credentials
helping tools will deal with attack else
as you often inject into else ask to get
access to those credentials so now we
have a bility to set protected processes
to greatly restrict who is access to
something that frankly no one should
have access to we get into things like
we stricted admin that's an idea of
trying to reduce the attack servers by
not leaving your credentials everywhere
that admin has actually interacted with
your environment you know right now the
current state is basically shotgunning
domain admin everywhere that admins ever
been and that's totally a fail so
restricted admin starts us down that
path of maybe reducing that attack
surface and then probably the most
important thing we'll talk about the
entire deck the domain protected users
group this is a huge win this is a new
group that comes out starting with
Windows 8 that allows you to now put
your highly privileged accounts inside
of it and it greatly reduces the
capabilities of those accounts to read
they're really sensitive tokens hashes
kind of around the environment now so
we're going to see we're going to see
that kind of reference as we go through
as a excellent kind of mitigation piece
it's a no-brainer to do you know it'll
make your admins job maybe a little more
difficult you have to figure out some
ways for instance delegate tokens they
won't be able to just single sign-on to
third-party systems but it is a huge win
from preventing attackers from getting
access to those credentials another good
news is these were so popular that most
of these have now been back ported to
Windows 7 so you really have no excuse
to not implement some of these so you
might be familiar with the past the hash
patch which didn't really prevent past
the hash but certainly added a bunch of
these capabilities that's now been back
ported back to your older systems then
finally in the new world we live in
Windows 10 I'm sure you're all
implementing Windows 10 in your
enterprise right now
and when we get there we do get some
additional capabilities credential guard
here is probably the big win this is a
truly kind of revolutionary piece
finally we get to a point where we may
be able to prevent the access to things
like caches and tickets basically what's
happening is they're taking that L SAS
process moving into a protected
hypervisor so all of your kind of
credentials now are in a very protected
space like an enclave with very very few
functions that can access them I'm not
saying this will never be compromised
but certainly it breaks all current set
of tools out there the only problem is
you need certain hardware and certain
software to get it up and running but
this is something that's going to be a
potential big win finally for us to
finally stop attackers from getting
those those easy wins remote credential
guard is an update to restricted admin
that's a better implementation not just
admin but any account again protecting
any accounts that are authenticating
over the network right through things
like RDP and then finally device guard
is basically an upgrade to a blocker
whitelisting capability that will
prevent certain binaries from running so
this implemented correctly could
basically break again all of our known
attack tools because essentially doing
application whitelisting so hope on
there ivan as we're going to see we're
severely outmatched
these mitigations are not going to be
the Silver Bullet for us but what I'm
going to do is reference these as we go
through with a thought of trying to talk
about how we can at least make our
attackers life's more difficult ok so
who's been in security more than 10
years Thank You Han all right of those
ahead your hands up who remembers
talking about hashes over ten years ago
yeah this is a gimme right we've been
talking about hashes forever right we
started with land man hashes those have
been largely deprecated although there's
probably environments that you guys are
working and where it may still be
present now we're at the in T hash we've
known the NT hashes are incredibly
insecure for I don't know a good decade
or longer right no salt totally
vulnerable to things like
pre-computation attacks and rainbow
tables these are one of the first things
that attackers will try to dump when
they get on a system right it's been
this way for probably 15 plus years
maybe two decades attackers have been
going after our hashes now the
old-school techniques when you know new
old timers were getting
your initial training was to dump the
hashes and do what crack them right so
you dump them crack them we still do
that a day because it's fun we still
like hackers but I'm telling you we
don't even have to do that anymore all
right so hopefully you've heard of
things like pass the hash where you
don't even need to crack the hash
anymore you're nice
25 character passwords so long and
complex it makes your fingers bleed when
you type it in it doesn't matter because
if you have the hash we can simply
replay it through the environment and
I'll syndicate with just a hash one of
the biggest vulnerabilities that's come
out as you can see tons of tools down
here that allow us access to these
hashes you know kind of the the rogues
gallery here now one of the interesting
things I've seen in the wild is that
while we get a lot of custom malware you
know we're all dealing with
nation-states now or highly resourced
criminal syndicates with obvious
capabilities to develop their own
malware one of the most interesting
things is that the one tool that most
attack groups are not implementing are
the credential dumping tools these works
so well there's just no incentive for
them to go build their own and so it's a
you know you took at any attack I think
every attack I've seen in the last five
years probably had me me cats involved
in it right you just got to learn to
look for that type of attack and your
role along your way all right so we get
our hashes right now one thing I think
the security community has absolutely
woken up to is this idea of where our
hashes are being stored I think finally
we're realizing this is an important
concept so you know just as a quick
review any interactive logon your
credentials are going to be in play
interactive logon smeeting at the
console RDP you do a run as alright when
you do those and you're authenticated to
that remote system your credentials are
now present on that remote system for
the length of your session if an
attacker happens to stumble upon that
box they can easily dump your
credentials and now they're off using
your credentials for evil so what we
have to do is we have to take the
knowledge as a security community we
have to filter that down to the admins
where it really matters I think most of
us are probably good with this but I
know that most admins are not most
elements have no idea that when they RDP
to assist them with their domain admin
creds the
the domain creds are now going to be
present on every mo system right even
worse than that they make stupid
mistakes now so when you RDP you can
either close your RDP session alright so
you can actually log off or you can do
what just X out and close the client
right when you X out and close that
client your session is still present on
that remote system you might have run
into this sometimes you'll run into a
box like your own you'll go into work in
the morning and you'll go to login I'll
say do you want me to log out the admin
because they were I in your system
overnight maybe patching it and they
just closed their RDP client they didn't
actually log out of your box your their
credentials are still present on that
system we've got to retrain well we got
a retrain our admin and we've got to
take the keys to the kingdom out of
their hands until they can actually use
it effectively map so lots of different
ways probably the most effective way on
this on this chart PowerShell when you
get to PowerShell remoting all of a
sudden it's no matter what you're doing
if you open up a remote terminal using
PowerShell that's still a non
interactive logon it's about the
best-case scenario using the best of
Windows authentication and you're not
sending your credentials all over the
place so we've got to train our admins
to do this more reasonable alright so
how does this work GG sect dump a very
very common tool so often see this
actually in this example this is a very
common place we'll see it what this
example was done on a domain controller
so what we're seeing here is at the top
we're elevating our privileges from
admin up to the system account so a lot
of these tools require actually system
level privileges to actually do the
injection kind of into L SAS to actually
pull the credentials out and then we're
simply just running the tool ji-suk dump
and dumping the output to a text file
the contents of text file look like this
this won't surprise anyone we get a huge
collection of hashes but remember what I
just said I just said that I should only
be seeing the hashes on the system of
the current login sessions this is
actually something that wasn't always
the case
I think XP service pack 2 started to
enforce that where they try to clean up
the sessions when you close them out but
we're seeing hundreds in this in this
example there were hundreds of hashes
available on this box
and the reason is because what I just
mentioned this actually happen to be a
domain controller the domain controller
is leveraging hundreds of current
concurrent kind of logon sessions
through that environment and this is why
you'll see a lot of attackers taking the
very risky move of dropping to your
domain controller and running you know
pretty evil malware on it you know if
you're a good attacker stay away from
the domain controller right this is the
one place that admins will actually kind
of look at and monitor but sometimes you
just got to do what you got to do right
and so a common technique you'll see is
dropping over the main controller
running a tool like g6 dump now I've got
you know 100 plus hashes on there the
odds of one of those being a highly
privileged user very high alright so
once I get these hashes well now I can
go to a tool like Mimi cats or
Metasploit or your tool of choice and do
what we call pass the hash attack all
I'm doing is essentially feeding one of
those hashes I just retrieved to my tool
and as that to authenticate now I'm
actually authenticating as that user in
this case we yanked the helpdesk account
so now I've got the hash and I'm able to
start to traverse or laterally move the
network as that helped us account
literally one line using mimic acts and
now in that person this is a classic
example what we call pass the hash
attack take the hash replay get through
the environment to accomplish my goals
anybody seen this in real life anybody
done this I hope we've got some pin
testers you must certainly have done
pass the hash all right how do we
protect about against this simple this
is all you have to do seriously so go
back and just stop attackers from
getting admin rights and when you figure
out how to do that please email me tell
me how you did it it's basically
impossible right now sad so sad but this
is just something we have proven as a
community we're just virtually
impossible at this point but if we could
all of these attacks I'll talk about for
the rest of this deck
I actually require admin rights so if we
ever got to this magic land where we
could enforce privileges well we'd be we
be well off to a head start on the
attackers but assuming that that's not
possible
there are other things we can do
certainly stop spraying your most
important accounts to the environment
get your admins to stop RT peeing with
their domain admin crits right teach
them about how to properly terminate
those sessions think about if you're in
a Windows 10 or 8 world in place on the
like restricted admin or remote
credential guard which Beth means even
if they already pee with their domain
admin creds those won't be present on
those remote systems they're protected
now with these new mitigations obviously
when we get to Windows 10 we can start
to prevent the ability to get the
credentials themselves if you have
credential guard running on a system no
current attack tool can actually dump
the hashes so you don't don't worry
about them passing them because they
can't get them and obviously things like
that the main protected users group
that's again going to be probably the
most important takeaway of the entire
talk today which is if you can get your
most important accounts in that those
also aren't providing those hashes
around your network and that can easily
be stolen all right hashes I think
hashes are the gimme here tokens where I
see a lot of people falling down on this
is just a surprisingly complicated
authentication mechanism in Windows and
so the idea of a token is that when you
log in to a session a token is created
the token as your your security
identifier it has all the groups you
belong to it has all of your privileges
now this token is reused all over the
place every process that you spawn and
your session actually gets a copy of
your token right this is how these
processes know kind of what your levels
of privileges are all right you'll have
things like a view attached to like a
file share something like that very
calmly that process attaching will need
to do something that we call impersonate
your token you'll need to load your
token up into their process space in
order to basically restrict or keep keep
all of your privileges in place to make
sure that you can't exceed those rights
and privileges that you have so this is
an idea of impersonate
is used all over the place in Windows
they see something else taking your
token and reusing it as you now as you
can imagine if a standard Windows
processor service can do this so can an
attack tool and what our attackers do is
when they get those admin rights they
get on the box they can basically look
at all the open tokens in the
environment or on the system that
they're currently on grab one and start
reusing it they can basically
impersonate you so very commonly this is
used for privilege escalation all right
your admin currently you want to be
domain admin so I can find a machine
that a domain admin is on or didn't
properly terminate a session on I can
steal their token I automatically become
domain admin maybe the simplest way to
achieve domain admin rights kind of in
the wild this also allows us to do
things that maybe hashes don't allow us
to do let's say I want to create like a
user account I can't really do that
through a pass the hash account or pass
the hash attack but having like a token
impersonation I can and probably even
worse and by far the most biggest
liability of tokens is that certain
impersonation tokens can be what we call
delegate tokens delegate tokens are
essentially single sign-on
they allow you to authenticate to remote
resources using your token so if you
have a domain admin token that's a
delegate token basically now you can
move around the environment using that
account so it's a huge problem you see
we've got some pretty classic tools that
allow us to do this this is what it
looks like
so me me cats has a one-line command
right so we're currently sitting here as
a tea as a key Dungan user all right I
run the very simple command with a mini
cats elevate domain admin but it does is
search through all the tokens on the
current system if it finds a domain
admin level token it will immediately
grab it and load that into memory for me
so I can start to interact as that user
and you'll notice in this case look at
the impersonation down at the bottom
this case we found a domain admin token
that had the delegation of capability so
now we can immediately start laterally
moving as users I now essentially owned
the environment so extremely common will
a to to achieve that next level or that
next rung up on the credential scale
you know how many how many of my pen
testers have actually still wanted token
in the last year anybody you have scary
yeah so I know we probably have you know
almost every pin tester is probably done
token stealing last year how many of the
blue teamers so I assume the rest of
your have actually found token stealing
in your environment it's really hard it
leaves very very few clues you'll see
some event logs some you know
essentially some chemist indication
events start to show up but actually
identifying the fact that a token was
stolen unless you have really really
good auditing you're basically blind so
again our best-case scenario is going to
be to essentially stop these tokens from
being available so yes if we could have
proven admin we'd be alright so I mean
that's not first cases stop the madness
I stop these interactive sessions from
being kind of using highly privileged
accounts we just can't do that anymore
right yeah so again something like
remote credential guard when you have
that in place it actually does not push
your token to that remote system simple
way so even if you can't get to some of
the new hotness like remote credential
guard in Windows 10 well-protected users
group you can easily go to Active
Directory and for your most important
accounts just mark them to not delegate
right that essentially killed that well
it doesn't kill it still allows on the
system impersonation which you can still
get kind of the next rung up from a
privilege escalation but it prevents you
from you under use that token now
remotely just what most attackers want
so that's a big win and then certainly
if you can get two protected users group
so if you can employ that in your
environment that by default does not
push tokens actually all tokens in that
group are non delegate by definition you
can't change it right so you
automatically get like this wonderful
kind of group of protections around the
accounts in that group all right
so hashes tokens right let's say that
you do everything right right you are on
the ball you've already implemented
credential guard in your environment
right you are high-fiving your team
right you get to actually have a weekend
for a change right so the attackers get
on the box they can't dump tokens they
cannot dump hashes you you've locked
everything down there's no delegate
tokens you got your hashes in in your
protected enclave of credential guard
and sadly all attackers have to do is go
and dump something called caster
controls and they're off to the races
again
now there's another super old-school
kind of authentication mechanism all
right how many have heard of this
probably a lot more than tokens right
this is something we've known about
forever the idea is that in a domain
environment usually your accounts I'll
Finnick eight to the domain controller
the only problem is what if you've got
all your Knights laptops in front of you
and you're not currently connected your
domain controller how do you actually
log on with your domain account well to
do that the account credentials has to
be stored someplace outside of domain
controller all right where this is
stored is actually something called
cached credentials basically allows you
to use a domain account offline by
default ten of these are stored some
brilliant individual at Microsoft
decided with that the 2008 server
release to upgrade this the last 25 for
the chills beam cache now I want you to
think about this all right first of all
how often should a server not be
connected to domain and that's pretty
darn rare right also on your laptops do
we have a lot of shared computers
anymore
how many people have actually logged
onto your laptop in the last year I said
you know I'll be you and you and you and
maybe the helpdesk right why do we need
to cache 10 credentials that's often an
historical record of everyone who's ever
logged onto that box including the
domain admin who set it up for you three
years ago hopefully they've changed the
password since then but if they haven't
their credentials are still archives on
every machine that they've been to so
cache credentials are are a huge
liability all right
the good news is they are not in the
same format as your traditional and
Killam hashes so they are salted so
rainbow tables don't work against these
this is one of the few places where
actually having a really good password
policy can actually help you because the
only attack against these is they have
to be correct
they can't be replayed like an entail
and hashes that's the only kind of
saving grace here but check this out so
one of the trends that we've seen
recently is moving away from dumping
credentials on a standard box so
dropping your G SEC dump or your Muni
cat store whatever that is because
obviously we're starting to look for
that we have security tools that know
what all of those tools look like and
we're catching that so a common
mitigation to that from the attack your
side is basically to come and just dump
your L SAS process or in this case dump
your registry hives and take them for an
offline attack that way I don't have to
run my nasty tool on your box I just
have to figure out some way to get your
Sam and security hi and I can do
everything offline without triggering
your intrusion protection system
whatever that is so this is a pretty
cool little project just written in
Python and so as you notice the top we
did a PW dump from the Sam hive now
those are just going to be the local
accounts all right those won't be a
domain account so I'll just be what's
stored in your Sam your local accounts
notice there's not many same thing same
project did the cash dump tool now
running it against your security hi and
look at everything else that pops up
these are what you really want these are
your domain account and actually in this
environment one of those was actually
the domain admin and so now we've got
the domain admins crashed cached
credentials all I have to do is go back
to my cracking rig practice using MS
cache - in John the Ripper you're curios
and with any luck they'll have a weak
enough password that I'll have domain
admin tomorrow
all right how do we prevent cash
credentials well a lot of you will see
guidance like turn your class potential
to zero sometimes a good idea NSA has
had some guidance to tell people to do
that a lot of your DoD guidance comes
out to four or less depending on if the
system's mobile or not you can tweak
that just be careful
zero is not always the right answer the
reason why is that it's not always just
your personal account that's being
cashed things like that computer account
sometimes good cashed here and so if you
drop it to like only one cash credential
well you might edge edge out the actual
users credential or even things like
smart cards sometimes a smart card
authentication is actually two different
authentication or so two different
things get cashed and that can override
or kind of age out the actual person's
credentials that need to be cashed all
right so you could have a lot of brick
systems if you turn this down to low by
far probably the best option just have a
good password complexity you know
usually I laugh at the complexity rules
because get things like pass the hash
for the totally useless this is one of
the few areas left where it still
matters and then of course if you have
something the protected users group by
definition those accounts don't cache
credentials and remote boxes so another
big win seeing the trend here get some
users into that group all right so cast
credentials super old-school something
maybe even older than that LS a secret I
will tell you this is very old school
but I've seen more red team's get big
wins from this and almost anything else
when we've talked about LS a secrets
we're not talking about user accounts
now we're actually talking more about
service accounts and so what happens you
have things like services remember a
service has to run without user
interaction all right so if you set up a
service to use like a domain account
well that domain account has to somehow
authenticate and the way it up indicates
without interaction is it has to store
the credentials locally and so what
happens let's say you have your backup
software and your backup software
requires a service being run across your
environment as some sort of highly
privileged domain account right so they
can access all the boxes to back them up
well that's awesome but what you just
did is you just shotgun that entire
highly privileged account into the LSA
sequence of every machines that service
runs on and wonderfully once you can get
access to the machine you can dump it
out in plaintext the particular dangers
here of serving accounts is they are
rarely changed right
you have probably have certain accounts
in your environment that haven't been
changed in three or four years people
are scared to change them because you
don't know what it will break right some
admin three you know three generations
ago set something up it's still running
so just keep it as is these are often
also very highly privileged accounts and
so this is kind of the just the syndrome
and the kind of worst case scenario
coming to light with these service
accounts so very very simple these are
stored directly in the registry with
admin rights you can do something like
this dump out all the LSA secrets this
case this is a big win this is the
sequel server we pull out a relatively
strong password that sequel server
account and now we can start to
authenticate on that around the network
now I don't know about you guys but I've
actually seen environments where people
have been told to run their sequel
server using domain admin rights and if
that's the case you just own the network
with one command another thing you'll
notice on this this is actually
PowerShell another trend we've seen is a
many many tools are now being rewritten
to to work in the PowerShell environment
you might be familiar with power sploit
this is a lesser-known framework called
nishang which is also a pentesting slash
offensive power partial exploit kit does
an awesome job of pulling LSA secrets
out all right so how do we protect about
this well this is where your big
takeaway you're probably the second most
important takeaway of today go audit
your service accounts alright these
things are such a liability in your
environment right if you do one thing
this year go back identify all the
service accounts identify which ones are
running as domain accounts because
they're by far the most vulnerable I'll
figure out if you need them forget if
you've changed the password recently and
if you've done all of that start to
audit those service accounts right this
is a wonderful place when you're hunting
to your environment identify malicious
servers account usage can be very easy
consider these sort of accounts do the
same thing that backup service probably
authenticates type 3 log on throughout
your environment so your server
environment right if you start seeing
that accounts indicating with a type 10
like an RDP
type authentication that's a god-given
clue that you are owned right go find
that and kill it and so you've got we've
got to wrap our head around these
service accounts if anything just doing
this will prepare you for when you do
get that intrusion almost inevitably
you're going to end up doing a full
passive reset of your environment at
some point in your career if you've
already gone out and identified well
your service accounts are your 50% of
the way there you know the level of
hardship that it puts teams on to
identify these is just astonishing so
get ahead of the game would be my
recommendation
and of course if you can Microsoft has
have a solution for this called those
group managed service accounts and this
will provide really strong passwords and
roll them over every 30 days by default
all right so you guys are probably
thinking Chad I know about all that
right tell me something that's I don't
know right this is you're boring me this
is all old-school we've been doing this
for 10 years and you're right
although I will say it 99% your
environment this stuff still works
ridiculous but this is was we're
supposed to fix it for us like Kerberos
I remember that Kerberos comes out of
MIT this was going to provide some
sanity to our authentication mess and
windows way back in in two days now
unfortunately as an idea in theory
Kerberos is pretty darn secure right it
has wonderful things like the ability to
prevent replay attacks you know there's
a timing mechanism in Kerberos but
you'll notice in the implementation in
real life is that it's been just largely
riddled with holes in order to make it
work effectively it has an example yes
you can actually prevent replay attacks
in Kerberos but what happens is that
everything in your environment is tied
to an account so it unde AIT's the
domain controller with all these
requests for accessing you know every
single object in the environment and
simply you can't do that the procedures
performance goes kind of
nose done all right so what happens is
you see here you often have tickets that
are valid for 10 hours so I get a ticket
I can reuse that ticket for 10 hours
which shouldn't be possible in the kind
of the Kerberos Beck right there's all
these kind of you know vulnerabilities
have kind of been introduced there so I
would say that while this is probably
the most advanced piece of Windows
authentication it has the biggest
vulnerabilities it's the typical kind of
the more complex it is the more holes
are in place and traditionally like the
last couple of years
Kerberos has just been under fire right
we've just seen how it sirs being aimed
at curbs and blowing giant holes into
here's the simplest so just like pass
the hash well if I can get access to a
ticket which is kind of the core unit of
Kerberos I can just pass that ticket in
the same exact way we saw passed the
hash it's all I have to do is in this
case we're running as a standard user to
Duncan here all I have to do now is just
dump a ticket from anywhere import it
into this computer and in this case this
was the domain admin ticket and now I'm
that domain admin all right so I can
just take a ticket and move it around
the environment import it and it's off
to the races you can see now I must
syndicated as that in this case domain
admin all right so that's the Mimi katz
tool it's way way more complicated than
passed the ticket so pass the ticket is
like level 1 if you get into things
called like over pass the hash this
one's clever so if you start to run into
issues where maybe pass the hash isn't
working you could actually go and just
take the hash supply the hash to the
domain controller and get a ticket back
and now you've got a ticket that you can
then use to do things like pass the
ticket
let's call this over pass the hash
relatively new technicals come out
called Kerberos ting this one you know
literally I had to sit down and almost
came to tears when I saw their amazingly
the way the whole Kerberos environment
is set up is that any user account can
request a ticket or service ticket for
any service in the environment the
domain controller doesn't know whether
you have privileges to a certain
computer or certain service right it
says yeah here's the ticket provide this
to that remote
and it will authenticate whether you
have access or not the only problem is
that ticket is encrypted with the empty
hash of that service so basically I can
request every service every account in
the environment get all of their empty
hashes back nicely
Kerberos provides them to me take them
offline find one that's a domain account
with high level privileges crack it
offline and I'm back in the game
ridiculous but extremely possible very
hard to detect who's sort of a golden
ticket Willy Wonka golden ticket I'm
glad to see so many hands go up this was
another kind of a-ha moment that again
came out via the Mimi Katz tool this is
an ability to create a ticket that can
literally work indefinitely to any
account you can make yourself match the
domain admin you can make it a CAPA
doesn't even exist in the environment
domain admin and authenticate the crazy
thing here this is the worst case
scenario you successfully remediate your
environment you do a full password reset
of every account in the environment
right your attackers go away they come
back the next month they get their
initial foothold again through another
spear phishing attempt once they have
local access they can re import that old
golden ticket in and they immediately
become domain admin I they can own the
entire domain there's only one way to
prevent this you've got to change that
KRV GT password and twice actually at
the domain controller if you forget to
do that Golden Tickets lasts
indefinitely silver tickets are kind of
a the not they at first they don't seem
as hot or useful but these things can be
incredibly useful this is similar to the
golden ticket but only is valid for a
single resource like a single computer
or a single service what's really
valuable about these is that they don't
authenticate against the domain
controller so you get no logging the
domain controller ponies are used right
so become a very stealthy way to move
through the environment and just to
punch Microsoft Munoz one more time we
got the skeleton key that came out a
while ago which essentially once you
have actual domain controller you can go
patch else ask the domain controller and
since you create a backdoor into any
account you want where your password
always works right so it basically is a
very very easy
backdoor with essentially zero logging
part of it right unless you're logging
your driver usage on that system which
is pretty rare all right so the and then
and this is growing right we're going to
see probably three or four more attacks
the next year or two kind of incur both
the latest hotness which isn't on here
things like DC sinking you can set up a
fake DC or pretend like your DC and get
the entire DC to sink if all this
accounts to you effortlessly alright so
how do we prevent about this I know this
is a depressed yet I'm kind of depressed
are we valuing preventers well
credential guard for past the ticket so
it certainly that will protect all your
tickets you can't just dump tickets from
a local system any more remote
credential guard will prevent your
credentials from being kind of placed
all in all those remote systems that
your users are authenticating to
Kerberos or Kerberos link is completely
reliant upon cracking of those hashes so
if you can have very complex passwords
on your service accounts which is
basically what Kerberos thing is
attacking then you will since you
prevent that attack you know your
service attack accounts are valuable and
interesting so set up really good
monitoring around those and then finally
some of the guidance and that I've been
giving to people is basically changed
regardless of what happens change that
Kara BG krbtgt ticket at least once a
year that way you at least are expiring
golden tickets that may be out in the
wild on your environment at least once
per year now that's scary in itself some
some admins don't want to touch that cuz
afraid though it'll break the entire
domain you might as well do it now
because you're probably have to do it
later anyway all right get the pain
while you while he can plan for it and
then get it into your regular rotation
alright and if it wasn't bad enough I I
feel like hands on heads like seriously
the nuclear option of course is why do I
need a single hash or I might just
dumping hashes all over once I've got
domain admin privileges I can just go
straight to the main controller and I
can just download the entire Active
Directory and so this is a very very
common technique view
see in modern attacks the attackers will
just go to the main controller find some
way often through valid volume shadow
copies get a back door into that locked
account which is called the NTS dip and
that is all your password hashes not
just all the password hashes that are
current it also has a history of all the
hashes of that account you have things
like you know kind of a history of how
many times someone has changed their
password so they can't reuse the same
password when you force them to change
it every 90 days you can get all their
previous hashes as well which can
sometimes be valuable because you can
predict things like password reuse
through that so basically we can just
yank that file take it offline and your
entire active directory's is now the
attackers right so extremely common this
is a great example this is actually
pulling it out this was Italy or these
were commands pulled out of memory and
so we see the attackers essentially
going using VSS admin to list the shadow
copies they must have found a shadow
copy because they just copy out the
three files they need number to extract
those hashes pull them offline and if
you look back one you get a tool like
the NTDs extract nice free tool online
which will yank all those hashes out and
allow you to start cracking them pass
the hash attack over pass the hash
attacks you know as you can imagine
you're pretty much good to go at this
point you ever wonder why attackers
continue to do things like this even
after they've they've achieved domain
dominance why do why do they keep
jumping credentials right once you've
got 20 good credentials at work why do I
need to actually go get everything it
just because I pack rats password reuse
or often what I've seen is you do a full
password reset in the environment do you
ever do a full password reset that's so
hard to do right commonly you're going
to miss a account or two they've got all
of them so when they come back but to
start rolling through all the admin
accounts you might have an old admin
account you haven't touched in three
years right if you haven't changed that
password they're back in the next day
this is almost like a
get-out-of-jail-free card this is their
you know kind of their big dumpster-dive
of all your data so knowing this and
knowing they're coming right do we have
any soccer players in here
you have a giant soccer field right
where are the attackers going help me so
your goal right goal right you know
where they're going they're going to
your domain controller if you do
anything watch that it's just like the
soccer goal we know they're coming at
some point now there's a million
different ways they can come at you you
know using PowerShell or any variety PS
exact or any variety of other tools but
we know they're coming so this is a
great place to kind of put some effort
towards some detection mechanisms all
right
this one's simple a lot of mine is how
do you protect this you don't don't give
them domain advocates again that's hard
the other way is detection you know the
way that you create those things like
the skeleton key or dumping in TDs did
or going and creating a golden ticket
you got to get the domain controller to
get those credentials to make all that
happen so let's sit and watch and look
for unusual activities all right I could
sit here for literally another three
hours and we can keep digging into this
this is only the start of the credential
problem in Windows there are so many
more issues you know we haven't talked
about things like the Windows vault
things like smart card pins the
Microsoft cloud accounts just total
disaster the Microsoft hello it's coming
out on all the newer systems right if
history has taught us anything we are
seeing an escalated amount of attacks
against credentials right so we're going
to be surprised at what attackers are
coming up with in the next couple of
years so you've got to stay on top of
those right there's a great chart put
out by Benjamin Delpy who is the author
of mini caps he continues to to surprise
us with new attacks against credential
if you're not watching him you
absolutely should be all right so we are
in a red state so I know that we're all
happy that them we have a matter in
chief up here to to encourage us along I
will tell you your mission is to go back
and do something about this right if you
are a blue team err go back and start to
audit those servers
start to look at your highly privileged
account can you move some of those into
things like that domain protected users
group right
can you actually start to think about
things like remote credential guard
preventing not if your credentials from
being shotgunned around the environment
can you retrain your admins can you
simple things like simply turn off
delegation for tokens of your highly
published accounts right every little
bit counts
right and for those red teamers out
there you've got up your game right it's
been really easy up till now but I will
tell you with some of these new
mitigations in place I've seen attackers
currently that are trying to pass the
hash in environments and failing and
they can't figure out why we're sitting
there watching them on the wire and it's
failing failing and they're not
realizing that now in the Windows 7 and
above environment local accounts don't
have the ability to pass the hash right
if the environment set up correctly
so their attacks are totally for not
what they're leaving behind clues that
we can track anyway those red team is
you're going to have to up your game
because you're going to start running
into some some brick walls alright so if
you're not familiar with sans this is
part of the 508 advanced forensics in
its response class you guys have some
hopefully some great notes that will
help you kind of with that charge from
the commander in chief and if you want
any more information my contact
informations kind of on this deck or
feel free to hit me up during the rest
of the conference we've got a few
minutes for questions oh you're you're
waiting because multifactor helped on
any of this the answer is not much all
right so we got these you know you
talked about like the DoD environment we
have kind of a smart cards it turns out
the smart cards once you authenticate
with that smart card you have many of
the same keys of the tickets the tokens
are still all in play and once the
authentication occurs those can still be
stolen and moved around irregardless of
of that kind of smart cards so in
general sadly multi factors is not a
great mitigation at this time
so are there any attacks that you don't
need admin level privileges to to
accomplish that we talked about today
man I not that I not that I can think of
almost everything so even some of the
offline attacks that you saw like things
like grabbing the system Sam highs you
gotta have admin to get access to those
if you could get around if you can get
access to the raw disk but you need
admin rights to get access to the raw
disk so you pretty much have to have
admin rights in my at least in my
knowledge for all these attacks to work
now as you probably know that's not a
very high hurdle right there are so many
privilege escalation ataxic once you get
your user account getting to admin it's
just not that difficult in majority of
environments but if we could stop it if
you can make your environment or hostile
you stop you know almost all of the
attacks that maybe everything I talked
about today outside of maybe Kerberos
tting Kerberos things an example where
you don't need admin because you just
request any ticket and it just comes out
so it's probably a few in there that
maybe don't but for the most part you
need admin yes sir
yeah they're like
Samson could be added to the hash to
prevent things like past the hash there
are actually a fair amount of timestamp
used for instance Kerberos is very
timestamp dependent it's just as we saw
it didn't work well scale so they had to
like let these things kind of persist
for for long periods of time so now I
don't see timing really working at least
I can envision what the next up
indications is going to be but they've
they've effectively prevented a lot of
pass the hash no but yeah I just don't I
don't see that as being a big big
mitigation all right well thank you all
very much
so awesome to be here I hope you have a
great rest of the conference
[Applause]