[Music]
welcome I stock it decided USB device
analysis this is not your typical
forensic analysis I am a kind of a more
blue team type of person but this is not
your typical walk through the registry
see what devices have been plugged into
a system after you've detected this
compromise this is more analyzing the
device itself once you've identified a
potentially weaponized USB device how to
figure out how it was weaponizing and if
it was weaponized before I get going
here how many guys are more towards the
red team side okay just just a few more
so the rest of you more towards the blue
team side in the defense either
proactive reactive in some aspect or
another great okay so this this is
focused more on the the defensive side
as I described just a quick about me I
work for the Verizon risk team
consulting agency we do cases for lots
of different customers this is based
upon real-life cases that I've
personally run myself as well as a
number of other people on my team I
can't discuss details of men if those as
many of you are probably well aware
however there are two scenarios in here
that I can discuss and we're going to go
over them briefly so first off the
agenda I'm going to tell you why this is
a significant threat and why you need to
be aware of this and then we're going to
go over the scenarios of how these
attacks can take place a couple couple
different things like I said real-life
scenarios from from the trenches of the
res and risking the types of attacks
that can exist on these USB devices then
I'm going to walk you through a
methodology that's going to preserve
protect and analyze the data on the
device and the device itself we want to
do things in a specific order to make
sure we don't destroy the potential for
recovering the evidence not necessarily
for chain-of-custody concerns things
like that but because we need to be able
to analyze this evidence in order to
properly assess the threat
that we're addressing after that I'm
going to walk you through some tools
we're not going to go into the typing
commands or anything like that but many
of the tools you're probably already
familiar with they're very well known
then a little device and show-and-tell
for those of you that maybe haven't seen
what some of these devices look like
that can perform these USB attacks and
then a little discussion about the
mitigation how we can go about trying to
prevent this or address this threat in
our organizations so to start off with a
study that was sponsored by DHS the
study was essentially throw out a bunch
of thumb drives in a parking lots see
who picks them up and plug them into the
computer's big surprise they got a good
turnout 60% of the drives that they
plugged in sorry 60% of the drives that
they dropped got plugged in they did a
more specific study within within that
and they actually labeled many of those
USB drives with a government agency logo
of some sort they didn't get specific on
that possibly DHS since DHS was involved
there 90% of the the drives with a logo
on it got plugged in so just to go to
show you here the the USB devices are an
effective phishing type of technique and
those of you that are familiar with more
of the social engineering aspect right
David Kennedy was talking about that get
your pretexting right and the rest of
the job is fairly easy so get the
pretexting right on these devices and
you're pretty much guaranteed because
guess what five years later Google did a
study with them with a number of schools
colleges and such almost the same result
you'd think we'd get down this is in
2016 last year right and we're still
having people pick up these devices 48%
of them plug these things in it's a it's
a little baffling to me the awareness
that we've got with all these cyber
attacks and the news and the sensitivity
of all this kind of stuff how people can
still be this oblivious to basic
security concerns well that kind of
falls
right get to the mitigation some of
those drives were in minutes that they
got picked up and plugged in on their
way into work sat down at their desk
forget the email let's see what you see
photos we got on this thumb drive here
you guys all heard of this little attack
out in the middle of nowhere
maybe called Stuxnet yeah yeah old one
right 2010 is when it happened
you've probably heard all kinds of stuff
there's a movie last last year 2015
about the the whole attack of
semi-documentary fairly interesting it
dragged out in parts I watched it in
short it was a thumbdrive attack on the
Iran nuclear program as we likely know
what you may also know is that the
agency that sponsored this attack burned
for zero days on it that says something
about that right that's the the
investment the the potential for income
the the burning of these zero days is
not something that people take lightly
when we're talking about these these
type of actors one of those exploits is
significant because this is one of only
just a few serious threats that you guys
as blue teamers need to be extremely
careful of you know why that link file
exploit didn't require any interaction
all they had to do is plug the drive
into the Windows system it exploited the
way that Windows interprets the icon
that gets displayed as a part of the
link file so as soon as you get that
drive in there Windows is doing it's
helpful little thing trying to figure
out what all's on this drive what do I
need to prepare for this user and give a
good experience that code was exploited
by Stuxnet that's how they got in there
and there was no interaction think about
this in your context
you receive a thumb drive you plug it
into your forensic machine do you know
if there's a weaponized file a
weaponized hardware in this thing at all
not yet right the goal is to figure that
out but if you don't approach this in
the right way you're going to figure it
out the hard way
so what I'm going to walk you through
here in a few slides is a safe way to
try and figure out how this thing is
weaponized and then to preserve the data
again so we can properly assess this
threat
so now vendor alert I work for brides
and I think I'd get fired if I didn't at
least mention the data breach
investigations report one time so here's
my my token Dvir slide this is from the
phishing chapter of the DVI are you guys
all familiar with the DVI our annual
president excuse me annual publication
there's another one coming out in I
think it's usually in end of March or
beginning of April Verizon compiles it
your guyses data is contributed to it
all of our competitors a number of large
companies contribute their investigation
data to it and it allows we have a team
I think there's like seven or eight
people that are dedicated data
scientists type of people so figuring
things out like this so there's a
chapter on on phishing and this chart
comes from the the attacks that are in
this this in this investigation corpus
all security incidents and breaches
combined together the number one target
and you can see by quite a large margin
is credentials what else is what is
going after being going up gone after
secrets bank medical and personal you're
not that interesting you as a person
unfortunately yeah you're not that
interesting to to most attackers however
your credentials into your network are
very interesting so think about now you
as a normal user on your network not in
investigation mode but in your elevated
privileges
you get this USB device you plug it into
your network you've now given the
potential to expose your credentials or
tokens or what have you out to some
external threat actor or internal threat
actor really okay one to two more vendor
alerts next slide another publication
that we put out this is this is where
the real life scenario comes in data
breach digests it's a in the trenches
stories and stuff if you're interested
in how investigations are performed by
the risk team there's there's a new one
this year that was just released so this
comes from the 2017 version it's a USB
attack at the case that we handled for
one of our customers the scenario
involved a janitor he was offered money
to take a USB device and go plug it in
for every day that he would go and plug
it in he'd get bonus money from this
thread actor so he did that and for
quite some time
weeks if I recall correctly there was no
interaction involved with the USB how is
that possible the Stuxnet link file
exploit was patched by Microsoft quite a
while back well I'm going to walk you
through some of those other exploits
that can be that can be done on top of
that there's no USB enforcement so you
know no USB policy enforcement the
company had a policy that said you don't
bring USB devices in but no one cared
yeah someone's got that thumb drive okay
whatever and they must be doing good
stuff with it things they know how to
handle those things right yeah so a
little quote for you the activity would
have remained that let me give you a
context a little this is from the
internal investigator of the company
that we performed this investigation for
he he gave us a number of paragraphs as
a from his perspective in regards to
this case so this activity would have
likely remained hidden for weeks or
months had an eagle-eyed administrator
not noticed an unexpected command shell
pop up upon logging in section right how
do we detect these USB devices getting
plugged in well step one you got to
figure out what what is that USB device
that's getting plugged in step two is to
try and figure out how you can recognize
that so you can build detection right
that's that's how we build our responses
and reactions this scenario is a
different company it was from our last
year's data breach Digest publication
this infection again USB we handled it
it was a unexpected USB Drive was
delivered to a high-level executive who
had just attended a conference and
visited a booth for a fictitious company
that was crafted specifically for this
attack very very involved I'm not going
to use the word advance but very
involved very very uh very lengthy in
the setup for this attack they targeted
this guy because they knew he had
high-level privileges in the company all
that kind of stuff they used branding on
the thumb drive pretext right they
included a letterhead to try and
legitimize this this marketing packet
that was being delivered to the guy who
just attended a conference who just
spoke with some people in a booth at
that conference build up right
okay so again here's a quote this is
from from I forget who wrote this but
it's someone in Verizon anyways once the
reverse shell had been established it
didn't take long for the threat actor to
start exfiltrating gigabytes of data
including an unreleased movie this was a
meterpreter reverse shell that that came
out of this case doesn't take a whole
lot you guys saw it on mr. robot right
social engineering toolkit to build up
that USB he goes and plugs it in and
done okay vendor alerts over we're out
of that the types of attacks first type
of attack I put them into categories the
first type is file based you're probably
well aware of these everyone knows PDFs
can have exploits PDFs can have
weaponized code in them they can have
JavaScript they can have ActionScript
they can be triggered or they can be
activated by user interaction of buttons
or links things like that
Excel Doc's Word docs I've seen some
talk about the publisher documents
coming around more recently to any of
those office files going back to the to
the 1990s and using macros right we've
got an incredible amount of ability to
enable our users to just destroy our
network with automation of this code and
the attackers are taking advantage of
that
and then the last one this it's kind of
dead by now
but the link files they've they've
patched it it was a vulnerability in XP
it's it's patched as long as you patched
up your your XP installs you you'll be
alright if you're running Windows 7 it
doesn't have that not to say that one of
these couldn't be revealed again in the
future right maybe in the vault seven
look that just came out yes a link file
exploit yeah lovely
so be aware of that with your forensic
machines because you don't want to get
that compromised physical attacks this
is what some of the the blue team side
doesn't take as much consideration on
but the probably most well known device
in this space because it's been around
for the longest is the hack five USB
rubber ducky and you guys on one of
those
how many own like five six seven eight
nine ten yeah drop those in the parking
lot mmm not too expensive so the
physical attacks involved what's what's
abbreviated in the operating system as
an HID human interface device that's
anything that we as people touch that's
the keyboard that's the mouse it could
be a tablet drawing any of those are
human interface devices think about when
you have a laptop you plug one of those
keyboards in or a mouse do you have to
type in a password though there plug and
play devices that's how they've been
designed again windows trying to make
things easy when you plug that keyboard
in it has the same authority that you do
so imagine a keyboard that's got a stuck
key on it and you plug it in right
what's going to happen
across your screen imagine a keyboard
that's got a little mini controller that
can start typing commands at will that's
the rubber ducky so you plug one of
these devices into the wrong machine
you're going to give it control over
your entire network it can even reach
out to external situ servers and report
things the the rubber ducky has the
ability to script you can write up the
script compile it program it into the
device and it's weaponized that easy you
can also have USB cd-rom attacks Windows
7 maybe vissa but no one cares about
that 7 disabled USB autorun right has
anyone tried to enable USB auto run on 7
I have I can't figure out a way as far
as I know you can't do it so having a
mass storage USB autorun is not going to
work
however a cd-rom is still allowed to
auto run by windows there are many USB
devices that can emulate a cd-rom
used to have those thumb drives the u3
and I think there's a couple other
competitors that had similar things
where you plug it in and it had the
portable apps that would pop up in the
bottom corner of your computer it also
had encryption built in so it would spin
up a little password box you could type
that in it would interact with the chip
that was through the autorun emulating a
cd-rom in the computer so it could get
something running so we could you could
use a device the the rubber ducky is not
specifically capable of that but there
are a number of other devices that are
capable of emulating these CD ROMs you
put the right execute on there and it's
going to pop and under the same
privileges that you are currently
running and then last the USB Ethernet
adapter this was made popular by most
recently the poison tap from Sammy I'm
forgetting his last name then before
that it was move --ax right uh and I'm
blanking on his name right now too but
they came across some attacks where
these USB devices
could emulate an Ethernet card the
rubber ducky isn't quite capable of that
capable of that it's not quite got the
power to do that but there are
additional devices called USB armory and
then another one called the hack five
turtle I'm sorry one more time land
turtle okay thank you so these are
essentially many computers that you can
do more programming on and they can do a
whole lot more this USB Ethernet adapter
again does not require any privileges
you don't have to type a password
there's no driver to install the driver
is already there it's a plug-and-play
device the threat with the Ethernet
adapter if you're not familiar you can
you can go into the details of poison
tap you do a Google search for USB
poison tap there's a number of blog
articles that explain full details about
how it works but in a nutshell it
inserts a USB Ethernet card which looks
very much like an Ethernet card it
establishes itself as a super high-speed
Ethernet card which then tells the
operating well the operating system then
places it at a higher priority and sends
all of its traffic out on that device
even though there's nothing else plugged
in on it but what the device does is it
turns it around and puts it out on the
lower priority device and in the
meantime picking up all the data that's
coming through there right so it's a
it's a very dangerous attack and the
poison taps specifically is able to
actually as your web traffic goes
through he is able to inject malicious
JavaScript into the I think it's the
Alexus top million sites so basically if
you're on the Internet at all while this
thing is plugged in he injects a
javascript piece of code that remains
malicious he sets the cache settings so
that it doesn't expire the only way to
get rid of your backdoor is to clear out
your browser cache as long as that
browser is running he's got a backdoor
in your machine through this poison tap
it's it's a very serious attack and it
doesn't have to have an unlocked
computer
works on the lock screen of Mac Windows
and I think Linux conformation yeah so
it's a serious serious attack it
requires physical access so it's a
little bit more of an advanced attack
however it is a real real attack okay so
the methodology that I'm explaining to
you here at a at a high level we want to
collect the image from the US DB device
if there's an image to collect if it's a
storage type of USB if it presents any
type of storage we want to get the image
off of there because there could be
file-based weaponized PDF Word docs
things like that the reason for that is
because some of these things with the
scripting they could try to execute and
then wipe their contents so we want to
get the contents of that disk before the
the script has a chance to to execute
and do anything with the contents of the
storage the next part is you want to
prepare of a throwaway machine and you
want to essentially try to infect that
machine and then you're going to collect
all the volatile data from that machine
and analyze it just like you would any
other machine with with suspecting
malware activity on it only we've got
the benefit of having a clean clean
image and then an after post infection
image and we can do a comparison and try
to get to the conclusion a little faster
if there are files in the storage PDF
Word docs things like that we want to
analyze those files with the tools that
that are appropriate for each type of
file if if there's volatile data from
our from our collection we want to do
some disks and try to identify are there
new processes that have been created are
there any files that have been dropped
and reg reg Keys that have been created
things like that and then like that last
one
collect the firmware yeah so depending
on the device it's easier than some
devices are easier than others
there is a capability and I'll show you
I got a slide at the end with
picture of the chip is why not there's
the ability to program some of the
commodity cheap USB Drive that you can
buy from Amazon in in bulk for a couple
dollars apiece you can reprogram those
to be weaponized USB devices and there's
tools out there that do that in fact
there is a converter out there that you
can write a rubber ducky script and it
will compile it into the the firmware
for this Bizon brand controller pH ISO N
and it will then program that firmware
onto the device and turn it essentially
into a rubber ducky it's fairly easy to
do now so the details of each step on
the first step for collecting the image
you need a physical machine you can't do
this with a virtual if any of you tried
to do stuff like this with a with a
virtual the VMware the those hypervisors
they monitor I've got a Mac I use fusion
it monitors for mass storage devices it
does not monitor for other things
not all other things if you get a phone
then it might put it over there you know
things like that so you need a physical
device you need a physical machine and
my recommendation is to use a Linux
forensic boot CD so you don't have to
worry about Windows getting infected you
don't have to worry about that disk
being damaged and infected in any way
you get a boot CD you you reboot and and
it's clear the reason why we use Linux
is because it's typically a less
targeted operating system right but the
key to this is using a hardware USB
write blocker anyone know why
okay yeah great it's the purpose of it
is to prevent all those right backs yes
but what I haven't heard yet is it works
like a firewall think about this the
device there I've got one in the bag
here too
it is designed to prevent right backs to
storage right it only recognizes storage
devices if you plug a mouse in through
that wedi tech or a tableau write
blocker that's designed for USB devices
your mouse know working it doesn't pass
through hid devices so if the hid device
can't get passed through it can't
interact with the system we use a
hardware write blocker to prevent all
that interaction we only allow the data
to pass through we're able to collect
the image that way if the script is is
self destructing of any kind
it can't do anything the script is not
running because the write blocker
prevents it from running make sense
they're also cheap you can buy it well
relatively cheap let me say that you can
buy them I think that guy right there is
is about like 40 bucks maybe something
like that
what that one so we BTech oh man they're
they're proud of that device now Tablo
has one that's that's also right around
that area like hundred two hundred
dollars something like that but think
about this if you get one of those USB
devices that has a capacitor built into
it that stores up the charge and then
BOOM blows up your computer
would you rather blow up $150 right
blocker or would you rather blow up your
four thousand dollar MacBook Pro I think
the question is pretty clear or the
answer is pretty clear there right I
mean if you got unlimited budget and you
like fireworks then well fair point blow
up the MacBook then okay
the last thing is use views whatever
tool that you want to do to extract the
data off of their DD any of the flavors
of DD to to make a disk image doesn't
matter at that point the key is the
hardware write blocker really the Linux
is more of a suggestion because you can
just reboot and everything's gone next
step is collecting the volatile data
this one's a little longer you need to
have a physical machine again because
we're trying to get those HIDs we're
trying to get the USB Ethernet anything
else that's going on with this device
then we want a Windows OS because
typically that's what's exploited right
so we want to go with the larger larger
footprint here's a tip wipe your drive
with zeros don't do one of those 37 pass
random junk things because you're going
to be acquiring this disk and you're
going to be storing it in DD or e o1 or
what-have-you
so wipe it with zero so it compresses
really well you know everything that's
written on there is just the data that
you put on top of that don't use a
terabyte drive again just little tips
that that we've learned along the way
use a smallest drive you can with if
you're using XP then you could get away
with a tiny little 64 gig SSD or
something like that but yet go small and
do all that step 3
software write blocker in this case you
can use there's a registry I call it a
hack but that might incite some rage in
some people there's a registry key that
allows Windows to manage the write
blocks you can do that it's free it's a
red dot reg file you can just upload
into your reg reg hive the end case
product has a built-in write blocker it
works without the dongle so you can use
that if you if you have any case there's
a number of other products out there
with software write blockers so find
find one and use it yeah question
the statement was that that reg key hack
only works in XP and the question is has
that changed it or does it work in
Windows 7 and my answer is I don't have
a clue because I don't like that hack
personally I'd rather use a tool that's
that's a little more robust like encase
or one of these others in cases still my
primary tool for accessing file systems
in images so that's that's what I
usually go with on that does anyone have
a response to that comment question a
group of keys and that makes it
effective on seven in ten okay you hear
okay so alleged hearsay take that for
what it's worth
yes so collect an image before you do
all the dirty work you want to make sure
you get that bet before image do do a
prep of any of your volatile tools
whatever it is that you like to use when
you're monitoring if you've got a
malware sandbox setup that you like to
use whether it's this internal tools if
you want to do a kuku setup on a
physical machine is that possible have
not actually tried that but anyways
whatever it is that you want to do to
collect all that data prepare it get it
all ready to go step 6
I've got a PowerShell that's going to
make your life a little bit easier when
it comes to analyzing specifically these
USB devices it is a very simple
PowerShell I've got a link to it's up on
github as a gist so you can grab that
it's it's very simple very effective in
detecting the the hardware based attacks
on these USB devices once all of that is
ready the PowerShell will will start and
it'll pause so it'll say ok insert the
drive once you've got all that prepped
you insert the drive and you kick back
for a minute go get a cup of coffee
something like that you let it have time
to do its dirty work you come back you
kill the PowerShell you kill your
volatile collection tools you power it
all down you collect your image and
you've now prepared yourself for a
differential analysis of this
system that's the last of it so getting
into the analyzing of the file contents
the the weaponized files or the
existence of you guys use automated AV
scans if you don't do it I know we all
make fun of the AV industry and how
horrible they are and how don't they
don't detect things and all that kind of
stuff but it's low-hanging fruit if it
can detect it I mean for a minute of
double-clicking on the batch file that
can kick off a multitude of these AV
scans why not let it go for an hour if
it's if it's that large and you come
back and review the results if you track
IOC s previous IOC s with your case or
if you've got threat and tell feeds that
have IOC s for certain types of attacks
file hashes anything like that run those
through through all those files again
automated things you get a high return
on your investment of time I've learned
that in my consulting side of this
career because customers don't want to
pay me to look through every single byte
and the price that Verizon charges so
got to be more efficient with your with
your time and it can extend to to those
of you that are in-house investigators -
and then lastly file format specific
tools this is where your time gets sunk
in you're using the tools I've got the
listed tools in a couple slides you're
Didier Stevens tools the desa Lodge his
Olay tools things like that - to
manually analyze and inspect the
contents to see how these files are
sitting as far as being weaponized go
look at the analyzed volatile data this
is this is the order that I put it in
because I find it most efficient look at
the file contents first that's the
easier attack to set up your your what
is set does that - right in Kali I'm not
real strong on the Red Team side but set
is the tool that will build like a
weaponized PDF or was there another tool
in Kali that does that yeah set social
they want magic unicorn I haven't even
heard of that one all right well pick
your tool it's easy to build one of
these weaponized file based attacks
it's a little more difficult to build
one of these hardware based attacks it's
so it's a little more money things like
that it's a bit more of an obstacle so
hit the easy stuff first so for the
analyzing volatile data you've got your
disk images do a compare use some sort
of file dipping tool win merge kf3 any
of these beyond compare you can dump
file listings and do comparisons of each
other and get a real quick result out of
that collect your RAM images and you can
do volatility dumps and do again a diff
between them and find those differences
really quickly and then review the
contents of the output from the
powershell that you also ran because
this is going to make it really easy
i'll show you some screenshots in just a
second and then whatever it is you that
you do that finds evil whatever your
process is just go look for evil at that
point because you're dealing with a
potentially infected machine however you
determine if a machine is infected do it
lastly this was only a step that's
necessary if if you think that you are
that valuable of a target that there is
this this specialized kind of hardware
it's not a trivial thing to do but it is
doable and that is to get into the
device itself there's a tool that called
chip easy I've got that on there it's
very potentially actually a weaponized
file itself depending on what dot are
you site you download it from I've got
the link of where I believe is a safe
one but again be cautious it's it's a
Chinese based website and you can use
your Google Translate to read some of
those messages chip easy I'll show you a
screen if it identifies the controller
that's inside there it tells you the
version of the firmware it also goes as
far as trying to suggest to you what
utility again from that Chinese websites
that you can use to dump the firmware
and then it's up to you to analyze using
Ida or any other tools that you want to
get into doing that with dipping and
have fun reverse engineering right
that's that's
the fun part and you do that reverse
engineering firmware yeah all right got
buddy back there to make friends with
beers tonight I think you got a whole
lineup comin to you okay so some of the
tools any questions on on the
methodology pretty logical right it's
just making sure that you account for
that this has been built because of like
I said many many cases that we've
handled some mistakes that we've made
we've learned from and we've kind of I
don't want to say perfected but we've
refined this process this methodology to
make sure that we don't miss any of
these things when we're doing analysis
of these devices so the tools like I
said Didier Stevens he's got a whole
bunch of them and he's added a few
question yeah yes
the I've got does this group post slides
do you host the slides or not okay yeah
I'll put them up and I can send a tweet
I've got a previous version it's a
little less slides in here that I gave
at b-sides in LA that's that's already
up but I'll put up this version yeah
happy to provide that because there are
a bunch of URLs across the bottoms of
all of these so you can have reference
absolutely
so the Didier Sivan suite the peep PDF
or PP PDF I don't even know how to
pronounce that properly but I love the
tool I just don't know how to say it I
like each of videos and peep peep peep
that the second one because they each
have their strengths some of them the
the PDF piece the second one has some
automated kind of scanning for some of
the event-driven actions that happen the
did ears tools are a little bit more
towards the manual analysis but he does
give some statistical analysis trying to
identify what type of objects and and
what keywords are in there so I
recommend both tools exploring both la
there's a great blog that Didier runs
that explain a whole lot about how to
use is too
great great resource there for the word
or office-based files the daesil odd
tools are my favorite he almost
primarily are almost exclusively I used
the des lodge tools he's just constantly
updating these and doing some some great
work with it so any of those ole a based
files the previous version the doc XLS
files including the newer zip archive
format of the word the docx the xlsx
those those series as well he handles
all of those he's got a ton of automated
things in there including a number of
decoding routines and decryption
routines for the various campaigns that
have gone around as they've been
reverse-engineered so he's got some
really good stuff in that tool if you
haven't used it definitely although I
need to update that because he's moved
over to github the bitbucket is still up
but he's moved over to github so make
sure you get it from github rather than
the bitbucket did here has some some
oleh tools as well but I think I've seen
Diddy or even kind of relaxed on some of
his overlay stuff cuz daesil watch has
such exert a great tool over there so
here's a picture of that chip easy you
can see the output that comes out it
gives you the controller information the
firmware information it even goes into
the volume size things like that
you can see if the device has been over
over allocated there's some of those
cheaper USB devices that they allocate
them for 16 gigs even though there's
only four gig of chip inside of there so
this chip easy can be used for that too
but it will identify the controller and
it will identify the firmware I'm only
aware of five on pH ISO n being
vulnerable to reprogramming that's not
to say that the others can't that's the
only one that I'm aware of currently is
the Bizon controllers it's not an
exploit it's not a bug that Bizon is
going to fix it is a capability for
companies like SanDisk to buy chips from
Bizon as their controllers and it's the
ability for them to program that to be a
u3 device with a
cd-rom or to be something with a hid
device or something along those line its
field-programmable some of the other
companies make it a write-once
type of firmware that you can only
program it to be that that functionality
once and it remains there Bizon you can
you can update as long as you've got the
right firmware tools and everything so
chippies you get it from that that you
pan see see because that's that's the
one that i've seems that it's the most
legit site anyways for this tool i still
run it in a vm my PowerShell is up on as
a gist on on github so you can grab that
it's ridiculously simple the
functionality of the powershell is about
three lines the process of the
powershell is you start it up before
plugging the USB in it grabs a list of
all the plug and play devices just a big
long collection list you then insert it
you let it do all of its stuff and then
you hit enter once it's done it goes
back and gets another list of all those
PNP devices and there's a command and
PowerShell that says give me the
difference that's it collect collect
give me the difference the things like
30 lines of code because of prettiness
alright that's that's how it works with
programming so it really is not all that
complicated it's not amazing it's
nothing but it's very effective in
identifying these devices and here's why
the output here is run against one of
these well no that's the so the first
thing at the top I know this is kind of
small for you guys to read the first
thing out there is identified as a USB
store the next device is identified as a
storage volume the next one is just a
plain USB as typical of a storage you
get a USB store and a USB and then you
get the WPD bus inu route which again is
typical of USB storage are we looking at
a weaponized hardware weaponized USB or
are we looking at a thumb drive
standards on the drive
this is a standard thumb drive just
run-of-the-mill any storage whatever it
is so that top part of the output is a
summary view just to give you that that
quick list of the devices you can see
there the vid and pid' numbers in there
below that is a full dump of every
property that PowerShell has access to
for every single one of those devices
currently you got a copy paste and make
it a text file eventually I'll get
around to having it output automatically
to a text file it's not that hard
it'll add like one more line to
PowerShell but that's how lazy I am
apparently so the next device is at the
top USB vid pid' the next one is hid bid
pit hmm
eyebrows raising there this was the
rubber ducky if I remember correctly the
output from the rubber ducky so it can
present storage in this case I did not
present storage it only does the hid
device and I think this is the the
script that opens the start run types
notepad and then types hello world
I've got it in my bag if anyone wants to
try me no no takers
so that's that's what that looks like
with an HID no storage this one has one
device a little bit is that better this
has one device and it is a USB vid hid
in the summary it's not real easy to
tell in the summary but if any one spot
the fairly scary looking thing in the
details I love the name of this by the
way down here can't point to my computer
screen but right where to go right here
are n D is Ethernet gadget that is the
poison tab that's it no
no HID just the ethernet that's what the
that's what the poisons app looks like
so some more output this is again the
rubber ducky it presents all of these
things you want to test your tools ahead
of time so you know what's good with
that right white list black list type of
thing no be aware of what your systems
are doing so this is the rubber ducky
output again we've got mass storage
we've got input we've got keyboard we've
got generic volume we've got ducky
storage I mean you can't get more
blatant than that right this is this is
a very blatant configuration of the
ducky this is the the hak5 the the land
turtle the correction was that land
turtle okay so the hak5 land turtle it's
a USB Ethernet device looking thing
funny enough but it's got a little
computer in it so you can actually
program it to do more things and this
does that elevated Ethernet so it loops
back out to the actual thing and slurps
up all your traffic that's what you get
you get an isatap adapter and you get a
real tech controller this is the USB
armory with the with the Ethernet attack
this is not poison tap although the
armory can run the poison tap the poison
tap output that I had previously just
came to me was run on the Raspberry Pi 0
if I'm remembering correctly like the $5
one super super cheap so yeah again
scary this is the armory which I believe
is closer to like a hundred dollars
maybe maybe a little more involved a
little more cost and setup but it has an
arm controller ARM processor in it and
can do a whole lot more it can actually
slurp up and store credentials and stuff
on that drive so you can just in a pen
test go in plug in sit there for a
minute while the secretary is looking
you up oh no you're not on the list is
to be approved ok all right thanks out
you go with your drive right
so you get a are ndis gadget again and
you get the isatap adapter that's that's
all they need for the high elevated
privilege USB Ethernet so questions on
any of those devices you guys need new
new underwear yet okay then a little
device and show us any questions on
anything else the bash money I have not
know if you have one though I'd be happy
to collect the results of the PowerShell
to see what it looks like at the the
Raspberry Pi poison tap was one of the
carbon black sales guys was at at Issa
meeting and he's like I got one of those
like okay run my script and give me the
output so he gave me the outfit so yeah
if if you've got any other devices and
you run this I'd be happy to include
this in in the slides for displaying to
others a Leonardo Arduino does is
similar to the Raspberry Pi of the
rubber duckie type of thing so not quite
to the Ethernet but but with the
scripting of the hid and things okay
good to know
I've not observed that not to say that
we've missed it I've not actually looked
for that but have you well as far as I
understand as long as the device is
created properly I used to work for
guidance familiar with tableau they only
program from the privileged side of the
blocker so you shouldn't be able to
reprogram the firmware on the tableau
from the the dangerous side true I know
I have a combo we BTech combo doc and
the firmware is only updatable from the
privileged side as well I can't speak to
the rest of the the Wiebe text but I do
know for those two devices you can only
do it from the privileged side I would
imagine that it's true but I'm not going
to speak to that because we all know
bugs can happen in code and who knows
what happens after that
absolutely yeah well what was it like
eight nine ten months ago something like
that there was an exploit that was
developed for the outside-in plugin it
was a little longer by the time might
have passed a little more outside in
plugin developed by oracle that pretty
much every forensic platform tool uses
your ex ways your in case your sdk nuoc
stay all use this outside in plugin and
there was an exploit developed for a
certain crafted file that would actually
execute code on forensic machines
essentially it was kind of a controlled
scenario but in it was still out there
yeah very very curious kind of setup but
I suspect that it would probably not be
very effective unless there was some
sort of mistake in the code bug kind of
thing questions
okay no I the what was it called the net
net hunter okay so there's a tool on on
Callie called net hunter I'm not a red
team so an Android tablet or phone or
something like that and it turns that
into one of these things that's awesome
yeah I'm not a Red Team guy I'm blue
team defense reactionary more
specifically not proactive even so no
I've not played around with that but
it's that's an interesting concept I
love it very fascinated about that the
attacking side but yeah it doesn't pay
my bill
I'd be horrible at it yeah I know I'm
not plugging that in so fitting though
right I opened up the bags like oh man
has anyone I've seen any weird mouse
movements on there on their screen
anywhere it Rison sponsored the
conference and provided those USB drives
no I'm just kidding but yeah speaking
any other questions okay
speaking of devices have you guys seen
any of these things in vendor marketing
materials the first one that I saw was
American Express and it was an HID
device it opened up your start run and
it started typing out HTTP because there
wasn't any s at the time at least for
most sites colon slash slash American
Express comm and it would pop up your
default browser on their website oh I I
have a few of them at home because I saw
that as like I need some of those I
think I heard that they're reprogrammed
what one point wait now you don't need
it because you get the rubber ducky but
but yeah this is this was years and
years ago I can't put a year to it but I
know it's quite a long time ago people
knew about this they they were
exploiting it for their for their vendor
marketing kind of advantages to bring it
up because they know oh you're not going
to plug in storage and double click on
this file here and there and so well
well if we just force them to do it
there are some of these that are storage
so not all of those card without things
are hid in fact I've not seen as many
HIDs lately so but that's that's one
that was fun so for those of you that
haven't seen this is rubber ducky the
insides of it it comes with a case that
actually looks exactly like the
conference thumb drive if you were to
take that that printed part of it off of
the conference thumb drive and put it on
the rubber ducky case yeah
suckers so the the micro SD card is how
you put the scripts on there just load
it up and it does one at a time
you can only have one be the script so
you can't like load it up with a whole
bunch and pick at runtime what you want
to do it's it's whatever you've
programmed it to be so you gotta have a
key chain of multiple that that you get
to the big which this is the USB armory
it's a little bulkier in size it's a
little harder to mask and convince
someone that it's a normal USB unless
you were to make it like one of those
Lacey baton USB drives you guys seen
those things weapons but it's it's a
little bigger it requires a little more
power stuff like that but yes that's
what it looks like and this is a picture
of the five on controller if you tear
the device apart that's that's what
you'll see I don't think there's a
specific model that's vulnerable it's
it's the PI's on in general like I said
not a bug not an exploit it's a feature
exactly working as intended yet so you
can configure it to be a CD an hie a
storage or any combination of those
three crazy oops last one
mitigation number one humans are weak
right we know that very well we need to
educate our users and make sure that
they are aware the gross majority of the
cases the USB cases that the Verizon
Group has handled have been because the
user identified something weird about
this device came in and I'm not going to
plug it in yeah the the other cases
where we investigate an infection and it
might have come from a USB that USB
long gone because the user doesn't want
to admit to doing any of this stuff so
the cases that we've done where it's
been specifically for USB it's because
the user was aware they were educated
properly they knew about the security
concerns and they identified this and
took it to their their InfoSec team for
investigation
so make sure make sure your users are
aware include this in your training if
you're not already getting them getting
them on that data loss prevention tools
some of them have the capability to lock
down or at least monitor ports what's
being plugged in and unplugged things
like that so there's there's a ton of
these things there used to be more
specifically USB or port focused tools
that could be centrally managed and have
policies I'm I'm I tried to remember the
one that that I've worked with
previously but it was specifically ports
and it would even integrate with the
encryption on certain USB vendors the
the enterprise level USB Drive devices
that have the built-in encryption chips
so that you could program network keys
onto the device that if an employee
unplugs the encrypted thumb drive and
went home to plug in it wouldn't work
because it couldn't get the
network-based keys on top of their user
base keys so it's data loss prevention
in a sort but it was specifically for
these ports and USB devices but but more
and more data loss prevention tools are
including these these type of policies
so this this is something you just you
got to make it reasonable right if you
lock it down too much users are going to
bypass and and they're not going to
report things so there's a balance in
the middle and then last the the blog
post here was posted just I want to say
last week maybe it's a pretty fresh one
and it's it's the the Twitter account
passing the hash I don't know the guy
but he put up a blog post about how to
mitigate the poison cap and the
USB armory the ethernet-based attacks
that are doing that highly elevated
Ethernet and then turning around
capturing the in poisoning the cache all
that kind of stuff the the gist behind
this is that the group policy that
blocks the association that the drivers
are already there I remember plug and
play devices it blocks the association
of new devices to these drivers and
there's a very specific driver class
that he talks about on there it's got
the GU it included and there's one point
that he's got in big bold letters
there's a checkbox that says apply only
to new devices or apply to all devices
guess which one's going to make a big
headache for you if you choose the wrong
value yeah if you do that your network
devices across your entire enterprise
will go and you won't have a lot of
angry users that won't be able to
connect although it would reduce on the
email flow so give and take right so
there's a policy that you can apply and
that that will take should let me say
should take care of the Ethernet based
attack on these new devices that are
getting inserted he's not fully vetted
he kind of makes a request to get
feedback from from guys that have tested
it and to ensure that that is good
advice on the policy that he's designed
but that's that's the best mitigation as
far as the the Ethernet based attacks as
far as the keyboard attacks and the the
hid the mouse and keyboard education
that's that's the best I got
you can't block laptop users from
plugging in a mouse right you infuriate
these users if they couldn't plug in
their mouse or external keyboards or
docking stations things like that so if
your DLP has the capability to get
granular for specific devices even to
the point of serial numbers maybe but
otherwise you're going to have to rely
on user education and them being the
detection mechanism for some of these
devices because I'm not aware of any
event logs event IDs that indicate a
mouse or a keyboard has been plugged in
so if you're in a hunting role you might
be able to get into the what's the
current version the set up dev API log
thing on disk where it logs all of the
USB plug and play devices you might be
able to hunt those logs pull those back
periodically and see what what's been
plugged in but other than that it's a
kind of a dangerous dangerous area to be
in so any questions on the mitigation no
thought if that hand is a head scratch
all right is that like a fake like no
all right well thanks for enduring my my
blabbering and I hope you got something
useful out of this and please I'm very
open to feedback if you've got devices
the the Android devices if you want to
run the PowerShell I'll throw it up here
I've been asked to give this talk at a
number of times because the threat of
this is very real
I had a SISO in my area who said it's
not often that people can scare me about
these threats he's usually the one doing
the scaring it's it's a serious threat
so take it seriously take the right
approach and we can address this in a
good way so thanks again
[Applause]