[Music]
good morning besides cricket cricket
there we go good morning hi hello a
round of applause Oh Oh works like that
all right pull out your wallets it's not
working all right so this morning we're
going to talk about facing the Kobayashi
Maru this is my guide on Incident
Response tabletops so without further
ado let's go the right way me in a
nutshell so my name is JC I work for
snow offensive we're a local consultancy
down here in South Jordan Utah I focus
in social engineering Incident Response
forensics one of my hobbies is a maker
so if you guys see the cyber Attribution
dice that pull it around that's me
like a scumbag I totally forgot to bring
some of the COS out to the audience I'm
sorry I'm also a former Marine did four
years down in Pendleton as a radio
operator I was fun a lot of the Marine
Corps oddities and how I present will
come through that will include me moving
around and interacting with you this
will be a somewhat interactive talk I
get as much value out of it as you get
so I'll pick your brains I'm curious
what you guys do well I try and part
some of my knowledge so snow offensive
real quick we focus in offensive
security style assessments so you're
fishing fishing those things this falls
under our training services we use
tabletop exercises to essentially get
two things out of it
first one is training your staff gets
more familiar with your instant response
plan and procedures and also testing so
you actually learn if you're a bless you
you actually learn if your instant
response plan works or could survive the
battlefield so let's get into it instant
response tabletop so how I'm going to
break it down is essentially we'll talk
about what a tabletop is we'll talk
about how to design a tabletop
conducting the tabletop and then
reporting
so the very first thing I want to do is
clarify why I'm giving this talk so
throughout my eight years in information
security I've noticed something and
that's what I call the Chupacabra effect
yeah this guy knows that you pack a bra
yeah the real one so the Jewpacabra is a
funny story put your hands up if you
know what the Jewpacabra is put them up
I can't see
alright so hey maybe a third of the room
is raising their hands the problem with
the Jewpacabra is exactly that a handful
of people will state they know what it
is however the people that raised their
hands who has actually seen one I'm
looking around the room and I'm not
seeing any hands you seen a picture of a
dead one I've got a pretty scientific
Wikipedia diagram here that someone took
the time to make that's the first
sasquatch they're practically related so
that's the first problem that I've
identified with the Chupacabra effect is
that there's there's little to no
first-hand experience the second thing
is multiple opinions on expectations so
for the people that raise your hands if
I pulled you over into a room give you a
piece of paper and told you to write
down what it is what you think it looks
like I guarantee that they would be all
drastically different that's a huge
problem
and lastly where is the single
authoritative source on the Jewpacabra
there is none and that is the joopa
effect now for those of you who have
been around incident response one
Jewpacabra that I've identified as the
incident response plan everyone has an
opinion I've done just probably under a
hundred incident response plan reviews
right taking a company's incident
response plan read over it identify
problem strengths weaknesses those
things I guarantee that none of them
some of them had some common element but
they all went crazy with some of the way
they handle things it was really weird
tabletop exercises are a serious group
of cover in my opinion everyone and
their mom will talk about them but
if you have conducted them very few have
conduct them successfully and very few
know what they are so before we get into
it too much who here knows what a
tabletop exercises all right you
remember the whole analogy I just did
what you put cover before we started I
said I'm going to pick on you okay so
who raised their hand
who knows what a tabletop exercises I'm
gonna go with you you're loving it today
yes is it interactive
I'm going to come up and talk excellent
so what the
was essentially we proposed a scenario
and from the scenario we introduced
details and as the details are
introduced we respond to it based on our
answer response plan that I paraphrase
describe the response excellent that's a
very good stab anyone have a different
opinion
now it's a time uh here we go a
different one a lot of people don't have
instant response plans it's very true
fact which is really fun to see him do
it instant response tabletop when
they've got no plan or documentation and
they just kind of make it up on the fly
any others this is a very good point
this is what I was looking for so on
Michaels point in the back sir your name
Darryl Darryl now you're on YouTube say
hi mom because they can only hear me
hide arrows mom so there is no instant
response plan we're testing all the
parts of our instant response plan and
we have an expectation that logs and
collections are there but no one really
knows so this is where we start to get
into different methodologies for
infinite response tabletops some schools
of thought are that you go through and
you say okay well we're collecting
Active Directory logs let's spend the
next hour making sure all of our ad
servers are producing logs they're all
getting centralized that is a tabletop
method I've seen I've also seen the
tabletop method where they actually use
the time to write their instant response
plan which was an absolutely horrible
idea because now the infinite response
plan is tailored around officiate now
and that was it and every once in a
while I see that what I'll call the
golden child where they're actually
doing it to this
Darrel's definition which is correct
that's the duper
I see the Jewpacabra in a lot of things
I try and do my talks around where
there's very little authoritative
knowledge around what things are and
that's the impetus for this talk we've
talked about what a tabletop is so I'm
not going to quiz you there but Darryl
hit the nail on the head
it is a scenario slowly presented which
your team members have a chance
descriptively to respond to does that
not make sense to anyone is interactive
this is here for you
this makes sense excellent any questions
all right
there's a handful of benefits to conduct
into tabletop the one which gets me a
paycheck nine out of ten times is
compliance the perfect framework is the
PCI when I talked about getting two
birds with one stone the tabletop
exercise takes care of the testing
requirement of PCI and the training
requirement of PCI for your incident
response plan compliance is a huge
reason to do it it's not the best reason
but it's one that gets being patron so
the gentleman over here
mentioned that it compliant is good
because it helps build a cadence and
I'll completely agree my problem with
that is the PCI requires a change of
once a year more mature it's 100% better
than zero and my my PCI soapbox is PCI
is amazing everybody makes fun of it but
if you imagine a world where those bare
minimum requirements don't exist there's
been so many incidents that I've
responded where the root binding is you
don't have a firewall they're out there
more mature organizations
I see go past the compliance and they do
about for a year or they'll deal
quarterly the way they do it to save
money is they do three internal and then
a big one hosted by an external party
the next thing is to identify gaps this
is the real root and soul of why you
want to do a tabletop because it's
better to identify the problems in your
plan and your team members and your
technology the gentleman over here sorry
what's your name mister logs sorry Devin
like Devin pointed out during an
incident is the worst time to figure out
that you're not collecting logs and it's
one of the most annoying things to do
when you come on as part of Incident
Response for a client you're trying to
get up to speed with the situation and
you get about five minutes in and you
say okay I'm gonna need the log server
this server this and they cut you off
the table we don't keep logs
well good luck Oh take off now there's
very little you can do so identifying
your gaps is one of the primary points
of why you want to do a tabletop the
next thing that's also important is it
defined responsibilities who in the room
has an incident response plan
see a couple hands not up which is cool
for your student get that you're
unemployed that's cool you don't work
for a company that things are good if
you work for a company you're on the IT
team you don't have an instant response
plan we've got problems of the people
that raise your hands and you know you
have an incident response plan how many
of them include non-technical team
members like your legal team your HR
team how many of those people know that
they're on the instant response plan
good there's a handful of times when I'm
doing these plan reviews that a company
will have their HR team their legal team
and one of the first questions I ask is
okay you list public communications is
going to do these three tasks who from
public communications has this
experience and they look at me blankly
and they say well we'll just hand it
over to them and they'll figure it out
that's their job
during an incident is the worst time to
figure out one you're on the incident
response team and to how to do a breach
notification
trial-by-fire is cool but it's not the
right way to do things any questions
about responsibilities this is very
beneficial when you're conducting one of
these tabletops it to get everybody in
the room look at them and say your
expectations of their role there's been
a handful of tabletops that I've
conducted where the tabletop screeches
to a halt and sometimes it's fun other
times it's just a bickering contest but
we get into who is actually going to do
what and that ain't my job argument
another benefit the three that I listed
first are kind of what I would call the
primary ones these three are your
secondary ones is to assess performance
so as we do more and more we should
start keeping metrics how many gaps we
identify what type of issues are we
coming up with as we get and I'll go
into kind of the exercise maturity but
as devin state there's other room for
questions such as what logs do we have
that's not the point of a tabletop we'll
talk about where you can actually
exercise things like that but to assess
performance of your team so here is a
notional data breach that we have here's
the situation here's how much data we
lost we hand that off to a team like our
legal and communications team let's
actually see them produce the breach
notifications let's see them make the
publication's
the internal statements let's give them
a random reporter calling in and
requesting comment these are things that
they're probably not practicing a lot
especially if you're a much smaller or
medium sized organization if your
organization that has a lot of publicity
time some of these things might be
second nature to them some companies are
in the news for more company related
business they might do something or have
access them to some data that gets them
in the news
one how would I say this example
one company was dealing with very
sensitive services
they were dealing with sensitive
services a tragedy occurred when that
tragedy occurred and lots of tragedies
like this occur the media immediately
bombard this company tasks questions
about what you're doing when you're
doing it who you did it for so this
company was well versed in handling
disasters tragedies very big issues so
when it came to things like a data
breach
this was actually second nature their
issue was more with their business and
we'll get into some of the things that
we talked about during a tabletop but
the business decisions so if I have an
incident where do I make the decision to
stop business processes in lieu of an
incident so usually I get a lot of
things out of the public relations team
that's usually a place that has a lot of
benefit for tabletops but in this case
it was more of your business operations
the next thing is educate for those of
you that have raised your hand about
having an incident response plan how
many of you have actually read it word
by word
I didn't see as many hands and I saw
some hands that didn't raise before so
one of the problems with innocent
response plant it is supposed to be
updated often at least yearly in many
cases usually after there's been an
incident sometimes it happens sometimes
it doesn't happen when do you actually
get everyone together and talk about the
changes talked about sir what's your
name talk about when keys from IT has
come over to networking what's Keith's
new role yeah he had a role in the
incident response plan back in IT the
mallies and networking so how do we
educate him on his new roles how many
people in your organization move to
different positions how many of them get
new responsibilities
so tabletop is a great method to educate
our members and lastly synergize you
don't have to raise your hand for this
one but who here has actually been
through an incident that has been pretty
gnarly gnarly denali factor changing a
handful of you how stressful was it
gnarly
this guy struck it off ain't no thing
this is every weekend some people it's
the most stressful thing jobs on the
line because that guy forgot to install
the firewall that we told them about
right others you know it's not too bad
but an incident is literally one of the
most stressful things that's going to
aside from I guess downtime depend on
your company an incident is going to be
one of the most stressful things you do
in an organization this is something
that could have legal ramification cost
ramifications to your business brand
right think about target think about
Home Depot you have huge brand
reputational damage yeah you have a lot
of stress on the line during an incident
is not the time and place when you want
to learn everybody's little s intricity
's about how to work with them when you
deal with an incident you're usually
working with a large team of people
some you've never worked with before
I've seen in some incidents you have
some lower-level IT guys networking guys
that are now meeting with the board if
you guys ever seen that happen it's the
most hilarious thing to watch it's
unfortunate but if you try and watch a
low-level technical person try and
explain the situation to the CEO there's
two different worlds colliding they're
talking over each other they don't know
how to interact they don't understand
the issues from one person's world to
the others we can help bridge that in
the tabletop there's a handful of times
when we'll do a tabletop operating the
executive team in and the technical team
and we'll go through the full scenario
top to bottom when we do that you get
the most amazing feedback ever it's
absolutely beautiful
it's like this coming to Jesus moment I
get it here in my eye it's so much fun
what happens is you'll especially for
budget if you guys need budget
will happen is they'll sit there in the
beginning of the tabletop and they'll
say okay well here's this scenario go
through piece by piece and then as we
get towards the end the c-level
executive last questions like how come
we didn't know this or where these logs
or how do I find out this information
and you'll have that low-level technical
person say well you didn't approve our
budget to buy that syslog server that
costs what 10 grand and then you just
see this whitewash on your CEO space
that we could have this huge issue
compounded by the fact that we're not
able to do any type of analysis because
I wanted to pinch pennies it's the most
amazing thing that you'll see actually
come together when you start bringing
teams from different worlds and on a
tabletop now I mentioned I talk about
this a little later on exercise maturity
tabletops are great but they have a
place they're not at the beginning
they're not at the end of what I would
call your testing framework your very
first thing is planning so this is for
the guys that don't have an instant
response plan that might not even have
logs you want to start planning you want
to build your instant response plan you
want to look at some of your
capabilities that's your initial that's
your neutral initial procedural
documents the next thing you want to do
and this was spot-on to Devin's point
you want to do these things right before
you have a tabletop you don't want to
flip them or they're not going to be
effective and that exercises practical
exercises you want to say all right
let's have a scenario where we need to
hold these logs can we do it let's
actually do it please do it literally go
do it we we think we can hold for a year
go pull me a year ago right we think we
can see when the geographical IP address
or the geographical location of an IP
address from our VPN users go pull that
data everything you think you can do you
should be exercising and confirming you
do it
because if not when you get to a
tabletop this is where we get into a lot
of bickering where we'll say we can do
things and again tabletops are very
fast-paced they're notional like Darrell
said they're notional so we're not
actually going to have time to go in and
dig out logs there's going to be a lot
of things moving on so if you say we can
get logs I take your word for it
tabletop isn't the place to find that
you want to figure that out before
figure that out before when we get to
the tabletop you can stand up and say
well we can't collect that a huge gap
tabletops isn't going to take you all
the way either
after you conduct it for you they start
losing value they sell value maybe once
a year but where you want to move who
gets a pen test every year
fewer people that you have incident
response plans kind of fun so from that
many people usually get penetration
tests why there's not many in this room
I don't know that's interesting one of
the things you want to do is leverage
your penetration test to be a testing
method for your incident response plan
so what I mean by that
who here has heard the term purple team
good a lot more of you you want to
essentially conduct a purple team test
you want to make sure that you have is a
military word for you a liaison between
your red team and your blue team so as
you're performing your penetration test
and let's say they're doing recon and
they find a box and now they're doing a
full vulnerability scan on that one box
you guys should have some tool that
might be lighting up that liaison is
there to look over the blue team's
shoulder and say
you see anything weird with that box
right there no you don't yeah you're
fired
yeah and that's the idea is you want to
make sure that you're leveraging a
penetration test to give you more more
capability specifically in testing so
you guys are getting attacked test your
instant response team to find it to stop
it to prevent it
that's what you pay them there to do
right that's kind of the maturity model
that I've come up with for instant
response plan testing does that make
sense is there any questions
none sure
no not for so for an incident right
you'll do as much as you can that's
that's yet for a live if you really
don't collect anything we're very
limited on the stuff we can do right no
that's fine you bring up a valid point
so what I what I do when I develop it
and I'll kind of show you this is I come
up with multiple information so as
because I don't get enough time to
really meet with the client understand
their infrastructure so I come up with
things that they should normally be able
to get if they have common tools in
their environment so one of my favorite
ones is oh my gosh drawn a blank what's
the it's like IP fix cisco has their own
proprietary thing what is it it's
aggregate count of all your data net
flow that's it net flow so net flow IP
pics that's one of my favorite ones
because most people who in here is doing
full packet capture don't you lie to me
you got this hand that's kind of like
half cocked and kind of doing it its
foot it's partial packet capture huh
okay okay oh so you are doing it then so
you got seven days excellent so what's
your name so Brandon Brandon's the only
person in this room that's kept seven
days a full packet capture good work
Brandon Oh a tooth you guys have it too
excellent so full packet capture gives
you a plethora of information however it
comes at a ridiculous cost especially
the more days you get one of the most
cost efficient things is net flow it
doesn't tell you as much information
really doesn't tell you much at all but
it does tell you how much data has gone
from point A to point B so it's a great
thing from a board level perspective if
we're going through an incident and
we're talking with the technical team
and I say okay bf gates have a net flow
or full packet capture like yeah we have
net flow great you saw eight gigs go to
this IP address which is great because
when you do an incident you're not
always going to have all the details
you'll know that your pH I server that
holds all your pH I was compromised and
now you know that eight gigs left a lot
of cases that's what you get in an
incident how do you respond so let's
talk about designing and this this is
kind of where we're going to get into
the idea who here's a Star Trek fan okay
good all the people with instant
response plans excellent let's talk
about designing a tabletop person talk
about roles when I conduct the tabletop
I have four primary roles I have the
facilitator that's me if you guys are
doing it internally that's whatever
brave person you decided to put at the
firing line because this is the person
that's going to deal with making the
exercise flow dealing with problem child
level getting to them coming up with
information if somebody throws a curve
ball then the next person you have is
participant there's a big difference
between participants and observers a lot
of times you'll get into these rooms and
a person from the risk Department wants
to come in and observe which is fine
however that person will want to
interject and want to act as if I'm
conducting an audit the most annoying
thing in the world
participants are there and they're
designed to participate observers are
there to sit back and watch when I build
the room I make sure if there's a table
of conference table what-have-you
participants are at it observers are in
the back
you're either standing against the wall
or you're sitting against the wall
you're out of the way you're not at the
big-boy table that's the idea if not for
me it's very hard to figure out who's
actually a participant in who's an
observer from an internal team it might
be easier but from an internal tabletop
it's a lot harder to tell the risk guy
to shut up and stay an observer for me
it's super easy
next thing is your scribe when you're
going through this things are fast paced
you're essentially role playing a full
incident that could take between one and
three weeks in two to four maybe eight
hours having someone there to document
and capture notes is a must I cheat and
I bring an audio recorder which sucks
because has anybody ever done
transcriptionists work oh my god those
people can't get paid enough
transcribing audio is what we're seeing
in the world does anyone have any
questions about the roles awesome
don't worry about
taking pictures of my slide deck when
it's creepy because I don't know what
you're taking a picture of to at the end
I'll put up my contact information shoot
me an email and I'll send you the full
deck and that way you're not getting
really bad images yeah take a picture of
the contact information or swing by and
pick up a card one of the two so as I
was mentioning you have two types of
facilitators you can have an internal
facilitator or an external facilitator
there's benefits to both the first one
is for an internal they understand the
company capabilities it takes me a
little bit of a learning curve as I get
in and start moving understand what you
guys can and can't do next thing is you
know where the skeletons are in the
closet you know where the weak spots are
you know what strings to pull in some
cases it could be politically dangerous
in your company to pull on those weak
spots the next thing is it's less formal
usually having an external party come in
is or not having an external party come
in is something very less formal you
guys can just get together on a Friday
at 5 o'clock before everyone goes home
because that's when incidents happen if
you didn't know they always happen at
Friday at 5:00
that's when I get the call we can I
don't know why stop doing it there you
know it's right before well well you
guys figure it out 4:30 and they need to
say to call me at 5:00 and then the fact
is you guys have been messing with this
since Monday you guys could've just
called Monday and I can help out I and
the next thing is it cost less right you
don't have to fly me in you have to
bring me in you have to pay for me it's
really great if you need to do these
multiple times right if you do them
quarterly you probably want to get some
internal capability however there's
benefits to an external person like
myself one I'm impervious the company
politics I'm the bad guy you can't mess
with me I can piss everyone off in the
room what's going to happen
you have weak spots I'll find them I'll
pull them right that's one of the
benefits is people can't hide behind
their title on their rank the next thing
is you get an outside perspective so how
many people have worked at their company
for over ten years
right on 15 he had 20 and I almost
sounds these gentlemen look like they're
14 years old and they've been at their
organization almost 20 years while I
applaud that one of the problems that I
see seventeen seventy eighty oh my god
is it your first shop you get it nice I
hate that exactly and that's the thing
is at least in my opinion right and we
can get on a soapbox and go back and
forth when I see things like that where
it's a first job right and I applaud you
guys I'm not I am picking on you I hate
you guys but the thing is is like a
bumblebee you don't get to pollinate you
don't get a go see how other shops are
doing it so things like conferences
going out networking is probably the
most important thing because you don't
get that experience that comes with job
hopping every year like some people are
you a yearly job hopper what 100 percent
I need to quit you guys are probably
like right on the hills of retirement so
you've got to get that pension hopefully
the state right state or federal it
helps to pollinate bringing out bringing
in an external facilitator brings that
outside perspective of that's cool this
is the way you guys have been doing it
for the past 20 years and there's a lot
of shops that have people that have been
there for years one of them they're
badgers has little indicators every five
years that they had been at the company
and that was like their badge of honor
right so people got really hoity-toity
if they had lots of little stickers and
other people didn't have any stickers
they do a little dance really
politically stupid but that's the
benefit of having someone else come in
is I can say hey you know I've seen
other companies in your industry do
things this way it might not hurt to
check it out turn on the Travel Channel
as a gentleman said I another thing is I
can easily like I mentioned I can easily
pull on the the strings for the weak
spots there's been situations where I've
conducted a tabletop it's been a
technical team it when you host these
things people group together it's like
the networking guys will be in the
corner whispering the IT guys would be
in the corner whispering they'll say
something and all the time you'll see
the nudge shut up that's my cue to jump
on them and start date that when I see
the nudge the gloves come off but that's
one of the benefits of me is I can come
in or any external facilitator come in
and take on those problems bring them to
light let your board see them because it
doesn't do you guys any good to hide on
those things the other thing is it's
more formal
there's just something inherently formal
about having an external party come in
that might be important for compliance
for the board for investors to see
things like that
a handful of you raise your hands you
guys conduct a tabletop while your
wallet
any money
you
so to Darryl's point
for some reason people like to keep it a
secret so this Darryl's pointing out one
of the benefits of having an external
facilitator is you guys are going to get
an external report finding those
weaknesses can move on to the report
that can find funding
sometimes I see nudges because they say
they did something they really haven't
yet or or we've done it we said we've
done it that's an excellent point that
is that is beneficial as having that
external report a handful of you raised
your hand and said you guys can get
tabletops is that correct how many of
you have remote participants
how do you like it
fine
excellent
so as this gentleman says 40% of his
workforce telecommute
excellent and what I find is companies
that have that telepresence capability
they've got essentially remote in their
blood they can do video conferences they
can do impromptu some people have Skype
they join up in a Skype room some people
hangout what have you it works well
a lot of organizations don't have that
yet they try and pull it off if you're
yes sir
you
yes
right and that's that's where we get
into my comment kind of remote is in
their blood if you're not used to
working in a remote situation if your
technical team members are remote then
you probably have a method to work with
them remotely and that's fine my slide
here is essentially when companies that
don't have that remote capability
there's still a lot it's very rare to
see companies that actually believe in
remote work they'll try and bring people
in remotely because then the marketing
guy doesn't want to come in and he'll
take it via WebEx you can't do it like
that so my comment here is it I guess I
should really clean up the slide a
little bit my comment really isn't if
you have a remote workforce abandon it
no it's don't allow people to
essentially participate remotely or in a
method that they normally wouldn't so if
I see people allow remote present for
convenience of the employee for instance
the marketing guy doesn't want to come
in or he's off-site to schedule change
the date if the guys normally on site
let them be on site if your technical
teams are remote or your employees are
mostly remote and it's perfectly fine
you guys most likely have the
capabilities to host those meetings and
handle those communications that's not
an issue just don't try and have
somebody just on a phone especially if
there are two doors over could see
suppose the only thing
when I build a tabletop exercise I build
it based on what participants are going
to show up and I have three primary
methods first one is technical
you can spend four to eight hours in a
room talking about the technical aspects
of an incident you can really get into
the weeds for that reason some exercises
are specifically designed for just those
technical team members your sis admins
your network engineers your helpdesk and
we work through all the intricacies of
responding where we get into some of the
logs and some of the analysis next thing
is just your executives see here just
your executives so focusing on your C
levels right the people that have what I
call an external foot in the interim the
incident response plan where they have
to where they might not be involved in
every incident for the really big ones
they are they're usually not well versed
in instant response in technical
situations one of the biggest findings
that I usually have from your C levels
is they want some type of weekly or
monthly catch-up meeting just to
understand what's going on and be kept
in the loop because as we go through
these things they feel really left out
so you get a lot of value from the
executive side where we talk about just
responding to an incident from the
business impact point of view from the
legal perspective how do we handle
breach notifications as that talk a
little bit about that earlier and then
the really fun one is when we mix the
teams there's two ways I mix a team I'll
do the technical first in the morning
and then I'll do the executives in the
afternoon this is more of a traditional
approach for me because usually it's the
technical teams that figure out we have
an incident they do some initial
analysis they work through it and then
they give the bad news at 4:30
I essentially designed the scenarios to
work that way so we work through all the
stuff and then after lunch I usually
take whoever my point of contact is and
I let them brief your sea level teams
that one's a lot easier because it's
more hands-off what you have from that
technical analysis from the first
morning session is what you have there's
no more data so your sea levels are
completely free to run through the
tabletop however you'll get the legal
stall for those of you have done a
tabletop internally how many of you have
included your legal team how many of you
okay so I got a handful of hands like
three out of those three how many of you
have had the legal stall where legal
says I need more information or we'd
have to figure out more before I could
answer that always a lot and that's the
internal politics so I got I got one
he's my boss other people agree the
legal stall is is death and they're
lying
that's just what lawyers do lie but they
do this stall technique it's not going
to benefit you I've literally worked
through all the analysis we have all the
evidence with all the answers to any
questions some of the answers might be
no or we don't know caveated with we'll
never know but what more do you need
legal team and that's what they do they
stall when you come in and you preface
your executive table top that we have
all the answers you'll have to make
decisions giving them that heads up
changes the game a lot the other thing I
do and I mentioned this earlier is I run
the two teams simultaneously I make sure
the c-level can watch the technical the
technical can watch the sea level that's
the whole coming to Jesus curing my eye
it's an amazing moment because the sea
levels can see what the technical team
has to deal with how they're how they
have their hands tied behind their back
if they do and the technical
team can see the impetus for why we do
things from a sea-level perspective or
why we need that information that make
sense one of the most important things
is selecting a date if you guys are
going to do this
pick a date I usually aim for 30 days
out just because trying to get on
everybody's calendars is painful
next thing is timing when I make table
tops I usually do it
following this metric if it's a single
scenario with one team about two hours
one scenario with a mixed team or two
scenarios with the single team for hours
and then two scenarios with both teams
around 8 hours Logistics when I do one
of these I have a handful of things
first one I mentioned was a conference
room kind of seating projector
whiteboard I do my slides to work
through these audio recording device
that was my cheating way so I don't have
to scribe things and then snacks and
drinks if you've ever been through some
of these it gets annoying people get
hungry munchies whatnot try and put out
some candy for some reason candy puts a
little bit more sugar in people's blood
they get a little bit more responsive
and then they crash and die so the whole
point of this talk the Kobayashi Maru so
where's my Star Trek fans at excellent
Darrell what is the Kobayashi Maru the
unwinnable exercise that is how I design
all of my table tops as an unwinnable
exercise who thinks that's fair
yeah one big big smiling hand goes up
right here it's perfectly fair there's a
there's a reason well it's not fair to
Kirk right that was the whole point the
idea behind it is if we get fifteen
thirty minutes an hour into a tabletop
and I let you guys win all right yeah
that's in the laws okay you found it you
shut it down
great what value is that going to give
you as a quote from one of my former
clients these guys literally said walk
that you're a mean man they literally
called me a mean man and the reason is
because I bring Hellfire and brimstone
I bring it all at the end of every
tabletop you have lost all of your data
you've been reduced in terms of brand
identity worse than Target worse than
Home Depot that's the whole idea if I
don't drive essentially to the biggest
data breach you guys could have as a
company I'm not going to be able to
focus on every bit of your incident
response plan so the whole point of the
Kobayashi Maru is I'm going to design
this to failure to figure out how you
guys fail figure out where all your
vulnerable spots are and that's that's
the idea when I do it I essentially
start with some type of real-world
attack what what's going on in the news
what's famous then I add some
practicality that's where I essentially
map it to your industry and then lastly
I top it with the risk you has a PCI
shopper you guys a HIPAA shop guess what
data's going out the window
I mentioned that I use a slide deck so
essentially like Darrell mentioned
earlier the talk now uh when I do this I
essentially take that scenario that
Darrell mentioned and I slice it up into
little details and I slowly present that
out one of my best scenarios is a lost
laptop out of the people that do
tabletops who does who has like their
best scenario that work really well no
one who here has done a lost laptop
excellent lost laptop is the best
because you can start from something so
weak to again the biggest data breach of
your company so I usually start with a
laptop on a Friday employee going home
had it jacked out of this car but
because he's a scumbag employee and
doesn't do we work on the weekends you
never noticed Monday comes around he's
looking for his laptop can't find it
check his office calls his wife so I
can't find it Oh can't find it
all right about noon I'll report it what
happened over the weekend well it got
stolen it got stolen now this is where
you start dealing with the people
because they'll say well we have use
names and passwords right right well
this guy isn't the best employee he
tapes his username and password right or
we have to factor guess what was in this
laptop bag is token so as you do
analysis you find out the attacker
connected over the weekend they've been
in the network they siphoned data it's a
great low risk to end of the world
scenario conducting tabletops conducting
what I've given tabletop training a
handful of times to organizations to
help them offer this as a capability
this
is the heart and soul of it when you
conduct it you're essentially playing
Dungeons & Dragons you have a handful of
things you've got player knowledge
versus character knowledge who works my
D&D fans excellent right so you know
what I'm talking about we're all in the
room it's usually not always the case
right so you have to take into account
that this might start off with IT we're
ten minutes into the incident legal
please don't comment yet you have to let
the scenario grow a little bit let them
show that they're involving legal one of
the reasons I do that is because part of
your incident response plan is
communication procedures how do you
bring in people how do you notify so I
try and test that early and then just
consider everybody in scope you provide
information as needed you change the
scenario as needed as people are clever
when I get a room with some of the
company's most clever people they're
going to throw curve balls that I have
to be able to adapt one of the other
things is making sure people participate
getting in their face making sure people
answer like I said one of the benefits
is testing and training so making sure
your participants are engaged in general
harassment I think is the title for a
mean guy for no reason you got to make
sure the stress is there the issues are
there the realism is there avoid
groupthink this is one of the biggest
problems as the tabletop goes on people
will just start to Mass together and say
yeah that's a good idea let's go this
way or gentlemen over here mentioned
that guys my boss you usually don't
disagree or recommend other methods from
that of your boss what I try and do is
make sure that if I see that twinkle in
the eye like somebody's got an idea
that's a little different make sure to
call on them figure out what he or she
wants to do how they want to drive and
make sure that idea has a stage to be
presented
the problem child for those of you that
have conducted your tabletops if you
guys ever had a problem child juice is a
networking guy I don't know why no it's
the networking guys it's not operate in
networking guy right here the problem
child there's almost at least one
there's always one in the tabletop this
is the person that's going to sit there
and poke holes in the scenario and say
oh that can't happen oh we've got this
or no way so usually the networking guys
like picking on sometimes sometimes but
there is always a problem child
I can guarantee it I don't know who it's
going to be for you but there will be a
problem child there will be someone that
tries to shut you down
the second you identify who that problem
child is you have to do your damnedest
to shut them down as fast as you can
come up with some this is why you have
to be quick on your feet come up with
some alternative when I do the lost
laptop once they said oh well there's no
way he could have had it use a man
password taped on it's like yeah yeah
there is a mate they worked with me
some of them brought up um oh we we have
full disk encryption like that's great
and the username password is taped on it
it's happened right so you have to just
keep fighting and and really get them to
stop you have to make an example you
have to stand up to them if you don't
this happened on the first one if you
don't they will steamroll your exercise
and reduce it to nothing question it is
Captain Kirk you've got to watch out for
Kirk you've got to watch out for the
Kirk's so after action summary at the
end of the tabletop I do a quick debrief
I make sure everybody this is where I do
allow the observers to talk and to
contribute I try and figure out what
went wrong what went well what other
gaps this is big because somebody might
be sitting on something when we move
past it we didn't get a chance to talk
about it
next thing is reporting handful of ways
to report the easiest thing to do is a
t-chart
here's your strength here's your
weaknesses next thing you can get a
little bit more crafty with is some type
of SWOT analysis who here is not
familiar with the SWOT analysis
handful of you guess what Google is your
friend I've got five minutes left it's
essentially a matrix of your strengths
weaknesses opportunities threats that
when you hash it out looks a little
something like this where your strengths
and opportunities map to your natural
priorities your threats and strengths
map to some easy defenses and so forth
now with five minutes left I'm going to
impart on you the most important adage
from the Marine Corps and that fight how
you train and you train how you fight
and it sounds a whole lot simpler than
what this guy was saying so we change it
up a little bit essentially when you get
into a tabletop you work through it how
you responded then is exactly how you're
going to respond when an actual incident
happens when I leave and that's my final
words for that group there's just this
huge wave of realism that either we're
rock solid or holy crap we're screwed
this is again not the only way to
prepare for an incident but it is one of
the better ways and it's a method in
which you can figure out where your gaps
are before an actual incident happens so
with that as I mentioned we've got five
minutes left
I can ask answer some quick questions
here's the final slide that you actually
do want to take a picture of or come up
to me and grab a card shoot me an email
I'll send you the slide deck I think
that's it so questions comments
concern save grounds alibis so the
question was how real do I make them
whenever possible I be as descriptive as
I can because you could say Oh a laptop
and we've done that right we've had some
organization where we don't want to name
names but when you say a laptop right
but when I actually say Oh Jim the
account executive for the western region
everybody all the sudden gets a solid
look because they know exactly what Jim
has on his laptop
so whenever practical and available I
make sure to use as much description as
possible even if it means pointing the
finger it's worth it because then we
don't have to play this game up
okay well it's also got this data and
it's got that everyone knows what Jim
has so the question was so the question
was on this scenario which laptop would
you pick the the one was not as much
juicy detail so the one with as much
juicy details right but I get that right
wellthank Kobayashi Maria right what's
going to destroy the company at the end
of the day shim with all the customer
information and the largest accounts on
his laptop sorry Jim question no this
this this is an excellent comment so the
gentleman
a really good point one of the difficult
parts in some of his tabletop Sigma
training is when does a customer go from
an event to an incident half of the
customers I work with they'll actually
have a definition that's its own finding
right there the way I do it is I
essentially just keep compounding the
problems and through every stage until
we make that determination I'm asking so
have we declared an incident and as I
got to the communication lines and this
is the last question we can chat
afterwards I'll ask okay is this an
incident no we're still an IT we're
still analyzing here's more information
is it an incident yet no we're still
analyzing okay well here's some more
information oh it isn't incident okay
now I expect you guys to follow your
communications involve other parties so
with that hopefully I think we just had
more of a discussion than a question
that's all I have I'll be around the
back I got to clean up for the next
speaker we can chat more thank you
everyone for your time this has been fun
thanks for being engaging
[Applause]