absolve thank you for coming obviously
the other
at work talk is very interesting a say
over there yeah probably go over there
for
um please ask questions anytime
is raise your hand and I'll his request
if you wanna wait to the end of so
'em our security on the island
this love is really in their because it
needs to be slight
all um
I'm not above the issue
for you know example thanks a in case
in and heard about it or normal that
much about it and
talk about it what it really is him and
I'm going up
talk about a above a solution for
from cash and lemme also it then I'll
middle name and
questions up so
on called wouldn't think with the
a.m. research does them I'll
to three years ago and when they a
sounds that a contrary to common belief
that you
are take power away from a computer then
up data in RAM not immediately
be raise rather will fade over time
and on a couple seconds column
but it can be and up minutes by corning
so up the the cold cold
if the really apply to do not call said
your computer but rather to cooling
memory the ranchers
and they've achieved %uh 10-minute
period with a
Stone cover: significant or of the
member so
'em when they folder
they combine that with the the
the knowledge that
when you have a for this bankruptcy or
any for
software a software needs to keep the
Christian ummm I'll well
this is a curious even if you have a lot
of computer
um were using for this conclusion and
so will not be able to get it for Julie
logging in or anything
they can now on uses
packed they got the memory cooler than
the
but in a different computer room um
you know runs a problem expect whatever
data memory
and so
carton for me just got lucky on
that up wasn't really that new research
I'll answer
ten years ago there was a paper or work
done by the end
at Rd founders I'll is
that that number doesn't mean
UK all on what was you
in this research was that it was bitten
by software
with %um reviews so
up and wasn't worth noting is the bus to
other the right which is program that
on as to I'll be refreshed every so
often
to to not lose there so rests on
other man replies there's that a
and they they are not really for
you know used a.m. as you remember well
on the solution to this affects
Americans
well as 65 some
you cash which sits inside the the gym
as living here
and leave everything else I'll a member
so on when you
try to five-year the infection are there
you will love you get to the
cryptographic key because
when you they held in memory
it's not a member and you can really get
to the key that
cash because there's no if read out
cached
other and also when you with that
you the casket sprays on huge
nation really my knowledge
nawaz again that they know that UK
so on
because I'm really mine is other
the 2533 his see congress
and huge game talk about I'll hormones
used in certain issues who is a I'll
lead
was replacement so at one point in this
talk is a
you know we are having issues with
memory controller initialization
because at all is low-level on
cousin called that needs to be
implemented for every
motherboard everything every member
control and that's all
really low-level custom
that's only for them avoids using memory
memories there yet
soul the we're looking for a solution to
sort of even their way out of this
complexity and what they
I'll I guess discovered is that you can
switch to cash in
for Mon them %uh you can use the cash
as memory am the cash taxes will not
sort of I'll in gym soul
what they do is they on agreement
discussions remote
and then as standards he called to do
whatever
on up they need to do up to initialize
the memory controller
of there some love or that need to be
done there but
for the most part a it brought them
possibly
so they don't have to you know you
every sorta aspect of warning them
um when trying to fight this
do security in terms of try to keep them
in cash only it gets a lil
tree so on there were some
John on also face England looking at
this
first one is that um x86
really have no cash management so to say
when you
as software try want to know about
what's in the cashless
they don't the cash on wanna cash left
been flushed
and all that there's really not much
there
so but you have to home
you know find a way to make sure that
would you put in the cash really will
not
automatically be perfect mem and
on thats um sort of
what from I get from the cash is remote
is that it'll behave like that
but you know obviously %um
security scenario here you want pitcher
will
my first approach was too just refresh
the moving over there into the cash
periodically
soldiers in KC it does get pushed out
Baggins
that game a hoe well I love you
better way and I'll came up with the
idea of
tricking the cash into polling data for
memory address that isn't there on the
system so if you have
maybe judy RAM then you have the
opportunities
where the year she had
address cash that trusted shove them you
know
you the very controlled no I can do that
a little never on northern
but rather orbin didn't work
I just could not get the cash to accept
data
were that wasn't the so
on if any you you know our
like a low-level see mishandling maker
that knows anything about this any
others
so on
second challenge is well with you
try to keep data and cache
and obviously you over his
the cash register G the most common data
nearby this review zones
faster on actors and if you sort of
say OK on keep just is then and there
then
your computer slow and I'll show you a
little ill get
so on one of the issues you
because on there really isn't any
fine-grained control
on using cast you you cannot just say
okay
freeze the long yes but keep the love to
catch going
on that's all on-chip known as
and there's Danielle any conservation
options
%uh the process provide are
what could be done is maybe many
level 3 cache if the chipset
bring by the a
on but nudging a looked just yet so
obviously with this and are being so
Anderson with performance on the
question is
okay of me minimize the effect of
lovers bars activate the the mall
much really is useful so if you're
having this is the
running that is greenlaw their only
to projector Keegan's would so
on part 1 only activated on its
really sent on and for that
to the front I'm use reblogged and when
your computer goes into standby
I mean standby else's bed where all urs
Corp
so and nothing
newsweek in not only keep the group your
memory
in at but also the most come
called so that of these some parts of
work sea views %um
articles are you there about feeling
that a all is
really a lot of work in progress so a
good
and to a lesser charge
there's an issue with the the keys of
you doing okay I'm a Christian he said
up 32 bytes okay I just need to keep the
third
by met in the day well as other through
goes
internally a lot of up grisham
work where they and on the who drove
cue that everybody's and your life other
is from the they then use for the group
B group in itself
all the keys goodall so you nominee
not only worry about 32 but he
al-sabah all these drive keys was if you
have those
you expect those they're just as good as
the master keys
say there the one being applied and
Butler you have
during the confrontation you have all
these you may be right there
that maybe you could want to do some
girls key you cannot samples
so the solution for this is
okay was implement girls that whenever
the up the software component those all
the
the distinction able dog
the investors for that eventuality and
whenever i switch to you
mode on then at all a certain that this
they've got into the red cash so
I'm s fairly easy if you're worried
about the
you that the his
the encryption key that is fairly easy
for the he's getting all those little
bit more
distributed but that's really hard the
any
meteor because you don't know where it
is might be some variable that
a items that during the computation
might be something that the
implementation
him so that really have to come down to
eighty
for implementation Pacific Solution
whereas the others up and these were
the the interstate love where you're
saying okay this is Mike Boehm
for provides them crash and
I'm flying on market
double so 1 I'll show you
is essentially on of activated
I'll me integrated uses them bus
a.m. it's not perfect yet so we'll
provide the same
the protection that 'em talk about but
inslaw's phones what really
of and I'm in the year
has proposed of at all the source code
on I'm not there yet yet
if you wanna see if you can go through
it on
if not them you know
is will though
where he is um you measuring approx
filesystem
and if I'm right ones with
elected by the mod and fuzz uracil
yet amid love you know
to
C
you
didn't enable striker
okay
as always um more
so what should have happened
is that the activation and when that
happens
here
on is that the maybe
as RAM methods activated and
on them all the keys that are rather
than
are them to the cash and the cash then
is problems although love the new normal
perch the cash so
I have no clue what were I'll
what was that like that on
performance was you type in the letter
only about half that online up
solve the level here love you
of your screen and if you move your
mouse for
for them as boss to come up
take about 10-15 seconds of Sweden
anything you could you know make usable
on
and the
were use the form adding you
I'm because of cash and over
so have
is arm for testing
on I created slalom some you both
their I'll will activity trolls
as mountains loss so that
though when israel %uh goes on his
previous column
and I'll buildings activate the modem
and I'll all the women
when largest region
go back for them implement so
our users were school Ali
okay so what up
on is on there's as well
them
there
you know the the ground at Goldman
writing
kernel module and 'em will initialize
the subcomponents on the car has grown
are %um for will initialize the
this conversion module and the reason
that
the for model
is that the what's that necessary to
invoke the
Mon or the registration 'em
I really found no Lee known really
good way to at that dynamically
ASM maybe rewriting function on or
something like that that all the time
look too good so what it is I copy the
Andrew
model them part
in this model and in order to
activate this model it and they close
the the improved
and on this model and provider for
the here sure and of course the
progress provide you or everywhere even
nerd so the
%um group model
is really just play the only thing that
attitude
really reno are on calls to the
the function that registers the Evans
of energy that needs for actively
activity
passions run wild and I'll uses
inside a function the functions that if
we can get in from the outside
on another model so you could look up
the
the events of it in the kernel and then
Johnson few
Nadia if you know the
the header a format and then try to
maybe page sometimes barging into it or
anything like that but
as Israel good practice so adding these
guidelines will
essentially a.m. till the
own model where he is are with
was but on the master in Group G
on of the the the derive
he's or your here so
past Ronald really love working growth
on deliberate overall he's that
I have and on
up insertion of other Paso everything in
the past
validated so you have a really
interesting cash
that stocked with and by
switching on the a non-durable
the she likes watching you sure that
nothing else happens while you run
through the
sold by accessing the on
data will automatically be added to the
cash and
on what I do is would take the heat
loaded into some registers wife of them
every
think the the key right back into the
the cash am them
you is actually good reason right there
sold for coffee
the he and the past
on I use as the registers because
they're big provide
up to 64 by of a storage capacity so
that you can copy
sees people by charms data entry cash
which is awesome
the you media headlines up
and then on
you know you rewrite the KSL
and offered castro
and yes
New Year arts like says
existing memory location well busy by
button
this is the restroom then just them
where
long
so
sorta the MARTA drive home
were up %uh
not seen that before so
like I said there's a improve the
embedded in this model
because there's no in wages or
dynamically at
love understood runtime: and
on one thing I am
touch is that on there could be a race
condition if you have all
horse
processor where while
working on these another and BBQ
the a well as which does the actual
intrusion the criminal
up that needs to go this on that is
any of the data while no is being
manipulated
Ashton of goods on when these his
the he all for
the activation national all
on one thing that buyers would like to
do
for performance is for more G Cebu
systems
to like that a few the as him
%um Cebu so that only the Cebu needs to
then be
cash which into the slow
most remote and maybe a as the Jazz
maybe then still get real-life
you from from the others you have work
cash
yesterday that of course homework few
are potentially to you share a passion
so Ivor but the
all what or most they
their lives do that um
and the you know he's got on the mayor
interview every day does all son of
bitches
to all that solves the last penny on
there's one issue that really is of
their
I also a catches you
to be a.m. because cash is so small
like a mother minutes third go but
level 1 cache up like about
on really a to on
figure out how June movie theater in
there
so that when you at another
they dive into the cash doesn't if the
another you know that's already in there
because
casuals yeah only laws a certain Mr
Evans
at his life in cash so
a I'm thinking maybe I'll figure it out
okay where with this
Evansville into the cash is there are
something outside
good if yes is I over the limit for this
cast the Civic on maybe then I would
a.m. where that ever was
moved to another address and the for
spawning
ones that are use with in love with them
re
3.2 mother and muscle that and his new
measures
good the cash on of
from you workers on
through you have any questions
then that smile almost there partner
thank you well