thank you hey guys so this talks about
finding zeros or whenever it is in
emitted system using average guided
fuzzy because to speak earlier and okay
my name is Quinn I'm hoping in Nanyang
Technological University in Singapore
and my eyes mostly focus on lowly one
system like a wealth of virtual machine
or binary analysis and happened to be
the father and maintain a few reversing
frameworks like capstone disassembler in
the corn emulator and keys to an
assembler alright my name is Kai Chen
I've been working together for many
years and I guess this is the first time
we are actually on a stage together
presenting our work together so yeah
that's that's what I'm here I'm looking
for JD comm ecommerce company so we
designed and me and my friend we
designed quite a fair bit of a badges
for security conference so that is a
part of it
mainly for hanging the box and I am from
hanging the box so I'm the crew our next
conference for this year that will be in
Beijing on early November and the late
November we all have fun now in Dubai
all right unfortunately the CFE is
closed so nothing much I can help over
here okay and then yeah some of the
conference's some of the things that
I've done before so that is basically
what about me
alright so pass it back to Quinn okay
on the background on company's credit
fuzzing and how does it work for a
better system and then you can show you
[Music]
and cannot fight
so this many heavy complicated
techniques to analyze the program before
we returns it
[Music]
in the American fuzzy show you meant
program so I can fight back
on so many issues to run on top of that
system existing issues issues in the
system is very system
the shell access so can I accept to the
shell and look into the system like a
typical and PC development facilities so
you can build new tools with a new
father from Japan do not provide user
compiler they do not provide our typical
or any an assistance so sort of her
system
secondly see that in many in the system
you do not have source code you have
binary only we have to be available for
Japan I am Scott and each human program
some in Malaysia not like cable to fast
manner is very slow is not reliable as
capacities I will show you see for many
many other points by John debug the last
series that CP only for impeded CPUs
like am 64 miss or puppy see some open
the sleep intensity only am and just
nothing for amps it for news or policy
there's a very popular film occitan
Memorial is all you stop what Intel and
very poor support and nothing for other
cities so we have many problems you want
to introduce a running system so all
right my tent we're gonna talk about
from the emulation and Y from the
emulation is we do have a very limited
resources when it comes to an embedded
system so we need to emulate and then in
order for us to uh put in more tools so
before we start all these things the
first thing we want to talk about is SOC
all right we are not not going to talk
about MC over here so we used to have PC
during the Odin days and then we started
to have for SOC so that is very big or
the vendor can started to build arm
mips64 devices all right step by step
chip by chip okay just like the bot up
there for that lesser power consumption
a better performance devices cheaper so
everything is scaled down from PC
including security so this is what we
are starting it alright so in order to
play with all these things okay clean
started of fossa and then he tried to
run and then I guess his lacking of a
friend that that can do hardware that is
the reason he comes to me III guess
Quinn is that right okay okay so the
requirement is you need to know quite a
bit of our knowledge on Hardware PCB
designed how does the chip runs
okay of course your new commands and you
need to love hardware and not only
hardware hacking that is very important
alright and I got a questions alright so
when you're talking about hardware
hacking you're talking about hardware
design it's always something that one
you once you cross over there are things
in a darkness that can keep your heart
from feeling the like again who knows
where does this race comes from
nobody watch blackhead nobody watched
Raymond reading that obviously all right
so okay so the first thing is we wanted
to test our from our father in a in a
former situation so I bought a
development bought something like this
okay runnings on a MDK chipset seven six
two one is a very very powerful chip
that can build a very nice wife i'm what
m we tested beer and our
[Laughter]
result is not really promising due to
the MEMS due to the design of the aircar
so we thought that maybe we can go a bit
further so we got a generic open wrt
runs and then we try to build something
on top of it and then we thought that
why not we try to get some real firm
ware and try to run it and try to fuzz
it so this is the thing that we are
trying to do so our idea is very simple
we extract the firmware it's either from
the flesh the website and the India or
from the apk some of the androids apk of
course are we don't touch those IPA
files some of the android apk actually
comes with the firmware ok or we try to
sniff a traffic put in a many in the
meter proxy all right and then we try to
extract the firmware so this is how we
get it all right so one method is to get
the phone back we either we extract it
we get it from an apk we goes to the
official website all right to download
the firmware which is possible for a lot
of screeding cameras a lot of router's a
lot of IOT devices ok or we need to do
some chip off take out the I think idea
flash from the device ok and then we
need to extract it we need to patch it
back so oh we need to go into a some
third party
modding website that actually provides
the original firmware I got no idea how
they do it but apparently they got it so
these are the things that that we do so
technically if you want to own the
hardware it's very simple you download
you patch me for backdoor you flash and
then you go and so our idea over here
you saw what if we really wanted to get
a remote code execution that is one and
number two is we want to fast and see
what is more and especially especially
from a country that I'm working in I'm
from Malaysia but I'm working China
right now from that particular country
you can have a lot of hardware with some
really really interesting backdoors ok
don't quote
I still want to go back to China and
work alright okay so previously I
thought Queen the easier way is a
Raspberry Pi zero can do a very good job
on an amp environment all right and if
we wanted to test on our 64 which is I'm
64 we can use a Raspberry Pi 3 that can
give us a very good platform honor honor
honor our 64 okay mix is a bit
challenging but there are tons and tons
of development bought that and can
actually help us to run a different kind
of our MIPS devices so how many kind of
MIPS devices that we need to purchase
before we can test our faster
all right so that is question number one
okay for me it's very simple I just
order from you know China website and
then and you'll send it to me like
yesterday if I order today so that is
what in China okay
Raspberry Pi is rather simple but along
the way we discovered that if we are
using arm or I'm 64 to email it certain
firmware it's going to give us a lot of
issue one of the issue is the sharing
Lipsy is not really compatible with the
one that they have due to the different
version that they compared you to
different platform that they're running
due to different SDK that they built
from different vendor so that is one of
the major issue that we are we are
facing right now so I talked in in order
to move forward we need a universal
platform okay something that I can work
in when I was in China am i right I'm
still in China and he can work together
when he's back in his own country so
this is the thing that uh the thing that
we wanted we don't want to ship hardware
back and forth just for the testing so
yep we try to figure out the way we
wanted to do a virtualization so we
can't ask our Father to put that our
Father is strong enough to figure out
the proof that our Father is fast enough
the main thing with the father are the
main thing with the virtualization is we
can add one or two or three or four
cores into the virtualized machine
together with hypervisor okay we can add
more ramps okay due to the design of the
spec of the original SLC okay we can add
in more space right not the traditional
in megabytes 16 or 32 megabytes or 256
megabytes limitation so this other thing
because when we tested with especially
MIPS or the original hardware alright if
we try to burn in a firmware opened up
the RT over so ever the it megabyte
limitation the 16 mega mathematician
really gives us a lot of issue when we
try to put in our tools we try to put in
off our father we try to add in more
libraries okay so and the most important
thing over here is we don't have apt-get
inside all these devices you do have for
Raspberry Pi but you cannot really
analyze those kind of all from a in
Raspberry Pi so we need up get we need
to install all kind of tools we really
don't want to do cross compile with all
these with all these hardware devices it
really killing our time I mean we got
better things to do in our life right so
yeah by by by running on on on a virtual
machine that actually gives us more
resources more flexible resources more
powerful thing and more space to run our
code and and by objective okay to run
all these a commercial devices without
source code and in order allow most of
us it's always we need to get one
process running okay yes I'm lying
normally too but one core process and
one supportive of process our explain
why later
so most of the time when you open up the
when you open up the main process it
always spawns the listening services
which ever part that they listen they
always compare Apache
not really opportunity a compiler web
server in there they have the attendant
in there you have all the services in
the so that's always a human when I talk
about this ok there are some CTF player
when we talk about only need one process
running people always says that you can
actually use qemu static to run it q mu
static - armed to run the entire process
but no q mu static allow you to run run
process and you cannot interchange
certain information with the sub process
alright the sub process simply means
when a vendor designer IOP device
irregardless of whether its camp is
Wi-Fi or whatever thing there is there
is one process that handling or the
listener order demons all right and the
other process will talk to the hardware
especially if you try to analyze up and
we try to fast smarts because right it's
irregardless of whether Amazon orders
Chinese piece because they are one
process that talk to the hard way pass
in the configuration and the main
process was started to pick up the
information and start the listening
devices so if we are using QEMU static
you will not be able to achieve the
intercommunication between the two
processes and during our research okay
we try to put up the entire firmware we
discovered that there is a couple of
solution okay
one of them of course is this one it's
called from D Y and Y alright but very
very nicely done but it's very heavily
rely on a scoffs casa FS if you move out
from there you cannot actually do
anything and it's very good for dealing
a virtualization but anything out from
that particular field model of modem it
doesn't prove any help all right and if
we search for more we discovered that
people used to run it on a very simple
way okay
2016 there's one guy actually posted a
video on how to do how to run different
kind of our
I'm for mayor or midsummer but due to
the requirement and the changes on daily
for inter Nexus or a different hobby
that you need to fit into the firmware
it's not easy to run so once we are able
to run out okay including hypervisor
which is very very important
okay that will make the entire system
faster especially for once we fix this
part we discover another thing that we
need to fix wishes to run the firmware
all right like what I mentioned just now
the lips see the the different kind of a
library is actually very very hard for
you to fit in the entire system so we
thought chroot
it's a very very easy development in
fact a lot of our exploitation training
still rely on a ch2 to make sure the
demon runs properly yes I totally agree
that that can be done okay but if you
want to attach with some reduce okay GDP
or whatever thing there is what are the
tools that can actually help you I still
don't really like the way on a running
gdb server and enter I will connect it
and do all kind of a bit stuff over
there so we always wanted a more easier
way all right
so in order to fix this field issue in a
virtualizing environment I want to run
the thing as native as possible without
chroot okay
I don't want to run in a virtual
environment and see through again dream
within a dream all right that is what we
wanted to achieve so we try to run in an
at4 qmu system okay for that optical
architecture the first thing that we
bump into is this very weird found not
found issue we try to run a binary okay
so we try to run a big bash inside the
system okay we have a virtual eyes
environment we download the firmware we
unpacked up from there and then now we
saw this this a it can be been bash it
can be been passage for for for busybox
like been bash it's not actually pin
bashes is SH but II just I wanted to
call it pain bash so we try to run it
and then
seis are found not foul and we we try to
troubleshoot for quite some time and we
discovered that the first library is
actually being required so how do we fix
this is we do LD and we do out and we do
a soft Ling and we get past the first
level okay it says found not found the
binary is there but it's actually the
call the con is always not there so that
is the first thing that face okay and we
got more library issue okay so the first
thing he saw once we move out from the
CH road we need to soft link or a
required library okay one by one or
different kind of a busy box command
which so you can see from the screenshot
is search for one itself Observatory for
and all kind of busy box settings okay
so once we saw fling or other things
okay then we are moving mirror to the
process that we can actually executing
that is number one okay and there are
some certain issue they will just give
us a sec fort without telling us what is
missing so we have issue number one is
found on far we have issue number two
which will tell us which now is missing
the issue is set for so we need to the
easiest things is always phrase okay so
our answer is the process and then we
discover along the way there are some
farm is saying we need to again patch it
we need to softening it before we can
get the process running so that is a
number two and then once we finish all
this part we discovered that the
interaction with our NVRAM okay so
anybody knows and VRM know it's a place
for you to store it's a place for you to
store your configuration inside your
hardware so the site for the entire
NVRAM is it relies on one process so i
did mention earlier just now there's one
process that talks to the hardware talks
to nvram and they will pass information
to the main process for them to spot the
actual process are the actual a demon
listener so
we spent quite a bit of time to try to
craft and vrm and try to make and try to
try to try to try to emulate every I'm
obviously V we feel we are not looking
enough so the the next thing we know
that is we should emulate the process
that actually passed the information of
the NVRAM in to the main process so we
we solve the issue over here okay so
sometimes the main process it's not
really look for the configuration if
they did not discover the NVRAM they
don't have the configuration the mayn't
binary will self create a set of
configuration for the system so if you
are into that that that kind of minor e
congratulation is very easy you can run
the binary as and when you won it okay
so fake NVRAM is always how can i think
the end we're i'm the communication
between the hardware hardware connector
and the main system is always using a
UDS unix
UNIX domain sockets alright so like a
Python scripts doing the put in the UNIX
domain socket written them whatever
information that they need into the into
the main binary you can get the binary
running as and when you want it anytime
okay so done and now one of the very
weird thing is wireless devices okay
it's much because our routers wireless
cam okay they need to run WPA
configurations okay wireless
configuration so we discovered that we
need to virtualize some sort of some
sort of wireless devices in there but I
was lazy enough to make ETH or rename it
to wlan0 and suddenly a lot of devices
box inside the emulating environment so
the model of the story over here is that
you don't have to email it or try to
simulate whatever hardware data that you
have
you just try to fit in the things that
they think is good enough for them to
run and to spawned the
before you can actually analyze it okay
so we talked about library feeding we
talked about we talked about feeding a
NVRAM he talks about wireless devices if
everything else still fail okay
just patch it all right this is your
last resort so there are certain parts
that they require all kind of weird
stuff that you you cannot fulfill in Sec
um you you cannot give you inside
virtualized environment touch it and
then you will get your way through to
run the entire firmware so once you able
to render from where within which is
virtualized environment that is where we
can start to run the dynamic binary
instrumentation so okay okay okay so far
you can already emulator firmware so
something you can introduce new tones
inside the firmware to run on our
virtualization system if a certain we
need to instrument the coatrack how to
build further for Imperial systems that
work for binary only without having any
source code so because we need to
instrument the program
it's a suspect so we have to somehow
human
so the idea be higher DPS vegetable the
best is a method for analyzing the
binary efficient at runtime by injecting
actual program at runtime so the idea is
executed as a part of original code
without changing any program the program
talking about the framework the
framework so you can force upon by
injection or for injection interesting
one
chuchi form now we want to human out
this code so we have we can run our own
good
after each action one after each action
to write so that we can and then then we
ran our own accommodation code and after
that we went through three and then we
ran our sensor code in P and we ran for
so the idea of DPI spaceship on either
the first one in translation so the idea
that translate this code to shun as a
code and you put the result to a buffer
and you run from its before after
translated like I said fern green
[Music]
we have less control of the code under
education and you need to know where to
each human it's much easier to design
implement and on this what we focus on
coping techniques our accommodation code
right after the origin right so and run
run I ain't to entry and being behind
around right first of all true we should
receive the position of true we should
the pushes energy and for
to have some help from some executable
memory simple in memory step step step
in stone buffer back into template
before and we branch from a tourist go
to the chaplet buffer has some
limitation compared to the inline
mechanism we do not allow is usman you
chaplet buffer you can overwrite to the
next basic block so just an imitation hi
this thing is very easy to design and
implement so I chose for
to the new place it doesn't run anymore
I can program already relocated which
I'm back to the original place after
that everything is going on as normal
jump from the origin place to the
champion buffer okay so the next
technique that we do not jump to the
chapel before we use any context and
original is a sham injection with Jean
please come back when you restart come
back restart the context and so with
Jacques on to champenoise want to come
back so next thing is because then many
a choo-choo meant a pentagram right to
change the direction the code change
direction to the champ so this thing is
called cone - champion simply restart
context which says the context before is
equal to come back and it going to come
back and restart the context right so
accommodation after the coup in this
mechanism
[Music]
because nothing beyond something better
for this specific space so it is our own
deep Arabic names copy oh so it can be
efficient on table spoon
so some special it can be like 100 times
faster compared to any other so here's
the diagram you can see that we all the
details about about our teachers and
teachers come in as a plugins we support
Windows Mac Linux BSD we support
capsules am stood for am new PC and
accessing some details about how
[Music]
to consider the convention because has
different way to you need to save the
context properly and we start probably
depend on calling conventions I think
you can look at the slice
so here's about how to support all
capacities so different a different way
to call the contact to connected to
support to branch from the origin to the
tuning offer so we have some checks to
support our PC for support
so because each size not fiction battery
we can over one or two it depends
I use my own
so ultimately you can optimize as cash
register how you say store contacts and
so on di - instrumental binary in the
system system coverage data from scratch
but we want of a photo which is very
powerful and very mature of other so we
do not do from Tsukasa
so many new PC system is much faster
than as you can experiment is a public
now
[Music]
and this information where - hmm - is
computed in scenarios in seminary some
music so what's going on so near native
speed
okay I'll I we don't have demo really
but we do fast one of the favorite our
Wi-Fi router in a China I'm not too sure
this part of the world whether it's it's
that famous or not and we discovered
feel interesting thing of course we we
get aa see okay we get a buffalo and
then how we across some shellcodes and
all these things and then we get our CD
but one interesting about this vendor
its you have one exploitable part in the
international version which is quite
obvious and on the China edition of the
firmware they don't have that particular
about so don't quote what I say it it's
not good and of course Anya on your own
Chinese version we do discover someone's
about which is still expectable but it's
not as obvious as the international
version so you can see me we were
actually a inject common we whippin on
the town and on four four four four and
we got down it not being activated
inside the system so this is fast by the
thing that we have built together
alright so the conclusion is we do have
certain issues on the close of software
we still have issue on on the IDBI that
are currently available out there and
then faster is not strong enough so we
bill offer Malaysian so we can do a dbi
we can do a guided faster for your
entire system so we solve three issue by
using a three different tools
okay the emulation the scope of DVI and
then finally the guided puzzle for
embedded system alright so uh yes we
built a smart Fuzzle not only smart but
one of the fastest of as I never I
believe if somebody want to challenge me
I will go away from here okay so we mail
it from where we have a cross platform
architecture
okay Anna Dibya of course we support
binary-only
and yeah we found quite a fair bit of
that and the the one in the tender otter
is uh one of them
we still have three minutes for
questions
yes we are not releasing it yet
just in case you ask so questions
another question is not about releasing
but do you need to do that by hand
no human the thing is with LT devices an
embedded system it's a fairly huge
binary that you are normally looking and
so they have two web servers they have
more kind of field stuff in there so
it's good to analyze before you actually
need to extract out the part you need to
fast and only you're fast you don't want
to faster entire format it meant binary
just for you just to facet each main
area right just also possible but you
want to be nice fat already to do some
method was to analyze the program before
that
applies for all cancers not only just
thanks
any more questions okay so thank you and
thank you a big round of applause