so as announced our next talk will be
leveling up your security by Mark and
I'll just hand over to you
Thanks so my name is mark Alec I work at
Riot Games my original talk was in 2015
so quick show of hands who was here in
2015 for it okay
so practically a new audience awesome
who plays video games all right cool who
has heard of Riot Games who has played
League of Legends I was played any of
other games yes in there so so stay
tuned and no I cannot tell you any of
the games were working on but yeah they
look pretty cool the tops gonna be split
up quick introduction into who I am who
ride are and then we're going to do a
really quick snapshot of 2015 which
seems to be useful considering most
people weren't here and then a lot of
the talks going to be based on 2018 and
then we're going to finish with like the
future section so staying with the game
and analogy of call that get into the
Nexus we hope we have a better sort of
success rate get into the Nexus than we
do when we play League cool so Who am I
I'm older than I'd like when I presented
in 2015 I didn't have as many gray hair
I'm Irish I do emphasize I've been
working a try for five and a half years
I've got about 17 18 years experience in
the industry and most of the time I'm
not actually doing work I'm trying to
surf I move to LA so you know surfing in
Southern California is a lot easier so
riot these are the numbers with regard
to the minor players that we have as the
screen shows it's a lot of players who
are up
and that brings the challenge of skill
so one of the problems that we've always
had with in engineering and security is
no exception is how do you do things at
scale and do an incident response triage
etc is quite hard when you've got this
amount of players because of this amount
of players you need a an infrastructure
and that infrastructure has to be very
diverse right our players are across the
world and how many people when they lose
and video games they blame like is
anyone like yeah so we don't want people
liking through genuine in most the case
people don't like a lot of the time it's
it's untrue which might be a surprise
that gamers lie but it is true so in
order to make sure people don't lie we
have a very diverse hybrid
infrastructure that spread throughout
the world so that it's close to the
players but that doesn't make Incident
Response or doing InfoSec very easy
this is eSports this is absolutely nuts
the people that play eSports have the
same working visa that for example David
Beckham or Zlatan has to play in the
retirement Football League in the US
right so you've got like an 18 year old
playing League of Legends comes from
Europe or China or South Korea that's on
the same visa that you know the Latin
Beckham Treo nori etc are like that just
blows my mind and does anyone know where
this is from No so this is the bird's
nest this is the stadium that the
Olympic Games run in 2008 so in 2017
League of Legends World Championship was
in the bird's nest which is pretty
unreal ultimately what we do everything
is about the player so the example I
talked about in 2015 was with the poodle
vulnerability so most people patch the
boodle vulnerability immediately we
couldn't patch it immediately because a
lot of our players actually run on XP
most of our players are in Asia a lot of
those players run XP not always
legitimately so the problem with that is
that if you run XP you actually need
lower ciphers so we
couldn't touch because we needed to
allow us as lv3
and we did parts eventually but I wanted
to make a point to illustrate that we
always think of the player so it's not
risk versus business for us when it
comes to security it's actually will
this affect the player will it affect
the player experience so in 2015 when I
was here bukhan I lived in Ireland a
really beautiful country as I said I've
moved to LA just before I moved to LA
living in Ireland Briggs it happened so
I was like cool I'm out of here
little did I realize what was going to
happen when I moved to the US but in the
Republic of California so I'm okay 2013
first year riot month 3 we lost the
password database not really a good
experience however it's a phenomenal way
to learn Network once you learn to
network an incident response you will
never forget it it's like you can't even
if you try to what I learnt during that
is that we had a really severe lack of
visibility and by that we were doing
Incident Response taking logs of
individual servers and then piling them
on so league of legends went through
this like hockey stick rough how that
happens if your player focus and you go
through a hockey stick graph you want to
serve the player right so you will add
more capacity build more network
security is typically an afterthought
because you need to serve the player in
the first instance but what happens with
that is that eventually it will come
back to bite you so 2013 came back to
bite us we got pretty badly owned we
lost the password database and we lost a
version of an unreleased game that was a
prototype via our founders Twitter
profile so so that was pretty awesome
experience but it was really great I
went there in a network and
as as you can see I've got pretty good
art I did not do any of this we've got
much more creative people than me and
it's pretty inspirational to see you
know what they do and how they serve the
player but ultimately this resulted in
firefighting for us right we had a lot
of fun abilities that we cost but down
read things like Moodle heartbleed the
Bosch phoner ability with various web
app issues so we were constantly
firefighting and it was emergent and
then we made decisions like this so when
you go to the cloud
you've got the developer developers like
I want to go to the cloud really quickly
because I don't want to go to ops
because ops will tell me it's like a
four weekly time the order server down
in all four weeks to get the server and
then or two weeks to Rock the server so
when the cloud came out everyone went to
the cloud and then they needed a test
version and then they needed stage and
and then they needed to be in multi
regions and again thinking back to
player focus if we constantly want to
serve the player we're like yeah we'll
give you that access we'll connect you
and this is previous to the days of
Direct Connect and AWS so we end up with
a Spaghetti Junction right and this is
like another element of emergent work so
we like to call this the wild wild west
of computing can you guys actually see
that and you see the orders of like it
in a way of the image so by iterating
really quickly and innovating what we
wanted to do was to serve the player but
basically we were like cowboys every day
we had blast radius that was super wide
we had shared accountability and with
shared accountability comes no
accountability how many you've got no
accountability you end up with a ton of
tech debt so we were like how do we fix
this right how do we get people engaged
to actually fix this security debt and
when I was here in 2015 I talked about
this statement for petsy so we never
wanted to be the security team in the
corner we wanted to be embraced and we
didn't want to be ignored so we wanted
to be brought into projects so that's
when we really changed our approach
we started to be like collaborative to
work with teams and like reach out so in
2015 I talked about a couple of ways
that we did this so the first Way was
t-shirts t-shirts are a phenomenal gift
people love t-shirts it's incredible so
this is gnar so anyone who was like a
really good security champion we're like
hey here's a t-shirt and they walked
away with a smile the the sign that this
was the success was when someone came to
us I'm like hey you give me a t-shirt
for being a security champion I washed
it too aggressively it's unsurprising
that we had a geek and they couldn't use
a washing machine but they washed it too
aggressively and they were like hey can
I have a new t-shirt and we give them a
new t-shirt and yeah it was a really
good way to celebrate success and make
people realize that security is fun so
another way was we used tools that the
rest of the engineering organization
were using and this particular one is
our FCS request for comments and this is
where we write a philosophy or a
proposal and then we send it out to the
rest of the organization and they give
us feedback and it's super useful
because it's incredibly collaborative
and it gets people involved and
ultimately gets people outside of
security also owning the solution
so within Riya it's a very feedback
orientated company an RFC these are no
exception it's not an approval process
it's about receiving advice and when you
receive that advice
you basically iterate through your
document so think of the document as
code or pseudocode and it has versions
and then ultimately you get it adopted
at different scopes so you have a
high-level scope and that's riot and
then below that you've got different
products like League of Legends game to
Game three Game four etc and for
security when you want to drive change
you typically want to drive change
throughout the organization so the
difficulty that we have is that most of
our RFC's need to be adopted at the top
level scope one one example is we wrote
a secure office RFC which which might
seem obvious to everyone here but when
you have a company in gamers no one
wants to think of security within their
office because it will stop them playing
games I don't know if you know but most
games don't actually work on HTTP or
HTTPS right so they're really good at
like finding holes through firewalls so
that's a big challenge that we have in
our 20-plus offices and when we wrote
that RFC we were like hey this is
awesome with 140 lines we got 850 lines
of feedback so for every like one line
of RFC we got like six bits of feedback
but what happened was we went from an
RFC that had like 60% alignment or 40%
alignment to an RFC that was 70 to 80%
of what we wanted but a hundred percent
alignment so it's really important that
you get alignment otherwise you're like
you know solution or product is just
going to fail
so this is the goal of the RFC this is
the Y and this is the hop so if you
remember in the incident that I talked
about we had no real visibility we were
just grabbing logs from individual
servers we didn't want that right we
want the visibility into the network we
wanted like loggin going to the central
place and we wanted to be able to like
tell our executive team or tell other
people how bad the incident actually was
as opposed to like sticking her finger
in the air so this is what an RFC
actually looks at like it right
can everyone see that or anyone not see
it but basically at the very top you can
see that it's adopted and you see the
scope and then you can see like a bunch
of action items what the problem
statement is and then we've got like
version history stakeholders and then a
bunch of other stuff that's like secret
sauce that I had to take out but we use
confluence and we treat everything as
code even our documentation so the final
thing I talked about in 2015 was a bug
binding program we launched a bug
binding program with hacker one in
November 2014 and I think as of Buchan
2015 we had paid out half a million
dollars we have now paid out about 1.8
million dollars which is a significant
significant increase when we launched
the product or sorry the service we had
70 percent of our sprint time for OPSEC
team being taken up by bug Bonnie that
quickly reduced within a few months to
15 to 20 percent and now it's currently
sitting at five percent
the really important thing for us was
always being grateful to the researchers
so we wanted to treat the researchers
like our players so a researcher focused
bug bonnie is was our philosophy as of
2015 with some really cool
vulnerabilities some really bad and bars
and vulnerabilities I think at the time
cross-ice Krypton was the biggest so
that's really where we were in 2015 so
now we'll move to the 2018 section
so as I said 2018 I now live in a place
that has Sun I had to bring a whole new
wardrobe here Europe in October is very
different from Southern California in
October my sandals are no good my shorts
are no good I need a coat but what's
changed right so where are we in 2018
the security team is not this big but
the security team has doubled in size we
now have around 50 people we have
multiple teams we've got platform
security so that's our team that's
accountable for our platforms we've got
bare metal
we've got multiple cloud infrastructure
we've got an internal cloud then we've
got our sac ops team so that's the team
that's accountable for like Incident
Response triage of incidents threat
intelligence Red Team Blue team purple
team whatever you want to call it these
days but a red team and blue team and
then sac ops work really closely
together and that's a super important
point for us like they're not segregated
if they help each other they work
together then we've got a rider security
team so we're games company so we can't
call it corporate or office security
because that would be too corporate so
we call it rider security so that's
that's all our office infrastructure and
our development infrastructure now we've
got our OPSEC team that's application
security but we've also added anti-cheat
it's Cal Poly people like the cheap and
games which is which is interesting
you'll find when your main demography is
like 14 to 25 year old males they don't
always react with the most mature
decision but as the security person that
gives us really good job security and
we'll talk about some of the stuff that
anti-cheat have done so 2018 right where
is RFC 242 so RFC two for two that's our
secure office RFC we now have it
compliant across the world we've
actually iterated through version 1 onto
a version 2 of that solution within 3
years so this is 20 plus offices
worldwide any office that needs code
access has to be RFC 242 compliant
otherwise it can't
be accessing code you may think that's
obvious but we had publishing offices
that had code access we had finance
people that had code access right so the
horse that truly bolted from the field
by the time security got there but now
we've tightened that up and everyone is
lined right we've had a complete culture
shift and everyone has come onto the
side of security and it's like hey not
everyone needs code access we have a lot
of automation and we predominantly use
saltstack
for a lot of our office security
infrastructure and a lot of error models
because a lot of people these days think
that servers don't exist but someone has
the rack the servers and rack the IDS
and rack the firewalls and rock the
proxy servers so a couple of the team or
you know cracking up the air miles and
then what we've got from it is
centralized logon
we've got visibility into our network
visibility into our hosts and one of the
things I talked about in 2015 was we
treat our offices code so every single
office can be represented by a JSON file
that we host it's machine readable and
we can query it to figure out is this
office secure which is phenomenal change
from trying to figure things out in 2018
and what we've also done is working in
the game industry and write specifically
we have a very specific threat until the
other companies typically don't have
right so the standard like signature
stuff that comes out from the various
vendors just does not work for us but
now with our own RFC 242 infrastructure
that's heavily open-source we have
actually integrated our bespoke threat
Intel into that so this is what it looks
like on a on a daily basis and hopefully
I've taken out all the secret sauce but
as you can see all IDs systems go to the
one point and then you can drill down
into each individual IDs system so
that's again like huge for us we've also
changed how we do packet capture on the
network so for those of you who use
Moloch this is Moloch it's been a great
success for us with version 2 we've
actually reduced the cost
the RFC two-four two-four to stack by
60% which has been huge
so Finance like this the business people
like us and we used to use security
onion we've ripped that out and we just
used sericata with a couple of our own
additions obviously but what we've
really changed from v1 to v2 is we we
own a lot more of the stock and it's a
lot more autumn Ottoman I can't even say
that word automated it's amazing how
much harder it is to speak up here but
it's like phenomenal change and
everything is much more visible we can
iterate quicker and we can spin offices
up and down but we also know the status
of every office cool so does anyone
recognize this so the answer should be
no the reason it should be known is this
is what it looks like if you're cheating
in the League of Legends so you should
have said no so I don't know how well
this looks with the light at the back
but there's like circles and then
smaller circles basically this is
scripting software that enables the
player to basically automate a lot of
moves right so they don't have to do
combinations they could potentially also
have cooldowns and things like that
monitored but it's super frustrating
like when you're in game and someone
cheats it's like an absolutely horrible
experience and scripting is essentially
where third-party programs formally
attach themselves or sorry forcefully
attach themselves to the game client and
then they use the clients memory and
functionality to accomplish out
basically to accomplish moves that are
like super difficult right another
cheating thing that we have is boostin
which is where you give your account to
someone who's much better at the game
and they like boost you up and then
baden-baden is essentially we you have
the game and put simulated like three AI
essentially and that's the level of
accounts and
sell their accounts on on ebay etc so
now that we have the anti-cheating one
of the things that we're seeing is that
a lot of people who used to write
malware are now actually writing cheats
and if you think about it it's pretty
obvious like if you write malware and
you're like hey I'm going to hack NASA
or US government or the UK government
then they're going to go after you but
the similar skill set you can actually
hack a game now do you think a judge is
gonna like hey I'm gonna put mark in
jail because mark hacked League of
Legends and then sold it it like just
doesn't happen like the judges like what
the first league of legends or what is a
video game plus there's like no laws
against it so what you're seeing is a
very similar skill set what we're also
seeing is that a lot of the cheating is
actually going down to the kernel and
the driver level which is pretty
incredible but it's like the next kind
of wave like that's how far people are
going so what's our strategy for the our
strategy is essentially three things
prevention detection and deterrence and
we have like a multitude of things that
we do we've actually started writing our
own software that is in the game client
to help us encrypt on this can krypton
memory so we're really raising the bar
there what we also do is we have data
scientists so we have like behavioral
models that run because you can you can
detect a lot of things like three
champion changes through like MMR
changes to like suddenly all this
person's winning like 80% of their games
or their plan on a different client we
also have device ID technology within
the client so there's a lot of
information that we have that we can
actually analyze how people are playing
and then finally there's like the
deterrence so we've been able to shut
down a lot of script in Suites so their
script ins like sweets are they could be
developed over like a year or two they
have a full business model they've a
full like you know marketing team
they've got like obviously an
engineering team so a lot of these
company or sorry a lot of these groups
are set up very similar to a company and
with our legal
I'm with a lot of the new tech that
we've introduced we've been able to shut
them down a lot quicker so the goal
there is really multifold and it's a
staggered approach and it's ultimately
to have a better player experience and
we blogged about this I think in July of
2018 so if you go to engineering right
Gamescom you can find an article on
riots approach to anti-cheat where we
dive into the technology and offer a lot
more so this is bog Bonnie now within
the last week we've actually updated our
bug bunny policy you can see it it's on
hacker wongkom slash riot and this is
where we've introduced legal safe harbor
so we publicly launched it this is about
protecting our researchers obviously
some of it's about protecting Riya but
it's also set in scope in terms of what
the researchers can attack so to speak
or can research into and we also
produced some of the figures right so we
want to be very transparent and honest
with what we allow in bug bunny but
we're also being transparent and honest
with what we pay now there are
exceptions where we actually go above
beyond and we have in the past gone for
like some pretty bad RCS but these are
the explanations so if you're able to
execute arbitrary code on a player's
machine for our client patch or for our
launcher for League of Legends client or
any mobile application then we will give
you $10,000 an example would be stored
cross-site scripting in chat we think
these are pretty much up there with the
top of the industry unlike everything
we're always open to feedback a lot of
the changes and improvements who have
made humble bunny have been basically
acting on feedback from players or
signing up players from researchers so
in comparison to 2015 the trends of
light changed a little bit I think when
I was here in 2015 we had
like fifty researchers we now have just
under 220 researchers in our program
it's still a private program 2015 we
suffered a lot from domain hijackings
cross-site scripting they've both gone
down through a lot of our tools through
collaborating with development teams
we're still we're seeing an increase in
improper authentication so it's 2018 and
authentication of a still super hard
thing to do and as I said we've paid
about 1.7 1.8 million dollars the since
we launched in November 2014 I think the
biggest biggest payment one-off payment
I think is around seventy seventy-five
thousand dollars I think that's the
biggest for like one particular exploit
so we took the t-shirt and we scrapped
it guys t-shirts are so 2015 and we
upgraded it to this metal so it comes in
a nice case you got a lovely fist bump
but over here you probably can't see it
does anyone know who this champion is
can anyone recognize it sorry bro yeah
so Brahma is this support champion we
like to see ourselves as the support
team he's got like a super shield if you
play him too aggressive it can go like
really wrong but you need to have like
some aggressiveness so we just felt that
it fitted really well and the reaction
to the metal has been sorry that the
coin has been awesome
and I think it's pretty cool but but
that's our new reward for like a
security champion so that was a change
there one of the challenges that we've
had a lot of riot is around secrets so
has anyone ever had someone in the
company leak an AWS API key to github
okay there's got to be a few more
because it happens all the time
does anyone know Bob I'm in Bob's
company the AWS API key was leaked cool
more hands got it thank you for the tip
right so in riot we've had it no
fortunately what's happened is it's been
noticed mostly by Bitcoin miners and
Bitcoin miners are not like the most
subtle of people so it's been pretty
noisy so we detected it now within we
think github and they have this new cool
thing and it's called git guardian so it
actually detects it and about a year and
a half ago I was playing around Russ and
I were playing around with canary tokens
so I was like a couple of the team's
tested like hey how quickly would this
be noticed right so there's three things
right get Guardian noticed it within a
minute and alerted me so that's like
super awesome that's new tech from
github
how long do people think it took an
attacker to like make a call to AWS with
this leaked API key yeah seven minutes
seven so you could see like a 80s STS
you know like version of Who am I how
long do people think bogdani took three
days like so disappointed
so one of the things that we did is we
were like in our evolution we started
the right tools right so we wrote a tool
to provide temporary API keys so that
when our developers are compromised or
the leak an API key that is like a
temporary thing right as opposed to a
permanent thing because permanent
credentials I think everyone here will
agree aren't a really good thing so we
wanted to eradicate as many API keys
that are permanent as possible we've had
really good adoption across riah and
like we feel it's been a huge increase
in terms of like player trust now one of
the things that we've learned over the
last couple years is it's good writing
tools right it's good providing
solutions but if you don't measure it
then how do you know if your tool is
actually any good or if people are using
it so we're really moving into like
metrics metrics metrics and so really
quickly the tool you've got a web UI not
everyone in AWS that uses either brass
or Ryder's technical so you've got a web
UI and that will give you the temporary
keys it links in with our multi-factor
off internally so in order to get a key
you now need to FA so that's a huge
improvement in security good removal of
risk you've got a command-line option as
you can see even though I'm a monitor
and have been for a few years I can
still manage the command-line although
usually what happens is I make a change
I push it to github and then one of the
engineers fixes it but it's super cool
AWS key CLI - version help you know so
it's it's got all the things you would
expect from a command-line so it's
really good also being integrated into
engineers workflow so our tools are now
part of our engineers day-to-day life
which is like huge and like I said we
want measurability
so we want to know are people using our
tool so we have our setups team runs an
elk stock
I think elk is like the much cheaper
version of Splunk
which isn't hard as you can see you've
got unique users number of push requests
number of OTP requests Keys generated
and we we took out the user names but we
can see how many keys are created the
timeline so this is really good because
previously what we do is would make a
proposal do a solution but we wouldn't
actually know if it was being measured
right so that's one of the big changes
that we've made also now I'm going to
finish by like going into like a little
bit of story time and as everyone knows
the cloud is magic the servers don't
actually exist everything is like an API
but there's nothing physical behind it
and I just it's not what we've
discovered is that this move to the
cloud paradigm has changed a lot of
people's perspectives right people don't
necessarily believe that they need to be
disaster recovery or backups but if you
look at the shared responsibility that
Amazon talks about you will find that
yes you still need to think of in the
bare-metal sense of like I need a backup
so storytime this is basically the
biggest screwup I've probably ever made
in my life at riot and I think a big
part of the reason I made it was because
I was burnt out
I moved from Ireland to LA and I didn't
take a break because I had all this
pressure on me I was like hey someone's
paid for me to move country and my
family I need to like knuckle down and I
never actually took a break and I think
that's a huge problem in our industry is
that we we don't we burn out too easily
right we don't take time out and as a
leader that was a big learning for me is
that I need to lead by you know taking
time off Americans struggle with like
the Oh
and personal time I don't think they
realize it's truly off most people in
Europe who realize that you know off
means you go away from work so it'll be
less super quick way to iterate how many
people here use AWS so okay cool I just
want to know how many of the terms I
need to explain
so you can really iterate and develop
and make products really quickly an AWS
and that's super useful for us because
we want to deliver a player experience
right we want to get stuff to the player
as quickly as possible so what happened
in 2011-2012 our web team wanted to
deliver content to players and they were
waiting on operations to I guess like
mine then take the mining and make a
server and build the server and they
just got pissed off still they were like
hey screw you guys
we're gonna go to AWS and they went to
AWS now that very much meant that we
were coming in after the fact so that
was like 2014 we were trying to think
how do we secure this so one of the
things that we did is we started running
security monkey now security monkey is
awesome the Netflix security team have
probably done more for cloud security
than any other team across like any
other company and I don't want to like
wash the tool but the problem with the
tool is that it literally takes so much
data so if you're developing tools and
giving them to developers what's the
problem with giving them a tool like
this
I've literally given them a tool that is
a red screen and told them hey there's
7000 security groups that have a problem
like if I'm a developer am I going to
want to like do security after that the
answer is no a product owner definitely
know so as a security team we're
constantly trying to work with teams to
get security into their sprints and if I
give them a tool that presents
everything in red they're gonna tell me
to get lost so we were like okay that
doesn't really work but we still need to
do something why because Incident
Response is super hard when you don't
have visibility
another thing with AWS is it's very easy
to create stuff and forget about it
right so in the bare-metal days it's
hard to forget about it because the
server is physically there but in the
cloud it's not there so if you're going
to do instant response
it's bad enough doing it when you don't
have visibility but trying to do instant
response in something that shouldn't be
there in the first place is embarrassing
right he don't happy like on you know
wired or TechCrunch or the register
going hey right games got hacked by a
server that he no longer needed it's
just so we were like hey how do we fix
this how do we give ownership
attribution give visibility and with AWS
it's through tagging so tagging is
essentially metadata that you can use to
tag most objects or resources in AWS to
figure out who owns it so we're like
cool let's do this being riping riot
what did we do he wrote in all their RFC
if we like our of season right as you
can see there's now a version too but
this was version 1 and it's how do we do
AWS right but AWS in a way that's secure
I know we can trace ownership so that we
can do that instant response the key
thing here is that if you look at the
security monkey screen with the red it's
like literally literally decision
paralysis you don't know what to do
because there's so many problems so
security is often about changing culture
changing behaviors it's typically not
about buffer overflows
you know popping the stack and things
like that a lot of the time is just
getting people to realize what they need
to do or make them want get them to want
it so we shrunk the change we focus
solely on ec2 instances sorts of one
element of AWS not everything and then
we wrote an RFC got feedback iterated it
and then made that standard across Rio
so similar to the secure office RC we
follow the same process this is what we
did they came up with three tags because
if you come up with multiple top if you
come up with more tags
it's literally Turtles all the way down
like you can then call it tech debt
within tags so we were like three tags
and then we did a schedule that was
staggered but we also created a schedule
as you can see that was notification
shutdown and termination so within AWS
shut down means it's still there
typically termination means it's gone so
another customer typically owns it and
we set it out over 12 week period this
is because we're trying to change a
culture we're trying to like give
people's daily behavior or workflows to
change and we wanted to like do that in
a staggered basis so we routed to a
called plot Inquisitor for short it's
called sync and essentially what it does
is if the AWS object in this instance an
ec2 instance is incorrectly tagged we
remove it if it's on owned we remove it
we also added some features to the tool
that enable those enables us to check
for features turned on so this means
that everything in AWS logs that all
logs to a central place we manage our
policy so this means that developers
cannot create policies that are way out
of scope and I talked about the main
hijacking it also checks for that
so what I cool those are the features
let's write it so we wrote it some of
those features got added Osby row and
1/3 iteration and then when I cool let's
turn it on so we have the adopted RFC
for engineers at the end of the day we
get super excited we're like cool we're
going to score this is going to be
amazing and then cloud Inquisitor turn
into Murderball now this may not be
obvious but when your tool is called
murder book it's not a good thing so the
implementation didn't quite go as well
as planned we actually took down clubs
so if you're playing League of Legends
in October 2016 and you're a member of a
club unknown it disappeared that's my
fault I'd like to apologize clubs his
back what we discovered journey was that
the team that ran clubs did not have
disaster recovery so remember the cloud
has a physical aspect you need to back
stuff up they hadn't on that now
unfortunately we have data in a lot of
places so we were able to get it but
look we messed up the communication and
caused a phenomenal amount of player
pain so if you remember our player
focused organization
what does player pain look like every
riot well slack slack is probably the
most toxic tool ever written it's like
IRC plus emojis plus reactions plus like
instantaneous and look I'm a huge Harry
Potter fan I used to think I was in
Gryffindor but that night I could move
to Slytherin and as you can see I lost
points a lot of points for my house but
the little bit that I've highlighted
this is Margaret Margaret is the product
lead for clubs so because we follow the
process be collaborated we got feedback
you know we engaged we had really good
intentions she actually came in and
supported us and was like as her like
we'd knocked their product offline but
because we went three things the right
way and we have like a culture of being
embraced
yeah she forgive us and I'm still here
so I didn't get fired but it really
sucked that's how I felt but what we did
is we did a root cause analysis on an
RCA and we did made a public
we did it transparently all in
confluence are our RCA meetings were
open to everyone and we got really good
feedback we even had an independent
rider outside of the team runner so that
we could gain some of our trust back
as I said communications we could have
done better we could have made it more
frequent we could have reached out to
other teams really interested in lis we
discovered that there was confusion
across riot tech about what adoption
actually meant so that was something
that was super insightful and we made a
lot of fixes with engineering leadership
with regard to RFC's and one thing to do
is if you make changes to your code
while your trailers live it's good to
test those changes it's also good to
have a code review habit of thought our
notification code had bugs but we
actually got a feature request in super
like player focused we were like cool
we'll do that help you out as a rider it
didn't really test it didn't get it
reviewed and then BOOM but the real
benefit of doing the RCA was that it
actually brought us closer to a lot of
people within tech and we got really
good feedback and I'd like to call it
that we followed the processes that the
tech org has right so this is us talking
in the language that everyone else talks
in not the InfoSec language and then
finally February 2017 it was moved back
into adoption and we were able to start
implementation and I think since our
tool has been running we've shut down
3,500 ec2 instances which is a huge
reduction in security risk it's also a
huge benefit for our finance team we've
also since moved around the EBS volumes
and
in the last week we've just launched it
for s3 buckets so despite what amazon
tell you s3 buckets are not are not a
secure file storage solution they are a
file storage solution that's scalable
with a lot of insecurities but yeah it's
not adopted a ride scope everyone calls
a tool murder block we open sourced
Atilla AWS reinvent last year so it's on
github calm ride games slash cloud -
Inquisitor we wanted to order our sorry
to purchase murder bot comm or murder
bot org surprisingly they're already
registered so we couldn't do that
so cloud Inquisitor was like the coolest
name we could come up with this is what
it looks like
so it runs in our own account this is
the security account these are multiple
other accounts on the right hand side it
uses STS ephemeral and then it basically
retrieves all the information checks for
security services writes it all back to
a database we have it on we have an ec2
front-end runner engine X Python flask
sequel alchemy and then the RDS database
back-end with my sequel as the database
so pretty standard tech it's a little
too monolithic because lambdas are like
the really cool thing and everyone's
moving the functions and Cerberus we
will move to a push based system
eventually there's just a lot of tech
data for it to remove so this is what it
looks like a couple things I want to
call out is again everything's measured
you can quickly see how many instances
are running public IP you can actually
see per account so replace Mars flight
space etc with like game on game to game
three all the other games that we have
them produced and yeah it's it's like
measurable visible transparent and it's
very easy for a product team a developer
to actually see what is that our
security posture within AWS with regard
to like demand i jaqen what systems or
buckets are missing tags and things like
and as I said it's open source and
github
you don't have to go into the UI he
would also email out notifications and
again everything is like transparent you
can see exactly what you have to do in
order to get your system back into
compliance right so we're constantly
thinking of like how does this look from
an audience perspective how do we make
this easy for the audience to understand
and to use in terms of like open source
in it if you're ever thinking of open
sourcing so we open sourced last
November where if you each spike a lot
of interest and then typically what
happens is it falls down if you go to a
conference or summits etc and try to
like evangelize it also you get a little
bit of a spike but it's like less than
10 hours work a month now for us so it's
similar sort of spike that we had with
bug Bonnie so how do we get to the Nexus
well the type of things that we want to
do is with RC - for - we want to take
our focus from Riot to the rider
so by this is what I mean is I was base
protection investigation with a very
light footprint is our goal we want many
network points of presence we really
want to think about how do we have
visibility when the rider is using write
stuff off of network because I know some
people in our sac ops team worry about
Allah and that's really the way we're
moving moving there so data finds its
way home home being the right security
infrastructure quickly with author goal
ultimately is to have no permanent
credentials and access policies that can
be spun up and spun down dynamically
within seconds like we're a little bit
away from that but that's the overall
vision like we really don't want static
credentials anywhere and then we have
multiple infrastructure's bare-metal
cloud so we've already started this with
cloud Inquisitor what we want to do is
have platform independent solutions so
everything that we do should be platform
independent so that if riot decides to
go to Azure Google cloud etc that we can
literally take our tools and our tools
come work regardless of the environment
because at the end of the day
shouldn't be that difficult it's just an
API that will need the query we've
removed a lot of tech debt over the
years the problem with that is you can
only go so far right so we want to work
new products a lot because if we work
with new products such as R&D or a new
product within legal legends or new
products within like internal riot then
we can create solutions that they can
leverage and these solutions can be
shared so the other the older tech or
the older products can then leverage
those and that's really our focus it's
like what can we do with the new stuff
that we can just deprecated the old tech
so that we're not constantly trying to
go back and when we've tech that we've
seen this work really well our apps tech
team recently ruled out some code
dependency stuff and we're out the
leverage of our shared infrastructure
that our global infrastructure team have
so for Java and go we can now with build
code analysis into the build pipelines
for all dependencies so that's an
example of like reaching out using tools
that other teams have created that's
like shared and it actually reversed
that worked the other way when our
global infrastructure team leveraged our
work we have a service that we built
that essentially you have to go through
in order to access our production
infrastructure so her game
infrastructure and they were able to
like query the endpoint that we provided
take that information and then leverage
it to raise up their network security
because everything is in code right
everything is quick queryable and
machine readable we're also going to
continue with the measurement because
it's super important we want to
understand how good our stuff is is it
being used where is it and then finally
collaboration right we want to continue
to collaborate contribute more do ss OSS
we will hopefully open source AWS key in
the next six months to a year and we
want to basically continue writing on
our blogs engineering at Riot Games has
got three security blogs in the last
year how we've evolved
poor bunny and an anti Chi so I take
away from the talk if you're all still
awake
is that we started with instant response
emergent urgent work we move to like
visibility being embraced working on
collaboration and starting to write
tools and then we took those tools I'm
going like other metrics but we also
integrated the tools into everyday
workflow for our engineers and in
addition to being embraced what we
realized is that on occasion you have to
block but it's not the block and it's
the issue it's how you communicate it so
that's been a good learning for us and
and we have blocked which we wouldn't
have done in like three or five years
ago and then finally continuing to
measure so that's the end of the talk
thank you
okay thank you for the great talk and
sharing the evolution of security at
Riot Games with us and also contributing
to open source security in such a big
way I think I'm sure there are a lot of
questions so if we do a short show of
science I'm gonna get another microphone
so you mentioned that one of the the
bank is GP though it was like 7075 key
can you elaborate at all on the bug that
you peeed out from that not not entirely
but it was remote code execution within
the client it's pretty cool actually
I'm Victor
I can't hear let's try this can you but
you share any thoughts inside the
threats obviously a large organization
with I guess a lot to lose
you've got you talked you spoke a bit
about threat actors on the outside
obviously to get the most out of abusing
your services so on with an inside
position would be a useful Ally right
that way what was the security team do
you are you doing about the insider
threat Oh insider threat that you can
talk about so I think it's quite public
that if you've been following Riot Games
that we've had leaks so there's a thing
called reddit karma karma I'm too old
for this but a para Nate's really
popular with the Millennials and it's we
like we have we have a threats team and
they're pretty scary on some of the
stuff that they do we've got data you
know from the hosts it's not that I
don't know I'm trying to figure out how
much I can tell you like we work a lot
with all their games teams I mean with
game teams within the company we work
with companies outside that are other
gaming companies within like a game
security group within what we really try
to do is we try to make the teams
accountable for their own security but
we like we have host security stuff that
we have that we do that most companies
would do that it's pretty good at
detecting unintentional things there is
probably ways that people communicate on
select that they're going to communicate
exactly the same way on reddit
surprisingly quite a few people after
the leak actually admit it
which is easy there's also certain stuff
that's leaked that only certain people
have access to that make sense so it's
much easier to like not narrow narrow
that aspect on with some of the work
that we've done in the last year we've
greatly reduced the amount of people
that have access to code access to
production so from that aspect and
insider threat is easier to triage
because less people have access to it in
the first place things like I guess I
can talk about it because it's public
but we we recently had someone leaked a
slack conversation and that's super hard
because everyone has access to slack but
again there's just there's very signals
that are that are obvious when someone
does that in terms of like how they
communicate and things like that
but overall we have a culture that's
like we default to share and we really
try to to to do that because we want
like an open innovative transparent
culture and with that comes like an
acceptance of risk that just
unfortunately some things are going to
have are going to be leaked
I think what we've started to do is that
when there are things that are super
topical like everyone wants to know when
is riot release in another game and
there are people that have access to
code that could potentially be the next
game it's really difficult to like to
manage the risk versus the benefit of
being like open and collaborative so in
those instances what we really do is
until become less sensitive we restrict
the knowledge as much as possible so
again it's it's kind of like a little
bit like the anti cheat stuff prevention
detection and deterrence but we have a
higher acceptance of risk because we
value our culture and the ability to
innovate more if that makes sense I'm
done with me when we do detect insider
threat to add to the deterrence we
sometimes communicate it what but other
times we don't and again every situation
is unique so it's not a great answer but
it's like literally every situation is
different and I think the big difference
that we have is we have a lot more
logging throughout our infrastructure
then we had three years ago that makes
investigations easier does that help
okay next up is like a short coffee
break so you can continue the discussion
at coffee table and we will continue
here at 4:00 p.m.
you
[Applause]