so I'm arming smile footage this is
Willie height and we're going to talk
about some vendors how many of you know
how many vendors you actually have that
you deal with how many vendors 15 so so
15 you're lucky it was great I think
we're up to what almost 4,000 now yeah
yeah so with you just merged so we're up
about 4,000 vendors shake here he'll
place in a whole suit is not accompanied
them so yeah it's about 11 12 different
companies fall under that umbrella all
right all right so it's going to be a
right line we're going to start off with
a little bit us why do we care about
vendor security and why other people we
think should care then we're going to
talk about go through an example or
sample process of health care how we do
it in health care now not really
specifics more of a broad overview and
then hopefully the end well some time
for questions and discussion I will try
to make this little interactive will ask
you guys questions would hope you'll
answer those off so be kind of a
learning community alright moving on
about us I am in the t-rex in this
situation it's this was our christmas
event at work they have ugly sweater
contest so where Willie has a wife so
she made them a sweater I have amazon so
I with the t-rex
you can talk about yourself first Willie
also Willie height I've been an IT
probably close to 19 years I'm gonna
deflation security about 13 14 years
I've worked as a consultant starting now
and I like the contracting and then I
met a girl and she wanted like medicines
and all that kind of stuff so I had to
get a permanent job and I landed at
deloitte work with his gentle back here
for about six and a half almost seven
years and I was in administration with
them back to risk and compliance and now
at healthways which is bought by share
care I am working in the Information
Security Administration compliance a
team leader we had a lot of work on our
tables and vendor security management is
definitely one that has pretty much
captivated the eyes of leadership and of
course in businesses especially health
care better suited to its pretty
important part of your day so alarming
spa judge as you never say my last name
I'm go with Smith or just Armand so
before I joined information security I
actually started in physics so a
bachelor's and master's in physics
there's a teaching before this so f kind
of bored so I decided hey security looks
pretty cool i'll join impersonation
security I'm got chains on the
administration compliance side luckily
teaching is just like dealing with
grownups they always bigger and you have
to figure out how to make them
interested in what you're saying so the
best way to make people interested is
hey this is how much money we could
potentially lose if something happens
with this vendor so start with
complected ministration moved over to
the sock but still work a lot on the
vendor security side of things
the wily here sometimes vendors we think
about vendors we just thinking about
like partners people that actually
physically show up and physically have
access to your facility there are so
many different suppliers now there's a
lot of people who are at companies that
are mid size too large they uses what we
call T cards or purchase cards and
they're engaging in vendor relationships
without going through the proper process
just because they take the card and they
get a software as a service agreement
and all of a sudden now your data is in
many places that you have an authorized
because they have the ability to do that
there's a lot of implications to that as
we would be violating our own policies
but we also are if you're dealing with
customers and you deal with other like
partners you actually have to make sure
that your policies your procedures the
things that you adhere to these vendors
also like 82 and you'll find out that
your vendors have vendors and you have
to ensure that those lenders adhere to
that and doing that is definitely like
not a small feat at all so there's so
many different areas where we could be
financially responsible we could have a
bad situation where our name is just you
know downtrodden because of how we are
engaging and not actually getting the
vendors to adhere to our stuff we're not
enforcing rules than legal impacts that
are involved in that but contractual
obligations that's again back to the
customer thing in a human safety
sometimes you know that's what that's
our greatest
ask that too sometimes it's one of the
last days we consider and think about
when we go into these engagements
because you money is what talks let's
jump into example so how many of you
know that your company purchases
software from anybody how many of you
know what questions you're asking those
awkward vendors or do you ask them
anything or like Willie said hey here's
a pcard let me about 50,000 licenses or
whatever this is so if you were talking
to this software wonder what kind of
questions you would you ask like motor
important questions for you to know
about that vendor anybody because I'm
tired people and is exceeding to realize
to get questions about our spirit if
it's quite a common see that like the
idea tech question you don't good
organization security questions from
arbys night and it's really I believe
that's because like this is it's not new
but you know we've been engaging with I
build a relationship other people to
expand and enhance you know the
practices but it what is it was that you
know I a company was held responsible
for something that a a cell company a
business associate did and that had
financial implications and that begins
to scare people and companies when they
see that okay something that I'm
attached to could actually ruin my
reputation could actually ruin
relationships and possibly even you know
have criminal
you know consequences to it so because
of that there's hundreds is not you know
depending on the size of organization
thousands of vendors that pre-exists
this whole process what we call vendor
security today and it's not common for
them to ask you about your security
policy because it's like oh just what
you're selling work that's what their
focus is it's like and from a business
point secure supposed to support the
business and these business leaders said
hey carbon what is what we need let's do
it trying to move forward and sometimes
we find out about it after the fact it's
like okay now you need to call them and
you're moving on to somebody else you're
not interested in talking to me you
don't want to tell me about your
security posture and all of this curse
their so I have to find clever ways to
like build a relationship with you and
at the same time evaluate you and do it
in a manner that's not going to be too
imposing alright so as open as you said
you guys don't you security questions
aren't really asked of you larkin and
I'm getting art piece for when we're
doing engaging new customers level
it's less than a percent of the time
that I felt awkward hilariously
dangerous this software that you sell is
it just like off right like do you have
to have D like a option for own
pregnancy and of options for cloud do
you do you have a maintenance agreements
that comes along with it would you ever
need to have access to the facilities or
like the hardware or software doesn't
work so software companies are not
usually what that at the vendor but when
we get into engagement where you
actually let's say higher carbon block
coming to implement this they're paying
them for that they're going to need
network access they're going to need
access to your facility and it's like oh
you know we think it's a quick install
but our customers don't think that way
if it doesn't take that way they have to
have background checks for our employees
so why would we stop when you get a
third party in place a software person
it's like only they're not HP they're
not consultants that are going to do
work on on behalf it's not augmentation
this is software but software comes with
people and needs and sometimes those
these impose on your territory and so we
have to be just as visual to protect
just like we do with people who are
directly hire any other questions so
from a vendor's point of view hardly any
security questions I've ever asked so as
a business what what would you like to
know about your software vendor that
really a ver SI something only show and
then we're losing energy in a
[Music]
they are who's Ed part of it I'm going
to a new one and help regrow bus access
control problems make sure you have some
swing what is a different one this world
it tool set well different reasons this
is a public comment and one question get
active if we do find it all with their
audiences timeline energy security we
have their service little things but
we're very fun time we will be working
with do we have a name contact there
that we pick up a social safety is our
number on there going to go so we had
three months and did that kind response
requirement yeah sometimes it does just
ship and sometimes you work in community
rotation yes this record is good
honestly I get a love that vendor but
also that vendors settled build interior
Microsoft us
on one side but another thing that I'm
getting is changing like two years felt
very deep but last year half of
engagements and this year and then the
level pressure is changing you guys are
here Harry noticing our new rules
constantly changing is getting warmed up
and it was probably four years ago I
minute health place for five years the
process happened one year after so that
our process is only four years old I
think loud was not a big forerunner our
discussion piece in the beginning it was
more of are you really a network access
are you going to need facility access
and just talk about your actual security
posture like what is your team look like
what is your privacy posture look like
for now let's see like 2014-2015 it
became more and more of a requirement
you know we sometimes do things because
it's just industry expanded and in other
times we do things because some of the
people there you know providing the most
income to us that big deal that big
relationship that you have they require
so you know we weren't required d hi
trust factors wouldn't even have been in
a vocabulary but you know anthem and the
different ones that we have
relationships with that they required
itself like now we require and now we
have to require our vendors to require
and we want them to require there
to require and it's not really so it's
it's definitely changing and I think
many of that because of the the intense
attention in auditing that's happening
from HS age of 80 tesco whatever it's
called and the big things that we see in
the news like no one no one wants to
have to work out 10 20 million dollars
just to satisfy some sort of like breach
and then you have to rebuild your whole
reputation is there that 10 or 12
million dollars this is the beginning
it's not even talking about all the
forensic costs that you had all of the
work workers that you have you know
working on this internet you know the
corrective actions it's like you can
that let's say it's a ten-million-dollar
briefs but by the time it's all over and
I'm if you look at the past cost and the
future costs and all the requirements
that's probably like 100 hundred and
twenty million dollars if you're not
making a whole lot of revenue I could
close shop and that's why people care
that's what we're asking all these extra
questions and that's what are the
responsibilities more and more on the
people who actually have these
relationships so here is a set of sample
questions that we asked our vendors
don't lead into the big three questions
that we asked so one of the key
questions that we want to know is are
you going to store transmits or access
the company's data so if you're in
health care visual phip I all the time
if you're going to access our data we
need to ask you some more questions so
also are you going to host sore are you
going to host the software or we go in
the house to soften currently
so also are you going to supply us with
a couple of contractors how long is that
contract going to last hello so like you
were discussing earlier if we hosted
time if you're hosting it or if we need
you to come and install it for us how
long is that going to take what kind of
background checks do you do on your
people what kind of training do you give
those people so is it a
software-as-a-service pull any third
party or external software admin access
be required so at that point we'll also
need to start including you in our audit
process so every quarter we're like a
cable these are the people to have
access to this from the external side
will reach out to you will ask a or any
of these people no longer on this
contract yet so we can remove their
access also in our contract will
actually include hey we need you to let
us know when someone has terminated that
is working for us or on our contract so
we can remove all their access
immediately also is it we've come into a
lot lately people are buying freeware or
open source software things like that I
can just install this it's free I don't
need to tell you i have this so it's
getting in touch with our developers
because well usually developers with the
first people to install tools and try
them out so it's like hey guys you even
if it's free we still need you tell us
as much information as you can about
this you install something it might not
no longer have support like centos 05
that last week is a week before like hey
you hope you might still have this why
like we didn't know about this until
we're looking through the network maybe
doing like an internal tentacle there's
like 15 of these servers out here for
some reason and our little group was
identified that even though it's it's
like freeware open source and sometimes
it's just that if you're doing it on the
small level but they're like Enterprise
inversions and it's like yeah I was free
until
and now it's no longer for you by the
way we're taking you to court so yeah
that's another reason why you just want
that I guys toss on your teeth and
ensure it is what it is and obviously
will you support any customers of ours
with the software at that point we have
to also include our customer
requirements so if all our customers
okay everything you do from now on you
need to push high trust a software
company is probably not going to like
well I don't know we're going to be a
hydro certified as a software company
but we're going to have to push that
down the line as we said earlier and
they're not usually the first thing we
ask is so the do we have software that
already met our requirements are you
just going out there because my friend
told me I should use this so we can work
on the same project later or do we
already have a tool in place that does
everything you need except for that one
functionality way now the toolbar is
purple and you just want it to look
different so we asked people that and
then if they're like well we have
something similar than we need them to
state a business case then we start
including their manager and their VPS
and as soon as you really as soon as you
start including people's higher-ups
they're like oh we don't really need
this software anyway no more we'll just
you know we'll do what you have this
yeah this this process here and then
we'll I think we'll get to on another
screen this is not really a security
function it's like you're integrating a
lot of pieces altogether as a securement
like beginning like we start with the
money as we end where the money is but
then you got privacy in law of this this
is legal this is information security
it's a lot a lot of different roles
involved in this evaluation
all I follow to make security which is
under BTW what they call business
technology IT a min real well so we all
were there but the roller I key is
working on it then our biggest task was
just including all the other departments
so financial legal procurement acting
contracting so financial is 12 financial
is the key player and everything as long
as you each of the people that are
giving out the mind is like well
whenever someone's requesting something
they need to go through security we just
tunneled everyone through they make our
process a little easier as we said we
had issues with key cards everyone has
issues with key cards like oh you and
those out to be fun you don't know
what's being charges until you get an
inventory a month later to finance and
they're like when we buy this vendor
like why are they here so it's getting
financial board was our biggest goal and
now that we've been purchased are you
don't looking at us to make sure
everyone across the board in finances
like okay security requires this this is
going to help us in the long run it
might slow things down but we need to do
this and then last but not least who's
going to pay for this when what
department you aunty who can we talk to
verify that you actually need this or
who can we talk to the escalade to make
sure you don't want about us anymore
vendors so vendors software suppliers
Kyle falls in same group we split it up
well we do software it's a little gift
that pre questionnaire and then vendors
have their own as well so let's start
with if you have 15 vendors mr. a
luckiest man on the planet right now is
what type of questions you guys usually
ask them as you starting to get involved
with an engagement
or is what time that it's awesome and
usually I'll just ask for soccer horses
and from there that you can muster
questions is against the open source
often times making sure the collection
is relations we're following items the
Nazis by a process without license so
yeah faces a bunch of SAS or one of the
key things we do is class harvest to our
company hang on the vendor we have to
classify the risk we'll talk about that
in a little a little bit with a couple
more slides any of you how to eat how
did your company or for my security team
classify risk based on vendors benders
just risk there's a high low medium
deals in packages hosting companies in
your tire
[Music]
and yeah next question obviously ostad
will they require access or process your
data with insurance I'm sure you've been
just get all all the data process help
with that same thing with healthcare our
vendors are always touching our member
data so making protecting that and one
of the questions that people don't
usually think about a lot of this
location matter because the location
where your vendor is or their support
staff whether the data center is
actually mattered to the company and
like we don't get into the weave of
contracts like we said we're relational
security and it's like all we approve
something we sign off on it we've
approved there it's okay but oh this
customer that utilizes these services
that we just got this weather for they
have an issue with anybody that's
outside of the US and they primarily
want certain types of jobs or roles to
be within their own state so we like
violated on multiple cases was like what
you know you know they're ISO certified
and they just seconds so so you're very
low so if you get tender head to work
there's on far west coast okay they're
not someone online to over two hours
main three hours a day and we have very
very powerful very loud people prompt
and doing his title before you I decided
contractors and helps head off yeah
that's key before it's up it's also one
of my christmas wishes you can take on
this and some of your comments by
business and the vertical with their
access promised data but are they going
to access the process your happiness
your own network you you are you got you
got a useful write checks that your
internal people's comfort of you you
make decision only you can only connect
with the company configured for company
which laptop we just fine so on or you
also get a visit and the ideas will for
the majors they don't say it's a better
quality of you they'll also a laptop to
work on regional in free their laptop
all the other side spaces on your side
and you can access behind the Laird
creative corporate protection so there's
some things their best work out for EMR
contractor and upfront agree maybe
there's a subset of people that you want
to use to allow your side as opposed to
anybody that's in the service department
but you want to bet the people
individually and you want to know on the
other side get some happening what's on
the inside
software controls are going to have when
they want to access your network or even
if they're going to access your data you
can send data to them they're going to
put it in a private sandbox due to the
north on it it's going to come back your
side how he is sure to the dance up on
some good straighten the notification
higher score question it away from the
mountain times I see customer off for a
less expensive support option that is a
spot for for a piece offers that shut
down the entire network gotta get all
the credit maintenance not a primary and
[Music]
reported Monday water look how we have a
problem get less correlated many
customers flock and have enough I mean I
anxiety explaining we stay overnight you
gotta be current is your knee and now
[Laughter]
i'm sure those last second support
aren't cheap basically we didn't do the
right thing and organizations but a free
go ahead and pay the extra X number of
dollars from post and give you need easy
there then going out for your questions
of second Gill these are you do the
three key questions that we ask so this
is what we initiate with with the
vendors well in our PP so so the vendors
office by require physical access to the
facility does vendor software supplier
require network access and will this
store access review all our stuff all
the data so if you answer yes to the
first question note see the other ones
will give you a badge but that's only
like you're doing maintenance in the
building
yeah still comes with agreed then or we
used to have a quiz but they don't like
that anymore so now it's just agreement
and you know they read and sign it's
like the Indiana said so we start all
our securities with the software intake
and then we have another intake form and
then we move on to these three questions
so based on how these get answered and
what type of data they're looking at we
give them a pre ranking so the types of
data classifications that we look at our
public restricted confidential and
internal data classifications yes so the
dead classifications is along the line
of the shredded understand what is what
like I think it's better to ask about
the data descriptions because everybody
has their own interpretations of what PH
is or p is you know google has is
interpretation and the lesser dictionary
has its interpretation at our company
member data is considered pH I so
anything that our customer provides you
you know is considered thi and we do
that just to protect it at that highest
degree and ensure we're doing our due
diligence but these data classifications
for us and security professionals if we
have data descriptions that we can see
if it's public is just something that
you know if it's lost its lost there's
no harm in that restricted is usually
dealing with the customer data or like
your employees like personal information
or banking information or their medical
information their address confidential
proprietary like this specifics it's
about business dealings it's it's about
you know this mystery project it's
supposed to you know take
Healthways from from one level to
another level that type of information
you don't want your competitors to know
about and then internal this is the
stool information that is like useful to
you procedures processes that you have
in place and just internal data like
about the company about a bit about this
disease lifetime so these are these are
the things that we use their like kind
of understand how we're going to
evaluate example yes so those key
questions they start off with internal
people whoever wants the software or
supplier those three key questions and
questions start off with in and then
this data classification is like this is
how data is classified in our
organization and this is how we have to
evaluate like what type of data is going
to be a part of that engagement so
there's an internal questionnaire to
tackling and it's providing that's
information and sometimes you can ask
them to say hey is it this that or the
other but that's dangerous because they
don't know so if she stacks four
elements but give me examples of what
type of data you're going to be dealing
with and I'll make the call to classify
it in the profile do we provide this
what will work like a request for
proposal yeah you're talking OS which is
it yeah the security required with
documented that that would be like
spelled out like how we refer to
whatever exchange of adversity
if not we first went there is no matter
what if you in their vice president
people call this force among us about 10
here's a time that my neighbors you know
I make sure they understand that I don't
think they're done I feel too glad you
agree as long as do it except should be
able to deal with financial markets I
like that you can I find a bigger
modifying out individuals who want to
take that this point as a divided into
two categories important and so the okay
big bill to integrate home they're not
gonna worry about selling information
about me Annette and then it does that
is just that intercept a vulnerability
assessment and testers I mean get rusev
dependent on staff is will allow some
people in here so it's important to
classify that data add important because
if you don't understand why they don't
understand knowing goodbye present I
Pete Souza who you know just doin lookin
on out there
yes so we like we started off with
accident to do this in 2013 and we
removed it in 2014 and how we go back to
them with our pre like our pre
assessment of the vineyard after you
give me all the information you give me
your data descriptions I'm going to tell
you this is restricted data and this is
why it's restricted data they suffer the
data elements that you gave me and in
that encounter I'm gonna we used to ask
that the business over to pass along
this vendor security questionnaire to
the third party now we do it ourselves
as well but we still have to let them
know this is a process this is why it's
happening and it will it has strike up
conversations because there's some
people out there that are not very
familiar with phn NCI and there's some
to come from companies and they're fully
aware it's like you know this is not th
islands like whoa welcome to health
place its pH I because everything that's
cuz we're related yeah that is important
to have those conversations such as your
off on the same page and hopefully never
have a violation yeah so almost we do
that internal questionnaire with just a
business owners and answer our questions
and figure out what the classification
is we move on to our pre rankings so we
do pre rankings and post ranking so
we'll give it a pre loyal pre medium
pretty high pretty critical so free lil
you just in physical access we need you
bad you take a test or you agree to our
standards then depending on now
obviously data classification we move up
in the rankings on medium high critical
depending on the ranking depends on what
type of secondary questionnaire we're
going to send to the vendor so first we
deal with our business owners figure out
what they know about this Avenger how
they plan on using them then you find a
point of contact with the vendor and we
start reaching out to the vendor so we
have a two different questionnaire so
you have one for low and medium it's
about 30 questions and also ask for
evidence for something samana high in
critical we bump that up to about 70
questions
yeah masony are familiar with a cig
standard information gathering document
from hell like the time okay yeah it has
like so many question about so much
stuff in there and it it's overkill in
my opinion it is definitely useful and
it is definitely something that you know
he's working for a lot of people but the
quicker you can get to you know the meat
of this relationship that you have with
the people that you're working with it
better you'll come away with it I could
have an incredible security program and
really suck in other areas or might have
not vetted the new security professional
that's on my team and my incredible
security program is in trouble and you
know I I don't know this yet I didn't
I'm not HR I'm not going background
screams out of Russell was coming into
my business there's still all of our
data and Guinness and China I'm it's on
camera with you but yeah it's the way
you goes out getting the information you
know it's on you and it's on your your
company and all your resources sometimes
you know utilizing that external third
party to help you do that creating
internal questions that are more
applicable to line up with what you're
required to adhere to is it's probably
better than buying something off the
shelf that you know fifty percent of a
dozen applying but you're asking your
suppliers your vendor the software
company to complete something that you
wouldn't complete yourself I just
something to consider with your external
questionnaires
all right yes my words both remember
years and the process they fell with
their treasures were closed on base
where they're kept a legend that Bateman
estamos question you request is so much
more vision as God's Word of
marginalization are less they are things
we want to thinking close that he
doesn't last as you described as last by
here bizarre you can roll fill the gap
so whatever works really really well
thanks when we tell you to the Maximus
and congratulations you now know how are
we the medication you need look at you
want to spend two months hi Angela one
question you don't follow you are
meeting or look at right yeah so like
safety questions have any questions we
think is reasonable what's the longest
questionnaire you have to fill out for
one of our vendors oh it's the people
that have something relationship with
the smarts and it was about 450
questions of all costs 13 different ads
so depending on how you answer one
question it opens up multiple subsection
yeah is that when I had
so we turn out or secondary
questionnaire surveys we also ask for
evidence gathering them so what's the
scope how long are going to support us
what happens when we decide to terminate
our contract how are you dealing with
our data at that point how are you
purging it you know returning it to us
how do we ensure that you still find
security practices of that Nana
third-party reports it third person at
third party review we're in a
relationship with a group called coral
still jump on conference calls with us
no scheduled conference calls don't look
for evidence they'll go out and search
the internet for breaches any kind of
history they can find out that company
as well it's a little bit here so just
make sure it's on by you know sometimes
we've like oh well you know this
assumption well they don't like this
unit because they always want to get
more vendors so well we'll just have
someone else that doesn't even know you
follow up like well this is a high
vendor based on everything they found
based on how they answered our question
is so we'll send them our questionnaire
they'll map it to different standards as
well like well you know to go on hydros
they felt like 40 or one hydros
requirements obviously that's a high
risk lender and we're going to need more
assurances or like hey this is what we
need you to do in this mix like two
three quarters pain to fix your security
posture so not only do we assess them
like hey what's the help of for like
this is what this company needs it will
give them suggestions on how to improve
their own security posture to help us
yeah and that come as well because again
they just security management I mean
there are people probably do this for
years but they were probably labeled as
in the security management team but
they're like before this process began
in
2013 we had over a thousand vendors we
already have a relationship with and
they weren't going anywhere so speak so
you're part of business security
management it's like okay Google for we
can do let's say this pretty decent
evaluation but what about the people
that already exist so we brought in a
third party to help us evaluate everyone
and have a idea of who we needed to go
back and help bring them up to
compliance yes so your video it's all
how you address that coverage with your
you're looking at Yuma that they have
different solutions for that long which
is a and you know work retail all of our
stores we have a solution out there
something that has been abroad pop
portal of Italy mouse hat get your stuff
right you're not trying to really assess
all of Cisco you're trying to let that
sunset right look like that how you take
questionnaire and shoot it off to
somebody
that President and how do you obviously
that's not nice to you tinea capitis a
part of that is we can use the
questionnaire to get get things going
but the other portion is like in the
very to getting your one in the service
internally I want a service i want this
service and I want this service for this
department or this discreet of people I
need as much clarity as I can from my
internal person what is it that they
want what is it me from there I go to
cisco and I say hey they thought of what
they said it any now I need to know like
what your security posture is around
what you're providing on this yeah yeah
i'm not i'm interested in your security
program i'm interested in your privacy
program like posture just to see how
you're behaving or how he was
potentially the hey you live one
security person no privacy person that
security person is everybody I'm going
to probably want to get on the phone
with you and talk you know more about
like how do you handle this and how do
you handle that and where I'm able to
determine and you have like a 10-person
staff security team and five persons to
death privacy team and having a little
bit more safe in your responses would
not think that I needed to take it a
next level especially when I'm not only
asking for responses but evidence
recertifications and evidence of the
company certifications to back up this
posture that you had and then use a
third party to do an independent review
and validate what you say so after all
these security assessments after our
third party goes in after we have
follow-up conference call so you answer
a couple questions that we're not happy
with we jump on a call with the ask for
clarity if we're still not happy we'll
ask you to bring in an architect or
something to explain a little more
detail and after that we're still not
happy then we have to have a business
owner sign off on the risk
ethics of the risks and then you you'll
find that your company will engage with
people who have no security program they
didn't have any no privacy officer and
they don't even have like a password on
their computer it's like and it's like
they want to do business with them and
it's like we can't we can say we don't
recommend because of this risk but what
we found around that is like if we're
going to engage them on pawn shop so
we're going to gauge the running while
type people with a hair on fire they're
going to go through our training they're
going to use our equipment like someone
was speaking of earlier and they're
going to be our contract it higher and
we're going to monitor them just as hard
as we would monitor the person that's
asking for it yes we bring them into our
processes we bring the visit and most of
those people and most of those places
are so happy to forego a long security
document and join the team basically
taking on our training passing our
training taking on our equipment and hey
work work away anchor it down
single you are British guy and he's your
brother multitude up it'll be your name
will be your name but another thing I've
learned is like people aren't as
malicious as it seems it did just
ignorant like they don't know any better
and if you have like information to give
them about that it's money talks like if
you say hey we could go out a bit of
this week we could be in breach of
contract that kind of stuff is
translates better than saying oh no this
is you know not some technical talk
jargon all over my belt off sick look if
we do this we're in jeopardy is this
that any other you make them aware of it
now sometime grudgingly go along with it
and then you just a rich ranking so
after our valuation third-party phone
calls back and forth well we've got a
MTN minimal to no risk so that's you
just you know if we're just buying
software we're hosting and we're doing
all the install Brenner and require you
to fill out a questionnaire we just
wanted to off the shelf will do
everything for you so you're inside our
data center we do all the security nope
no question it required so much that
that also goes along hey your contractor
you coming in we're giving you our
training you're getting our laptop
you're getting our badge give them a
media everything comes from us nothing
is personal and obviously we finalized
with the low medium high critical what's
the critical those are the ones will
actually reach out to that business
owner okay we need you to sign off on
this your name is on this for except
all the risk if anything goes wrong
you're the first person that they go to
in there just the beginning the business
owner is probably over your CIS believe
we will you throw everybody attention on
it that's all those signatures are for
like I'm telling you now so i can say i
told you so later legal sign-off cio
everyone's had the same form knowing
this business are one stalk keep using
this vendor and hear all the risk that
we've assessed and then they get to
justify the cio illegal would so
additional asks as well he was alluding
to earlier so if they don't want to take
our training to have to validate that
they provide training and have to give
us a rubric or an outline of the
training they provide saw their
contractors so there's business
continuity the type of things like oh
the size of security questions that you
want these different things to help kind
of validate it gives me more insight to
their program you know the training as
he said the business continuity disaster
recovery plans security requirement
agreements baa NDA s owm SAS that's a
business associate agreement and
non-disclosure agreement a statement of
work the master service agreements legal
and contracting information privacy
information and a listing of all contact
data for people that are on the account
and they're 8r for verification so
that's one of the easiest things to slip
up on is doing business with carbon
black and I'm actually allowed them to
our network and they have access to my
account or carbon black different
facility different location I don't know
when he gets fired I don't know what's
going to happen during their day to day
so how am I to continue to be aware of
who still has access to the accounts but
everything that I'm doing in-house is
working but I have vendors that still
have access to my account and they don't
even work on Blackie
sorry these are companies in reserve so
if we have a vendor and on the
questionnaire like the one of our
question assets actually have some
vendors that are going to perform task
for us as well so as soon as we find
that out we actually begin the whole
process with them as well and we won't
complete the process was the main vendor
until all is sub members have completed
it so that's our same process we need
training validation you get in the same
questionnaire so it it can it slow down
the process but like we said we should
get once you get financial on board
they're okay with slowing it down it's
rather we wait now and pay exponentially
more later on what's up when he doesn't
be done at karmaloop contract this comes
up that you see this is beginning Cindy
doesn't wear a to a parallel record yeah
yeah that's what we try to do with our
financial once they get it they kick us
off and we send out our requirements and
our question is as they're working on
everything else as well record-keeping
you do all this work what are you
storing it this is just everyone just
has a filing cabinet so centralized
storage location so we started using
sharepoint a couple other tools to just
keep everything in track also we have a
shared email inbox so Willie myself or
anybody else it's helping us perform
these will send up from one email mr.
vendor response we all know we got it
and we'll just let each other know hey I
want to pick this one up I'll look at
the questionnaire first once i'm done
i'll post it on the SharePoint site let
you guys go review without you know what
I thought so it goes through at least
two or three of us internally then if
we're still compete if we still have
questions will engage quarrel as well
then they'll review the entire question
again and then we'll come together like
ok these are the issues that we have
with the questionnaire what were you
guys able to find what's there
search based on that will engaging
vendor get them on a call start an email
chain so we have all the all the data
ahead of us and are able to just work
between each other yes so we we from our
stage we that we delve into what existed
what tools that they were already
already were leveraging to handle a
vendor payment and the vendor process is
it accounts payable all that felix sells
forceful so we tweak salesforce to
basically just have a intake process for
security and that intake process would
deliver a notification out to all the
various different departments we have of
the GRC tools for us and specific there
in the GRC tool that we want it but they
would send a VA agreement so we resort
back to just we go wherever finance is
whatever systems that they're using we
can use our sharepoint we use it for
other type of intake things but because
they use that and they already have
access to that we wanted to plug into
today resistant so why audit purposes
and organization everything is essential
application we can all go in and play
with it just add your name at the end of
it or turn on comments speaking of
audits so we'll do internal external
audit with our vendors for the pinning
all under final rich ranking you have
we're going to review you either you
know at least an annual review every two
years or just periodic so minimum to no
risk we started the audit process this
past year we're going every month i will
pick 10 at random and then we'll start
the pratt so we'll start the actual
intake process with the business owner
depending on how they then answer those
questions we can figure out if
aluminum to risk or someone might have
left some information out for there was
some sort of change in what they're
going to do and then we have to start
questionnaires people try ways the real
process and sometimes people will
unintentionally do it in sometimes they
will intentionally I say hey if I just
say no none of this I've never had to
see where his face and so that's what
the auditors floor and for agreeing like
one more slide like annual evidence
gathering so if you say hey next we're
going to have a sock to report ready for
you forgets what make sure we're going
to ask for that sought to report want to
keep asking about until we get a copy so
any kind of evidence whether we get this
year we're going to require of you as
soon as you update it again the
mitigation follow through so like I said
will once we engage vendors and we
figure out ways to improve their
security posture will discuss with them
hey here's the timeline this is what you
can do to show us that you know you want
continue the relationship with us and
you want to improve your posture to make
us safer in yourself reviews we start
the process all over again as soon as
they're the changing scope so like you
were saying maybe we just want my
Rockies issue well next year under buy
something else the whole process starts
again and inactive like we said if our
business relationship ends there's a
whole nother set of questionnaire that
could send out what have you done with
our data are you following what we
signed our contract how can you ensure
to us but you did follow this process
some quick tips always look for ways
automate automate automate automate when
you can well there's two people and
there's four thousand vendors automation
is your best friends try repeatable
processes so we've learned these
question is work for us we adapt them as
we go keep going simplify degrading if
they meet the requirement yes or no if
it's close they still need it
ninety-five percent depending on the
risk they meet it you don't want to
start asking questions A through Z for
one small thing we use electronic at the
station form so we can email them and
there's always a copy we save it to the
SharePoint side it's
so I is much as possible identify all
players like we said finance procurement
legal anyone we can get involved to help
us in our process the tunnel everyone in
where we'll be best friends with them as
long as possible integrate into existing
processes like we said we'd share point
because finances your share price
whatever everyone else is using we're
going to try to you know meet them on
their level and go from there and then
just centralized intake to limb process
and that is it we're out of time thank
you guys so we'll be outside I saw a
payday boys you guys hear their
questions