all right good afternoon everybody hope
we've all had a little chance to digest
lunch and get started we'll wind up the
propeller beanies a little bit on this
talk so i'm bruce wilson i work at oak
ridge national laboratory when we
started this effort i was one of the
enterprise architects i'm fortunate that
I actually happen to be the CTO for IT
at oak ridge as i have a couple of
months ago j tu es OU is student at UT
Knoxville much of the code this here is
stuff that he's written so if you like
what you've seen it is if we screwed up
it's my fault coordinates are up there
there's a little bit of some background
i am by a regional training a chemist
this is the first time that i had a
chance to speak of cyber security
conference so let's have some fun and
walk-through i will rip off topic for
just a half second on amanda's topic at
the keynote this morning and i was
reminded that when we look at others we
tend to see their highlight reel and
when we look at ourselves we see our
outtakes i will simply say amanda
commented that she was 25 before she
realized she needed some help i was 45
before i realized i needed some help
moving back on topic saml what is it how
does it work that's the first piece
we'll talk about some of the attack
vectors arm and things that we need to
look at and that are behind this test
the testing framework that we've
developed and the test results so Samuel
security assertion markup language this
is a broadly used protocol for logging
into websites using employer or
university credentials it enables a
single sign-on so for example we're now
uses service now I suspect a lot of
folks do i log into service now using my
ORNL credentials that's done through
sam'l to pass that information on and it
is a useful tool because it involves
letting the user in but we don't have to
do things like say replicate usernames
and passwords out there as we step
things up and implements a multi-factor
authentication internally on everything
that comes out of our Samuel IDP
benefits
that it is based on XML which is at
least signed and in some cases
potentially encrypted and if anybody is
familiar with soap as a process that
tends to be somewhat complicated that's
a word that gets my attention because
complicated software certificates there
be dragons so what kind of dragons and
what motivated this work well first got
my attention was there's a paper
published in 2012 the citation is there
that they found a significant number of
flaws in 14 different sam'l service
provider packages including Shibboleth
that should scare people because
Shibboleth is by far and away the most
widely used sam'l service provider
basically by every single university in
the country it is the primary open
source provider now shibboleth has fixed
those problems but that still gets one
concerned oh ah is related roth is a
similar process often used in a number
of mobile applications and this is a
black hat paper from 2016 they found
that forty-one percent of applications
did not implement oh off correctly and
were susceptible comparsa nation attacks
so let's dig into this and see what we
can find so a couple of key terms I've
used one of them on the service provider
that's the website that the user is
trying to log into if you're used to
looking at Kerberos or oooff they'll
talk about it is the relying party if
you are like me fortunate enough to have
to work with things like mist 863 as
standards for authentication they will
also talk about the relying party the
identity provider that's the thing that
is validating the users credentials and
it is for us we happen to use pink bed
many people might use on Active
Directory Federation services adfs that
would be the identity
wider so let's dive in a little bit
there use their sim perfectly obvious
right yeah you can go cross-eyed looking
I will dig into what some of this is if
you go to Wikipedia this is the diagram
that they put for what happens in a
sam'l transaction and I find this is one
of these things that once I understood
what the heck sama was doing this made
sense but it didn't make a lot of sense
to me until I actually started to dig
through and watch what was happening on
a sam'l transaction so let's walk
through it there's a couple of things I
want to point out with this so we have a
preset up here so this is a step
typically taken by a human that we are
saying we're going to have this service
provider and i'm using SP example.com
here these are the identity provider
systems here and this is a pc via
password credentialed alligator in this
case think for example something like
Active Directory or LDAP but it's the
thing that the the sam'l software is
going to call Samuel is based on public
key crypto asymmetric cryptography if
you will so the thing that you have to
do is you have to tell the service
provider what is the public key that the
IDP the sam'l software is using you
might go the other direction as well and
this is essential of course if we're
doing the encrypted forms of sam'l and
give the public key for the service
provider to the IDP this is done out of
band for those of you who are familiar
with in common that provides a central
trusted repository for this information
but most of the time this is an
administrator who has access to both
systems and is moving some keys around
so we start with the user and in this
case i'm looking at a user who happens
to be on our internal network i'll talk
about some of this a little bit later
and that user talks out to the internet
says I want to go to this particular
page on you mr. service provider
or ms service provider then asks the
question does this user have a valid
session with me at this point great if
we do then they can use it no well we're
am I supposed to send this user and
there's a couple of different patterns
that that happens with and that's what
they talk about is IDP discovery but in
this case we're talking about SP so it
knows that this should send this user to
go or Nels provider so here it is so
it's going to give the user a sam'l
request which is a blob of XML in a real
estate and the whole point here is the
real estate is the means by which the
service provider will remember later
where that user needs to go user then
goes to that identity provider it says
here's mice animal request here's my
real a state I want to log in the sam'l
software can then be asking questions
does issues already have a session with
me well let's say no so now we need to
do a credential validation step and that
credential back to the sam'l software
that then talks to a credential
validator let's assume for the moment
them that they credential is valid now
then this animal software and in this
case is going back to the same place but
it could go someplace else goes to pick
up attributes about the user so in the
case i'm simulating here i would be
logging in with an internal user name
and password but my username off here in
this insane and spe example.com happens
to be my email address so the the sam'l
software that needs to talk and get that
information it's got it it will then
look up the information that it had the
sam'l requests the relay state assemble
all of that into a sam'l response that's
the thing that we're going to talk a
little bit more about and it since thats
a no response and the relay state back
to the user who then sends all of that
stuff back to the service provider the
service provider then needs to take
look at all of that information say is
this a valid saml token is this user
somebody who should have access and a
bunch of other checks and all of those
checks pass then it gives the user a
session cookie for talking to it and
then the user can move on and do what
needs to happen so some notes about this
number one there are multiple different
ways of doing sam'l what I'm talking
about here is what's called a post or
redirect binding also called a bearer
token this is the most commonly used
method of doing sam'l and potentially
the least secure but okay that those two
things often go together but what
happened here everything which is the
important went through probably one of
the most hostile territories around the
users browser so what can be done with
that information well we can encrypt the
sam'l payload that's not often done for
a variety of reasons but it's absolutely
done if we're passing sensitive
information through the user's browser
there is another more secure method this
is called an artifact binding so that
what I sent back in that sam'l response
is a nonce and then the sam'l service
provider needs to then talk back and it
will get all of its information through
that back channel and this is how a walk
is often done but that also then
requires some things if you notice in my
diagram my identity provider was buried
down in the internal network there's a
reason for that because in that
particular configuration with what I'm
doing my identity provider is not
internet exposed this is one of my means
of protecting this asset to only allow
access from people who are legitimately
on the ORNL network it's one form of
authentication into the service
or attack binding is useful in some
cases but can't always be used so
digging into this there is a lot that is
buried in this one box and in particular
if any folks have done signed messages
if you've done asymmetric cryptography
it's easy to make mistakes so let's dig
into what that SP should be doing and
ask some questions about how can we test
I mentioned summer oskis paper that was
the 2012 we want to look for their code
it was written in Java which is not my
particular language of choice and it
looked to be largely abandoned I think
this was somebody's master's thesis and
that student then went off to a real job
and the code was abandoned JC hidden and
I have been working on some testing of
our existing infrastructure tools some
synthetic transactions and we've been
using cucumber which I will talk to
about it in a minute it's a
domain-specific language for writing
test it's got this great interface with
what's your web driver so great except
that what's here didn't help for reasons
that I'll talk about but you know we've
got the pieces parts this shouldn't be
too hard as usual there's an XKCD for
that so more time later than I expected
we actually got to the point and so this
actually is the way the test appears
this is a simple test that I will dig
into in this case what we're doing is
simulating what or is testing whether or
not the service provider will accept
unsigned sam'l in sam'l should always be
fine because if I'm not sending a
signature through I'm going through the
users browser then an impersonation
attack becomes trivial so what can we
test does the service provider validate
the signature and the common way that we
do that is we change the sam'l subject
which is effectively the username in
this transaction
does the service provider handle a
supplied public key correctly I can put
a public key in that sample message to
say this is the certificate I'm using
that should have a service provider to
go that's the key to use out of the list
and this is used for rolling keys so if
I'm signing with one key and now I've
gotten a new key because my old one is
expiring I send in the sam'l message I'm
using the new key i'm using the old p
this service provider shouldn't actually
say oh that's icky you want to use great
that's fine that was actually some of
what seminar offski found and that's why
i put that test in this list does the
service provider fail completely if the
signature is tripped up a service
provider should never ever ever accept
unsigned sam'l that was again part of
the problems with samer osky found in
their paper this is the one problem that
we found that was due to a configuration
error and the sam'l should time out so a
saml token should be valid for a period
of minutes this is configurable in the
set up between the service provider and
the IDP it does require that they are
using a common clock a fairly standard
setting is that a saml token is valid
for five minutes that accounts for an
awful lot of clock skew we actually
often use a three minutes timeout you
may be aware that there has been some
precompute attacks against sha-1 there
still are not things that are feasible
to do in this context in under a few
minutes so that's an important feature
within Santaland some of these other
tools we have not yet put in the
framework to be able to do testing of
replay attacks a saml token should be
valid example exactly once that was a
problem thats a moroski noted in a few
places as well we are not presently
doing anything with encrypted payloads
more are we doing anything against the
artifact binding nor have we got
anything working today like a lot of
folks we are doing more and more with
multi-factor authentication scripted
tests involving MFA or yeah so what kind
of test would you do part of what I
would try to do is reverse the
encryption again a knowledgeable
attacker who happens to be you have
knowledge of the encrypted mechanism you
can do encryption a couple of different
ways you can encrypt the entire payload
you can encrypt certain fields and so
what are the capabilities for example to
replace that filled with an unencrypted
that should cause something to fail if I
synthesize a transaction or if I've got
the public key or the service provider
from some other means in many cases that
public key is available so if we're in
common I could get the public he let me
substitute something else into that
sam'l transaction and again make sure
that that should fail properly if I'm
doing something where I'm working with a
service provider and I want to strip out
the sam'l signature for example and then
encrypt that would be one of the kinds
of attacks that we couldn't envision it
and we have not played it all with the
sam'l request the peace that comes from
the service provider entire equation the
entire connection will be under TLS I
can't think of anything that we're doing
so everything is done over HTTPS but
you're also doing an encrypted Taylor
inside of the TLS tunnel
or you're doing united we are and some
of code that you'll see so we actually
do use internally Kerberos tokens for
authentication we have a number of
connections that will do certificate
based authentication pit card for those
that are used to working in the federal
government space or RSA token or other
out-of-band authentication the problem
is it's difficult to make those work
inside of a scripted test so we've been
working primarily with things that are
using usernames and passwords today
because it's an easier problem and that
covers some of what we're doing we do
have the Kerberos piece working you
should you know she can restore the
final review should feel complete agenda
actually get a number provider and the
erection that as the one hiding for the
account that he had I can't accept the
fact that all of the one-time password
token generators that we use a
hardware-based I don't have access to
the seeds there's some advantages and
disadvantages and working with paranoid
environments or just because you're
paranoid doesn't mean they aren't out to
get you so test results we tested all of
our sensitive internal and external
sam'l providers we did find one
configuration error that led to unsigned
shall then we're going to dev site right
actually what happened in this
particular case and I'm not talking
about the vendor because it's still
under investigation we did an upgrade of
that vendors cloud software or what they
provided the update so we told them when
that could happen in that environment
and in the process of doing that updates
for some reason that all of the sudden
started accepting unsigned sam'l
shouldn't have happened and that
actually did lead to the understanding
that this is actually something that we
want to include in a regression testing
environments but I did actually have
something what was just a dev site so
it's not a problem I um the other thing
that was interesting out of all of this
is as he's appropriate when we were
working with an external company and
attempting the test sample we spoke with
their security groups beforehand said
hey we want to be running this test from
this IP this is what we're going to do
great fine one of the people that I
spoke with said great thank you very
much I'd like you to be very noisy when
you do this because I want to see if our
soccer picks it up they didn't so in
fact none of the service providers that
we worked with mom actually came back to
us and said we were detecting this
unusual activity coming from your
network the kinds of things that we were
doing are more likely indications of
adversarial action they could be
indications of Miss configuration
particularly unsigned sam'l that could
be a configuration error so I think this
is something that is worth the provider
would see on invalid sam'l coming in so
they would see something where Sam old
signature failed no signature presence
the software that we're using I see all
of that in those in our laws and it is
something that has caused me to ask some
questions of our stock in terms of some
alerts that we might want to come in
look at four things where we ourselves
are the SP and we're looking with
external service providers but it's one
of those things we did cause me to go
hmm I kind of would have expected a
little bit more of a response so there's
some things that we learned
bomb JT has a very bloody forehead at a
point in time trying to get what's here
to not follow redirects so part of what
is going on in here is there is a
tremendous amount of redirects that
happens in all of this some of these are
HTTP 301 redirects others of these are
redirects incurring in JavaScript or in
headers and they differ home at
different stages and using different on
software so we will end up falling back
to a much more primitive method of using
rest clients in Ruby to do this and you
have to be careful about how you manage
the cookies because you just need to and
that lettuce and false positives and
false negatives the other thing that is
interesting this would be fun for an
ongoing discussion if anybody is
interested in digging into this we've
gotten some things to work but the code
is not as well abstracted as I would
like I would like for this to be much
more generalizable than it is today and
so folks who have suggestions on that
would be appreciated and you'll see some
of this as I dig into the next sections
to talk about how did we get here I
mentioned cucumber I'm an open source on
domain specific language you saw what it
looks like absolutely built on top of
Ruby if you are working with sam'l I
strongly suggest that you get the sam'l
tracer as a firefox plugin this lets you
see all of the details the eight this
animal requests in samo response or
actually transmitted as base64 encoded
strings in posts typically and Samuel
tracer handles all of the basics before
decrypt you actually get to look at
those things you also get to see all of
the other post variables well by the way
watch because if you're doing usernames
and passwords in your post for password
credential elevator those will be in the
sam'l tracer logs like i said already
framework for testing um we had some
in-house cool the credential tests I
will mention that a good password bolt
would be a better answer
some of what we've done I will also say
that Thomas Edison when he was asked
about what he had learned after 500
successful 500 experiments trying to
make light bulb said I now know five
hundred ways to not make a light bulb we
had several of that and of course stack
overflow with some essential elements to
getting to where we got to yeah so I
mention here is the sample test and I
want to walk through what this looks
like so for example this given my
testing default credential what this led
us do is with a little bit of setup JT
can be running the test and he's running
under his credential his username I can
run the same test and I'm running under
my user name in a few cases we can use
testing accounts but in a lot of the
systems like our internal SI p
environment where we were trying to test
it you actually have to test some of
these things from a real account and we
actually have some rules designed to
prevent problems that actually make
creating synthetic accounts problematic
snake biting his own tail so that looks
something like this test cred is a ruby
script it stores the usernames and
passwords in a encrypted location off of
one's home directory that way you know
if I named it now my testing default
credential and he names it testing the
ball this script actually works and
pulls up his user ID or pulls up mine
the main reason that i started this is
because i have made the stupid mistake
more than once unfortunately putting
like credentials into the git repository
and then having to fix history yeah
so you know I threw on a cyber Ark or
something else like that you know plug
for a vendor out there we don't use them
but i like them would be one way to
actually store those testing credentials
LastPass enterprise or some of the other
tools but this works and good enough for
present purposes so we did have to do
some retry stuff and we're put in the
there's a service provider initiated URL
to start and the transaction this might
look like something like onl by espied
service now but we're know about SP dot
example.com it actually is or know about
service now that comp were using that
but I just didn't want that in the
slides yeah I know but it's not text
searchable yet exactly but they can they
understand my Tennessee accent exactly
so when we have this in the retrying
part of this was in place because like I
said we actually do use kerberos
internally and some of these things are
doing the standard Kerberos dance up hey
got a Kerberos token no hey you got a
kerberos token no you have to do that a
couple of times forces okay fine I give
up I'll present you with the username
and password stuff and then all of the
the redirects that one follows to get
through so we can specify a retry limit
and we're looping through if we're
getting 301 redirects or work we know we
need to parse through and we do put a
limit on that this is an area where i
would love to talk to some folks that
are better developers than i am about
how to take this and abstract this out
so we did have to put in some things
that we're fairly specific to some of
the web forms that we use for collecting
credentials and some of the
idiosyncrasies i toyed around with some
of this a little bit with a shiva with
him installation and we would actually
have to make some fairly major changes
code if we were using ship or using a
DFS as the identity provider but that
does lead
into some of this code in the way we
phrased it was to try to allow for being
able to substitute out oh okay this is
an ad FS form that you have to parse
instead of a ping fed form and oh by the
way this is where you have to stuff the
username and password in for this kind
of a thing to pass it on we can see
that's where that's getting that
username and password out of the test
grid we wanted to put together some
different ways to say what we're
successful so these are examples of okay
if I go through all of this I'm going to
specify that that the resulting page
should include some information I should
have some specific HTTP status codes and
that's basically collecting up that and
what a mess to a set of expects that get
saved so now this is where we have fun
we've got to follow the redirect to the
point where we get the sam'l response
back from the IDP which actually is
again a little bit more following a
redirect some of which are buried inside
of JavaScript and some of which are 30
ones and then we need some point okay
now we actually want to have fun let's
strip out the same ol signature great
we've got all the tools to do that so
this is now actually the easy part the
hard part is actually getting to the
place where we have a sam'l response
that we can play with and we basically
take that sample response here's that
whole gibberish here's the piece that we
care about this is what the XML looks
like for a sam'l signature inside of
that then we basically say you go away
stripped out of the XML nokogiri makes
that really easy to do and we then
submit the thermal response and the
success criteria should fail now again
the way we do this is part of a script
that we start with a you know samo
breaker does nothing all of the success
criteria should pass then we walk
through in that test script and apply
some of these changes selectively and
the test should then fail and then
I have at least in some cases then
recreated the block at the end that says
Samuel tracer does nothing and the
success criteria should all pass as well
and we get something that looks like
that it's sending all of the stuff on to
the service provider and then walks
through the tests and make sure that if
we're mucking with the sample at least
one of the tests should fail we do have
some ability to capture the output we've
structured this so that we set a debug
level we're actually capturing all of
the HTML that we get back in response
storing that off into a log file that's
time stamped with that particular run
and so forth so where we are with this
is there's some code cleanup that we
need to do the intent is to put this at
on github I have not done that yet
that's mostly a matter of what we have
still needs a little bit more cleanup
and I'd like to try to make sure how do
we put up some things that describe
actually useful tests without giving
away too much operational security
information that turns out to be a
little bit more difficult but I will be
publishing some tests probably go
against test ship dot org I have some
permission from those people to be able
to put out that as a real test would
lessen and put that out to the community
let some of the brighter Minds out there
take a look and say oh well if you would
just think about this this way then that
simplifies all of your tests thank you
things are often much more obvious to
somebody else looking at the code than
those of us that write it and then the
last thing is actually an interesting
challenge because in doing some of this
digging there's a session hijack risk
that intrigues me and part of this was
demonstrated by the fact that I would do
something like for example get onto our
corporate VPN and get on use that to get
onto one of the external sites that is
validating against the internal identity
provider
I only do that from within the VPN
environment but now once I establish
that authentication and I drop the VPN I
still have a valid session cookie back
to that service provider so that said oh
there are some interesting possibilities
here with session hijacking what happens
if i have an endpoint which is owned
what is the adversary actually able to
do in order to grab that session
credential and now take that someplace
else and replay that session credential
to obtain access into that cloud
environment in a way which I am
potentially blind to it will tell you
that working with a variety of cloud
providers there is a wide range of one's
ability to be able to get logged back
from the cloud provider about who he's
been doing what I will call out one
vendor as the exemplar of that I work
with Dropbox on a regular basis the logs
that we get back from Dropbox in my
opinion set the standard for the kinds
of things that I would like to be able
to get back from a cloud provider we put
a hole for about 12 months on a
deployment of migration to office 365
because at that point in time one of the
significant weaknesses in over 365 was
that we could only get logs back from
them at a higher level than we would
like 12 hours in arrears but this then
leads to that question of if somebody's
doing this they can potentially replay
that session cookie into the cloud from
someplace else where I have no
information and I can't get information
back from the cloud provider about who
is doing what I'm blind to an attack but
I would really rather not be so that's
the currently active area of
investigation is how do we take in any
more general fashion abstract out how
these logs are managed whether the logs
that were getting back from the very
service providers and hook them into the
logs that are from all identity provider
and I should see an authentication event
internally for every access externally
in his service provider by service
provider specific i know that when we
started with service now for example
their default was 30 minutes we've
increased that to somewhat longer i know
there are some service providers that we
work with or low confidentiality that
it's a couple of days we typically do no
longer than a half a day for anything
sensitive and we're reading if we can
get the mitigating controls and seeing
what's happening we're willing to go to
longer timeouts if we can't then we'll
have to go with some shorter time outs
in the panel or detailing what remote
has the technique down for van halen
massive questions where the saml
supports detailing the the remote host
and where it's valid for it is not in
the sense of the hope of the sam'l
specification that would be an implement
implementation specific issue but in the
situation that you desire to allow
authentication in sanitation crawl out
of this kind of metal foundry as you
Abraham internet and then we can do
wealth that gets yeah we've got a few
minutes so I'm going to dive into where
that gets complicated is that if anybody
is using direct access on Windows
systems direct access in the if you set
it up the way microsoft recommends it to
split tunnel VPN so my IDP sees an
internal address the service provider
actually sees my home address
so that complicates that question yes I
can set up some things and for example
we do have some AWS instances for
example where it will only permit
authentication from or IP address range
period and so you can't get in there
from just a general but that's not
anything that's in the sandal
specification itself other questions
kind of we're done a little bit early go
enjoy the hallway track go enjoy
conversations and I'll hang around for a
minute if they're off