alright guys I think everybody is in
here that's going to be in here
hopefully or they'll miss out but i'll
go ahead and get started so I name is
Ryan I'm going to be talked about
weaponizing splunk a little bit about
myself on the director of security
engineering at CVG security for a
consulting firm out of Boston and we
specialize in all sense of security some
certs up there hopefully means I know a
little bit about what I'm talking about
I don't know so this talk came from last
year my team and I were on an engagement
we had gotten into access to the
organization um and during recon and
enumeration we found a spunk server
really cool we navigated it navigated to
it and it was very nice to us and just
logged us right in and load this right
in as admin so like that's awesome but
what can I do with this so we built a
custom application we installed that it
allowed us to get root access on the
machine that we were on and then we
thought hey how can I expand this out
how can I get more access into the into
the internal network of the organization
so we build more custom applications and
then we utilize the functionality of
spunk to deploy ease out at every system
in the organization and within about you
know a few minutes we had you know
domain admin and we had to access every
box in the organization that's kind of
where this whole thing came from and I'm
going to go through the steps of what we
did to actually build those and you know
exploit the organization so we're going
to start out them to talk a little bit
about splunk and some of the basic
functionality this Punk has three you
guys know exactly what I'm doing during
the talk on some of the
misconfigurations that we see just the
basic stuff and then I'll actually talk
about what what I mean when I talk about
weaponizing spunk there's basically
three attack surfaces we're going to be
attacking the server attacking the
organization that will be the lateral
movement and then attacking the data
that last part is more moving away from
actually using a customer slunk instance
to utilizing your own spunk instance um
during a pen test we generate tons and
tons and tons of data and it takes time
to review all that data and generate the
report everybody hates that part I know
I hate that part it's the stores part of
it so if utilized spoke to bring in all
that data we can
to speed up that process and it actually
speeds up your attack as well so I'll
talk about that and then the finally I'm
going to wrap it all up with mitigating
actions a lot of the stuff spunks
already put together for you people just
don't read the documentation um so we'll
kind of talk about that just real quick
at the end because if I tell you how to
attack it I need to at least give you
some options on how to fix it so what is
funk it's a wall decoration and
correlation tool it's very powerful has
the expandability through what they call
applications and all these applications
written in a lot of different scripting
language languages Python Perl bash
PowerShell things like that the nice
thing about the applications is it gives
me command execution on that host I can
run anything I hand it and there's
really nothing to stop you your phone as
long as you have the right privileges on
the application so some things some
functions within splunk that we're going
to talk about later on in the
presentation one aspect of swamp since
it needs to gather all this data it
needs to have a way to get to data right
so a lot of applications offer syslog so
it'll send in the logs your network
appliances and stuff all offer that but
some of the applications such as you
know just windows in general it doesn't
offer syslog so slut gives you a
universal forwarder that will install
the operating system collects all these
logs that we're talking about they're
already on the host and then also again
is expandable by applications and gives
you command execution it's really nice
all these Universal forwarders are
controlled by what's called a deployment
server so the deployment server
basically allows you to collect all
these get over supporters they allow you
to split them up into you know different
categories um yeah basically different
categories but based on host names or
operating systems this just helps you
manage the deployment so that you know
if I'm if I'm looking at a Windows
application I'm only employing Windows
applications out the windows hosts and
not to pull out to linux boxes and
things like that um yep so who's just
what the deployment server looks like I
get my clients I can break them up into
classes which is the category and then I
decide the applications that go to
classes
the classes decided with applications
got to which hosts so that's basically
splunk in a nutshell oh you know if you
guys have any questions or if i'm going
to quickly raise a hand ask some
questions i don't mind the dialogue
while I'm talking so the Mets
configurations that everyone sees on the
older versions that's plunked the one
that i was talking about earlier i think
it was for dot five these have been
fixed in the new one did that
automatically logged you in if you
didn't have credentials set up the
default passwords admin and change me
every version prior to six dot five
which is the current release didn't
require you to set that password it
automatically had it configured for you
so it's grown into that um ssl is
another one is to check in the box
nobody ever checks the box though unless
you call them on it so if there's no ssl
configured you can do man-in-the-middle
attacks as long as your internal the
network already and then always spoke i
find this every single organization i go
into maybe the smoke application is
there running his route but all those
universal forwarders they will be and
that's actually the key to the entire
attack so smoke is always going to be
running as a privileged user unless you
have a you know reputable organization
install it for you may be like oh so the
lesson I think spoke so there's three
attack surfaces I talked about earlier
attacking the server attacking the
organization at second data packet of
server is I have accessed that server I
have those admin credentials somehow I
got them either through credential reuse
or one of those misconfigurations that I
just talked about um the first thing you
want to do is you want to know your
environment so look at the logs that are
already in spa are their windows logs
can I can I look at those those windows
logs things like that um spunk allows
you to read in fought from the operating
system the local hosts that you're on so
let's start pulling in and files at p
shadow if you are SE password groups
host any anything really if it's a
windows box we look at some of those
files so start looking at the local
files on machine and then we'll get into
most application attacking the
organization so that's the we're going
to be abusing the trust with the
universal forwarders that are already
out there let's send out applications
that executes code on all those machine
let's configure those applications to
run every five seconds so that a cape
somebody catches me I now have my shell
back immediately
and then attacking the data will be
bringing in all our pen tastes they do
I'm going very quickly it's cool so
reviewing the logs as I said let's look
at the logs that are already in slunk
ever slug is huge and everybody's
gathering everything because they need
to know all this information about their
environment so you're going to find web
application logs windows logs Linux logs
everything custom application so now I
can go in splunk and I can look up and
say hey here's all my database servers
here's a list of all my domain
controllers here's a valid list of users
that log in just today actually I can
look at login logs and say hey this
organization runs from 8am to 2pm or
whatever it is they have a rotating
shifts they're always in here's users
that work different shifts all this
information can be pulled out a plum and
we can review that and immediately have
all this knowledge in our hands being
being intact if it is custom web app
logs we can go in there and look and say
you know these users have higher level
of privileges than other users here's
things that I go and look for just some
key terms to throw out user name
password things like that those are
really going to get you the quick wins
and here's some files that I usually go
for the ssh keys that's really fun if I
can't get command execution maybe it's
running as a lower level privilege but
then I can go i can grab these ssh keys
and what I'm what I'm looking at these
things um I'm always one to build up
attack profiles and kind of get to know
my environment how do how do they
structure the host names you know how
can I can I look at the host names and
kind of determine what these boxes what
the function is in the environment and
build out a you know kind of an attack
passive way I want to execute so here's
a quick demo the nice thing about this
right is so crap of course that
resolution we can't read I just shot
these lower quality too all right let's
give up on that anyway it's like you're
going to add data you're going to upload
a log file from the local file system
and you're going to keep hitting next
stuff here in the top right and as long
as you don't go all the way to the end
none of that information is logged so if
I pull an SE shadow I can review the
data look at look at all those password
hashes grab those the Roman of my
password cracker but spoke never knows I
was well splunk knows i was there but no
one else knows i was there none of the
administrative users so then i can just
go back to pick a new log file hit next
review that collect the information I
need and keep going back and forth over
and over again and as I said nothing is
ever logged there I hope my other video
show because that's going to suck are
you attacking the server malicious
application um so I built an app is
called splunk shell basically when you
install it it's a Python reverse shell
funkiest package with the mates punk
applications package with their own
Python interpreter it's two got 72 I yea
sorry Oh sides i built a basis basically
just a common python meterpreter shell
just a basic payload to demo demo the
activity so that we can show off see
this video it's better okay so let's
start up a handler first inside that
exploit
hopeful
people are familiar with metasploit a
little bit know what I'm doing here so
as I said the shell that's going to be
coming back as a Python meterpreter
shell so we have said we have to use
proper payload you can do reverse you
can do buying shelves it does support
both of them it does support basic
command shows as well if you needed that
all right so we have a handler set up
now we need to go back to slunk we're
going to use those credentials that we
have I won't stall an application come
on
you
so the fun part here is we could
substitute any you know any code here
that you wanted i obviously i'm using a
python interpreter shell but this could
be anything if you have something custom
on your team that you guys use if
there's you know some other function you
wanted to run all you got to do is swap
out my python code for yours and install
this and run it the one setting that you
have to change for 625 is that i haven't
figured out a configuration file there
may be one I just haven't figured over
20 it is but now basically what this is
has installed is a command that we can
run up from the search and reporting app
so we'll run the app will say I want to
reverse shell I want a matter prover
shell and here's who you need to talk to
so if you don't this actually Forks off
the profits if you don't fork that off
that will hang and keep using that that
profit the splunk process to run and
execute your shelf so the entire time
that you're running in your shell it
would sit there so you do need to fork
off the process the ones that I have
built-in do so if you do swap them out
that would be one thing to keep in mind
and it also prevents the admin if you
restart splunk my shelf still there it's
still calling home so there's that any
questions there on that one yeah all the
videos of you in github um actually the
entire presentation is it the links at
the end of this as well so awesome it's
cool everyone's to install it it's on
github right here at this link and I
said there's another link at the end of
this presentation as well and I did have
it in splunk base or yeah this funk
based app store so I submitted it it was
cool everybody thought it was awesome
and then about 57 minutes later they
figured out what the hell was going on
and they told me I was crazy I don't
know who got in trouble for it but
somebody got in trouble and because I
got pulled if it was in the spunk faced
that would have made it a lot easier if
you were to
Eric you're a pen tester inside an
environment you can log in literally say
browse apps type in spunk shelves and
thought never having to upload any code
to them so it would have been funny but
yeah they caught on oh I'm sure they
have I I was going to go down the route
of trying to hide it and you know
obviously it's a code and I was like
nuts wasted so my way to my time all
right let's just put it up on github
people get downloaded be funny that way
so extracting data so all these apps
that we install I guess not really mine
because there's no configuration for it
but all the other apps that you install
all need credentials to talk to
something you know next pose has an app
you need to give it credentials to talk
to your next post console windows needs
a user usually need a domain user
usually it should only have read access
a lot of times it has more but all these
all these things need configurations so
you need to input a username and a
password so smug takes all those in
through your app it's all stored in a
file on the file system and luckily
spunk does do it correctly and they do
salt and encrypt all these credentials
this is what it would look like for
Windows app you install a I'm sorry you
set up your configuration with your
username and password and everything and
if we looked at the actual file on a
file system this is what you would see
so you can't actually read anything
awesome on splunk part bad on schooling
support because about 14 lines of Python
code and utilizing the API I now get
clear text passwords here in the middle
so the API needs to need to be able to
speak to all these applications so if I
give it a dose or username and password
it needs to be able to reach out to that
domain controller or that other windows
system in the network and give it those
credentials so the API have to be able
to unencrypt those passwords well it'll
also give it up to anybody else that
asks for Moscow so as I said there's all
14 lines of Python it'll lift your every
application that you have and decrypt
all those credentials and present them
to you not once long so yeah
so that is a business trip so the
encrypted password storage endpoint in
swamp prior to 65 required physical and
mental objects and pensioners for dot
yep because you have now is the
developers unfortunately takes half the
liver delivered food capability my lists
or password it is still it all saying
how would you do not have to give that
but if I'm going to minister I have it
or can give it to myself yes correct yes
so there is there's a setting there so
as long as but if you have administrator
credentials and this is assuming that
you have in some way have administrative
level access you could either if you
didn't already have it on that user that
you had you could give it to yourself
because you're an admin or you know if
you need if you already did have it yeah
you are correct but that is new for six
I think it's 653 or 60 65 oh ok so
attacking the organization this is what
we're going to talk about those
Universal forwarders and that deployment
server that we talked about the
beginning so along with the application
that we talked about just a second ago
there's to what we call technology
add-on it's just a Splunk way of talking
about a different apps I built a Windows
one in the linux one and again these are
all basic interpreter shells you could
swap out this code with anything that
you wanted so the windows one is just a
bat file runs a PowerShell command for a
reverse meterpreter shell the Linux ones
all Python it's honestly the same code
that I used in the other application
just poured it over to a technology out
on I'm here's a demo of that real quick
so i use the unicorn application to
generate the power shell code and as i
said a lot of times these universal
forwarders are installed and running as
root or system so as soon as this code
runs it gives me a reverse shell i also
have the same level access
questions or just don't er I've had yeah
I have an account of some sort there's
either miss configuration with a default
pass where there's password breeze in
the environment yeah the assumption is
that you do have some sort of access
into the server there's really no
vulnerabilities I'm just a creative way
of using that pretty much so I thought
our PowerShell payload here with our new
stuff again all this if you had some
custom code that you guys use for your
red team or your your pen testing that
can all be swapped in here as well this
is just for demo purposes I felt like my
display was even that was like crap on
there you still here we can read some of
it I have high res videos then you
couldn't read it on the low res
projector so i swapped them now you
can't see that anyways it'll start up
our handler will go into the deployment
server here i will just oh man that was
horrible one bad to the next anyway so
these deploy out so the nice part with
it with these technology add-ons is
again we can set the restart time of the
application so if you needed it to run
every five seconds or if you want it to
run average six hours whatever you
really wanted you could do that so that
every whatever your time is it'll it'll
kick that show up again and again and
again yeah we'll just go with that
because that sucks anyways any questions
there that that was kind of that section
yeah
so I started out with yeah so I started
out with which is putting power shell
code basically is a reverse meterpreter
shell with powershell so I put that in
there and that runs they favorite every
five seconds or 10 seconds whatever you
put I'm sorry so those last section here
attacking the data I'm super ahead um so
I said we generate a ton of data with
pen testing and map scans we're running
Nix Oh every tool you have is going to
generate some sort of data responder
everything all that stuff unless you put
it in splunk it also some text files
normally for me and I have to go through
windows and windows and go through these
crazy hierarchy of folders and that's
how it's all organized and that's how I
go back to read it and generate reports
and takes me days and it sucks so if we
had it all in splunk for instance is the
Wi-Fi pineapple it's just hold on let me
grab
guess I should drag it over here
shouldn't there we go slightly better
okay so we have a we have an app for the
Wi-Fi pineapple in real time all these
logs are coming in from your Wi-Fi
pineapple you could look at one single
dashboard and you get SSID geez I get
the clients that I've already got
attacked or attached to my pineapple
down here you get two timelines for the
different probe requests and the
different SS IDs that we're seeing and
it kind of speeds up that attack so now
I know who who's on my network who I
have already and what SSID is I'm saying
in the future I'd like to add some more
context menus that I could drop down and
say hey run this attack on this guy and
it'll run those those scripts on the
different point out on the pineapple so
that it would start capturing everybody
else that hasn't been built yet right
now we just got dashboards but we're
getting closer and the other app that we
have set up I'm just going to do this
outside of PowerPoint for now would be
responder so responders a
man-in-the-middle tool kind of it's good
enough i guess response men and little
tool for pen testing you'll run it it'll
do men in little on SMB HTTP FTP all the
different protocols that are going
across the network it'll say hey whoever
you're trying to authenticate with I'm
that guy send me your hash and so you
collect all the hashes and again in real
time if we're sending all those logs
into splunk if you're running spunk on
your pin test box it would make things a
lot faster so up top right away I can in
real time see how many credentials I've
already captured what couple of type
they are what protocol they are the
usernames that I'm looking at and then
down at the bottom here I cut off and
some of this stuff is blurred because it
was actually like a live engagement I
was on down at the bottom I have the
hashes that you could easily just export
and kick over to hash cat or John or
whatever school that you're using and
again there's I would like to build out
some context menus in
future to say hey run this in hash cat
and it automatically pushes that out for
you here school starts where I wanted to
so we'll end it with indicating actions
and I'm Way ahead but it's cool um
obviously just update your software I
mean I said at the beginning the
engagement that started this it was
running a 45 installation that
automatically logged me and his admin
had they been running a you know six to
five or six auto installation at least
it would not to log me in maybe they
still had default credentials so update
your passwords enable ssl it's one it's
one check in the box and then there is a
secure deployment guide there's a kind
of stuff in here it's about 15 to 20
pages long there's ton of stuff in here
you can do it you know to do domain
authentication you know add in more
complex layers besides just basic
application stuff yeah that's it as I
said sorry about the videos I have never
know what I'm going to run into here of
the presentation any questions there oh
and there's the contact info bring that
back up sorry
so you would want to I guess split your
data up so I mean for instance there
I've had somebody in accounting that
need to look at something only
accounting data you obviously wouldn't
allow them access look at all your IT
data as well so you can segregate out
the data like that and assign users
access to different they call them
indexes so that would be different data
sets mm-hmm I mean that's one one thing
but there's a bunch of other stuff you
know don't obviously don't import your
passwords hunting for things like that
yes um so this would be more of
something that I would be running in
real time for myself to kind of keep an
updated sat if there is a cool shirt in
there yeah i would put that the report
but most of that is just for me to know
right away hey I've got 20 ntlm v1
hashes or you know whatever that would
be my own luck implementation we I
usually pop that on either the cali box
or whatever box at hi I'm gonna be using
yeah so if he wanted to go in if you had
pulling for instance my credit card
information there are ways using the the
configuration file to actually say hey
just put access to the credit card
information or you know whatever regit
regex pattern really that you wanted for
data that you didn't want the entire
piece maybe I only want 20 characters
outline instead of all 50 you could do
it Reggie Jackson and kind of pull out
stuff or do whatever Graham anything
else yes
technically it would be logged in small
can be in the internal logs um that's
normally not something I've noticed in
engagement that people have like reports
or alerts set up for yeah it is
something you would want to go back and
clean up so honey pot he wants to swung
and roll off early application say they
know you know yeah I mean there's a lot
of information and I don't see a lot of
reports and obviously a lot to more
people hat yeah it does it would have I
don't think I have any customers that
run it yet that's 65 yes but not
multipad yeah I mean I would but I would
still need that second factor
authentication if that I mean if we're
going that route yeah so what other
additional resources having something
like lots of the last and quickly search
the data allowing a quick from the
right-hander
suicide retino-a now I've got flagon
pulling a whole bunch of data very
quickly climbs into this what's the
equivalent on the residence I mean
technically there isn't one I've been
kind of building slowly building stuff
out on the pineapple and responder one
dashboard that we have been working on
an nmap show me really quickly things
that are open okay yeah and any of your
custom tools a lot of this if you start
move migrating in the in this route
you're going to have to either do a lot
of configuration and reg reg ex matching
to really get the true output on stuff
or if you have custom stuff to just
output to JSON or CSV or XML something
standardized anything else cool all
right thanks
you