um yeah i'm clara i'm a first year
student at napier
i've been involved with computer for
quite a couple years i was the best code
mentor dress codes a charity that
focuses on getting girls on the computer
um so yeah i'm just going to talk a bit
about the numbers and what we can do
about it
um
so yeah
so the field starts to lose people or
not gain people's interests as early as
primary but secondary skills really
where you can start to see the decline
happening
so as you can see in the graph the
numbers have been in decline from
females which is the blue and since 2014
and in fact further back from this graph
it's been dropping since 2003
so there was a slight increase in uptake
in 2020 so just last year
two years ago
and you can clearly see how much of a
gap exists between men and women
we're never going to get the numbers in
university if we can't capture the
interest early on um from both men and
women and the numbers for males have
also been dropping as you can see since
2016 and further back they've been on a
general decline since 2008.
um so a lot of schools are not a lot
some skills don't even offer computing
at all um and some rotate with other
classes so you get like less than 20
periods a year of computing and your
board general for the general education
year so that's like s1 to s3
um
and then so how can we prepare kids for
the necessary skills for computing
career or just life in general when
they're getting about 15 hours a year of
computer education
and a couple classes and a couple skills
in scotland have two or three different
levels of qualifications in one class so
they might have national four national
five and hires or something in the one
class so then the teachers have to
balance
multiple curriculums and multiple
courseworks um and just totally
different classes that shouldn't be the
same and obviously the kids suffer for
that
and if they're not good at secondary
school they're not going to get any
better undergrad
um
there's about 10 000 undergrad
applications in scotland every year
um within computing so that includes
like networking cyber security
software engineering creative and social
informatics anything that comes up in
computing and you can see the massive
gap in girls and boys again
this time the blue is the girls
and
yeah the overall the number is still
pretty low 10 000 compared to what the
demand could facilitate or like what we
could achieve
um if we put work into it
and we're not really producing the
amount of recruits that is necessary
anyway
um
there's about 13 000 digital jobs in
scotland
um the demand for that and we're only
producing like 5 000 new recruits each
year so massive gap in numbers and it
raises the issue that scotland-based
companies have to go overseas to find
the skill that they need in their
require
um as well in undergrad
18 there's about 18 women say 82 of any
given computing degree is men
and this can be more or less dependent
on the university
um and the issue isn't solely with women
and envies and non-binary people but
with everyone in general and in
2016-17 the academic year
9.8 of graduates in computer science
dropped out in computer science fees
which is 2.6 higher than the mean
dropout rate of all subjects
um
based on other trends there's no more
new data on this but based on other
trends it's probable that this has
continued
um so as i said
that the problem originates as early as
primary school but even for women who
made it to the tech industry the
struggle's not over
women are at risk of quitting their job
at 45 higher rate than men in the tech
sector
and they're habitually outnumbered by
men in tech companies
we know this based on the gender gap in
almost every part of computing
there's a general two to one ratio and
26 of people of women in a survey have
been outnumbered five to one multiple
times before
and on top of that
30 of women over the age of 35 are still
in junior positions
and on the flip side less than five
percent of men are
and and that's
even if they get the junior position to
start with so a hesa study and that's a
uk wide company um
company research groups like that
found that 73 of male graduates from
computing are in a tech world six months
after graduation compared to 58 of
females
and the issue isn't just around women as
i said before 75 of employees are having
difficulties in
recruiting qualified staff due to the
lack of workforce so as a whole we can
really see that computing is a
struggling subject
so in 2001
we in scotland had just over 8 28 000
students studying computer and exam
level so that's not five higher in
advance higher in high school
with
9825 women say even in 2001 there's a
massive gap
um especially
and this dropped in nine years so in
2010 we had a little over 22 thousand
and 7 100 of them were women so that's
quite a substantial drop in nine years
especially considering the tech
explosion that happened in that decade
and if we go to last year's figures
um only
9873 people study computer science
and of that less than 2 000 women take
the subject
so in the whole of scotland we're
currently sitting at 1895
women taking computing not even
wanting to take a career in it just
having an exam
in this computing
and the number of teachers has also
dropped from 699 to 595 in 10 years
and we just can't wait and sit for this
to fix itself
um we can see the skill and update
decline isn't a new thing
in fact in 2012 on the 3rd of april so
almost a decade to the day the bbc
published an article called warning over
skills gap in computing
so a literal decade and the problems
only got worse so we just can't afford
another 10 years in this situation we
all have to act now to save the subject
and the path to doing that is definitely
a high school level
i'm getting that support for teachers as
well as well as hooking that interest
before pupils even choose their subjects
in third year
so yeah there's a lot of reasons why
people might leave computer science and
we need to acknowledge and act on these
um the reasons i give here uh for
leaving computer science at any stage so
some might be like more relevant to high
school or industry
so why women and nb's might specifically
leave computer science
we've got social identity threat so
women can feel their identity within
computing is perceived as unusual or
negative or they're just feeling unease
or on guard about who they are within
computing and we do have like quite
strong stereotypes in computing and that
can just relate to that um a lot of
people
a lot of women especially have avoided
feeling imposter syndrome
um
and the lack of support is definitely a
big issue there's a significant gap
obviously within gender as well as a
curriculum and jobs typically fashioned
to men so it's necessary to have that
support available and while there's the
gap
the fear of knowing less than male
counterparts stigma lack of role models
and that's a really important one and
recently as part of a
research group called
computing science young people's advisor
group um as part of the carried out
survey um on what students thought were
the buyers to competing and this came up
quite a bit in responses
some people have also reported being
discouraged
by authority such as teachers or career
advisors and parents
and being steered away from computing is
it just it can't be a subject for them
or like multitude of reasons
um and similar to this is not being
taken seriously um
people if people around you aren't
taking you seriously just for the
basis of your gender that's going to be
hard to
get motivation and to stay interested in
it
um and the atmosphere in the workplace
and microaggressions just are sort of
all of these things combined
um
and it can like it it's often a
combination of all these reasons oh
these reasons and the ones i'll get to
in a second it's never just one which is
where you have to look at all of them as
a whole
so the issue isn't just solely with
women and angries as i've said
anyone might leave computer science
so
some reasons might be lack of retention
in high school teaching
some schools face a high turnover
for these teachers as they move on to
different things so they drop out
and this makes it hard to create that
student-teacher relationship and it
makes it hard to build a strong
computing department
and anyone can say face some of the
reasons like lack of support and lack of
guidance
if students don't know what's coming
next and not knowing what to expect then
it can make it really difficult to
choose to continue down that path of
uncertainty when there's other more
secure or more
transparent subjects to take
and sometimes people don't feel that
they need it for their career which is
like totally fine but
it's such an important aspect in all of
our lives and understanding a bit of
that and learning some skills which as
i'm sure we all know is pretty cool and
really necessary for
a wide assortment of jobs not just
computing related
so there's also the issue that some
people don't even get access to
computing they don't get an option to
study it in high school at all they
didn't get to study in s1
and s1 if you don't get to study it when
you first come to high school it's gonna
be really hard to get that interest in
second year because i've had a whole
year of other subjects to like learn
about and hope that interesting
some as i said earlier rotate with other
classes so they're getting less than one
every fortnight
of computing so how how
are they expected to understand the
subject and to want to take it further
if they're hardly getting any class time
so another issue that people it tends to
be in smaller times and villages that
people face is they don't have a
computing specific teacher um they're
just there's just not the
teachers available to go to the
uh like the urban areas
and then finally giving worksheets some
teachers and some classes are quite
lacking in their curriculum and they
just get worksheets and
we know how amazing computing can be
actually as you're all here
but if you just get worksheets you're
never going to see that
so what we can do about it so that was a
lot of like
look at how bad this is so this is some
things that we can do
so
we can create support systems
um
so that's just so important for
retention
and i've lost myself
and
so yeah as i said earlier almost every
woman or number any i have met
completely and just faced imposter
syndrome so having them support systems
and contacts in industry they can really
just make you feel a lot better about
your career and where you can go
and then
and then also role models are great for
opening that path to computing and
helping people
um and collaborative product projects
i'm a really big fan on on those there's
hardly going to be a time in computing
when you're working on your own with no
help from anyone else so why would we
not encourage collaboration from the
start and start working together to
solve problems
so that can build connections with
students and gives people the chance to
learn and teach in a less formal
environment
and the last one there is really
important and i know we might not be
able to do loads like this other than
petition and fight for it but funding
teachers are so necessary to grow the
subject there's only so much we can talk
about clubs and projects as the teachers
we hoped around these are pulled in so
many directions
industry as a whole can also help a lot
um they have such a pivotal effect on
people's confidence and access to
further career furthering opportunities
so we've got mentorship programs and
they can give someone a contact in
industry because like they went through
similar stuff
and they can offer support to students
or new people
and they don't they can be formal or
informal
um
and i can't speak highly enough of
having someone to just support you and
push you upwards
um they don't even have to be industry
they can be teachers or students further
up or senior years of skill
there's also competitions um
they're a really good way of fostering
community within the attendees and the
good way to share information
information around teams
sponsorships are really good they can
take a financial offload they can give
someone a contact
and they
yeah they can just make it a lot easier
for someone to get into a career
and then asking for minorities feedback
of women and other minorities is really
good because you're not going to know
what people want if you don't ask them
and it makes them feel really heard if
you specifically ask them
so yeah our own actions so this is
something that you can really work on if
you choose to and you should if you
choose to
so we can so while change can and should
happen at these larger levels there's
always small things that we as
individuals can do and these are things
that can have the biggest impact short
term and they can gather momentum and
change the atmosphere so we can question
how we view the gender gap and the
workforce in general and if it's
conducive to closing that
and question our own biases so we all
have them and these can translate to
microaggressions and not seeing like for
example women only events are productive
and important for us or not believe in
the issue can be solved because
obviously women don't want to do
computing which just isn't true
and to look at that and question why we
think that is really important
um being an ally
is really good and to give credit where
credit is g is one of the best ways to
demonstrate that and create an inclusive
environment
so yeah it's not all bad thing
um
i want to share a success story with you
so i was incredibly fortunate to attend
an amazing secondary school and we had
an amazing computing department the
school wasn't that good the computer
department was great um we had an almost
50 50 split of girls and boys
with seven s3 classes so that's the year
before exams um and then in exam classes
we had four s4 classes three higher
classes one advanced hire and an mpa
class
and this didn't come about by letting it
be the my department consistently worked
hard at hooking that interest early and
let
and maintaining it
so yeah there's
down to a lot of factors and a lot of
trial and error so in my opinion one
thing that worked really well was
building that strong student-teacher
relationship
um everyone who chose higher computing
at my school had at least had a personal
relationship with at least one of the
teachers and having that and someone to
talk to when he passed the department
was really good at cementing people's
interests
and having a laugh with people is really
fun even if like i was doing my advanced
high project i wanted to cry i could go
and have some banner with my classmates
and so it's just really important to
have a strong student teacher but also a
student student like to
do outreach within societies and to
just these stations as well and like
many different areas like not just
always at a park or a clock a club just
like in different places so
accessibility-wise there's a lot of
options for people
um competitions and coding clubs
so they're a really good structure to
base that encouragement on um
just getting
as many people into it as possible um so
during my time at dresco club which i
was talking about earlier
i noticed great things about the passion
that students can have when they're
given the opportunity so the difference
in
someone's engagement can be so
noticeable depending on the environment
they're in um if they're in class if
they're in a lunchtime club if they're
with their friends if they're on their
own it just really does depend and
giving them that option and having that
safe space can bring out some amazing
projects as well as boosting people's
confidence
so creative more collaborative
projects are really good um having
freedom and creativity in younger years
and really wherever possible and is
really important i think keeping that
passion and that love for computing is
paramount in closing that gap
um
people will learn what they need to and
if they don't you can offer options for
learning but
people do tend to
learn what they need to
just give in
just giving a
in the right direction
so a flexible curriculum is similar to
that um it's a bit harder obviously when
you're in third and fourth year of the
university degree and you need to do
things but having
options especially in first year that
people can do
and having options within like society
is really
good
at just like maintaining that and
keeping that passion because people do
love computing and
i've met so many people in young years
like in high school that really really
loved it and i know that
a lot of them
will lose out on that just because of
the access that they have
and finally having a supportive teaching
department is really important because
teachers if they
are pulling their weight and if they
have people that they can support that
can support them all the time it's just
really good
and it comes it shows that in the
students and it shows that they have a
love for the subject
so yeah it really is possible to
turn this skills direct
skills decline around with some targeted
work
um and it's really it is happening we
can see there's so many movements
that are
making this happen um but we really just
do have to work hard and
it's going to take a while until we see
results but we've just got to keep
working on it
for women and just anyone in general
in computing
so yeah thank you for listening
[Applause]
you