this is strangely more disconnected than
doing this
to students and remote lectures which is
a bit odd
i suppose if anyone's getting questions
during
during the talk
um if you want to just put it in the
chat here because i'll keep open
otherwise a little bit of time for
questions
and otherwise i'll just
so uh hopefully obviously
a decent number of people there
uh
i
i think the last time i did this was
actually
in person
not this talk actually so the talk is on
friends considerations for the high
efficiency image style format i'll talk
about what that actually is in a second
so i'm hoping some people at least will
have heard of what this is
uh but we'll kind of go through a little
bit detail uh but i'm just introducing
myself quickly i'm uh sean cuon i'm a
lecturer at ed bernice university so
obviously been doing the sort of zoom uh
online stuff for a couple of years now
so this isn't a
new experience for me but if you want to
get in touch i'll have my twitter and
email down at the bottom it's the whole
talk so you don't have to
you know pay much attention to that just
be on the slides as we go forward
so i should probably mention that this
is uh taken from a source paper so this
is actually just a modified version of
the talk that i gave at this conference
roughly the start of the pandemic give
or take
so it's really available paper's really
available you can either google the
title of this talk or the paper as is
there
and you'll find an archive link or the
pdf on napier dc uk
and if you can't find any of those just
feel free to email me i can send you a
copy
uh because the whole point of this is
that we want to disseminate this
information make sure everyone's able to
get to it so
if you guys are serving up the slides
afterwards i can send mustard as well
right so why am i talking about
and that's how they like to have their
products so we can also enter the sea
for heat which doesn't sound quite as
nice to me but let's go with it for now
so as you're probably aware of jpeg
zones
you might not be aware of how old is uh
1992 is when the standard by wallace the
original paper was actually produced
so it's uh it's very long tooth
especially for the sort of internet era
so in 1982
yeah things were low resolution and
geocities was a thing and everything
looked awful and jpeg has
done quite well to age as well as it has
i think
but fundamentally it's lacking support
for modern things so hdr
might be the thing in the movies
potentially it wasn't it wasn't a thing
for image file formats back then so hdr
wasn't really considered and it's not
really something that's been bolted onto
jpeg sensitive uh we've also only looked
at the 8-bit color depth so we've not
got you know all the colors of the
rainbow as it were things like
transparency you probably realize if
you've ever tried to make a transparent
image you have to stick with into png
and the same thing for animation
jpeg doesn't do that you need things
like apng or gif or gif depending on
which of the sides you're on with how to
pronounce that
but one thing you've probably noticed if
you've been around on the internet since
the 90s is the cheap pick looks awful
particularly low resolutions just
blocking messes once you actually zoom
in
so
when you compare to the more modern
formats
it doesn't really hold up very well
either in terms of compression
uh reduction of size or in terms of the
artifacts or in terms of the features
like we just talked about there
and it's no surprise there's actually
been a bunch of opportunities let's say
to to get rid of of jpeg and uh only
eight years after jpeg was released jpeg
2000 that says jeff gpf it's meant to be
jpeg
jpeg 2000 was a thing
and it never really took off so it's
objectively better in every way than
jpeg from 1992
but it just never went anywhere the
support never really gained enough
traction to replace jpeg properly
and we've seen this time again things
like bpg which i think stands for better
portable graphics which similar kind of
name to png actually webp which is
google's formats you've probably seen in
fact the background that i downloaded
for this talk was yp when i got off the
internet so that definitely isn't you
somewhere just not very often
and you've probably not heard of jpeg xt
and a bunch of the other jpeg
formats that tried to replace jpeg or
they're trying to develop standards that
were placed just now
and avif but one of the common themes
for the latter ones
is that they're typically using
the uh codecs that are meant for video
and video actually encodes still still
images effectively as a keyframes so
because video technology's actually
we've done quite a lot
even though our stellar standards
haven't then we just kind of borrow
those video still image compression
elements
and that's actually what heath does
so he
was actually it's been around since
2015. it was quite one thing it was
seven years and it's got the file
extension heath or geek so you guys see
at the end
and it tries to bring in all of these
improvements that we've seen
so if we look in terms of the
compression ratio
it's up to 50 now in practice i haven't
actually seen that
and a test as you can see on the right
hand side i took a pair of damage of our
reasonable resolution which was about
five megabytes and converted to jpeg
and you'll see that the version
definitely is smaller
but not not by a huge amount it's not
going to be dramatic in any case but it
does have all the support for all the
hdr stuff that we're talking about
and it's allegedly got fewer artifacts
and it's better quality there's a lot of
arguing about that when uh apple decided
to release that as part of their
ios
so from iphone 7 and whichever the same
era ipad was on ios 11 right above 2017
apple switched to heath as their default
for camera based images
so you're taking that software taking a
picture
and for
the iphone users we've probably
experienced some grief because of that
like we'll get to the second but that
transition was really the first major
step in getting rid of jpeg in my
opinion is the first time we've seen
something that's really had an adoption
market adoption
and that was a lot of fighting over you
know whether it's actually better not to
look at but one of the benefits is
because it's using these video codecs
it's actually using h.265 or hgbc
to encode the images
and the burst shots which we'll get to
we can actually use hardware
acceleration so it's just better in
terms of
being more modern in a lot of different
ways
so the problem really is the software
support
so it is improving and since i wrote the
paper in 2020 or since it was published
in 2020 i can imagine things got a bit
better but i keep checking
and it doesn't seem to be getting better
you might expect especially given that
apple has taken on
as a sort of large-scale adoption
so
quite often
the advice has been to export
to jpeg if you want to send it to other
devices
so you've probably seen if your iphone
is you've probably seen articles like
this
where it's saying oh uh just just
exported to jk or here's how you export
it to jpeg as part of ios 11 for 12 or
13 words
and this article i'm screenshotting here
is actually from 2020 so
three years after apple adopted it this
was still a thing
and it probably still is i'm not an
iphone user myself
so unfortunately this same advice i
found in quite a lot of forensics books
now i don't want to name them because
that's not really the point but
even the forensics tooling the forensics
and uh
blogs and companies that are doing this
for a living didn't really have much of
a better solution at the time which is
really what inspired me to write the
paper
so i noticed there's just not generally
a good understanding of the format
this includes forensic circles and
anyone that's done any forensics will
know that knowing how things are
constructed is actually half the battle
you know if you want to do a browser
forensics then you probably want to
either have a good tool for it or be
able to go through sqlite databases same
thing with mobile forensics if the tool
doesn't support it then fundamentally
you're looking at sqlite databases or
xml files you know it pays to understand
how these things are structured
so most of the papers were on
compression and media formats and
features so it's more to do with the
encoding rather than
how does this work in terms of forensic
artifacts
so i thought i want to remedy that
and there were some forensics blog posts
in fact one of the ones i referenced in
the paper is cheeky monkey foreign
a conference paper with a reference to
cheeky monkey for instance's blog which
i thought was a new career high
but yeah it's uh it's actually not about
post so
it's quite funny monkey msp drawings so
yeah go it's good stuff
so the investigation of the paper is
basically saying this is all bad news we
need to do better than this
as a as a friends community
so again why do we care about this well
if that wasn't convincing enough well we
just have to look at the market share
that apple actually has for ios devices
so worldwide
we're sitting at about
you know a sort of
three three-quarters android although
it's been diminishing every year since i
started keeping track of this and ios is
a bit more than a quarter but if you
look specifically at the sort of main
english speaking markets in the usa and
the uk it's actually a bit more like 50
50.
so i probably should have checked this
for the wrong paper because i said
basically if you're doing
mobile forensics about 20 of the
investigations at the time would have
been ios
but in fact if you do meet in britain or
the usa it's far more than that it's
more than double that
so we definitely have to know how these
things work
and one of the problems is really that
we've moved away from
the still image format just being about
a single image
so this is one of the things you might
not realize with key format is actually
a container where we can put multiple
images inside
so
the as i said it takes the codec from
video encoding but actually it borrows
more than that is following the
structure
of a video
format a video file format to be
specific
so we look at all the way back to the
quicktime quicktime movie format
everything is sort of derived from that
all the sort of mp4 mkv containers
they're all just that they're containers
because if you think about
and this is maybe showing my energy but
if you think about like a dvd menu right
you've got all these different tracks
you've got different chapters for the
film you've got the extras you've got
different audio and language settings
you can go to the one where they
they have the commentary on top right
these are all effectively different
channels
for the same
related content
so video formats have to deal with that
for quite a long time but now we're
getting to the point where images
are not just a single picture anymore
so you can think of a containerized
image format is basically
a gallery in a file so we're not storing
a single image and something like with
jpeg we're storing a sequence of images
or a series of related images that we
can then do stuff
and the trick here is that when you're
displaying that
we're typically going to display the
cover images like so that's like the the
book cover you know there's loads of
pages in sight there might be more
images inside but we only really see the
cover
that's the main thing that you want to
display is tagged as the primary image
in youth
so there are actually multiple what we
call master images
so
like source images if you like and
there's also potentially a bunch of
derived images which are actually as
then it suggests derived from one or
more master images
and we've got multiple sequences so if
you think about sort of live images you
can take on phones these days or the
brush sequences hold them the camera
snapshot button right take a brush to
move it right that's the sequence and
that has a specific encoding we have to
take care of in this kind of format as
well but we've got more than that as
well so if you're thinking about
traditional image strategies then we're
looking at things like exit data
or maybe we've got thumbnails
embedded and the thing is for every one
of these master images is embedded
they can have separate exit content or
they can have individual thumbnails
so we've actually got not just a couple
of images but we've got a bunch of
attached information to those images
and as we'll see the support for that
and actually dealing with that is not
good at all
so most applications don't seem more
than that just that coverage that big
cover if you like and that includes the
conversion utilities so all this advice
saying convert it to jpeg and then do
your analysis there well all you're
really doing is converting that cover
image down what you want to be displayed
and nothing else you lose the rest of
that content and that information
in fact i'll just go back to this a
second so what we're seeing on the right
hand side here
is
the fact can i
turn on the pointer is that might be
more helpful
so hopefully you can see the laser
pointer and capturing uh let me know if
not so we've got
the mac preview application being
displayed here and basically we've got
an image or heath
container if you like that's got one two
three four separate images of different
seasons allegedly and then we've got our
fifth image which actually combines them
all together into a bridge format so the
thing we're seeing displayed in the main
pane here is that bright combination of
the four master images
so if i was displaying that in most
applications i would only see the
support right here i wouldn't actually
really get access to the individual
images that are comprising that
grid
itself
so that's you know i might not think
that's a big deal right now
but not having access to those
individual images might be a problem for
trying to do proper analysis
and if you take that a bit further
then one of the things is
you can actually tile images together so
not just in that sort of grid combine
them together into a big collage like
apple actually makes use of this just to
store their images normally
so i tested this out i had a friend
who's had like an iphone whatever
maximum plus you know one of these like
golds i think it literally was a gold
phone for
nothing he wanted the gold version
specifically he was doing it again
and they sent me some images over and i
had a look at it and basically what is
happening is they're taking 512 pixel
blocks
and they're combining them together into
a big grid
five minute warning code here and that
print is what is actually displayed
so there's tens of some entities
depending on the resolution
that depends on the phone we're taking
with so derived images are really
important because they're actually you
know quite strongly liked
the time before
they're quite strongly linked to the uh
you know the very nature of the whole
thing so the right hand side you can see
there's other forms we've got alpha
blends so you can take two master images
blend them together into this sort of
nice combination of the two
but we need to figure out how to display
that how to render that how to deal with
that
so the right languages are combining
things together and you can do that in a
bunch of different ways but the
fundamental thing is you need a
mechanism to do that
so for the the blending for example
there's actually a third component we're
missing here which is the alpha mask
so how do i know which pixels to blend
from each image well i just have a
bitmap it tells me with ones or zeros or
something in between how much of each of
the ones to show
so that's actually a third hidden image
of the alpha mask and we can do the same
thing with depth of field so we've got
depth mask which we can apply which is
actually more likely what you're going
to see with apple
know you've got that sort of portrait
mode where you take the depth of field
image
so these auxiliary images aren't even
displayed in
any of the tools that i've used so mac
preview doesn't show them they're not
really viewable you can't see them but
the problem is that could be used to
encode other information right
so if i've just got an alpha mask that
could actually be just a different image
that could just be a bit that knowledge
and if i really wanted to i could have
three of those and i could have them
represent different rgb channels combine
them later on in social image
but we wouldn't really be able to notice
it without proper analysis tools
can run over great things
right so this gives us a bit of abuse
potential because we can now use these
auxiliary images we can't actually
really display it properly at the moment
as a carrier so we think about it in
terms of steganography
or just
any kind of data hiding coding this is
now this sort of grayscale illuminance
channel that never really gets displayed
anywhere and if we're subtle about it
you wouldn't even be able to notice it
even if you're using that in an alpha
blend or a depth of field blend so it
just gives us additional channels
that are not really up for analysis in
the same way we'd really thought of
image transits
so what does it look like on windows
i've showed you a couple of previews of
what it looks like on mac
windows
typically looks like this you try and
open the image and uh yeah it just says
we can the photos application in
particular has a lot of trouble with
this
however you might see that it is
rendering the thumbnail view in explorer
so the grid version on the left hand
side of this is
[Music]
which is just a different combinations
it's a different
setup for deriving a derived image
it doesn't display at all right so on
windows it's kind of tricky there's a
bunch of plugins you have to have some
of them are paid
it's just a bit of a mess right so even
though windows does support this
it doesn't support this out of the box
right it's still a bit of a mess even
two years after writing that original
paper
uh android does support it but again it
doesn't really have that full support we
hope
so one of the other things we can do
here as well is have lossless editing so
you take the original image and you chop
off some bits and normally what happens
is once you've made that edit
you don't get access to the original
data it's gone right
but if
all it does is it gives you a different
aperture for viewing that image so the
rest of that data is still present in
the file
it's just not presented
so what actually happens is the
modifications of keith you can do them
in real time
at display time and the player
players that technically use the
documentation is the thing that does
that problem
and this applies to rotate mirror and
crop which are we call lossless edits
for the original image is still there
you just might not be able to see it
because again our feeling isn't quite
there and a requirement of a complete
heave player is that you do all these
things
losslessly so it's not so much a problem
right now you can imagine situations
where like the illegal part of the image
is cropped out if you don't have the
tools to see that that's a bit of a
problem
however last time i checked apple isn't
supporting the lossless editing but so
much but you can use it you can't
generate these using apis
[Music]
so in the future
the cover image might not really be
representative
for apple devices either
but you can still generate these images
and there's a github link in the paper
you can generate these images using the
api as i mentioned in that paper
and if you just look this is what i just
looked at
just earlier before the talk
if you look at it in it still
doesn't let you see the rest of the
image you're still only seeing that
segment of it so even a tool that has
decent support for heath
doesn't give you the full image it only
gives you that cropped segment that the
player
is representing so the rest of that
image is still there in the fireworks
can't see it
and to make matters worse we can hide
things so i'll increase speed a little
bit just to get through this but
basically
just as the auxiliary images those
bitmaps those depth maps
aren't visible by default it can
actually flag things to be hidden
specifically so we look on the right
hand side this is actually a first shot
there's a few preview images and i
flipped one bit
that basically told the player not to
display one of those
and i'm just going through this so a
single bit
in the in the information box basically
just said don't display this none of the
players actually get around that they
all just do what that bit says
so the lack of frenzy still is a big
deal here because i can hide all the
illegal stuff just display the behind
things
and not be any the wiser because the
tooling isn't there
and oddly he can actually refer to files
outside as well it's got a url
data field which i think is supposedly
for exit
you can see how pointing external data
could have security issues but also just
be a bit of a pain to analyze generally
there's no support as far as you can see
for any of this stuff and the only way
to get all the information for
birthshots that
and export and that gives you just a
list of all the keyframes as well
so how does this apply for hashing well
hashing is an issue because
cryptographic hashing is meant for
identifying legal content that's usually
meant for identifying exact things so
there's a bunch of semantic things in
approximate matching which i thought
about the lectures but we don't really
want to get into that
but if it's looking for exact things
we've got container
well that's kind of one image in one
thumbnail
but if you've got a container like
format like eve that's about
hashing a zip file you know we don't
even move around things in that zip file
we can add them to the zip file you can
change the order of things so hashing
the whole thing
isn't necessarily that useful unless we
just want to identify that whole
container we're not identifying
individual elements at that point so i
flip things around i add new items that
hash breaks
and we also have to bear in mind that
for brush shots the images are recorded
like videos recorded
effectively between the frames
so if you add in an extra frame or
remove some frames then we're going to
again change the whole binary sequence
which is a problem for action fits
so ideally we need to do something a bit
more clever
maybe involving hatching all the
subframes so use that event export
individual keyframes and hashtags
so i'll go through the layout just
uh really briefly
in fact i'll skip over this if you want
to know more about this look at the
have a look at the paper basically
because it's a complicated format it's
kind of all in place right
uh you've got a lot of different ways of
encoding this information a lot of
different combinations and basically
there's nothing that's going to look at
all these different boxes right there's
tons of stuff in there it's a lot more
complicated than jpeg is
i'll skip over this as well but
basically the point of this is for
software support
it's just not there so if you look at
this and again this is the paper i don't
really want to cover this i was just
throwing in to show you that is
pretty good support for still images
not for the first shots ffmpeg doesn't
really do still images it does quite
well at birth shots but all of the other
things i looked at really hit miss you
know a lot of them don't really cover
even the master images for them
and they just don't handle worse
sequences at all so you really need to
pick your balance here when using the
tilling
so given
all of the sort of lack of support i
found
basically the the analysis approach i'm
suggesting is have a look at the header
if you see
anything that looks like this it's a
file actually just says like
um f-type geek or mif1 heat right so you
could just read that out and then we see
the picture part and that tells us it's
actually still images of picture we want
to check for the box structure which you
just do by looking at strings
and the main reason there is we want to
see if there's any derived images so if
we just jump back really quickly we can
see here that that says green right and
that means that there's a grid and you
can see there's a bunch of individual
boxes with the individual master images
so that tells us how many pictures are
actually in that image even if you can't
see them all of our tools
and then we want to check there's a
specific bit again you can check in the
paper there's a specific bit the mark
since it's hidden so we want to unhide
those flipping that bit
and then you can preview it in lag or
and it's a video we want to export
using ffmpeg and that gives us at least
for now the best shot at seeing
everything inside that container because
really the tooling just still isn't
there
so conclusions
is a complicated container format it's
not really a still image format in the
old sense or png or jpeg
current phrasing skills not good you
actually have to do quite a lot of
manual work if you really want to find
out what's inside this files
and
future forensics tools should really
display the box structure in the item
structure because remember it can be
complicated the arrangement of
thumbnails and exit data you want to be
able to completely unpack that you want
to be able to display the hidden items
that includes the auxiliary depth map
things sequences of frames all that
except data
we want to be able to hash the
individual elements which again
uh because it's a container format
there's no point hashing the whole zip
file we want to see what's inside of it
and we want to attempt to address things
like external references and some of the
other weird behavior that's in there
so if you want to know more there's the
specifications in the iso documents iso
bmf and iso keith
uh they'll probably also read stylus
which is why i wrote this paper but the
full paper like i said is easily
available online
so uh
i think i'll wrap up there i know that
the time is pushed a little bit
so i don't have a good time for
questions or not but if you want to ask
me a question feel free to hit me up on
twitter
so uh that's the little one there and my
email address is at the bottom if you're
if you're interested in
following up a bit on that
does anyone have any questions
so i don't know if we've got 10 for any
questions or
should we just wrap up
two seconds
i should probably point out there's a
couple of apis and the the best overall
is this uh i think it was a master's
paper a master's thesis actually at the
moment implementation
for the format
and then it's just it's a really useful
document
for working through this and apple also
have a bunch of videos on stuff which is
quite useful for the developers
usually the 2017 uh wwe dc is the best
one but i think they've been a few cents
how difficult is it to write metadata
files well that assumes that you've got
tools that can actually parse the format
and allow you to edit that stuff
so the editors for it were few and far
between uh most of the stuff including
is really working with a limited set in
fact i didn't even see a good way of
viewing the except data on editing
now obviously you can just get out
get a hex editor and you can find the
except blocks and you can do whatever
you like with that
but in terms of having tooling to do it
or even viewing it's not really there so
if you take exit tool and you point at a
heat image that has
four images in the auto exit you will
see precisely one of those you'll see
whichever one is marked as the cover
so the whole thing is just about over
the place like if you edit it
people probably won't even know this
because they won't see it
if that makes sense