thank you
um so thank you for coming along and
listening to my talk uh this is a topic
i'm in fact i'm passionate about it's
also great to be given a talking
personally first time
in two years um hopefully we'll see more
of this thing happening
um later in the year as well more
impressive about it's great um so i'm
going to be working about giving a whole
slide of about myself i'll just give you
a quick thing um so my name is
i
involved in application security so this
is why i have such a vested interest in
supply chains or more supply chains from
the software
so
i'm going to start off with
two questions and don't answer them now
i'll come to them at the end but
now the first question is would you
allow any sort of stranger off the
street
to commit code
to your code
i think another answer for this but
let's keep that in mind
and then the second one if you're an
attacker would you take the easy route
[Music]
so i think one of the important things
is we need to take a step back and see
how things have changed
especially when it comes to developing
software and including uh third party
software
so when i first got off my career i
started off
at a time where
third party software wasn't really that
common
most often or you would develop things
from the ground up so companies will go
off pull down internal libraries and
you'd probably be asked the question why
would you want to use someone else's
stuff why not develop an attorney from
the security point of view this is great
you have better conform visibility into
the alliance
from a code re-usability point of view
it's not so great i mean you could
reinvent the wheel there's a lot of
maintenance around these packages so
everything sort of new functionality or
updates that needs to be done you have
to have invested time and
resources doing that
so if you shift towards to what how we
approach it today it's completely
changed
so i think of most applications it's
kind of blue you take all these
different libraries and frameworks and
you code them together to form the
functions and features that you want and
this is fantastic from a business point
of view what it means is we can get
things out faster and quite going with
nasa efforts
from a security point of view though it
does introduce some element of rights
you're taking
code essentially from outside your
organization clearly to your
suffering
and this is where the risk starts
growing and it's starting to become
more of an issue today and i'll go
through that
what i have here is a snapshot from a
company called
so i'm going to talk about kind of the
de facto
uh name in uh dependencies and third
party libraries
and every year they
produce those reports called uh i've got
to remember the name of it
the state of the software supply chain
so they do that on a daily basis
and what this shows is just the number
of downloads in terms of an increase so
this was from ross's report 2021
um
comparing that to the year before so
2020. i'm really interested to see what
this year's report's going to like that
but you can see those numbers there are
quite significant and that is the
increase
in the number of downloads of the
different languages
so you're looking towards something like
java which is like 71
um join the script fifty percent
bathroom ninety-two percent so on and so
forth and those are already a high
number and they just keep on growing
correctly and this kind of forms into
that whole point about the way we change
our
strategy
that's great we need to get those things
out a lot quicker
so
this
does introduce the element of press as i
mentioned
um
[Music]
because you have the third party
occurred this means attackers can start
leveraging this to attack organizations
or kind
[Music]
could use but some of the methods that
they can use to
target these libraries and targeted
organizations
so at the top is
a
attack type called dependency confusion
this is quite a relatively new stacked
up it was
a ton of conceptualized last year
this leverages the way package managers
work
um
with package managers you typically have
a
public
facing repository so in the likes of
java modern
you could have made a repository called
native central
um in parthenon you have pie pie
and
organizations have their own internal
primary repositories and these are
repositories that aren't
um publicly facing well they shouldn't
be there any progress that are only
accessible to their organization and
this is where organizations would place
their own
packages
on needed repositories so any sort of
software they're
developing including
web applications that are bundled up
nicely and can
be done about a
crc
way of doing things
now dependency confusion
takes these two repositories and it
leverages the fact that by default
most package managers will attempt to
download the package from the public
repository first before it attacks any
completed problem
so what attacker could do is create the
same package structure name and version
number and
then they can post it as a public
repository
so when the organization comes to
develop and then pick the right version
or download the attacker's package
versus the external one
and this
attack type is actually very quite
significantly i forgot the exact numbers
it is about silence of course but it is
becoming a big issue in fact it's now
one of the most common types of attacks
on software dependencies
other examples
of tyre attacks are malicious packages
so this is where an attacker would
actually purposely create a package with
vulnerability with that
and then compromise packages so this is
quite similar to the malicious packages
but this is where so the german package
that the attacker compromises
that account somehow so they can
compromise the author's account or
compromise the bullet structure that
builds and deploys that package
and then the last one is vulnerable
packages so these again are legitimate
packages but they have some sort of
vulnerability in it whereby they're
tackled within your own exploit
and coming towards
the title of this talk is
it's becoming very impressive so i've
personally seen this starting to rank up
um i've started giving this book
a lot of designs back in 2019
but um
i started giving this book in 2019 i
couldn't wrap my head around the fact
that there's a glaring whole
easy goal for attackers and i couldn't
figure out what other entire regime is
first forward to today
we're starting to see that happening
pretty significantly i just saw a tweet
yesterday from trusted said oh
[Music]
actually sorry 2020 um all the way
through to
uh 2022.
um so you started off with the likes of
solarwinds which i'm sure many of you
realize or heard about the internet so
that happened in december 2022
um and then the latest one actually
happened this week and i'll actually
show hopefully a lot of them
so one of the things i'm not doing when
everybody
is to give some real world examples so
it's always good saying hey this may be
an issue or this could probably happen
or whatever
this is this could happen this has
happened um and trying to highlight some
cases where it has happened
so probably one of the most
targeted philosophies
at the moment is npm
so low package manager or whiteboard
um so this is basically
javascript
and
there have been numerous cases over the
last two weeks and months where
attackers have
leveraged the
public nature of it and started hosting
their own malicious packages so they've
done things from parker's quantity uh
squadron is where attack would try and
create a package with a very similar
name or
notion to the package to target
so example
was
this one with roboblocks there was some
npm
packages that you could buy in the
discord
[Music]
which package is a legitimate package
that's probably one of the problems that
we face today there's no way of saying
well this is a legitimate this is
probably nice
um
and then i think
i forgot the exact article but also
recently um
spring before
they were
doing research and they found a whole
bunch of other malicious packages on him
here i write it i actually didn't know
this for recently
and now i'm doing a pretty good job of
finding rid of this but it's
basically an easy battle because i'm
also in nature most
attackers can just simply go
[Music]
when people are using packages for
software the iphone comes in their own
conclusion that okay it's an official
repository so therefore everything can
be trusted
and thank you very much most packages
are legitimate and unfortunately there
are some that aren't
and this example we have thankfully
wasn't an idiologist mental malicious
package but there was a package that
apps did absolutely nothing nonetheless
they have three fathers
if you try to use this package it would
accomplish nothing
um
and i don't know why
the author created this package maybe
they were gonna
do something with the letter
there was only one version um and it
eventually got taken over by the
official npm
accounts
this package name was
dash that was named just dash
again i think they're assuming that
people will start things when they're
dropping commands
what was worrying and so great about
this is if you have a look at those
graphs
the first point in the graph is when
that packet was released or sorry when i
could do snapshots so with the npm
repository
downloads and how many dependents so how
many other packages used as a dependency
and that first snapshot was taken in
19th of august in 2021
sorry that's a tough one
and
all the way through to just a few weeks
ago
and you can see the significant increase
so we talked about thousands of weekly
downloads
and there was about
94 i think
dependence uh
84 other packages depending on how has
package of the dependency
and this package does nothing
so that to me points especially if
people are just downloading stuff
without actually that
another example thankfully this one
didn't go anywhere but it could have
ended up really bad
php
i'm sure we all are all parallel page
peers you have really common things such
as wordpress
um php
and what the attack has done is it
managed to
do a malicious code commit to the
official php repository
if that got out you can imagine the
impact that that would have but
thankfully that coach comment was called
everybody else anyway and php
subsequently changed their whole way
that they not even
i think they moved for possibilities to
get started
but that just shows you the potential
for this
if they if the attacker managed to
successfully put a backboard
that would have compromised thousands if
not tens of thousands
of
service potential
[Music]
uh
this one
i have mixed reactions about this
because
on the one hand it is pretty significant
so java is very widely used blog for jay
is
the kind of de facto logging framework
so it is used extensively across
multiple applications in java so you're
talking about web apps
and so the breadth of this was pretty
significant the fact that you could also
export exported with redness and ease um
when i said i read into these it very
much depended so if it was like
an internally developed web application
it would be pretty difficult because
everything you're doing
whereas if you have open source you can
actually then see things
see the code and all that lesson is
pretty significant and then allow
foreign execution
the worrying thing about this is the
aftermath
so a lot of these types of great perhaps
there but then you stand back and look
at it a few
weeks months later
how many
[Music]
all right so let's first write out some
numbers
one million
how many do you think
that's about money
one question four million
[Music]
um since the december the
10th when it came out
[Music]
what
so
since december the 10th there's been 30
just over
say around about probably now close to
37 and a half million dollars
of a vulnerable version of oxygen
and that accounts for 46
of all downloads
are blocked from jail
and the thing at the time that really
got me warmed up is the way we're
approaching this and i'll come
a bit later
ironically another gentleman will be
patchy strands
and this one here is pretty significant
um
the reason why i picked this when i was
debating when i should stole
paul conventions
this happened in 2017
organization for imperfects which i'm
sure most of us have heard about
and it's been subsequent i mean
sometimes sense
that vulnerability costs that company
one and a half billion dollars
but more importantly for me is that
vulnerability should have made people
aware
of the things that you need to do back
in 2017
so the really frustrating thing for me
um when i love today is
without projecting that
people should have already been prepared
based off this vulnerability
we have people going around not
wondering whether we're using them for j
but this vulnerability here where patchy
stretch should have got people thinking
about this
and then actually we find a separate
situation
oh my gosh another day
[Music]
um
and hopefully with this i'll be able to
show you a uh demo and talk us through
this but again another vulnerability has
come out
not aware of any attacks yet but there
is a working proof of concept
so
we have these problems
this was one of the very frustrating
things
with relaxing work for jay when it came
out
when it came out
we saw many people jumping on it and
that was great
but in my view were oppression and wrong
so about that i mean
people trying to create satellite
scanners but hey we're going to scan
your network and scan all the files on
that's great for software that you buy
or use open source
fantastic but any kind of software that
you develop
that's not sustainable
and it's a really rudimentary way of
doing it there are ways that are going
to be much better
and as i said back in 2017
that should have been a long while for
you to start doing this stuff
which is why i would work for jake and
i'm so frustrated
but as you see it's still a problem we
still try and solve the same problem
using old methods
so the way we should be doing these
things is using something called sca the
software composition analysis well what
this does is actually scan the code
generates what's termed a software
development materials and s1
that that can be used to manage your
dependencies in your software the sas
model can also be scanned by the sca
to determine which packages are
vulnerable
so in the case of a multiple job if you
use appropriate
sda you can send
in hey
where am i using this specific version
of this package
all these uh projects create anonymous
exactly where i need to go and update
those libraries i can't update those
libraries i don't know where i can
running
focus uh remediation so rats that kind
of thing
you're not dealing with this by me
and this is what organizations shouldn't
be doing back in 20 from 2017 likewise
not very network scanners and thought
scanners and that kind of thing
this is gold
this is
how you can help solve this problem
so what are the tools that does a really
fantastic job i don't often recommend
tools i try to keep as much as possible
but i like exception for the school
this is something i've seen firsthand
the benefit of
it's a total loss that can
[Music]
or thousands of dollars to use but it's
free
use it there's like no reason why
you should be using something like this
and make sure that you integrate this in
your body cycle so it's continuously
doing
this scanning before it's
continuously creating the results
it's not a single point of time once the
vulnerability comes up you need to make
sure you stay on top of this this is
something i've seen
done
generally pretty
quietly in the past where
versions will be used at that specific
point in time and then they won't be
updated afterwards it's a continuous
process you need to make sure that you
stay on top of this
so what i'm going to do now
is
i'm going to show some examples
[Music]
uh
there we go
so i have some projects in here you can
see it's gonna
boards and all that kind of stuff
but the really cool stuff about this is
and now you start seeing the snapshots
away your different vulnerabilities
so if i can i can see the first series
so you can now start seeing where
what makes up this specific building
on specific projects and you can even
see when packages are out of date
but you're probably more interested in
the vulnerabilities
[Music]
and you can go with the vulnerabilities
now you can start seeing snapshots
of the different vulnerabilities and
severity
so now this makes triaging the update
5000 updates
even better so you can start determining
from the top
critical high
maybe in england
the other also very important thing is
you can
with this tool
come into the components view
and then start searching for different
components across all your projects
so
say for
there's very instance
entry for this like there was with a
spring
which is why you see
that spring demo
this week
it should be showing vulnerabilities
because that is actually wrong
but because there's no entry yet in the
vulnerability databases saying
um some other ones that can be applied
as well
um
you can't see that or fan when you
notice above eventually you can come
into this component section search for
the companions and see where to be used
and then deal with it appropriately
and as i mentioned
one of the other
best of this was
the continuous advice
so this toy has a planner that allows
you to integrate with jenkins and you
can actually start running this as part
of your whole cycle
so as you can see on the right hand side
there's a nice graph so you can actually
see that little fact
that projects
and see how many probabilities you have
and all of that and you can't even go
further
so what you can actually do
[Music]
at the bottom is you can have these kind
of release gates
uh
what they're called their thresholds
so you can actually cause the bubble to
fail if it has a certain level of
critical vulnerabilities
or a certain number of high
you can set those thresholds and whether
they're new or existing
so you can have suddenly
start being reactive rather than
um also
being proud rather than being reactive
so you can start really attacking this i
do have a continuous manner
so those are the tools that you can use
now as i mentioned
maybe a bit more exciting is the spring
of mobility
so the spring capability came out this
week two days ago in fact
on wednesday
and there is
this game
[Music]
cool so i'm saying
simple page
this is a beautiful concept so
bear with me
the real assignment is probably lower
level
and then the actual exponents itself
so
what we have here is
some query that's used around this
concept
um
this is the vulnerability in the spring
mvc model view container
it's a
passion that's used by many web
applications in order to represent
business like logic data and then
represent that as a view to the user
the
the interesting bit for the proof of
concept is
the view could really be anything the
the vulnerability itself plasma
controller where you have a vine this is
basically a way of tying the model
to your business content
and
we
allocating this controller as a resource
called part and
this is where the magic happens
this next book
so listen
when the song moves came out a little
bit of confusion around it
goes back to get it working
um there were some difficulties between
the
x-ray script itself
some details and it's but eventually we
think but thanks kind of people managed
to get it working
what this does is actually actually for
the london building screen
dumps a jsp file i'm a top cat server so
this is only vulnerable if you're
running spring that's right
uh way back on actual tomcats
and it does
jsp basically whatever you
[Music]
um
so the next thing we need to do
is actually write
um
[Music]
oh
so what i'm going um do now is
run the exploits so this is going to
send off the request to the server
with the command camera
and if it's successful we should get the
user that it's running as
fingers crossed
there we go yeah it works
so
we're going to review i'm running
that root
so i can do
uh
[Music]
probably a bit slow
come on there we go yeah um so that is
full remote code execution
now whether this can happen with uh out
authentication now i don't know um
just my medium
i think it could possibly be so
it uses
the combination of the header and post
bodies in that
[Music]
as you can see this is pretty
significant and this was just found on
the screen so the point is there's all
these vulnerabilities out there and
is
so coming back to those first
impressions are so many beginnings
would you allow someone to remind
some random stranger along the streets
around uh
i'm talking about the problem
you yes or no
no yeah
so
why are we then just putting
stuff from a repository where we don't
even know the person we've never seen
them
there's no difference right we are
literally just pointing forward from the
internet
off uh without any validation go ahead
and look at that very dash that's a good
example no validation mean that if there
was then people wouldn't be diagnosed
[Music]
we just need to verify the whole
transfer verify so
libraries that you are using in your
software
try to do at least a rough review of it
and then from an attacker point of view
would you want to spend hours and a
whole bunch of effort trying to get
through to an organization
when you can do something like
create a malicious package
and then get immediately inserted into
an organization
or many organizations
with relatively
little effort
and you're going to get
straight away and much better escalated
privilege
with blood effort so it's going to be
running in a production environment
possibly
with privileged access to customer data
obviously preparing your notification
your target but from attacker point of
view it's a great way to
the other problem is there's just
because of that wealth or that volume
and you're talking about if you know it
would be every single time uh sorry
every line of code you're talking about
thousands of lines possibly per um
dependency and then the dependencies
have low independent seasons gets messed
so trying to manually review every one
of the quotes it's not feasible
so you've got this paralegal and
haystack type of thing try to find that
snippet of code that's hiding in your
massive wealth of code
it's going to be really difficult
so
just ending off
i think
the closing thing i
would like to say
while
it's going to be difficult to tackle
this problem
and there's different things out there
such as google cells that are that
aren't trying to look at tackling this
problem we have to start with somewhere
and if
going back to the way we approach things
like blood
about
we're not even starting off there we're
still doing the old things so our view
is
if we can just start looking at using
things like seas that's a good starting
point that's going to put us in a good
position to get you forward and have
anything else that comes up with you
talk about the
uh authors and different dependencies
and all that kind of thing
so we just need sort of somewhere
looking at this tuning in
it's not cost prohibitive
so we shouldn't be here and
so
thank you um
been great to give this talk to you and
finally talk to people's faces rather
than some webcam
which has been fantastic
and yeah any questions
yeah
you kept that
the majority of organizations have got
zero control over their code
so how are they gonna
do this
it's all compiled
uh what do you mean zero
[Music]
is
this is where you can start holding
vendors to account so things like when
spring or love for j comes up you start
posing those questions to those edits
what are you doing about this how are
you protecting me
um and then also looking have things
like security advice and each of those
vendors it's a really good case because
it shouldn't start if they are affected
by that they should or even if they're
unaffected by us they shouldn't have
some run up informing their users of how
they're reacting to it what their users
need to do
so um
um
yeah so
i think
the trouble is with vulnerable learnings
and malicious packages right so in
camera i could be wrong but as far as i
know they don't remove vulnerable
versions from their repositories if they
did they'll probably break a whole bunch
of things
malicious packages there's obviously a
very
dire
this is why
organizations need to invest in their
own repositories
so they can have control
and there are tools like sign up
firewall we can start sending some
policies
um using one organization it's really
great we can start saying our policies
where you kind of get called about those
versions
but there's also just another important
thing that many people forget
package is a lot of the dependencies are
cash
so it's all very right we have this
malicious packages and something like
the mpm let's pull it to your private
repository
that's not very very well so you
physically remove that
yeah you remove it from that repository
uh and then having things like scholarly
or constantly monitoring so this is
you could argue that the composition
[Music]
managers could do
more to help
but um
[Music]
it's
it's a difficult one but all the
organizations ready to take control of
this
[Music]
unfortunately reported i wish they did
they would include some examples but i
don't just say yeah this is the biggest
so i'm telling you what you're saying
especially if it's an internal uh
package you have to kind of create it
exactly the same otherwise
the long vowels um i think sometimes
organizations build their own internal
packages as well i know google does
themselves they don't actually download
packages so obviously
um the building is only so
that could maybe be a way to get access
to the source code results
but unfortunately i don't know i just
know that someone's talking about it
says the largest
[Music]
all right well
thanks android
[Applause]