okay can you all hear me
alrighty
so i wanted to give this talk for a
while uh i was going to give it in first
year as a
workshop so i'm happy to finally give it
in some kind of form
okay click it's not working
okay so before we begin a couple things
i'd like to
say
so we got less than an hour so
i can only cover a fraction of what
there is to know and for that reason
we'll be focusing very heavily on the
technical issues but it's very unlikely
in the case of personal safety that
the solution will be purely technical
it's also possible that your privacy
won't be a secret so
if you start encrypting your
communications anybody who's currently
used dropping on you will know that they
can no longer read your messages
and we're also going to talk a wee bit
about the topic of domestic violence so
this talk is by no means an alternative
to seeking help if you are currently
going through a crisis
so i've left the link for that as well
so you don't have to throw all of your
tech into the nearest body of water
you can actually still have nice things
and by making you aware of the threats
you can make an informed decision
about
how you want to deal with them
you definitely don't need to do
everything in this talk
and
if you are the victim of a crime
make sure that you gather evidence of
that and
it is often safer to do that when the
evidence is digital
does anybody know who nadia is
you might know her better by her band
and art movement riot
she personally offended along with her
band
the
russian government and the russian
president
back in 2011
and ended up on the run she managed a
whole week
before being captured which is quite
impressive
and
eventually she was caught because one of
her bandmates forgot to use tor
we'll talk about tour a bit later
but what this is an example of is that
the tools that we're going to talk about
today are not necessarily perfect
but they can go a long way to keeping
you freer for longer
she was for her first arrest sentenced
or
served two years in jail
so threat modeling is a huge topic we
don't really have time to cover it we
could do a whole hour's talk on threat
modeling but we'll do some risk analysis
for four very different groups
public figures uh there's a huge amount
of personal information on public
figures and famous people online you can
google them you can look them up on
wikipedia
and a lot of that information is
accurate
they also have very motivated and
well-resourced adversaries
but they do have the advantage that
generally speaking their physical
security is very strong
domestic abuse survivors
are similar in that their adversary is
motivated and all of their personal
information might be known
their adversary's resources are going to
vary
and their technical abilities are going
to vary but in general
they're likely to put a lot of resources
into their abuse and also even if their
own technical abilities are limited
they're likely to be able to
either
hire somebody with better technical
abilities or collaborate with other
people with technical abilities
the big difference is that domestic
abuse survivors have very very limited
personal security
so
activists wherever you are in the world
uh you're very likely to at some point
face a rest and depending on where you
are in the world
uh
it depends how bad that arrest is going
to be for you
in general you can assume that your
devices are going to be seized both the
ones that you have on you and
potentially the ones that you have at
home
so it's probably in your best interest
to make sure that
there's no
harmful evidence on those devices
devices can also be tracked so if you
take your mobile to a demonstration
there's the possibility that the police
can
track that using stingray devices which
emulate
cell towers and can be used to uniquely
identify the devices that were at the
demonstration
even if the police don't actively use
stingrays at the demonstration there's a
fair chance that they can still subpoena
your cell carrier to share the
information about your location
retroactively
because your cell carrier is always
monitoring your location
using cell site data
and
and they'll actually often sell this
data for advertisers as well
finally journalists
a lot of the same issues that we've
already discussed
but the main difference with journalists
and whistleblowers is that they may want
to hide the fact that communication
occurred in the first place
so our first risk is metadata
and we're going to be looking mostly at
images because we share images all the
time and there's a huge amount of
harmful metadata that's stored in them
but images are not the only thing that
store metadata
your pdf files and your office documents
do as well so if you're trying to
anonymously publish something you
probably don't want authorship
information or information about the
hardware and software that you created
the document on
so
metadata and images can involve
your kind of exif data so there's a
bunch of unique ids there's timestamps
so like time and date when the photo was
taken geolocation so they're geotagged
with gps coordinates and
even a whole bunch of information about
the device that took the
photograph
which can even include how like how long
it's been powered on
there's a python open source project uh
called map2 and this is the best way to
wipe the metadata out of all of these
files
so
yeah that includes pdf files audio video
and images
it does not wipe file system metadata
and it does not support heat which we'll
talk about in a minute
your mileage may vary with social media
some of them
may very well delete the metadata but
there's no guarantee that they won't
store the original image and there's no
guarantee that they won't use that
metadata for their own purposes
so heath is the file format that's been
used
for iphone photos since the iphone 7
and
it
is generally superior to jpeg in every
way but the metadata is effectively
unwipable because it's not supported by
matte
or any other metadata anonymization tool
that i know of
so my advice is if you want to wipe the
metadata from your iphone images
you have two choices either
convert the images that you want to wipe
to jpeg first
and then
wipe the metadata from the jpeg
or
you can actually store the
images in jpeg format rather than heat
format by going into your camera
settings
and selecting most compatible instead of
most efficient
the conversion can be done with a tool
called image magic and i've given an
example of
another command that you'd use to
convert a
peek file called selfie to jpeg
the conversion will not wipe the
metadata so you'll need to do that
separately
so because heap is superior it allows
you to take higher quality audio and
video or
picture and video so
i'm hoping that at some point somebody
will just add support for heath
to matt
it might even make a good honors project
for someone
at a minimum if you're not going to wipe
any of the metadata you can
at the very least
disable
location access to your camera and then
at least you won't be geo tagging
your photos
so if you were to need to relocate to
australia and you were geotagging with
your location in the gold coast
you might be giving yourself away are we
though
so malka or spy cameras is an issue that
started most likely in south korea
in 97
according to wikipedia
cameras have become really small they've
become inexpensive they've become really
widely available and you can connect
them to the internet using wi-fi or
cellular
which makes them possible to hide in
basically anything
so
my advice to you is whenever you're
staying in any kind of rented
accommodation whether that's a long-term
rental
for your actual accommodation or whether
it's an airbnb or a hotel for a holiday
is actually sweep the room and look for
cameras
what you're really looking for is the
lens it could just be a kind of hole in
various things from
the tissue box to the plastic shroud of
a smoke detector
or behind towels
anything that's facing the bed or the
shower
is particularly suspicious
and
if you can't confirm that a hole has a
camera in it you could always take some
electrical tape with you and just plug
the hole with the electrical tape
so if you do happen to find a camera
you should not try to engage the bnb or
the hotel staff because they may then
try to destroy the evidence so capture
your own evidence using photographs and
videos and then contact the police and
take allow them to take custody of the
suspected device
so the devices can work in multiple ways
they could be live streaming straight to
a website or they could be storing their
video
feed to a sd card and then the creepy
person would upload it later
there's a real risk of blackmail so
famous people are at higher risk
because if they know who you are
and if you're in a hotel they probably
have your name and contact details
they can
find you on social media on linkedin and
then threaten to reveal
the video that they've captured to your
friends family and colleagues
in south korea they have specialized
equipment to track them track the radio
signals from the devices but it doesn't
seem to be particularly effective
so i'm not sure how much of a deterrent
it actually is
and women in south korea are
disproportionately targeted
but nobody's immune to this
stacy dooley did a documentary on
malka in south korea so if you're
interested in that topic that's worth
the watch
so we're blowing the lines away but
between physical and digital
but
facial recognition is generally
something that happens in the physical
world but most of the issues are with
the long-term storage of your
face
on digital media
so there are a couple of different
varieties of it live facial recognition
has been deployed in london in a limited
number of cameras according to the mat
and they use it for targeted
surveillance of people to actually track
people in real time
in other places it's actually illegal so
in
california for example the police can't
wear them on their body cams
so i'm not quite sure how effective that
makeup is
in
hiding your face from facial recognition
but
it definitely looks cool and the makeup
artist mimi is over on instagram and jan
is the cso at brave
so finally
it's also in airport arrivals and
you might be able to opt out but
if you do you're very likely to have to
identify yourself to border guards
personally
so the advantage with facial recognition
is uh during a pandemic it is
contactless
and there's an ongoing effort to work
around masks because mouth and nose are
particularly distinctive and relied on
for a lot of the accurate facial
recognition
and iphones from the iphone 12 onwards
can unlock
using your face even when you're wearing
a mask but they can mostly only get away
with this because they're not trying to
uniquely identify you they're just
trying to make sure that there's a
reasonable chance in a crowd of people
that you're the only one who's going to
be able to unlock your phone
identical twins cause a really serious
problem to
all facial recognition
so shoulder surfers are people who look
over your shoulder
to try and see you entering passwords on
your keyboard or your phone
and
there's a few protections that you can
get from them
firstly
you should just in general avoid
entering passwords and pins in public
and instead rely on biometrics like face
id and touch id
they might be able to figure out which
finger they need to cut off
but that's a very different threat to
somebody entering your password without
your knowledge
you're not only looking out for people
if there's a camera over your shoulder
that's the same issue
you can also get a modicum of privacy by
using a privacy shield like the one on
the picture
and if somebody's sitting next to you
they're unlikely to see what's on your
phone because it's
it just looks really dark
but it is directional so if you're using
your phone in landscape mode instead of
portrait it does approximately nothing
so the same goes if somebody's looking
down from above or up from below
keyloggers these can be software based
or hardware based
the main difference is that hardware is
something you can hit with a hammer
software is something you can only cuss
at
so
a software-based
keylogger can be dealt with in
primarily by using something like
tails which is an operating system
that runs in memory
so you're not actually using whatever
operating system you normally use where
the malware is installed but you're
using an entirely different one
and we'll talk a little bit about tails
later
you can also often just run an antivirus
scan because most key loggers are just
commodity malware
a hardware base might look like the one
in the picture but on a laptop it could
be hidden within the laptop so you might
not be able to see it
you might get some defense from using an
on-screen keyboard but then you've got
problems with
some malware that could
record your screen
so ideally it would be better just to
use a trusted device either that
of one belonging to a trusted friend or
maybe a library
so
keylogger is generally used to steal
your password so let's talk about
passwords
passwords should be long nonsensical
strings that are generated entirely
randomly and stored in an encrypted file
or database
then the file or database should be
unlocked with a single strong passphrase
and
yeah what we're obviously talking about
is password managers
there are two main varieties uh online
password managers and offline password
managers
the online variety will sync your
passwords onto your different devices
but it means that you're entrusting
whatever service it is with all of your
passwords
hopefully they can't read them
the offline variety gives you total
control over your passwords but with
that control comes responsibility to
synchronize them
across your different devices yourself
many passwords or many browsers have a
password manager built in now if you
choose to use that one and my main
recommendation would just be to make
sure to use a master password so that
they're encrypted and a wee bit harder
to steal
also make sure your passwords are unique
for each website
because a really common attack now is
credential stuffing where most people
don't use unique passwords for websites
and as a result if they get your
username and password they can try it on
every single site that they want to gain
access to and have a fair success rate
of gaining access
you can even go as far as using a
separate email account and maybe using
aliases
but that's a way that advanced and as
long as you're using a strong password
and you're not at really high risk
maybe not necessary
final tip is to
change your password after a breakup
your email password is particularly
important because it can be used to
reset
all of your accounts
on gmail you can also do a security and
a privacy checkup and you can actually
see what devices are logged into your
account and you can kick out stuff that
you don't want access anymore
and there's also a website called have i
been pwned and you can actually check
whether your credentials
have already been compromised
so password managers are great but have
you tried two-factor authentication
there are three varieties of this
text message
is the most popular and weakest
[Music]
if your choice is text message or
nothing use text message but there are
two vulnerabilities that you really need
to know about
for highly
at-risk and targeted individuals there
is an ss7 vulnerability
and basically text messages are just
super insecure
they are transmitted entirely
unencrypted and a powerful adversary can
just pluck these out from the cell
network
and they've got your code
you wouldn't even know what's happened
there is a lower attack but maybe even
scarier attack which is sim swapping
where either by colluding with an
insider at a cell company or
by social engineering the company
they can actually have your phone number
switch to a sim card that they control
and a phone that they control and have
uh
just take control of your number and
then your two factor codes will be sent
to their phone
you will at least know that this has
happened but unfortunately it's because
your phone will stop working so
not great
so a stronger form is time-based
one-time password where there is no
interaction with anything else it is
stored either on an app on your phone
or on some kind of hardware token
an example of the hardware token is the
rsa secure id which is actually used in
conjunction with a pin
and is really really popular at
financial institutions
but ultimately no more secure than an
app on the phone because it's all
vulnerable to a man in the browser
attack
basically if you have malware on your
computer particularly something that's
in your browser you've got a problem
we've got u2f
is
another form of two-factor
authentication things like yuba keys it
uses some clever crypto and a usb device
which acts as a keyboard
and
provides a really strong form of
two-factor authentication
but
uh it's not very well supported uh over
the over the different websites so only
maybe half of your accounts will
actually support this
so security questions offer
approximately no protection from
somebody who knows you so instead of
filling in accurate information
use
long nonsensical strings
and store them in your password manager
now these should also be unique for
every account
the google advanced protection program
is also available for people who
are at particular risk highly targeted
individuals it provides a whole bunch of
extra protection
google will make it
way more difficult to hack into your
account and
provide enhanced protection from
phishing they'll provide some protection
from harmful downloads by forcing you to
get stuff from
the official app store or play store
and
there's a couple of drawbacks so
you have to use google's apps for your
mail and you have to use u2f two-factor
authentication so you need to either buy
their titan key or yubikey
[Music]
and it is a little bit more easy to lock
yourself out of your account but that is
also kind of the point
so how do we browse the internet
anonymously well let's start with some
myth busting it's not vpns
most vpns are terrible and they have two
primary use cases
one of them is evading geoblocking by
which i mean getting better netflix
and the other one is torrenting all the
things without getting all the emails
from the torrent trolls telling you that
you're going to jail
tor is the best we've got for actually
browsing the internet anonymously
tor works by proxying your connection
through three different computers or
nodes the first one knows who you are
but not where you're going the last one
knows where you're going but not who you
are and the middle one knows who the
first and last node are
there's a couple of vulnerabilities to
tor so
there's a problem with
centralization if all the nodes belong
to the same entity they know everything
if they collude with one another they
know everything
and there are some clever attacks that
use confirmation or correlation
so if they suspect that you are the one
visiting a particular website at a
certain time they can do some traffic
analysis and confirm that
uh private search engines like
duckduckgo are great you can keep your
search history out of the likes of
google
but they only provide any protection to
you while you're searching for stuff
and as soon as you actually go to a
website
you have no anonymity at all
you're also entrusting all of your
privacy to one entity who ultimately
knows who you are
there's a few ways that you can use tor
first of all the official sanctioned tor
browser which is based on firefox and
available for desktop and android
there is an ios version called onion
browser
but because ios mandates the use of
webkit
this may be a whole bunch leakier than
the official tour browser so it's not
it's not official
now brave is another unofficial version
and this is really really useful for
casual use
because again it may be leakier than the
official tor browser
but being chromium-based it makes your
experience on the internet a whole lot
better
it makes using tor super easy because
you can just click the button that says
open a new private browser window with
tor
and
even if you don't use brave with tor
there's a bunch of fingerprinting
protection and privacy protections that
are built in
that can
help to give you privacy even when
you're not
disassociating your ip address
tails is for the
more hardcore tour users
it's a linux based
live system that you've talked about
earlier
and it forces all of your internet
traffic to go through tor and it
mandates that with iptables rules or
firewall rules
to avoid
any kind of leaks of your ip address
if
for example you're opening a file
outside of your browser
that then interacts with the internet
that connection will still be made over
tour
tails will also
uh wipe all evidence of what you did
off your
uh
yeah during the session that you were
using tails it will
wipe all of the memory and there will be
approximately no evidence of anything
that you did on your computer while you
were using tails
so we talked about using tor as a client
but you can also use tor as a server to
anonymously publish
we're talking about hidden services or
onion addresses so in the same way a
client builds a
circuit through three nodes to the
internet a server can build the same
circuit
uh and then a tor compatible client can
connect to that server and it's done
entirely end to end encrypted
so wiggle is a service which
uses a procedure called wardriving
to map the location of
wi-fi access points
it will capture the ssid so this is a
kind of friendly name for your wi-fi
it will also capture the mac address or
bss id
and
you can also use date ranges to filter
the results
so again the example of having to
relocate to australia
if
somebody then war drives past your new
location and an adversary who knows
what ssid
what friendly name you like to call your
wi-fi and that's fairly unique if they
see that cropping up on the gold coast
then your location is going to be owned
it's also possible that if they know
which wi-fi access point you had
like to the point of actually knowing
what its mac address was they can then
filter for that mac address and see it
popping up in your new location
so
if your wi-fi access point may be
compromised in this way throw it away
and buy a new one at your new location
there's also an issue with phones being
used as
hotspots i'm not aware of any way that
you can spoof the mac address on this so
they could actually map
your movements if you use your phone as
a hotspot a lot for example at your
favorite cafe and pub
they might somebody might actually be
able to map out what locations you like
to visit
you can opt out of
being in wiggle but other services do
this too like google and microsoft so
you end up having to opt out of a lot of
different services and
this can just draw attention to yourself
because you end up with an ssid that's
like got various different ways of
saying opt out
so your clients can be tracked in a
similar way using war driving now the
software kismet can actually find
clients and even knows which access
point they're connected to
so windows and ios make it really easy
for you to spoof your mac address
android and mac os and linux do not make
this easy
you have to use third-party software or
terminal commands
but yeah where you can just
toggle this on i'd recommend everybody
does this
so for the truly paranoid
your wi-fi and bluetooth are basically
beaconing out all the time
and
shops airports
gyms and many other
areas will have beacons which track your
movements
they kind of want to know how you're
using their space if they're a shop they
even want to know how you're shopping
there's not much you can do about this
other than actually turning off those
radios
and in a world where we're all using
bluetooth headphones and fitness
trackers
it's not a practical solution for
everyone
but if your threat model
has this problem then you should
you should disable those radios
especially when you're not using them
full disk encryption can be used to
protect your data at rest
you'll want to do this because if
somebody gets access to your laptop
in various ways either they've stolen it
or they have
access to it
for a period of time and maybe you're
passing through airport security
you don't necessarily want them to be
able to just boot up your laptop and see
your stuff or remove your hard drive and
tamper with your device
so the built-in encryption in windows
bitlocker or mac os
file vault or linux lux is absolutely
good enough and
i'd recommend that you just turn that on
but
there's also some third-party software
called veracrypt
my main recommendation for this is that
if you have multiple different devices
and you want to encrypt usb drives then
veracrypt will allow you to decrypt
those usb drives on all of your devices
and protecting your communications can
be done
using
various methods the old way of doing
this is email encryption using pgp or
gpg this is still really useful today
for verification of software
and if you are somebody who makes
security disclosures to
websites of zero-day vulnerabilities
that you've discovered
you really do need to learn how this
works
but it's really hard and
you'll probably mess it up at some point
it makes searching your emails really
difficult
and
uh is just generally
uh yeah really hard so
for those of us who are not security
researchers uh dropping zero days to our
vendors
signal and whatsapp provide the same
strong encryption but make it really
easy to use
through
just a phone app
whatsapp is owned by facebook so even
though they can't look at the content of
your messages they can still
see who's talking to who how often they
talk when they talk
so they can still profile you pretty
effectively that way
another disadvantage is that you have to
share your mobile number and we talked
about sim swapping earlier and
we really don't want to share our phone
number with people we don't trust
it's great for friends and family but
for strangers that you're meeting for
the first time
social media
discord might be a much better
alternative
and
obviously there is a lot of personal
information on those sites too so it's a
personal choice which one you want to
share
but social media offers a really good
protection because you can really easily
block people
and
yeah you don't have to give your phone
number out and
you can
okay those are the good things bad
things
uh it's not end to end encrypted and
snapchat allegedly had their employee
employees
look at their users personal information
including phone numbers and also
look at the snaps or photos of their
users as well
there's a lot of different privacy
settings on your social medias
[Music]
you can control who has access to your
profile so you can make your profile
entirely private and accessible only to
your friends if that's something you
want to do
you can also control who's tagging you
in photos
you can block a piece of accounts
you can control who has access to dms
which is probably a good idea
and you can limit the amount of location
information that the social media gives
up because social media loves to share
your location but you might not
social media also loves to track you
outside of their social media site
you'll see they have their feelers all
over the place with their like buttons
and all that
so
you can to a certain extent limit that
with your social media settings
and you can just go ahead and request
what data they have on you and go
through it to see
iot is becoming really popular and
there's a lot of different types that
we're probably using ourselves
smart assistants are a good example
these
the main risks with these are that
they'll quite happily reveal your full
location so if you ask what's my
location to your echo device they will
they will tell you
including your flat number
so if you're on a video call or a voice
call with someone new you might want to
either mute your echo device or wear
headphones on the call so that they
can't just
ask for your location
they can also unlock your doors if you
use them in conjunction with smart locks
so if your flat isn't totally soundproof
like mine they could just yell from the
hallway and let themselves in
and
even if your house is quite soundproof
they could commandeer some other bit of
iot in your house that has a speaker and
then speak to your smart speaker to let
them in
so
yeah
a lot of risks if you have those
along with other devices
uh smart thermostats
sure nobody wants to come back to a cold
house or a hot house uh but if you
uh if you
have somebody leave your property that
no longer needs access to the smart
thermostat you probably want to get rid
of their access to that smart thermostat
pretty quickly because people have
abused access to smart thermostats to
make a residence in the house
uncomfortably
hot or cold
video doorbells are also really useful
as well as other security cameras
you can catch stalkers people who are
walking past your house just a little
bit too often or looking through windows
but again
when somebody leaves the household they
should lose their access to that video
doorbell very quickly
and if these things get hacked
you've got the problem that the hacker
will then be aware of your comings and
goings
and
also if you have a cloud-based service
that the the cloud
who's storing all of the video
will also be able to see your comings
and goings
a lot of us are wearing fitness trackers
they capture huge amounts of data which
is really useful for tracking your
fitness but you really don't want other
people to have access to that data
because it's really revealing
not going to talk anymore about fitness
trackers because jason's going to talk
on that later on so if you're interested
you can catch that
one big defense with iot is to segment
your network better
so you can use a tool like pfsense which
is a router
and vlans on a
managed switch to
have a separate network for your iot
devices to the rest of your network
apple air tags
are a small inexpensive
easily concealed and highly accurate
tracking devices
they use the
find my network uh same as your iphone
their use cases are supposed to be
finding your keys or keeping track of
your luggage but unfortunately they've
also been used to steal cars and stalk
people
so apple's worked quite hard to on
mitigations for this
uh they have
built-in uh speaker
which will sound after
it was originally three days which is a
very long time i believe now it's
between eight and twelve hours if it's
not been in contact with the device that
it's registered with this alarm should
sound but
devices have been modified to remove
that speaker
so some alternatives to tracking these
things is that if you have an iphone
you will actually get a notification
that uh airtag has been found moving
with you if you use android you need a
third-party app uh called tracker detect
and if you don't have a smartphone your
sol
airpods
have basically the same problem they're
small and you can track them using find
buy
mobile malware
this can be commodity malware like
stalkerware this is malware that has
access to your camera your microphone
and gps location
the commodity variety is not
particularly subtle
government malware does basically the
same things but much more subtly you
might not even know it's been installed
it might use a zero-click vulnerability
to get itself onto your phone
malicious mobile device management is a
different type of mobile malware
and this is primarily installed using
social engineering
mobile device management is a legitimate
thing used by businesses and schools to
manage their devices
but if you have a personal device you
really really don't want to give
somebody the ability to manage it for
you
so a few tips you can avoid third-party
app stores because they're loaded with
malware
you can delete unknown apps on your
phone
and if you have an app on your phone
which you really don't want to delete
but
it's kind of got excessive permissions
so whether that's a calculator that's
got your location camera and mic
you can just you know get rid of
all of those permissions
and finally just generally good advice
keep your os and apps up to date
if you are a highly targeted individual
like a journalist blowing the whistle on
bad things or reporting on bad
governments
you might find yourself the victim of
this government level malware
and citizen lab can help you out
they track human rights threats and
they'll analyze the malware that's been
sent to journalists who have been
targeted
and help them to recover from the
situation
these guys are absolutely not for
commodity malware so you know don't
bother these guys unless you really need
it
so i've got a bit of further information
i'll be making these slides available
after the talk
um but we'll run through these quickly
follow eva on twitter she's got loads of
good stuff
if you are
somebody who programs things who makes
things
look through ibm's
principles to combat domestic abuse so
that you can avoid some of the security
fails or security engineering fails that
we've discussed in this talk
there's a manual for
locking your iphone down where personal
safety is an issue
and
i've also added apple's update uh on
their air tags that's a press release of
the things that they did to the air tags
to make them less creepy
if you're interested in surveillance
self-defense eff has a whole site on
this
and
uh google also has a safety page which
is there for you to do your security
checks
uh if you're interested in
whistleblowing i've got
some really interesting new research
from cambridge
and naomi wu's security camera advice
and boom
so
make sure you educate your friends and
family on security and privacy
because if you become too difficult to
target they may be targeted in order to
get to you
and my mom's mastered pretty much
everything in this talk so you really
can't teach this to anyone
and uh yeah thanks very much for
listening and stay safe out there