so a couple of things before i start my
name's adrian cottrell and i the cio at
the institute of cancer research um if i
could ask them to give me a five-minute
warning so i stayed at time i'd be
looking out for the signal and the
second thing just to let people know in
terms of the prize for the best tweet
i've given up twitter for lent so it's
not going to be me the field is open
there
um i'd like to do uh
four things today first of all i'd like
to tell you a little bit about what the
institute of cancer research is
i'd like to talk to you about the
threats cyber presents to us and you can
probably guess that from um you know the
talks been given so far
um i'd like to tell you about the
journey my organization has been on and
lastly i'll throw out a challenge to you
all in the room about the role you can
play to help research organizations like
my own
so first of all the ico or the institute
of cancer research um what is it well if
you if you get cancer and you're in
london the the likelihood is you'll be
directed to the rural mars and hospital
and about 70 years ago um it was agreed
that the research part of the hospital
should be spun off to what is the icr
the institute of cancer research so in
the morning we have some of the best
people you know in in their field
telling life and death decisions to
patients and then they have a research
team across the bridge in the afternoon
and that's where we have
about 1500 um
scientists uh staff and students working
at the institute
it's a non-profit organization but quite
quite a few of these research
organizations that operate in this way
and you can imagine in the current
climate with the way fundraising and
things have gone in the last couple of
years it is grim out there actually for
all of these sort of sorts of research
institutions
um but about the ico it's it's what we
call the comprehensive uh cancer center
this is about going from the the bench
the research you know
increasingly doing less in the test tube
and more on in silica but but also going
all the way through to the the patient
at the bedside
and if you look at the papers and
publications and citations
globally the icr comes third fourth
globally so we're kind of a hidden
secret there the big american
institutions with huge budgets the ones
that stand in front of us
um just say then that we are um
reading my writing yeah we're a global
organization so we have
staff and students from over 50
countries and we're collaborating with
people all around the world one thing
you will find is oncologists kind of
different from other researchers they
are literally dealing with life and
death decisions almost every minute of
every day and they're more likely to
give you their home number but approach
you with research because they're
literally trying to save lives and it it
becomes personal um and so the the fight
for discoveries is a global effort
across the board
and in terms of the uk about 50 of the
practicing oncologists in the uk will
have done a post-doc or a masters in the
icr so it's like the finishing school
for oncologists
a couple of achievements that we've done
um the icr were the first organization
to publish about the
linkage between
cancer and cigarette smoking we were the
first organization to say that dna
damage was a root cause of cancer
and we also have um let me pick out a
couple we were the first organization to
pick out the braca gene therapy which is
crucial to towards all the therapies
that gone towards breast cancer
we are doing amazing amazing stuff
around radiotherapy at the moment and
sadly most of you will know this but if
you get cancer it's surgery it's chemo
and radiotherapy and the the the
advances in technology in recent years
has really pushed radiotherapy to the
fore and i'll give you a couple of
examples in a moment and um finally uh
in terms of prosecute prostate cancer
and we really have come up with some of
some of the best drugs in the market and
licensed those through j and others and
that's having great impact
so i just
advanced the slide yeah so let me just
say about you know the the number this
the story and that's about
technology evolution clearly gives
better outcomes from cancer patients so
if you look on the on the x-axis you see
technology advances over the last 20-30
years on the y-axis you see the
collaboration and it wasn't that long
ago clinical trials and so on they're
all written down in paper forms you know
and it was all very what can you do in
its paper barely anyone's reading the
paper that someone wrote the day before
but as things got
digitalized we got systems that were
bespoke within organizations those
solutions started to get bit more
networked so you could share systems
share data
in the last five ten years huge amounts
of data so in my previous role i was
in charge of clinical trials and
development within gsk and i remember
being faced five years ago with this
challenge about how do we store these
medical images they're just so big these
files where do you they're just off the
scale compared to where we were before
where i am now at the institute it's
videos of these things because cancer
doesn't just sit there waiting to be
taken it moves around and if you kind of
do radiotherapy you've got to know where
it is so so actually it's a very dynamic
field with huge data volumes being
generated
and then finally you know what we're
seeing is and i'll show you a few
examples in a moment through the use of
aim and machine learning we were able to
really really improve the outcomes for
patients
but unfortunately at all this time with
all this fantastic technology and all
this big global collaboration
cyber risk is just a nightmare and this
is this is really putting the brakes on
a lot of what we do i i am constantly
having to tell my scientists who just
want to get on with things you've got to
take care you know we've heard ronan and
others earlier on today about one
careless email and the whole institute
could be brought down and it's really
hard to tell people who are trying to
save lives they've got to be a bit more
careful it's really difficult but that's
that's the role i have to play
so let me give you a couple of examples
about some of the breakthroughs that
we're doing and this hopefully some
encouragement for for all of us as we go
through
you will probably know that if you get
breast cancer or lung cancer obviously
the origin of it is quite well known but
actually it can move to other parts of
the body and metastasize in different
ways and so you've got to look for it
everywhere it is and a key aid to this
in radiotherapy is full body mri
where you look at the whole body and you
can see all the sights of the infection
you can see that rotating body will show
you that that case where the cancer is
showing up
and um
what we're finding now through ai is you
used to have to spend about half an hour
in the mri machine to get enough images
to do the full body we can now get that
down to five minutes when you think this
is somebody that's a patient probably in
chronic pain that's supposed to stay
still
that is actually a big move forward and
we're going to reduce that all the time
we're also doing work to make other
equipment ct scans which are much more
available try to use ai to simulate an
mri full body scan from a ct scan so
this is really clever stuff and what's
really fantastic about this is if you
get somebody currently who may be
diagnosed with cancer maybe given told
they've got three months six months nine
months to live
all you know conventional therapies out
of the way they're given experimental
treatment perhaps in a clinical trial
and normally what would happen is you'd
have to give them the medicine and you
every day counts right you give them the
medicine for six weeks eight weeks to
see how they are and then you have to
monitor how are you feeling to see how
it goes
with full body mri we can track it
straight away and we can know that as we
get data after two weeks three weeks you
should start to see signs of this this
having an effect and if it's not let's
get you off that and get you on
something else because they just don't
have the time so you can see this is
fantastic research that we're doing here
so yeah that's the thing about it going
down to five minutes
another thing i want to talk to you
about two quick other things um to
mention too one is uh the traditional
way of
if someone has cancer is you have a
biopsy and the way in which biopsy
happens then is take the biopsy you
slice it down you put it on a slide you
stay in it and then you look to see
whether there are cancerous cells in the
in the on the slide and um increasingly
there is a shortage of pathologists to
do this work but this is a massive
opportunity as you can imagine for ml
and ai so as we build this global bank
these biobanks of samples what you can
do is take the sample run it through and
within minutes find out this is
definitely not cancer this is definitely
cancer this might be cancer so then you
train your machine learning to be better
at that and then you refer them to a
specialist so that that gives much
quicker diagnosis and in the very same
way with cyber threats early detection
is really important to have good
outcomes
and we can add to that because with the
the again sharing of data around best
therapies we can look at the genotype
and phenotype of the individual and say
yes you've got this sort of cancer and
for you for you these are the best
therapies for you based on global
information so we're going away from the
the knowledge of one
oncologist to a patient to harvesting
the information from the whole world and
i think you can appreciate that is a
very powerful way to proceed
and the final thing to say on this one
is individually we've got great
radiologists we've got great
pathologists we've got great uh people
looking at the genetics side of things
and at the moment when people get
together they have a meeting and people
cut and paste from powerpoint to try and
say here's what we're seeing and it's
static what we're going to do you can
imagine is make this integrated
diagnostic so you've got real-time way
of looking at the data to give much
better outcomes for the patients
so let me just quickly in the last five
minutes i have talked a little bit about
the journey because this is probably
stuff that you will know but when i
started out on this journey at the icr i
had quite a lot of resistance you know
it hasn't happened here why are you
doing to this to me we're trying to help
patients by trying to describe this as
the the balloon that's about to burst
you know and when it does it's a bang
and life is different i had at gsk a a
really horrible cyber incident
then i tell people offline about that
and once you've been through one of
those you you never forget it because
after it happens everyone says well why
didn't you tell us if we'd have known
that well we can spend any money you
know we'd have spent any money then you
know if we'd have known but it's too
late the balloon is burst
so so what did we do um the first thing
i had to do is get a kind of a sense
check of where we were in terms of our
cyber maturity um i engaged accenture to
do that i thought external credibility
might help me there we identified our
top 10 risks you could probably guess
what some of them were we sort of knew
but again we wanted to make sure people
went on the journey we identified
recommendations to address those risks
um and we laid out sort of a costing
plan to make it happen
um we also uh
we got approval for the investment and
what we did realize of course is this
there's an insider threat which is key
part to this but also we needed to
introduce greater technology and we made
a conscious decision just
coming back to the previous speaker to
go with an mmsp model rather than try to
hire in and actually for us that was the
best decision because we also did agree
to augment our internal team but
recruitment is really hard and we don't
pay you know the same rates as industry
so i think the mmsp model actually works
for institutions like us
um and what we also then did then was um
the we have pointed a see so we had
somebody actually who was in role but as
we made the role the team bigger we put
that in place
we went after the insider threat really
hard right from the get-go and as ronan
and others mentioned this was all going
on during the pandemic
um we looked at all our policies we went
right after our acceptable use policy
and did a big launch campaign because it
was ten years out of date and people
were doing all sorts of things they
really shouldn't um we then run a
campaign of cyber hygiene we called it
and we said this is not just about when
you're at work it's about in your own
private life too it's about phishing and
being aware of what goes on there it's
about using strong passwords and what to
look out for and initially we had very
low attendance but um we had a town hall
meeting and i kind of scared the bejesus
out of them and we had everyone turn up
and those have been very successful
since
and we really did fish a ramp up our
fishing campaign um to the point where
our stats are looking pretty good now i
mean you only need one but they're
looking very good compared to the sector
and now we're looking at the next stage
about you know what is the impact if you
constantly fail some of these who are
the worst offenders what are the
implications you put the organization at
risk you know when someone was lighting
matches you'd do something about it so
we're thinking about that and of course
we um
brought on um
made our mmsp selection
um msp selection was smart tech through
a rfi process and we've been working
over the last year on that that was
formally launched just about a year ago
we have the 24 7 monitoring which gives
us comfort um we established the log
transfer i think about 90 of our log
files are now out there and being
managed the scene we set our
vulnerability management and we're we're
halfway through our pam implementation
at the same time
i think it's fair to say that when you
if you're going on this journey there's
there's pain first so there's the
ignorant incompetence once you know what
you've got then you've got to fix it so
i think we're sort of on our way through
that part of the journey but we've seen
some pretty good inroads on a number of
fronts now
and then finally in terms of what we do
it's about monitoring and improving and
so you know um it was great help from um
smart tech that we got early warnings
around solarwinds and log4j we have
weekly tactical meetings about what we
should do we have quarterly reviews and
we get the forecasting that helps us
engage with our senior organization so
in the last 20 seconds or so that i have
and i see the clock it's kept me in good
time let me just say a little thing to
you all probably all of you have been
where i've been where you've been at a
funeral or you've heard some terrible
news about somebody who has got an
ailment and you just say to yourself if
there's only something i could do i feel
so useless we've probably all been there
let me tell you two things there are two
things you can do if you're working in
cyber and looking at solutions
institutions like mine really need all
the stuff that you're doing it and i
would just ask if you can do it at a
price we can afford because pockets are
small
and if you can't do that
donate to the charity that means
something to you those charities or the
research organizations excuse me they
are really struggling out there so
whether it's icr or somewhere else they
need your help