good morning everybody um we're going to
go through a little bit of a
law enforcement working with industry
type
startup we'll talk a little bit about
the ncis mission and as we go through
this we're going to talk a little bit
about agility
as it hand works hand in hand with the
innovation
we're going to talk about integration a
lot
because the whole reason why any of us
have jobs is to make sure that we're
sharing the information that we
have within our organizations but at the
same time protecting those organizations
from bad guys and i'll just use that
term i won't mention any countries or
any entities and then last but not least
we have to worry about the impact what
it means at the end of the day
and for ncis our mission is relatively i
guess i need to use the clicker here our
mission is pretty simple
we protect the navy and the marine corps
many of you have probably seen the tv
show which they do in about an hour and
it's really really simple
not so not so much
we protect the navy and the marine corps
and contractors and academia
and industry from bad guys
in
fighting wars and maintaining that
strategic advantage associated with the
navy marine corps mission
so i just said that
so prevent protect reduce
prevent secrets
uh
and terrorism protect secrets and reduce
crime so that i said that too so sorry
all right so let me talk a little bit
about how we do
the previous things and then we'll keep
we'll get into
his three c's which
are the underpinning of how we work
you know for years and years and years
all of our countries have been in
competition with each other to maintain
that strategic advantage
and in many instances maintaining that
strategic advantage kind of gets lost in
the sauce
as you're
signing up signing up a new contract
or developing a new technology or making
sure that that technology is delivered
uncompromised to ultimately
one of our governments or one of our
organizations and if a compromise occurs
at any place
in those early stages
what happens
it's potentially unreliable
the security that's associated with it
may have some limitations
and last but not least
you're not giving that
bill payer what they paid for ultimately
when it comes to that piece of gear
and unfortunately
the checks and balances we're talking
nearly a million people for the navy and
the marine corps alone
but if you wrap into
that construct
all of our organizations
private sector public sector
industry when it comes to academia
industry when it comes to research and
development technology you've got
millions and millions and millions of
people working those issues
and with those millions of people come
all the vulnerabilities and the risks
associated with them
so we have to make sure that we're
connecting and we're integrating
some of the good news stories that
you've heard earlier
and the results of some of the bad news
stories that you heard earlier as well
and unfortunately
we don't have a lot of time on our hands
because the next crisis is already in
the works right now
you know we we talked a little bit about
ukraine earlier we talked a little bit
about the pandemic and the effects of it
but there is another crisis right around
the corner
and our workforces have to be ready for
that crisis
and for the most part
it could come from almost anywhere
and as was mentioned earlier it's
extremely profitable for the bad guys
to kind of work within our
environments
to
work against us
and in many instances people are
compromising things
unwittingly
and in rare occasions where lake and i
come into place from a law enforcement
standpoint where people are going to go
to jail
go to prison for a long time
people are doing it intentionally
or they're feigning ignorance in terms
of
some technological loophole
or some loophole in policy or procedure
or some loophole in terms of a company's
standards right and that's where
it's important for all of us
to understand the benefits of that
integration
sharing information sharing threat
information
sharing vulnerabilities
and
when it comes to an example we'll talk
about a little bit early later
a lot of it boils down to are you
willing to raise your hand and say that
you've been compromised
are you willing to share that
information with law enforcement or
counterintelligence organizations
regardless of the country
to make sure it doesn't happen again
and make sure that that particular
device or or military platform that's
supposed to be delivered uncompromised
works during
an act of uh conflict around the world
so i'll turn it over to lake
hi everybody uh kik suthar i'm a special
agent um with ncis but i'm also the cio
and it's kind of weird because i get to
do a little bit of a uh
giving back to the organization when it
comes technology but i just wanted to
share something with you real quick um
we're gonna i'm gonna get into the three
c's but i'm gonna
go fairly quickly on how an attack so
i'm an attacker i'm gonna go in i send
my uh spearfishing email it has some
type of a link to uh site link gets
downloaded gets about 500 people you
download the um the actual bash code
bash codes go on your computer it tries
to execute it the execution sometimes
occurs it doesn't depends on what your
site security is depends on where
location of the
environment is and then all of a sudden
it does work the person gets compromised
you get on the system you get access to
a little bit of something you try to
create another account because you want
to look like you're alive and a real
person so you create a real account and
then now you're trying to move lateral
so you move lateral and you get into
a more of a different type of system
you're going to administrative accounts
here so now you want to get again
elevating privilege get into
administrative accounts and now i am
going to look at
how do i get to the information so i'm
going to get to the database so i'm
going to get to the database because
that's where the data is that is
the gold
i elevate i get lateral i find another
account i compromised it cleaned up my
tracks and now we're at six months in
and nobody knows any better i get to the
data center and guess what it's
as good as i want it to be
i look at it
and i'm going to decide what i'm going
to do with it well first thing i'm
probably going to do is manipulate it
change it up well actually i'm going to
expel everything i can manipulate it and
then
encrypt it
light a match throw it on it
and catch it on fire
so
let's go toward the cyber security side
as the cio
i got the junior admin so what's going
to happen on the company side or the
organization side they're going to look
at it and they're going to be like oh
i see something over there what is that
it's a light
so the junior admin might say it's a
light and then you got a senior person
saying
no
that's a freaking
dumpster fire that's coming toward us
and everybody knows about dumpster fires
because we all have them if you're in
i.t
everybody has them don't raise your
hands i can see the smiles and um
so me as a cio i don't call it a
dumpster fire i don't call it fires i
just call it unplanned work
and that's where the ceo or the
organizational leader is going to come
in and they look at that and they'll be
like i have no idea what that is
most of you know that because they don't
know what it is
you can explain it to them you can take
out crayons you can take a construction
paper you can explain how this is going
to impact everybody but they still don't
see the dumpster and they don't know
what the fire means just yet so what i
did was i looked at the three c's
capability capacity and control
fairly quickly capability is what is
your people capable of doing and you
have to explain this in a very
high level
do you have the capable people in your
organization to do the job do you have
the capable equipment do you have the
capable software do you have that in
your you might good
talk about capacity
do you have all those people have enough
time to do everything that they need to
do you got the dumpster fire that's
coming towards you because you know the
company is about to get
had the information get out everywhere
so what do you do
you have the capabilities they're
already patching they're already doing
vulnerabilities they're fixing
somebody's computer you've got a leader
over here who's mad his email doesn't
work you've got customers yelling so
do you have that now the next one is
control
control is a very interesting one
because it's again data
i'm gonna go into three again three
other
uh issues here three
which is
your data
and we talk about supply chain everybody
knows about supply chain everybody knows
where your information
kinda is
uh but you know how to make the widget
that's what your company does
and there's a supply chain for that you
get all these pieces there's a string
that comes about and it creates your
widget
that's the first supply chain the second
supply chain we already heard about it
is a cyber security side
you know where your stuff is coming from
have you vetted it have you looked into
it
so that's number two number three is the
new
one your data does not stay with you
anymore
your data is on the cloud whatever that
means
so if it's on the cloud
are you paying attention to where their
stuff is coming from where their routers
their systems
probably not
so that's something that i like to say
about
the supply chain it's very important
there's a fourth one that just came out
last about two years ago
it's from the pandemic
it's people who want to do things faster
and they want to do it from home so
where they can put that stuff
in their house
because it's easy
if you don't have a virtual desktop then
guess what you're going to give them a
computer go home and hopefully they
don't lose it oh and hopefully you're
encrypting it
i don't know but
and if they put it on their home
computer the information's gone so where
do you go where is where are these
people going towards they're going to go
to the
underbelly
so these two documents everybody knows
about the hsc and um really focusing on
something i read in hsc it's 157 pages
if you haven't read it
157 pages
and um
there was one comment in there they have
about
350 people
working on
i believe about 140 000 people 70 000
devices
that goes to a capacity and capability
thing they probably were very capable
but are they did they have capacity they
have control
good document this other one
is from the department of navy
it's interesting because this one was
presented to congress it was for the
secretary of navy to say that you have a
problem you have a culture problem when
it comes to all information
um very good one it talks about
resources because i helped write that
actually i wrote the resource section on
that one next slide
read these documents so i'm going to get
into i'm not going to get into the whole
uh on the on the
left side or your right side
what i've created i was the special
agent in charge for all cyber
investigations and operations within
ncis so i created something that was
very simple
because remember we talked about that
person in a suit the ceo has to be very
simple
it has to be simple so i called it eva
it's a term
knowing that
you're going to have the vulnerabilities
no matter what happens it's irrelevant
what is going on today because all of
this stuff has a commonality
you're always going to go back to eva
you're going to have a vulnerability
that comes out you're going to have an
exploit that comes out and then you're
going to have a path for the bad people
to come in and take it
and we see that
these are always
going to be there could be an insider
and that's what we focus on when it
comes to uh
criminal acts
so
i mentioned earlier
a good way for a problem a dumpster fire
to evolve in a bad way
so let's go with the bad way first
if if your information has been
compromised and it doesn't matter where
you are you could be at a university
that's developing the next generation
weapon
you could be
at a company that's making underwater
technology
or
air platforms
you could just be in office
in a military organization anywhere in
the world
but once you discover
that you have an issue you have a
problem you have a compromise or a next
fill
what do you do do you call anybody
yeah you're going to call your security
folks i hope
and what are your security folks going
to do
they're going to make recommendations
they're going to help you get back up to
running speed
they're going to
help you remediate your your network and
identify where the bad guys got in
but are you going to notify law
enforcement
are you going to notify
intelligence organizations if you need
to
and to what end
what is your network set up like you
have proprietary stuff on the same
uh location as your hr information i
hope not but a lot of companies do
and and to what end to what end of the
notifications occur
and back in the early 2000s we had
several
investigations
and operations subsequent operations
where we had companies that
weren't notifying
law enforcement and counterintelligence
about their compromises
and to this day we're still suffering
the effects of it
conversely
good example
your company is
has an issue
you have an x-fill
you know you have something like the
colonial pipeline that was mentioned
earlier
who do you notify
i would say notify everybody
does the time in
position you've been with your company
two years or 20 years or 40 years does
that matter is it a generational thing
no but it goes back to a comment that
was mentioned earlier in terms of trust
in some ways you trust no one
but in other ways you have to trust
everybody when it comes to
that vulnerability in your network your
system your organization because if
you've been hit other people probably
have been hit as well
and that collective
connection
has to occur
for everything to get healthy and for
you to be ready as i mentioned earlier
for that next event
that next compromise
and there are a lot of different ways i
won't go through the whole long laundry
list of them
where you can connect
but
you know that that old adage you know
you probably need to have that
relationship before the event occurs
range true every time
if you don't know who
within government or who within
eight different sectors you're supposed
to contact when you have a major event
occur
now is probably the time to start
thinking about it
you have to have those connections in
place early
so that you can push and pull
information
maybe it's something that's going to
happen over 48 72 hours
the day it happens is not the day to
start making those phone calls and
making those connections
it's better to have those things
established well in place before the
events
it was mentioned earlier about
legislation and and rules and
regulations
that has to happen way before an event
occurs
we learned two three five years ago with
a bunch of different events that you all
know
that
responding
and going to congress if you're in the
united states or
your equivalent
during the event is probably not the
time to get things tightened up
you should probably work on that well in
advance
and i know a lot of groups out there are
doing that
but you have to become one of be part of
one of those groups
and last but not least
as the bad guys get more
aggressive
we need to be aggressive
we need to be just as aggressive as they
are when it comes to
getting ready for that next event
and that being aggressive
works hand in hand with innovation
and integration
all of those things happen have to
happen at the same time for you to be
effective
and how many people love winning over
the bad guy right that's everybody
everybody in this room
is employed to do that
but again we only need to make a couple
of mistakes for our
our organizations or our networks to be
compromised
they they've got
tens of thousands of hundreds and
millions of events where they're trying
to get into our systems and get our
information
so on that note i just want to make sure
that that connection piece
is ingrained in every single one of you
and everybody can do it at any level
so one of the things that and i put this
here
besides it's a pretty cool slide um
what we do in ncis we want to make sure
that
goes out
and hits the target
we don't want
when the pushing when the button is
pushed
we don't want clown music to occur
and that's that's key there and you can
substitute whatever you think your
company does and how you push it or your
organization does you want to make sure
that that goes out and i'm going to tell
you when you make that phone call to law
enforcement and you say this is the
first time i'm telling you about
something you're not it's not going to
be a friendly conversation
but please call ahead make that
relationship make that connection you do
that over here already you can start
with small stuff
it can be an ip address domain you know
snort yara alert whatever you want to
decide do you already do it amongst
yourselves
we're good the law is broken
somebody came in took your stuff and
left it's the same thing when somebody
comes in takes your money at your that
was put underneath your uh couch
then removed it to the bank
they went to the bank and took it now
you the money's somewhere in the cloud
now they're going after that it's the
same thing with your data
it's a crime
and they're winning
so connect uh real quick i'm gonna go
this i just wanted to put this up here
which is the pcss pcss is a program that
is in uh germany garmish i'm uh alum
from them uh they get everybody from all
the countries usually about 40 countries
to come together and it's a month long
and garmish right between thanksgiving
christmas great program i'll look into
it next week
this is something i usually give to
company so when i'm knocking on
somebody's door and i'm talking to them
it's not good news
i don't come in and say hey i'm from
ncis hi it doesn't work like that i'm
here to tell you something that's bad is
going on but i'll leave you something
good
and this is their top 10 from nsa
this is what you can do and you can take
a look at it and decide where you want
to
go with it i'm not going to go through
all of them because i know uh the time's
up here but
i really want you to understand to
connect
because they are connecting
and it's not we're not going to be on
the winning side if we don't team of one
is a team of none