foreign
we were debating yesterday after after
seeing all the cool graphics uh the
graphic recordings how long we need to
stay on this slide in order for the
butterfly to appear there
uh so I'll try to take as much time as
possible
um so first of all it's not a butterfly
it's a moss and more specifically a luna
moth we track a threat regroup by this
name Luna Moss
um and what we want to share with you
today is a case study of how we took
iocs that we discovered by responding to
incident
and through the process of pivoting how
we uncovered and unraveled their
infrastructure
um
in our talk we'll have three main parts
uh we'll give you a bit of background on
this group and their go-to technique
that they use in order to infiltrate
networks next we'll share two pivoting
examples that we used in order to track
this group
and of course we'll wrap it up with some
insights
before we start a bit about ourselves
I'm Nam uh it's a pleasure to be here uh
I am an incident responder at signia
I've been with signia for three years
almost
uh tomorrow actually
um and I come from an ex-military
background so that's about it
hi nice to meet you on I'm Owen for the
past three years I've been working as a
senior IR expert at signia I'm a
bookworm
a foodie and a coffee lover
let's start
so we all get fishing messages all the
time right you know the message from the
prince that really needs our help and if
we would just help him now he would make
us rich one day
but there are different types of fishing
events out there take this simple
message for example if we carefully
write the email we can say that it's not
from the prince it's from a well-known
service it's for master class and there
are no typos in the email no links there
is a PDF attachment but it's not
malicious at all if we click and open
the PDF we can see there a receipt for
one of Gordon Ramsay's cooking classes
the foodie I would love to attend this
class but if you don't want Gordon
Ramsay to yell at you you can just call
the number at the bottom of the email
and cancel the subscription
since there is nothing malicious about
this email message
anti-spam Solutions won't flag or block
it but this email is in fact the first
stage of an attack called holdback
fishing
callback fishing is an initial access
attack Vector heavily reliant on social
engineering it's comprised of three
stages first a phishing email like the
message we just saw second a phone call
which the victim initiates and third
some sort of software deployment the
email messages originate from free email
Services they may themselves do not
contain any links and while some of them
have an attachment it is not weaponized
in any way
the emails mimic well-known Brands like
master class or Duolingo and they inform
the victim about an upcoming charge due
to a service or subscription that they
purchased if the victim wants to cancel
the charge they can just call the call
center and a human operator will answer
the call and will manipulate them into
downloading some sort of project
the Trojan will be later used by the
threat actor to gain Hands-On keyboard
access to the compromised host or and
depending on the group conducting this
activity it can lead to that
acceleration ransomware deployment and
quick compromise of an entire network
how is this all connected to Luna mode
well Luna mode is a group that
specializes in callback fishing based on
a research conducted by Advanced Intel
Luna mode were originally part of the
ryuk county operation back then in 2020
and
Luna mode had a different flow the call
center operator will try to trick the
user into downloading a weaponized
Office document when the user enabled
macros Bazaar loader will be executed on
the endpoint ultimately leading to
ransomware deployment
following the Russo cranewall Concrete
disintegrated into several groups and
Luna mode emerged as an independent
group in merch of 2022.
in their post container Incarnation the
group is not yet another ransomware
group
they their technique is a bit different
things they do not use malware they
don't encrypt files and they do not
maintain elixir
lunamix avoidance for malware combined
with the highly Reliance on social
engineering means that technology alone
is not enough to stop this threat what
can stop them good with intelligence
awesome
so I want to finish this background on
luna moth by sharing with you what a
Luna Mata tax flow looks like it all
starts just as we've explained with a
phishing email
containing a receipt for a purchase
service let's say a Duolingo sir
um the phishing email contains the U.S
phone number and the victim calls the
phone number on the other side sits the
operator who leads the victim to
installing remote Administration tools
on their device right these are not
malicious tools by nature but they are
used maliciously by lunima
now just to to be able to get you the
feel of how they work these operators
during an investigation that we
conducted we found out that the victim
who was on the call with this operator
was instructed to install these tools on
their device however they didn't have
the permissions to install these tools
on the device so the operator led the
victim to open a ticket with I.T in
order to install these tools on their
device
it's a very bold move but they got
initial access
so they have these tools on the first
device and they use these tools for the
next phases of the attack they deploy
additional tools such as our clone and
sharp shares and many others in order to
explore the network locate sensitive
files and information and explicate them
outside
once they believe that they have enough
information on their hand they turn into
the Final Phase which is extortion they
send out a ransom demand to the
organization demanding a large sum of
money while holding the sensitive data
hostage right so just to reiterate we're
talking about short breaches
very focused on the the the location and
locating information and stealing it and
then moving on to the extortion
so this summarizes our background at
this point we have these iocs and we
want to start to find additional iot we
want to understand this attacker's
infrastructure naturally we turn to
pivoting as you can see
um and so let's start pivoting right
so two years ago at Sun City I Summit
Joe stovic shared with us this amazing
visualization of how to Pivot on network
infrastructure so the method takes each
one of the indicator domain IP
certificate and breaks them down into
their building blocks into small
observables so if you want to Pivot on
domain name we can for example pivot on
registrar or registrant if you want to
Pivot on IP address you can for example
pivot on hosting provider hosting
location or on the jam Hash a quick
refresher Jam is an active DLS server
fingerprinting tool it's a very useful
tool to Cluster servers together
now I know this is highly theoretical in
practice it all comes down to an Excel
spreadsheet
and this is a snippet from our Excel
spreadsheet don't bother reading the
information in the table it's not as
important as the method so we first
encountered Luna mode doing IR
engagement and doing the investigation
phase we collected all the indicators of
compromise and then we wanted to Pivot
so we took the iocs broke them down into
their observables and put the data into
the table
since people think is an iterative
process each new indicator that was
discovered was broken down and inserted
into the table
analyzing the data in the table clear
patterns were starting to emerge
all the phishing domains shared enemy
thing it was the name of a known service
like Zoho or masterclass with the word
appendages okay so Master Class cooking
the hot teaching Master Duolingo class
the top level domain was either.com or
dot XYZ
and there was no sub domain all the
domains were registered under namecheap
during 2022 in a short time spent before
the actual campaign started
analyzing the IP address information we
noticed that all the domains were hosted
under host wind and they share a
specific Jam hush
at first when we started to Pivot the
jam hash looked promising
but we quickly realized it yields far
too many results
turns out that the jump fingerprint we
used actually fingerprints a clean
installation of Apache web server on
Ubuntu and clearly lunamo does not own
all Apache web servers on Ubuntu so we
decided to combine the jam hash with the
hosting provider and we got few results
to filter out additional cost positives
we added the top level domain
this allowed us to create a very strong
signature that helped us identify the
entire Luna modes infrastructure
additional IR engagements that we
conducted help us confirm and validate
our signature and and I can tell you it
feels great when the signature is
created works and identifies attackers
in the real world
okay cool
um so we have this signature on the
infrastructure at this at this point of
time we were starting to look for
another key element that we can use in
order to Pivot on this attack
we decided to Deep dive into the PDF
files that are sent out as part of the
phishing scenarios and that's because uh
we you can see them in all of the
different luna moth attacks it's the
first stage of the attack
now the methodology behind pivoting on
PDF files is not that different we just
take the samples and break them down
into different building blocks let's say
for example the pdf version The Creator
the producer the amount of pages in the
file has all these different
characteristics which we can use and
work with in order to Pivot on these
files
now before we start it is important to
understand our Viewpoint into the
landscape
um and as incident responders our
Viewpoint is or are the incidents that
we respond to and on top of those we add
the layer of engine such as virustotal
and many others in order to widen and
broaden our pipeline as much as possible
okay so we start with the complete
Universe of PDF files that we have in
our pipeline
the first characteristic that we decided
to look at touches to the process in
which these PDF files are created
we often like to look at these uh the
way the files are created because in
many cases when attackers send out Mass
amounts of files they often have some
sort of automated way or process of
creating these files with Luna Moth they
use a tool called WK HTML to pedia and
by using this tool it also adds certain
information to all of the different PDFs
that they send out and you can see on
the snippet to the right we have the pdf
version we have the creator and producer
tags that are added to all of the files
that they send out
so this is a good starting point right
we can use this information we can take
it in order to start pivoting but Luna
Moss are not the only ones who are using
this tool which means it's not a it's
not a signature yet right however it did
take us a step forward right we started
with the whole universe of PDF files and
we started narrowing it down to a
smaller subset of files
so next we started looking at the file
structure we're talking about receipts
about some kind of payment and all of
the samples that we had only had one
page and we can use this information
right we can filter out anything that
has more than one page right at this
point we wanted to look at another layer
we calculated the average file sizes of
all the samples that we had
we found out that when we limit the
signature to look at files that range
between 30 and 50 kilobytes in size we
were left with a subset of files that
were all related to Luna month campaigns
now that's amazing now theoretically if
that was not enough we could also add
another layer of the process right let's
say for example looking at the file
contents itself we know this is a
subscription related
receipt right so we can look for any
keywords that might be found in these
files in this case we didn't add this
layer but of course we could if if it
was needed
so we started with the whole universe of
PDF files in our Pipeline and we ended
with a subset of files that were all
related to Luna moth's Campaign which
means we have another signature right so
we have the first signature on the
domains and infrastructure we have this
second signature on the PDF files and
then the question to you guys is what's
next naturally
because we want to track this group we
turn to automating the process of using
these signatures
um
so you can see on the right there's a
alert of the that popped up as part of
this automation process it's showing two
new domains that luna moth registered
back in June uh one is related to a
Master Class campaign the other two a
Duolingo campaign doesn't really matter
but we have some sort of automated
process that's popping up new domains
that we think are related to Luna months
potentially of course
another angle that these two signatures
helped us with is to determine the start
start starting point in time of of Luna
moth's operation and that dated back to
March of 2022 right but the first
samples that we saw the first domain
that we saw in register
um a couple months after we we reached
this conclusion and published it in our
blog post uh we also saw uh Advanced
Intel I released a nice paper on on this
group
where they reached that same conclusion
and it's always nice to see other fellow
researchers reach these same same
conclusions about these groups
now one thing about automation that we
really really want to share with you is
that in practice many times automation
doesn't doesn't go as as neat as we want
it to right sometimes we have false
positives now the new alert you can see
on screen shows three different domains
two of these domains are actually really
related to Luna Moth but the one in the
middle is not connected at all right
it's a false positive
so since we want to create threat
intelligence or actionable threat
intelligence in the form of domains that
we can block and we don't want to block
legitimate domains
um this is a problem right we can't just
use this information and stream it
um so what we decided to do with this
problem is use two different layers
through our process of automation the
first layer of automation uses a more
permissive signature and this is exactly
what you see right now on the screen it
allows these false positives right
however and more importantly it allows
us to determine the new campaign themes
as they emerge
and by knowing these new themes as they
emerge we can actually use it and apply
it to the second layer of automation to
filter out or actually filter in only
domains that are related to these new
themes
so we have an automated way
to find new domains find new PDF samples
we know they're related there's a
connection between the PDF files to
these domains so we have some sort of
validation that we're on the right track
which is exactly what we were aiming at
we also took the signature on the PDF
files and applied it and across time a
bunch of different samples popped up you
can see uh a few of them on screen
um one thing to note about all these
samples is that they all share a certain
footer they all say secured with SSL and
of course we know that if it says secure
with SSL the actual vendor incentive
right of course if
so taking all the information created by
the automation process and putting it
into a graph allowed us to analyze past
lunar mod campaigns and complete
continue tracking the goal it also
allowed us to identify patterns at the
macro level so if we go back to the
beginning of lunar month activity
we can see that in April and May they
would run multiple campaigns
simultaneously for example for
masterclass subscription scam and
Duolingo
a July all their campaigns suddenly
stopped this is when signia published
our blog post on the group and we would
like to believe that we have the power
to stop touching it
after a month of Silence the group to
return the resume their activity but
this time the picnic was a bit different
so instead of running multiple campaigns
simultaneously they would switch
campaigns approximately each month so
from class pass to Philo to Bubble to
curiosity
although the the different campaigns use
different teams our signature was still
valid because they did not change their
ttps so we were able to track the
group's activity for almost a year we
are still tracking them and we are
waiting to see what fishing team they
have next to us
Okay cool so I see the timer there we
need to start wrapping things up
um we talked about Luna months we talked
about callback fishing we understand
this technique
through this case study we wanted to
show you our process our thought process
step by step of how we took these iocs
how we broke them down and through this
process of pivoting created these
signatures to track this through
to do this we first needed to understand
our Viewpoint into the landscape and
widen it as much as possible and then by
working through a structured line of
thought we're able to connect all the
different dots and uncover this
infrastructure
attackers and even the most
sophisticated ones often leave ways we
can use to track their infrastructure
now we talked a lot about Luna moss and
this type of family of threats that
focus on on the human factor right these
might not be the most technologically
sophisticated threats
but as such they often sometimes over
overcome the security stack that we have
right
now in order to tackle and Bridge this
Gap we we turn to threat intelligence to
be able to create
actionable threat intelligence in the
form of ioc that we can block even
before we see them being used in
breaches
another angle to this threat
intelligence that we
we took is that we provided this
information to authorities and worked
with them in order to track this group
while they were running their operation
of course you can learn a lot about a
group when you track them while they're
running their operation
so we shared with you the research that
we conducted and the two signatures that
we created
our goal was to show you how you can
take separated isolated iocs and create
a strong signature the method that we
used was to take the indicators of
compromise and break them down into
their building block into small
observables and then we started pivoting
on these observables the the problem or
the challenge that you have when you
pivot on such small indicators that you
are likely to get a lot of results
for example the jamas that we started
with retired nearly half a Million
results
and this makes you think that you are
not on the right path
but when we started to combine the
different observables together we were
able to refine our signature by by
layering the different building blocks
on top of each other we were able to
create a very robust signature that
allowed us to create that allowed us to
track the group over a long period of
time and multiple campaign
so the next time that you get half a
Million results remember that you might
just be on the right path
thank you very much
thank you