foreign
well thank you Rick for the introduction
and uh thank you Dave for the Pyramid of
pain badge we're all repping it today uh
and also thank you everyone both
virtually and in person uh for joining
us and joining me as we talk about you
know uh the economics of cyber threat
intelligence operations and consumption
and production
all right so before we begin just a
quick rundown of today's uh agenda here
uh first I want to start off with a
introduction about myself what I do what
my uh work experience is like as well as
my dog obviously uh and then moving on
we'll talk about what is economics right
and what is the economics of Sabbath
threat intelligence operations
next we'll talk about consumption and
production essentially the outputs of
any CCI operations
then we'll talk about people process
technology behind CTI operations what
drives the operations themselves
moving on we'll talk about resourcing
scarcity trade-offs because ultimately
CTI operations are not running with
infinite resources right so there has to
be trade-offs and there are scarcity
involved
next we'll talk about economics of
demand or also known as Intel
requirements what drives the demand or
what do I drive to supply to the demand
itself the requirements themselves
finally we'll do a quick recap of you
know what uh we've been talking about
and some key takeaways and hopefully
everybody can learn about uh the sort of
Economics of society intelligence so
once again my name is Sherman Chu
currently I am a solution delivery
manager with Deloitte where I focus on
providing clients with cyber threat
management cyber threat intelligence
operations advice and operations uh
previously I was the technical lead for
a state and local governments CTI team
where we built the CTI operation from
the ground up
prior to that I was a senior Intel
Analyst at a financial institution and
in my past life I was a non-commissioned
officer with the US Army
as you can see my dog is also now in
Consulting mode
all right let's let's start so economics
right we've all taken classes before
high school college AP econ micro macro
econ I can promise you right now no
charts no there's no Pareto optimal
charts or whatever we're talking about
the principles the basic principles
principles and fundamentals of Economics
here so as a quick refresher let's talk
about the definition of economics itself
right as according to Merriam-Webster it
is a social science concerned with a
description and Analysis of production
distribution and consumption of goods
and services
now how do we apply that to CTI then
well if we apply to CTI that we can
think about think of it as the
involvement of or the understanding of
resources and scarcity that enables or
limits the production dissemination and
consumption of CTI
now you've got you you know everyone
here will be hearing consumption and
production a lot so let's talk about
that for a little bit
so one can think of consumption and
production as two sides of same coin
they're both outputs they share
similarities right uh in that they have
to be timely accurate uh and relevant
they can be tactical operational or
strategic in nature
they also require people processes and
technology in order to actuate or
actualize
but the biggest difference between
consumption and production is that
consumption is really about the mapping
of available intelligence to defense
whereas production is to generate is a
generation of intelligence for sharing
and others peoples to consume so to
expand us a little bit a little bit more
with consumption you are basically
collecting mostly primarily Finnish
intelligence and then essentially
breaking that apart extracting the core
information from that to apply to your
own you know security posture
um whereas producing is uh you you're
collecting from a lot of raw
intelligence data your Intel internal
Telemetry or perhaps external Telemetry
to provide new insights of threat
behaviors or unknowns
so to further sort of expound on
consumption we can also apply the
mindset of consumption into the uh Intel
life cycle here I'm not trying to
reinvent the wheel and promise you uh
but at the same time you know I think it
would be good for us to think about it
through the phases right because you
still have to plan and direct what to
collect uh what to consume and how to
consume then you have to go ahead and
collect the information
next you have to process this obviously
because you know most collections uh
most fish intelligence are uh very uh
verbose
and then afterwards you've got to
analyze whether that is applicable to
your own environment and how what do you
need to extract from it and ultimately
you consume it so creating detections
analytics unpackages if you will
providing that to you know your
respective teams your sock your bread
hunters and then of course uh without
saying there has to be tuning and
feedback
you know you can't just throw a
detection in and just call it a day you
want to see whether it is spitting out
false positives or do we need to tune
for a certain you know um ilcs out of
the detection right so it essentially
follows the similar phases within the
Intel cycle
okay
so now let's talk about people process
and Technology
you know we've heard about PPT framework
before right it's a means to assess you
know economic activities in the country
or perhaps you know workflow activities
within the organization itself
and in CTI it presents the fundamental
factors that allows or enables for
consumption or production of threat
intelligence so how about we just break
it down um a little more granular and
should look at usually elements
individually
okay so let's start off with people
personally I believe that is the most
crucial uh element of all of the three
elements itself
people are the backbone of CTI
now when I talk about people here I'm
not just talking about the nuclear core
uh analysts within ctm itself CTI team
um but more so anyone that that is
related or impacting the production and
consumption of cyber threat intelligence
you know we're talking about of course
the analysts as uh cursive talk uh has
been talking about also detection
engineer just sock your cert your uh
leadership your Executives these are all
people of CTI and of course they all
come from varied backgrounds um if I
were to pose a question to you to the
audience now both online and in person
and ask them what is your background I'm
sure everybody would come from would say
you know I'm from I.T or I'm traditional
uh Intel or I come from you know more of
an academic background and the point
here is diversity is key right the
background is key uh for for the people
of Sonic art intelligence
of course uh people drives process and
Technology
we'll talk about that more a little bit
so process
so kind of like your furniture assembly
instructions it tells you how to do
things when to do things the protocols
and controls right but in in CTI or
mostly in processes themselves we're
we're talking about two levels of
processes there are macro processes and
micro processes
macro processes are more kin to your
phases in your Intel life cycle you have
the collection phase your processing
phase your analysis phase right
but I would say more importantly are the
micro processes that we often forget
about the small sort of controls and
procedures that we should follow in
order to make sure that these major
phases succeed so take collection for
example during the collection phase we
might have a micro process that involves
the evaluation of sources and
information right it may be the admin
Realty code that we are using to
determine the reliability confidence
level of you know a certain Source
information or perhaps during an
analysis space you know we we have
certain structured analog techniques
that we're using to ensure the quality
assessments so these are all
microprocesses and one thing based off
my pre my personal experience and
talking to a lot of colleagues within
the industry so we often forget the
importance of defining implementing and
following these microprocesses
and it is very important for us to spend
time to develop these uh microprocesses
and time is something that requires you
know people to commit to
so the last element within the PPT
framework is of course technology needs
no introduction we're all using some
sort of tooling and Technology here you
think about your scene your intelligence
platform your link analysis tool maybe
it's your python script that helps you
uh automate some of those Monday and
more repetitive tasks right these are
all technologies that we are leveraging
so that people can do their task more
efficiently and that processes are
followed through now
technology itself does not operate in a
vacuum meaning you can just turn it on
and just let it run it obviously also
requires people
to once again uh develop maintain or
update
as we all know if you've just turned on
a certain intelligence platform a tip
and just let it run and collect all the
all the fresh feeds it becomes really
noisy and really floaty right you need
to analyst to go in and curate the
information to data
so all to say that within the PPT
framework people are the core
and people is a finite resource
So speaking resource
as we said resources are finite we hit
onboarding people having the ability to
hire on people you know is is finite and
people can only commit to a certain
amount of time or hours in their lives
to their job
and of course Financial Resources some
technology needs to be procured
monetarily speaking or you have to spin
up a team dedicated to the sort of
upkeeping of the technology themselves
these are all resources and the
resources that there are that are scarce
we have to look at trade-offs
we can't have everything right even in
metaverse we don't even have legs there
yet so
so let's talk about some of the high
level sort of uh trade-offs that we uh
that we can look at for both the p p and
t starting off people one of the things
I want to highlight here I emphasize is
that people cannot effectively consume
and produce simultaneously the processes
surrounding consumption production can
defer greatly some technologies can do
both but at that point there's a lot
tuning involved and as an organization
itself we need to sort of lean on one
side unless you are you know a
multi-billion dollar organization where
you can spin up two teams right
um and I would also argue that
consumption is harder than production it
was consumption of thread intelligence
requires you to understand your own Tax
Service the courses the defensive
courses action that you can take in
order to consume that intelligence and
turn it into something that will benefit
your organization
so while there are no scarcity for
processes right it does require time and
expertise from people to implement
refine
we can try to copy pasta a bunch of you
know uh process processes from from
textbooks or CTI textbooks slap it on
and call it a day but it is not uh
essentially compliance to your to your
organization's requirements your you
know the workflow and does take people
to go in and look at what works and what
doesn't work in terms of processes and
really refine them
um so that's time and expertise
and of course technology right
technology is there to augment processes
in people
um and it but it also requires people to
go in and maintain and tune and upkeep
so you can you can you can think of that
as more technology means more people to
actually manage
um so
some and there are often times uh where
a lot of organizations out there when
they spin up their CTI their first sort
of instinct is to purchase everything
under the sun
um and by focusing on technology first
we oftentimes would run into the problem
of people maintaining it and a lot of
this technology would deprecate so
people people-centric CTI
Okay so
we'll talk about some balancing or
balances between the three elements here
um
as you know reality dictates equilibrium
equilibrium is hard to achieve in
economy and both in any organizations so
gotta present you with three
hypotheticals here these are extreme
hypotheticals but what we want to do
here is to Showcase what happens uh what
are the results of of missing one
element over to two
so let's just say that we are you know
are on the up and up for processes uh
technology and kind of long people here
what really happens here is that you
know we cannot adequately follow through
the technology that we have we have
implemented or the processes that we
have set up um set forth and people have
to will have to bounce between different
work streams and that look that's the
last thing you want you want people to
be focusing on you know a a single issue
or a few issues not too many and people
can be strained and overworked
and the output itself is optimal at this
point at this point in time
now the second hypothetical here so
let's just say that we have
a good team of people uh we haven't
implemented you know the processes right
for the life cycle of the phases as well
as the micro processes but we're lacking
in toolings and Technology
when it comes to you know processing a
huge amount of data that would be you
know it will become very painful in that
you know you're probably hand jamming
into an Excel sheet and then having all
these pivot tables right it takes a lot
of time although Excel is actually still
great
um I'm not jabbing it taking a jab at it
obviously uh but you know if when
compared to say like you actually have
well-defined you know scripts that can
help automate a lot of these parsings
um one would take a lot more time than
um than the other within the latter you
will
so additionally if we're trying to
disseminate uh for intelligence through
a non-automated process
it's not fun blasting emails to
everybody you know every single time you
finish intelligent products some might
think of getting a sort of centralized
knowledge of management or perhaps a
delivery like a CMS to deliver their
finish intelligence right so technology
does matter in terms of streamlining the
people in the process
so
let's just say that we have people we
have technology but we're kind of
lacking into the sort of implementation
or processes well
now you're talking about inconsistent
outcome right we're not following any
instructions here so we're kind of just
going you're just doing things on the
whim right especially when it comes down
to assess assessments and Analysis work
you need structured analying techniques
you need structured processes to help
with providing consistencies in your
assessments your confidence levels so on
so forth so without that your you know
your products your output is going to be
inconsistent and may actually impact you
know your either Superior posture or
your credibility as a finishing
intelligence provider right so processes
definitely matters
but overall to sum it all up you know we
have to think about people first right
create you know everything is without
people there are no processes there
there can be no technology that can be
actuated or actualized
okay so let's talk about demands the fun
part
so when we talk about demand in a in
this in the CTI sense we really are
talking about Intel requirements now
unlike traditional demand within you
know um most economic activity in CTI we
can actually have more direct control of
demand slash Intel requirements because
it is a essentially a contractual
agreement between the CTI team and your
leadership what can be supplied right
for their demand
um and additionally you know
we can also evaluate via the people uh
processing technology
uh to understand what Intel requirements
can we commit to right
um say an Intel requirement requires a
lot of uh people you know people to to
actually uh commit to uh maybe it is
tracking down a nation-state threat
actor right and uh your your you you
should spin up you know uh personas or
perhaps uh additional threat Hunters
right that's that's a lot of commitment
from people's side as well as processes
as well
so if you look at your current
organization
uh or at least your org chart can you
actually commit to that right maybe you
just have three people obviously you
wouldn't be able to directly
um track these you know uh threat actors
or these these groups right
um so be realistic obviously based on
what your current uh resources
now another thing that we want to do as
well is to periodically assess your
consumption of production
you know generally speaking on an annual
basis or perhaps a recurring basis what
are you producing what are you consuming
is it up to part is are your people
um are you do you have enough people to
to actually commit to all these demands
um and it's critical because oftentimes
we uh you know we are contractually
agreeing to demands that we want to
um sort of achieve and not what we can
achieve right so Canon one of two
different things we should always start
off with what we can achieve based off
of actual resources find our resources
and then moving on with what we want
then plan forward
so always keep that in mind right
because CTI operations does they do it
does not happen in a vacuum it requires
resources time uh financial resources
and people
Okay so
quick recap here
as I said no uh no charts here but we'll
do I'll go through some takeaways here
um the economics of CTI
through the lens of Economics principles
we can understand the scarcity of
resources that affects consumption and
production
and you know speaking consumption and
production they are two sides of the
same coin
um and when you flip a coin usually
usually one one side faces up right it
doesn't fall both uh to stand up
straight meaning you know commit to
either consumption or production
CTA Human Resources as I mentioned I
cannot consume produce at the same time
yep uh and you know use
people processing technology to evaluate
how much can you consume how much can
you produce
and then we should always think about
Intel requirements as demand
and assess whether
we can supply based on the current level
of resources
okay well with that
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]