foreign
hi I'm Sydney Jones and I'm here to talk
to you about how to use CTI in various
size information security teams from
that one person doing infosec to 10 plus
people on a CTI team
so here's what we'll be covering I just
wanted to get through you know I've been
talking to other speakers here today in
the past and preparing for the summit on
different topics that are presented at
various intelligence Summits and
nobody's really talking about how to use
CTI in your various size teams and we do
a lot of discussions on how to
um
make and tailor your products for your
customers but we're not talking about
how to tailor your actual team
so here's what we'll be covering
a bit about myself so I lead the CTI
team at BNP pariba here in the US prior
to that I led a CTI program and another
large bank and also in an exchange I
also developed an external engagement
program at my last firm and I have
several years in the Department of
Defense again as a CTI analyst and doing
intelligence policy advice
I also am in various uh committees
within the financial services
information sharing and Analysis Center
and co-chair of the critical
infrastructure subcommittee at the
intelligence and National Security
Alliance
and outside of all of that I find time
to have fun um so I am also an avid
sailor and Dancer
so let's start off with a couple of
questions I asked them to raise the
lights on this slide how many of you
think that any it department needs an
intelligence function
not as many as I thought okay I think
they do uh
but I also have been an intelligence
professional most of my career
um so I think it's really in how it's
used that is the best thing I don't
think we all need to be writing those
long-form intelligence reports that a
lot of speakers thought was what an
intelligence function did yesterday I
think we can do a little bit more of
information sharing within your company
and then the last couple of questions I
have and then you can bring lights back
down
um how many of you have CTI as one of
the many functions you're responsible
for
about five percent how many of you have
been that one person doing CGI the only
person
okay less than five percent okay that's
good that I guess more of you have
actually done CTI on a larger team
um so we'll be covering again like I
said from that one person kind of
macgyvering information security making
sure that the networks are up
um then going through like a smaller
medium-sized CTI team and then up to
that larger CTI team of like 10 plus
people I will be kind of building upon
each team so please don't kind of tune
out if you are in a bigger team don't
wait till the end to listen
um and then if you are on a smaller team
don't forget about what's coming up just
because this will give you some advice
on how you can mature your program and
kind of ask for more resources you'll
have the ability to tell them hey this
is what I can provide you in return for
those resources
that's it for my pull the audience
question
okay so what about that one person doing
information security
um my biggest advice that I will stop
here is to be a part of your sector's
information sharing and Analysis Center
or analysis organization your ifac and
eye style it's a big thing here within
the US and I've noticed that we have a
lot of people from other countries and
probably online they do have similar
programs outside of the us as well ready
spoke yesterday from the Nordic
Financial cert or cert I think it's one
of those Freddy how to talk yesterday so
go look for that
um there's also FSI Sac AS Global
there's a group in Israel as well and
I'm sure there's others that I am not
aware of
um So within the us there are 25
different eye sacs and eye styles that
are listed on the National Council of
isac's website so your sector is
probably a part of one
um what they do is they can give you a
lot of information specific to your
sector so you're not going to be
inundated with all of this information
that's out there about all the threats
that are going on globally it's kind of
narrowing it down for you
um and then also within your sector
they're going to have those smaller
groups so I would suggest that you reach
out to the membership director or
whoever your account representative is
for that ISAC and ask them hey this is
my Niche business within my sector and
that's what I'm trying to find out more
about
um within Finance which is where I have
spent a good chunk of my career the FSI
SEC has groups devoted to the broker
dealers insurance companies exchanges
and then any other kind of smaller
subsets and then for those of you who
might not know not everyone in finance
actually cares about credit card fraud
which for me is kind of a blessing
um it gives me a little bit more time to
focus in on other threats that I am
actually concerned about
um so it's within these groups that we
can kind of find out a little bit more
information and in my last company I
actually started a smaller group devoted
to the market segment
um so we were more concerned about our
smaller clients and how they could get
information specific to their firms and
their threats we thought if we could
help protect them and get them kind of
talking with each other about threats
that they're seeing it would actually
protect the market overall and keep the
sector as a whole or at least hopefully
as a whole more secure from those
threats
separately
um Within These isacs they also have
Regional focused groups so it's not
specific to your actual smaller
sub-sector but it can be based on where
you are located geographically so this
is instead of just going to their annual
Summit once a year seeing everybody and
getting you know a lot of fun out of it
you're actually meeting up quarterly
hopefully or more often and getting to
meet peers within your geographic area
so you can have those conversations
those smaller groups which is actually
really great
so that's kind of a lot about the ISAC I
really like the ISAC some people may not
but I think it's a good place to start
and then after that I would say even
beyond the US you can look at the Cecil
vulnerability catalog they actually post
a lot of updates on vulnerabilities that
are actively being exploited and they
updated on their website which I
actually made sure to put on the screen
which I hope is big enough for you guys
to read
um so that way if you're that one person
caring about literally everything going
on in your company you can kind of
prioritize your patching cycle based on
what's actively being exploited they
will actually also prepare monthly
summaries depending on your sector and
provide those as well saying hey within
your sector in the past month we've
noticed that even older vulnerabilities
are being exploited so you can go back
and make sure that your patching is up
to date if needed
and with all this information that's a
lot to come through so you may want to
talk to your firm about using either a
seam or a tip not my preference at the
size team but it's a lot for one person
to handle so if you have the budget it's
something you can consider
as far as outputs I really don't think
you're going to have time for any
intelligence help but you already have a
lot going on so just kind of help this
or use this information to help inform
your processes you already have in place
so for a smaller information security
team so a little bit bigger than one
person but still not that large kind of
pay attention to what we just talked
about but another way that you can kind
of help with that information and any
additional information you're looking at
externally is an open source aggregator
so I've been using the free version of
Feedly I know free tools are popular
here
um paid Feedly does have a paid version
but I've been using the free one for I
don't know how many years at this point
um I am actually putting in the sisa
information that we just talked about as
long as well as some FBI pins flashes in
the financial sector we get finra
notices about fishing campaigns that are
ongoing I'll have that in there and any
security blogs that I'm following
proofpoint just gave a talk listing
multiple different blogs that they are
citing so that's another thing that you
can add into your Feedly or any other
aggregator you choose to use and as well
as any news so that you like and I would
suggest that you kind of keep tweaking
this as it's needed you know if you're
interested in a paid version Beauty has
a paid version data Miner and sprinkler
are other options as well and for my
Twitter users if you still enjoy Twitter
I think tweet Tech is still available so
don't quote me on that but I hope it is
um and then some things you can also
monitor for are data and credential
leaks
um for this you can either use a paid
vendor or you can also check have I been
phoned or breached since to see if your
information's been out there
um what else do I have on here and then
ocent Frameworks I learned this in my
ocean class csans they have so many
things on that website that they
actually update so not only just for
this slide as well but future slides
that's a good a good resource to go back
and look at
and again still no additional outputs
that I'm asking you guys to do or even
try to do because you're still focused
on that broader information security
Mission you're really just going to be
looking to Monitor and detect anything
that you can
okay so we're at a CGI conference when
are we going to talk about CTI teams
um so this is the one I wanted to start
with so a small team of one to three
analysts
um there's a lot of external information
that I've just covered but I really
think that this is when you can start
focusing on your internal Telemetry and
tying in all of that external
information to what's internal this
would mean your sock data or any other
logs that you have access to and through
this you can start using the ISAC
information about phishing campaigns or
malware hits occurring in your sector
comparing it to see if you're having
similar issues going on at your firm
this is also when a tip would actually
come in quite handy because you can tie
in that external data to your internal
data and then if you're looking to do
malware analysis we talked about malware
analysis yesterday a couple of tools
would be abuse.ch
virustotal and hybrid analysis I also
put on here cert gadgets it was on the
ocean framework site so that's another
resource you could use
for your focus here it's going to be on
that operational lens and you're talking
about tactical operational and strategic
and your outputs I really want you to
start with those intelligence
requirements that we've talked about
throughout this conference an example
that I like to start off with as a big
intelligence requirement you know you're
only going to have like four to eight
overarching ones if you have more than
that it's going to be way too many for
you to think about so a big one that I
always start with when I go to a new
team is hey are we looking at
information related to a campaign
targeting us
or a peer that's very similar to us that
should be your main goal what are your
crown jewels and what are the threats
that are trying to get to that so that's
my advice for in regards to Intel
requirements
um and then you're going to use those
Intel requirements to create some type
of reporting or information that you're
sharing with other teams so I give you
some advice here for working with your
incident Response Team you're going to
look through those phishing metrics
you're going to look through the
phishing campaigns that are going on
within your ISAC channels kind of
comparing contrasting seeing if you're
seeing similar hits
don't just say be like hey we saw this
in FSI Sac here you go suck go see if we
have it you can actually go look for
that and then if you get a hit you can
pass it on to the stock for them to do
additional research and if there are no
hits you can just put it in your tip or
your scene and then it'll notify you if
you have something in the future
um for your vulnerability management
team again it goes back to that Cecil
alerts or any other reporting that
you're using for vulnerabilities you
want to let them know hey we saw this
vulnerability that's being patched but
it's actually actively being exploited
in our sector maybe that's the one that
you guys want to patch first
uh then I wanted to talk about exercises
and red teaming activities a lot of
people have a hard time understanding or
thinking through what should the red
team look to exercise or Implement so
you can provide the real world
intelligence about what's been going on
in the past few months past week past
year depending on how often they do
those exercises so an example that came
out last week is now we're now being
delivered via OneNote attachments so
that's something you may want to see if
your red team could exercise
and then if that's not enough if you
have time uh you can do some weekly
reports some teams of this size do
weekly reporting to their staff it can
be either technical or operational
reporting lines that you're reporting
those to so this would be external
intelligence that you're seeing and
trying to tie that back to your
intelligence requirements I'm not saying
do a summary of news articles please do
not do that otherwise they're going to
think that's all you do
so you're actually wanting to tie the
external intelligence back to your firm
so where's your firm operating where are
they looking to expand their business to
who are their clients are they operating
in a high risk operational area what are
the threats for that what are the threat
actors targeting your sector this week
that type of thing
uh for a mid-size CTI team this is
actually when you can start adding in
that strategic focus and focus on all
three aspects of intelligence that we've
talked about and your analysts can start
kind of deciding which one they might
like more interesting I'm a strategic
analyst but I love my tactical analysts
because they love the malware
yeah
um so some things that you can look for
as far as inputs if you have the budget
and I'm assuming if you have a team this
size you have a little bit more budget I
would suggest adding in a dark web
monitoring vendor so they can start
looking on the dark web seeing if
there's anything talking about thread
actors wanting to Target you
specifically or your type of firm so you
don't have to go out there nation state
or Espionage focused vendor is also
really helpful at this point
um and then if you don't have that money
at least for the nation-state vendors a
lot of them will provide log updates and
security blog updates as we mentioned
earlier on the larger activities that
they're seeing so you can at least kind
of add that into what your wanting to
report back to the firm if you want a
more powerful ocent aggregator like I
mentioned earlier this is another time
you could probably start adding that in
since you're going to have enough
analyst focusing on that
and then also a domain monitoring tool
so this is when you're trying to you
know look back through to see if
anyone's kind of doing your things to
your domains but then also when you're
trying to figure out hey we saw this
happening from such and such domain
where does that tie back into
infrastructure wise
as far as outputs you can do a lot more
on the sector Trends threats that you're
seeing sector-wide geopolitical events
and how that could impact your business
line or your bottom dollar and business
strategy are you looking to operate in a
new location are you looking to add in a
new line of business in finance a lot of
people want to add in crypto for some
reason
don't do it please don't
um you can also do some products with
your physical security and business
continuity teams as well so this would
be are there cyber threats that could
actually happen at the same time as a
physical disruption to one of your
locations or again you are looking to
expand into a high-risk operational area
whether the Cyber threats involved in
doing that
and then my personal favorite you could
start trying to do here is external
Partnerships
um this would just be an additional duty
if someone has some time maybe one or
two analysts and what do I mean by
external Partnerships I'm a big
proponent of having relationships with
your local law enforcement and
government entities prior to an incident
so I know that a lot of people aren't
really sure where to start but it's a
good thing to kind of get to know who
those people are you can also start
building more one-on-one trusted
relationships within your sector so
again like I said do this prior to an
incident you don't want to be dealing
with a ransomware attack and trying to
figure out who to call
you want to already know who they are
like hey dude yeah it was great seeing
you last week by the way I need your
help you know you want to have that
relationship already
and it's also good use for intelligence
collection because you already have
those relationships and someone might
tell you hey we're seeing XYZ activity
before they even put it in an ISAC
then for a larger team of analysts
coming from the government and into a
large multinational Bank
I kind of used to think this is what a
CTI team wants I've learned over the
years this is not a CGI team in most
places it is usually you know the
Fortune 100 Banks or 100 companies for
the government or security vendors that
have the science team but if you are
fortunate enough I guess fortunate
enough to work for one of them this is
some advice for your size team again I'm
assuming at this point you're going to
have a lot of budget because you're
going to have this many people so you're
going to look at some specialized
vendors and what do I mean by
specialized so some firms are actually
building specific teams for specific
threats and that's going beyond your
strategic threats they're looking at hey
we've seen a lot in the supply chain
sector we're really concerned about that
so let's look for some vendors that can
help us explore that option or in the
cryptocurrency world or blockchain chain
analysis really is really great and
useful for people who are concerned
about that but you can also double up on
your vendors so if you have a specific
region that you're focused on some
vendors are better at focusing on
certain regions so you can add in a
vendor that's focusing on that
uh some firms of the size are also very
concerned about brand protection and
what do I mean by that you're concerned
about how your brand is seen online or
if there are scams implicating your
brand without your permission so you're
looking for tools that will be
monitoring for new domains that pop up
impersonating your brand social media
accounts that are impersonating your
brand or possibly your c-suite and I'm
not just talking about deep baits
um and then when we get into ex your
outputs it's still going to be the same
recording lines but you're going to add
in a little bit more because you're
going to have those more Niche teams so
your supply chain cell that some firms
have you're going to need to be working
with your third-party risk management
team as an example and the relationship
managers for those vendors you're going
to be talking to them regularly talking
to them about the threats you're seeing
all these data breaches that keep
happening to our vendors these days I
don't know how many I've seen in the SSI
stack realm this month I it's been a lot
of just vendors that we were concerned
about
um and then you know they're going to
build those reporting lines specifically
for that
and oh the other one I had was
cryptocurrency because again I work in
finance there are cells that are
actually very much concerned in the
thefts of cryptocurrency and monitoring
those threat actors on a daily basis
and then again external engagement I
think at this point you can actually
have that one person who's focused on it
maybe too full time and that's going
Beyond just the relationship with law
enforcement this is you know building
those relationships with the
cross-sector engagements of you know
everyone is dependent on energy and
telecommunication I don't care what
sector and you're dependent on that for
your business so you're kind of building
those relationships across your isax
through the you know different
cross-eyes hack channels you're finding
other information sharing groups that
you can talk to you're talking to
Academia you're talking to other
government sectors you're talking Beyond
US government or your local government
um so anyways that can be a whole other
talk in and of itself so if you want to
talk to me about external engagement you
can see me after
okay so I've given you a lot of
information hopefully it was enough for
you guys to absorb but I want you to
think of some questions before I show
you a summary slide
where are you now in regards to CTI
and where do you want to be
and how can you get there
so I hope that this talk gave you some
ideas of how you can kind of mature your
team and some things that you can do to
convince your management of why you need
more resources or when you get those
resources that you'll be able to provide
them better outputs
I had meant to tell you I was going to
give you a summary slide of everything
but here's a summary slide of everything
if you want to take a picture of this
before the slides are off
and please don't do this all on your own
right and with that again not malware
[Applause]
[Music]