foreign
who started public speaking during the
pandemic since it's actually my first
in-person talk
um thank you
um one of the things that I don't get to
do a lot with virtual talks is involve
the audience so I am going to be asking
you questions throughout so I hope you
enjoy that my first question is how many
in the room know what Sops are
okay almost everyone in the room so if
you're not familiar with that's a piece
standard operating procedures how many
in the room think that you have the
perfect Sops definitely up to date
definitely centrally located
okay this talk is for you I was hoping
there would be like one person that
would raise their hand and I can make
fun of throughout the talk but it's okay
I have Rick
um
okay so I'm gonna introduce who I am
um then I'm going to talk a little bit
about cognitive science uh hat tip to Dr
Chris because I'm a huge fan of his and
I always also like to include some type
of cognitive science to my talks then
I'm going to talk about the state of
current intelligence Sops and some of
the challenges that I have seen working
in the field and then the impact of
having poor Sops or just not having sfps
at all and then I'm going to
um introduce something that I found when
I
um did my last talk at the 2020 sand CTI
Summit I introduced my framework and one
of the parts of the framework was think
steps and I'm going to give you some
examples about how to use think steps in
a not only for your CTI investigations
but also to improve your Sops and then
I'm going to give you some tips on how
to operationalize uh not only my idea
but just generally tips to help you with
your Sops and then I'm gonna hopefully
if I have time do a quick summary and
maybe some questions
so I just started last week at Cisco
Talus I'm very happy to be on the team
as a cyber security research analyst and
writer I'm also the author of the
children's book series The Mighty
intelligence Warrior you'll see her on
the screen and all her glory you might
see characters from my books throughout
the presentation
um just because I could
um I'm uh also the creator of the
cognitive stairways of analysis which
you can go back and watch that talk from
the 2020 CTI Summit or if you want to
know more about it in my book or that
talk you could go onto my blog on
perthuntergirl.com and at heart I'm a
tactical intelligence junkie I like to
be as far in the weeds as possible
um and I'm not a regular Mom I'm a cool
mom
and I'm also a massive Lego fan I
actually have a Lego city that I built
during the pandemic I have not named it
um so if you have any ideas please let
me know
so let's talk about the process of sense
making uh Dr Chris had talked about it
in his keynote which I was very excited
about but this is basically how our
brains make sense of the world around us
and
um
when our brain experiences an event it
collects data about that event and it
looks through like our Rolodex of
schemas that it's already created to see
do we need to make a new schema do we
need to update an existing schema or is
it probably not useful information like
kind of like if you ever see something
out of the corner of your eye and you
think did I see something is it a ghost
and your brain's like oh and you just
stop thinking about it that's when it's
just going to get rid of that data so
knowing that that's how our data our
brains make sense of the world around us
why do I remember the words to every
Britney Spears songs in existence but I
can't remember what I need to do on a
day-to-day basis without making a to-do
list
if our brains are so amazing and they
have all these different features why do
we always forget stuff that we find
useful well I read this article
it was on nature.com and it was called
The Forgotten part of memory and it was
written by Lauren gravitz
and it was about neuroscientists in
Canada and they did a research about the
process of forgetting and what they
found was it's most likely a feature and
not a bug and that our brains are
constantly going through this like data
management
process to help us learn and to help us
evolve and um
learn new things that is good for
survival again I don't know why out of
all the things I can remember it's
Britney Spears but it must be useful to
my survival
so let's talk about the different types
of business knowledge explicit knowledge
it's very easy to express I give the
example of a threat landscape report if
you work in CTI you've probably heard
this phrase before you could probably
Define it easily you could probably say
what is in it but how your individual
business uh puts one together maybe like
the style of it the keywords if maybe
instead of executive summer you have
key points or key findings that's more
of the implicit knowledge that's
specific to your organization
the tacit knowledge which Dr Chris also
mentioned in his keynote if you go back
is really how we go to quote him from
perception to reality this is the
tradecraft of analysis and some people
think that this is challenging to
capture but I am here to say it is not
and you'll notice under tacit knowledge
that I have a little Mighty Warrior
symbol from my book this is going to be
found throughout my presentation and
it's going to be opportunities for
capturing that tacit knowledge
so let's talk about the state of current
Sops one of the issues that I understand
regardless of the size of your
organization
it takes time
and I don't have a solution for this is
going to take time to have Sops and it's
going to take a lot more time to have
good Sops
um and I'm going to talk about time in a
minute and you will see another shout
out that makes you think that you might
actually have more time than you think
another thing that I see with Sops is a
lot of times it will talk about tasks
that you have routine tasks but it won't
necessarily say why do we have those
routine tasks it won't say what business
function is this task helping and I feel
like there's an education opportunity
for analysts because if you don't know
why you're doing it
it can be challenging when you take that
implicit knowledge to another
organization and they ask you you know
in the interview or whatever
why did you do that like why do you
think that that type of uh report or
task is important and you have no idea
because you just haven't got that
education so I think the why you're
doing something whether it's why it's
important to the clients or why it's
important to the business is important
to add into the Sops
so if you haven't seen this talk by
Sherman if you're in CTI or you manage a
CTI team it's one of the greatest talks
I've ever seen I saw it and instantly
was like yes
this so if you think you do not have
time
you might find that you actually have
more time than you think so I recommend
going back and watching that either on
the Stan's website or on YouTube
so
another thing that I've noticed is Sops
are not I don't know why it has a Dell
I felt really silly when John had a
Taylor Swift and I was like is that a
Taylor Swift why did the why did I find
a meme that has Adele whatever we're
gonna go with it but a lot of times saps
are not up to date and or a lot of times
what I see is you have this expensive
product that your manager thought would
be a good idea to use and so you have
Sops for that specific tool but then
they decide the license for that for the
whole team is too expensive so you've
switched to a cheaper tool or open
source tool but you haven't updated your
Sops so then when someone comes in to do
that job they're like oh yeah
that we don't do that anymore and then
that person has to kind of like Shadow
someone and Flounder and I feel like
they shouldn't have to do that it's
stressful
the other thing I've noticed is a lot of
times if you work in an environment that
Fosters creative freedom
where people could come up with new
ideas
um and say you know I think it would be
a really good idea to do an end of year
report or I think we should do uh you
know whatever it is that you think is a
great idea for your organization maybe
it's just a way to automate a process
and you create something
and it becomes part of the team like
part of a critical routine task but it's
not necessarily
uh documented it may not be documented
in a way that anyone but that one person
understands
so let's talk about impact
so when you do not have good Sops it
sucks when someone leaves
especially if they've been there for a
long time because they have all that
tacit knowledge
and if they haven't captured it you're
going to basically try to find someone
to replace that person and I'm here to
say might be an unpopular opinion but I
don't think anyone is replaceable I
think everyone that is in the audience
whether you're virtual or here
physically you are not replaceable
because you all have your own
experiences your own tacit knowledge
your own perspectives and so a lot of
times when organizations go to hire
someone the long process because whether
they know they have a bias in their
brain or not they do sometimes and
instead of looking for someone that's
qualified for that role or is eager to
learn and has a good attitude and could
quickly grow into that role they just
want to find a replacement I want the
Unicorn that has these Niche skills that
the person who left and you're not
always going to find that
and then if you do find someone and they
go to the onboarding
and you don't have Sops in a central
location it could feel like a goose
chase not only for the person
onboarding that employee but also for
the person that is the employee and like
I know for me specifically I write a lot
of sticky notes and I stick them all
over my monitors and I kind of Judge My
Success at a new uh business like uh how
many I could take away over time and I
feel like if I'm already doing this why
aren't we you know capturing that in sop
so people don't have to flounder in
right like you know dozens of notes the
other point I wanted to make is that
single point of failure if you have
someone that leaves and they have all
this knowledge or or they had created
all these new ideas or reports
it sucks for your team trying to
replicate it especially if it has to do
with like coding and things like that
and maybe not everyone on the team has
that
so I want to talk quickly about how I
stumbled upon thick steps
in 2020 I was writing a blog or I was
doing research to write a blog about the
analytic tradecraft
and I wanted to expand upon the word of
analysis because I felt like we don't do
that enough as an industry and a couple
people have said this throughout the
summit that we kind of have an
assumption that everyone understands
what we're talking about when we say
certain words
and I went through different Industries
to see how do other Industries perform
analysis and I took my favorite things
from each one and created my framework
and one of them was think steps
and
this one was from a white paper and it
was called how analysts think think
steps as a tool for structured sense
making and criminal intelligence
analysis try saying that five times fast
it is not easy but basically the authors
of this white paper interviewed criminal
investigators and they all had cases
that had pre-prepared to discuss and and
they talked about their analytic process
throughout their investigation
and the mind map that you see is kind of
what the authors put together
this is a lesson in QA because it
literally says model of police
operational intelligence analysis I put
model of police crime analysis process
don't know why we will talk about QA in
a minute but
think steps basically are a template
that allow the investigator to approach
the case decompose it into separate
elements and then classify the data
during the investigation accordingly
for example one particular
investigator that was interviewed
they had never
investigated the type of crime that they
had brought they had prepared for this
interview and it was on human
trafficking
and this is where I learned that they
not only use think steps as a way to
help themselves during their own
investigation to keep on track and
Associate data accordingly they also use
it as a training tool
um for people who have never you know if
they've never done it they already have
a template to kind of go learn and they
do something called a phenomenon study
and this is where they
they already have the template for this
crime they go and research all of the
little bits of that crime so that they
know what they're looking for during the
investigation
and this is a similar mind map that what
you'll find in the white paper I
recreated it in Whimsical which is free
and I love it on the right hand side you
will see the information about the
person or persons involved in the crime
and this is just useful information for
them to have readily available during
their investigation
I have a small confession to make
I have ADHD and I don't know about some
other people with ADHD but sometimes
when I'm reading something particularly
if it's about anything related to sense
making or cognitive science Dr Chris's
dissertation
um
I get so excited and sometimes my brain
skips ahead to what I think is most
interesting and I may or may not fully
understand the holistic view of what I'm
reading and when I first read about
think steps I took out key pieces
but when Rick reviewed my slides he had
pointed it out so thank you Rick because
I realize I missed something very
important not only in my framework but
in the blogs that I've written about
think steps and you noticed on the last
Slide the think steps were just words
they're just you know very short things
that you need to think about
during the phenomenon study the criminal
investigators added the context and what
I thought was think Stacks or think
steps was the context because I knew in
my life that's what was missing and so
today I am
um presenting the think steps plus the
context to not only improve your own
personal investigations but also your
Sops to help with training
so my first example is a threat actor
profile this is a very repeatable
um report or even if you're just doing
it for an internal knowledge base at one
point or another if you work in CTI
you've probably done a threat actor
profile
and on the left hand side
these are my think steps and you might
think well this looks a lot like almost
like an outline of things to include in
your paper but if that's your
deliverable or it could be a PowerPoint
however you're delivering the
intelligence but it's not exactly that
similar but not exactly it is basically
the things that I want to think about
during the investigation but not all of
them may end up in deliverable so like
previous known attacks that you know if
they don't have any previous known
attacks you're not going to add that but
it is something that is critical that
you should look at
um and the tricky Dragons It's not a
real threat actor but it is from my book
you might look cute he's very tricky
don't trust him
so on the right side
um the first two points are the
intelligence requirements and this is
specifically if you're doing you know
I've always been at the vendor so I
always do a lot of rfis but even if
you're doing something internal for your
own knowledge base I feel like having
some type of ir is still really good and
for an sop
I mean our all rfis are going to be
different sfps are going to be a little
bit different for the most part there's
a lot of IRS that are very much the same
and so I feel like having example IRS
it's another training tool that you can
have
um and specifically if you have it set
up so that it's similar to like what the
client is going to request to help your
analysts to be able to read through the
lines
on the bottom on the right hand side I
put example information that you might
get from a client or just from your own
knowledge of that particular thread
actor and that's just useful information
you can even put another one like
tactical audience a strategic audience
so adding the contacts this is one of
the thing steps think if I just clicked
on it expand it Minority Report Style
I feel like
you know previous mentions of an example
organization it's important and a lot of
us know it's important but if you have
someone that's newer that's getting into
the field they may not know why that's
important so I think it's important to
Define not only why it's important the
potential impact but also the different
types of mentions because not every
threat actor is going to go out and be
like Oh I'm tacking example you know
they might say I'm attacking a financial
services institution in the United
States with the revenue of 50 billion or
you know whatever it is
so
that's tacit knowledge that I have from
experience but may not be you know
something that everybody knows and I
feel like we can capture that
so
uh another shout out to Gert for Bob
Ross talk that he did the joy of threat
Landscaping
um because my second example was cyber
uh threat landscape I wanted to give his
quote which is the intelligence
requirements are the sketches of my
research I absolutely love that so on
the left side again I have the think
steps these are the things that I would
add to a report if I was doing a threat
landscape report and this one is
industry specific so it's very general
it's very broad just as an example and
again another example intelligence
requirement on the right
and then if I were to break out one of
those intelligence require or uh think
steps expand upon it add the context
Define what it is Define the impact of
that thing Define
um the different uh things to look for
why is it important and this is an
opportunity not only for you to add
education but this is the information
you might actually end up putting in
your report especially if it's an
executive audience so you're just saving
yourself time by having it already
prepared in your Sops
and then even going into like how are
you doing it you know I like to use
Google door King because it helps with
like at least for secondary reporting
because it gets to the point it saves me
time so I feel like going into specific
details where are you looking for uh
this information what are things to look
for
um why is it important
so this is a quick I am running low on
time so I wanted to give another example
I don't have context for this one but I
wanted to show another example of how it
could be used for Sops it's more like
how the criminal investigators were
using it which is information or
characteristics about a specific crime
or things that you may see
um if you are you know in your
environment so on the right hand side I
added some invest some intelligence
requirements but I also think this is a
great opportunity if you're going to
model it like this to put stuff that
like common words or language that
um at least if you're on a vendor that
clients use because sometimes uh you'll
notice when you're trying to create
intelligence requirements you have to
read between the lines you can kind of
see what they want but you have to be
able to kind of put it into clearer
words so that you can actually provide a
deliverable so that's another way that
you use it
so how do we operationalize this
the first thing I would say having a
central location is extremely important
and of course I'm going to recommend
Excel because like Katie Nichols says it
is undoubtedly the best CTI tool of all
time
one of the other things that I love
about it is that you can
you can add in kind of like mind maps
but then you can link it to other slides
so if you did want to expand upon it
even if it's linking to another tool
that's fine but it's centrally located
so it's not a big boost Chase for your
analysts so first thing I say is make a
list of the routine tasks that your team
does
and then after you've finished that put
that aside and then make a list of the
strengths of all of your team members
and the reason I say that is because
sometimes when we're just thinking about
routine tasks we're just thinking about
the tasks that are in our job
description
but when you start thinking about the
strengths of people you start thinking
about all those little single points of
failure tasks that they do for us that's
not really part of their job description
so you might find some more goodies in
there that you can collect Sops for and
then use your own internal resources you
know if you already have Sops just build
upon them there's no use like
Reinventing the wheel
um and if you don't you know you could
start small with just a couple processes
and
um the way that you capture the tacit
knowledge really the meat and potatoes
of the presentation is I feel like we
always say everybody learns differently
but we don't really talk about everybody
teaches differently
and I don't know about you but when I
get assigned Sops
I don't really like
um because it's like it's hard to go
through the process and you want it to
look nice and it takes time as I said
but something that Rick's team actually
did really well when I was at digital
Shadows
um hat tip to Ivan riggy he used to
videotape stuff
that he did and it was amazing for me on
a remote team because I can go back and
watch it and when you're doing it on
video
you might you know spit out that tacit
knowledge that you may not put into
written work
and it was extremely useful and
I feel like sometimes you're you're
limited because some of the
investigations you're going to do going
to have client data so you can't
necessarily keep that in your Sops so
you can sanitize it or also if you have
any type of repeatable tasks that's not
necessarily related to a specific
company or if you can recreate it in a
similar fashion
um with just information that's out
there
um like a known malicious things that
you can put in its place
um one of the things I like to do that I
have actually done before is after I
have finished I had like one week where
I had finished a tactical report in a
strategic report just so happens in the
same week and there was someone on my
team that was looking to know more about
my thought processes so I got on a call
with them and just kind of went over
like you know if I'm on virus told I'm
looking at the you know malware that's
communicating with it and then I'm
looking at the related you know
infrastructure and then I might go on
uh if I'm doing like a strategic report
I like to use uh unit 42's Playbook they
have a lot of Industry specific stuff
secureworks has some stuff leaping
computer is a great knowledge base if
you just go in and you type in like
whatever your industry is financial
services or whatever then you could see
every time they've tagged that in a
story and that's extremely useful
information and this is just stuff that
you know we might think is obvious but
it's not going to be obvious to other
team members so I think pay attention or
ask your team members how do they like
to learn that would like to follow along
do they like to not talk to anyone and
just read it do they like screenshots
but also ask them how do they like to
teach
because if they are just going to get on
a zoom call even if you're able to just
record it or if they're just going to
explain it maybe even just in a lunch
and Learn Type situation where they're
just explaining their thought process
that might be more comfortable for them
and everyone will still get the
knowledge and you could even record you
know that for people that missed it
and then peer review as we saw very
important
um and I think it's really important to
not just look for grammar mistakes but
look for like actually try to do that
thing and
have your managers do it have your
seniors do it have your newbies do it
and try to go through the process
because if you can't follow the steps or
you have one part that doesn't work you
have to document that and onboarding is
a great time to review your Sops but
I will say every organization that I've
been at is really good at asking me you
know what are my opinions are about the
onboarding process what are my opinions
about their Sops and their processes
they're always looking for feedback
um I don't know about you but I'm never
gonna be like oh it's garbage
it's it's total garbage thank you for
hiring me but let me make fun of you so
don't expect your newbies to actually
answer that question
ask but they might not answer what you
should be doing is asking them how is it
going
and if you notice that they are reading
an s p and it doesn't make sense to them
or some part of it's disconnecting
especially if it's something Technical
and they're getting some type of error
that's a cue for you to update it or to
get someone else to update it put it on
your to-do list it's not a job for your
newbie to figure it out it's just your
cue as a senior or manager to get that
fixed so it's easier for the next person
and lastly make sure it's a living
document it's hard
chasing
um
Sops down and getting them done it is
hard it takes time but it's worth it I
have seen pure chaos and and not a lot
of processes in place that I've seen
where there's a lot of processes in a
lot of Sops and it makes your life a
hundred times better as an analyst on
your day-to-day even if you have to do
extra work because it's organized so I
do think there is light at the end of
the tunnel and you will see
um rewards for that and then anytime
again if you're switching tools and your
Sops for that specific tools try and
update that or any changes to existing
tasks any new ideas that get created
into a task the great way to do it so
remember
uh our brains are amazing at how we make
sense of the world around us but you're
not going to remember everything so if
you know you're wired to forget then why
not capture that data while you still
have it it takes time but it is worth it
and try to keep them up to date try to
not only talk about what it is you're
doing how you're doing it why you're
doing it and avoid single points of
failure
and while you're avoiding single points
of failure make sure you're not impeding
on creative freedom unless you want to
and that's that's on you but
also
adding the think steps as a template
specifically for those repeatable tasks
that you have not only like internal
tasks but you know whether it's rfis
reports and then you know that
information can be used not only to help
your analysts stay on task during the
their investigations but also for
training other employees
and I finished on time
thank you
foreign