foreign
thanks guys uh so my name is Drew
Schmidt I am the uh lead analyst for the
guidepoint research and intelligence
team and today we're going to be talking
a little bit about ransomware rebranding
and ultimately why it's so hot right now
so a little bit about me I've been in
I.T infosec sock defer threaten towel
malware for quite a while
um I kind of landed on malware that's
one of the things I just really like to
to dive into and and really kind of put
a lot of my time
um but enough about that um we can talk
later about who I am and what I do but
what I want to get into is ransomware
rebranding so to start off I just want
to take a little bit of a step back and
just look at ransomware rebranding as
it's occurred since basically 2020 and
then getting get into a little bit of
case studies to look at why ransomware
rebranding is so effective
then I want to get into some tips and
tricks for how we can actually identify
what ransomware rebranding is doing and
and how it's progressing through from
Rebrand to Rebrand before we figure out
you know how do we take all this
information and put a lot of this
knowledge to work
um the last talk did a really good a
really good explanation of a lot of that
piece so I'm glad that happened
beforehand but
um we'll kind of wrap it up with that
so to start with ransomware rebranding
it's so hot right now
um Hive right in the middle
um is going to be probably a really good
example of why rebranding is is so
successful and ultimately why it's
important for us to take a look into
rebranding so that we can stay up to
date with what threat actors are doing
so to begin with this is a graph of
publicly posted ransomware victims from
2022 and this comes straight out of our
annual ransomware report that we just
put out last week and what you see in
the blue or in the solid line is the
number of posts that went on throughout
2022 the dotted green line is actually
the number of groups that were active at
any given week during
um during 2022. so the one thing really
to to pay attention to other than the
fact that ransomware is obviously a huge
problem is at any given time there were
11.2 active groups that were posting
victims to public sites now this is a
very high number and and ultimately as
we go through 2022 we see that this
number went up and down
so when we think about ransomware as a
large problem obviously that's obvious
but as we dive in a little bit deeper we
can see exactly why it's a problem and
why it's a little bit harder for us to
track from a CTI perspective
so to start with ransomware rebranding
has been around for quite a while we've
seen groups like maids we've seen Gan
crab become Rebel we've seen e Gregor
Hive Conti a whole bunch of evil Corp
variations all this has been going on
for a long time even longer than we've
been talking about it as rebranding
so
one of the things that we did was we
wanted to break this down a little bit
more get a little bit more granular to
have a taxonomy for how we should talk
about ransomware and specifically
rebranding so on the x-axis of this
little chart here we have kind of the
duration of operations and on the y-axis
we have activity and so we came up with
this idea where we have different types
of groups one is going to be full time
these are the groups that are operating
for long periods of time they have long
consistent activity they have
well-established infrastructure
well-established ttps and they're
operating for again a very long time
now rebrands are going to be kind of the
the offshoots of a full-time group that
have to go through a free brand for any
number of reasons Hive is going to be a
great example of what we see in terms of
Rebrand activity
now Splinter groups are going to be more
of an offshoot maybe it's an affiliate
that decides to go out on their own or
it's going to be some other smaller
group that is an offshoot from either a
full-time or a Rebrand group a little
bit more erratic less established ttps
um and ultimately they haven't been
around for for all that long
and lastly we have ephemeral groups now
these are very interesting because
they're the ones that are a flash in the
pan they're there for a second then
they're not and these particular groups
might be used for any kind of uh
specific targeted operation
um but ultimately they're there for such
a short period of time that all they
really do is add a lot of noise for us
so the thing to understand about the way
that we think about ransomware groups
and the taxonomy that we created is that
a lot of these groups will move between
different types they may start as
ephemeral and move into a splinter group
or ultimately full-time or maybe they
come in as a Rebrand and move to full
time but there's a lot of movement that
happens with ransomware groups
and so what this results in and then
what we found is when we break this down
into these different types of groups we
see some interesting trends so the dark
blue are the uh the lighter Blue Line
rather is going to be our full-time
groups and as 22 or 2022 progressed we
actually see their activity being pretty
consistent with a little bit of a drop
towards Q4
the darker line darker blue line is
going to be rebrands and those are the
ones that started off 2022 a little bit
lower and steadily progressed through
the remainder of 2022 and ultimately
converged with the full-time groups
which is exactly what you would expect
when you think about what a what a
Rebrand group is and what they do
now what's a little bit more interesting
is when we start taking a look at
Splinter groups and ephemeral groups and
how I mentioned that a lot of times
these groups are ultimately causing some
noise for us these are consistent uh
they are there were consistent Trends
throughout pretty much all of 2022 with
respect to Splinter groups and ephemeral
groups and how they actually popped up
and went away at any given time so again
that noise makes a little bit more
difficult for us to track these
ransomware groups as they go throughout
2022 and ultimately when you break them
into individual categories you see how
they contribute to the overall
ransomware activity at any given time
so you might be thinking to yourself
well why ransomware rebrands and
ultimately it goes down into the 5Ds of
rebranding which is Dodge duck dip dive
and Dodge
in all seriousness all seriousness
though a lot of what we're doing here is
we're flying under the radar we want to
make it harder for intelligence analysts
to track we want to make it uh easier
for us to extend our operations or for
the thread actors to extend their
operations and we just ultimately or
they ultimately don't want to be caught
right and so that is the entire purpose
of rebranding
so what does this do to us well it's
another group for us to track it's
another League site disgrade there's a
whole slew of behaviors and ttps we need
to learn there's all kinds of
intelligence that ends up being fed
through this never-ending cycle
so it's ultimately harder on us right
and that's exactly what they want
so my wife actually took this picture of
me when I was preparing for this looking
at some of the case studies of
ransomware rebranding and so I really
wanted to take a look and show you guys
how effective ransomware rebranding can
be
so to begin we have all these different
groups and they all operate on different
uh different life cycles so this chart
shows you the active days are the
average days that group any one type of
group was active in 2022.
full-time groups unsurprisingly were the
most active they're operating pretty
much all year rebrands are going to be
active in the um you know a little bit
less than a full-time group but they're
starting to approach that full-time
status that's their goal they went from
probably a previous full-time group to a
Rebrand and now they're trying to
achieve that status again the Splinter
groups are usually going to be
you know Affiliates that have experience
in the game
and they're moving forward to really
achieve that long-term status and that
full-time status
but the one thing that's really
interesting here is the ephemeral groups
and those lit only lasted on average 21
days
um again this makes it difficult for us
from a CTI perspective to make sure that
we're tracking these groups we're
defining ttps behaviors and really
starting to use that to inform our risk
profiled and how we're going to use this
type of data to effectively track
ransomware and and the threats that we
face
so the first case study that I dove into
here was dark side to black matter to
Alpha so to start here we have Darkseid
that that was active for about 200 days
um then we had black matter that took
over for about 90 days and then we got
into Alpha which has been operating
basically ever since
so when you actually look at the
Timeline there's two very distinct dates
that correlate with the rebrands the
first one was the colonial pipeline
attack
the second one was a shutdown from black
matter saying they're getting pressure
from authorities so during this whole
time going from you know 2020 all the
way through 2021 and into 2023 there
have been very uh distinct points where
this particular group has found
themselves in the spotlight
and when they did that they went through
a Rebrand
now when they did this uh the first time
they actually did a Rebrand from Dark
Side to black matter at that lasted or
that Rebrand took less than 60 days
they obviously learned a little bit
because the next time they went through
a Rebrand they didn't less than 30. now
as you like basically from these numbers
you can see that the overall level of
effort is going down and the reward
definitely pays off this group was able
to extend their operations for over 400
Days and every day that Alpha is active
now moving forward it's just another day
that they've extended their operations
so from this perspective you can see how
effective it was to actually Rebrand to
a couple of different groups here
another really great example is going to
be evil core so I'm sure we've all heard
of evil Corp we've all
um you know experienced intelligence
related to evil core they started their
ransomware operations with bitpaymer and
they were active for several years
before they started to really get put on
things like sanctioned lists and and
started getting a lot of heat from you
know the intelligence Community uh and
then that's when they start going
through their rebranding process so they
went through wasted Locker Hades Phoenix
Locker payload Ben McCall locker and all
of these had a different
um period of time that they were active
but what you can see is that they got so
good at rebranding that they were able
to put out a new rebranded ransomware in
about 21 days which is consistent with
the data that we saw with some of our
ephemeral
Rebrand data from 2022.
so what's interesting about how evil
Corp did some of their operations with
was that there is some overlapping from
when they were going through different
rebrands
um as and as time went on the rebrands
became much more quick or shorter in
duration just showing again how
effective some of these operations are
now especially towards the end when we
got to McCall Locker
um they were already on the sanctions
list of U.S treasury so you couldn't
actually pay them the hope I think from
their perspective was if we can Rebrand
fast enough we can start getting our
rants more out there we can actually
receive payments before anybody realizes
that we uh that McCall Locker was a part
of the evil Corp tool said and so this
is another example where the average
Rebrand duration was about 38 days got
way shorter during the end but again we
extend they extended their operations
for over 400 Days which is huge when you
think about how much money a lot of
these ransomware groups are making at
any given time for any one Ransom and
even more when you factor in the the
double extortion aspects of this
so knowing that rebrands are a thing and
knowing that they're so effective well
what are the tips and tricks and and how
can we use these tips and tricks to make
sure that we are effective at
identifying grants more rebranding
the first thing to start with here and
this is the best example of identifying
um you know technical information and
concrete facts and evidence to identify
ransomware rebranding this was a report
by Sentinel Labs
um it's the best example that I've seen
to date of actually
confirming and factually based evidence
for identifying rebranding and so a lot
of what we're doing when we're spotting
these rebrands is how are they doing
certain things how are they doing file
and drive enumeration how are they
proceeding with encryption how are they
doing API hashing or import routines any
number of different pieces of
functionality that you would see in
ransomware if we can start to identify
things
you know in styles that individual
developers are doing that's one thing
that we can then take and Implement so
that we can identify that same type of
style in other ransomwares now for all
of you guys who who um remember the 90s
there was a movie called blank check and
that's where that little uh get or that
little meme came in at the end so one of
my favorite movies and wish that I could
do it when I was a kid but anyway
um so big thing here is just continuing
to identify ways to identify these
ransomware rebrands so one of the big
things that we can do is in-depth code
analysis so especially when we see uh
source code that's like for instance on
the right hand side we have Conti's
source code that was leaked we can
actually take some of that and we can
then identify key components of what
happened in or what's being used in that
code how it's done the style that's
associated with it and we can put that
in our Arsenal to be able to detect that
being used in other samples
on the left hand side we could use
certain tools like bindiff to look at
routines that exist in one sample but
maybe don't exist in another or they
definitely exist in both and that's how
we can start looking for that code reuse
we can start making sure that we're
tracking these things and identifying
when these types of these pieces of code
are used from sample to sample again
looking at trying to identify that in
other variants
one thing to keep in mind here is that
leak sites are code two there is HTML
code that's associated with developing
these leak sites and if we can start
identifying the similar types of code
used and leak sites that's another way
that we can we can detect
um when certain groups are going through
a Rebrand process so that's just
something to keep in mind
and so you know this is something that I
think the last talk covered really well
but I think the big thing here is as we
go through all of these different
components right we're looking at code
we're looking at leak sites let's make
sure we're making this work for us so
whether it's Yara whether it's figuring
out how to contribute to aluminum
whether that's adding signatures into
your different sandboxes or other
routines for ghidra however we're doing
this we just have to make sure that all
this information that we're Gathering
is being put to work and that's you know
one of the biggest components for how
we're going to build these long-term
capabilities to identify when rebranding
is happening
the last thing here really for for tips
and tricks is we need to start profiling
behaviors so as much as there's Behavior
there's style and how developers are
creating things and the fact that many
developers including myself are lazy and
we want to reuse code whenever we
possibly can because it's faster we just
want to make sure that we're profiling
the behaviors
so whether it's ttps in terms of initial
intrusion or post-exploitation
um you know that's something we need to
keep track of negotiation tactics one of
the things that my team does is put
active negotiations and so figuring out
what kind of negotiation tactics do
these groups use may be very helpful in
defining their their profile
um any kind of dark web identities how
they communicate
going through how they go through
rebrands you know getting into tracking
that long term
um any kind of financial behaviors or
relationships with other e-crime groups
these are all important things that we
want to add to a living threat profile
so a lot of times the tendency is
develop this profile and it's going to
serve us now and in the future but the
unfortunate reality is threat actors are
move fast they change fast and so we
need to keep up with this we need to
have a living threat profile that
develops as these threat actors develop
themselves
the one thing I want to take a step back
on here and talk about is just some of
the pitfalls and so we have to watch out
because there is an entire ecosystem
that that Services Ransom more groups
and it's it's quite large so
it's a tendency when we see something
right out of the gate to have
um you know quick attribution we want to
we want to tie that to a group we want
to say hey it was you know something we
saw is definitely locked in and we want
to do that quickly and move forward but
there is a difference between the actual
Core group of developers and some of the
Affiliates right and so there's some of
this extension where media and others
are going to want to really provide that
attribution quickly we kind of have to
take a step back especially because
ransomware as a service really
complicates things
um Outsourcing is a real thing a lot of
these threat actors want to use
um some of the the quickest and best
ways to get the functionality they need
and so when you look at something like
code reuse between lockbit 3 and black
matter clearly there's something going
on there that we need to incorporate
into our intelligence to make sure we
understand what's going on there and not
jump to a conclusion and say hey lock
bit three and black matter are the same
group
um another thing is more groups have
leaks I think Conti is a great example
of this they went through a huge leak
which probably forced most of their
Rebrand to actually occur and so their
playbooks were released their Source
quotas was released so we need to make
sure we don't have a tendency to just
step back and say hey I saw this
Playbook it's used by a different group
you know that must be Conti well we have
to we have to really put it through its
Paces here and say is that something
that's a little bit more widespread or
is it truly something that is defined by
that group
um large groups have options there's
just a lot of stuff going on with how
they operate they have a lot of
relationships of their own so really
what I'm what this means is it does make
it a lot harder for us on the blue team
side of things on the intelligence side
of things
um but this is where we have to make a
lot of this data work for us we need to
have long-term trends use our data to
really establish
um you know these rebranding activities
and so what is the point of all this
really we want to take happy hacker
and make them into sad hacker
we want to make them Rebrand so often we
want to make sure we force their hands
so often that it no longer becomes a a
very
monetizable strategy to just Rebrand so
if we can force them to have to go
through that process over and over again
eventually they're going to start losing
money and that's exactly what we're
looking to do here
and so with all of this what what do we
do now
the first thing is communicating what I
call the single source of Truth so we
have threat intelligence as part of a
bigger cyber security group or a fusion
Center or however your organization
looks at it but the biggest thing we
need to do is all of this intelligence
that's coming in all this research from
various organizations we want to make
sure that we're communicating this if
we're not communicating this in groups
like The Sock can't take any action or
Executives can't properly Define risk
then we're not doing something right
with our program and our capabilities
so when we are disseminating this
intelligence we need to focus on a
couple of key characteristics we want it
to be something that can be consumed and
we want it to be actionable if they're
not able to consume the intelligence
you're providing and they can't take any
action on it then I don't think that
you're actually providing intelligence
we want to make sure that that
intelligence is also highly
contextualized so if you're providing
something that's not relevant to your
industry or not relevant to your
organization it's likely that it's just
not relevant and able to be used by the
various teams that are going to be
benefiting from your intelligence
so again making sure that it's relevant
focusing on your industry focusing on
your organization making sure that they
also get that in a timely manner if
they're getting threat intelligence
that's a month old obviously that's not
very actionable and they're not getting
that in a way that's going to be
beneficial to the team
um another thing is is rate limiting
right so you have to understand the
context of your organization if you have
a three-person sock they're not going to
be able to consume thousands of threat
intelligence alerts or you know
thousands of their intelligence bull
bulletins you have to make sure that
you're providing a rate of intelligence
that your organization can sustain
and lastly you want to make sure that
it's easily understood
so again you know they want to in order
for it to be consumable and so that and
for them to be able to take actions on
it you need to make sure that it is
something that can be uh analyzed and
understood very quickly
so another key component of how we make
this intelligence work for us is we
incorporate our intelligence that we're
creating into threat modeling and then
when you have a threat model for the
organ or the ransomware groups that are
likely to more Target your organization
or industry vertical then you have that
informed threat hunting
um obviously there's a whole other
component here that is going to be built
into making sure that there's proactive
alerting and that was basically you know
the a lot of the message from the
previous talk but really making sure
that you're going through and informing
all the different hunts that you
possibly could as a proactive measure is
going to be extremely important
and so kind of lastly throwing throwing
everything together here one of the
biggest calls to action that I have been
focusing on with my team over the last
two years has been threat intelligent
sharing and I think that overall we do a
pretty good job of threat intelligent
sharing as an industry you know we do
get iocs out there there's a lot of
really great Twitter
um Twitter accounts that are sharing
Intelligence on a regular basis and and
providing those up-to-date ilcs and I
think that's great
but I think we could take it a step
further and I think we could share
threat profiles between groups between
individuals so that we are actually
keeping everybody up to date
I think we could share tools and
techniques whether that's a
configuration extractor for a ransomware
uh binary or it's some way of making
sure that we're tracking or or ways of
extracting other ilcs and information
from specific ransomware variants in
families
sharing that emerging Trends and and
research I think is also a really big
component of making sure that we're
staying and keeping everybody up to date
um a big thing here right is we want to
make it difficult for the threat actors
and in order for us to do this we have
to share information even better and
intelligence even better
so data sets huge you know additionally
analysis nodes there's a lot of really
complex routines that a lot of threat
actors create in their samples and
there's a lot of really brilliant people
that are analyzing these malware samples
on a regular basis and they are
extracting out the methodology and
intelligence from these samples but a
lot of times it stays within the the
organization that that analyst works for
I think there's a huge opportunity for
us to get in and start sharing these
types of notes so that when this is seen
by a different group they're able to
move fast and actually establish some of
the different indicators and and some of
the different behaviors that are being
seen by other groups
so at the end of the day you know what
I'm really going for here is share
everything I would much rather seem more
transparency between intelligence
working groups between organizations and
individuals
um and ultimately again and I've hit on
this a couple of different times we have
to make it harder for these threat
actors to go through a Rebrand they have
to make it harder for them to make
slight changes to their ransomware and
then continue operating
so really again let's just start sharing
um I'll I'll put all the call I'll throw
the call to action out there and say my
organization is ready to start sharing
more if you guys want to share more with
us please get into contact with us we
would love to do that and I hope that by
showing how valuable some of this
intelligence sharing could be that more
organizations more individuals will all
take part in providing threat
intelligence to the community
so that's what I had for today
um I want to thank you for your time and
and definitely happy to answer any
questions that you might have
[Applause]
[Music]