the session is I can't find the title
which official standards
y control systems cyber security sucks
us define leaders
thank you very much I would have nothing
against
reading here thanks for the invitation
in my previous life I was physicist
I move to control system engineering
I was doing safety systems afterwards
and
poking around the safety systems I got
him the job offer security officer
some I'm heading the security commits an
I'm usually I thought that title is why
control systems cyber security sucks
but since you are putting the 25th year
anniversary of the WWW
I'm I re maybe twice some control
systems cyber security
is big butt exciting so I would do in
the next hour 50 minutes
is is it 24 talk first to introduce
limit of Sun
doing doing a small session about excite
the physics of an ass for that
and then I will def into our concerns or
problems with operations
in terms of control systems cyber
security so this is far away from rocket
science
it is running actually run control
systems
the problems we've seen control system
which you cannot soul withstand i2
Technologies
usually what we're doing is we're
handling security issues on control
systems like we do with core
security issues IT systems and we do a
comparison between
computer centre security and control
systems cyber security and
pinpoint down to three to four points
well I'm completely fed up because I
cannot treat control systems
like a 12 2 Chron want to treat them
when they would have been
I'm
computer centers so what a sense on its
European organisation for particle
physics
I'm we're not European anymore nowadays
we are international into
our main business very simple I'm this
is the area around genealogy both
on the right hand side you see the
Geneva Airport we have some comments on
the ground the large ones 27 committed
in circumference
and what we do is we take protons
problems are Wallace all over place
we take two protons reply to put on some
clothes protons we can look at
deep back into this into time something
like 1,000,000,000 for the second
after the Big Bang and Teresa lately
said to be the conditions which were
happening at the time
we take photos of those once we got some
digital cameras and details talking like
this
you stop the photos you put the portents
into punches the punches you put into
beams
so I each of the penis 1,380 punches I'm
you put them into some kinda wynette if
you come from a big city this was
looking like the public transport no
public transport is the same thing
you stop somewhere the beginning I'm you
see it here link on
Lina to other so work today a process we
start next week in part because
with different types of tax returns for
the protons are X-rated here
first yes second Kia that Kia fourth
gear
and once you for picking up to possibly
thing to something larger which the
Large Hadron Collider
this the 27 commit along accelerator
which
which is hosting the beams in the center
of this push to
so you can see the two beams p.m. so
marked in blue and red but usually they
don't have any color
their separate to the size of the beam
is as big a spin on the one euro coin
I'm saw him I don't have a nervous in
New York on it so I put a picture here
the problem with the beams there is
something that's why we need to have
lots not
safety systems local control systems the
energy of the bean
is Eklund eighty kilograms of TNT this
segment to the energy of a Boeing 747
fully loaded when it's starting
but all been as a size 0 for millimeters
all the size of Spain
this beam is getting lost with on our
actuator we destroy the accelerator
be destroyed much im because it's like a
lady like a lady says
saber of Star Wars cutting open a lax
writer
and then the beam is more less about
breaking into the time three-time
national safety systems control systems
which are monitoring the puppy was
exactly was staying with
to be inside the machine but not outside
for taking the pictures we have to come
across this one of the digit cameras
which just know what
from surface to air to the cabin level
which 1i meters underground
this another one you can see one of my
colleague standing on the platform
just give you an idea of the size the
length of the scum rose 43 meters
by me just 26 meters and to his mother
picture you can see where the two beams
are supposed to go
here the beams are led in 1 p.m. type
because we have to establish the
collisions
in the center of the digital camera once
the the interesting part
it's like in the 5500 I'm
it's pouring into the collisions so
collisions are looking like this
this when a ship collision we can
produce something like forty million
conditions a second which means that the
cameras are taking
forty million pictures the second this
is one of the pictures
and this another picture it's like like
a car accident
just take it as a car accident you can
now take everything here
can nope lead everything back and figure
out what happened at the time of the
collision
so what weather conditions when the
collision were happening and this gives
you more or less the simulation
what happened at the Big Bang time 30
million million and $30 billion years
ago as a set we taking something like go
forty million pick just a second we
process them know another computer
center but which is not big enough to
stall the data
so the data is distributed over some
like 150 computer centers worldwide
the data rates were taking per year some
like 20 petabyte 225 petabytes the raw
data rate in the collision
is something like one picked up by per
second which you cannot store so we have
to be selectively not taking every photo
will be taking every $1 million 422 to
start this week so in the end
and this is processed and the processor
properly in a good physicist
at any given nobel prize which was about
to air have
to Peter hates his colleague in 2012
just look at this
running XO regis running experiments
needs lots and lots of control systems
here the list of control so I won't go
into the details but we need to compose
electricity for progenics for data
taking so long
salsa pashley control systems being
developed it so I'm
mostly their control system which just
brought ministry
because in the end of his one is no
different than the producing cars
reproducing
pictures of collisions of protons and we
said this to physicist
so here the control system running this
is a it's a control system for
energy distribution we gotta control
says for gas distribution control
systems
for micro Genix pumping BIOS and control
system for safety
your control system for access control
so you wanna go in
you need to have go to work with certain
sauce and to get access to the exciter
this requires an iris scan of your I
just make sure that you are you
and we could control rooms with all the
Synaptics all the panels
to see
the plenty of control system sets on and
was pissing me off
when we started investigating of control
system was that the security footprint
of those control systems
when on existing when I started doing
safety systems
I was able to predict my safety system
the safety system you can take that one
is the optimum my safety system
was the availability was there like you
that the safety system is failing
so I was making those cake nation but I
was able to finish my conclusion because
all the control system
I was calculating on at all meeting at
Port and it was awesome question what
does somebody like
you are hacking into my control system
and this was 2004 was able to answer
this question to me
so I was given the mandate to
investigate people we did some some some
more testing and every system attested
every commercial system attested was
showing some floors
this when I started thinking that
control systems have secured is
completely
vacant exciting welcome picking stocks
so why should you worry
I don't know I've collected the a couple
of snapshots from from the media
then let's not submit snapshot some of
them are true some of them might not be
true
icon judge I know at least that one is
completely untrue which is the one which
is appearing aa
Wallace now have justifies the face
nearly seaside
and came close to switching off the year
the particle detector
and this was far from the truth but damn
somebody what if I single-page
but if you look at this I think the
basic questions which were facing is
we have a problem do you think we have a
problem
so what nobody is carrying
what I see is lots lots of talk about
control systems cyber security
I see that some Big Ben this acting
motor control system I'm buying
on small vendors and every time looking
at the control system
I see the security footprint of those
small control systems
a completely non existing what I mean is
very simple
you control system like those too the
first one is a doozy meter reader
this does it is a small monitoring
device which you carry on your body
when you go into the panel's and every
month have to check under the box you
put those meat into the box
and it's freezing your your monthly does
32 the penetration testing on this
device
action wasn't really penetration testing
because of the thirty seconds the
confession testing was done
what I'm doing with my team is
we get a small red team go team exercise
from
if somebody might he managed to get the
root password of the device
I only eaten a bottle of wine someone
managed to end since 2000 and up on the
device
I own the crate of wine why and not just
to prove that you can install something
completely different on the five
which you shouldn't be able to in the
first case I lost a bottle of wine
the guy who tested the device was more
or less than dumping the call ok in the
device
extracting the cord on where TFTP
analyst analyzing the TFTP called
company found the root password
for the 10 access this was thirty
seconds of course you spoke to the
vendor
and then the promise to fix this the
second advising on trusting the supposed
supply which museum thousands of those
power supplies
for control systems you can see on the
back
therefore you finna ports one actually
is a really thin a port to connect this
one
and you do not have service attack for
70 seconds just from them
just sending random garbage to the
Ethernet port the device is dead
dead in terms of you cannot control it
anymore you still have the power
sister left with wats nine boys three
boys months he was and so on
but you cannot control the piney more go
anyway how to reset the device
is you pull the plug can you think a
long it takes to not mine
to run around Sun side to kill the plug
1000 defies
in case something like that is happening
this we're taking a fortune of time
so what we've seen is that the control
system has been tested
they forcing use cases controlling
something
guaranteeing the safety or something but
once you look a little bit different on
the devices with easy to woods and this
is not something of a sophisticated
stuff
i've seen earlier today this is
something very very plain no ending
fruits
basic stuff the devices start to failing
security at least from my perspective
on the controls i've seen is not
integral part
of the overall sometimes they do
something through security
like in some protocols that the vendors
in principle
saying the the the communications
encrypt it but it looks
deeper in you figure other this just
lived of shape is shifting of XIII ski
coat
three test and control systems we took
our control systems we did something
very simple
just took Nessus and the five necessary
to control system
this is not rocket science everybody if
you guys can do but if you see the
outcome
this is just shocking devices will you
send a pic is saying I'm IP version 5 in
the devices starting blinking red and
yellow
retirement security anymore we come
under bust this
resilience this is completely insane
three-test levi's a 17 percent of the
device 2:53 bus have been tested in 2000
and
and seven 17 devices were completely
staining
which means that they are you sending up
actually Christian Christmas tree attack
or
i Commission 5 whatever's and device is
dead
the control processes to pumping you
still able to control something
but all the network on occasion have
seized the LED's a blinking red or
yellow
network on occasion is dead which means
now the process cannot talk
anymore the other processes into
communications completely seized
so I have to go around and we should all
those devices it'll appear sees
embedded devices how to use and so on
fifty percent of the devices didn't pay
completely but they failed somehow
devices running 10 added you send them
at ten a password of
4000 characters buffer overflow 10 it is
dead
same with the web server web server you
a lot 8,000 characters
web servers dead is this supposed to be
like this
I have my doubts but I'm looking forward
is why don't we have a certification
scheme for those devices
why can't nobody came up with a list of
to its
easy to woods write them on the paper
and saying you have to test this year on
this
this tool this to invest with this too
if the outcome here
is a the device is fine if the outcome
is be the revised is
flawed just a stuffed with something
very basic
use necessary from its but whatever as I
don't care but the list
they also the vacation schemes in the
word which you can buy you can buy in
and you can certify devices for fortune
of money but most other than that I'm
talking to
they don't have a fortune of money so I
would like to give them a small
procedure recipe
run this tour on that tour and that went
if the outcome is ABCD
your devices at least for that moment
for this particular recipe
at that particular date considered to be
robust resilient enough
and the good thing is the vendor can do
the test
but I can also the test at home so if
he's telling me my device passed the
test I can verify
whether he's telling the truth or not
all I can give the test to a third party
and third party can make money like a
nice for 9000 certification
running the same test but unfortunately
is not existing
there is no open public security
certification get
I'm looking forward there lots lots of
people thinking on cool big scale test
stands
which has another use case was also good
but I'm still looking at the basics
defense in depth is starting with the
fundamentals and fundamentals are
robust devices and what I see is the
device
i'm looking at I'm not robust they
completely shocking if you just say hey
I'm I P bush in five the device is going
into the knees
and this is not something we should
happen we can talk about lost
I i think is the US you can be happy
that there's one law if I'm not mistaken
and you're a blast to them negotiating
for the next twenty years on the law's
I'm I feel that that too many guidelines
there's a couple for your guidance for
print them out I think it's able to meet
this
and i Justi 21 guidelines so please do
not produce more guidelines I'm done
and then there's an unwillingness to
share incidents this is something which
is not moving
but I still if I talk to them that we
communicated I was on a bill it is to
some other vendors
I'm they say apps but don't tell anybody
because they fear
it's fun because they fear that
somebody edge by the misuse the
inability for something so responsible
disclosure
is not existing this we on it was nice
to have a computer center
computers and I got a computer center
10007 I can run penetration testing up
and down as long as I want to
I do not pay my sisters my face systems
might fail but there are a ton
some other system a takeover and we got
decades of experience knowledge
in terms of security so what we're doing
now also the control system Sat Sun
you're scanning them for taking the
Burnaby joining
and maps comes again the control system
on our life in operation systems
sometimes some other assistance might
fail but if the system failed to detect
that they feared
we can replace them and make the whole
overall system more resilient and
before my big question is
why do I have to be a the costs of
all this what you have to do due
diligence
and set up the when this which shipping
insecure applications
on devices question mark hope this
we can keep for later for discussion but
interests and opinions
at the moment is something what has been
said this morning that religion and this
software
at the moment all the costs of me so I
have to do defense and DEP
I have to do the one going to scanning
and I have to bother when the device
is not robust so I have to say to the
vendor your device not robust
what is your new new product can i buy
that I cannot just return and saying
not secure enough I give it back the
next problem I'm facing with the
patching
this is a screenshot of an FTP I wake up
screaming
where somebody managed to hack into 300
devices which occur
to office network saying that though
he's alone and that is offering the 6
gigabytes of hard disk around
if you look deeper difficult this is not
a computer
this is an oscilloscope if you haven't
seen on a Cisco been also scored
nowadays
to buy one from the crowd Tektronix HP
and whatever also PCs
with some dedicated hardware lots of
knobs but them see you can't even move
where you see the blue screen of death
if you move into the connie has to the
stop button
our engineers at that moment in time did
know that they were running Windows XP
devices
so nothing got that how many device to
run Windows XP and you don't even know
about this we got a couple of us let's
go to get several dozens of a Cisco to
running Windows XP know it is also in
the seven
and we have a problem because now they
have to be patched here we didn't even
know all the engineers didn't know that
they can patch the device
so I'm the usual argument why you can
approach it
is you need to make compliance testing
if you all tell you control system which
has been sold to you by your vendor
then you lose any guarantees any any
certification anything as you have to
reset it to his
recertifying control system if your
safety system
me too I keep you current is Uni reaches
you need to recertify you safety system
that it's still safe enough that he can
run it but this was only for a very
small fraction of
control systems for scope I don't care
the school doesn't need to recertify I'm
thinking of the school has a PC with
some dedicated software
and some dedicated mother and how to
report and then the next from
approaching is there a row
maintenance windows you cannot just
patch a control system
when your production site and you have
to wait for cap when your maintenance
maintenance mode single clue how blue is
done glue is done in the big celinda
as long as the slimmest turning you glue
is staying fluid
if the slimness stopping you do is
heartening out and you can for
four-way the also into know you think
the whole thing is is no
driven by a small Windows PC when do you
think can reap with the Windows PC dual
to you did
have questioned on because you use your
product
and the same thing is happening it's
under control systems which %uh slow
gas distribution kooning imagination
water distribution
also snow systems if you shut down our
control part
Linux server reboot and Observer
Reporter Windows Server
you can easily to began other systems
which are much more critical Japan
critical that you report them
you lose your process you have to wait
until you get the maintenance period we
have every six
Mundus every six weeks making period we
can apply patches
and I we faced with local legacy a
better devices
which you cannot patch because there's
nothing to patching more nobody provide
to the most most recent
I upgrades so now you have to fence
around it apply your defense and up
but also only arguments more this coming
by the vendors
the main argument I'm facing is my
control suspension is appearing to break
it defies which cost than $100 million
1000 Swiss francs do you dare think
often use call you by body in your car
50,000 box and now the van is saying yes
you can apply know this patch but if the
patch is failing
the responsibility and the bed like just
a few
the same thing here such an oscilloscope
you can easily cost 100,000 Swiss francs
dollars snow my control suspension is a
very reluctant to apply a patch because
I'm
most of the cases the patches can be
applied if it's paving
and then he has a 10 thousand doughnut
break sitting in his lap
who is taking all liability was taking
the cost
is the security team because I'm forcing
into patch is at him and he's not taking
the
the responsibility or should I go back
to the bend and ask the vendor
whether he can fix the problem at the
moment you really doing this this and
this exercise
because we have a couple of Windows XP
devices and would like to upgrade them
when is excused absence I have two would
win the seven the cost up to devise a
bit between 3,000 and 10,000 Swiss
francs
just upgrading from Windows XP to
Windows 7 completely insane
and much less less expensive than buying
new device if another computer center
this is completely different when hubby
came out it took me 20 to get some like
two hours
to catch all the service facing the
Internet actually not me but the guys
will maintain the computer center
two hours
to fix everything else 24 hours
if I need to reinstall the cast of 7,000
notes
48 hours with grace periods to tell the
physicist
that the calculations jobs a kid and
rebooting the service
I can to foster but then we will use
efficiency because they're killing
actually analyzes job so the physicist
we don't want don't want to kill them
less jobs
to you what you do is to announce that
the so the custom we go down
you stop accusing nobody can submit new
calculation jumps into the computer
center
and the new aid into the QB calculations
of the dropping out which is usually
between 24-48 hours
if you do the idea after 12 hours to
kill the jobs and then you re reboot
possible we had times where we Reese
reinstalling 7,000 notes a quickie
because someone ability which came out a
couple months before Andrew ensure will
be completely sick where we were
completely secure on the computer center
why can we do this
because the computer center we have a
full configuration management
in the computer center we have suffered
enough life cycles get regression
testing
we get nightly builds we virtualization
and you for redundancy and we try to
keep the numbers have sex exceptions the
computers and as low as
as possible every exception is a killer
this at least what I love my job a
security officer
everything was homogeneous heterogeneous
was when maintain centrally
I can easily generate I can easily
handle but then taking all the small
exhibition
a.m. exceptions here and there they're
costing me my time
20 trying now to trying to run or
control systems
excellent to the computer center having
something about cited behind
making Russian testing making nightly
builds and trying to reinstall the
service also a regular basis
just to show that we can but still a
long way
and I things getting worse
with an Internet of Things thinking of
the fridge
think my call
my wii my television mice might be to
the smoke sensor and everything as I got
my house
now in the future everything is running
with some firmware everything is
vulnerable because by default
it is wrong to how do you do with the
patching we want to patch
a replacement television every every six
months because I am
there's something more secure coming out
there's another discussion
discussion I don't have a question and I
don't have an answer to this one but I
believe patching must be prompt
and agile for control system the same
thing must hold
to see some other control systems
this that the top picture this is a
a.m. on the computer I think this is a
cop comes
a system and you can see on the screen
the ex so you can get snow which
operating system it's running
we'll all this is a a big laser cutter
which is running Windows XP if you could
zoom into the screen can see this stuff
but not Windows XP both devices cost you
1 million
Swiss franc savalas we depend on both
devices
most devices are all what from external
company
so those external companies like to
service the devices
for servicing the devices they don't
want to come in because coming in means
they have to travel to San
which might take them 24 hours than they
need to do the repairs
many to move up again for 24 hours so
this will cost a fortune
they are asking for remote access so
somebody know of
mean why do your control says need to
have remote access
this is expected argument why suppliers
need a back seat to the devices
and then they don't have even one
solution every supply has its own
solution
TeamViewer nephew were BP and then
VMC VMC oh SH Citrix whatever
as than the sis's committee for
passwords and
undocumented effect also and they don't
have integrated power
macy s access control on those devices
just a pain
who s thing i've seen
I don't even know whether I should laugh
or not is some other control systems
require
to have a license at startup and the
option given to us
by the software vendor was
you need to contact well home station
someone the US Sony just admission a
line of sight between my control systems
behind some various talking directly to
a server somewhere in the US
just for activating my control system
this doesn't feel right at all
a computer center
yes oh computer centers open because
it's serving a worldwide community
but then we get all the nitty-gritty of
the pieces of
access control single sign-on it up
Active Directory multi-factor
authentication certificates
cameras and there were even looking at
the Federation
future so know if you think of
the ad Cup the ACA is amiss I think even
if I was a myth nowadays
and it's hard to maintain I think we
should strive to having
more robust is more resilience each of
the levels in particular the control
system
I'm not completely sure that we have
this today I'm not in computer sure
well we have this next five years the
last
think I would like to discuss
is education if you look at the CV's of
my students and getting students are
getting a pic phone every year
of some %uh students have taken students
working at certain something 400 to 500
students
also the kids tho so I kids which I'll
program issues in the future
but if you look at the CBS I'm wondering
whether security is taught in the city
if you look at them they got a Bachelor
good got a Bachelor bachelor in computer
science
so they learned about databases
operating system programming setting up
a web server
brilliant this is what a computer CA
computer engineer supposed to do
but many of the security and if you go
out no security is not part of my
bachelor
security I do went to the master this
again doesn't feel right
I think security must be more embedded
in the overall going to have no
profanity
professionalism on that play a direct
control system engineering
most in the control suspension is i
seein look in this EP
they believe they have ideas about it.
technologies
but this not part of their curriculum
they don't learn computer engineering
they learn control system engineering so
they don't know actually how to set up a
network
but they train themselves when they on
the job they don't know how to patching
so they just %uh forget about
watching man they'd doing reinvention of
the
of something I T instead they should
embrace it. technologies
so all control system outage from the
design are using
GetJar all the standard IT technologies
just to make it more homogeneous
what you trying is he trying to bring
together the controls when that he would
just having the same paradigm from both
sides but is it a lot of time because
if you do with people changing minds of
people is very very hard
if you want to convince somebody I just
a suggest to you this book
who moved my cheese it's about the
reluctance of
Shulman's for change how quick are you
changing how quickly can you move from
one city to another
how quickly can you move your job the
young nothing easy at all do you getting
the more resistant to all I got some
people in particular physicist was to
programming Kobal
pasquale a basic because this is what
they did when they were young
nowadays they're not forced to move to
some more modern tech nerd
programming languages so they don't do
sushi again we are
why security
still separated from maintainability
functionality usability and a visibility
why do have a security conference I've
never seen availability conference
of functionality conference this is
something which comes out too much when
you write your software
it has some perchance have to forfeit
some functions
has to be usable and anything about
maintainability
know is carrying what secured with the
Securities just have cost factor
nothing this is utterly wrong we need to
change that we need to talk to your kids
need to talk to our youngsters we need
to talk to education
to get the security
much much early n you should I say isn't
about swimming
are you able to swim hussein to swim why
because you're your parents taught you
for your safety do you think of swimming
or did you think of safety when you're
swimming
course you don't we should teach the
same thing into in terms of security
I so that people have to tell what a
phishing email is but they should do
this automatically
the change of mind summers awesome for
your password fishing don't ignore the
ignoring just deleted
the something up to teach people so to
wrap up
I don't need any more stunned that
if you working on this time a body on
security
best honestly gas companies test and
that's the petroleum companies in
chemical area
the standouts in the oil company in
Europe and the oil companies
in Germany they are all companies in the
US three different standards
electricity lots not just on electricity
in the US
and Germany and the Netherlands
and speed and in the region and do you
think they all translations of the same
some not know they are not they all add
up to the country
I wonder why too many stomach to stop
that one
retirement defense in depth of course
between defense and DEP
yes we do that for segregation to
depiction making mechanisms
we doing from patching where we can even
oscilloscopes yes we're patching also
scope
me pension promptly and so far I haven't
picked one
still waiting for that day maybe a iris
I'm before but still of foundations of
flawed
I'd buy devices which cannot be secured
i buy devices which are not robust
and I think this is something we have to
change we need to have an edge over
ability mitigation life cycle I would
like to be able to patch
any device I have as quickly as possible
or do you think you will have it
touched you stay for your house thing on
a patch to stay nowadays Patch Tuesday
ZZ
its automatic on my Windows PC here
maybe I'm on one of the few was running
Windows here
but later pictures to have to go around
my house
update the Wii update my Apple TV
update my smart meter go out for the car
then the fridge my nice espresso machine
so I'm busy the whole Tuesday afternoon
pension money buys you know of no I'm
pissed off at my Apple TV
every time I'm using my f2f a TV very
rarely every time I'm using it
its saying there's a new download for
you available to be won in Seoul and now
no I don't want to I would like to have
happened in the background but it's not
so do you want to do this no I think we
need to be much more agile
I like to see something which is more
robust weekend apply the patch is
automatically
I don't wanna run run around every
Wednesday and every Tuesday a month
and patching all my devices and the
device and getting few other guys are
getting more certification event
and devices this is what I'm looking for
the recipe of some real security experts
who can tell me you run those free tools
those tend to lose
in the default configuration they all
open source to what you just download
them
you should imaging device and if it's
always showing green
then your device is reasonably secure
I'm not saying I'm asking for indep
security we're talking about robustness
resilience
something at the basic level and as long
as my device obtaining necessary
I don't need a penetration testing once
missus is fine
and all the other test three to a fine
then we can look at that penetration
testing goalkeeper
but as I'm a device to fail I don't need
to have more but someone needs to come
up with a list
this this I come to this but maybe
someone you guys can do this come up
with a list of testing and saying okay
you run those test here
should this against devise and if
everything is fine you can claim it as
your vices
resilient enough that it can be a put
out into the field
IT technology is not bad
still they are not so to control systems
with believe they have to reinvent the
wheel
and I think this is something we have to
also choose to change at least with us
our development now is using the same
technologies we using for the computer
center
maintain your computer center using
puppet gets
forman some other twists we doing the
same towards me now using
for control systems suffered development
Atlassian
gyro again kit using the same to us now
for control systems having nightly
builds a bolus of that making aggression
test looking what with the changes
to the changes have some impact on
safety up to am
on safety applications we can run
security scanners in parallel
static code analyzed on the softer to
figure out is the control software
recently secured his to the stand above
our secure study called elisa's
and so on but this something which you
where we needed to make the step
forward at all and developers accepting
this we don't a few developers
we talk about Sonic Free onto for
developers just doing development of
control systems
and last but not least
swimming and security I think we have to
go back to our universities in C
whether the teaching of security is
whether nicely embedded
into the over curriculum is this done at
the right time
is this time too early too late do want
to have security courses at all I do
want to have the security course
embedded which each of the different
topics I don't know
and i think is open for discussion so if
you want to see more about certain this
a film called angels and demons
five minutes I do they are donated to us
if you're younger this also for Muppets
you have been invited to come to certain
we have for public tours
not anymore on the ground because we're
not shutting down excited to restart it
but there
a lot of us it honors which you can have
a look at if you want to see your
computer center
I'm just go on Google Maps draw the
small me think on Google Maps on to the
onto the I'm onto the computer center
and you can we were on the computer
center to have a look inside to
for those ones want to be challenged we
have hidden some thanks 30 small little
many fix the computer center
if you find the more you get a small
them a small gift from me maybe a
t-shirt with a Lagrangian like
like that thank you very much Christians
will
yeah
let me first so should think
no we just meeting thing publication to
have
so so the question is what do you think
about nuclear reactors in the security
of the cybersecurity erectus
this what is your question legacy liza
I'm not coming out on the pier what I
know it is from the nuclei
from energy companies which are running
nuclear devices the EA and again and so
on I think they doing a vast
effort in securing the devices into
having the same safety levers
in cyber security than they have in nama
safety so I think they doing good but
I'm an expert in give you the right
answer more questions
ok
I get your point to the point she's
making is that
not so ben is asking for input house
which how to secure the devices
and I think we limit on what
generalizing here
their vendors which are very proactive
and they doing very good in protecting
the devices and
and trying to talk to the community the
other vendors
who were completely ignorant so I'm the
truth somewhere between yes
copyright I'm sorry
so
follow control systems and Prince movie
we've made an assessment is control
system has made its assessment their
control systems
other the question is what is the
consequence
when when we doing the patching is there
any risk to the to the patching
so we with them unless there's some
systems like the the drill machines all
the laser cutters
well I don't care so they can patch
anytime the worst thing that can happen
is
that the laser cut us down for 48 hours
because have to get somebody from the
support in
from the home country to make a repair
we don't care for the systems which are
sensitive
which you can I rebooted running times
we shot the men during the maintenance
window switches every six weeks
and then we do the patching every six
week or even longer we get some systems
which have been patched for
four-year because those just need to be
up all time and then we offense the
systems and
and put all the bets missus round two to
make sure that them if something's
happening we get there
we get early warning in any case for the
control systems we have
at these what we can say is if the
country if the servers are going down
Windows PCs are going down
we bring the machine will bring the beam
into a safe state which means that damn
if you think of as a teacher up to TNT
there are exit methods to attack serb
this eighty kilograms in T&T
once one system is down the eighty
cubans can t is
the smallest exited and then it's the
same state
I don't have the statistic on this so
I'm are shown some of the the media
articles I'm reading
arm give 24 don't know that the
media is giving more attention to those
both both from abilities in both attacks
or they might increase automatically
because the media coverage
I can verify whether everything what has
been written that is true or not
I have my doubts concerning certain at
the moment we don't see any big change
in the in the tracks in the threats
narita Sun
so I'm p.m. for example so far not seen
any dedicated
attack against the Red Sea oil too well
more questions
some that breast at this
this would be something like you like
your like it like a bad case scenario
if a device infected study infecting
other devices
and Prince ok
0 not the chance to turn off to get
always the chance to turn off
so in the worst case we turn off but
then we lose being time which means that
the economics writers
in the end the costs are controllable so
then that case would just shut down
reinstall main thing is Asian than the
McKean
but we had cases where on the other side
for the experiments you know the the
digital cameras
we had once an experiment in 2007 which
was compromised and that system we did
not
shut down because ap look at some if you
if your small experiment with us on like
fifty people you been up to experiment
you getting the beam you get two weeks
have been time
which means you're just two weeks lot we
can you can can get collisions
and I'm fortune would happen that case
was the device was compromised three
days within this
to ease up in time shutting it down at
that very moment would have been
that the experiment is is done for the
year no data
to come to this what we were doing in
that case we did three hours forensic
and looking what happened
the defense the server with a complete a
compromise server running for another
two weeks
at Sun out to let them finish the the
day to take enough to HBO
we shut it down should it's a triage
you have to see but this is everybody is
doing this if your computer centers
compromise I think nobody is shutting
down computers and some compromise for
to try to figure out
how it happened what happened and
whether it's worth it shutting down a
way would be to mitigate it differently
questions
so the question is without a concrete
frets now are you
how can you justify cost icon some
principal
but why should I what why should I
justify cost for security
I'm not justifying cost for
functionality or usability
maintainability
I'm not justifying cost availability so
I'm
in that case security is again it's one
of the IT things its ending with a I T Y
so I'm
it should be treated like the other ones
and Prince movie got to get a risk
assessment
3 know well we have to concentrate
because I can invest in any corner
to do security better three no more or
less from assessments where we need to
invest more
and do what we can deliver if I am save
this location data plan
you like poking into my loans aren't you
the question is do we have a Q+A
environment for control systems
I'm the elite she is a prototype there's
only one awaits you in word and then
know for that we don't have a second one
so most control systems
have test call us test that's where you
do the
this offer the moment on in the first
for situations but in this at a certain
level you need to move to the real
device because the interaction between
tax rate is
and the controls in the control group a
quite complex
and this we can only do it with having
the real gnashing life
sometimes even with having p.m. in the
machine but this is then
way restricted development can be done
so we get a balance on this one
I'm it's not the most optimal balance
we're trying to move this
more to the test and some far away from
the exciter moment
yes get a Q+A to a certain extent and
then we know D to go live it's a little
different than than
non-production times where they have a a
full-blown test them for everything
and then they can rule out into the
plant recap
depends on the system some sis some some
citizens are very independent of being
and independent commission they can do
all the testing for some effect
if you look at investor controlled
crowds and excluding ventilation
electricity
those devices i I'm stunned out
industrial installations which you find
everywhere else
they had developed completely offline on
test stands and then they rode out and a
few
if you come closer to operations affects
writer
the more you come to dedicated hardware
dedicated software and this is where
your shift is then going more towards
the x-ray to
but there's still some some from area
where we can work on
and went to work on questions
from governments I think I'm not dead
but to that question I will not answer
this question
at the moment the government's I'm
investing lots of money into security
but I don't see whether this money is
really giving products which are useful
for at least for us
from but no most on that please just
yeah
to do have control system which which we
decided to cross reason not to patch
them
and principal not catching because of
cost them a patch or not
not be able to a two things some if you
can patch
I'm there's an there's and there's a
there's a paradigm which means should
must patch said woman me too need to
patch unusually
we're following standard evolution so
movie when XP to seven
moving from redheads 6 threat at seven
right at five to six
and this is the the break point we have
to up in any case I'm
we have a very few systems which are not
patched
but although since I like the the
cad/cam systems which I'm principal
I don't care yeah if if this cap comes
as shown they all the
on the laser cut they getting infected
so what
they getting fact that they're not
sitting on our control stepper they
actually sitting in my office networks
so they're sitting somewhere where they
don't harm and down one of its network
they getting infected
just reinstalling from scratch the
critic once for operations we try to
patch as soon as we can
because time he is always them its
definition
do we do assessment of well of the
system's I think
this when we do that in principle every
device we getting in
we're trying to penetration test so this
interesting tried to it to get an idea
how secure how the device setup and then
key for my work is in mint Oreos
every device connected to our networks
is registered in the database so I know
every device non-network
I know every account into every web page
I we're now working on dependency secure
control system
control system engineers a supposed to
understand the dependency for control
system
on other control systems but also on on
the underlying technologies
city controller serving NTP you need to
have SACP meaning to the pilots ever
somewhere local database
add up Active Directory may be based on
campus I mean servicing a chance on so
this all things which we know building
up and then
no I think I benefit just on the other
side
welcome thing of the past there was
never a team doing control system that
works
and I was not routine doing IT networks
know we doing that one team was doing on
that working at San
tweeting for competence of them to do
with network connectivity itself
for control systems and for the computer
center in the pasta we always discussion
about
availability and reaction time bandwidth
and throughput and so on
but now it's the same the same for
databases we don't have it and gave him
a standing offer the control sector the
databases and so on
provided by the IT department with
database administrators who know what
they're doing
so they're doing the patching up the
databases in soon
with the control system experts are not
necessarily very quickly
a tricky enough that it's for fits my
needs and we can operate X-rated
operating system
for the control system operating system
no coming from the IT department so this
is where they are to be published
jumping in
we try to move everything away from the
control systems which
I'm not gene control systems operating
system but I T
webservice it. mating IT networking I T
wireless communication I T
and so on this on a move toward trying
to move with norm want to the IT
department
Jarrad get all the tools at the moment
the controls people are running their
own jar and get instances but I hope
that in the future
we cannot quite this virtualization this
was a recent separate done
lots of controls development is done on
virtualized a.m.
out where and virtualization custer's
maintained by the IT department
this this happened 10 years ago when the
country if you look at the control
system itself
the time when the vendors move to the
Windows platform and using TCP IP
instead of more puzzle pro people so
whatever its
this was the time with a threat some
ability to treat them so I think than
you won't let you never make the step
back you never
fix this again and move back to profit
bus I think the
the IT technologies have also the
benefits something we just have to get
the security now properly integrated
and this is a big step
I come to the congress of the security
team my security meeting with all types
of security incidents at Sun
control system is just a part of this
but again you got a computer center
is a control system failing all the main
so I'm home page
web server fading what is more
detrimental to the organization
know you do a risk assessment can do
some balancing and so you can pick out
but in the end I'm its its Melissa same
thing
so those groups are physicist
they can do the analyze this the freedom
of academia which efforts and some
control systems are not written in power
impasse guy fucking a basic that we're
talking about the analyzes jobs
to take the collision pictures mentoring
them lies on top of this this their
freedom
they can use language in honestly this
software is not even security critical
because
what with a list analyzes and then that
we get something which they don't want
to get so
this is not critical for the big project
the control systems
there are environments where the people
of also program in C C++
spoke on Java and then you can have the
softer than life cycle on top of this
second we got
do we have control system which of front
those were you asking I we doing again
and again life cycles on all devices
with now running another
life cycle every devices has registered
reviewing regulary whether devices 11
owner who is actually it's on
was taking responsibility I'm very based
on my side I got
for everything I can see I would like to
live sighting device working on
for web pages you leave Sun your web
pages I either given to you supervise or
deleted
you leave said on your account is
getting blocked you made to delete it
and to date has gone after a certain
time period
you leave some to revise the to be
propagated to your supervisor
& Sohn file an opening for a lifesaver
for pie what will pick you ask for pie
when opening
we do some initial testing you get your
opening and every month we looking
whether they're traffic to your device
and whether you still have an HTTP
Server whatever you ask for well that's
a service listening on the part
if not we close this I think inventories
and file
and and life cycles are the most
important things for me running security
operations
Andrew ok
have to find somebody taking
responsibility
so I'm this something the concert which
I didn't introduce here
but them I am NOT the person responsible
for security it's on
we have delegated security to everybody
who is running
system so if you are control control
system expert you and
in first instance responsible for the
security of your control system
and we are here as a security measure
facilitating in a blur
to get the security right with the IT
department was giving him
you the all the 2022 running a database
give the database that can be poppin you
do need to take care about orkut and
patching whatever's
often systems we try to identify them as
quickly as possible
and then this happened to somebody who
can take responsibility
or weaken the system's minutes
so how do you motivate manage
management to pray to invest in sink
into security I think the best
in center for management in security is
from time to time a small security
incident
this is what's the most the most
brilliant think
yes something like hockey brilliant I
love top
I'm sorry I shouldn't say this and you
guys should write that up
but white why did allow Hopley a
it was tricky public public sized it has
sufficient impact in the media stand by
management learned about this and many
other people it's and learned about this
it was very easy to patch and fix apart
from some some
devices where we still waiting for the
patches from the Big Bend us but that
motor things to fix tricky
and I use this to change all the
possible turn because I was 100 percent
sure that we didn't think anything
I'm pretty sure that by nineteen I
personally didn't think anything but
still
change your passwords is also then in
fostering the
the awareness of management so this is
what working fine comparison between to
lay into a B
the proteases operations at Sun so I'm
first
protease safe operation not harming
anybody
not harming the environment not
destroying the traitor the second thing
is operation itself
and then come security the
on the question
every time we find something we me talk
to the vendors
try to explain why we think it's up to
me how they've implement this
nope
I'm we had some some information
exchange between governments
I'm which is called the US cuz European
has got a control system information
exchange
without big no vendors but they're big
utilities and governments were present
I'm but we have never been this on on
on the body we talking directly with one
big spenders very good one so I'm big
ben is now a days they have sets
to talk to the surgical and storage to
the search and they say oh that's not
good
we'll fix it and they will notify you so
I we can improve I think they can
improve on that to have
better disco just like a I'm
smaller than this the problem is they
don't even understand what you say
because they just they bought the TCP IP
stack from somebody
and then they just using the TCP IP
stack and if you tell them that there's
a buffer overflow they just say yes but
it's a
its library from outside so we come to
anything so they had to learn more
difficult and again then
depends on how critical is the
application if you look at the does a
meter reader
if you can have the password or not this
is not leaking any sensitive information
this is
personal data indicates it's not
critical so that we would prompt them
reset fix it and I think a two years
later they came up with something which
was more robust
if relief yeah if you wanna come to
discuss we can go outside