join us for the last session of the day
and we talked a little bit touchy point
most of the author and media with once
the appointees my large companies the
same point very very communist rule very
easy to set up its notoriously difficult
to contact you directly very complex and
it has a whole bunch of functionality to
do so alone can go wrong when I love you
go wrong with talking about things like
closer to document which is really what
you want about who I am on current deals
for company calls since both Pretoria be
doing it for three years now I think any
questions about sports and or something
you don't like about it
firing you gonna go into too much detail
of what she went to use just because the
fact that most of you guys have used it
at some points in 2001
latest version is 2013 sides come
through quite a few generations of the
box office going to be really seen you
want for 2016 next couple of months but
on the internet the majority what you
see is points 2010 so what I did was a
basic human needs and make mine shape
twenty students on AWS Amazon and stuff
and I'm going to be doing it's basically
been smiling since breaking the law when
you get up I think about my setup in
about 15 minutes reading minimal
interaction
can be implemented without story of high
to low and basically it's really
difficult 16 to make sure that you lost
on missions and that's something that
really can be coming back to lots in the
beginning was making mainly used to
internal environments
being black jeans and document
management personal power flow
management business intelligence and
more recently the whole web content
management
inside a whole bunch of the focus on
just one from my perspective and then
it's probably the web content management
class city previously it was made you
gentlemen
conjul management's thought see
organizations which all using ship went
to host their corporate leaders thought
so much of previous just going to text
although very inexperienced expose it to
the incidence
miss configurations and that something
is going wrong
missions that's going to be licensed
next and gonna be free game
structure she points it's sort of like
hierarchical structure is rushing back
to ESCO you've got money thing inside
another so on and so forth
one of the top you've got something
that's one of the renowned for all
things generally companies illogic
companies have a whole bunch of some of
the things that might be managing things
like footballs
Hibs international internet with you
might have a whole bunch of science of
like a website but it doesn't actually
media websites what you bring to you
it's more like a box or container to
contain little bits and pieces and
actually might need to work so for
example you might have a blog and have
one group that's a decent side look to
it and invite the bottom line cool web
pages like your HTML pages or UAE speaks
basis with things like this kind of
thoughts on as soon as you excel sheet
rose and condoms in a bunch of areas
inside and in my home you've got like
these which are very similar list
accepting that instead of just having
been used but things like fun so we took
some pictures and things that are most
interesting to have because that's where
all the sensitive information if that's
what you want to find
widespread because his home village see
microsoft said something like two or
three large organizations
points which I can't think that's what
makes it so on this page but a whole
bunch of different points is 500
companies yet I looked up when they
mention us overusing shape once you much
should recognize those names on the left
hand side we've got an example of what I
miss conflagration marketplace so
instead of being presented with the
company's corporate sites you get access
to the same points back in and this is
purely because of exposures of suits and
just like that so this is a major player
in the back they're going to be home
today didn't go any further than that
because I don't want to we present
audience but it's very easy to find a
whole bunch of these sites that have
beset up incorrectly
why do you choose to use it could be
because many companies operating
partnership and getting like she pointed
nice hehe
document collaboration system something
like that and she went and he acted
directly there might be completely
dependent on Microsoft's so many points
was it will go in with you get over
myself around for a long time
going away so either Microsoft because
that's what they know that's what
they're comfortable with longtime
collaboration platforms people like to
stick to what they know and also the
fact that my son had a really great
sales machine may be a great job of
making sales and advertising so a lot of
what you see
and it's really easy
incidents
quite useful you trying to be a lot of
factors could really what you're doing
so you know things you just trying to
show him and show him the presenting you
with what
well then you are sure it's not like
it's just that sometimes is this whole
fiasco there is a general aleksandr he
says the leak was disgusted with the
bases actually make sure that the right
information on the same winces anyone
know what this is but it's not cheap
with false made you provide you with
security mechanisms to make sure that
things like this don't happen to us you
can have the fence yes you can have
titanium
front doors only get a lot of factors
but if you back door is open
becoming more common way of content
management system and a lot of companies
posting their web pages on the phone
with caissons so we look at the most
people involved if you look at all the
general feeling that you look in normal
implications injections
wats good things come on injection
possibly causing the bus to prove he is
quite interesting is she went context
because she was texting directory your
company's Active Directory
you manage to brute force and it if you
could be going to use that is to gain
access to lots of companies for example
they might have my own place and
somebody credentials you could
potentially get into people's boxers
set up a rule
the you can get it today
things like that
the commenting that investigation and
coming back and ABS CBN communicates
with a database on the back and my son
ridiculous but a lot of times VCD
databases Microsoft databases
because the internet and they raised and
presentable the standard documents on a
shape when you might be impossible to
explain which means that they probably
didn't care I changed the default
possibility that they could possibly
love me with something like this say
it's a it's a bank and shit you don't
have those rights equal injection or
cologne injection you can just copy the
database and right straight off she
points which is quite cool to me that
you're going to see his mission to slice
when you find information disclosure you
gonna grab the documents and that's what
you're off the whole bunch of people
used to start one of them that's why
he's cool he's been this page and change
this whole time
seen playing some sort of external
structure by default is going to have a
generic she points so but if companies
using a custom web applications that
they can have custom services as well
you going to use the database without
having you want these cases of Education
no one is quite useless users did so
many demonstrators but later and then
allows us to do you use it he said he
gave you see points and she don't mean
that's uploaded by somebody who is
containable happening
uploaded by middle name and you click on
that link to your profile will contain
information and wants to buy rings are
using the telephone number email address
all these bits and pieces of you can you
possibly bring more social engineering
attacks in the last few this which is
why not show it to people 61 thats
lockheed on all of them and stuff so
that's something that you might wanna
check out late said she had she went
running and isolation and see what you
can find
actually really stupid exercise with a
couple of months ago and before I
started this means the guy hits me we
need to have a chance
months ago we act and easy to change
make sure that can happen again
arounds
and I try finding the URL one of the
pages and basically what that is
puts the pages edit my and it's an
honest anonymously and paid on a website
and so there is a problem
yeah it's really actually have led many
are LTV Steel page that you find and
possibly get my which has gone husbands
isolated
I really like 40 went out and they do
the basics very well so it was quite
well that's going to be a whole bunch of
extra bits and pieces back I really
needed to do that I'll be honest with
you cannot even actually tried it's just
kind of baseball game which comes with
gas
I tried and tried and tried but I cannot
get that was really a great day
confusing enough you should do it that's
not for me
risking that it does she is a printing
what do you call you more about it all
better exactly twice because the kitchen
sink at an old friend she's a lot of
when to expect during a cold front page
techniques against USC 2013 I'll be
going quick so we do this whole thing of
printing process so we can get it I
wonder if you get bigger picture of Mary
couple of blocks and is doing so it
looks at response headers from the site
and extracting information not being
tells you what she appoints versions
that enables and it tells you exactly
what you think will be high and then
something that came from