okay so I'm Andrea Barzagli I'm the
founder of a company called inverse
puffs which you might or you might have
not heard of and gonna talk to you here
very honored to be in this very
beautiful venue about our latest open
hardware project which is the USB armory
so how many of you have heard of the USB
armory please raise your hand okay okay
so there's a fair number of people
doesn't know anything about it which is
great so that I can tell you about this
project so what is the USB armory they
use the armory is a open source computer
which has been in design in a timing for
factor and specifically the form factor
of a USB stick so why are we doing this
so as a company every two years we try
to publish a research which has to do
not only with software but as well as
hardware and of course in the point of
view of security we talk about hacking
cars for the first time in 2007 then we
did side-channel attacks over the
powerline attacks on credit cards and so
on and two years ago we wanted to for a
change to make a talk where we create
something and build something rather
than break something and wanted to take
our expertise into embedded systems
auditing into actually creating one and
the reason why the USB army was created
in the first place was for personal
security applications because the first
thought that we had was we need
something we want something that can
provide us encrypted storage but not you
know with some military-grade encryption
USB Drive which you really don't know
what is actually doing and that most of
the times when we do audits on these
kind of devices there are security
especially if you have physical
possession of the device can be broken
or bypass very very easily so the first
idea was why don't we do an open
hardware device which can provide
enhanced mass storage so instead of just
providing you know a standard USB Drive
it would also maybe you know filter or
scan and encrypt maybe with GPU or
something all of the contents before
actually being saved on a micro SD card
and then we fought but you know mass
storage oh okay
it's a driver Ricci which is very well
understood by all computers but why
don't we do a device which can provide a
richer interface than just you know
copying files to it so this way we could
leverage a more complex authentication
and more secure methods so why don't we
just provide a device which supports
tcp/ip over USB using the standard
drivers that are there for providing
emulating an ethernet device over USB
and then maybe we can expose a richer
application using a web server or
something and and once this transition
you know was clearly in our minds then
we quickly realize that we need
something a little more powerful than
just a microcontroller on own and such
as device and we thought but if we have
you know something more powerful and
also something where you can customize
the code that runs on it you know you
can we can do some crazy and exotic
things which you don't find in devices
nowadays such as you know if I copy a
certain file if I input a certain
password maybe we have a fail-safe were
detect and maybe the device will just
wipe itself so some data self-destruct
unfortunately like that and then we took
it further and we said but we have
tcp/ip connectivity to this device then
we can SSH to it with a credentials that
we don't care too much about or maybe
one-time credentials and then you can
have your keys there and if you route it
you can use it unless a SSH proxy or of
course you can use it as a password
imagine all these kind of ideas quickly
came out you know as something that we
could implement on such as generic
device authentication tokens and and so
on and also more importantly if you have
a device which provides richer
functionality where you control the code
that runs on it there's no reason why
not only you can authenticate to the
device but also the device can decide to
authenticate the host that is being
connected to since it becomes a full
computer that can actively perform tasks
as soon as it's plugged into your
computer so you know the idea was that
you can also have a device that as soon
as you plug it in will communicate to
your laptop or host computer and if the
device itself decides that for some
reason the host that you're connected to
is not the one that it's supposed to
talk to then actions can be taken
you know if that condition is being
detected so
we set some design goals very quickly so
for supporting all of these applications
it needs to be a compact USB powered
device so no external supply it needs to
plug in directly into a USB port without
a cable or something which is fiddly it
must be a little bit future-proof so
amass have a fast view and a generous
amount of RAM given the form factor in
the applications of the device it must
support secure boot so the code that
you're executing on the device it must
be possible to verify that it is the
Intendant code that you want to execute
so that it's signed with your own keys
it must provide standard connectivity
over USB and also very important for us
the development environment must be
familiar not something which requires
you know some specific vendor SDK or IDE
you know code development tools you know
it must be something where you can
easily put code in the same way that you
will put in on a server on your laptop
you can put it on this device and of
course the design must be open as open
as possible
so one of the first tasks into into one
of the most important choices that you
have to may may right away when you
design such a device is selecting the
correct
you know components and specifically the
system on a chip so a system on a chip
is a CPU which also has a lot of
internal peripherals we'd help you in
designing such as device and also when
you want to make it very compact we
selected the formerly free scale now an
XP IMX 50 free because we were very
familiar with this device with the
security features of this component is
also used heavily in automotive which is
where we stumble upon it it's an arm
cortex a8 which can be clock up to one
key cards almost all data sheets and
manuals are public which is good no NDA
is required that the documentation is
actually fairly good which for Hardware
it's always a good thing when it's not
super crappy but it's actually fairly
good it has some security features which
I'm going to mention about later on
detail power consumption guide available
which for us was important when
developing something that needs to be
power over USB so the amount of current
that you can drain is limited and
there's excellent nanny support for
Android Debian Ubuntu free base the N
and so on and good stock and production
guarantee you don't want to commit to a
design
to realize that maybe after two years
the part is not available anymore
because that sucks a lot so in this case
they're gonna produce this party I think
2021 this device the system ownership is
a lot of peripherals as a canvas
controller display controllers 2d and 3d
GPU and our design fries not to power on
the blocks that we don't need to be
power on to reduce power consumption on
the device and to simplify the design as
much as possible because we have to cram
it in such a such a tiny space which is
unusual in this kind of designs with
these specific components in terms of
hardware security features we have
something called high assurance book
which is authentication of the initial
bootloader which means secure boot so in
an XP parlance it is referred to as high
assurance boot but it's really secure
boot we have a security controller which
is a hardware module which can do a s
encryption which a with a device
specific key and then there are a lot of
cryptographic accelerators which
actually it turns out that if you use
them the overhead in doing the MA to and
from the accelerator accelerators is
actually you know it takes more time
than doing those computation over in in
pure CPU so unless you're having
parallel class to perform those are not
really useful line or not we're now
going to cover them we're just gonna
cover the first two security features
later on and also we have a very well a
very complete implementation of arm
trust and so I'm Trustin is a feature
which is supported must be supported
both by the CPU core as well as the
peripherals that are connected to the
system on a chip for separating the
execution domains in a non secure one
and a secure one and the idea is that
you can also leverage on functionalities
such as sort of hardware firewalling
functionalities where you can decide to
segregate a specific hardware components
let's say a USB controller or the micro
sd controller only to one of these two
domains and this allows to a further
separation within the device which you
know it can be useful on certainly a
good playground because one of the
things
we see We Trust is that the threshold
and and the learning curve to approach
it is always very high and we also
wanted a device where we could do
trainings and we could experiment with
trust and very you know fairly easily so
an augur go too much into trust zone
this is a very nice article from the
Jean otherwise project so Jean otherwise
provides an implementation of trust on
which is supported so provide support
for the USB armory and and the idea is
that you boot a richer OS such as Linux
into the normal container while into the
secure container you have microkernel
base
lightweight OS such as Gino doe s which
can take over certain functions or
certain drivers and exposing virtual
drivers to the Linux OS so that you can
do things like encrypting the microSD
but the key remains in the secure domain
so even if your Linux instance is
completely compromising your route on it
you cannot dump the key from memory
because that will be segregated on trust
them so if you're interesting into these
the gene OS provides a good example for
this on the USB arm so and of course
it's open source that every software
will publish for it it's open source but
also the hardware layout is as open
source as possible and at the end it's a
very tiny device as you can see 65
millimeters by 19 by 6 we have a micro
SD card slot which is where all of the
code comes from so there's no
persistence on the device all of the
code which has been executed other than
a very tiny brute forum which can be
dumped by the way which is not something
that can be done on most hardware so you
can expect that at least all the code
comes from your micro SD card we have a
breakout header for GPIO serial i-square
CSPI and so on and we also have a LED
which in case you using Trustin can also
be used to indicate that the Trustin
code is being executed if you want that
was the original reason for putting it
there and is now supported by Debian
Ubuntu Arch Linux arm genie otherwise
again and it can emulate any USB device
so this device is primarily designed and
was primarily designed to be used in
device mode but
you know and actually after having the
the first production we realized that
the USB controller and this devices is
so forgiving that even if the hardware
layout was specifically designed for
device mode so we were driving the IDP
in a certain state that usually it's
associated to device mode we can also
have it to host mode so this was
actually a picture from the first test
that we did where with a very crude
breadboard gender converter we converted
the male USB form factor to a female USB
form factor and we attached it to a
power USB hub we plug a Wi-Fi car a USB
keyboard USB mouse a USB displays and
then we could actually use the device
entirely on its own so because we
thought this could be also nice for
certain application just to have it on
its own we design a very inexpensive and
cheap host adapter which just changes
the gender of the USB Armory this is one
configuration flag in the Linux kernel
you flipped and then you can use the
completely standalone so in this example
you there's a Wi-Fi adapter on the left
you just feed power back in and then you
you can use it as your own you know
access point or whatever you want so
this was also some it was nice to see
that we had the capability of doing this
but after you know we produced the
device so we didn't think it before it's
but it's just something that we could do
it afterwards and it's because a USB OS
controller it's it's you know it
actually provides you a lot of freedom
which also you know it's also a good
thing for testing as I will mention
later on so for developing this kind of
hard work being so tiny
typically the components that you use
for this kind of design are BGA
component so BGA is ball grid array
which means that you have form a
packaging factor where all of your
contacts are below the actual component
and it's actually you know it's fairly
difficult to solder and D solder this on
your own
and so prototyping these kind of devices
is is always quite a challenge so we
fought to be clever at first and we
thought ok let's create a breakout board
where without having to solar anything
so we bought this this is a very nice
but expensive socket which allows you to
climb
and screw the system on a chip on a
socket which requires no soldering
whatsoever and then we bro you can break
out all of the different connections of
the system on a chip in order to to do
some development on it and we thought it
was a good idea at the time it was a
terrible idea in in fact because the
tolerances for the various distances of
the components required for powering up
the system on a chip in the first place
are so high that it's very difficult to
create a working power regulator for
this device by Sol right on your own so
this ring has about six or seven power
rails and we will get you know most of
them will be stable but then will be one
of two that will be unstable so at the
end we realize that in order to do the
power components for this device we
actually need an actual PCB but if you
have a PCB for the power component then
you can put the system on a chip on the
PCB as well and if you do that then you
can also put the ROM and if you do that
you can also put a microSD and if you do
that then you have the first prototype
so the first prototype of the device was
actually something which is surprisingly
close to this to this final design so
the message here is that if you're doing
open hardware you know be brave you know
you know sometimes if you try to over
think in and over optimize your
development process you might end up you
know doing the brown choice and actually
in our case going for the final design
from the beginning what does it was
actually the right choice so this was an
effort which you know maybe we would
have saved some money if if this would
have been would have worked but
certainly didn't save us time and at the
end also didn't save us any money
so this breakout board which we did is
very fancy it's like a super
stardestroyer something which is
expensive it's big but it really doesn't
work and it's gonna crash down on a
planet or something yeah so you know
it's there in our office it's very nice
it was a brilliant effort you know
completely useless so you know lesson
learned but it makes for good pictures
the second challenge was that we wanted
the design to be open but we also wanted
the tools to modify and access the
design to be open as well because if we
you do an open design and you publish
the sources of something which requires
a twenty thousand euro license
you know it is open technically but you
know it's not something which is nice so
we decided to use Kai CAD or a ticket
for for for this project which is
open-source software which you know when
you want to make such a tiny design it
really really doesn't help you in
achieving your goal and one of the
biggest challenges here was that so on
the right side you have the ROM module
and on the left side you have the
system-on-a-chip and all the traces that
needs to go from the ROM to the system
on a chip they all need to be exactly on
the same length to the FIR decimal point
of a millimeter and that's because a you
don't want to take any chances and be
because you know if one of them is
longer than the other then you're gonna
have RAM issues which you cannot simply
fix and at the time and even now it's
not really mature
there was no length trace matching
feature into kicad so all of this was
done completely by hand into matching
the length of all of these traces and
normally when you are breaking out these
connections you can go around the system
on a chip from multiple angles so you
can go on the side here and also you
have a longer you can have a longer
distance between the system on a chip
and the round which gives you more room
to do a lot of zigzags and do the length
trace matching but here we don't have
that because our system on chip is at
exactly the edge of the boardroom two
sides so this was quite a challenge
which which we'd assumed but you know
for the sake of open source we took the
effort of doing this my hand and a DME
worked and that was one of our biggest
risk that the ROM would just note not
work properly on the other hand the 3d
viewing capabilities of Pi cuts sorry it
is a huge fly here they're really
they're really excellent which they are
not really that useful but at least as
an open-source tool this works
brilliantly and much better than
commercial tools so there's that
so the schematics can be downloaded you
can modify them you can access them so
the electrical schematic as well as the
PCB layout so and it's licensed with a
certain license which has no commercial
restriction whatsoever so it's as open
as it gets in terms of hardware design
so this was the Alpha prototype which is
the same four factor as the final
version but he has a Jetta connector
there so that in case something would go
wrong we could easily access access that
port and it was also designed so that we
could cut those two access
surfaces and it would actually still
work and it would actually represent our
final form factor it turns out no it
turns out that the Jetta connection
wasn't actually necessary because our
first alpha prototype work right away
but nonetheless it was there and this is
now in our office museum the first board
worked right away and I think you know
it's kind of amazing that with
completely hundred-percent open-source
tools in you know two months you can
design from scratch or hardware which is
a full computer of that form factor
which is more powerful than a pension to
of a few years ago I think it's it's
rather cool but Darth Vader there
prefers black much more than green so we
made it black so they would look even
cooler because you know that's the way
it's supposed to be it's supposed to
look cool as well so you can see the
different iterations of the the boards
that was the Alpha prototype with the
betas what we did we we found out the
number of revisions that we could do in
one single production so in a single
panel we could do seven different
versions and we try to optimize and lose
certain components over replace certain
powering methods we'd components that
would not cost five euros my baby would
cost money more us to try to optimize
the design as much as we could and to
lower the cost and we found two versions
that were good for that purposes one was
much more strict more stripped-down than
the curve version but it was consuming
more current it was draining more
current so it wasn't as effective so we
found the best balance of features and
then we made the final version which is
there so we basically went through three
different production runs to
to find the the final production version
and the second one it was testing seven
different designs at the same time okay
so now before covering the software that
we're on device I'm going to talk about
the security features of it so the first
most important one is secure boot
so the system-on-a-chip supports high
surance boot which allows to fuse your
own public keys we're not talking about
om keys that we put or that and XP boots
you can fuse your own fuse your own
public keys and this is a one-time
permanent operation
that then are going to be used to verify
the authenticity of the bootloader that
you're gonna execute which in this case
is you would mean can be anything but
you good is the one that supports this
this device and this activation unlike a
PC it's not that you can go into the
BIOS or something and that you can reset
or clear that option once you do it is
there forever and this is a feature not
a bug and you can also provoke up free
keys out of four so you can also do nice
things like you put free legitimate
public keys the fourth is random and
then if you revoke the first free ones
you end up with a brick and nobody can
ever execute code on it which is also
something that you can do so we have
published procedure for that by the way
you do it you go into the bootloader and
you fuse the hashes the combined hashes
for the public keys that you have and
now also this was part of our effort
which i think is interesting NXP
provides code signing tool which allows
you to sign bootloader images but until
very recently their last version was
buggy and they wouldn't publish the the
previous version which was working and
anyway an NDA is required to download
this this tool which is is annoying well
it's actually not on NDA it's an
end-user License Agreement which is not
too bad but it's annoying to go for that
process so for transparency we decided
to re-implement what these tools are
doing as open source software in a way
that not only is readable so you can
understand what goes on and now the
signature is actually computed but you
know it also make it easier for
executing as a
as you know in your environment and it
doesn't require to pool binary blobs
from from annex B so we provide guides
both in using the annex B tools which is
not trivial so that's also a useful
guide for anybody that use uses and XP
tools and we also have our our the same
guy by with our with our own tools and
everything is on our github repository
and we have two tools one is for the
hash generation which is then Huson
system-on-a-chip and one is for signing
on the bootloader they take your keys
and then they produce the output now
when you want to maintain a secure chain
of trust secure boot plays a role only
in the very first phase so secure boot
provides an anchor between the hardware
and the first piece of software that
you're going to execute so in this case
the bootloader so with the to boot
you've use your key in the system on a
chip and those are used to verify the
bootloader but then of course you want
to maintain these chain of trust because
if the bootloader is not gonna verify
your Linux kernel for instance then
having a secure boot is not really
useful so you could support something
called a verified boot which allows you
to embed a public key when you're
compiling the bootloader to verify the
Linux kernel image that you're that
you're gonna put so and with this
feature you maintain the chain of trust
because you're you good image has been
verified by the hardware and it is the
one that contains the public key which
is going to verify your Linux kernel
image this is an example a successfully
booted you good image so no - Sam are
you sure inspire been found and this is
an example of a fail attempt now the
example for the fail attempt here is
done into verification mode so
verification mode is an intermediate
step or you're not locking the feature
yet but you can test it and the reason
why you have this is to test that you
are you know you have the capability of
actually stunning images and then you're
not ending up with a break and and also
when you have a failure in final mode
you're not gonna see any output you're
not gonna see a
because the bootloader code is just not
gonna be executed so you cannot even get
an output saying you let secure boot
fail the CPU will just hang and nothing
can happen because no external code will
ever be executed and this is an example
of verified boot this is an output from
you boot where it will verify the hashes
for the kernel and the device tree blog
which is an external file which provides
certain hardware configuration which are
the two pieces of components watch that
are going to need it for booting up your
or your Linux OS I'm gonna explain how
this is gonna all play it out in the
piece of software that we provide for
the USB armory in in a second there's a
second feature a hardware feature on
this system on a chip which is called
the SEC v2 this is not a standard as
name don't don't be fooled by that is
annex B name for a security controller
which is a some sort of HSM so it's a
hardware module which is in the system
on a chip which implements 20 56 bit AES
using a key which is fuse in each system
on a chip and it's unique and it can
never be read it can only be used so you
can use you can ask the system on a chip
to do encryption or decryption but you
can ever ask it to give you the key back
and there are certain hardware
properties which protect this key inside
the processor and it is generally used
to derive device specific secrets for
full disk encryption and more
importantly this key is only unlocked to
you if you're secure booting so if
you're not secure booting there's gonna
be a standard test key which is gonna be
the same for every device which is gonna
be used for encryption so and the reason
for this is that the theory is that you
on your own code which supposedly this
is lockdown to be secure boot and
accessing the decryption and encryption
function otherwise anybody can use them
we ported a driver for this and we
created an additional drivers that allow
us to use these security controller very
easily it's as easy as opening a carter
device that's a ruby example you said
Damone other encryption or decryption
you said initialization
and then you just speed blobs of data to
the device and you read back blobs which
are either gonna be encrypted or
decrypted depending on the mode which
you set and we have support for this in
interlocked software which is what I'm
going to cover now
so interlock is you know we created this
hardware device and then we wanted to
you know create some you know reference
software that actually shows one of the
many ways that you can use it because of
course this is a platform that can be
used for many many purposes so interlock
is an open source file encryption front
end which was developed for the USB
armory but it's not limited to be news
on the USB armory if you have you know
you can use it on your own laptop if you
want to you can use it on a Raspberry Pi
you can use it on any hardware that you
want as long as it can run Linux and you
can execute go applications which means
any Linux hardware because you just end
up with a static binary which is just
gonna work and the point of interlock is
to provide a web accessible file manager
which will be a front-end for Linux
unified key system encrypted partitions
and also we wanted to put in some
additional cryptographic operations for
symmetric and a symmetric operation on
stored files so I'm gonna show you a
demo of this application hoping that the
demo gods will be kind to me so I'm
gonna take my own use the armory which
is it's an enclosure we also have an
enclosure by the way and I'm gonna show
you the various features that this that
this fronton has so and also what I'm
gonna show you is that not only we have
encryption features for own files but we
also have messaging capability and we're
going to show you the signal plug-in
that we have for it so what I'm gonna do
I'm gonna connect to my USB armory in
this specific instance so I tested this
before so you're not seeing the pop-up
here but the USB armor itself is
demanding for a very specific client
certificate in my browser so if I don't
have that certificate I cannot talk to
it so this is already one form of
authentication which has been happening
here and then I'm presented with
let me zoom a little I'm presented here
with a volume name from than a password
prompt so these are gonna be my
credentials for logging in into the USB
armory now what's gonna happen is that
volume is the actual volume name of
unencrypted partition and the password
is one of the multiple pass phrases that
you can have for a an encrypted
partition and if for some reason I don't
trust the operating environment that I'm
using if I want I can tick this box and
the passwords that I'm gonna use is
gonna be wiped as soon as I'm logged in
so if anybody intercepted the password
on my lap door maybe by doing shoulder
surfing that password is now useless and
you can have more than one so you can
use you can have a one-time password
here as soon as you input your
credential what's happening right now an
increase the partition got unlocked and
I get this partition accessible with a
file manager when I can you know I can
decide to compress files I can download
files and I can also upload files if I
if I wanted to so I can just you know if
I have a file here now it got uploaded
to the USB arm or if you are on Windows
and you don't have a very minimalistic
Windows environment like the one that I
have here you can also drag and drop
files directly into this area and
they'll be uploaded and then you can
decide on these files you can encrypt
them now we support three different
encryption methods you can have standard
symmetric encryption with the passwords
that you choose you can have the same
kind of encryption but being piped
through the security coprocessors so the
actual key that is gonna be used for
encryption is not only your passphrase
but it's also combined with the unique
secret which is on the USB armor itself
which means that you can lock encryption
and decryption of that specific file to
the specific devices so if I take the
microSD card out from this USB armory
and I use it on a different USB armory
even if you know the passwords you won't
be able to encrypt and decrypt that file
again and this can also be done for the
initial credentials that I use for
logging into the encrypted partition if
you want so this is our optional support
which you can enable and also you
do PGP encryption and accretion so I
have two keys here and now I just
encrypted this file with PGP now the way
we have PGP functionality is not by
typing through a GPG binary but it's
actually all using standard native go
libraries because this is a go
application so there's no outside
dependencies over standard go libraries
except for the optional signal support
which I'm going to show you in a second
and once you have the files here you can
compress them you can download them you
can delete and you can do whatever you
want and everything that you see here is
living on unencrypted partition so
nothing that you see here is store
unencrypted you also get an audit log so
every operation that you're doing its
audited you can add and remove passwords
you can change them you can power off
the device and when you log out the
encrypted partition would be will be
locked again so now I'm going to show
you signal connectivity I'm assuming
you're all familiar with what signal is
yeah ok so we have a plugin for signal
here which allows me so not only to chat
with other other mobile phones so in
this case I'm talking to my mobile phone
so I just receive the message from my
interlock here so hello there but also
we can share files so now I had a file
on the encrypted partition and of course
I could just PGP encrypt that file I
could download that file I can put it
into my email client and then I could
send it away but we know how that's
complicated nowadays so what I can just
do I can just send a file which is
sitting on encrypted partition of the
armory to my phone so I just sent here a
picture of my cat and the reason why we
are doing this is not only to have
communication between a phone and a USB
armory and I use the armory on a phone
but also to simplify communication
between two different USB armories so
for instance my colleague Andre there
has another USB armory which is blinking
over there much more loud than mine mine
is better it's a steady LED yours is
blinking it's just this truck
and he I had his number here and what I
can do or what he can do he can send me
a file from his encrypted partition on a
USB armory and to an encrypted with
signal directly landing on the encrypted
partition of my USB armory so now I get
a mock notification see I receive the
message and if I go onto his contact
directory I see that a file appear and
that file let's download the file let's
see what it is and it's another picture
of a lovely cat
so our two cats can decide to have a lot
of story and share pictures completely
secure in safety with interlock and the
USB armory so and also the interesting
thing is that by using the signal
infrastructure this way we can send much
bigger files with what you can do on a
mobile phone there's no size limit there
and also the metadata of let's say the
file name gets preserved which is
something that you cannot do if you just
communicate it with with mobile phones
and and this is really to make you know
a very as efficient as quickly as
possible a file transfer which you know
in this specific case my laptop is just
acting as a router and nothing more and
all he sees is is encrypted traffic and
I don't have to worry about GPG or any
other things I just use this
functionality which which we think is
pretty good and of course I can also
chat with Andrey if I want to and this
chat also leaves on the encrypted
partition so if I want I can also
leverage on all the functionalities that
we have here in the file manager to
download the file and manage the file
like you like like it would be any other
file on this on this system and as soon
as I log out the partition is locked and
encrypted again so so this is one
software that we've done you can it's on
our github repository and again it
doesn't necessarily need to be used on a
USB armory it can be used on pretty much
on any hard
you want so even on your laptop if you
have a container which can access an
encrypted partition and you wanna you
know you want to access to that you can
also use interlock if you want we also
have an embedded interlocked
distribution that leverages on all of
the features that I explained to you
about secure boot and the security core
processor 12 as you know as tight a
secure environment as possible running
on the US your USB armory so the build
environment that we have so build root
is a framework which is developed by
people like Atmel but it's a completely
open source and there are many sponsors
to it which allows you to easily create
a final embedded image for embedded
systems and the way works is that you
have configuration files which are
similar to the Linux kernel
configuration and then you just I make
and you end up with your kernel your
user space all conveniently packed in
the way you want it to be so with build
run environment with just two commands
you can automatically create a
monolithic kernel which will include all
of the user space as a run disk inside
the kernel image and why are we doing
this because the idea is that you have
your system on a chip which secure boots
the bootloader with secure boot the boot
loader with a verified boot verifies the
kernel image but the kernel image
doesn't only contain the kernel
it also contains inside all of the user
space application and interlock as well
when I say all of the use of this
application I mean just you know the
standard Linux tools necessary to maybe
create a microSD partition and to set up
networking nothing nothing fancy we're
talking about less than four megabytes
of image including interlock itself and
so we maintain the root of trust in
executing all of this code and then
everything else that is on the micro SD
card is just an encrypted partition
where your data or even programs can be
there so everything is locked down and
either sign or authenticated with your
credentials into this case and our
default image also you can put it on a
blank micro SD card will automatically
create the encrypted partition and the
first boot and
then you can also change the passphrase
for that so to make it as easy as
possible and you can optionally enable
the security coprocessor which means
that every credential that you create
for the encrypted partition on that
device will be tied to the specific key
of that specific system on a chip that
that you have ok so these are the
defensive users that we created the
armory for in the first place but of
course there are also some offensive
uses for it and there's a lot of papers
which play with the idea that not only
you can emulate arbitrary USB devices
with with the USB armory which use a lot
in in penetration testing of USB stacks
and USB drivers the amount of freedom
that this controller gives you is a lot
so you can emulate and you can bring up
very fairly complex drivers and modify
them so that they misbehave without
losing any performance and any speed and
this is the USB Leno's gadget framework
that we use which is the same one that
we use also for emulating a network card
and there are a few papers around about
you know doing USB eavesdropping attacks
or doing network at jacking attacks with
the USB armory since you can emulate a
you know an arbitrary Ethernet device
from it and recently you might have seen
this attack here which was published
where it's about stealing credential
tokens from other OS X or Windows
machines even if they're locked by just
plug in a USB armory that emulates a
network interface with a higher priority
and then provides authenticators that
would respond to all the authentication
requests from windows and this allows
you to get the ntlm hashes from the
machine even if it's locked
so just by plugging in the armory so
it's of course something that you can do
with any device which is capable of
emulating USB Ethernet cards but in this
attack in 10 seconds the credentials
were were were stolen you can find a
link of this in our wiki page under
external contributions and
this is the blog post that Brandon did
and the it's a step-by-step tutorial on
how to configure the USB armory to do
this kind of operation and what you end
up with is this which on the USB armory
in a secret lie database you end up with
the actual ntlm hash and the username
which then you can crack or can use in
pass the hash attacks so this I think
this got really popular last week and I
think it's one of the best example of
using this device for offensive purposes
or offensive Studies so it also makes a
good platform for that and on our own we
also found at the end of last year and
it was disclosed I think March of this
year we found a bug for both OS X and
iOS were by plugging in the USB armory
and presenting a misbehaving Network
driver even if the machine will be
locked we will be able to have a crash
into kernel land because we would
present certain descriptors that would
that would cause memory overruns in the
network buffers of of the driver that
would handle that on both OS X and iOS
because the drivers actually the same so
we investigated these annoying sacks but
surprisingly it was also working on on
iOS you know panicking and and rebooting
the the machine and this memory
corruption is trigger regardless of the
fact that the user is logged in or not
so it requires no user interaction and
actually the trigger is traffic which is
sent by the USB armory to the host which
makes it very inconvenient and
scriptable
from the device itself and a single ipv6
packet can be used on reproduce the
issue so now of course the issue has
been fixed we reported it to helpful and
we disclosed the bug on me when it was
fixed and yeah it's an interesting
market it's very similar to this open B
is the issue here where memory buffs are
are being overwritten so but regardless
of this specific issue this is just to
prove the point that the USB army also
makes a very good case for you know
testing USB payloads whether it's
you know something at a lower level or
something at a higher level where you
have to present a full kernel driver and
it's very easy with the Gotcha framework
to identify the drivers which are
supported and manipulate them in a way
that you would make your hosts misbehave
so almost good time I think I also saved
some of the delayed I was there so I
thank you very much for your attention I
will be very happy to take questions if
you have any thank you very much
any questions yeah where are you raise
your hand right right so the first
question is how many layers the board
has so the first alpha version of the
board had eight layers and then the two
ground layers that are usually kept to
minimize crosstalk and to maintain
better
EMI we removed them to see if you work
anyway and yes it was fine without the
two ground layers so you know that saved
the cost of the PCB by fifty percent and
it had no negative effect so we started
conservative and then you know we went
less conservative to to understand if he
work anyway I mean we have a lot of non
conservative violations here I mean if
you take the recommendations from any
component data sheet there's no way you
can apply all of those in such as design
so that was one of the first
optimizations that we did so we have a
top and bottom layer then we have two
ground layers which you know are two are
kept there but it would would have been
two more in the inner core and here we
have the power layers which are these
two right in the middle and then we have
the two signal errors so sorry actually
this design okay no it shows the two
ground layers but those were actually
not produced in the final board sorry
it's just that I opened the file which
has all of them so these two were gone
and then we just have these layers over
here
the second question it was the if we
consider to apply for fifth
certification right in our testing of
smart cards specifically and
all of hsn's we find that v
certification has a very relative
practical value there are still some
mistakes that you can make and for a
company of our size and with the budget
that we have this project it's not a
process which we thought it would be
worthwhile worthwhile also this device
has been designed specifically for
having no persistent whatsoever on it in
terms of code the only thing that
persists is the fuse public keys and the
inner secret key which is burned by
annex B so the way we promote the use of
the device is that if you lose it and
somebody has it in its possession there
is no value that you can gain but
actually tampering with the device
because all of the secrets are either
using the right form with something that
you have and it's not like a SIM card
where you know the pin unlocks it but
really doesn't decrypt any contents of
the SIM card like a SIM card or as mark
our it's tamper proof because the pin is
only something which sets a state which
then allows you to use it but it doesn't
necessarily mean that the contents on
this mark are encrypted which is why the
time-proven capabilities of the chip are
very important in this case we have no
persistence so even if you dig up the
chip and you're very good with those
kind of stacks worst-case scenario you
get the secret key out of it which
anyway is gonna be using the right form
with your own passphrase to encrypt
secrets so we wanted to minimize the
importance of tamper proof thing on this
device I mean we see a lot we do a lot
of tests on point of sale devices in the
financial sector and we see that if we
bypass that um proof in sensors the
whole security of the device falls apart
because he completely relies on on those
on those mechanical sensors so in this
case you wanted to avoid all of that and
that's why we thought this kind of
certification would be wouldn't be
interesting for us not to mention
expensive and exhaustive to do thank you
any other question no good lunch yes
lunch thank you very much