good day everyone my name is given
amazing to find up working for kaspersky
lab for nine years already and i'm
heading crushin part of a great team so
my presentation for today is about like
our research and mostly about ethics so
it like a first presentations of the day
it will be also food for thoughts so my
overview for today is a bit of
explanation who am i what we're doing
then we will go and see what happens
during several like months and why
attackers doing bad things mmm there are
Arsenal very interesting techniques that
we found recently and certainly stories
so this is our leader Eugene Kaspersky
and he founded our team if 2008 and we
are focusing not just on detecting my
way but on digging deeper so we are not
just to find it but connect all the dots
grab her all explores the connected to
these things and so on and so on so if
them aware by taking some factory it's
our job we need to reverse engineer it
see what's happening and so on and what
is like first like most interesting a
pima advanced persistent attacks it he
heard of black energy carbonic okay
first but before before stacks that
exactly you see 2010 started so we were
two years already working and we were
prepared to reverse engineer this
these things actually what we use to
protect is something like that and you
still remember your ATMs yeah still
running how many teams so do you think
still running in percent are still
running this operating system 9098 so
and this is like and well this
Microsoft's stopped issuing patches for
this system februari yeah so this actual
state of information security in the
world and what was what we need to
protect now is looking like that and do
you know how to update such things me
know because for example to roll up
updates what you do you have a
production server you have a testing
server so you wrap up roll up updating
testing environment everything goes okay
then you move to production server to
overlap updates here you in to build
another one the same test everything
roll up hmm yeah and these things like
it built like 20 years ago 10 years ago
15 years ago and it still works as it
was designed and the worst thing is that
these things are connected to internet
they were not designed to be connected
but they are very often we do like a
security detail such kind of things and
in one such incident we came to similar
thing and understood that a developer is
that there is additional a dsl modem in
the network right they said okay it is a
legacy petplan power plant why why do
you need to hear additionally dsl modem
and it goes straight to the internet so
everybody said who this is some attacker
now how do you say who it was engineer
lazy engineers that don't want to go to
the work of something emergency happens
he just remote desktop to his working
Club working computer and every sink of
the key yeah so three years ago we draw
such a pyramid at the bottom internet
annoyances spam dealers at X trojan
downloader spyware adware a different
kind of mass malware in the middle cyber
crime gangs they are financially
motivated main goal is to steal as much
money as it possible and on the top like
top-notch malware writers nation-state
states like with unlimited budget
unlimited time yeah you do you do
understand what the models mean like
what happened next number of such
attacks rose in these two segments
subsequence and after that we predicted
it the line disappeared and eventually
all these techniques that were used by
nation-states all these technologies now
they are it's now normal criminals now
they using it and I will show you a lot
of examples of such things and as I
mentioned stacks that was like a first
drop and so they came and we started
regulating such attacks so one by one
and not only for so my profit of our
company but we made it public so the
general audience and to our people runs
ago can benefit from it and know how to
do how to detect it and how to protect
it against such things
and every time we detect something new
it's and we publish something new it's
like a clean pink on a top of a mountain
because yet another big liquidity in
2016 it's a joint to work with semantic
tread micro now that and those
indifferent to other companies it is a
report on blockbuster malware or
Lazaro's glute group that were
responsible for Sony hack and other
hacks but rising sunny with the most
interesting one and projects how one
this year very interesting my way I will
talk a bit more later on reddit so for
those who already faced apts advanced
persistent threat in their networks they
know it is like I'm right in your
network hard to get rid of really hard
hard to detect if you get rid of it they
just came back another day and why they
are here it is strategic position so why
in some cases they're after your
business itself so they trying to steal
your innovations blueprints trying to
understand how your business operates
they're after your business plans and to
give financial the condition also they
are trying to understand your network
local own network of your like who you
speak whoo you sell and so on and they
use this trust and they can like write
to these people yeah and this is you
writing them
and you can get access to networks if
you are like let's say IT company what
is the most valuable asset most valuable
asset for them is your digital trust
that other people put in your company
and they're trying to stood very easily
your digital certificate your credential
for different systems you're different
recommendation and in some cases we even
saw criminals were after physical plans
floor plans of offices why God knows why
but I'm afraid of it and if you are
research institute they are after some
scientific stuff they are after your
secret studies especially if they are
connected to some military studies and
they're trying to understand like if you
have like government grants that means
the study is very interesting and also
they use these institutes Institute's
and to research academy as approximate
proxy to exfiltrate data from different
organizations small example a rating
malware what they did they infected
several key organization in the country
let's call it contradicts in involving
president office and telecom provider
and also they can infect that research
institute so yes like people who are
protecting governmental network is a
really look after who is where there are
traffic goes and actually they use this
research institute as a proxy to proxy
fine it for our traffic from
governmental network to research
institute and then out of the country
and that's not the end also they're
trying to understand business procedures
of some organizations and then blackmail
people and it happened several times
already so this is like main motivation
for apt attackers and what do they use
let me introduce you three nice guys so
this is like very fast explanation zero
day one day only all these guys so your
network is well protected by they need
to get into somehow and in some cases
people do I'll leave the door open get
in but in most cases the door is closed
so to get the key to this closed door
they need to use some kind of exploit so
0d is exploit that there is no
prevention against it yeah it means
nobody knows about it it costs $100,000
sometimes more and it's very efficient
all day he is a zero-day retired today
so but considering how slow everybody
updates it means is still effective if
you remember configure warm three months
after it was released the patch stuff
out it was released a patch for this
vulnerability that configure bomb used
still 8 billion computers for vulnerable
08 million and one day one day is
interesting concept what barriers is
they just reverse engineer patches that
vendors issue and it'll uh huh they just
paged this chunk of code mm-hmm let's
check can we play you this check of co2
yes okay now we have working exploit yes
it's not
such effective is zero day but still
considering that everybody updates very
slow it will be it can work ok after
they get in they need to bypass internal
security of your network of your castle
yep so like in the castle you everybody
has the identity text yeah yeah and
guards checking them and this text in
computer world is certificate so what
they do they issue fake certificates but
it's easy to spot yeah like any normal
God God's will check out now it's fake
certificate you are not allowed to do
anything what they do also these steel
certificates from vendors stuxnet you
stolen a certificate like a lot of apt a
text use stolen and certificates so it
just the stall in quicker sonic
mechanism like all the needed files and
that's it also they what they do is a do
it in legal way kind of so they just
register a firm that sells vegetables
and some other fruits and also this
company has a certificate for digital
for digital signing files why I don't
know but it works and also what we saw
is a first for certificates so sometimes
people use weak encryption method or two
small keys and bad guys can just for
justice if it a certificate after they
get in so they understand that
everything is okay they can need to move
move on and the most cases they just
upload some first staging plant and this
implant searches for needed workstations
and then upload all other modules so
when you do incident response
it's very hard to get all the modules of
given a PD and what they can do they can
do a lot of stuff like every time they
do is file file system getting passwords
sound recording screen recording and
even smartphone infection and in the
most by advanced a text what we saw the
demonstrated variety of other things
like register-based virtual file system
so when you do a forensic you found
nothing interesting on the file system
jailbreaking my bio lawyers they do fear
where infection of hard drives the only
way to disinfect such hard drive is it
take some something very heavy and do
like and GSM such stations intercept and
what we saw like this year is full
network compromise like the network of
thousand computers is compromised but
everything is in memory it means that
the persistence modules is all only on
several key servers so every time you
switch on your PC it's clean and several
minutes after it's infected you
restarted it's clean several minutes
after it's infected and in other thing
that we also spotted during class two
years is a heavy usage of white listed
programs like legitimate problems
powershell scripts vincy from profiles
VNC program and so on
and now you know why we think about like
how they get in but what is the last
thing is how to initially penetrate one
systems as they need what do you do good
old spearfishing works very well don't
think I think everybody saw such a email
such emails social networks and instant
messaging the same way is spearfishing
watering holes so once it is a infect a
website that employees of a company
would sooner or later use for example
you run some kind of scattered system
and sooner or later you will go to the
schedule vendor website to download some
files you are they heck this website and
replace files so you download your
schedule system page plus nowhere and
hospitality networks is it's a really
interesting vector also for those who
travel a lot what is the first thing you
do when you check in a huddle after
chicken Wi-Fi exactly ask me for Wi-Fi
and what criminals do they in fact hotel
network and then now that in a given day
given person will be in this hotel and
then switch off on the infection when a
person checked in in a hotel and wants
to connect to our Wi-Fi you need to type
in his room number and his surname to
enter after the afraid they seize it o
night as this person connected to Wi-Fi
let's soak him you know adobe player is
outdated person clicks okay because it's
legitimate window profitable player it
downloads adobe player installation
package with but it's signed not by
Adobe but some german website for
strange german website and it embeds
original other way player update and
malware after my wanna get installed it
does nothing for 180 days so when this
laptop returns back into the network of
an organization then only then it
switched on and it's particularly
impossible to understand how this laptop
was infected and USB drives still
effective like because people you know
like is still using USB to like give me
a let's transfer pair of files up to
your computer you know that kids so
using Wi-Fi stew slow let's use USB and
the last thing is interdiction
interdiction actually it is a mail
through term is there any military in in
room yeah so what what they like do the
work they took this technique from
military's they when somebody buys a
equipment hardware for example disks
servers and so on they just arrived
already infected so we get them into
your system and they're already infected
and also what we saw is in on one
conference
attendees of the conference got CD discs
with materials and like photos and so
and so on and some of the people got
like better version of this up upgraded
version of this discs so somebody
replaced this this during their sending
process so do you remember yeah line is
disappearing this my this line I mean
and we already mentioned it yeah
Bangladesh hack 88 millions 81like they
were trying to steal one billionaire but
type for one letter one wrong letter and
only 81 minutes but still it's quite
huge amount of money believe me another
case 88 8.8 million in a team ATMs in
Japan at the same story in tail end and
one day one central european bank bank
came to us and showed us a similar video
so it is one of the capitals of in
central europe and as you can see this
guy did not assert his credit card or
even touched it him now he need to
and SMS confirming that he is standing
in the on the garlic in front of the
right ATM machine operator says okay and
this is really hard job so when we in
this together like we investigate this
ATM machine we found nothing on it so
ATM was clean when we came to bank when
this is a it's a mess ATM network was
not separated from Bank network and we
found true banking Trojan that was used
to attack bank itself yeah it's quite
quite alone corporation but it was two
years ago it is it was two years ago and
they use the same techniques to issue a
limitless credit card another story
winter cold winter several cities black
part events with huge guys inside they
got out of pot even go to ATM machine
insert and get a credit card instead it
give me a money okay and give me money
okay give me money okay give me money
now you don't have any morning okay
let's go they got into the car and drive
200 meters to the next ATM give me money
give me money and in several cities at
the same day and with the same card as
you can understand it's quite a cool
card it's not even black or gold is the
best cat in the world but how they
achieved it you wouldn't believe
by clicking have you ever lost your
credit card so what do you do when you
lost your credit card yeah exactly and
on the other side of the line there is a
nice girl she talks to you like hello
nice to meet here what is your problem
how can I help you please provide your
identification information yes your
surname name number of your card and
what she see at this moment in front of
here this girl in a bank years some
application with your data in in most
cases it's just a web browser web
browser application sometimes it's a
standalone application but this
application and there are several big
buttons that she can push like get the
list of luster injections block card and
some somebody some somewhere down there
is a special button roll back last
transaction so what they did they
infected the bank in fact it pc of this
operator and just click click click
click that's it and bank like in the
morning after this nice strong guys
drove through several banks so other
banks started to call a bank that issued
it this card and asking money bank said
no no no well no money is sorry we don't
have any locks I mean no no transactions
what do you mean no transactions no
transactions everything rolled back
yeah hard situation don't know how to
solve it okay yeah do you like it next
story yeah prepared it is a good test
it's hard to open it ATM safe yes it's
hard to open if you saw it it's ATM is
about 1000 and a half kilograms it has
very thick metal plates you can just
open with it with like your hands or
bomb bit not very effective so the safe
is very safe sorry but it is because
people that invented this thing they
were like they understood that they my
money should be in a very like well
protected place the problem is that this
safe is a commanded or operated by a
small computer on the top of this ATM
and have you ever seen how well
protected this computer is now you can
just in some banks SUV there is a master
keys for this door a service door in
some banks they change these keys but
anyway it's a simple key you can do it
like NZ did and what we saw so on every
ATM there is special eggs if I'll SBI
services its extension that Microsoft
extension for working with financial
services and we saw a plastic virus like
from 90s it was like it was like this
moment whom Wow something very very old
infection of this SBI service it
torrent is that certainly at the first
point they switched off protection of
ATM but I will explain some how they did
it and it guarantees that malicious dll
will be in memory and they have special
magic cards with special check one and
track to please you and set the size
card your ATM will show you this message
but the most interesting part of it was
that attackers didn't steal anything I
thinkers did what did not steal hmm
strange so it was a strange moment for
us and we started to dig deeper as
always and found this very worst
engineer rate and understood they have
several commands they can take money
from cassette it can gather all the
information that is on that card so we
take one to two and then it can print it
out because in each ATM there is
embedded printer so very convenient
where you just criminal just came to ATM
print it out all the information
gathered from this ATM it can sell
destroy switch the back boat and so on
oh no in our office we have several
testing ATMs and here are my colleagues
they inserted a card it is very famous
carpet bank
so you see we reversed engineers it this
malware and we understood how it
operates so we just reproduced
everything it asks for a one-time code
but because it is traditional virus this
why we know how this algorithm is inside
of this virus so you need just to
reproduce it simply so here you'll just
issue a comment to give banknotes from
the first cassette yep give banknotes
enter and this it so it works perfectly
unfortunately this is a merger of like
techniques that were used by
nation-states to attack different
companies now the same techniques is
used to attack for example finished
institutions by normal cyber criminals
but still we do a lot of cyber Spanish
stories and for today I prepared 0 first
one is the cosmic story what is it what
is it now not to comment hmm close hmmmm
kinda ok it's satellite on a gear stable
orbit so it doesn't move and to talk to
a satellite you need something like this
in a modern world plus you need a dish
yeah round and round and cool you get
your dish connected to this device dvb
card and you can receive signals from
satellite and this is used by apt
attackers what for for hiding competent
control servers because if law
enforcement get content control server
it means operation is over and they can
understand how the praise who are the
victims who were maybe attackers and so
on so like comment control server is the
most vulnerable part of any operation
what they did they used IP addresses of
different satellite users as a contact
at all server so how it works click
click click malware in some organization
calls to IP address in some satellite
network in the IP address range and
sends pack it to this IP address it goes
to satellite and goes down to this user
unfortunately this user doesn't has
don't have any open port for this packet
so it just drops it because satellite
connection is very slow and instead of
giving reply back that there is no such
open port the this packet just drops and
a taker receives this packet why he
receives this packet because there is no
encryption on the same matter because
satellite link is very slow
there is no encryption so they receive
this message do all nursery staff and
reply back using traditional ethernet
why they can do it because this system
like with original IP address don't
reply back it just drops the pocket and
packet and a taker can simply Forge
needed pick it and reply back how to
find such let's say comment a controller
server quite impossible because like
it's several hundred square kilometers
and anyway I could be this computer
black energy yeah I we it was already
mentioned today well backhander gym and
what I wanted to show you is actually
they got into a system of several oblast
and ergo it's like distribution
companies in Ukraine and they switched
off several sub networks the worst part
of it is that 230,000 people were
affected and the two months later the
system is not fully operational and the
more and more apt c takers they
implement something in their platforms
and first signs of what they that black
energy was trying to do such attack it
is februari 2015 so like
11 months they tested solution let's
call it solution and then they performed
an attack so actually is a been treated
a lot of systems a lot of companies and
they used for example they penetrated
small company then they used VPN
connection from this company to main
target too in fact to get in size of big
network also the all this story with bec
ng it started 2007 and it was just
another d does but and now it is fully
operational apt Sarah netting let's call
it platform with thousands of plugins it
can infect rotors different makers it
can work with a scatter of machines make
it can exit rate data from different
using different channels but still the
like people that word means to defend
yeah network of critical info session
networks they did very few and that's
why they were able to like they were
they had plenty of time to understand
how everything works and switched off
actually when people ask me like is it
possible to switch you off any and
electric electric grid in a world I say
no because in some key in most cases
they are unique and it's and each
Network electric power network is
designed in a way that is foolproof and
means that it's like if you switch off
several relays
still uber national and one more
interesting story projects are on
actually it is not our name it is the
name of the developers name and what is
interesting we targeted very few
countries we saw Russia wonder Iran and
our colleagues from Symantec saw also
Belgium Sweden and China so as you see
not very big set of countries but it is
number of victims is very very high and
they just not just in fact several
computers they in fact the whole network
and these guys they definitely read our
reports because like when you do
research you are searching for some
patterns and they do and they did unique
unique configuration unique files for
each victim which means indicators of
compromise in this case more or less
useless so what the key features they
have 50 plus plugins for doing different
stuff they were interested in getting
keys configurations getting set to
service to a special software was that
was used by government to encrypt
messages and as always they use very
strong encryption algorithms like 36 rc5
for Salazar 20 etc etc and they use DNS
to exfiltrate data actually what they
did also to accelerate data from
networks and they facilitated gigabytes
of data they proxy fight through high
load servers like proxy server of an
organization webgate you know everybody
watching YouTube in this organization
coke we will use this server to
exfiltrate data because you wouldn't see
any spikes in this case and everything
is technical details showed us that
these guys they learnt a lot from other
extremely advanced actors because they
used features from DQ oh my where they
used features for flame and the youth
features from region so for example they
have ability to infect air-gapped net
air-gapped networks they create special
partition on USB drives that is not
visible from windows but it is visible
by former where they use registry-based
or visual file systems they use lua
script like kind of JavaScript language
to operate different to create plugins
so yeah yep and for like so I said that
as you can see it's like race of weapons
is always like getting faster and faster
then use new technologies by the way
it's still unknown how they got into
this network no please right now and the
problem is the line is disappearing not
only in a way from that traditional
criminals learning from this highly
professional guys
but also once again lazzaro's team and
once again bangladesh bank heist when it
would do a lot of for your sins
engineering and you're you're starting
to find patterns you like patterns as i
mentioned it and i know there's like not
everybody likes the compiled code but
believe me it looks the same more or
less and on the left hand side is a part
of code that were used in Sony hack on
the right hand side is a part of hope
that were found in Bangladesh Bank for
the difference no difference what could
it mean it could mean that these guys
the active from 2009 they attack
everything they take south korean
companies their tech south korean
government sunny and now they attack
banks and there are used it also the
same problem suffered several more banks
in vietnam and a couple different
countries which good may i mean that
this group also made like a billion of
dollars and it's like a new way of
getting funds for nation state actors so
it's a this line is not working only in
one way
but in two thousand so the odium
ultimate the ultimate goal for these
guys is power and money and by the way
how's it getting as when they get him
into the network of a bank to bypass
security and to start issuing fault
length Swift transactions they needed to
page two bytes sews it pitched two bites
of legitimate implication and it was
enough to steal more or less maybe 1
billion another lesson there are a lot
of ransomware and they're a lot of wiper
text right now it's in the crane it's in
the Curia it's in Sony hack a lot of
watering hole attacks and another thing
that apt attackers started to use very
very aggressively I would say is giving
false flags into the implementing some
false flags into their code what for
because everybody loves attribution it
is the main question for actually like
victim especially if it is a
governmental entity or something like
that and in some in most cases they are
what was it started to do as to how
attribution is done right now is the
best tribution is when law enforcement
gets the server understand who is behind
the server and go to concrete to people
and provide them to to jail it's the
best attribution that could be made and
but in digital world in most cases we
just rely on some infrastructure
overlaps come to control service I mean
in some forgotten debug strings like in
different languages also and they
started to just add some strings for
example in romanian language some
strings in spanish show and you start
this increment maybe spanish maybe not
doin samsung so attribution becomes
harder and harder for us and it's more
and more cases of finalists malware and
it means harder harder to do any
incident response because when you come
to a company and starting to do instant
response in DB understands it there is
no files created on file system it's
problem and when you see work that all
the plugins also uploaded from attackers
come to control only in memory it's a
big problem so you just get got like
small piece of puzzle without any
additional pieces and I already
mentioned it but so apt techniques
actively adopted by cybercriminals
business supply chains are very
interesting method of getting inside of
big companies because a company with a
50 employees can't afford would like big
IT security department in most cases we
see like the IT guys doing everything
from installing software hardware and
doing information security and these
small companies they have access to big
targets VPN or some other credentials
but Posada means but they have access to
this
big companies and they just get inside a
small company which you which is quite
easy task and then get inside big
company so and there are a lot of
companies that are providing this kind
of attacks as a service not only
companies also i mean not only attack
itself but also a malware yeah we heard
about the feeling finfisher we heard
about NSO group so yeah it's a commodity
right now nation-states trying to gather
as much intelligence as it possible and
they are starting to build larger
botnets and as I showed you hospitality
networks could be an attack vector
especially when it is good when it is
good detail oh ho toh and be careful
when you are using free Wi-Fi so as a
conclusion has a conclusion many years
ago we said we are here to save the
world it is a slogan of our company and
now it's time to choose a digital
bodyguard so I hope this presentation
was interesting for you and if you have
any questions please contact me I forgot
to add my email but it's a Razzie easy
Yuri dot enemies think of at Kaspersky
com yeah you can find it you can build
it up using schedule from this
conference so do I have some time for
questions yep cool any questions
thank you for questions no actually we
as you might know kaspersky was a target
of apt attack and resources like I came
to to my office after a trip and
understood that nobody use emails and
nobody use phones and in in a middle of
our were like workplace it is a desk
with a pen and paper with some around
things and names of suspicious files and
the biggest problem was actually said
there were no persistence on infected
machines so every time we rebooted
machine we the machine was clean and but
fully non-persistent like finalists
malware it can be a full achieved by
attackers that if they know that they
can easily penetrate you once again so
there these attackers for example they
were one hundred percent sure that they
were which they would be able to write
in fact system once again it is achieved
by using zero days or it is achieved as
you said for example by using
vulnerabilities in rotors and sai staff
that is not easily easily monitored and
not easily patched yes so we are moving
to a world where would there would be a
way
persistent modules on in the network any
other questions if you're in the second
floor you gotta yell because we can't
see you oh yeah or you can jump down you
okay actually yes the easy maybe they
can't go and the bark but they can use
infected systems as a debacle also their
documentation is freely available so
they can use it plus they can get
developer versions and use it to debug
malware okay thanks for question as I
said is there is no easy solution yeah
I'm like a threat intelligence guys but
most effective way is to have several
layers of protection certainly and like
you can just switch on 1 way switch off
one layer and
be secured because attackers will
identify that you don't have this layer
of security it means that they can go
through this hole to your network when
we are talking about monitoring traffic
and most cases they use HTTPS ssl
connection to get the traffic out of the
network or dns they worked but what you
can do you can change for look for
anomalies it's not very easily
implemented but you know it is
implemented several solutions our
company provides such solution that
looks for such anomalies in network
traffic and tries to detect it it called
kaspersky anti targeted attacks platform
actually so yeah it is possible but you
need to implement some nice logic inside
of this system because if your security
officer will get like 100 or 1000
notifications like in on second day he
will just stop small or watching these
notifications it's very hard to find
very very needed and really tied to
target to the tech connections and error
questions
Thanks I adhere like we saw already
several attacks when for example
printers were used as an initial attack
vector with us so I T is growing very
fast and it's like a disease so for
security officers like after the
University everything looks for you when
you first came to office its first shock
because you think that your security
perimeter is like server and a lot of
work stations but unfortunately it is
not your security perimeter right now
with the workstations I like phones
different finishes everything and it all
generate traffic sand it all connected
to internet the worst thing is that
consumer electronic life time is very
short so when when the issues you device
on the market the lifetime of these
devices like two months after this the
developers of this device they are
already doing some new device and if you
will find some vulnerabilities and sent
them to a vendor vendor would say ok it
will be patched in the next release of
this device which means that users it
water is this device already will never
ever get any update it is the common
situation and certainly hackers can use
it to interest rate at work but they
still have more efficient way to get
into and you know the answer
spearfishing because people still
clicking and still opening documents and
people are like most
people do have updated versions of PDF
Reader office suit so they just don't
need right now to use it as a user I OT
as a vector but they can do it we think
again I'm just going to start with the
questions at this point because of the
time but thank you again for the
presentation thank you very much Thank
You organizers for game kappa baby