I know most of you still don't consider
Microsoft as a good security provider
but Microsoft is changing their whole
strategy when it comes to endpoint
protection in fact the name when those
defender is not just the antivirus we
all used you know and perhaps choose not
to trust now Microsoft Defender ATP or
advanced threat protection is the new
thing and it's a brand name that
consists of many products not just only
the anti-malware all those products are
working together tightly using the power
of the cloud and the signals from
Microsoft threat intelligent to deliver
a comprehensive solution that can
protect endpoints from zero day attacks
and most sophisticated malware out there
as an example when this defender smart
screen block low reputation web
downloads and even malicious websites
while Windows Defender endpoint
protection monitors all windows
processes and files and then their
minutes or cleans any infection found
the next innovation that comes with
Microsoft Defender ATP is the ability to
automate the responses when an attack is
detected which is possible through a
recent acquisition to a company called
hexa dyed so that security admins don't
need to worry much about responding to
threats as this is taken care of by the
new automation capability and the new
way of defending against attacks is by
utilizing the power of the cloud and the
intelligent security graph at Microsoft
Microsoft intelligent security graph
provides rich signals from vast security
intelligence machine learning and
behavior analytics that Microsoft's
allow you to consume and use to enhance
your protection and detection speeds so
when Windows Defender encounters a new
file for example that it does not know
if it's bad or good file it sends a file
query to the cloud hey cloud do you know
about this file now if the cloud knows
about this files it will provide the
feedback to the endpoint otherwise it
will ask the endpoint to send a sample
that client holds the file and uploads
the sample to the cloud the cloud
services will process the sample and
shake against machine learning
classifiers trying to find out whether
that file is good or not and then if the
file turned out to be holding a
malicious code the cloud will generate a
new signature to that file and send it
back to the client not only to that
client it will send it to all clients so
that when they encounter this file they
know already to block it now you can see
that many pieces came together to defend
against to these zero days attack you
need a strong endpoint detect and
respond engine at the endpoint level you
need the power of the cloud to help you
against zero day attacks and you need
the power of machine learning and AI at
the endpoint a data cloud to recognize
new type of malware that are seen for
the first time and you might be asking
does this mean the client needs to
consult the cloud and wait for an answer
and what if there is no internet
connection at that time well here is how
things are designed each Microsoft
defender client has local machine
learning models and behavior based
detection algorithms right so this means
you can use all that logic offline
without consulting the cloud this
operation takes only milliseconds but
the client can consult the cloud by
sending only metadata only metadata so
that cloud can use metadata beef's
machine learning models the determine if
the file is malicious or not this only
takes milliseconds also but if the cloud
requested a sample then sample analysis
based machine learning models are used
in the cloud which might take seconds
not milliseconds seconds now in certain
scenarios detonation based machine
learning models can be invoked which
might take minutes and big data
Elisa's can take up two hours what this
means is that the client will not wait
for minutes and hours if the file is
infected and the cloud could not
determine it is a bad file in seconds
the client will allow the file to run in
the background the cloud will continue
working and analyzing and might do the
tunisian piece ml models and big data
analysis to get the truth about that
file so other clients are notified and
updated although we lost patient zero or
that initial client who encountered the
file in the first place when it comes to
the cyber kill chain we find that
Microsoft Defender ATP fits in the
advanced threat detection area trying to
detect and prevent malware from
installing and using machine learning to
detect zero-day attacks now it's time
for our demo finally now attacks that
introduce file based malware using
socially engineered emails are quite
common recipients are tracked into
launching a backdoor that gives that
hackers control over what is now a
compromised machine now this demo
simulates that attack similarly the
attack that are launched using a
socially engineered word document in a
spear phishing email the attack is
designed to ensure that the receiver
does not suspect a thing and opens the
document the document however is repo
knives with crafted macro code that
silently drops and loads an executable
file into that machine the executable
then writes a registry key and creates a
scheduled task both commonly known auto
start extensible points after the attack
finishes we can explore and understand
how Microsoft Defender ATP detects and
respond to the attack and enables prompt
investigation and response in this demo
I will start by importing a machine to
Microsoft Defender ATP then I will open
an infected document from the user
machine the infected document drops a
bag
and creates a scheduled task for the
resistance I will then show you how
Microsoft Defender ATP can help you in
all phases of the incident response
management including detecting and
incident mitigation and containment
recovery and remediation you will then
get the chance to explore the Microsoft
Defender ATP management portal and see
all the new features let's go to part 1
of this demo onboarding a machine to
Microsoft Defender ATP in this demo we
are going to on board a demo machine to
Microsoft Defender ATP do that I will go
to Security Center at windows comm to
access the management portal then
settings and I will scroll down to find
the onboarding section under machine
management here you can see different
ways to deploy Microsoft Defender ATP
including Group Policy System Center
Configuration Manager and a local script
I will quickly choose local script and
click download package I will run this
script to my machine to unboard it to
Microsoft Defender ATP and as you can
see it takes couple of seconds now this
machine is protected and managed by
Microsoft Defender ATP so as you can see
there is no need to install anything
just running a script to guide this
machine to report to the right
Microsoft Defender ATP tenant and part
two of this demo I'm going to deliver a
malware to the demo machine let's
pretend that this machine is a Windows
machine of a user who received this Word
document it could be delivered to him by
email a chat window or by any other
means
now with the user opens that document he
sees this tempting yellow bar in the top
to enable editing and then of course
there is that macro bar that users
cannot resist and they feel they need to
help that enable content a few seconds
later a hidden PowerShell script is
launched from this documents malicious
macro and it performs the following
actions
first that macro drops an executable
file which represents the backdoor onto
the disk top folder then the scape goes
on to create a scheduled task to launch
the backdoor at a predefined time and
finally when the backdoor is launched it
creates an auto start entry under the
registry run key allowing it to stay P
resistant by starting automatically with
Windows you can also see that Microsoft
Defender 80p detects what's happening
and this is where we will continue the
demo by logging on to the Microsoft
Defender ATP management portal now that
the malware is delivered to the user
machine we are going in part three of
this demo to detect and investigate the
attack on Microsoft Defender ATP portal
let's switch to our defender role and
explore the attack from the soft point
of view in the Microsoft defender ATP
portal located at Security Center dot
windows comm Microsoft Defender ATP
applies correlation analytics and
aggregate or related alerts into one
incident entity allowing the Sauk
analyst to understand and deal with
complex threads across the organization
with the right visuals as we see here
let me select this incident and then
open the incident page you can see in
the incident page all alerts related to
this incident all machines involved
investigations evidence and graph here
I'm at the alerts page reviewing the
incident alert list and Falls the
progression of the attack from this view
you can dive into individual alerts you
can also see all machines affected by
this attack here we have three machines
for example with high security risk the
graph is also a great visualization that
shows all machines involved in this
attack and all entities involved so for
our machine we can see there is a
PowerShell script involved and you can
see the hash value of that script the
script creates a scheduled task to
persist after reboots here is also the
office word process that starts the
whole attack when a user opened the
infected word document and finally you
can see executable file or
door that was dropped from the infected
word document now let me go to the demo
three machine and as you can see each
machine protected by Microsoft Defender
ATP has its own page on the machine page
you can see different sections like
alerts timeline security recommendations
software inventory and discovered
vulnerabilities you can see also the
risk level of that machine the logged on
user and basic information about the
machine like the domain membership and
operating system information let me open
this alert as we try to reproduce how
the attack took place the alert is a
PowerShell dropped a suspicious file on
this machine you can see the process 3
here we have the Windows Explorer L
process and the word document that
triggers the PowerShell script now that
script
the two things drops a backdoor and
creates a scheduled task as you can see
here you can also go deeper and see the
full PowerShell script that was invoked
on that machine and the hash value of
that script you can also see the hash
value of the backdoor file and this is
useful if we want to search if the same
backdoor exist on other machines now if
you want to know more details about this
scheduled task that was created by this
attack to persist after reboots you can
see here the comment used to create a
scheduled task by the malware this is so
powerful I will go to the alerts page
again and let's open this alert
suspicious PowerShell command line and
as you can see you have the same process
three and even a nice graph of showing
all entities related to this PowerShell
here you can see the same PowerShell
script is invoked on a machine called
demo one which is so important to know
not only we discover the attack but now
we can reimagine how it happens and what
machines were infected I will go now to
the machines timeline to get more
details about all events happening on
that machine
to ease investigation here you can see
each and every process activities
recorded for every machine for example
you can see we have the office click to
run executable establishing a connection
to a remote IP you can see the comment
line that was run the hash of the
executable and the remote IP URL and
even the port number now let me filter
the time line for alert related events
and we now have a filtered view of all
suspicious activities in that machine
including be suspicious partial command
line and to show you how this is a
powerful thing let me filter the view
and search for PowerShell you can see
immediately I can see all events and
suspicious activities that involves
PowerShell on this machine so for
example I have a PowerShell created a
script and the behavior is document
exploit and we have the Windward that
exe created the process PowerShell here
we have the context which is the user
called master now we know that the word
document created a process called
PowerShell dot exe which invoked a
suspicious PowerShell script that
dropped a backdoor and created a
scheduled task now that you learn how
this attack took place it's time to take
some actions I will go to the incident
section and open the incident page for
this attack you can see I have the
action and assistant section here I can
resolve the incident or assign the
incident to me so that others in the
sock team can acknowledge that I will be
investigating this one before conducting
the investigation however it's good idea
to look at the reports dashboard it
provides high-level information about
alerts and machines related information
generated in your organization the
report includes trends and summary
information on alerts and machines
knowing the trends and summaries related
to others and machines in your
organization can help identify where
focused improvements can be made for
example if you see a sudden spike in a
specific kind of alert you can drill
down and start investigating directly
from the irrelevant card to pivot into
the alert or machine queue with the
relevant filters applied and determined
what action to take to address an issue
finally I want to show you one of my
favorite tools to help you investigate
incidents remember that the infected
word document was found on the machine
that drops a backdoor executable and
invoked a suspicious power shield I can
copy the hash of the word document and
use the search bar to see if this word
document exists on any of my other
machines doing that gives me more
information about this document like the
digital signature and hash values and
whether this document was seen on other
organizations globally to give you more
insight if this is a targeted attack or
not you will also get alerts related to
this document and the most important
part is you get a list of machines with
Microsoft Defender 80 pcs that file a
new organization in this case we have
three machines where this word document
get dropped this is important for you as
a security professional because it's not
just mitigating the threat on one
machine but you really want to see if
this attack spread to other machines and
then cover all infected machines during
your investigation before we end up this
demo let me show you another interesting
feature called automated investigation
Microsoft Defender ATP can start an
investigation and automate a lot of
actions without human interactions and
using machine learning here you can see
Microsoft Defender ATP recognizes a
dangerous tool called mimic ads running
on one of my machines and it
automatically started an automated
investigation for me if you watch one of
the famous crime-scene investigation or
CSI TV series you know that
investigators at the crime scene start
by gathering evidences and ask witnesses
to learn more about what just happened
this is the same thing we have here
under the investigation graph we have
the dead body which
the machine or machines list we have the
witness list people who might know more
about this crime and in our case we have
the entities analyzed so Microsoft
Defender ATP is investigating two
thousand three hundred forty two files
one hundred and fifty processes in this
machine
two hundred sixty two services and
couple of drivers and the TV series the
investigator will look at the list of
phone calls made by the victim before
the crime happens and here Microsoft
Defender ATP is investigating the list
of IP addresses this machine talked to
during that period and all this
investigation to all these entities is
finished after 45 seconds only by
defender ATP this is the true power of
automation we have the list of alert
part of this investigation
list of machines infected a view of all
entities involved in this investigation
as you can see we have three thousand
four hundred twenty entities involved
here and the investigation log which is
list of action
Microsoft Defender ATP talk during this
investigation and we have one pending
action that defender ATP asked me to
confirm before closing this
investigation I already approved this
pending action which is to quarantine
Democrats folders and executable in part
four of this demo we are going to log
into Microsoft Defender ATP portal and
collect investigation package from the
infected machine when your forensic team
is involved to understand how the attack
happened and truly understand the depth
of the attack the first thing they want
to do is to collect as much information
from the infected machine Microsoft
Defender ATP gives you the ability from
the management portal to go and collect
an investigation package that your
forensic team can use so here I am
logged to the Microsoft Defender ATP
management portal and I can see I have
couple of alerts and they have some
machines at risks let me quickly choose
demo three machine and open the machine
page I can quickly see the risk
level of that machine obviously there is
one incident with seven active alerts so
it might worth investigating
you can see a list of actions in the top
bar as this action you as security
professional can perform remotely from
the management portal without going to
the machine itself one of the actions is
collect investigation package if I click
it this will send a request to the local
Microsoft Defender ATP agent on that
machine instructing it to collect
forensic information right now from that
machine and send the results back to the
Microsoft Defender ATP cloud services
and then make it available to me as a
security professional from the portal so
that I can continue my investigation I
already did that so in the Action Center
I can see there is an item waiting for
my review I can see the investigation
package is now ready for me to review I
will open it quickly and see what's
inside
here you can see a lot of information
made available for you to help you in
your investigation let me start by the
auto runs as most attacks involve
modifying the auto run on machines to
persist after reboots so it's a good
thing to review the author and
configuration for the infected machine
you also get a list of installed
programs on that machine the list
contains information about each
application installed on the machine the
date of installation and other more
detailed information for you to review
next we have the network connections
very important piece of information if
the attack is still happening on that
machine you want to learn about what
this machine is communicating with so
here you have the active network
connections on that machine including
ports and IPs this machine is
communicating with right now you can
also get both DNS cache and ARP cache
just in case DNS poisoning or ARP
poisoning is taking place in this attack
and to help you understand how the
machine is performing name resolution
you also get the firewall execution log
and the IP configuration of the machine
which might become handy for your
forensic team the investigation package
also includes a list of processes
running on that machine which gives you
deep inside about what is happening
inside that box without even touching
that machine you also get the scheduled
tasks information to learn if an
attacker creates a scheduled task on
that machine perhaps to persist after
reboots as you can see in the excel
sheet here you get a lot of information
about each scheduled task on that
machine now my favorite one is the
security Event log here you can search
inside the security log files of the
infected machine and analyze all
security events to help you understand
more about the attack happening next you
get a comprehensive information about
services running on the remote machine
including service name running state
service account used to run each service
and the associated process ID for
running services you get also
information about SMP sessions taking
place on that machine because remember
attackers might move from machine to
another by using pass the hash technique
and they can use SMP for lateral
movement so here you get a list of all
SMP sessions
system information is another good
information you get as part of the
investigation package to learn more
about the machine and the hardware
profile
finally you get information about all
local groups on that machine as you can
see here you also get information about
session information so you can see that
a user code master is connecting to this
remote machine using RDP protocol you
get a forensic investigation summary
file containing information about how
Microsoft Defender ATP collected all
this information together for example
Microsoft Defender ATP agent on that
machine ran this command to collect the
process list and generate a CSV file
this can help you as a security
professional to learn which commands you
can use to collect forensic information
which I believe is so handy in part 5 of
this demo we are going to explore
Microsoft Defender ATP remediation
actions like running antivirus can
restrict app execution and isolate
machine
these can be considered your mitigation
and containment tools in your incident
response management I am at the
Microsoft defender ATP management portal
and I can see I have many alerts in the
active alerts section I can find all
machines at risk here so I will check on
the demo 3 machine to zoom in and see
what's happening on that machine
here you can get the risk level of the
machine and all associated alerts in the
bar above
you also get list of actions you can do
remotely to that machine as part of the
investigation or response process you
can remotely initiate an anti-virus scan
to help identify and remediate malware
that might be present on a compromised
machine you can select the scan type
that you'd like to run you can choose
between a quick or a full scan I will
type a comment and select yes to start
the scan now immediately the Action
Center shows the scan information as you
can see here now on the machine itself
you can see that the scan completed
successfully returning back from the
Microsoft Defender ATP management portal
perspective the Machine time line will
include a new event reflecting that a
scan action was submitted on that
machine Windows Defender Av alerts will
reflect any detection that surfaced
during the scan this action is available
for machines on Windows 10 version 1 709
or later a Windows Defender anti virus
scan can run alongside other antivirus
solutions whether Windows Defender AV is
the active antivirus solution or not so
say for example you have Symantec
AntiVirus running on that machine and
you are not using Windows Defender
anti-malware or real-time scanning you
can still invoke a remote antivirus scan
from Microsoft Defender ATP portal and
this will wake up the Windows Defender
anti-malware engine if it is not the
primary anti-malware service on that
device and asked to run a quick or full
scan depending on your choice in
addition to the ability of containing
an attack by stopping malicious
processes by running an anti-virus scan
you can also look down the device so
that only programs and executable signed
by Microsoft are allowed to run on the
device and anything else will be blocked
this method of restriction can help
prevent an attacker from controlling
compromised machines and performing
further malicious activities so let us
restrict app execution on the machine I
will type a comment and select yes
restrict app execution now immediately
the Action Center shows that the app
restriction command is building as I am
running on the machine itself you can
immediately see what the user can see on
the machine I get a notification that
the device is restricted along with a
message explaining what is happening on
that machine remember that this action
only prevents any program not signed by
Microsoft from running on that machine
so the user can open Microsoft Office
applications without any problems and
even browse the web but if the user
tries to install anything that's signed
by Microsoft
like for example installing Adobe Reader
for example this action will be blocked
along with a notification explaining to
the end-user what just happened
this is a good balance between security
and usability from security perspective
we are restricting executing malicious
code but from the other side the user
can open Outlook Excel and communicate
using Microsoft themes for example so
that he can still be productive while
security team's investigating the
problem now depending on the severity of
the attack and the state of the machine
you can choose to reverse the
restriction of applications policy after
you have verified that the compromised
machine has been remediated and you can
see the action appearing in the Action
Center which becomes the hub of
notification for all actions performed
on that machine so you can track back
all actions performed by you or anyone
in the security operation team over time
now that the app restriction is
moved we can try to install Adobe Reader
on the machine again and as you can see
there is nothing preventing you from
doing so now just keep in mind that for
the app restriction to work you need two
things first you need to be running
Windows 10 version 1 709 or later and
this feature is available if you are
using Windows Defender antivirus as your
malware engine now depending what the
severity of the attack and the
sensitivity of the machine you might
want to isolate the machine from the
network this action can help prevent the
attacker from controlling the
compromised machine and performing
further activities such as data
exfiltration and lateral movement this
machine isolation feature disconnects
the compromised machine from the network
while retaining connectivity to Windows
Defender ATP service which continues to
monitor the machine so your machine will
not be able to connect to any IP except
the IPS of the Windows Defender ATP
cloud services so that you can keep an
eye on what's happening on that machine
and continue your investigation
now if the machine is running Windows 10
version 1 709 or later you get another
cool feature you can do a selective
isolation which means you can see this
machine is not allowed to connect to any
IP except three services number one is
the Microsoft Defender ATP cloud
services the second one is the exchange
online services and third is the Skype
for business services as you can see
here this means you don't want the user
to be able to do anything on the machine
in terms of network connectivity except
using Outlook and Skype for business
which makes it easier for the user to
contact the help desk or the other way
around it is easier for the security
team to contact the user of the machine
using Outlook or Skype for business
explaining to him what is happening now
if I choose to isolate the Machine the
end user of the machine will receive a
notification card stating that the
network is disabled and that your IT
administrator has caused Windows
Defender to disconnect your device and
you should contact IT Help Desk
now just a reminder the full isolation
works for Windows 10 version 1 703 or
later while the Selective isolation is
available on Windows 10 version 1 709 or
later selective isolation means the
machine can only talk to Microsoft
Defender ATP cloud services and allow
the user to use Outlook and Skype for
business now depending on the severity
of the attack and the state of the
machine you can choose to release the
machine from isolation after you have
verified that the compromised machine
has been remediated
in part six of this demo we are going to
explore more features and Microsoft
Defender ATP that helps you harden to
your environment by following security
and configuration recommendations from
Microsoft we are going to explore secure
score advanced hunting threat analytics
and threat and vulnerability management
in the Microsoft defender ATP I'm logged
onto Microsoft Defender ATP management
portal and I will go to the secure score
section the security score dashboard
expands your visibility into the overall
security posture of your organization
from this dashboard you will be able to
quickly assess the security posture of
you all organization see machines that
require attention as well as
recommendations for actions to further
reduce the attack service in your
organization all in one place from there
you can take action based on the
recommendation configuration baselines
now the Microsoft security or tile you
see here is a reflective of the sum of
two things first the Windows Defender
security controls that are configured
according to the recommended baselines
and the office 365 secure score it
allows you to drill down into each
portal for further analysis just in one
place you can also improve this score by
taking the steps in configuring each of
the security controls in the optimal
settings now let me go to the threat
analytics section threat analytics is a
set of interactive reports published by
the Microsoft Defender ATP research team
as soon as emerging threats and
outbreaks are identified the reports
help you assess the impact of threats in
your organization and provides
recommended actions to contain increase
organizational resilience and prevent
specific threats so let me open this
threat for example and you can see
executive summary information and deep
dive on how this threat actually works
in a nice visual you also get some
mitigation steps and detection details
all to help you understand how this
thread actually works the nice thing is
that for this image
threat you can see a list of machines
vulnerable to this threat and whether
this threat is mitigated across all your
workstations I will go now to the threat
and vulnerability management section
which helps you detect and assess
threats across endpoints for example I
can see many areas of improvement in my
environment these areas are listed here
such as the application the OS Network
accounts and security controls if we
take the operating system area of
improvement for example we can see our
score is 41 out of 183 which means I can
do better by following Microsoft
recommendations let me click on the
operating system improvement area and
learn more how I can raise my
configuration score here I get list of
security recommendations like this one
right here and I get information about
the security recommendation and how to
harden my workstations along with list
of machines who don't comply which I
believe is a great insight that helps
you quickly fix this on the list of
machines here instead of just going to
every machine and trying to solve the
problem if we go to the security
controls improvement area you can see
also a couple of recommendations like
enabling smart screen some firewall
rules configuration recommendations and
enabling pet Locker on Windows machines
again for each one of these
recommendations you get the list of
machines that don't comply now your
objective would be to raise your overall
configuration score by hardening pure
machines from emerging threats and
following Microsoft recommendations
another area I want to talk about is
advanced hunting which is a super
powerful tool during your investigations
here you can get the schema for
information collected my one true soft
defender ATP and this helps you build
your own queries but don't worry you
have some ready queries for you made by
Microsoft engineers like searching for
heading PowerShell windows across all
your requisitions here you can see the
query language which is quite simple and
now you can see we have one machine
called demo three that Microsoft
Defender ATP
agent observed the creation of hidden
powershell windows this can be a
suspicious activity that worth
investigating
you can also query for all internet
downloads across all your machines and
here we have this machine and this
machine downloaded Adobe Reader from the
internet using a browser now this become
handy if for example you are
investigating an infected machine and
you want to filter this output to see
what this machine downloaded from the
internet during an attack finally
remember that attacks happen usually
using the context of a compromised user
so if you suspect that an attacker stole
the credential for a certain user and
use that credential to perform pass the
hash to move to other machines you can
switch your investigation from focusing
on the workstation to tracking
identities and what they are doing
across machines and identity tracking
allows you to track lateral movement
inside your environment so I can search
for a user called master and ask
Microsoft Defender ATP to return all his
activities across all machines so here
we have the user logging on to two
machines and we can zoom in and see what
activities or others are associated with
this user on a certain machine which is
so powerful now Microsoft has a great
solution called as your advanced threat
protection or as your ATP that can
integrate with Microsoft Defender ATP
and fill the gap when it comes to
detecting anomalies using compromised
credentials I highly recommend that you
have a look to add your advanced threat
protection and enable the integration
between the two products
I'm going to leave you with some
resources to learn more about Microsoft
defender ATP to help you detect attacks
while they are happening in your
environment if you work in the security
field you most likely know what is
incident response you have a security
incident which is a result of attack or
malicious or intentional actions and
part of your role is to respond to
security incidents when they happen now
an effective incident response
management is handled in several steps
or phases you have detect response
mitigate report recovery remediation and
lessons learned phase which feeds back
to the detect phase again to improve
your detection and response let's now
see how Microsoft Defender ATP features
are mapped to different phases of your
incident response management in order to
respond to an incident you need to
detect it first so Microsoft Defender
ATP alerts help you detect incidents
when they happen on your machines after
detecting and verifying an incident by
analyzing the alert in Microsoft
Defender ATP management portal and
depending on the severity of the
incident you might activate your
incident response team to help
investigating the incident assessing the
damage and in very mediation and
collecting evidence in the response
phase Microsoft Defender ATP consolidate
related alerts into an incident so any
set of dealing with dozens or hundreds
of alerts Microsoft Defender ATP will
automatically group related alerts and
create an incident for you you can
assign the incident to individuals and
you can change the status of incidents
in the portal this gives your security
team or your Incident Response Team a
focused view on what needs attention
inside the incident they can see all
machines involved in that incident all
alerts evidences and a nice visual graph
to help your team in their investigation
now in the response phase also your
forensic team or Incident Response Team
might need to collect more information
about the machine like what services are
running on that machine list of
applications installed auto run
configuration and more
here you can use Microsoft Defender ATP
collect investigation package to help
you collect such information right from
within the management portal and without
even touching the infected machine next
we have the mitigation phase and let me
be clear on what this phase means
mitigation and incident response
management attempts to contain an
incident because one of the primary
goals of effective Incident Response is
to limit the effect or scope of an
incident this can be for example
disconnecting the network interface to
prevent the malware from spreading or
prevent the attacker from leaking data
outside now in this phase it might be
important not to turn off the infected
machine when containing an incident as
doing so means you are going to lose the
temporary files and data stored in
memory or it might be you want to study
and learn what the attacker is doing on
that machine without letting him know
you discovered the attack now Microsoft
Defender ATP offers two great mitigation
features first we have the app
restriction feature which restricts the
machine from running any software not
signed from Microsoft and the isolate
machine feature which is exactly like
disconnecting the network card of the
machine but with allowing that machine
to communicate with Microsoft Defender
ATP service so that you can monitor
what's happening with that machine
meanwhile after you mitigate the
incident you should report the incident
within your organization and perhaps
individuals outside the organization
this might be to comply with laws and
regulations and you can use Microsoft
Defender reports to help you in that
after you mitigate and report the
incident and after collecting all
evidences from that system the next step
is to recover the system or return it to
a fully functional State from the
Microsoft Defender ATP management portal
you can start an anti-virus scan on the
infected machine you can quarantine a
file or this might be happening
automatically for you by Microsoft
Defender ATP thanks to the new automated
investigation feature and the recent
acquisition of a company called hexa
diene now recovery might also mean
rebuilding the whole machine from any
image depending on the nature of the
attack in the remediation stage you
attempt to identify what allowed the
incident to occur and then implement
methods to prevent it from happening
again this includes performing
root-cause analysis here is where things
get interesting as Microsoft Defender
ATP offers many things to help you
identify what happened across all your
machines you already have the
investigation package you collected
earlier which is a great source of
information to learn about open network
connections SMP sessions local groups
process lists and more information from
the infected machine you can also use
the Machine Timeline feature in the
Microsoft Defender ATP management portal
to reproduce all events happened on that
machine during the attack and you can
even go back in time and see what
happened on that machine this includes
learning about what each process is
doing what network connections were
opened and by which executables you can
also use Microsoft Defender ATP advanced
hunting and write your own queries or
use the built-in queries available for
you in the management portal that allows
you to hunt for possible threats across
your organization using a powerful
search and query language and finally
you have the lessons learned phase here
you are trying to prevent this incident
from happening again and review your all
security posture Microsoft Defender ATP
offers a lot of capabilities that can
help you harden your environment by
following security recommendations
letting by Microsoft engineers the
secure score expands your visibility
into the overall security posture of
your organization from this dashboard
you will be able to quickly assess the
security posture of all your machines
threat analytics is a set of interactive
reports published by Microsoft Defender
ATP research team as soon as emerging
threats and outbreaks are identified the
reports help you assess the impact of
threats in your environment and provides
recommended actions to contain increase
the organization resilience and prevent
specific threats and you have that
thread
vulnerability and management capability
in Microsoft Defender ATP which helps
you detect and assess threats across
your endpoints by now you know how
Microsoft Defender ATP helps you in your
incident response management and in
hardening your environment by following
security and configuration
recommendations my Microsoft let's not
forget the role of automation and
machine learning that can significantly
reduce the work you should do in
responding to incidents
[Music]