morning for my side my name is bachi
stukowski and it's a pleasure to present
you the preliminary work that we are
working on mess with respect to
disability and user experience this is
joint work with my supervisor Gabrielle
Ellen Seanie and we are from the Center
for security reliability trust at
University of Luxembourg so just to give
you a brief outline I'm gonna introduce
a bit the motivation about these
projects the methodology and preliminary
results that we have and what are the
next steps that we do in this direction
so I guess I do not need to explain much
to this community how Miss works
what type of use it has or how the
information is shared or could be shared
among the instances and communities but
it is important to know that there are
different types of users that come from
different types of organizations and
they have different purposes for which
they use the mese platform so we're
dealing with a very technically advanced
information sharing platform here and as
I said it has a diverse set of
stakeholders that are involved in this
platform they all have distinctive needs
and objectives and probably some of you
have experienced but as communicated by
Miss often there are sharing
difficulties so basically that are not
so much in the technical level but on
the social level in terms of certain
restrictions why people share
information or do not share information
how do they consume the information do
they trust the information or not so
there are a lot of issues that hover
let's say the technical layers of this
platform and as research suggests as
well the importance of user experience
and usability let's say these aspects
are paramount for the successful
operation of an information sharing
platform and the amount of information
that is consumed and contributed towards
it so we set out to investigate
basically how do miss P users evaluate
the accessibility and user experience
aspects of the platform and more
specifically how do they perceive both
the pragmatic and hedonic qualities of
the system and I will explain a bit more
in detail now so we set out to
investigate this
as a first step via a quantitative
method called the user experience
questionnaire which is basically
combination of six scales with 26 items
that asks people to rate specific
aspects from to imposing views such as
for example do you find the system
annoying or enjoyable so they have to
pick a value between these two values so
there are 26 questions of this forum
that try to answer or get some
information about the attractiveness
perspicuity or basically how difficult
it is to learn the platform or the
system the product how it is efficient
what is the dependability the
stimulation and novelty of this platform
so just to give you an interdependence
of these scales basically the
attractiveness is a pure valence
dimension whereas the efficiency
dependability and price security are
more on the goal-directed aspects of the
platform or the pragmatic qualities and
then on the hedonic sides we have the
stimulation and novelty basically how do
people find these aspects as well which
usually in the past have not been
considered by usability studies so the
second part was to investigate a bit
more who are the users that use this
platform so basically the demographics
the background profile education etc and
some of the questions were what is the
company that you come from how long have
you been using miss etc and the last
part is one more quantitative scale
which is called the system usability
scale and I presume maybe some of you
might have come across it because it is
a more known or standardized scale that
has existed for more years than the you
EQ however with any like with all of the
other scales there are certain
limitations those things that we need to
take into account when deploying them
and in specifically in the s u.s. it
does not look into any of the user
experience for the hedonic aspects so
this is for example what it what
questions from the SES look like so at
the training session that was carried
out in March early this year
we had discussed with the team of circle
to try to get the preliminary feedback
from the participants of this training
session on a voluntary basis to tell us
how do they perceive the the MIS
platform etc so there were 50 people
that were the training session 25
responded 25 did not respond to the
questionnaire of those 25 24 were male 1
was a female they had 20 had a technical
or engineering background five were
non-technical in terms of education 19
were more than 75 percent anonymous
taken had the bachelor's degree or
higher when it comes to the age span we
can see that the largest group of people
were in the range of 26 to 235 so
relatively a young age group and when
when it comes to the prior experience
with Miss the majority of them had used
the system for less than six months out
of which from one to six months was the
largest group were basically eight
people when we asked them how often they
use NISP
the people that attended this training
session said that most of them said that
it is between once and three times per
week it's only a small number used it on
a daily basis and the next smaller group
seventeen was even less than one week
when it comes to the industry sector the
participants came from these let's say
industries the largest was banking I
don't know if it has to do the fact that
we did the training here in Luxembourg
but that was the case in this training
session and when it comes to user
profiles now this was interesting
because before the survey we thought
that people have a clear let's say role
but many of them actually see themselves
the software analysts in addition to
another role so this is how each of the
people have whisperer
basically how many have indicated it and
see themselves the software analyst in
addition to maybe some at some of the
other roles so it is interesting to see
that there are certain users that use
the platform for multiple purposes
actually okay so just to summarize so
48% were in this pain from 26 to 35 the
majority and I'll identify themselves as
security analysts they came from banking
the majority of them and while it was
the first training session for all of
them over 50% of them had used the
training materials or the virtual
machine before coming to the training
session which is one of the let's say
materials that cert circle provides okay
so these are the results of the
questionnaires and I presume this might
not necessarily mean much so I will try
to explain it within a larger context so
we'll start with the user user
experience questionnaire and basically
if we look at if we compare those means
against benchmark values we can see that
the miss platform is positively
evaluated on all aspects except for
perspicuity or basically those users
found it quite complex and difficult to
use the platform all on all the others
it is very good and especially on the
hedonic side which is actually excellent
or above-average so these benchmark
values are obtained from a data set and
that has been carried out or that
compromise comprises 401 studies with 18
more than 18,000 people so basically the
average estimate of different types of
platforms using this scale give us
certain benchmark values against which
we can compare other systems and of
course we need to take this with a bit
of a consideration but I will come to
the let's see the limitations in a
minute so when it comes to the hedonic
aspects so basically how people find the
platform in terms of novelty motivation
etc it is above average it is in the
best Henry's then present best results
when it comes to how easy it is to learn
the system that is let's say the aspect
that me is worst on 25% and when it
comes to the SU s so basically the third
and the second scale that I showed you
before
the average score is sixty four point
five again this is a benchmark value
that has been obtained by analyzing a
lot a large number of different products
etc where 68 is considered to be the
average value so basically sixty four
point five is considered to be below
average which again probably might be
due to the fact of the difficulty to
learn the platform etc so what we need
to mention here is that these findings
are based on a very small sample so
basically based on 25 responses so we
cannot really conclude anything strongly
however it can give us an early
indication or direction in which we can
try to explore further and that is
definitely what we would like to do so
using mixed methods and here I again
mention these quantitative surveys such
as the EU q but also using interviews
and other methods we would like to
understand better what are the biggest
usability user experience issues because
of course these surveys can only point
us to a direction but it does not they
do not really explain why people answer
these questions like that or why do they
find the platform difficult to learn etc
so we would like to complement within
the next period quantitative methods
using some interviews so I'll be here
throughout the day if any of you have
any feedback or comments I would be more
than happy to hear them but of course it
is on a voluntary basis so you're more
than welcome to also provide maybe some
other feedback where other ways through
the tip etc so just to mention as a the
final step I invite you all to take part
in the user experience survey which we
have ported into an online forum and
this will be basically provided I think
also with the latest training materials
and the link will be provided from from
the circle website but from my side that
is all for now and a thank you for the
intention if you have any questions feel
free to let me know either in person or
do
in this podium man thank you yes
so in relation to this trivia how long
do you plan to keep it open and then
wait until you get enough results just
to have a rough idea so I think we will
perform analysis on a continuous basis
but I would say we would have it at
least for six months but even more
hopefully it will be something that will
continue on and we will get continuous
feedback in terms of also to be able to
compare how the introduction of new
features might impact the overall
experience etc so it's not like some
stuff you've done here are also like
related to the threat Intel community so
maybe it'd be interesting to compare
with already's threat Intel wise or
maybe other similar software have you
considered doing that with similar
software that's an interesting question
so basically if we have more data we
will also be able to compare how
different people evaluate the platform
depending on their background depending
on their background their role etcetera
but as you say it would also be good to
compare different types of products
using these methodologies now we would
probably need to find a large enough
sample that uses both of these systems
so that we can compare and see how they
evaluate those systems or if it's if
it's an even bigger sample than maybe
not the same people need to necessarily
evaluate both systems but we need to
make sure that the sample of the users
that answer these questions is
representative so that we do not come to
some fall conclusions but I think that's
something definitely that could be done
thanks very much for this what's your
instrument clearly focused on what I
call the UI of the tool because it
occurs to me that there may be
particularly in some of the categories
of respondent
some conceptual issues like what's a
galaxy and that might be a separate set
of you know user experience issues then
why is this button disappearing at this
time kind of thing I just wanted to
where's this both either I what if
there's a connection between I don't
understand what you mean by matrix and
I'm not having a good experience with
the tool so the questions that are in
the scales they're independent from any
platform they can be applied as such
across different so there is no
ambiguity when it comes to the specifics
of the LAT form such as as you mentioned
specific features etc those are probably
things that could be investigated
furthermore in an interview but I would
not say that any bias was introduced via
the terminology that is used in the
platform and what the question is asked
because these are basically yeah
applicable throughout without any
consideration for the specific features
okay thank you
[Applause]