[Music]
foreign
with us today Siddharth is the supply
coordinator at uh Paramount
rehabilitation services he enjoys
learning about programming and malware
analysis and graduated from Delta
College with an associate's degree in
General Studies in 2019 and graduated
from a grand circus.net angular boot
camp this past February and Sarah's free
time you can find them in a bookstore
bookstore looking for something
interesting to read or in a coffee shop
drinking tea so we really appreciate
your time Siddharth and uh take it away
all right sounds good yo oh my name is
Siddharth
um you guys can just call me Sid
um and uh yeah my presentation is on
dissecting agent Tesla so let's just get
into it
all right so before we start just give
you guys a bit of an outline we're first
going to talk about
um malware analysis in general and how
it works
um we'll then cover a brief history of
agent Tesla from 2014 to 2022
um following that we'll discuss
really quick just its ID and
characteristics
then we'll roll into the automated
static
um
automated static and then Dynamic slash
behavioral analysis
uh move on again really quick to uh
indicators of compromise
go over ways to defend yourself against
it which are pretty simple
um common targets and then talk about
why recently in the past few months and
also throughout a little bit of 2020
it's been coming back so
here we go
so what is malware analysis well before
that what is malware so
um
malware is short for malicious software
and network analysis is the process of
examining a malware sample to determine
what it can do in the develop counter
measures against it
there are several stages of analysis
Depending on time available
the skill level the researcher detail
needed
and the size complexity of the sample
foreign
analysis stages are
the first is fully automated which can
include static dynamic or both
then there's manual static analysis
that is manual Dynamic analysis and then
at the end sorry again there's a manual
code reversing and what separates these
four analysis stages is
that fully automated is
the fastest the easiest the most service
level
and requires the least work from
an analyst
one second
oh here we go all right cool so one
second
yeah we got you great all right thank
you perfect so um
yeah like I said so
at the top level at a very high level um
the fully automated analysis whether it
includes static Dynamic analysis or both
is very easy to do
um in fact like you can simply take
hey you malware ID dump it into assault
into um
let's see some software like any dot run
and get an automated report generated
um and then after the automated oops
after the automated analysis
each stage after that increases in time
and complexity in the skill required and
um the amount of work
and so we'll be getting into those other
three into the 4-4 right now
so fully automated like I mentioned
fastest and easiest
um very service level but the purpose is
it can provide a good overview from
which analysts can start their
investigation and it's very useful in
handling large amounts of malware and
for quick
triage and you know deciding and for
those who don't know what triaging is
it's deciding whether or not like how
much of a threat something is and
whether it even deserves
whether it even deserves a deeper
analysis or
not so an example of that tool is any
dot run and uh virus total both of them
are web-based are basically websites you
can go to them like with a suspicious um
ID or hash copy and paste it into the
tool and once it's run it will it can
automate
both static and dynamic analysis give
you a simple report
but it does not allow for as much
control or as much detail as the
following stages
next up we have manual static analysis
it's called Static because the file is
examined without running
um
an example of a stack analysis tool is
ghidra an open source tool developed by
the National Security Agency and it is a
disassembler a disassembler is
essentially takes
um
let's see
they take some binary code and I believe
it returns it to assembly
and what this does is
it provides information for the analyst
to decide what to focus on or if again
to focus on it at all and versus just
moving on to something else examples of
static analysis findings are
hashes metadata which is data about the
data like you know the date that the
file was created or
um the data was modified things like
that and also any embedded resources
compared to
um
the automated analysis it doesn't take
that much more time and doesn't take
that much more work in general but then
next up you have
a manual Dynamic analysis so it's called
dynamic because War isn't static you
don't you simply examine the file
without running but Dynamic is where all
that changes that's where the malware
was actually ran and examined however
because
malware can cause serious damage to both
a both the developers or the
Distributors
um system
but also researcher system at the same
time a safe environment is required on
both fronts so this is usually done
using virtual machines like personal box
or VMware or some other kind of sandbox
environment
um
Dynamic analysis requires more skill
time and control but it also allows for
greater details about the malware to be
discovered and um
tools used here are
x64 dbg or X32 dvg both of them are uh
different types of debuggers so the mail
will be ran and the same way for any
developers out there um the same way you
would
um you have a bug in a
software program you just like step
through that it's pretty much the same
thing
here
um
and examples of dynamic analysis
findings are processes Network traffic
and um
how the malware interactions with its
environment otherwise known as Behavior
Analysis and another cool thing that can
be done with Dynamic analysis that
cannot be done with static is
the
a creative and malware analysts can
imitate
um different parts of the environment
that I will reach out to like an email
server for example and then simply see
um what the malware can do in regards to
that so
then at the far end
um you have manual code reversing this
is the most time consuming and skill
intensive process and because of this
many investigations
um will not proceed with this step
the tools used are both disassemblers
and debuggers and decompilers and other
plugins and tools like the ones I
mentioned earlier all at the same time
um
Ida Pro is a well-known option and at
this stage memory analysis can help as
well
um
manual code reversing findings include
encrypted data
domain generation algorithm logic and
hidden capabilities that did not show up
in other stages
foreign
so a brief history of agent Tesla
um first showing up in 2014 agent Tesla
start off by being sold on a Turkish
WordPress site
however it would take I'd say what two
or three years before it really started
appearing on everybody's radar before
um a lot of reports of it started being
generated by different um companies and
um
the threat group that currently
distributes and modifies it seems to be
based in Nigeria and is referred to as
Swede by Cisco or silver
carrier by miter
and although Asian Tesla has faded in
and out of popularity over the years its
ease of use dedicated support and
constant Evolution has given its staying
power in various fishing campaigns in
fact
one of the common ways of obtaining it
is
through a dedicated website called agent
tesla.com where there's different
payment plans listed the same way you
would like pay for any other software in
each level can get you like a different
level of
support and set up updates
um
and so on and um all of that for an
extended period of time depending on
what someone is willing to pay and
because they make it so easy that's why
it's been around for so long so
let's see body and characteristics
um
miter's ID for it is s oops is s0331
it's classified as a rat which stands
for remote access Trojan we'll get into
that in the next slide
um
some characteristics that haven't
changed over the years are that it's
written.net
it mostly works as a key logger they can
do other things too
it can fill processes so for example
um
any process that say an analyst is
running that might be able to
um analyze it it can detect those and
possibly kill them so
basically it gets in the way of an
analyst trying to analyze it
um let's see its factors are that it's
delivered mostly through spam emails
either from
legitimate but compromised email
addresses or malicious email addresses
that look normal at first glance
um it communicates through meaning it
sends once it gets its data
from the victim computer
it sends that data back to
in to like a mail server through SMTP
the most most the time but it can also
use FTP HTTP and recently as in like
within the last few months it's also
been seen sending data to private
telegram chat rooms
now let's talk about what a remote
access Trojan is
or a rat for short
it allows attackers to control computers
similar to what would be allowed by
System administrators
but without the um without like some of
the restrictions that even system
administrators would have
um a sophisticated attacker may use
remote access Trojan to scope out the
environment for a long time before
making any moves and this would not only
allow them to
gain more knowledge about the
environment but also avoid detection for
a long period of time
so
Asian Tesla Beyond just being an
information stealer can also create a
jumping point for an attacker to infect
more emails and steal more credentials
which is why I mentioned the previous
slide that
um these spam emails can come from
legitimate but compromised email
addresses which makes it a lot harder to
deal with
all right so we got an automated
analysis with any dot run
um
as you can see here there's
one second so
uh you have let's see one dropper I
guess one dropper file here you have
another dropper file right here
and then finally you have agent Tesla
right over here so
I'll be discussing more about dropper
files in another slide but it's just a
general preview of what it looks like it
seems like agent Tesla no matter what um
year I look at
um from the reports it seems like it
always seems to follow the same format
of
two dropper files followed by the
payload itself
so
static analysis um agent system will
start off by identifying the computer
name the user's name
IP information internet connectivity
processor name and information
memory and operating system
and it'll start setting those over for
use by the threat actor
um I mentioned earlier that um Asian
Tesla is a keystroke logger so that's
one things they can do but it can also
gather screenshots it can steal
credentials for example the ones that
are saved in think um
autofill
autofill information that some people
store in uh browsers
um it can still browser cookies and can
also check if another you know piece of
like Asian Tesla malware has already
infected the same host computer and shut
it down if it has
and um
finally after it's collected all this
data that I mentioned
it can in some cases uninstall itself
in order to cover its tracks and make it
look like it was never there in the
first place
so Dynamic behavioral analysis like I
said it usually contains two dropper or
executable files before the actual
payload agent Tesla file starts up
the purpose of a dropper file is to
evade surface level detections and look
as harmless as possible
and also dropper files can
get in the way of analysis efforts and
slow things down
some more stuff so agent Tesla will
check if it's running on a virtual
machine so like those sandbox Solutions
I mentioned earlier which and which um
analysts will use to study agent Tesla
it'll detect first if it is running on a
virtual machine
and if it detects I believe
I believe it's like if it doesn't detect
user input it'll shut itself down after
a certain period of time without running
um
in one case it injects code into Reg
assembly like dot exe to collect Target
info like the name of the computer and
credentials
and it also checks for network
connectivity once data is collected and
use SMTP in most cases to send stolen
data to a remote mail server
foreign
domains are pretty I think out of all
three indicators of compromise the ones
that are most useful are the hashes
because
like I mentioned earlier you can take
you can simply copy and paste one of
these hashes put them into any.run or
virus total and check and see if anyone
else has uploaded the same thing whether
it's malicious or not what um
anti-virus Solutions will
detect it or not and go from there as
well as look at similar hashes
so um defense against Asian Tesla
um
it's pretty simple use a well-known
well-supported antivirus as I saw in
virustotal debt not all antivirus
Solutions will detect the same malware
sample not all of them
have um
have I guess encountered it or have you
know checked for it also make sure you
keep it updated
watch out for strange emails and
seemingly innocuous attachments so one
example of you know a seemingly
innocuous attachment are um
let's see an Excel file but you'll have
at the end of the Excel file attachment
it will have another
file name after that but most people
will just look at the Excel file
attachment and think like okay it's
legit and then start downloading it
and uh when in doubt
don't click the attachment or link to
another website simply set it aside and
have somebody else look at it
so common targets are
there's a wide variety of turrets but
um let's see
I believe there's a Spam there's um
fishing campaigns throughout armor
late 2020 that focused on energy and
manufacturing companies mostly
um
some fishing campaigns that have used
Asian Tesla have taken advantage of high
profile events around a lot of people's
minds like kova 19 and the Ukraine
conflict
so one way of fishing campaign using
agent Tesla alert victims was by sending
an email
regarding
through crane Russia's supply chain
conflicts with a executable file titled
req supplier survey and that would of
course get a lot of people's attention
because they're worried about you know
supply shortages or and so on and in the
early stages the pandemic there was a
campaign a fishing campaign that
advertised base fast supplies with a
malicious PDF attached so
current state so as of um
April
it is currently ranked number three in
top malware families by checkpoint
security and it affects two percent of
global organizations
and some of the reasons for
Resurgence are like I said in the first
slide ease of use friendly support in
setting things up
um increased options for communicating
all that to the SEC to success of this
malware telegram is sending data back to
a private telegram chat room is actually
the latest
um
like communication option
for this malware the new version is
harder to statically analyze and no
longer uses
um
AES for encryption it uses um
I believe it's pronounced zore to
obfuscate and make it harder to like
statically analyze
um they can extract data from more
Targets in the latest version and buy
more targets I mean
um more browsers for the most part
um the fact that it's been successful
for years as to its credibility like I
said this thing has been it's existence
since 2014 but it's been it's been
popular it's been useful since like 2015
2016 and 2017 and it's just stayed
around
continuing to be modified
um in small ways to make sure that it's
successful in a wide variety of
scenarios
all right so acknowledgments
um I'd like to thank Grimm for allowing
me to present I'd like to thank my
mentor uh Miss Whitlow for giving me
guidance and resources that I never
would have found otherwise
I like my fat I'd like to thank my
family for supporting and encouraging me
these past two weeks and uh lastly thank
you you know all of you are watching for
taking the time out of your day
um it means a lot
and here are some of my sources
and
my contact information I'm on Discord at
Sid M uh zero two five three and then
I'm on LinkedIn as well so you guys can
reach me there if you'd like
thank you guys so much
thank you sir we really appreciate your
time it was great you're getting some
Applause in the in the Discord Channel
too so thank you very much
um I'll check your questions here hang
on
Joe you got anything uh while I look in
the other place we've got two questions
after you're done with those two I've
got one go ahead and if anyone else has
any other questions please uh write them
down in the chat uh we're monitoring and
we can ask them on your behalf
um so uh did you want me to ask the two
that have already been asked
um yeah sure I'm not seeing them so go
ahead okay cool no problem all right uh
so we'll Sid make the slide deck
available for us to download if so where
can we download it
um if you're on Discord already uh you
can probably post the link in the
Discord if you if you don't mind
otherwise uh if you have a location for
the sides or if you're planning on
sharing those
yeah I absolutely plan on sharing these
so um I can uh should I just like copy
should I just like um copy and paste to
like
um get into like the Discord chat or is
there a certain area I have to like uh
cop like um attach it to or
I mean Discord chat seems as good as any
place I think you could just uh copy
paste it unless it's got videos or
anything that makes it too big for
Discord
nope none uh let us know if you have any
problems we'll find a place to host it
for you
okay all right cool and then uh second
question any tips and tricks to
de-obfuscate heavily obfuscated code or
scripts during static analysis
any tips to de-obpluscate
I'm gonna be honest like I didn't I
don't know the answer to that question I
didn't dive too much into
um how to de-obiscate
um
I have the obfuscate files in general at
any step of the process so
um sorry about that ah no problem I mean
it's it's a pretty common thing that you
have to balance as an analyst like how
much do you want to dive into actually
the obfuscating the code versus how much
do would you much rather pull from doing
Dynamic analysis
um because
there's also the balance of when you're
an author of malware as well is you
don't want obfuscate too much because
that's a signature like it is very much
a signature that can be detected even on
even on the wire so it's not something
you want to rely on too much
um and then you have the extreme end of
it where it's like VM protect where
everything is just in this encrypted VM
that all the sys calls are the only
thing you'll ever see and it's like well
again like that is something that's
pretty easy to pick up on and it's
pretty noisy
um as far as uh
anti-virus signatures go
um right and um I just wanted to add in
real quick like um I was reading on a
blog post that um even like
um
I'm not sure like if how much this was
back from the obfuscation but even like
a larger file size can you know alert
um malware analysts that like okay like
some things
um they're like something's kind of
fishy here and you know lead them to
um examine the file a little more deeply
so I mean there's that too also super
small files are pretty big red flag as
well uh I've definitely had someone tell
me this is how we caught it we just
sorted by size and I just laughed so all
you can do
all right and the the one question I had
was I I don't know if you've played
around with instrumentation it's not
necessarily A malware versus Engineers
required toolkit but I use it a lot in
doing vulnerability analysis and back
when I spent some time in a malware shop
uh where you're essentially just trying
to exercise the binary wall it's in a
sandbox or in your Dynamic analysis
environment uh trying to hit as much of
the functionality as possible and some
of it can be automated but like I felt
like most of the time I spent massaging
it just to try to get it going I was
curious if you have any experience with
instrumentation
so um when he's like you're just talking
about um
just pools in general Beyond like you
know any dot run and buyers total right
right so um
I don't I mean early on like um like two
weeks ago
um I did try setting up a um was it
I tried going through a malware unicorns
um
reverse engineering uh like lab setup
and ah yeah well the resources were out
of date so I couldn't get the lab set up
so what I ended up doing for this whole
presentation was
um just reading blog posts and uh
like reading blog posts that like
reading blog posts and write-ups that
other people had done in order to figure
out
um what agent Tesla did so I don't have
any I have virtual box on my computer
but I don't have an environment set up
yet and um
I think like I don't know I
I want to be a bit careful when I'm
setting up the environment because just
like a few weeks ago
um I believe some an attacker actually
compromised their own system with agent
Tesla on by you know I'm not sure how
but it just goes to show what can happen
if
um you're not careful with environment
setup so
that's something I want to take some
more time on
yeah there's some uh interesting VMS
published
um I think mandian has one that's pretty
popular I forgot it's called flare or
flame uh yeah I think it's a flare VM
and then I've also heard of uh remnucks
as well so
nice
yeah those those often includes will
include a lot of the tools you'll need
which is really nice because trying to
set up your own image uh like sometimes
you'll you'll just get the sandbox
running and just the way you want it
um but then trying to collaborate uh can
be pretty difficult if you don't have a
standardized set of tools
um
but I I believe some of those do include
something like instrumentation so that's
definitely worth checking out
all right does anyone else have any more
questions
um happy to ask on your behalf otherwise
we can play a video
uh until
1400 which so we've got about 20 minutes
yeah we'll be back with a talk on uh
teaching big companies about security so
looking forward to that one
thank you
foreign
[Music]