thank you so much Rob I will have to buy
you that beer that we agree in now so
it's alright it's alright you wonder you
won the coin so well my name is Matt
Valenzuela and thanks to Robin and to
the rest of stands for putting together
this awesome awesome summit for the next
20 minutes this is a short presentation
I'm gonna try to summarize a very
specific solution to a very specific
problem right and hopefully you can get
away something from this something
useful and this is a line to the sands
motor right just get something that you
can use as soon as you get back to your
office right to get back to work
tomorrow and and play with something
that you have you have seen here and you
have observe probably during the the
last few of tall so since we started the
whole summit with a band be sure talking
about you know squeal and some of the
awesome stuff that he's been doing that
when you mix when you get like a coder
right a pen tester a forensics guy and
an IR guy working together in a sock
something awesome habits all right
you've got the power we've seen this
with Google and their awesome projects
as well there and how to pronounce that
your whatever grr right and all of those
awesome tools because we have we have
issues right we know these issues we
know how to solve them right so if you
have some coding skills you can quickly
put that together and might be quick and
dirty right that code might might hurt
when you actually see it but it works
right so this is the story I want to I
want to share with you today briefly so
a little bit about me
he already mentioned pretty much
everything what I'm a science instructor
I also lead the instant response on
forensics team for Intel security and I
have this problem I am addicted to gr
certs right so I don't know how to stop
and I've been also collecting some
titles right for some some time like
penetration tester instant respond
channel is forensic analyst but I still
have to add that one chaos specialist I
love that one oh but yeah I've been
doing all of this for for a while so
when you've been doing all this for a
while
you know and you've been coding a little
bit I'm a Spaniard some a bit lacy
right so I want to code like something
quick and dirty and so when you you've
been doing this for a while you come up
with solutions right and all you
probably need is just a bit of time to
do actual work and anyone here from the
Northeast probably you know from from my
accent you can tell I haven't been here
for a long long time but and I I live in
Northeast New York area and you probably
remember I think was like couple of
years ago the Snowmageddon right thing
that ended up being a little mageddon
well that was pretty much the the thing
right it wasn't that bad but he actually
gave me like two days where you know
people shut down the city and no trains
nothing so you couldn't commute into an
office and this is how you define work
right that's how I define work the
absence of going to the to the office so
you can actually do stuff so it was like
you know now I'm gonna I'm gonna be able
to work on something that I wanted to
work specifically for a project I was I
was working working on and this is a
challenge that I had right I was working
with a customer and you've probably seen
these might resonate with what you have
in your own organizations large
organization with 50,000 plus endpoints
but we're managed by a central solution
right in this case I mentioned it's the
magg of EPO agent but it could be
anything else right in this case this is
what they have and they had like a you
know a large large environment and no
forensics in place so essentially the
guys the field services guys that would
be just running around running antivirus
scans when you see that a machine was
infected with something what they would
do run another scan and over antivirus
scan and if they found nothing anything
what they do next
they run another scan again right
obviously because you're gonna find
something at the third scan or fourth
scan maybe maybe not so what happens in
the end right if that machine keeps
reinfecting
you just reimage the machine and you
just bring a new one is that that just
resonate with maybe what happens in any
of your environments what are you
learning from that absolutely nothing
right so this is the the can of the
environment we were dealing with and
containment remediation pretty much was
exactly the same thing so how do you
know what's going on with those systems
right this is like the can of the
typical day average day for a stock
analyst you see something like this this
is say an alert for a system that it's
identified as suspicious because it's
going to an IP address that has been
collected in you know this project
collective intelligence framework
awesome open source project that brings
feeds from different different places
right open source sources and if you see
that this machine is connecting to this
over IP address or domain that is deemed
as suspicious you want to know what's
going on right but what if the antivirus
says the endpoint but what have you half
of the endpoint says there's nothing
wrong with this system why is this
machine connected to an IP address in
Russia or Ukraine or Brazil if I don't
have any business with this folks right
why is that happening
you need additional context right and if
you find that there is something
malicious on that box how is that
impacting my business do you have any
information to know what's the the
response strategy and we've had an
awesome talk from from Matt right from
Google mentioning mentioning this Rob
Lee also touched on on that how
important is to know where are you
facing were you dealing with in terms of
strategy we've seen this summer 2012
largest IR we saw after that date 30,000
machines destroyed in the Middle East
largest oil and gas company in the world
you probably remember this thirty
thousand machines destroyed as a result
of a bad containment so would you be
tipping off the attacker if you're just
disconnecting machines here and there
pulling off the cable
maybe attacker just change the tactic or
take retaliation and destroy the whole
environment so that that becomes
relevant right when you do when you do
IR so that's really important so we had
to
type a solution like quick and dirty and
what I was thinking about this was like
okay what can I do that I can bring into
the office into just two days and with
what we have built some basic triage
forensics one forensics like collection
right forensic collection life response
capabilities into this environment that
is highly highly immature
it must be something that must be
crossed cross-platform must support
automated response I should be able to
wrap tools that are already out there
like sis internal tools you don't have
to reinvent the wheel there are awesome
tools out there that will collect all
the information that you need from auto
runs for instance or things like that
you don't have to write that from
scratch just reuse it and also it should
give me the opportunity to scan for
indicators of compromised right the
thread handy so how do you prototype
something like that quick and dirty
without actually having to use or deploy
an additional agent right the Google
grab the response project is an awesome
project but for this particular case I
couldn't deploy an additional additional
agent right so how can I do this in a
short amount of of time so you know
Python allows me to do this I mentioned
before I'm a lazy coder right so python
is awesome for that lots of examples out
there are lots of books out there lots
of security dedicated libraries and
snippets that you can you can use it
also supports the idea of building a
restful api which is awesome to design
client and server services right you can
also use something like py installer to
free start to package your Python code
into a single file a portable executable
a binary that now you can push to your
endpoints or use you know using in your
Windows environment so really awesome
even better it's named after the awesome
Monty Python so what can be better than
that all right so what do we need to
automate we know of this everyone here
in this room we've touched on some of
those things that you have to collect
some of the things you have to hand for
so for instance the guys from our end
game has been they have been mentioned
in this things we have to collect
to examine the machines and taking the
challenge I probably mentioned in the
beginning how do i define threat hunting
or more appropriately
how do I use Fred Han team obviously we
would use it proactively to search for
the bad guys the attackers in our
infrastructure but also something very
important that I just touched on the
idea of scoping the incident right once
you have found something suspicious in a
machine you want to grab that binary you
want to see what's going on with that
with a binary and now create some kind
of rule that will allow you to sweep
your environment and see if there is
anything that is suspicious in any other
system in your environment so you can
scope what would be the impact what's
what's the attackers TTP's right this is
something that no one has seen my before
is this something that could be targeted
so now you can define a gooda scope and
then move into containment eradication
and lessons learned again with the era
I'm not going to touch a lot on this a
lot of things as we mentioned I just
want to add something that probably
hasn't been mentioned before on this
repository he added rules anyone knows
the other rules will come some of you
cool it's it's awesome right it's a
great repository it's actually run by a
friend of mine Spain this folds half
also twitter account yeah da rules comm
sorry yeah rules on Twitter so follow
them go to their repository they have a
huge collection of the errant rules on
github that might be something you can
use straight away in your environment
and you can thing about yarra is that
you can call it call these libraries
from your own Python code so you can
write your own code and now you run your
scans on the endpoints using these
libraries and the scanning memory and
scanning also for artifacts on on disk
right and you may have been in this
situation before you may need to deploy
a security tool that you want right and
it's like oh I need to deploy an
additional agent and you have to
management and sometimes this this is
what happens right when you say you want
to deploy an additional agent or
best-case scenario it might take you
like sometime between three more
for six months to get that approved
because now people have to figure out
whether that's gonna make the Machine it
slow or what's gonna be the impact on on
that so what is the solution that we
came up with this is how I call the
project it's called rust Riyadh or and I
know it sounds weird comes from the
Spanish from Hunter right so hunter
rusted or bit of the elite thing
modifying d with the two that's the
whole deal maybe we can do a poll if you
want to change the name something like
that but it's it's open source right so
the the code is out there if Bandar sure
had actually to apologize for the
quality of the code I don't know what to
say myself I would have to say I will
have to pay you to actually use this as
a compensation or something like that
but you know it's it's out there you can
be use it I have the binary somebody
compiled for you if you don't trust my
binaries which is a good thing to do
you can you can compile yourself but
essentially uses a RESTful API so you
can do your scans and report back to the
to the server it's easy to integrate
with any kind of tool that you have on
the endpoint so if you already have an
agent that can kick off a process or
kick off a binary you can you can use
that that wraps
certain third-party tools so I'll show
you some demos if this works so the
camera functionality in version zero
seven I made it to zero seven likes
wheel I'm so pumped I'm a huge fan of
squeal so we are we have Yarra disk er
mem mem dampen and triage so you can
scan for iosys in in memory you can scan
for iOS's on the disk poorer memory time
so when you see that our system is
behaving suspiciously you can just get a
memory time McNelly across the network
using wimpy mmm it's also embedded into
the recall google project and you can
also triage the endpoints and get
information out of outlet so well this
is just a small diagram on how you would
do that essentially what you need is two
folders I'd read only share where you
have all the binaries all the tools like
Asus internal tools everything
run on the endpoint and then I write
only share where you have where you dump
all the results of that triage process
right so all the artifacts are going to
be written to that share on your network
and also there is another piece which is
a year a server that is going to be used
to pull the error rules and also to
write the results of the ers scans via a
restful api so something that you can
integrate a straightaway now the next
few slides just for you as a reference
right I'm not gonna read these but yeah
since we're gonna share the slides with
you you can see how to invoke this it's
all command line based why because
command line is sexy right it's cool for
us geeks and it's just based on
parameters so it's very flexible very
modular and it allows you to just modify
the behavior of a tool just by adding
different parameters so this is just
like a quick demo at one minute video it
works where you can see a restaurateur
we're gonna do a triage so we can uh
from the command line get information
out of our machine right and we're gonna
use the triage module and these two
folders share folders one is the right
only folder where there's going to be
created a particular folder for each of
the machines that you investigate with a
host name and then each of them inside
that folder you will have another
specific folder for each of the
timestamps where that has been executed
right and inside those folders you will
get the results so this is from the
command-line right you can see all the
different tools that are being being run
or executed on the endpoint and all
different timestamps where this was
executed and you have you know just a
sample of the output right just Windows
commands like are or the DNS cache any
kind of information you wanna you want
to get from from those from those
systems right no rocket science here
something that you probably have already
automated in your environment maybe not
right but it's something that I found
useful in different
mints and I thought I wanted to you know
to share with with you guys
so something also you can do is to
modify some of the batch scripts that I
already have on the read only share so
if you want to execute any kind of
Windows command native commands with
wmic or anything like that you don't
have to modify the code you just go to
the the share and add whatever you want
to execute on the endpoint and rusted or
will just take it and write the output
to the write only share this is what it
looks like with all the different all
different folders also you can grab
memory damp right so you can get a
memory example that machines you can
analyze it later with volatility or
recall and this is what it looks like
just using win pmm and a full memory dam
on draw format so for the era pieced
what you do is you start a server it's a
restful api server with an imp i thumb
again you have the binary so you can run
that on windows but also on mac or linux
and it's going to listen on port 8080
and from there you can run rostral or
with a set of janna rules you can get
from yeah also come or create your own
rules and scan for ioc is both in memory
and on on the disk and that's that's
kind of the format that you will you
would use so again just a shore
one-minute video but i can
so that's the formality of the command
line and this is your memory our memory
our disk we're gonna start the server
that's going to be listening on this on
this box it's going to bind to all the
interfaces and listen on port 8080 and
now we can run a memory memory scan
looking at connecting to the server and
localhost and I'm gonna use fake malware
yet a rule from Florian Roth that it's
on yada rules comm is gonna scan
physical memory and it's not gonna find
anything you can see here the rest of
all API it's pulling the yeah tag rule
from the server and executing that that
scan on the endpoint right I always say
never go hunting on a Friday I always
said that before listen to Heather's
talk right but after that I would say
you know never go hunting on a Friday
unless you work for her and then that's
perfect perfect hit but this is the same
thing now we're doing this on the disk
right so in this case I have a file that
would be actually detected and it will
just create a simple text e-file
text-based file on the same directory
where the server is being executed from
and you will see this this file will be
populated with the details of the scan
so if there's been a match you will get
a timestamp the house name because we
might be running this across hundreds of
systems and you can see where this was
found the module that was used where
there was a memory or on disk the
process where it was found right if it
was a process or the file where this was
found if it's a file on on the disk and
so just based on on this how how would
we solve solving the problem that we
mentioned before
right like two days later but something
like this you go back to the office how
would you be able to get more context
out of an alert like this well if we
would run the tool and this is where you
know it becomes like really useful to
see the integration with some of the
tools you might already have in your
environment and in this particular case
is just like
my PPO but you could use this through
SSC m or whatever mechanism you can
using your environment to push the this
binaries this is just a client task that
we define so we define a client task for
pulling memory temps we define another
client task for doing triage on the
endpoint so exactly the same arguments
command-line arguments that we have we
just we just write them here and we
create those clients as we go back to
the dashboard look at the at the system
we want to investigate and the cool
thing about this is that you can now you
can enable the people that is in the
shock that uses these tools like
point-and-click tools to actually
collect artifacts and do kind of threat
hunting without actually having to open
up a command line and and do more
advanced stuff right so he integrates
these fred hunting and instant response
procedures and tools into the workflow
that you already have in your in your
organization you can see now here now
executing the task and you just have to
go to the share and the share will be
populated with the memory time and all
the information that you have from this
machine within minutes so typically in
this particular environment within like
five minutes you can get like a four gig
memory time and maybe like six or seven
minutes you can get all the information
from the triage so this particular case
you look at the auto runs you see a high
entropy name so something weird
something you want to investigate you
look at that and you also find on the
DNS cache resolution for this mail but
are you how suspicious what's going on
with this box you have already
identified the file and you want to look
at so you pull the file you check the
hashes with virustotal
awesome tool by the way PE estudio
writes something you can you can use and
you see that this is a spam bar that
also steals credentials and do some
other kind of stuff right so that's just
an example of what you can do with them
with something like like this now the
next step would be how to now is scope
the whole
the incident right based on that sample
you can go to your again for instance
generate a Jana rule and now do a search
across all your environment to see this
particular malware has been seen
anywhere else even though you might not
even have you know detections from your
endpoint solution so that's it pretty
much that's the you know the benefit of
having something like this in like two
three days now in this particular
environment we were able to an eight to
to add these capabilities to the sock
where now they could do fret hunting and
do some other instant response and
triage in a quick and dirty way right
this is by no means anything as cool or
fancy or advanced as many of the tools
we have mentioned during the day but you
know it's open source it's out there you
have the code you said write the
commutation is really bad because of
this almost no documentation but you
have but you have my details right so
please you said I would like to have
your feedback on it if you're using it
and that's it thank you very much for
attention