all right how's everybody doing this
afternoon all right
some of you still sound a little sleepy
from lunch yeah
still a couple seats up here see one two
three you guys in the back want to come
forward there's two over there this is
exciting full crowd so a couple things
want to talk about first in my
description of the talk I talked about
there might be something to help you
with the hackers challenge there's not I
was going to talk to the game masters
and like kind of embedded codes
throughout my presentation they didn't
get back to me on that so you don't have
to strain your eyes and look real hard
for anything or do you know there's not
also I've got a link to the slides at
the end so you don't have to worry about
trying to hurry and jot down notes of
stuff it'll all be there this
presentation for you to check back and
go and look at afterwards I've got a
bunch of links to like the wasp and the
NIST regulation so you can dive deeper
into those as well as the some of the
hashing stuff I've got the metrics all
right so my topic is the four horsemen
of passwords I'm Chris Mader
I'm gonna be talking a little loud in
the mic try one of those ear things
before I kept falling off my head I must
have a small head or something but so
let's get going
not the right one false start yeah there
we go
I just want a password alright so I
thought about the same should they go
with like the scary apocalyptic Horseman
or like from the movie and I thought
well make it a little friendlier and the
color scheme worked well so we're going
to take the perspective of these four
different people you've got the good
site which would be a website that's
trying to do their best like you guys
hopefully maybe some of you out there
developers you're in charge of a site or
something
and you're trying to learn alright how
do I do this the right way and then
we've got the users they're out there
they're trying to figure things out
they're not always the greatest some are
on ball some are not and then you've got
the bad sights those are the ones we
like read about in the news that they
just got breached no other passwords
were hashed they were playing text or
they used md5 things like that and then
of course the hackers how many of you
guys out here are the hackers Wow not
that many hands interesting
oh there's one way in the back so the
bad sides they use weak hashing like md5
and sha-1 those are fast hashes I'll go
into more details on those later on they
don't salt their passwords and they
burden the users with password rules
they have low minimum on their password
length it was funny two years ago when I
sign up to do a talk the login for the
st. Conn thing had a minimum of 6
characters for password like I actually
included in my talk they also have a low
maximum password length some site should
go to a maximum password is 14
characters like whoa that's my usual
like minimum come on here and they get
breached and as you know those breaches
just contribute to the knowledge base of
the hackers they now have a ton more
passwords and usernames to go through
and figure out what are people using for
their passwords so we're trying to not
be the bad side the users they use short
passwords like as short as they can some
of them I remember one time when I had
to have a password of 12 characters my
oh my gosh I could put 12 characters in
holy cow these the same password
everywhere even I have a couple that I
use more than ones I know a bad practice
they use patterns in their passwords or
common words we'll see some of that
later
they hate dealing with passwords it's a
nuisance they just want to get in do
their thing check their Facebook or what
have you and some of them aren't
educated on good password practices we
want to try and help them with that some
of them don't care but they need to know
one of our biggest problems is user
knowledgebase and I think we're getting
better at getting that knowledge out
there to them people are becoming more
aware with all the hacks they see in the
news they're starting to get more
interested in oh I better protect my
stuff a lot of them don't use password
managers that's fine I've talked to a
lot of different people and say hey do
you use a password manager they're like
no should I'm like yes here let me
educate you and then another problem
that we have them and even like me they
don't know the good sites from the bad
sites they don't know if the site that
I'm logging into is just md5 hashing
their passwords and if they get breached
I'm toast or if they're one of the good
sites you know that oh they're using
great concretion
and all that and even the big players
like Facebook Yahoo Twitter
they've all been breached and we found
out oh they weren't salting their
passwords so it's really hard to tell
who's the good side who's the bad side
so hopefully be thinking about that if
you're a site owner how can I
communicate to my users I'm one of the
good sites so they can trust me and then
here's the good site you got to worry
about the hackers protecting yourself
from them you got to worry about the bad
sides have you ever thought of that of
like I have to protect myself from the
site over there that just got breached
and now I've also got the user that's
using the same password on that horrible
site and my site so now even though I'm
using good hashing techniques the
hackers are going to get into my site
because the user used that same password
on the bad site that was easily breached
so that's kind of tricky you know how do
we protect ourselves from the other bad
players and the curse the user themself
help them out and of course we want to
try and follow good password rules and
practices but some of them are new and
we don't know and by everybody being
here hopefully you're here to find out
and improve your your password
strategies so those are our players so
let's get into the rules the good stuff
here's the new rules although they're
not that new I gave this talk like two
years ago on some of the NIST standards
and that came out at about 2016 I
believe the the OWASP though the
applications security verification
standard 4.0 I just came out in this
March of 2019 so that's fresh it's got a
lot of good stuff in there there's more
than just like password security in it
it talks about a lot of things you
should do if you're building an
application and other security standards
within it but it does cover
authentication and password management
in there a lot of good tips and those
line up right across the board with NIST
and a bunch of things that they said so
you can study both of these and get some
good ideas on what you should be doing
so let's jump into those the first rule
is no rules we want to make password
policies user-friendly because the users
hate using passwords so we need to
eliminate the composition rules that
every site has you need one uppercase
one lowercase a number a symbol the name
of your favorite Marvel superhero or
something and just a little while ago
the inventor of that I think was guy
worked at IBM came out and apologized he
said I came up with this scheme of upper
lower number like you know a bunch of
years ago
I'm sorry for doing it I realize now it
was a bad thing and we'll kind of see
how that plays in later on because the
users like now I've got to remember all
these things and they stick them in and
they start creating patterns and things
that just wind up being easy for the
hackers to guess or crunch through and
so it doesn't really help them but then
they can't remember their passwords so
they have to write it down or they keep
it short so that's one of the rules to
get rid of just let them put in a
minimum length password and if it's all
lowercase that's okay so moving on to
the next rules allow more characters you
should allow them to put in kind of any
printable character they can come up
with especially like emoji so many
people have on their phones now that'll
just plop stuff in and they can throw
emojis left left and right on their
Twitter feeds let them put it into their
passwords because you hash your
passwords anyway so any weird coding or
whatever in there just gets hashed into
a nice string that you can store in your
database so you don't have to worry
about that
you can't sequel inject a hash so here's
a great example this one has Unicode and
it's got Arabic Chinese a bunch of other
Unicode characters in there and that
just increases the number of characters
that the hacker is gonna have to put in
their machine they're used to working
with about 95 characters they've got to
use for their brute-forcing throwing one
of these in there ups the game immensely
for them we'll see we'll see the numbers
on that later on another maximum length
of at least 64 so I've been to a couple
sites where like I said maximum length
was 14 characters you're like well I
want to go like 20 or 30
there was another site that I went to I
required 14 characters and
I had at least 14 I think I had 16 it
kept erroring out on me so you must have
on like I'm counting okay I know I've
got at least 14 in there and then I read
it again after three tries and it said
password must be 14 characters long not
less than more than it has to be exactly
14 I'm like are you kidding that's like
yeah the hackers now can eliminate all
the 13s all the 15s and above and just
focus on that string of 14 characters
like you just want to send these guys an
email and say um hello can you change
that but some of these are like
government agencies that I've done it
with Mike you can't do much with them
they've got all the bureaucracy so NIST
their guidance and this was in 2016
said to use a minimum of 8 characters
does that sound very high anyone any of
you hackers out there hash catters what
do you think of 8 yeah it sounds pretty
low to me too so I'm like why would NIST
recommend 800 us from this year
recommends a minimum of 12 okay so that
sounds a little better
I've always recommended 16 in fact I
went to an OSP conference 8 years ago
maybe 9 I was talking with a hacker guy
there I said oh yeah at least 16 and
that was yeah eight years ago he
recommended 16 so we've got a special
little chart here if carry that says the
top million most common passwords by
password length so along the bottom
we've got the the length of the password
starts at 2 and then you'll see it
starts spiking around 7 and 8 and then
it dwindles down around 9 10 11 12 etc
so if I'm the good site I'm trying to
figure out what should my minimum be now
on the one hand I don't want to burden
the user with you must have a password
of 35 character
there's no like oh my gosh I'm never
going to this site I can't come up with
anything but then on the other side
you've got the bad sites and so we can
kind of use this gauge here to tell all
right if I'm a bad side I'm probably on
the lower end and so you'll look at
eight and the spike is on eight so you
figure a lot of bad sides probably have
their minimum around eight
so if bad side has eight character
password and it gets breached and my
user uses that same one of mine if I can
up my minimum to maybe 11 or 12 or 13
odds are they didn't use my 13 character
password on the bad site that allows 8
they got lazy there went oh man this one
requires 13 ok I'll come up with a new
one to add a couple more exclamation
points on the end of it right so now
you've kind of protected yourself a
little bit from the bad site if you can
change your game up a little more to
make it easier on the user but still
kind of distinguish yourself from them
you can protect yourself in the bad
sides and hopefully the users will be ok
with it and and part of that too is
education tell them why you're requiring
15 explain hey due to cybersecurity
stuff you've seen all the heck's in the
news we want to protect your information
we are requiring at least a 15 1 and
also put on your website we recommend
using a password manager and give them a
link that describes what a password
manager is how great it is and links to
various ones they can choose from so
help educate them is gonna say likewise
on the emoji may be put on there you can
add emojis to your passwords thanks you
just tons of teenage girls you know
smiley smiley smiley heart heart heart
awesome password
so reduce vulnerabilities this is stuff
that the bad guys don't do and this is
something the good site will help you to
also protect your site and the users
validate against abandoned lists there's
so many lists of hacked passwords out
there that the hackers are using and
users are just reusing those hacked
passwords so if you can get a list and
they're easy to find out there I've just
a ton of them put them in your database
and if a user uses one of them say sorry
that passwords been hacked please don't
use it we won't allow it on our site
also password hints and this is you know
I say here put a password hidden in case
you forget yours somebody actually had
one that says rhymes with password that
help them remember their password don't
do that
also the knowledge-based authentication
Oh in case you forgot your password go
here it's like what was the first date
you went to school and what was the name
of your dog that you've posted a
thousand times on Facebook information
like that the hackers can just search
their social media and dig for it and
bypass that and get through so take that
option away from them to use that or if
you really must and you really want to
don't give them a set of actual things
to answer like you know your favorite
color your favorite car
let them type in their own and say like
what is the color of the lamp next to my
bed that one you can probably still find
out social medias like Instagram
Instagram there's this bedroom oh it's
green so just get rid of that two-factor
authentication definitely encourage your
users to use it maybe put a link
educating them on what it is and if you
can offer multiple options NIST has come
out and said SMS is not safe
we've seen that in the news now with all
the sim jacking the hackers can bypass
that because it sends the text to their
phone hackers have already jacked it and
they get the text and now they've
breached the tooth factor authentication
so offer the other types there's the
authenticators like Google Authenticator
and Microsoft Authenticator and also if
you can offer Yubikey the hardware ones
using the phyto standard I would say
it'd be ok to put a two-factor one but
maybe give them the list of options is
like okay here's the worst no two-factor
here's a little bit better if you really
have to SMS text here's the better
option Google or Microsoft Authenticator
and for the ultimate pick the Yubikey
one so maybe give them that so then go
oh well I don't want to pick the worst
one because nobody wants to be worst
right I want to pick the bare minimum oh
I'll go middle ground I don't want to
have to go purchase a Yubikey or
whatever so I'll look into that Google
Authenticator one I use it works great
nice and friendly so yeah educate your
users give them options and try and make
them do it I know Google is getting a
lot better about popping up hey security
alert or security feature that they have
to go through if you just put up there
along with everything else they won't
see it they'll just click through their
normal path and ignore it so you might
need to make it a little intrusive in
their face I still click past them a lot
but at least you're trying you know you
can give them a chance and that's the
important thing help the user to improve
themselves and you'll protect yourself
and them as well and then no expiration
periods don't make their passwords
expire if you don't have to
because I've done this myself they
create patterns
yes I've used the one on the bottom
password fall 2015
password winter 2015 I was somewhere
where like every quarter you had to
reset your password so I'm like okay
I'll just winter fall spring and that
just makes the password worse because
the hackers have wanted to figure out
these patterns you just increase the
number on the end like kitty cat or you
shift things around and so that just
creates user fatigue they're like
changed my password again and you just
have to do it every quarter or every
whatever and they start coming up with a
hard time of coming up with good
passwords especially if like oh you
can't use any of the 20 past ones you've
had before like after three or four I
forget what they were so I reboot it in
it's like you've used that before ah I
have no I haven't say so get rid of
those just keep their password and the
only reason to require them to change it
would be in case of a breach they say
hey you need to go change your password
something's happened that would be kind
of the only reason because until then
their password should be good and just
encourage them to use a nice long
password like I've got there at the
bottom I don't know if that'll actually
last for 10 years with all the quantum
cryptology stuff going on quantum
computers but it should still last for a
good long time so help the users out
don't put too many rules on them don't
create fatigue but educate them I think
a lot of people nowadays they will they
want the knowledge they want to be smart
but they don't know really what to look
for what they need to do you might need
to kind of handhold them through your
process these are some things you can
throw in a couple other items I didn't
get out on here but they're on the wasp
list a lot of sites you'll see now you
can click the
I ball and it'll show you the password I
love that it used to be like dot dot dot
dot dot dot dot okay back back okay I
think I did a shift there no denied oh
there's a great meme I should have
thrown in here goes through this guy
putting in his password and saying no
that password is not acceptable no this
password is not acceptable it's like
okay this is my stupid freaking password
not acceptable okay this is my stupid
freaking pet and just starts cursing and
says we're sorry that's already been
used this is so frustrating
okay how about this how about this how
about this dang it it's like now help
the users out give them that little
eyeball that they can click and go okay
yeah oh I missed the exclamation point
there or what have you
also I lost mentions having password
meters help them with their strength
those are Canada funky because it's not
the best judge there's different ones
out there that are kind of less last
year one of the guys talked about one
they have and it looks at their password
not just do the way it does it have
upper lower or whatever but it looks at
the actual entropy or randomness of what
they typed in and that was their gauge
of this is a good password that's a
little advanced maybe maybe you can find
the code for it I don't know it might be
out there
at least tell them how many characters
they've typed up to that can help and go
okay I've got about 16 characters or 20
and yet feel good that way so password
meter I don't know what I think about
the OWASP recommendation on that but use
your own judgment alright so let's take
a look at the hacker
so when I was preparing this talk I read
about a guy that created a 25 GPU
cracking machine and this was a couple
years back and he used like I don't know
10 60s or some other lower AMD GPU cards
on it and then they come to Saint Conn
on Tuesday did we start Tuesday Tuesday
yeah
walk in and they've got this puppy right
here it's like oh dude how many GPUs you
got in that puppy oh I think about 25 my
sweet can I take a picture it's like I
want to throw that in my slides because
like I'm talking about a 25 GPU machine
now he's only got like ten eight only
he's got ten 80s and 10 70s in this the
examples I'm gonna go through are for
the new r-tx 2080 t is to just kind of
give you an idea of where the you know
hacker spectrum could be and you got to
realize the you know the hacker
I don't know power out there varies
you're gonna have the guys they've only
got like three four maybe five GPUs
maybe you've got the guy down here it's
got twenty five but there's like
criminal organizations out there
nation-states they've probably got a
hundred and etc more to throw things so
this is just kind of a maybe a nice
middle ground perspective to consider so
let's get into the geeky numbers so what
we've got here on the left is the
different kind of hashing algorithms
you've probably heard of md5 sha-1
there's also the new shot - of the 256
512 flavor now I've got those
highlighted in orange because those are
the bad ones at least for passwords
because they hash fast they were they
were built to do the hash quickly and
when you're protecting your passwords
you don't want that
you'll notice the ones balloon green
those are slow hashers they are
purposely designed to do the hash slow
and take up a lot of resources so that
when mr. hacker gets your hash
he can't just blaze through it quickly
you know with millions of hashes per
second and get your password these are
designed for password storage for hash
and passwords you'll notice on the
bottom are gone - I've got question
marks several years ago there was a
password algorithm hashing algorithm
competition argon - was the winner so if
you're implementing a hashing algorithm
for your passwords find argon - and use
it if you can I couldn't find any
hashing or hacking stats on it so
they're not gonna be through the slides
I was talking with one of the guys and
he didn't think that hash cat actually
has that algorithm built into it so they
they can't even use hash cat to try and
crack argon - hashes but there's
instances like for example if you need
to be mist compliant argon - is not on
the list
for NIST yeah so you might have to go
with something like pbkdf2 in order to
be mist compliant
even though argon - is better you're
told in this guy's hey Argan twos better
it's like sorry it hasn't been vetted
it's not on the list you got to use this
so but still it's it's not a bad hasher
bcrypt and s crypt and as you can see
here second column is the Killa hashes
per second for just one GPU one of the
the twenty ATT is so you can tell ya the
md5 we can go through 50 what 50 million
killer hashes per second
trying to crack it an md5 hash go down
to bcrypt
only 27 killer hashes per second so
clearly is gonna take a lot longer to
decrypt a hash with bcrypt that makes
sense and then on the right i've got how
many if you've got a 25 GPU rig
okay so that'll that will guess it up to
the scale of mid-range of what you might
be up against and kind of through the
rest of the numbers we're gonna follow
the 25 GPU example so let's look at how
long does it take to crack something
using these numbers we're gonna take our
25 GPU rig and we're gonna take just an
eight character password and that's how
many combinations three I don't know
whatever the number is that and I like
to make my numbers nice and long so you
can see it you put them down to the
exponential notation and it doesn't give
you the same feeling of like well is
that much different but when you see the
numbers you'll go oh wow that's much
better and then we've got how many days
to crack and how many years to crack so
an eight character password on an md5
any of the lower hash ones they can hack
that in less than a day the good ones
you can tell even the slowest or the
fastest actually would be the PDK pbkdf2
it'll take one year to crack and a
character password so that should kind
of make you feel good about a characters
and this gives starts to give us a
little insight into maybe what NIST was
talking about because they were saying
hey here the good guidelines use
something like PB k if you're using that
then an a character password is kind of
okay you had a question
what No we'll get into that good
question so yeah so let's take our
example a little further so yeah when
you read the NIST rules I'm like eight
that doesn't seem like much but if
you're using better hashing algorithms
and the other rules eight can be kind of
okay maybe on your lower end but let's
expand it a little bit so up here you
see how I've got ruled eight and just
eight the gist eight is like double and
the reason for that is it's not
requiring upper lower number symbol and
so you can tell by adding those rules
you've cut the number of hashes a hacker
has to go through by half right so if
you allow them to have the password
a-a-a a-a-a-a it's gonna take twice as
long to crack that so by eliminating
those rules that we thought were good
and then the IBM guy said I'm so sorry
it was a terrible role I came up with it
we've just increased the difficulty on
the hackers because they know that the
the passwords they have to hash oh it's
got it at least you know an upper or
lower and etc they're following those
same rules and so they've cut out all
those passwords that they don't have to
try and hash through like a AAA AAA or
AAA BBB et cetera so you can see the
statistics for just cutting out the
rules that doubles the number of
combinations that they've got to go
through in the example on the the PBK
it'll take the cracking time from one
year up to three years just by
eliminating those password rules
and as you can see the numbers just get
bigger and bigger as we go up to 9 and
and yeah so under PBK I don't know I'd
go with anion character password to 200
281 years if you want to be really safe
I'd go for 10 so now those missed rules
kind of start to seem a little more
palatable you know okay maybe it's not
so horrible
oh I'm saying 12 they've definitely
pushed it the other direction we want to
make sure you're totally safe and you'll
notice I cut out like the md5 and the
beak rib just to kind of limit what
we're comparing to so we're taking kind
of the the best of the worst and the
worst of the best to see the disparity
between but then we'll go the other
direction later on so moving on Unicode
and emoji just blows things up so we're
gonna go back to just our length of
eight a character password
yeah yes these are all based off the 25
GPU machine yeah I kind of started
running out of room on my columns to
disco it's like alright you know I've
shown you that I will cut that out cut
that out
so normally character set is bound 95
that's what I've seen
you've got your upper your lowers your
numbers and a whole bunch of symbols
thrown in there the emoji character set
itself just has actually this numbers
wrong I looked this up last night I
didn't have time to change my slides
it'll be changed by the times you go
look at this
it's about 3100 emojis that are out
there now and just by changing that
character set even on the sha-512 you go
from less than you know a year to crack
two
was a two trillion years so all I have
to do is throw one emoji into my
password and I've exponentially
increased how protected that is because
the hackers if you throw an emoji in
there they just can't pick from
I don't know hackers are pretty smart
they'd probably pick the most common
emojis and throw that into their library
and work with those you know the smiley
face the thumbs up the heart the
whatever
eggplant sweet put the eggplant in there
but like the princess or the fairy or
who knows what there's a ton out there
you use one of those less common ones
and now the hackers they've got to put
that entire character set into their
lineup of stuff they've got a grain
through and so that makes it so much
more difficult and now if you throw
Unicode in there as well yeah question
yeah it's good don't look at these
exactly it's kind of a magnitude kind of
a feel for magnitude if you look at the
statistics that they give you on you
know like hash cat to crack a md5 a
bunch of them will show like four runs
or six runs and then you take the
average cuz every time you go through
it's gonna be a little different yeah so
it's not exact it's gonna vary like you
say but this gives you an idea a feeling
of kind of the magnitude difference
between stuff now Unicode there's a
bunch of different stuff on you to code
out there and I kind of had to pick
through it to make it clear the BMP
stands for base multilingual plane so
there are multiple Unicode planes to
choose from
the base one is probably what we're all
used to it's got our normal character
said and a bunch of the others in there
it's the most common and that itself
just has 55,000 characters in it so if I
can throw instead of an emoji I throw a
Chinese character in there you can see
how much longer a different is to crack
that just one unicode character throw
that in there find something obscure or
whatever kinda like the example I had
before I had Klingon Arabic wing-dings
that's fun just throw one of those in
your password you're good but then I've
got Unicode and emoji put one of each in
there and you're just increasing the
time at least on the the sha-512 from 48
whatever that is number 272 you've
almost doubled the hashes that the
hackers have to go through yes question
right yeah exactly good comments so he
was saying tell the users like we said
educate the users maybe they used the
smiley face and the heart the thumbs out
on all their tweets and posts so if I'm
a hacker and I'm targeting them
specifically I'm gonna see that on their
Twitter their Instagram and instead of
me trying to you know guess through the
entire 2800 character set of emoji I'm
gonna crank that sucker down to I'm
gonna just use these four or five in my
character set and get them and so maybe
on your you know login page or password
page hey we allow emoji try to use one
that you don't use very often you know
encourage that educate them but you know
we can't protect nothing's use user
proof you know but we can do our best
try and help them out and maybe even
tell them like on your phones it's easy
everything pops up you can do emoji
windows a little harder I found out oh
yeah I just hit the window key and the
period pops up the little emoji screen
sweet I can type emoji in Unicode a
little tougher but maybe give them some
screens on how to put a Unicode or
whatever in there yes question
I was just gonna start into that I don't
know I've that's gonna be kind of one of
my next little projects is like alright
can I put emoji in Unicode in LastPass
or a key pass or etc yeah and then also
part two of that how many websites will
take it you know
can I put emoji or Unicode in my
password for Twitter Facebook etc yeah
that's gonna be kind of my next project
it's kind of a look and see all right
how many are gonna accept this you know
can't we use it because if you're gonna
recommend it and say hey we recommend an
emoji we recommend using a password
manager they load up LastPass they trim
put the remote gene it's like it won't
take my emoji in all this socks I'm
gonna do you know same old thing so
hopefully the the bigger sites are
catching on to this and they're gonna
facilitate the NIST guidelines and the
guidelines but that's a good question
but at least if you're building the site
yours does
alright also we see on the the slow hash
at the PBK just throw an emoji in there
with the egg characters yeah you can see
the difference any other questions
Oh back in the back yeah
yes so so the Unicode is the BMP emojis
are the unicode SMP I've got a link to
the whole Unicode stuff so you can
figure that out the emoji character
space is actually much bigger I think it
was like 20 or maybe 30 thousand but
we're only using the three thousand
right now and so how it translates kind
of might depend on your front-end
and maybe your middleware weather like
dotnet or PHP or whatever but it should
translate into a Unicode character just
on a different plane than the BMP then
like the Chinese and the wingdings and
etc but yeah that's a good question and
I don't totally have the answers on it I
was trying to figure it out myself on
the different things like okay so here's
the basics to get you going if you need
to dig deeper there's the resources out
there so let's take it to the next level
the best versus the worst so we're gonna
go down to our md5 and our bcrypt
and you'll notice on the md5 I increased
my length to kind of compare and on the
beat crypt I wanted to see how low could
I go and still have a safe password so
if I've got a site that's using B crypt
and I can stick in a Unicode and an
emoji to character password not quite
enough that's still less than a year
handful of days but a three character
password nine years to crack now let's
take your md5 one character length of
ten two years to crack
so I can say hey my three character
password is better than your 10
character password in the right
situation and and and that's it all
depends and I'll get into this later
there some other parts you've probably
already starting to see the picture
there was a talk last year and they
talked about kind of the same similar
stuff and one of the guys in the
audience said so what is the lowest you
know number of characters I should allow
my password and they say I don't think
add yes but it was like eight but that's
not the full question because people
will see that out there was like oh I
can have eight characters no problem but
there's more to it than that as you can
see there's what hashing algorithm is
the site using what character sets kind
of use and we'll get into the the
entropy whoever had that statement in a
minute
to show like no you just eight
characters of anything doesn't quite cut
it so yeah so I figured okay a nine
character password or a three character
for character if it's bcrypt with an
emoji and unicode I'm safe I'm good for
good five hundred fifty thousand years
so this is where we need to educate our
users and let them figure out what they
want help them to pick a good one they
can keep it shorter if they follow the
other rules if they don't well they
gotta there's there's rules they have to
follow and this helps distinguish us
from the bad sides
you know we upper limit but we allow
more characters oh we don't have the
rules which actually makes us less safe
so there's there's lots of things to
juggle when considering this alright
we're gonna get into the trickery
somebody brought up so there was an
article
ours couple years old they gave three
hackers a big library passwords not too
huge I think was eighty thousand hundred
thousand remember 13 maybe 20 thousand
these guys were using this one guy just
used two AMD Radeon graphics cards and
they cracked thirteen thousand in just
over an hour now a lot of them were
probably eight character and you know
real easy ones but there were ones like
these here on the left
now those look pretty good right some of
them 16 characters 16 characters
shouldn't that have taken him like you
know at least sixty years to crack based
on our stats from before but it's the
entropy the randomness that got them on
this and so the hackers are smart I mean
they're not gonna go to all the work if
they can take the easy right out they
don't start brute-forcing every possible
combination till the very end and only
if they want to get a specific one they
will go through their list of top
500,000 passwords that have already been
hacked they'll do those and then they
have libraries of common words and
combinations so they'll start using like
a hybrid or a mask attack or combination
attacks one the hacker was kind of
surprised that popped up mom of three
great kids he didn't necessarily have
that one in his list but later when he
kind of started switching him up he had
great kids and he had I think mama and
then by throwing those in as almost the
character in themselves he popped up
with mom with three great kids in less
than an hour probably various minutes to
just get that one and so we can see that
length isn't king so to speak I even
said this two years ago in my
previous presentation that length is
king but it can't be King alone even
long characters if you don't have enough
entropy can get hacked you're all
familiar with thee what does a horse
batteries staple correct bunch of words
nice and long but I'm sure you know
that's in the hackers list I would say
if you're gonna have more you need at
least three more words because here's
another thing your whoops your um your
master password for your LastPass or
your password manager once again you
want to make it easy for the user and
memorable because they hate keeping
track of passwords and all these darn
rules so they want to have a master
password that they can remember so we
usually recommend something nice and
long a passphrase get up in the the 20s
with your phrase and that way it can be
I have a blue lamp next to my desk that
I got from my mom something like that
maybe put a couple numbers on there and
so we need to pay attention to that and
help the user you know if we can say
like we said that thing that your
password strength looked at the entropy
and so it would look at these and go ah
not enough even the one down here Shia
LeBouf the users thought they were being
all tricky I'm gonna use a number
instead of a letter the hackers know
that stuff that that's built in their
libraries they blow through it not a
problem so the rules that we need to
keep track of are not just length is
king we have three kings to have a good
hand so to speak the length very
important king and putting together this
slide I was actually gonna have like
king queen and Jack but
looking on you know they're all kind of
Kings if we go back to the bcrypt
example with three characters I had
enough entropy and character said that I
could you know kind of minimize on the
length so let's see the long at the one
on the left of length nice and long
probably still gonna get hacked because
the the hackers the word password is in
their list so all those characters
basically count as one character when
using their dictionary tax etc the next
one nice and long a lot of entropy
probably pretty good password users
aren't going to remember that one but
hopefully that's in there LastPass their
password manager for their various sites
and then just to like beef things up
throwing some emoji and characters that
one there that's not gonna get cracked
for like ever
unless they come to the presentations
like oh hey I'm gonna put that one in my
list because there's some guys out there
they're gonna go use that for their
password don't do it don't use that
password I just disclosed but you get
the idea yes question
yes because it would make it longer they
would still use like the dictionary
attack on it but they would have to kind
of compensate for you know still we saw
with the 95 character set the length the
longer make it it does make him go
through it but they might snag you with
a dictionary attack or a Combinator
attack of the password maybe some other
words but adding spaces I think it would
be good excuse me because it's user
friendly instead of motion it all
together like we type normally this
space is space my long password put the
spaces in there your hashing algorithms
can take the space character so yeah
that would help might not be totally
perfect play gap it adds over the one
two three four more characters to it
makes it easier for the user what was
that yeah right so we're increasing
length but not necessarily our entropy
yeah so because the hackers they kind of
know that
yeah yeah right ello space in G yeah
throw the space in in weird spots yeah
yeah that kind of blow through it but
yeah that's a good question
I like it like like we say it's not just
oh it makes it longer so it's better I
have but there's if this and if that so
if you've seen the movies you know
there's more than four horsemen there's
a fifth one and he's kind of sneaky I
hope I'm not spoiling the movie for
anybody from seeing it there's actually
two movies this guy call him the advisor
you'll see him on Twitter Lee that's
where I've seen him on Twitter that's
the main social meeting what I do others
you'll see him and they go oh hey it's
over security month here's some you know
cyber security tips and they're throwing
out tips like you know they're trying to
they're trying to help people you know
that they're trying to be good but then
they throw some stuff in there that's
not good anymore it's bad so yeah we'll
look at some of their tips a lot of
different versions of this one treat
your password like your underpants
change them often no do not change them
off of them
don't leave them lying around maybe if
it's at work
yeah don't leave it laying around if
you're at home it could be okay
if you have a nice long master password
that you need to remember for your
password manager it could be okay to
write it down and stick it maybe not
right next to your computer but at least
in a book or something in a drawer
because odds are if somebody breaks into
your house they're not looking to steal
your passwords they're looking for the
big-screen TV and the the gaming set and
whatever else they may take your
computer and leave the password in the
desk
so it's actually okay to write down your
passwords even though a lot of people
don't write your passwords down oh no it
depends again are you at work in a less
secure area then yeah don't do it but at
home a little safer put it in your diary
or something in case you do forget your
master password yeah question
yeah no cuz when they take the TV
they'll get your password
I thought brought just looking guy what
is this that's probably the model number
throw that away and don't share them
once again it depends like with my wife
I have no problem sharing my passwords
we'd share the same password manager so
like that but other situations no you
don't give it out or maybe you do give
it out to a friend for a certain reason
but then after they're done getting
whatever they need you go and you change
it so once again yeah question in the
back yes well yeah so if you're using
the same password across multiple
accounts first change that bad habit but
yeah if you give your friend your
Facebook you know password just for a
minute
and then you change your Facebook one
but
your Twitter your Gmail or your other
than you know they can get to that so
you got to be smart about it here's
another one that I love once again not
bad it's trying to help them know Oh use
long passwords you know seven characters
oh that will get hacked immediately
eight nine you're a little better our
twelve character password takes two
centuries but they're not conveying the
entire picture we've got the first King
but not the second king of entropy and
so users are getting educated oh I just
make it nice long and I'm good
not completely and so this is also kind
of bad and then here's another one it's
mixed create a password you will
remember not for your sites let LastPass
come up with star pound asterisk AV zero
five nine three six whatever that you
can't I don't know my passwords I only
know one so create a master password you
can remember yes random words that you
know the meaning of once again
dictionary tax update your password
frequently no that's a bad one
characters at least fifteen yeah pretty
good two-factor authentication yes but
not SMS don't save your password on the
browser probably pretty good use a
variety of characters depends bottom
right corner do not use dictionary you
can in your master password if it's nice
and long to help you remember it so yeah
kind of be careful out there there's
some good information and not so good
information here's the references I
talked about the links to the different
sites you can go to and you want to
really research this and before
everybody struggles out here the very
bottom white cap Cybercom slash 2019 st.
Conn
that's all you need to remember that'll
get you to this presentation so you can
go back and really look up the
references and check all these things
out I'm Chris you've been a great crowd
I've enjoyed doing this hope you learned
a lot any last questions yeah I don't
have an opinion I don't know anyone else
yes
hmm
yeah you might need to test your stuff
out yeah alright thank you you guys went
great
[Applause]