alright guys it's time thanks for coming
out lots of you here so today I wanted
to talk a bit about the dark web and
hopefully in a way that you haven't
thought about it before but first I want
to talk about moving let's do this a
different way there we go okay forget
the notes we don't need those alright so
I want to talk about kind of the idea
behind this and why I even wanted to
talk about the dark web to begin with
and I want to tell you a story little
story probably a story that many of you
in this room can tell because your
security professionals and the story
starts something like this right so I'm
at home and I'm mowing my yard and I'm
talking to my neighbor who knows I work
in security or you're in your office and
you know somebody drops by because they
know that you work in security or just
friends or family you know my mom likes
to send me random texts and like you
know ask you questions about security
and the way this story goes and the way
this question goes is that person
whoever it is in your life right shows
up and they look at you and they kind of
look away and they look back and they
look away and they shuffle their feet a
little bit and you know they want to ask
you something
right usually it's like is email secure
no okay whatever or can you fix my
computer definitely no but the question
as they look at you and then look away
it's like spit it out already
right and so they look at you and they
kind of get up close and they whisper a
little bit
have you been on the dark web has
anybody had that question had that
conversation right if you've been on
security for a little while probably
because people don't know what to think
of the dark web they're like what is
this thing can I even say it out loud is
the dark web like Voldemort we don't say
that word all right and so that was why
I wanted to have this conversation
because I think there's a lot of
misconceptions about the dark web and
exactly what it is before I dig into all
of this so I do want to have a little
disclaimer okay I'm gonna talk about
things that have happened okay
they actually did there's things that
happen so this isn't political I don't
really care why they happened or who did
them or you know who was involved it's
just things that happened that
illustrate a point this is not a
conspiracy theory okay again things
happen we can look at facts and make
determination about how we want to
approach those facts but some of the
thinking behind why we should be
embracing the dark web some people would
think or say is conspiracy theories or
something else that's not what this is
about this is also not a call to Anarchy
okay
I am not condoning illegal activities
I'm not asking you to go participate in
something that's gonna get you in
trouble in fact exactly the opposite
so before we dig into this too far there
I want a level set on a couple of things
okay a lot of people in here maybe I
don't know maybe go on the dark web
every day maybe you host your personal
bio on the dark web that's weird but you
know I don't know what everybody's
experience is here so I just for the
purposes of this conversation
I'd like to level set about what I'm
talking about
so on this graphic that I stole from the
internet
it shows the internet as a whole okay
and what they're saying is
at the World Wide Web the thing most of
us think of as the Internet is the tip
of the iceberg
okay that's everything that's indexed or
publicly accessible and then somewhere
in the middle is the Deep Web which is
stuff that's not necessarily publicly
accessible but network connected to the
Internet and again the purpose here is
not to debate semantics because if
anybody's really into this stuff we
could probably go off in the lobby out
there later and we could argue for a
really long time about what constitutes
the definition of the world wide web or
clear web or Internet what the Deep Web
is what the percentages are doesn't
matter for the point so that I want to
talk about today and the final piece is
the dark web okay and again from the
graphic that I stole from the N or that
even that says this is the place where
all the illegal activity happens so and
basically what we're saying is that the
dark web is just a layer that is a part
of the rest of the Internet and I just
want to like disband any of the whispers
right now right the dark web is just
technology okay you can say it out loud
it's okay you can talk about it you can
tell your friends about it just because
you went on the dark web doesn't mean
you bought drugs or sold guns or tried
to hire a hitman okay but the important
thing is that it's technology that was
designed in a specific way and that's
what I want to talk about today so the
technology itself that powers the dark
web is designed to be private okay it's
designed to be anonymous it's designed
to be secure and depending on how you
approach the dark web it's also designed
to be decentralized so why do we care
about those things right because what
I've seen as I've been in technology now
for over 20 years
is that as new technology comes along
somewhere along the way we start
thinking that we have to solve problems
or come up with ways to deal with things
like privacy that supposedly we've never
thought of before
it's like this is a new paradigm we've
got a new do new stuff right but I want
to dig into a little bit those aspects
of the dark web privacy security and
decentralization and talk about where we
come from in that space so we'll start
with privacy who here cares about
privacy okay a couple of hands it's
becoming more popular okay
used to be people were like you're
giving me free email I don't care okay
I get a coupon to the barbecue place I
don't care right there's been a little
bit of a shift back the other direction
in the last couple of years because
people are starting to realize as
there's a breach announced three times a
week that maybe all my data in the world
shouldn't be on the internet that's not
where it belongs what we hear lots of
times when we talk about privacy is this
idea of I have nothing to hide who has
nothing to hide in here I got one hand
up but I think he was actually waving it
somebody to hands okay so somebody in
here thinks you have something to hide I
think a more important question is who
here has an identity
very few people this is disturbing okay
who here feels like they have an
identity that there's something about
you that's unique right okay a lot of
people now are sort of raising their
hands I think they're embarrassed about
their identity
okay and I did okay there you go very
good you have lots of items I'd like
okay so most people cultivate uniqueness
they cultivate an identity okay whether
it's online or in real life whatever it
is most people you know choose the shoes
the clothes they wear because they want
to look a certain way you get a certain
haircut you have certain friends you
participate in certain things whatever
it is you're building up an individual
picture of yourself okay and everybody
has that so I want to look back at what
identity has meant historically okay who
knows what happened and this is going to
be a stretch right because I'm about to
talk about history
okay and when I talk about this today
history means 10 minutes ago on
Instagram I'm but things have happened
before today things that have influenced
the way that we've built our societies
and that stuff is important as we look
forward into technology and start
thinking about how do we take those
principles and the things that we
learned and apply them today don't act
like we just made them up right I've got
kids that are in those teen years and my
favorite thing is when they walk up and
they're like or I tell them it's like
you know hashtags actually an octave
thorpe right there was a name for it
before Twitter yeah okay or a pound sign
I'm fine with that right but but what
we're seeing now in technology is it
moves really really rapidly people keep
feeling this need it's like oh I have to
come up with a new name for something
know it existed already ok privacy isn't
new so as we go back into history who
can tell me what happened in December of
1941 Pearl Harbor okay so Pearl Harbor
for the United States was the beginning
of World War 2 it had been going on
before that okay but we've been staying
out of it we were like I don't think the
Pearl Harbor happened
and everything changed in the United
States and so because of that the
President of the United States signed an
executive order that made certain parts
of our country strategic military zones
now as a result of that in February of
1942 there were hundreds of thousands of
people that were involved in their
communities ran businesses were born in
this country were active going to school
had homes lived all over the this
country okay for generations who had
nothing about them that was wrong except
for an identity okay they had the
audacity to have parents or relatives
that were born in Japan you really
should keep that under control all right
so they had this identity that resulted
in soldiers showing up at their door
with guns in the United States okay in
California on the East Coast and taking
all of these japanese-americans they
were Americans they were born here most
of them and putting them on two trains
and taking them out to internment camps
where they were stuck in shacks they
were surrounded by barbed wire and they
were guarded by soldiers with guns and
that was a difference between a Tuesday
and a Wednesday on Tuesday they were
business owners and neighborhood members
and you know students on Wednesday they
were prisoners of war here's the
interesting thing about this event that
happened 59 years later in the year 2000
even though the US Census Bureau had
denied it for a very long time it was
revealed that they use census data to
identify these people and then seven
years after that it was a reveal
even though it had been denied and it
was expressly against the statement the
top of the census form that said we will
not disclose this information they used
detailed micro census data to the block
level and house level to identify and
locate japanese-americans they were
incredibly successful at rounding them
all up because they violated their
privacy and their civil rights and use
something that had been turned over in
good faith as something that should be
used to help her in our country in a
more effective manner to put them in
prison this activity is part of the
foundations of the right to privacy
there's lots of other examples that
happen in this time period of world war
two but it was so impactful that we
learned something odd when that happens
but we learned something and when the
war was over the United Nations
Universal Declaration of Human Rights
was drafted okay part of that as you'll
see here is article 12 okay and says you
shouldn't be subjected to arbitrary
interference with privacy it's a human
right and we talked about it today like
it's an option okay I want to talk about
decentralization next now we're gonna
move back in history according to the
Instagram ten minute timeline but not
nearly as far okay 2013 who knows who
this guy is I got some hands who we got
yeah Edward Snowden who's ever heard of
this company couple of people so lavabit
was the secure encrypted email service
that Edward Snowden used to transfer
information now up until this dude
showed up the guy running lavabit was
running a successful technology company
and then Edward Snowden came along and
he got a letter that said you need to
turn over your SSL keys and your
encryption keys for everybody because
Edward Snowden Snowden used the service
now if you're running a secure service
that the whole point behind it is that
it's secure and is private what do you
think the fastest way is to kill your
business maybe give over all the
information inside of your service right
so he was faced with a choice his choice
was do I violate everything about my
company and turn this information over
or do I go to jail because there's no
other option and not only that when this
happened you get what's called a
National Security Letter anybody know
what that is go read about it they're
cool they're from the FBI
okay National Security Letters when you
get them they come essentially with a
gag order okay so you get it you can't
even talk about it you can't tell
somebody you got it you can't tell what
it's about and so the CEO of the company
was in this position where he really
didn't have many choices and what he
chose to do instead of give the
information over ago to jail was shut
down the company okay now this is
unfortunate because something he'd been
working at for a long time you know lots
of us work for companies and find them
to be pretty important they pay my bills
lots of us have started companies and
know what it's like to put that kind of
effort into something and care about it
and in one day this guy lost his company
just because of somebody that happened
to use his service he had no control
over and the challenge here is that when
we work in a centralized model there's
always somebody at the middle of that
that has control so if you have an ax
company that's important to you
you're operating inside of a centralized
model you find out that you have very
few choices okay you can either comply
or you can destroy your company you know
we see this in lots of other places too
who's ever downloaded an app on their
phone couple of you all right
when you did that you had permissions
right and now you can agree to the
permissions or not but where's the point
where you get to agree to some of the
permissions and still use the software
it's either don't and don't use the
software or agree to everything that you
want to do yeah I want to play this game
right now it needs access to my phone it
needs access to all my contacts it needs
access to take pictures of me you need
why I don't know right but you have no
choice there right and we see this
expanding so there was this journalist
who decided that she was going to go
through an experiment and cut the big
five tech companies out of her life
okay Facebook Amazon some people say
Netflix I don't know why but whatever I
guess they invent some technology
Facebook Amazon Apple Google and
Microsoft and what she did was she went
one week at a time and and she had a VPN
set up that blocked all the IP addresses
and you can see the headline in here
I cut the five tech giants from my life
it was hell okay because what she found
out was that if you want to turn off
Amazon
good luck right because just about
everything you use you want to use a
lift or an uber yes really they run on
AWS okay you want to use Google Maps
guess what runs on Google cloud now
sometimes AWS depends on what you're
dealing with but the point is is that
almost everything that you use on a
daily basis from a technology
perspective goes back through one of
these five companies and so that affects
your freedom and your ability to make
choice and if you choose not to it's
turned off no recourse
let's talk for a minute about security I
was gonna get there eventually it is a
security conference what happens when
you choose to browse the web securely
has anybody ever done that all right we
got one you don't use the internet right
yeah sure
so browsing the web securely there's a
few components that go into this so you
can turn off ads because you know who
wants that stuff in your face and
they're always putting cookies on your
machine then they invite other cookies
onto your machine and it's like this
whole thing plus I just don't like them
because I think it's weird that when I
look at something on my phone it shows
up on my wife's computer later
right and vice versa I don't care that
much about shoes all right so but if you
start blocking ads then you start seeing
this stuff it's like we noticed you're
using an ad blocker our site depends on
this to survive please turn this off and
we're not gonna let you look at stuff
okay so that's a pretty minor thing
though right it's like ads whatever well
then you start blocking some cookies
okay and if you start blocking cookies
you actually start breaking things for
real
the IRS really doesn't like it when you
block cookies I don't like it when you
block anything it's weird
Amazon stops working you can't log into
Gmail there's a few other things that if
you turn off cookies your web really
stops functioning and if it does
function at all it looks like something
I really expect the gifts with the music
when you load the page it's looks really
old
how about blocking scripts okay well you
turn on script blocking go visit a new
site like CNN and you'll notice this
thing pop up whereas I think there's 45
scripts that tried to load when I hit
the first page and I don't know what
most of them are so what happens though
is when you block it and then you try to
navigate
site the site doesn't work anymore right
and if you blocked ads and cookies and
scripts you probably don't even see this
much you know to do these screenshots I
couldn't turn them all on at once
because there's nothing to show you it's
blank screens I can only do one at a
time well then what if you add on top of
that deciding to browse anonymously like
I don't want you to know where I'm
coming from well then they just say no
right we have to know where you're
coming from or you can't see our website
and then if we take all of this stuff
and put it together people have even
written books about it
right cookie scripts had surveillance
capitalism there's a reason why all this
stuff exists right because it's making
people money because people are getting
data from it because and it goes further
than that because then we start having
problems understanding what is true
because a lot of us look to the internet
now for truth this is where you get
information that's the promise right
that's the cool thing about the Internet
you know I rebuilt an engine over the
summer I did it with YouTube I've never
worked on a car in my life okay I have
no idea how to do that but I can watch a
video and I can do what that dude did
right so it's like having a master
mechanic behind you all the time that's
awesome okay I've learned so many things
in my career from the Internet and
that's really cool you know but now
somehow it just doesn't feel like a safe
place to be and I'm never sure what to
trust anymore right because they take
all of these components and it's not
just ads anymore it's not just a cookie
on your machine because I don't really
care about that you know it's not just
that they're tracking Who I am because
that's creepy and weird but even that
sometimes I can live with but then it
all comes together and I go and I look
for information and I get something that
I don't even know if it's real okay and
that's where things really get
interesting right there's some studies
that have been done and there's this
thing now called the search engine
manipulation effect okay and it's based
on all these things I just talked about
where because with what they
know about us and because of how they
manage and track our computers they
understand now how you're gonna respond
to things when they put it in front of
you okay and we've seen things like in
this this this study that was done in
2015 they could change people's position
on fracking by as much as thirty three
percent ok pro or con okay we've talked
to everybody familiar with election
interference all kinds of other things
that go on and that's based on this
stuff that I'm talking about right now
okay
and human nature a little bit and if you
want to see it in action any of you can
do this right so there's this fun little
game you can play with Google now if
probably won't work with most of the
people in the room because we all do the
same thing right we're kind of boring
it's like we're in technology we look at
security and privacy stuff you know
whatever but do it with somebody that
doesn't do what you do and go to Google
works especially well with the images
page right and search something and then
compare your results okay what they see
and what you see are not gonna be the
same thing you're gonna get a different
set of images you're gonna get a
different set of information because
it's curated to who they are it's
curated to their identity that we were
talking about earlier and now we're in a
place where like I said you don't know
what's true so before I jump a little
further into the dark web and I just
want to summarize you know these ideas
here of the importance of privacy
security decentralization and the
natural question then becomes why bother
with the dark web can't the Internet be
better can't we make it a better place
well maybe I don't know right there's
some things that are happening out there
there's some things that hopefully will
make it better we can talk about
technologies that are really promising
like blockchain there could be some
interesting applications of that that
allow it to function on the Internet in
a way that helps solve some of these
security privacy decentralization
problems
on how its implemented so that's wicked
cool and I'm excited about it
there can be information sharing right
just between people where we say here's
a good service here's something that's
ethical here's something that doesn't
track your data you know you should
really use DuckDuckGo instead of Google
or whatever it is that you decide to do
right so yeah maybe could help
there's watchdog groups out there like
the Electronic Frontier Foundation right
they're constantly looking at this stuff
they're looking at laws that are being
passed looking at technology companies
to see what their terms and conditions
look like are they violating people's
rights you know so there's some of that
that's going on - that could help
however we still have issues with the
Internet okay and the first one is a
name asymmetry of power and that stems
from that decentralization problem okay
I don't have the Internet in my house in
a box where I can control everything
about I depend on lots and lots of other
people I depend on those big five tech
companies to give me access to the World
Wide Web
I depend on that for my YouTube videos I
depend on that as I do research for this
talk right and if I don't like what
they're doing guess what I can do about
it any ideas yeah somebody give me a
better idea there's a lot of people in
here somebody's got a good idea right
what do you do decentralized so I
decentralized Amazon Facebook Apple
googa I have no control over that yeah
decentralization absolutely okay but I
can't do anything about it I can either
participate or not where's the choice in
that right and then there's a network
effect how many of you guys are on
Mastodon two three how many of you are
on Twitter a lot more hands how many of
you tried to get your friends to go to
Mastodon and nobody would go one right
we have Network effect issues
everybody's on the Internet there
are using all the stuff that's out there
who uses venmo there's a few of you yeah
who got your friend that has been Moe
installed on their phone to take Manero
instead nobody right it's a pain it's
like I don't want to download another
app connect my bank account to it all
this kind of so wherever people are
that's where the stuff is and that's
where everybody goes so we have a
problem in that all of this
decentralized not private not secured
stuff has all the people and nobody
wants to leave because the alternative
is useless all right you know and then
the last the last thing here and I
really can't read that lack of monetary
motivation right people are making money
at this stuff
okay there is no incentive if you
control it all and you're making lots
and lots of money on it
why would you change a thing you know
you can go sit in front of Congress all
day long and talk about privacy and just
not care because you're still cashing
checks bigger checks and their salary
and then the whole government makes
probably right so at a point you just
don't care you're gonna do whatever it
takes to keep the gravy train rolling
you're gonna say whatever they want to
hear and then go do what you want to do
and so even if we had some companies on
the internet decide yeah we'll do the
right thing you know hey Facebook Apple
right we're gonna protect your personal
information right how do you know what
can you do about it
do you know if Apple's protecting your
personal information i pinky swear but I
made another billion dollars off of
selling your data so I don't care right
like I said this all comes back to
choice and that's where the dark web
comes in that that's why I wanted to
talk today to the security community
about embracing the dark web because the
rest of the world is like the people I
described to begin with they whisper to
me have you ever been on the
well okay and years and years ago there
was this really cool little operating
system that people like called Linux and
it wasn't on anything
who here installed Linux like way back
okay my first in Linux and I wasn't
right right at the beginning but I was
rotating thirty to three and a half inch
floppy disks right because I wouldn't
hold enough and I didn't have enough
floppy disk to actually write it on it
so eyes rotating them is like I didn't
put one in install that piece of it and
and one I just took out I'd write with
the next segment of the image right and
so and it was really obnoxious and hard
you know and there were some famous
people in Linux community that talked
about just run a few shell scripts you
know you write some C code you know
pretty soon the thing works kind of on
some hardware maybe right but it was
really really hard and now I can stand
up in front of you guys I can walk into
a place like this I can plug my Linux
laptop in and it works and guess what I
installed it and I didn't install any
drivers it worked
power management works I can close the
thing and open it again and it still
works you know that's awesome because
for people that don't remember that was
a gamble you did not close on Linux
laptop all right you might have to
reinstall afterwards but that all
relates to the dark web because the dark
web is hard and scary right now and so
we need to do something about that
and technology and especially security
people the perfect people to do that
because who better to help you know
people get on to the dark web than
people that understand security because
there are things there you should avoid
who better to help people understand
privacy than people that have been
looking at privacy issues for as long as
technology's been around and hopefully
before if we remember that stuff
happened before us right or who better
to look at decentralization that people
that understand why that matters so
I'm gonna dig into just real quick some
of the dark web technologies because
that's not the focus of this talk but I
want to make sure that everybody has
enough information to walk away from
here and go do something so the first
thing to understand about the dark web
is there isn't one of them does
everybody understand that it's not just
the dark web
okay there's three major dark web
technologies and they don't necessarily
interoperate you know I mean you can
connect to some things from other things
but so the three the one most people
have heard about is tor okay so the
Onion Routing network so there's tor it
provides some things it gives you some
anonymity gives you some privacy gives
you some security it's got three layers
of encryption that it goes through when
it's making connections which is awesome
unfortunately it does have some
centralized aspects to it and I'll show
you an interesting thing when I get to
actually demoing some of the dark web in
a second that relates to centralization
the next technology is i2p
okay I 2p focuses again on anonymity or
privacy security they wanted to be
cooler than in tor so they did four
layers of encryption and they have some
decentralized self-organizing aspects to
the network now again the purpose of
this talk isn't to give you everything
and make you walk out of here as dark
web experts the purpose is for you to
take the slide right here and go learn
everybody in here is a security person
okay so I want you to give you a little
bit to go fish and then come back
hopefully next year you know and do your
own presentations on the cool thing you
did on the dark web but the last one is
free net free Nets a little bit
different okay it provides anonymity but
it's really focused on censorship
resistant communication okay and
publishing so free nuts really cool
because it provides anonymity it also
provides total decentralization there's
like a complete copy of everything
shared everywhere okay so you try to
take something down on free net it's
basically impossible
you could go raid the data center and
take all the servers out guess what
there's copies and every other data
center in the world
you're not getting very far but each one
of these has their own ideology if you
stucked or people on I to people and I
to people in a room there'd be a great
argument about why three versus four
layers of encryption about what the
better way is to do it whatever doesn't
matter to me at this point the point is
is that they all provide these features
and they all provide a choice which is
what I'm interested in a super simple
illustration of how tor works basically
tor network you connect to it and
there's a series of nodes and and the
way this works is that there's three
layers of encryption get peeled off as
you go through the notes so it starts
out with you and the next hop in the in
the network illustrated by the first
green computer there right and when you
connect to that it peels off that first
layer of encryption it says I know how
to talk here
well that computer then talks to the
next computer in the node and this stuff
is randomized and that peels off another
layer of encryption before it finally
gets to your exit node where it peels
off the last layer of encryption and
turns it loose on to the internet or the
Tor network or whatever it is okay so
this is basically how this works the
nodes only know the identity of the node
that preceded them okay so when you
connect to a resource on the Internet
you know when you went through all this
work to protect your identity and logged
into Facebook Facebook only knows the
red computer okay they don't know where
you started right and that's kind of the
idea behind this at a high level I to P
functions in a fairly similar way with
some technological differences like I
said that people will argue about a lot
free networks completely differently but
again the point isn't to dig into all of
their technical capabilities it's more
about this is generally what they do so
I want to take a minute to now to just
do a quick demo of what it looks like to
access the dark web okay because I want
to get rid of the whisper okay lots of
people you have you been on the dark web
yep in about five seconds all of you
will have done
all right so first thing I want to do is
bring up another time and be able to
read so first thing I'm gonna talk about
tour today because it's fairly
straightforward and people are familiar
with it go to tor project org first
thing that you're gonna see is gonna get
to this home page there's a download
link there download the tor browser
that's how that works
okay if you downloaded something before
you're good depending on what you use if
you use like a Linux distribution or
other distributions Mac works fine if
you download the browser you can also
install it from brew on Linux sometimes
it's in your package manager there's a
launcher that will go down and pull down
the latest version of the tor browser
whatever point is it's simple if you can
click it download link you're pretty
good
the next step is going to be installing
okay if you've ever installed a piece of
software on your computer you're still
good okay so if we can get past these
two amazingly technologically difficult
URLs you can get on the dark web once we
get that done and you install it you get
a thing that looks like this if any of
you guys have ever used Firefox before
you're still not lost okay
the tor browser is based on firefox and
once you're here there's a few things
that you can do so again first thing i
want to do is verify that i'm actually
on tour okay congratulations i'm on tour
that's awesome now if i look back here
this is my regular browser
second one you think it have my
bookmarks memorized right
okay well we verified that one of these
browsers is using tor and one's not okay
so this is a good thing to do after you
connect people it's like if you're gonna
if you want to be anonymous you should
verify you're actually anonymous tor
project provides a page to check that
out all right so that's cool next thing
I can do is actually check where the
internet thinks I'm coming from which is
this link right here okay
IP location somebody that's looking at a
bigger screen than me tell me where I'm
at Amsterdam awesome
anybody here in Amsterdam yeah help me
out all right so my regularly configured
browser I assume so somewhere near Salt
Lake or Provo what's it
alright close enough right so we can see
here tor browser has just by installing
and using a different browser I'm able
to ensure that I'm connecting through
that series of nodes and that I'm it
looks like I'm coming from somewhere
other than I am
so I've handled a couple of things I've
dealt with some security and I've dealt
with some privacy anonymity right now I
think which one is that
that's a good one okay so once you get
on tour then what right I'm on the dark
web yay we've done it okay that's how
exciting it is and how difficult it is
so once you hear hope new time all right
what can you do well you can do a lot of
things that you do everywhere else
you want to look at the news okay fine
here's a wiki page okay this is the
hidden wiki I believe basically gives
you an index of a lot of stuff on the
dark web things you might find
interesting
okay kind of like what the internet used
to look like before search engines we
used to go to this page and check out
all the stuff now I don't want to waste
time trying to navigate all this stuff
because I can't see it but one of the
interesting things I was talking about
earlier is there's actually a note on
here you guys might be able to see some
of it up there the red letters probably
they were down for a few weeks okay
they're running on tour and there is a
massive bust over in Europe in their
data center for other people on the dark
web and they took all the servers in the
data center okay tor is not
decentralized is the thing that I
brought up earlier where I 2p and free
net have some decentralization aspects
to them so when the Fed showed up and
took all of the servers in the data
center even though these guys weren't
doing anything illegal they were kind of
swept up in the process and they're back
online now but it took a couple weeks
because they had to go find some new
servers okay if you've been running on
one of the other networks they have more
decent civilization and resiliency to
that something like free net this would
have never disappeared because it's
actually in a million copies all over to
the internet so you can look at indexes
of what is on the dark web we can look
at things like news so maybe you want to
look at news that hasn't been tailored
to your personal preferences you want to
hear other viewpoints instead of just
having your own personal biases
reinforced over and over again so you
have an option here
to go and look at a website that is a
major reporting agency throughout the
world and you're gonna get first tier
news but without any of it being
customized to you you're just gonna see
the news okay and there's lots of
resources like this on the dark web I've
got a whole list of them here and I'm
not gonna go through each of them but
you can go to DuckDuckGo from tor so
you're hiding and browsing privately
anonymously right and take that extra
step to make sure that even though
DuckDuckGo says that they don't track
your information they definitely cannot
if you're doing it through tor and that
brings up another point that i think is
really important here which is my hope
is that through usage of the dark web it
gives each of us a tool to get beyond
the pinkie-swear right if a company says
like DuckDuckGo we're not tracking you
then it should not matter if i use your
site anonymously if I turn off ads
cookies you know scripts and I get there
from a place you can't track your site
should function exactly the same way as
it does if I go there from another
Avenue right which gives us a little bit
of power back because now we can use
this to make the internet a better place
we can use this to hold companies
accountable if they say that they're not
selling our data or they're not abusing
our privacy right because what's gonna
happen is we've been able to take some
level of control about how we interact
and prove that they're not doing those
things because it still functions
all right so I want to talk about a call
to action and this is where we're gonna
finish up I'm gonna take you back in
history again just for a minute okay to
Amsterdam in 1943 Amsterdam had been
innovated by the Nazi Party and the Nazi
Party had been rounding up Jews in
Amsterdam with incredible effectiveness
and the reason why was because there was
a public register there that had very
detailed information on every single
person that lived in the city including
their nationality or ethnicity and so as
a result of that the Jews had no chance
okay there were pictures
you couldn't pose as somebody else you
couldn't offer a fake ID you couldn't go
get food somewhere else right because of
the detailed information that was there
now there was a group of people in
Amsterdam that was aware of this and it
was a teacher it was a doctor it was a
couple of students there was a tailor
all in all there's about 27 of them I
believe if I remember correctly that
decided that they had to do something
about this okay it wasn't the army it
wasn't trained soldiers it was normal
people they put together a plan and said
we don't want to hurt anybody we're not
in this as combat we just need to stop
what's happening right so they hatched
this plan where they would sneak into
the public register which was under Nazi
guard they would knock the guards out
they had a doctor with him who could
actually administer some stuff they
didn't want to harm anybody so and they
had a tailor that made policeman
uniforms for them so they looked
official and they wouldn't be suspicious
right away when they walked in the door
and so they waited until nighttime and
they went in knocked the guards out and
poured kerosene
all over the records then they lit it
all on fire
well they had also coordinated with the
fire department they said don't show up
right away okay and then when they did
and they said use a lot of water let's
make sure we finish this off and so a
bunch of normal people saw something
that wasn't working right and decided to
do something about it and they destroyed
the amsterdam public register and so
that's what I'd like to do today I'd
like to have each of you decide to do
something about it because one of the
problems that we have right now with the
dark web is that it's hard okay it's
hard to get to I showed you something
pretty easy but for non-technology
people they're not gonna go do that
because they don't they wouldn't even
know where to start so they need us to
facilitate that process this little box
that I'm showing right here is something
I have at home I love this thing it fits
in my hand it's got a network port on
each end okay and I can use it in line
or it's actually a wireless access point
so in my house if you connect to that
wireless network you're automatically on
VPN and tor no configuration necessary
super simple anybody in my house knows
how to connect to a Wi-Fi network these
types of things make stuff easy you know
it's a little difficult right now to
create content for the dark web there's
not a lot that's useful up there you
know maybe somebody should create a Wix
or Weebly for the dark web wouldn't take
more than you know a couple hours worth
of scripting to make that happen okay
and we have the skills to do that right
my mother-in-law does not so this is
what I'd like to leave you with today
I'd like you to walk out of here and go
use the dark web okay do what you can do
if you grade it right in software write
some cool software that makes the dark
web easier if you like hardware build a
cool device if you aren't technical at
all and you just like security and you
think this is important go read a book
and talk to somebody about it right tell
them that privacy matters
tell them why decentralization is
important and tell them why we want our
data to be secure
that's it go play on the dark web thanks
for coming
I think I've got just a couple minutes
if there isn't yeah that's called an
anon abox okay so it's basically just a
single board computer in there and you
can build your own I purchase that one
because it's super easy but yeah it's
just any single board computer you could
do it with Raspberry Pi you could do it
with a Lena whatever you want anybody
else yep mmhmm yeah speeds definitely an
issue and I would I found now is it
depends on the site so you see that
people that are hosting in better
locations like DuckDuckGo is super fast
right they're a corporation that's
enabling people on the dark web some of
these independent news sites or like a
social media site they're still terrible
they're not super fast yeah yeah and
that comes down to the network effect
right so that's a real problem
that that's like I try to browse things
from tor and they're like nope and I
found this very interesting when I was
researching some of this I went to a lot
of state government websites most of
them let me in okay Utah was like yeah
no problem I don't care New York City
was fine Texas at the time had just been
hit with that massive ransomware attack
they were like nope you're not getting
anywhere near us right so I mean that's
definitely an issue but I think it's an
issue that's addressable through usage
okay it's that network effect I talked
about if there's enough people there
that they have to account for it then
they will account for it but until that
exists then there's always gonna be
things we can't access this way anybody
else yeah
um probably I don't I mean I think I've
been on the FBI watch list for about 20
years because of my career and it's like
I subscribed to Linux magazines and
don't have social networking accounts
but you know all of that puts you on the
list just downloading the software I
don't think necessarily puts you on any
list you can easily use a VPN or some
other technology to go download the
software and at least get some level of
anonymity right until you make the
connections there is certain content on
the dark web that absolutely I mean
unequivocally do not view do not go pass
go that will get you in trouble and I'm
not gonna talk about what that is but I
think anybody that has any understanding
of the law would know when they're
crossing some lines pretty quickly yeah
I have at times I don't currently and I
would like to again in the future I'm
actually working a lot right now I want
to create content for the dark web so
that's where I'm focusing my efforts
right now as opposed to exit notes but
yeah ya know that's power chords yep yep
uh-huh sure
yep I agree with you and Mozilla by
default I mean you can just change go to
about config you can make Firefox access
tour site so you don't have to download
the tor browser the reason why I say to
do that is because it's got other
configuration in there that plug-in
security things like that that helps yep
yeah cool all right I think we need to
get out of here so the next guy can get
going but thank you guys
[Applause]
testing testing hello that good