all right welcome everyone to my
presentation today thanks for coming out
I know there's a lot of awesome
presentations and I'm glad you decided
to come spend some time with me today is
one man's trash is another man's home
lab which I should have done the subtext
under there that how Shawn learned had a
dumpster dive and not get caught
I like how y'all laughed at that anyway
a little bit about me first off just one
disclaimer all my slides are pretty word
heavy reason for that is I want you to
I'm gonna distribute these after vac so
you can have them I've got model numbers
prices stuff I'm using a little bit loud
sorry model numbers prices and whatnot
so don't worry about trying to take
frantic notes or anything along those
lines because I'll be distributing these
I am a UVU graduate right here from the
valley I I did what they call their
10-year plan and that's where you
basically go to school for the first bit
sorry we good so it's when you go to
school you see a new class come in and
they go through the program and graduate
and you're still going and then the next
class comes in and they go through four
years and they graduate and you're still
there and then after ten years you get a
bachelor's degree and it was like why
are you gonna after your doctorate no
just taking a while I'm a wire shirt bar
shark could fix you not oh I did that
for ten years every trace is interesting
to me so if you have an awesome one come
find me and say hey I got a goal tres4
I'd love to see it I have very strong
opinions about VLANs and network
segmentations so just one of my one of
my quirks if you really want to get me
talking for the better part of an hour
ask me should I VLAN my home network
other hobbies I'm a mountain bike
enthusiast here in the valley it's great
making braking tinkering I think we all
do that PC gaming of course a little bit
of podcasting not too much and I'm not a
Cylon if anyone is asking thought I'd
get that out right now so why do I need
a home lab this this question is
something that I posted with a lot of my
co-workers a lot of friends over the
years why do we even need one
and really IT workers have become the
tradesmen of the 21st century if you
think of times of old you'd have
carpenters and plumbers and electricians
they'll have those now but back in the
day you'd have to sharpen your tools
after work you couldn't go to a job site
with dull tools and expect to sharpen
among the customers time and it's gotten
more complex IT systems has gotten and
bigger and stronger and more connected
and and it almost seems like it's hard
to keep up with just our you know 8:00
to 5:00 9:00 to 5:00 time learning and
keeping up with all these new
technologies budgets are stretched a lot
of employers are really actually
foregoing having a tester sandbox
environment just had a question you can
raise your hand if you want how many
actually has a true sandbox at work true
not connected to anything else sandbox
that if you break it no one cares so
eight a few more okay that's awesome I'm
glad you have that most people don't
want to learn so the time kind of
sharpen your school skills at home has
arrived and that's and that's what this
is all about and and a lot of people say
well why don't you just go to trainings
why don't you do online courses all that
and those are great paying for
professional hands-on training is a very
effective method but a lot of those are
focused on one piece of that one piece
of a technology one aspect one thing and
a lot of times they're one and done will
go for a week have a great time make
some new friends learning about
technology
six months later if you haven't touched
it again do you remember it
not so much and a lot of trainings that
like I said are focused on short-term
memorization one-and-done pass a test
get it going in contrast a home lab is
your own personal environment where
you've built it and rebuilt and torn it
apart and breaking it and had the rest
of your people in their family yell at
you because the Internet's down again
for the eighth time because it was just
a patch it should have had a problem but
yeah here's my favorite John Wayne photo
you can't play in prod you can it's a
terrible idea but you can the path to
the unemployment line is paved in
changes that should have had any
problems everyone I think it knows a
cowboy in their organization if you
don't you're likely that person
again everyone's laughing but they're
like oh yeah I kind of am as complex and
connected some stuff is it's getting
hard to the point where you can't make
changes downstream um I remember I was
benchmarking some dis stuff and all the
sudden prods start to feel like I'm like
I'm isolated there's no way I'm touching
it well I was saturating the network
linked a little bit heavy and things
happen so I came up with the rules of
home lab now just a fair warning with
the rules of home lab I break every
single one of these on a daily basis but
still they're good rules and we should
probably follow them but I don't
you should I should do home lab stays
isolated do not put your family photos
on home lab minor on home lab right now
look proper clothes don't find their way
to home lab they will move them off you
should be able to break it crash it tear
it apart and no one cares except for
yourself having your production edge
router in your home lab bad idea we
still do and then like I said real stuff
you care about does not live there and a
lot of fun oh I love it I love tearing
apart stuff I love building up labs I
love finding high-value enterprise gear
that's been discarded and thrown away
and repurposing it really if you're not
in if you don't really find this fun
you're probably in the wrong seat here
in the bus some awesome home lab
projects how many have a plex server
yeah there's my plex users yeah that's a
great first project one of the first
thing I almost everyone does home
automation is getting really awesome in
in-home lab and the reason to me I
mentioned a home assistant and open have
these are isolated systems these are
systems where you actually make a choice
whether connectivity from the outside
world comes in or not a lot of the
off-the-shelf Samsung smartthings
looking at you has to be cloud connected
right and in a world of privacy which
I'm very much a part of I really want to
make sure that we control that and open
have or no home isn't great thing on
that same privacy token private cloud
services run your own cloud stop using
Google Drive or whatever onedrive
containerization right place to play the
containerization if you've never done it
before
micro segmentation I've actually got an
environment right now where I've got two
hosts on the same broadcast domain they
can't talk to each other
it's fantastic Sdn VPN private's no can
do t if you go to your Starbucks you go
to public places you could use a
third-party VPN service that claims they
don't have logs and claims they don't
get hacked
I have news but I would try to zero tier
awesome project for that if you're a
play to zero tier you should check it
out it's fantastic run your own IP
camera envy our system blue iris shinobi
there's a few others out there that are
super great again avoiding the cloud
always onto technologies with that PBX
if you've ever want to put a phone in
every room of your house and have an
intercom to call everyone I don't know
why you're weird but ok that's cool we
can do that and then piehole another
awesome thing if you want to do a whole
home ad blocking go and check that out
great place to put it in the lab so kind
of what makes a good home lab I've come
up with I like to call the the Trinity
of home lab and I made this up myself
and it's it I think it's pretty great
you have your upfront cost
you've got your ongoing cost which is
your power and you got your performance
and you want to balance all three of
those those things you to hit me on one
of them you're gonna have a bad time and
then you have to pass what I like to
call the chaff that's the cohabitant
acceptance factor yes
chaps can can vary from super easy I
mean I live by myself so if anything
goes to you better have it all cleaned
up and nice but in a closet and then
you're doing exhaust fans and all that
good stuff once you pass that chaff
security gate you're good to go
and we're doing home lab so think about
your chest right now
I'm flowers or presents or gifts or
build them an awesome gaming rig and
then you do what you want ok so again
very calm to heavy I'm very sorry
pick a budget and stick to it when we're
talking about your upfront cost and
buying something it's so easy to
nickel-and-dime yourself and I have done
it so many times be realistic with your
expectations don't go and think and
you're gonna get yourself 44 cores for a
nickel it's not gonna happen we're using
your home gear as a fine place to start
it works
it comes with limitations and don't
think to get a home lab you need to go
buy enterprise gear that's what I do
because I like it I like playing with it
I'm trying to mirror production as close
as I can but really you could take your
old desktop PC throw some alternative
software on and start learning and
that's great it's a good place to start
the one that I've bolded that you really
can't tell is bolded says do not force
yourself down an expensive path because
you found a good deal on a single item
and I'll get in that in just a moment
these are your main pieces right here on
the right side you got your compute CPU
RAM stick with ECC I'll get more into
that and out-of-band management is
fantastic for a home lab for your
storage you got your cache and capacity
tiers rent talk about that and then
switching we run I run ten Giga home for
my home lab for my server interconnects
not tell my desktops it can be done it
can be done for cheap and there are
options to do it I'll talk about that
software VMware fantastic run v san I've
ran visa at my house it was painful and
expensive but it worked
hyper-v can do stores bases the stores
basis directs pretty good have some
patience when you're building this don't
go out and saying hey after this
presentation it was so good thank you
then I went out and bought a whole new
home lab you will spend a lot of money
doing that way this is a marathon and
not a sprint so I'm gonna tell you a
cautionary tale of forcing yourself down
a very expensive path it was the summer
2015 let me set the scene summer 2015
Terminator Genisys had just come out
disappointing fans worldwide David
Letterman was at the end of his show and
I was browsing public surplus as one
does and public surplus is a great is a
great tool you can find a lot of stuff
that cities governments schools are
getting rid of it's it's one of the
resources you can also buy yourself a
box of 205 port gigabit switches I don't
know why you do that parenthetically
kids don't like those as the
trick-or-treating gifts I don't get it I
would have loved one but it's fine they
didn't like it but more like well what's
this I'm like it's gigabit welcome so I
found myself a dl380 gen9 was think
about putting one in their house yeah I
did
and this was the time I was moving from
more of a analytical role to a to a
hands-on practical role and I thought I
need a real server I'm gonna do this for
realsies
so as my acknowledgement server hardware
came I knew Zeon equals server that's
about as far as I got so I said hey if
this has to Zeon's that's got to be
better than anything right 220 watt TDP
Zeon's I might add there X 54 60s if
anyone's curious had an HP p 400 RAID
controller built in with a bloated
battery didn't know the dangers of that
first time had dual power supplies
because two was better than one of
course and 32 gigs of high-performance
ddr2 memory mm-hmm we're excited and it
cost him about $200 you'll see that's my
sticky note you see the green laser
through the back of it does that work oh
oh technology you can see like my
initial analysis of my server and my
winnings also notice I'm wearing some
kind of like crew socks with dad shoes I
don't know what that was going on but
and lucky for you guys I take pictures
of all my stupid projects you get a
laugh at them I mean learn from them so
what a smart person would have done at
this point this point liver said hey I
have a server let's get started let's
learn some things this is great that's
what a real smart person would do what a
moron does is he goes and buys at eight
friends yeah that's my basement of my
house with nine dl380p five because if
one's good nines got to be better so I
thought hey I've got them all of us take
the parts out we'll build one super
server it's gonna be awesome it's gonna
be sweet so I did it I took all the SAS
drives a pin mill enclosure I racked it
up notice you can actually still see my
sticky note there on top that's the same
box and I had 8 by 146 gig 10k SAS
drives for a whopping 11 68 gigs raw a
twenty six I forgot read six I had done
it I needed more so logically the first
thing to do is say hey those are two and
a half inch drives SATA can go into a
SAS backplane well why don't we just go
and buy ourselves much a two terabyte
laptop drives I don't work so I did I
spent 400 bucks
said hey
- these that'll be great so I got him
like a moron again I unwrapped them all
real quick put him in all my sleds
shoved in my server there are no
available physical drives oh the HPP 400
can't support a hard drive over 800 gigs
I just filled out a bunch of laptop
drives on a server that won't work okay
no keep in mind I already open the ball
I already put him in the sleds they're
not going back so what would an
enterprising young man do at this point
nobody do he would cut his losses and
try again no I'll buy me a P for 10
controller that supports drives that are
bigger so I bought a P for 10 on eBay
spent 35 or $30 on it buy it now
fantastic oh I didn't know RAID
controller just had different connectors
for backplanes
but that's a thing s FF 8087 what is
that I don't know well I'll just build a
fan-out cable I don't need to do that no
stinkin backplane I got a fan on cable
okay
well if I just did a fan-out cable why
am I still using these little laptop
drives I can just run em outside of the
chassis of the servitor well I don't
wanna have dry state around I know
I'll buy yet another thing which is a
hard work which is a little external
hard drive rate or dock with you know
the five drives in that have it sitting
outside next to the server it'll be good
that'll work so I did that and that's
what it'll bike again remember my chaff
is low yours might not be this low now
now notice there's one of those drives
right there that I bought remember that
ya gotta use it but after all of this
hullabaloo and all this work success I
had a drive so again I've got a serve
working server I should use it this will
be good I'll learn things no no no let's
rip up our my perfectly working nasod I
already built and put all the drives in
the server yes that's a great idea
so I did that yeah horrible idea but at
the end of the day I was on a mission
and my mission was to get ESXi running
with my drives all ready to go so
I did it you can see it there it is
running it's beautiful I got ten point
eight two terabytes variable in grade
six success I had done it seven hundred
and eighty two dollars later remember
this started with a two hundred dollar
like purchase from public surplus we're
just gonna forget the other eight
servers I bought happen let's just
forget that happening cuz that's not
include in that figure six months later
might be four ten died yeah so on that
note what happens when your specialized
RAID controller dies can you just grab
your drives and shove them in a new box
no you can't you need another P for ten
so I had to literally grab my rack of
hard drives run over to a friend of mine
who had a P 410 rebuild my array and
then export my data back off on to large
format external drives which I had to
purchase a Best Buy that night that was
the gift that keeps on givin the whole
year it really was so you know for a
thousand dollars in seven months your
life you can have a server for seven
months so coming back to the Trinity
there's the upfront cost please learn
from my mistake that was a horrible I
actually wanted to subtitle this whole
talk of don't do what I do I'm dumb but
I didn't think they'd accept it so I
kept that off but I'll tell you that
let's talk about ongoing cost this is
your power calculate this as a yearly
cost not as a daily cost it is super
easy to fool yourself thinking quarter a
day's not too bad thirteen cents a day
of power is not too bad calculate on the
yearly just as a frame of reference 500
Watts running 24/7 is about four hundred
thirty dollars a year in Lehigh because
we don't have cured power yes my what my
back right now is about a kilowatt I'm
about a thousand miles from Iraq just in
case you're curious and I'm running warm
will keep your house warm in the winter
and hot in the summer putting it in your
romaine office where you work day to day
is a bad idea unless you want to go for
that whole sauna thing in the office
which more power to you I think it's
awesome
your increased capacity and replacement
is an ongoing cost your capacity tier is
going to grow exponentially as you start
getting more stuff and building more
projects
plan on component failures if you find a
good deal on on a component that you're
using and you like and it works well by
two of them just by two so you don't
have to run hat and hand over your
friend's house to get him to build your
RAID controller by a kilowatt that
little beauty right there take it with
you when you go test stuff to buy it
because a lot of stuff we do second hand
oh when I go buy a piece of hardware
I'll actually take my kill while plug it
in look at the power and be like have a
good day thank you so much here's ten
bucks are every time software's cost in
there give MSDN v mug we'll talk a
little bit about it but if you've never
heard of e mug Advantage program it's
fantastic it's $200 a year you pretty
much get everything VMware has for home
lab use and so that's how I ran V San
you an even dozen VDI horizon good stuff
like that I'm talking about performance
we're not billing prod here we're not
going we're not going nuts so think
about your workloads and plan
accordingly if you wanted run a bunch of
VMs having a single platter as a bad
idea trust me from experience I thought
ten terabyte I can fit a bunch of VMs on
that thing
Wow I'm running to and it's def focus
your efforts on ram capacity and you're
gonna hear me say that a lot ram ram ram
it's wonderful if you are going to do
spinning drives for your capacity tear
go ahead and get some SSDs as a cache to
end up so now that that's all out of the
way I'm sold
let's build it let's do it so obtaining
components ranked by effectiveness
number one end of life decommission
equipment from your employer if if you
have a if you have the employee PC
purchase program if you have like a a
garage sale type program the employer
works participate in that that's usually
the best place you'll find your best
deals the stuffs already been advertised
the taxman took his cut whatever nine
times out of ten little sell to you for
a really good cost my work does that
it's fantastic if you don't have one
talked to those in ite talk to those who
manage that stuff even get one set up
it's a fantastic way to do it please
just make sure that it fits the home lab
criteria don't run any C 7000 it's at
home
I actually know someone who is and
they're nuts but awesome and ensure
proper data destruction best back to
this please number two is have a guy and
that's pretty much the same as number
one it's just he's gonna take all the
good stuff first and give you the
leftovers still pretty good
I have a few guys that I use like that
you're getting second pickings but it's
it's pretty it's usually pretty
effective sometimes that guys just
better looking at EBA than you are
that's okay
number three classifieds Facebook mark
place eBay you do okay their Facebook
marketplace I don't had a lot of server
stuff eBay there's tons and tons and
tons and tons classifieds not so much
there's some here in the Whaley and then
number four is your IP right cyclers
these are the places like Tam's if
you've heard of them though this is
where the companies will send their
stuff to be destroyed and resold you're
gonna spend a little bit more there
admittedly but they kind of know what
they have going on so it kind of comes
with the territory sometimes it comes
with warranty I hit a switch fail after
I bought from one of these recyclers and
I had them replace it which was super
awesome so let's start compute and again
content-heavy slide I'm very sorry but
you'll get at these afterwards right now
as of 2019 right now your best bang for
your processor best bang for your buck
processors are right here in this top
corner if you can't see them they're the
2650 B twos if you do the L model you
get 10 cores 20 threads and very low
power usage as far as that goes you're
talking about 75 80 watt TDP at idle
they're gonna be takin about 15 20 just
for the processor itself and it goes up
from there all these processors on this
list go for about 50 to 80 dollars on
eBay and then they are on the VMware HDL
46.7 so you're gonna stay supported if
you don't care about the HDL so much
that's fine you can use them older stuff
I like to stay on that list just so I
don't have to deal with gremlins inside
my lab they use LGA 2011 motherboards
they can be found for about 180 for a
dual vertol socket generally the super
micros are the ones that are out there
they're sticking with ddr3 memory which
is a little bit cheaper right now
especially if you're going easy see I
haven't made the jump in the home lab
guides to go to a ddr4 yet just cuz it's
still a little bit pricey it's coming
down and it's coming up pretty quick but
it's still not quite there if you don't
want to do a true enterprise board you
can do an X 79 chipset that was the kind
of the workstation or enthusiast boards
a little bit cheaper alternative fine
notice right here the bottom will avoid
the Aliexpress motherboards they
actually have some x79 s on Aliexpress
they're about $60 here's a few problems
they work they do work and I've tried
one here's the problems
one all the manuals are in Chinese like
all of them to BIOS updates not gonna
happen
and three they're not making that
chipset anymore so it kind of makes me
wonder where they get them are they
overruns are they old stuff are they D
soldering recycled parts I don't know
you're gonna end up spending six months
waiting for it then be sad on Christmas
morning so I try to avoid it they also
sell at dual x79 board on there which I
found the other day which the X I mean I
never came in a duel at 79 set up I
don't know what black magic voodoo is
happening make that happen just avoid it
plug for the best when it comes to like
mounting this if you're doing yourself
you're building your own server don't do
this this is a recipe for unpleasantness
so what I did is I had a 3d printer I
salut and I said hey I'll just print
some brackets and put these 7200 rpm
drives all nice and cozy with no airflow
right here down here this is where
they're supposed to go there's a fan on
and that works pretty well but right
here this is where the magic happened
fun fact
Sony turn rpm drives act really weird
when they get up to 80 Celsius really
weird you're like I swore I saved that
file and now it's gone fantastic there
are affordable server enclosures if
you're going to do something like this
build some fans and make something work
you also may SMO stop power supplies
that you'll get into don't have enough
SATA power headers for that so using
what I like to call Chinese fire
starters and that's your molex to SATA
splitters or your SATA 2 SATA splitters
yes houses burned down because of this
so be careful dry failure rates increase
dramatically when dries off right out of
their operating temperatures so that's a
fun fact for you ok let's say you want
to rebuilt the pre-built server is a
great way to go if you don't want to get
your hands during do-it-yourself the the
thing sir rs1 40s right here in the ps1
40s I don't know how but a slip through
the cracks
a lot of the live guys aren't even using
them enterprises that are throwing away
for about a hundred bucks to 150 to 200
somewhere there they do 35 watts at idle
and 50 to 60 under load they're running
a Xeon e3 1200 series which is the
version 3 which is actually fairly
recent you get four pretty solid cores
and they support Intel Quick Sync so if
you want to do any type of offloading of
your encoding for NVR cameras like that
fantastic option there they come up and
on ebay every now and they're not not
all the time but they're a fantastic
option next is a Super Micro x9 series
these come in literally everything most
people did white-label a lot of Super
Micro stuff the CSEA 25 fantastic
starting place if I want to find Super
Micro gear on ebay I just search for a
Super Micro Spacey 5 and that will kind
of show me all the e5 series that are
coming up and then kind of check your
process your process or compatibility
matrix your Intel Arc all that stuff to
make sure it is what you want they come
with an else I RAID controller it's an
HPA but most people call them raid
controllers and they're about 200 bucks
and you have 200 letters shipped to your
door today I actually noticed some the
slide show those are links when I hand
that out you can click on and not you
take you to an eBay auction it's not
mine I'm not making money off this it's
just something I found because a lot of
these presentations I go to they'd say
you can get these for $80 and you got
eBay and they're all 600 bucks I'm like
are you sure that's why I put them in
there the next one I have is called the
fat twin which less Super Micro and
they're weird and naming things but fat
twin it's actually two nodes
side-by-side in a single chassis and
both of them are twin efox and you can
actually slide to them they share
they've redone a power supply on the
backplane and they've got three PCI
Express slots in them so you can use
those for a 10 gig card or other stuff
really cool chassis if you want to go
really nutso and I applaud you and
please send me pictures they got this
for you CSCE
a 46 that's got 24 size bays in the
front of it you want to talk a build a
FreeNAS that's your ticket right there
that thing would be rad as far as the
Dells go our 720 r6 20s are great buys
right now I say avoid the r7 10 if you
want to stick on the HCL for VMware if
you don't care about that you're just
gonna run whatever Linux Windows
whatever on it you're probably fine with
a r7 10 and those are getting super
cheap
those are also labeled across 20
different labels so you can find little
super cheap and they pretty fantastic be
careful with the version 1 or version 2
compatibility in the processors because
it can get tricky and they had kind of a
mid-cycle refresh on those you have to
be careful there are a little bit on
power-hungry
they come with their perc raid
controllers raid controllers and there
about 300 to 500 dollars depending on
your loadout so let's kind of like your
do-it-yourself and these kind of your
pre-built so if you wanna build a server
now it's getting nutty out of warranty
LAN optimizers now you'd never think hey
I'm gonna build a riverbed I make an
ESXi server out of it you can and it's
fantastic really low power I'm talking
Full Tilt the sucker running as hard as
I can
25 watts is all it takes it's an 8 core
Xeon proc they don't tell you exactly
what modeled is but if you go and do
some digging it's I've narrowed it down
to two specific models it's like I said
it's a it's a soldered on solution it's
not meant ever be changed
runs ESXi just fine open sense wicked
open sense performance it's got eight or
six or eight gig gigabit ports right
across the front so if you want to do
some crazy multi LANs other stuff you
can totally do it you have to turn the
network cards from non pass-through to
regular but it's not easily done the
only thing to be careful to remember the
CX 770 careful with your ram
compatibility they can be a little picky
and they're gonna have RAM limitations
as well so as a monster hypervisor not
so much but if you want to run a bunch
of small stuff that doesn't require
about your am absolutely do it the next
one's the dfid T 120 to be e second
generation excuse me that's a mouthful
there 120 bucks you get an AMD rx series
4 core at 2.7 gigahertz base 3.6 boost
with an in grade in a graded Vega
graphics chip so you can do some room
ATI offloading stuff they also have a
PCI 8x slot in a 16 X form factor so it
just has the lanes of an 8 X but
physically it's a 16 X and therefore
status if you want to build a really
cheap multi node lab set up those are
about a hundred and twenty bucks apiece
and you can pick up three of them and
maybe a fantastic little in lab they
come and go and and available is limited
unfortunately all the lab guys got
turned on to this and they go nuts
forums they sell out really quick when
they hit eBay but you can get one there
fantastic that's what's running my
current production open sense does that
guy right there and it's fantastic now
another cheap way to do it and a lot of
folks do this and this is a great way to
do it is get workstation class machines
you're still getting a Xeon
you're still getting something that's
rated for 24/7 operation for business
use but you can find it quite a bit
cheaper than all servers in the HP
series you're lookin at Z 400 Z's 600 z
6 20s the 80s z 8 20s they can be held
there they're a gamut of prices from 100
to 300 dollars they make fantastic labs
absolutely fantastic good in those same
a5 processors which was on my list of
the ones I liked but you're spending
quite a bit less you're gonna be usually
probably single proc but that's okay the
Dell Precision counterparts that is the
5600 series it's same processors just in
a dell flavor if you prefer dale the 36
hundreds are cool you can get those
working as well they are stuck on
version 1 of the e5 2600 series but they
work just fine for a home lab and then
Supermicro also makes called be super
workstation so it's another totally
viable option for you so that's kind of
more of the pre-built so you got your
do-it-yourself which works you can get
decommissioned servers or you do some
workstations or some crazy riverbeds
which are that link right there is
actually active and they've lowered the
price down to 175 today so after this I
may be buying it alright you might have
you might be B to it networking
one gig is dead long live 10 gig in the
homeland kind of as far as network cards
go the Mellanox connect decks X 2 and X
3s are fantastic for home labs you get a
single port or dual port they come in a
10 gig SFP+ they're 22 for do depending
on your branding you can get them in an
HP branded or Mellanox themselves the
chelsea OT 420 another great option
those are all dual sfp+ is 35 to 40 and
slap those in here to em on your PCI
Express slots and you've got 10 gig
which is which is really awesome
especially if you're going to do any
type of hyper-converged from my testing
even with an often up front and a sat on
the back end I end up maxing about 2.3
gigabits per second on my ports as far
as that goes so a lot of people say well
how about InfiniBand can you run
InfiniBand at home absolutely you can I
know some guys that do it it's just
those are 40 gigs you can if you hit the
pricing right you can get one for cheap
and it's fantastic and it works out for
you
just know you're kind of going in a
cul-de-sac you're not going through
there's no exit strategy there you're
running InfiniBand
and you have to uplink it to the rest of
your network so just know that going in
but you can absolutely do it power usage
this is just an interesting tidbit that
I found out as far as what use are the
most power or at least to most DAC cable
as your least and then you have your
transceiver plus fire and then the one
that surprised me the most is a 10 10 G
base D copper actually uses the most
power out of all those which I found
quite surprising I don't work for FS
comm whatsoever I just like them if you
want to buy optics Dax fiber patches
they'll get it to you within a few days
and it's about 10 bucks 10 bucks for a 6
foot back cable and they're super nice
kind of awkward though cuz sometimes
they'll call you randomly and ask you if
you liked your purchase which is weird
because they're like hey is that working
you have that deployed your enterprise
and I'm sitting there in my mechanical
room going yeah yeah it's in prod that's
great I love it they're super nice I
love it it's like great customer service
but they're they're thinking I'm
something like big business I'm just a
dude who moved as you know water
softener Singh for another rack
who needs soft water I need more power
talking about switching one thing where
I do allow in my own rules to let home
lab and home product of mix is my
network or just because I don't like to
have to do an uplink and run two
switches if you want to run a home
switch with 10 gig here's some options
for you
brocade I see X 64 50 series they come
in a 48 port 1 gig Keowee which is nice
and then for 10 gig ports just please be
careful with port licensing brocade
loves to give you 4 ports but only 2 of
them work until you buy license and in a
home live environment yeah that makes it
not attractive so find one that is
licensing the real money though in this
one right here is your Aruba as 2500 and
yes 3500 these are fantastic 48 ports
gig p OE plus in fact and then for 10
gig ports they're about $125 and you're
talking 48 gig boards and for 10 gigs
and they're not horribly loud as long as
you stick with the lower up power
supplies they got a higher version and a
lower version stick lower unless you're
gonna run some crazy amount of p OE
devices which again I applaud you you're
awesome but just be careful that a rube
is rad because they own them
Ruba slash ruckus they actually give
away firmware updates for free there's
not behind a paywall so you actually go
to their site and pull the latest
updates for your switch which is
fantastic to have I love that if you
want to go Siskel and I get it
WS 3750 e you get 48 ports 1 gig +10
gigs there xfp instead of SFP just keep
that mind if you a lot of people see the
Aruban go like I don't know rubas
command-line if you've ever done a Cisco
it's 80% of the way there the review
ends a little funky but I'm happy to
explain how those work - for them
they're great they're absolutely great
that's what I'm running I was running a
brocade but it explode due to a power
issue that I had that was caused by
myself
let's talk storage I love the storage
part and I love my the 2000s called and
they want their hardware raid cards back
HBAs and software raids are all the
hotness right now and it's true I love
it right size your storage before you
start going nutty with nvme and cache
and optional and stuff maximize your RAM
first that will give you much more bang
for your buck going forward if you're
going to do spinning platters I'd say
stick to the 54 hundred rpms just
because you're gonna spend a lot less
power and heat and other things on that
aligns mind your bus make sure you
balance them if you got multi proc
systems and become real comfy with
cabling types and closures back planes
like you don't want the first time you
ever see an s FF 8087 to be like what is
and can i plug this into my dl380 so
just give them their worth that talking
about SSDs nvme is actually getting
pretty cheap and the reason being is
datacenters are starting to move the Gen
one drives that they put in out of
service so you're talking the the Intel
data center drive P 35 20s you get it
from in a four or 50 gig or a 1.2
terabyte flavor and I'm kidding that's a
hundred eleven dollars for 1.2 1.2 T
nvme and I literally bought it last week
so that price is actually accurate if
you do a best offer of 111 they'll take
it just FYI
they're fantastic they're available in
you dot 2 or you can actually do a full
PCIe slot which works fine too if you
wanna go the sadder out the dcs 35
hundreds or 35 tens or fantastic options
we're talking 80 gigs for 12 bucks 120
gigs for 20 bucks now you notice that
I've got some writing
after the after the capacity and before
the price the tbw that's your terabyte
Renton that's your lifespan of your SSD
just in case anyone doesn't know in this
room you probably all do that SSDs have
a lifespan they have a certain number of
bytes they can write to him that's a
thing most consumer grades even a nice
like a nice one are gonna max out about
200 terabytes written for a one terabyte
drive that's about where they are
planned obsolescence gotta love it
Enterprise drives on the other hand for
a one point two is fourteen eighty
terabytes retina so if you're in the
market for an nvme drive consider going
enterprise
now I already see all of you looking at
me going I don't have a you dot to slot
in my PC or in my server and all the
servers you mentioned won't have you
done - haha we can do this they actually
sell PCI Express to you top two
converters that's a star tech there's
another one there's another company that
sells on their own Amazon they're on a
few other places I don't run you about
$39 and you take your YouTube just slide
it right in there you put the screws on
the back and you drop in a PCI Express
slot and suddenly you have got nvme
goodness they also sell it in at MDOT -
- yup - adapter it looks like that guy
right there the only trouble with those
is you have to pull power off a SATA
header off your power supply they don't
power them there the card the Cardinals
self will power the whole Drive so you
just drop it in and you're and you're
good to go
but those what the m2 is you have to put
a power header on there and I will give
anyone extra points for dropping
enterprise SSDs in their gaming rig
that's what I do that's sitting right
below my graphics card it works great
make sure when you buy one of these
there's some that don't have this cut
out there there's a heatsink there's a
heat spreader on the back of that drive
you want that so it can heat can escape
the thing because it's sitting in there
as you can see upside down and the heat
spreaders are up just some of those will
not have a cutout and they can get kind
of toasty now as far as like lifetime on
them and how good they're written might
have a 93% of its life left when I put
it in when you're buying one when you're
buying one I'd reach out to the seller
and say hey can you give me an S been on
you know lifetime Intel sell the tool
they'll actually pull it up and say hey
we're at 90% life and here's how much
space has been written and all that most
sellers are pretty cool about it won't
say hey here's where it's at you'll be
somewhere in this range and if you're
not will sell you new one
they're not gonna go test them for you
but most sellers are pretty cool about
it if you're buying one secondhand test
it yourself
it's a tiny Intel utility they give it
out for free works great use don't want
to buy an enterprise SSD like on its
last legs that's the only the only real
takeaway they're talkin capacity if you
want to go spinning platters if you want
to go most bang for your buck most
storage you go to Best Buy and you're
all looking at me really funny right now
like Best Buy you buy the Western
Digital easy stores they are a Best Buy
exclusive it's the only place you can
get it but inside of this very
attractive black casing is a Western
Digital red or a white labeled red drive
which as you know is the NAS Drive that
is built for 24/7 operation and is built
for naz's this is still a valid thing I
bought one last month they're still
white the Reds you stress test them
before you shuck them or not the hard
way you will buy this external drive
plugging in your machine right across
little platter give it a stress test use
a utility something about make sure it's
good and then you shuck it like an
oyster and you pop the drive out of the
enclosure you put it in your own server
and you're off to the races
as far as warranty where it goes I
actually keep one of these the one that
I did the best job on shucking that
looks like there's no damage on it I
keep one of these just in my closet in
the event a drive fails cuz they do have
three year warranties on them and I've
put one back into the enclosure and
shipped it off and gotten a new one just
fine so you can do it be careful whether
that's legal or ethical I don't know but
yeah it's a hard drive isn't it I know
I'm gonna get like hauled off like the
Western Digital police are gonna come
and get me after that great we'll enjoy
it folks the last time you'll see this
as far as raid controllers HP is of a
hotness that's where you want to be
software aids are great FreeNAS ZFS like
I love ZFS I had my pea 410 diet and it
made me sad inside I've had several
boxes just flat-out die I've grabbed my
drives ran him over to a new machine
plug them all in ZFS found them all and
said yep there's your drive we're off to
the races
so ZFS is great these are fantastic
options for free HBA is most some
motherboard headers actually have enough
SATA headers on there for you and might
be some
ported which it works fine if it's not
these your options all of these the 92
10s 11s 9 207's all are on the VMware
HCl and your FreeNAS guides so they're
well supported you'll notice there's an
eye on the end of some of them or an e
that basically tells you whether the
connectors internal external if you get
one with an e you can do something super
nutty and awesome and get yourself a
Zyra text-based sass sash tray so you
can actually go by yourself just a dumb
6 gigs ass enclosure has a bunch of bays
in it you slap that in run one single
cable up to your to your HPA and you now
have an entire shelf of spinning drives
for super cheap
those are running about 100 bucks for
these enclosures and they and they come
under a few names Dell Compellent
they're also our tech base SC 200s you
can find him out there and some of the
guides and resources I'll give you after
this can help you find which ones are
great I know one person doing that right
now he went through a very difficult
learning phase because he bought a dell
tray or a Dell EMC which has different
formatting and it was just a it was a
nightmare but there's some definitely
some good options here if you want to
look at the reliability charts black
back glaze puts these out every quarter
I think or every semi-annually or
something
and honestly I used to like really
agonize over these and be like holy
smokes I have to make sure not all which
drives the best avoid the Seagate's get
the hg s DS get the WT reds in all
honesty that you've gotten all pretty
close lately they're all pretty much
within a few percent of percentage
points of each other so I haven't
worried too much about it recently and
again all my drives are coming from Best
Buy parenthetically it's almost Black
Friday and you'll see an 8 terabyte
drive go to 129 and a 10 turbo drive go
to 149 on Black Friday so I will see you
fine folks at black best non Black
Friday Best Buy and be like a lion
drives huh you'll see all the home lab
or show up cuz every else is gone for
the Xbox's in the PlayStation the TVs
and I'm over there like gathering these
up like me go looking for this precious
drives you know right growling at people
who just want to do a backup of their
family photos like no need them my more
okay let's talk software on the top be
Santa's rad there's a reason they charge
so much for it
for be my cue game to it thing to know
about visa and if you're gonna and this
is most this is mostly my
hyper-converged slide if you weren't on
hyper-converged at home which you can do
and I've done it you're three node
minimum four V San you have to have one
cash in one capacity minimum per disc
group you get no inline deduplication or
compression if you have any spinning
media in your disc group just something
to keep in mind and with a three nodes
you're stuck to raid one type formatting
so your your capacity gets cut in half
you really if you want to do these stand
for realsies you need to go for a node
or higher but that gets pricey yeah I
get it a little bit cheaper often you
can do storage spaces direct from
Microsoft as 2d you need to have the
intel on a limb or later processor
that's kind of your i7 920 if you
remember that era and it's compatible
Xeon and forward I'll support that you
need two SSDs and four hard drives
minimum but you only need two notes and
it actually works pretty well it's it's
performant I mean a home lab it's fun to
play with I set it up just for grins
because I want to try it out the last
bullet point if you wanna more do more
traditional instead of hyper-converged
ZFS on freenas and then you just I
scuzzy NFS whatever you need to to get
it out to your compute boost your ram
before doing your SSD cache can't stress
that enough 32 gigs on a on a ZFS pool
is a good thing is a good kind of good
rule of thumb it used to be like one gig
per one terabyte it but now it's just 32
gigs it generally enough i've got a
hundred and forty-four gigs in my free
nas box for two reasons one I literally
bought a cardboard box of RAM in a Sears
parking lot I don't know where it came
from but I ended up with nearly a
terabyte of ddr3 ECC memory so I took
everything I wanted hock the rest on
ebay funded more of my addiction that's
what I did so I've got a bunch run gels
in FreeNAS so my Plex is running in a
jail which is fun play one fun way to
learn about jails and all that good
stuff one thing don't install prinos on
a USB or an SD card your performance
will be abysmal when you do updates
it'll run fine once the things booted
but you're talking like a 30 minute
upgrade boot up window which is painful
and also panic-inducing
the last thing I'm gonna say here is do
not do hardware RAID with ZFS ever like
really don't that's a horrible idea you
need to have your drives go straight
into ZFS to command them otherwise you
have an abstracted the abstract upon
abstract and things get really dicey and
you will have a sad day let's talk
mounting options
has anyone heard of the lack rack yeah
19 inches across IKEA you geniuses so
you can rack things between this little
lack cute end table for $12.99
unfortunately in the last two years
they've made the top the top about that
much of it is solid wood and then they
do that hollow fiber board in the middle
so in my excitement to get everything
racked up my first two mounted upgrade
and the other thing I don't like about
them is you have to use wood screws
which is super ghetto and you can't like
move it ever but anyway so I put my two
switches up on top I go to put in one of
my servers drilled in and go in the fell
down I was like dang it so I was
actually gonna bring a lack and cut it
in half and show you that it was hollow
but it wouldn't be kind of awkward the
microphone what not but yeah you can do
them if you're only doing like a switch
or two on top you can't get away with
the lack rack um if you're chaff is
relatively low get some two by twos and
just screw some wrapped rails into them
works great in build your own four post
rack for dirt cheap
and you're off to the races other thing
folks do this is something that my good
friend Ukiah turned me on to with is a
portable LAN party in a box if you ever
seen that musicians rackmount cases they
put their amps and gear in these little
portable cases guess what they're 19
inches across and you put whatever you
want in them careful sometimes they're
not deep enough because a lot of the a
lot of that stuff isn't really built for
servers obviously so they'll you'll end
up hanging out the back you'll have
little flags hanging out back your thing
chaff is gonna be hard if you put a
musicians case in your front room put a
lamp on it maybe I don't know I'm sorry
I can't even relate to that I'm like hey
I just do whatever crazy stuff I want
keep in mind racking is great and it's a
tidy way to do it and a lot of stuff
comes in a rack mount may not be your
best option
really they can be efficient but they
can come in the sanity of noise
pollution
I'm gonna level with y'all right now
it's not like noise server fans aren't
white-nose I've heard that arguing story
times like well my servers loud it's
white noise no it's annoying and their
shrill it don't fool yourself tower
servers are generally quieter put them
on the bottom of your bread rack put
some networking on top keyboard mouse
can have your so a little tight a little
set a tiny little set up velcro no
spaghetti monsters you only saw my rack
how horribly spaghetti it was that's
okay do as I say not as I do now I read
somewhere somewhere that somewhere
something somewhere that all
presentations have a stat so hundred
percent of IT professionals should have
a home lab I made it up and Google said
I should have done that so here's some
resources to follow and contribute to
serve the homebuyers guide forums you'll
find some serious lab or there reddit
there's a great subreddit for home labs
you got people who've done all sorts of
crazy stuff with that you need some
benchmark white papers hop on YouTube
watch some videos this bottom one is a
is a QR code for the discord it's a
discord group for the Utah home lab
builders we just barely started that up
please feel free to join us contribute
learn you got quite a few guys that have
done some pretty crazy stuff in there so
feel free to come on in and ask some
questions and to finish up I wanted to
talk a little bit about what happens
when your boss green lights and sponsors
key word and I said a layup and you have
a spare cubicle you get that we have six
individual nodes there's the on D series
that's the embedded series eight cores
16 threads at 80 watts each 256 gig DDR
M each one duel 10 Giga sefie pluses
they're running Intel obtain 800 ps4
their cash tier in an m2 for net that's
4,600 SSDs one taped on fan we'll get on
to that in a little bit I've got new
biggity X 16 G switch you get 12 ports
of sfp+ 4 quarts of 100 ones 10
I got a Cisco 3750 that was literally
sitting under my desk and a lowly end of
warranty Dell if you can see it sitting
right there that's for when someone
breaks their vCenter and they have to
recover it it's klaris we call that the
Dell of shame just as far as a
performance which you'll get out of that
I ran the official VMware HCI
performance
monitor I got 76,000 iocked each side so
grand total 150 mm I ops out of some
cheap super micro sitting in a cubicle
pretty darn impressive I think and
you're talking to 30 grand online that's
for everything in there we also decided
to modify it slightly and do a VDI if
anyone heard about virtual desktops I
don't any of that and I had to put an
enterprise I had to put an enterprise
video card in it and you'll see those
are meant to be done with fav passive
cooling and just passed that through
since it was passively cooled I had to
put my own fans in it and I made the
cardboard duct master of 3000 right
there founders edition and yeah the card
gets pretty warm and you can own their
own the VDI lab for about an hour
parenthetically you mentioned I've
talked about the tape donphan when we
bought these super micro didn't have a
port or didn't have a part number for an
actively cooled device and so I had to
basically figure out my own I went
through for several iterations I 3d
printed a little box that went on it but
I meant melted the PLA and then my best
solution was actually 3m adhesive and I
took 120 millimeter fan and I just blew
it across this heat spreader but that
one exhausting out actually works great
I've never had a problem my boss hated
that idea he said I just spent $30,000
and you're taping on fans until I walked
out to his BMW and showed that his side
panels will held on with the same tape
and my yeah so it ends up working up
great like I said the whole point of
home lab is building it and having fun
and learning you don't have to go nuts
you don't have to have you know 150,000
I ops but get started get playing with
it and thank you so much for coming you
have any questions for me I think we
have like a few minutes just real quick
yeah good I'm gonna I'm gonna post it on
the scheduler dealio they all sign up
for it there's a way to like distribute
slides to class and then I'll type of
the saint's con folks if there's an
alternate that those didn't use that
yeah
um if I was just getting started
for the very first time it depends kind
of what your enterprise marks like if
you're like a VMware shop run ESX and
start writing some one little VMs you
can actually do the free version that
doesn't have V Center you know and that
as long as you want but honestly I'd do
FreeNAS trina's is awesome out of the
box you can consolidate your storage you
can run jails you can do plex you can do
pie holes all stuff like that free now
is a great spot I like it cool thank you
so much everyone
[Applause]