hello
I'm giving a presentation
[Music]
and it's actually about that you
can perform ehm cyberstalking or actually stalking
with eh wifi and very
detailed I'll
show you that later that's very relevant eh
tonight eh at 7:15 I think it's Chantal
and eh  we are Chantal van de zeekopter and
Dave Maasland of IZZ is in a
program eh on NPO 2 Eh and that is
also about cyberstalking what I show
is something that um actually everyone can
perform without too much technical
knowledge and with less than  €100 in eh
stuff that you can buy at the Media Markt
eh I work at Harry Potter I'm a
technical producer eh and I eh talk
to my colleagues about funny things
Ehm yes look it up can I talk let's see
yes I always do eh some
disclaimers  eh when I start him eh presentation
Aya to I'm Not Always Right I tell
you things as I know this moment
and may well be that things
have changed or that I missed them
or that I just learned things completely
wrong I think  it's fine
if you're going to improve it eh But
please do that afterwards
I know I'm not lawyer
Maybe I say things that really
shouldn't so always check
your law just a presentation is
sometimes eh in
English
People  In The City
in English
My apologies ehm
About Me A Little Bit have
something about wifi en that you can do
uh really details stalking with wi-fi
watch quite Un detectable for the victim
je about the claimers wel I'm Not
always right I  told you that uh I'm not
a lawyer ehm depending on where you are
in Which country Always check Your Love
what I'm going to percent
instructly not aloud by Law
but it's Almost Un detectable you don't
know that Somebody is doing This  so
don't do this what you can do is
pronounce and Gender
I'm Old you see my Gray Here I'm a bit
set in my way so I will say The Old
pronounce but please Hair The proper
pronounced apply to you I love  Everybody
Of You
is because The
Presentation actually about metadata
Meta dt's really Bit Of my game eh Meta
data is ehm is Something When I see A
Glass Broken on the floor ehm That's
effect dat he observe but I can
surmaise that The Glass has fallen would
not  see me Class Falling but I can The
Jewels 30 Class Hey Western Falling the
same Thing Goes with the small particles
the look at Sean The Dancing The
particles Them cells The Make large
collisions huge a Mount data en from
that huge Mount of data They the
jews  this particle must exist
and this is actually what you do with Meta
data and that is more Meta data around you
the actually Real Eyes
with this audience I don't think I need
to Delft Too Much in all of these
pictures but let Us
open
there  are they with those well what Pixie on
the bottom is
It is the wi-fi channels can
stay Chance en of course on the right
It's a bit How wifi Works too I know
That's changes in there but for the
Shake of the Playstation argument Just
Leap even that
This Is important because what I'm doing
What I'm going to show you is we going
to completely ignore
The Green the light green And The Yellow
layers
We Don't Care About That so We Don't
Care About doing  all the people with en
gription and Hide and all that stuff We
Don't Care We Just Look at the Mac and
Alice llc uh de Visible addressing
en de core of the Idea is if you have
Something wireless
it must transmith to base station
Lot of
transmissions going Around Us on Around
Us All The Time and you guys really need to
identify how expensive City in this
and everybody can re that recipient From
The Air
does the base station Now that it is for
the baystation or the Climate
so
wallow worth a sticking  gives
myself eh and meet It This one of my 100
euro challenges Every cup of Years I
Give my self-100 challenge and That's
These requirements need to be done
with really available components would
mostly going to the Media Markt should
been of
The software should  be mostly available
and require minimum of self Be king
and anybody Any Tex Sense should be
able to replicate this and Reason
Projects like this is because I want to
have a feeling of What People around me
like students
security Would you
be able to do what Attack Factor  landscape
I have in my home
so I came up
With The Course Raspberry Pi
or let Panda latte Panda I really like
we can
frosessor and Tenson form Factor
pandas for this project that Boat Enter
changable
sure
every The Little Bit because I have One
Line Around  This is one of these Big
battery packs ehm you can use that and a
Raspberry Pi and Leave The Raspberry Pi
Running for at least A Day and if you
have lots of wifi dongles It's Closer to
eh hvd
Alibaba
is because analog wi-fi Systems Nou  this
mode
but is he got to really cheap Once the
firmuis
There all able to go Inter promiscious
Mode promiscus Mode is necessary because
uh it able to see packets Which are not
for your heartwere address Girls Look at
all the wifi all the package to the air
and the sign
this
is If We use for instant kiz met
ehm wat je kan already CN Which wifi
dongles Which hardware is already
compatible with you goodbye I using Just
stock wifi dongles wat je produced Any
of this hardware
and You Can See It's really easy to  also
monitor Bluetooth zigbee or do Any of
the other sensors
so
it's just on the problems that you
have if you want to spam The Hall
Spectrum Because you have All This wi-fi
dongles Because you don't want to Any
Channel hoping
if you  want to monitor one channel that
you need to
lock yourself unto that Channel and you
cannot Skip to the extens on the next
Channel to Excel to get all the Flames
wouldn't you all the wifi dongles something
from Locked One specific frequency
And then Comes a big  problems The Give
You all the package that I receive
and this will be coming Nightmare
Because if you do is all over USB you
get The Lord Of traffic It's a lot of
package on Around It is moment
So This is wel die if you ever buildish
this  Will Be One Of The challenges that
you have not hardware multiple Agents
ehm The variance strategy is how you can
softis Problem but they you have you
will have a lot of Wars
and of course if you have a Remote agent
like Raspberry Pi You put The dongle  sentence
ehm je Put the battery on you want to
Dick it in Somewhere Close To some
Victims home ehm Univers And that data
back to yourself is wel zo en Just of
course In Your Way
GPS modem
process all of this data
en we want to get all  the Metal
and the code
vps
so for that we have couple of software
choices the things I Use Wear
Kiss with wireless
kismat is really nice because out of the
box it supports all of this hardware It
does all the Packard decoding en thus
Lord of in richment  As well she has eh
GPS on your Raspberry piar location It
can put that on the on the day as well
zo kistnet is really a good Choice For
Your Central processing system
from Kismet all of this package Because
you want to have a Time Serious Day
todays  are Get Back to Why We Are Want
To Have A Time Serious database
if you have a
societ but you don't have GPS coordinates
eh Wiggle is ehm database of eh lots of
eh wifi ssidies en de GPS gordons It's
really fun to look Your look  up your own
address on wiggle.net and see If You're
On WiFi is there an How many people are
to the Walking post That You Know How
many War Walkers wiglers I don't know
what the protect World How many Of Those
People you  have
client or An ssi Die is seems an
apex point or client you can see the
Activity and the incidents freekes you can
see the frequency ehm en dat is ons is
somada interesting for the hacker People
for the penetration test People The Red
Lines This Is site effect  of my project
I'm not using it but Whenever There is
in Kiss Me A Redline in means It has eh
intercepted handshake Packard
means you don't need to the out the
wi-fi force a Believe so it's not even
noticeable So if you  have kiss me just
Waiting round and some Point that will
be handshake package And then you can
start tracking The password
dan doe so you
can see about Anything Like That on the left you can see
if your raspberry pi with all this
source and i have budget  else Pacific
Place I always have in a plastic Bag
ehm and he has it specific locations
round and data source de counter Which
Frequencies met Just Would frequencis
you want to look
and basically you can Just say this data
sources Only disreference This data
sources Only that so  you can manage
interference en eh the Mount of package
you can capture
i it really nice logging command Line
login's well from all the things
[Music]
like somebody's trying to do a crack
Attack some access point eh someone ssi
die en dat maybe see spoofing en  this
is was just happening All Around my
house I was in the one doing it so
It's just things that you see if you
have all these dongles On And if All
This channels coming in
Let it Still Give me a picture of what´s
going on
Looking At All The Clients And The
Access Points And Gears Met Use Your
Ready Clear Idear Where We Going It Is
Good See The Middle One That's An Access
Point And Art He All The Associated
Kleins Is Ever Had
I Can See How Busy It Is What Wifi
Frequencies Day Use What Type of data de
use all those Kind of Things You can
also see that uh kiss me ads Defender
already from offenderday tobase but die
falls de backad dresses is wel En dit is
wel also Beer important part 4 daredevil
like Super Power Of  Blind scene later on
dus is actually Where The Real Friends
Stars at least for me
This Is database
on the left it all the devices Points
over Time
storing
but it's Just cumulative so I Didn't Do
Anything of the processing is it and the
Cool Thing  with Prometheus is that you
can if you have the pulling in the data
you can add some Formula estoid and pre
process it so you get images Like on the
right
on the right is
clients that Active and not Active je
kan die has your unificent eh die
does Kenneth have your own a definitions for
that and it's from Zero eh from Zero to
120 This is like I can see It is from
Zero to die off
and you can see from that access point
When People are Sleeping That's really
really Obvious
That's on  the left that low Line en je
kan even Sea eh One small device
beconing In The Middle Of The Nigel van
data And then When People Wake up you
can see Them realling the news then
doing other Stuff
you can see Active
grafana For The Night pictures I  did not
Manic to get Anything comparencible
if you want a person really Bridge The
Graphics you can really make Something
nice other and May The Small hotspot for
the for the Frequencies but
SO
en ik go back to What I can see is Let
me just go back  to the Prometheus
database Mitch
if you have All This Type of Meta data
you can see When The specific device
connects What the disconnect you can see
how much data itsens How many packassed
Sense
and That's basically All I am using
en What can I do that I  can de juice If
Somebody is at Home It Doesn't Matter if
the Hat There mimic presents setting on
under the Philips Hue lights because I
can see There home phone There phone is
not Connected to the access point
bedroom because all those repeaters A
Place The  Clean
I can see Which lights are a Switch On
and Hunting is if you use the meaning
presentside by Google orbee Philips
no zigbee switches will be activate So
you get no Sigmund Signal say Switch
Light On The Light Just Witches on
Because The bridgewalf Send it and  not
The Switch So you can even Sea If
Somebody really is at Home or If It's
All ultimated
I've also scene and This Is What I Had
ehm croperated with some Physical ehm op
het
Change In The relation en Ready
suspected that was students Living cross
Me and I so One phone Whenever that
phone was not Connected after While
Another phone Connected
en aftale net van Disconnected Back
en Ja I Could See that the Girls Are
House was Changing relation
If You neighbors Wake Up In The Night
was most of the people Special  If You on
iPhone is your face It will lower It's
beginning rate and if you just Look at
it in the middle the night than The
beating rate will go up you can see that
So if your burgler It's really cool
Because you can see if the Neighbors
are Waiting up and if they Calling The
Police so Those Things You can do
en dat was interesting case en Let's see
of you can
I'm VR Equipment so I know bit How that
works
and Point I Sauce and mariels also with
the same Mac address  from Oculus and there it
says eh viewhim
stuff@in evening Night
can see what Type of content It is I'm
not Looking Into the date about There's
not a lot of content that users like
forty megabits of data
forty magaz If you don't  know VR videos
I Twice resolution of normal video So
you use lot More bandwit
je was 14
magazon package
en een stop If so
not really bashult so I went over
anybody of you have and VR helmet
I want to talk to a private
your doing
What I  suspected en die eh actually
confirmed so you can see that
and this is a Thing that you can see
just why having length of data transfer
ehm de transferspeed de Mount of package
the frequency the Rhythm Because We are
people and People do uh There's a lot of
Things that you doing That are actually
Habits en Those Habits we can roborate
back to ar data specialy with device we
do so much with are devices I can eat
and see if Somebody at Home if the after
one of these smart doorbells
a Special If You Were  af after Ones
from Amazon really funny
of the camera Goes directly mobile phone
I There Gone the camera compressor The
image to lower bandwit
and I can see because it's Goes over
wifi does for some bloody Reason
Everybody even for things they have
Hanging there for like thirty  Years I
think Take This extra 50 minutes and
Wire
So This door Bells show you if Somebody
is really is that home Or Not So that I
can act like There homese are I'm
Upstairs eh put it over There's it
doesnetty you can see It Because  The
Band with over the wifi from the Smart
doorbell in Which you can see from the
Mac address is lot lower If Somebody is
not at Home That's A Good Time To Break
an Again
and you can alsossi ehm
If People are watching television
people have Everything even  The
television on wifi content U Can See
When A Switch Channel Because you get a
little Break That Little free Animal
because uh The television has the
grociate uh with the streaming provider
About The Stream And then The Stream
starts
ze kan se Lord of Things going on  with
People
en Martin
CM coming you can see the police Coming
because they have All This wi-fi
broadcasting
The presents
and I'm not saying This Is something
that really happened but Maybe in Zwolle
that was an Area Where People Where
parking For Free quite  for Twitter long
time
It is without Breaking Any of the
incryption Without doing Anything Else
but Just listening to What is already
going on Around Us
and this is why I do Give this
Presentation Again hotel because
Together with a Cyber ​​stalking I can
imagine
If I take  a lot of time and he starts
monitoring uh and mapping What Somebody
is doing like say I'm really fix say
that on Somebody
I think so in I can see if the visitors
I can see a mom visits
Family
Lovely for Cyber ​​stalker
interesting I can  see you there Alone
I can see when there Sleep and I can see
Lot of odytings
en he really at the moment This
Is actually Pretty and old project Of
Mine And logeers Nothing
# wifi 6 with Better And cryption even
some some eh
management package really  nice What It
Doesn't help Us I can Still Spy On
Everybody with under 100 Euros of
hardware
and this is the
accepted as the near reality and Just
librated
Orb we have to think about What can we
do with wifi
Another
radio eh missions How We  Can hydostings
I have not found really good
That's also implemental at Any of the
fenders cost the problems even Defenders
Figure Out Something now
in all Need replace clients We Are The
Ready can see if you just Look at Those
kismat logs that the Range from really
Old  crap Watches online to the new
devices It's so broad Everybody Keeps
Everything In competitiveness Mode Just A
Feel People can a forted by Everything
new het most Of It is a compatibility
mode Osso Because Of Your vacuum cleaner
Oil Fridge ore Whatever Else because It
Doesn't  get update It Still 2.4 [ __ ]
Heads eh old school WiFi
zo If You of Any ideas please contact me
else email address en Let's try to
figures Something Out or really have to
Just cam kluber This Is What's Going On
A privacy is already shot online zo  a
Physical World It's True this Well
that was basically My Presentation Sound
thank you
en die bobbins
zo
is wondering did you see a lot of
devices That We using a meg
randomization Which I think should be
the case for wooden phones for eksempel
in ehm het is  making Whatever could to
ehm eh
learn morning information about People
is it effective and practice [ __ ] More
devices to used The Mac randomization is
good in ehm that it Only identify
Defender so I can Still se It's an Apple
device
ehm en in Theory It shoot eh hide  that
uh he has not scene this device
Before but Again People are habitual
Creatures The Would Do things at the
same moment in the same frequency Saint
patter so even that the pattern he can
died as patent Again en het some
Point I can with quite some certain  tea
Okay this is device also has dismack
address I can LinkedIn back together
the Instagram
[Music]
outwards of my house
I think you will think you will be visit
that really quickly
Yes at the Dutch FC ehm and I had it
dinges of course Everybody  will visit
you en ask you thank you for protect
tell you thank you for protecting a
privacy
Have You tried shaping The Beam of your
antennis by the tuber Something
The Beam Kind of Works but That's Only
for More technical People en People
Willing to do this
realized  this realization really strong
that
99% of the people are there They Don't
Care About How This Works and and Why
this Works that Just Want to go to the
Media Markt by that stuff planket enter
Somer and have it work up and running in
Within  5 minutes cel ehm deed dan Really
Care About old are things The There's
Old so the people with plugging in older
repeaters even don't need it but Just
Need To switch a Channel because can
religion Channel is but it instead of
that Just putting More repeaters  South
Signal That's noise here and Letting The
wi-fi's Bad so eh shaping Would Be A
Good Idea and
it all but the most sensitive eh
receivers but Again Cyber ​​stalker would
have Those receivers eh must not weable
to find it but Again Most people One do
that
It's Nothing
The really correct answer is ride the
way
because when you start Kiss met
basically you ready listening and
tracking that you can track People but
if you just meet with Out And The Off
The GPS location stuff You just Looking
At what's going on in  my immediat Area
in If you don't historically log that
Thanks Okay but a soon as you start doing
historical data en attract People That's
totally eh not ok This Is white set dan
doen dit
ja
Ja is het
investigating on this
in the Mean Time we  had also had a
couple stories from That's A Major
venders of shops Big shopping mods Lot
of companies uses To The Wrong benefit
Isn't the real issue There I mean As
long as There is a lobby to use this
data for financial game by companies how
are we gonna defeatoes companies we need
more money to the moon Right or More
pressuation at least
part I know of that uh couple of Dutch
when you supiloties ehm have pin severi
referamanded by eh using exactly this
Type of technique but with More
professional Equipment to track  uh
citizens of was the city
ehm other eveng it Simply not aloud
but doing This Inside Your shop make it
Different Story
It can under AEG we have this sentence
legitimate interest Greetings the Most
horrible shut up because
maybe safe along miens Whenever
There's Reason for my business  to do
something i'm Kind of allowed to do this
and When I say eh I'm tracking all the
people in in my shop Simply Because How
I know how to put uh The Different Rex
On The Different Space then you already
Have This checkmark  en and you can do
this so
it's not nice bathing is if you have
Chain of of Stores en een lot of Stores
now and then these Industries are of a
Chang dat je een even see you Bel From
This Store to Dead Store so and we know
how long you took eh if it takes normal
Walking speech You Want Looking At other
shops you were really Looking forevers
This Is can This methodata Is extremely
powerful If You start qualiting though
ThingsSoya ehm persuation and namely the
standard Problem That We all Events in
security is Just How to bloody Hell The
we can Vince all those Average users
that oldies convenience features en
productivity features I not really the
best privacy features
en Moos of the time we Lose because
people Just Want To Have that
convenience
Challenge
or Unlimited Resources with your
projectas Martin to build to build me a
couple of receivers en
things like that uh and Ever really Big
database
[Music]
base ehm on Different Parts zal het even
eh Koppelov ML Engineers working on that
is wel dus de collecting of the data is
is Just  One Part And then Everything
That's A velable that shouldn't be too
Hard eh specialive Cities have There Own
wifi some Cities Paris eh City White
wi-fi eh available Those Access Points
can already read Everybody going around
the whole of Paris ehm It's What happens
after Works That's Why you but I Would
put some extra money in some extra eh
People Just monitor uh People
That's problems are doing yes [
Music]
Smart algorithm that says well In The
Night Time on your local
use probably Sleeping a special of your
on your  face lots of Rules like that so
ehm It's Not as tricked and Hardline as
Ashe would just have eh direct algorithm
but You Could See It Thinking A Little
Bit but I Made It a little bit bigger in
my timeshares Day To base ehm Justin B
because I  'm as a human interpreting
These signals She had me ehm Time gap
was 10 minutes Right Thing Something
like that uh second Question dat is
Channel Just Said what you did you Had A
Man in you said largesting things I
seebay You Wake for City kopter Does  It
Mean you have climbs Would Be
interesting to eat
I'm not at Liberty Style
you talk about it Being
Nearly in the table
Nearly
party is that if you really start
looking for you see some Idiot satelli
with like 30 USB wi-fi dungos coming
online because all the wifi dungos will
tell you I'm Here so The Destiny short
burst of Ridiculous amount of Activity
on all the channels en of course if you
eh start counter listening you can see
eh LG Paul mcadresses popping up and a
fuc a lot  of the same vender Med
probably Yes and that's all his promiscus
calls himself
you can die Technic but you really have to
already Look for it it's not
something that will pop up in in I drop
your ehm in je normal ehm yes detection
Systems or uh  wi-fi Attack or in Thing
like that because it's mostly passive
I'm I was working on on eh Looking eh If
I Could dus ebol de transmit on on the
wifi longles but all to feel the end to
small en zo Maybe That's A Point  I can
talk to my collection Figure Something
Out Which is not detectable at all
Challenge of course
Do you know
I don't know
a lot harder and I don't know if for
Jesus Is laid On The Same Models I'm
Looking At My  College 4 Look That's I
don't know
oh
that would as an answer Toy To You
and Neymar able to detective Signature
of a Fine When a better two Man and
Seconds Of
probably Yes is the answer
Anyways
sorry
[Music]
with you online
somebody's trying  crack Attack to One Of
The extra Points Somebody Strike to
spoof zo You can see a lot of wifi
attacks and even die Out attacks on All
Of Your Neighbors So You Good uh provide
eh Friendly Neighborhood dat spider-man
wat eh Hero and if you Figure  Out Which
excess Point we Long To Witch of your
neighbors you can tell 'em Somebody is
really trying to attack You Could do
Those Things
but then You First have to explain All
This to your neighbors and
I'm a good relationship
dit after the
first Round Of this project ehm at eh
desburdendag wat je least neighboursday
en in Dutch en
we Brother Coffee ehm en I prote My
slides and I presented to them and a
told Them What I Could See about oldam
ehm dit was het interesting  discussion
because s s things with security always
go People are still Why are you doing
This And I'm Keep telling because
Everybody Else could also and I'm Tell
You The you get most It That distanamic
uh with your name is after all the
understood it  I Promised I Would Never
Do It Again then afroposed eh The Thing
That Never happened with the parking car
and then we all we Friends Again
[Applause]