hello everyone welcome
my god there are a lot of you
everybody's still awake after the
accident Lynch they serve here
awesome
well
probably just napping everyone it's a
bit hard to see there because
this is slide one of
384 so we're going to need the hour
now I'm just messing with you they're
less than 30 slides
Network hacking 301
previous to 101 and 201 said basic
networking Network hacks encounter
measures for educational purposes only
that one remain the same this one is
Advanced networking networks hacks and
counter measures the pilot Remains the
Same is the for educational purposes
only
the previous presentation was fit for
both
Network owners or people responsible for
networking
to make sure that what could happen on a
certain
type of network what could happen What
should happen and how to defend against
the stuff that could happen that you
don't want to happen
this one has a slightly larger audience
and I'm going to get there in a while
but first a short recap
the network hacking 101 like I said the
basic networking
going to be go through the entire
presentation very brief there's a
scenario you go to the favorite coffee
house you connect to the wireless
network and browse to Facebook
what could possibly go wrong
we talked about Wi-Fi pineapples we
talked about DNS spoofing we talked
about our poisoning we talked about drug
DHCP servers
and then there were the character
measures
be careful Implement some basic security
measures on your network and verify the
status of your VPN and use a VPN if you
have one
it's a very very brief summary
then there's the network hacking 201
which is still basic networking
networking hex encounter measures
then we were talking about zeros we were
talking about heroes we were talking
about switches routers hack switch hack
routers and we even had a booty session
on screen
I'm not going to go into the the zeros
here they already had their own musical
here on the hacker Hotel
but I'm going to
leave them here to make sure that the
time frame of the presentation is a bit
known basically then everybody had a
real Brook in their slide deck in one
way or another so there's more or less
dates the
hacking networks 201 the people on the
right they're still bear naming the most
the lady over here is Radia Pullman
inventor of the spanning tree protocol
and one of the most important people in
inventing part of the land Network
protocol
the guy in the right is someone to be
proud of
he's from the Netherlands
inventor of the shortest path first
algorithm used in ospf
so we were talking about spelling twin
ospf and this one
how to hack them and a couple of
mitigating measures
for example have a property Design
Channel root guard and if you want to
add extra security into form
authentication
802.1x is a mitigating measure
then look at a possible alternatives for
spanning tree protocol the trill
shortest path bridging fee excellent and
the most important part is training make
sure that the people who are responsible
for managing the network have received
proper training so they know the
protocol they know the best practices
they know the equipment they know the
design
make sure they know what they're talking
about
then there's logging
and logging is only as useful as you if
you ever use it so not only lock
everything but read them that does not
mean you have to read through every
single line
automate or
make sure that you start looking at the
most important ones or the one that
occurs the most of the time and there's
another couple of security feature like
Port security and bpdu guard but
mitigating measures
design 802.1x
okay this worksheet will be hacking
802.1x
have I been lying to you why would I
recommend implementing it as an as a
security measure well I'm now going to
show you
how it can be broken
well a good security consists of many
layers that means if there's if a
security gets breached but it takes a
lot of time if you put enough of them in
your network you're probably safer than
your next door neighbors
as the previous scenarios we're going to
as the previous presentation we're going
to start with a nice scenario but from
the coffee shop we went to a small
Enterprise we're now going to
a bit more high visibility Enterprise
you're in a campus with decent
networking in place with a security team
regular audits the best practices even
pen testing is performed every now and
again
raising the bar here
what could possibly go wrong
as I said just before the target
audience for this particular
presentation is not more or less people
responsible for a network in which way
or another but we're also going to look
at different roles for example what
could hackers do what could pen testers
do and for all of you who don't know pen
testers are good guys but they're trying
the techniques of the bad guys so there
are bits bit bits of things you
may have to do but one of the things you
should not do is to make sure that you
amp up security specifically for pen
testers because you're only deceiving
yourself then
what could possibly go wrong let's start
with the basics
with a company like the scenario we have
here it's probably reasonable to assume
that a proper Network design is in place
it's not out of the box plugged in and
it works and then and don't touch it
probably also has a decent security
design
and given the scope and amount of work
and money that the company put in
there's probably also proper maintenance
and management
um if they hire Penta so they're
probably reasonable security conscious
company it might be a company with a
crunch use their data want to have it
heavily protected it might be a
financial it might be in healthcare
who knows
everything is applicable to all of those
companies
then there's the heart love hate
relationship between 802.1x and Pen
testers
another question that was asked multiple
times during the years where Penthouse
says can you please disable your network
access control your 802.1x so we can
stop wasting time trying to bypass it
and get to the meat of the situation oh
never mind we'll just use the printer
network cable and it doesn't usually
have 802.1x
these days it's on one end it's
easier to
negate the impact of 802.1x and on the
other hand it's
still an extra hurdle to bridge
don't worry we'll get back to the
printers
let's start with the basics the term has
been named a number of times what is it
it's an IEEE standard it has it was
started in 2001 for the first iteration
for Wyatt network security
2004 Wireless was added and there was a
later version in 2010
it defines e a p o l which is the
abbreviation for extensible
Authentication Protocol over LAN
and it uses radius on the back end
it's very very old
there is some dial up in the radius
abbreviation that's how old this
technology is
can be used in wired and wireless
networks and its authentication only
doesn't Implement any encryption any
additional security authentication only
for the accessing of the network
it can be expanded
but in essence 802.1x is authentication
only
in the basis it's a very simple protocol
it describes three roles
a supplicant an authenticator and an
authentication server don't worry this
is a lot of text I have pictures
a basic architecture looks like this
there are devices who want to access the
network whether it's a mobile device or
computer
or a printer or network camera or
whatever is going to connect to a
wireless a wireless access point or
wired access switch
when a client knocks on the door for the
switch a the cable gets connected and
Link comes up the switch doesn't allow
anything but one thing
completely unauthenticated it drops
every single packet that you send to it
except extensible Authentication
Protocol over Lan frames those are the
only ones that are allowed when the
switchboard is unauthenticated
there's no IP here yet it'll come
afterwards if you after you authenticate
the HTTP kicks in you get an IP address
you have an IP network at the very
beginning you don't have an IP
networking here so all of the other
stuff that was in the previous
presentations about our poisoning and DH
Rogue DHCP service it doesn't even work
because it's not allowed
if it's not EAP ol
it gets dropped as soon as it hits the
first Network device
the part behind here
is an IP network the policy server that
serves as an authentication server it
can be local it can be remote it can be
a 100 kilometers away there's an IP
network in between it'll probably work
and after that it the uh the credentials
supported supplied by the device get
checked against some sort of Truth and
database it might be local it might be
remote but the roles that are part of
the standard are supplicant
authenticator and authentication server
what should happen
is either the supplicant or the
Authenticator
starts the authentication process it can
be the supplicant says Hey I want to
authenticate what can be the switch this
says okay who are you
then there's some sort of negotiation
on the front end it's simple ethernet
frames
for EAP ol on the back end it's the same
EAP information
encapsulated in the radius protocol
encapsulating RP going towards the
authentication server
when the entire negotiation is done the
authentication Services yes
or no
and then
the answer is no the switchboard in case
of switchboard will remain
unauthenticated and nothing will go
through unless something else happens
if it's a success then you get full
access to the network then DHCP kicks in
etc etc etc
you can
enhance this as much as you want you can
say oh if you're that usually you're
going to put another VLAN or we're going
to implement some additional security
controls or you get some nice quality of
service because if you're on the board
of directors and that means your video
once that status that are
whichever those can be pushed towards
the authenticator the the switching in
most cases but it's not really part of
the 802.1x standard because it's about
authentication only
all additions whether it's posture
assessment make sure antivirus is up to
date is an add-on to that
this one's for him
this is
how short this negotiation on a packet
level actually looks like
it's done in no time it's very brief
it's usually just a couple of seconds
after that authentication is done and
our date is able to flow freely
this is going to be a very interesting
slide
because what I said before
has to be taken with a grain of salt AAP
extensive Authentication Protocol is not
really a protocol it's more like a
framework
it has a couple of standard it has to
meet you have to provide a number of
information you have to provide
something you have to adhere to certain
standards
but it's accessible if you want to roll
your own I think you can but there are
many many different flavors of extensive
Authentication Protocol most of them are
quite old like the md5 one
it's it's it can be hacked by a
dictionary attack it's really old it's
really vulnerable and the cracking Brute
Force cracking can be done in a feasible
time at that
the multiple flavors here I'm not going
through each and every one of them some
use certificates some don't it basically
means the more complex it is to set up
the more secure it should become if it
gets set up properly
and
exactly so it takes a bit more time and
effort to make sure that you pick the
right one and make sure it's secure but
it's only as good as the implementation
if you make mistakes during
implementation you might have a decent
EAP standard for your exit 821x
but you may still be vulnerable for
things like this and there are many of
them
there are a number of well-known
vulnerabilities in the protocol
because like I said in the front end
part it's not uh IP so the all The Usual
Suspects in IP hacking like are
poisoning and stuff like that is of no
use but it's still ethernet
one of the first six first successful
attacks were done hearing a hub
it's a very old technology it works on a
layer one of the ocean model
which means physical data and bits only
it literally deals with bits only
and it doesn't do the funny stuff like
oh that's Mac address it doesn't know
what a MAC address is
using a hub it's possible to make sure
that an authenticated device on a
certain switchboard would happen between
make sure the switch transitions from
authenticated
to active and everyone connected to the
hub
can then interact with the rest of the
network there are a bunch of downsides
but if you're it really depends on the
purpose of of the exercise of what
you're trying to do I have may be
sufficient
and it doesn't even matter which flavor
of the EP you're using
the important part is you're trying to
live with the Authentication Protocol
and make sure on with a proper device on
the same network port and it transitions
to proper State and it's done
um a couple of improvements can be made
for example if a switchboard sees
multiple Mac addresses it usually
authenticates a single Mac address and
not other Mac addresses that can pop pop
in through that port
in the very beginning of the
implementation that was not the case it
was simply a port is allowed on the
network reporters not allowed to the
network
logo of frames are in clear text
and they do not contain data matching
the initial Exchange
that means that if you're on the Hub
and your flood
log off frames it's a denial of shares
from the legitimate client
but there's another denial of service
attack for this situation possible
radius may be an old protocol but
depending on sizing and scaling if you
have 10 thousands of clients
your server can get heavy
if you're forwarding all sorts of
traffic to what your radio server is at
denial of service on the radio server
that means the radio server does not
have the opportunity to answer to
legitimate requests
and that means legitimate requests don't
get handled and the port stays
unauthenticated client's legitimate
clients cannot
a connected Network
and there's of course Max spoofing
it's also usable for help then you can
send some traffic
but not very much not very well
there was a target attack for the
well-in vulnerabilities it's called
Marvin it's a tool don't worry I'll be
crediting at the end of the presentation
it's written in Java and it it's a proof
of concept tool to make sure that you
can actually live on the same network in
between the supplicant and the
Authenticator
and Bridge the legitimate traffic to and
from and maybe have some sort of small
access
to the network based on that port
a well-known vulnerability already named
it it's very difficult to implement a
proper solution
it's also very expensive there are of
course free uh free radius servers but
when you have a Cisco IRIS a Rubik clear
pause just name them those are expensive
and have a head count so the larger your
network the more you're going to pay
and there's of course
the Everlasting curse of the 802.1x
implementation
Mac address bypass
not all devices have a supplicant
most dramatic are usually the printers
some cameras a pixie boot is something
that is not always possible using a2.1x
supplicant and this process automation
usually equipment that got put into
place 20 years ago and it has an
expected lifetime of 30 so it's going to
be here for a while
there's also a hidden trap in here
because nowadays some printers do have
an 82.1 supplicant
you ain't that's why the first slide I
said I'll never mind you would use the
printer port first
I see a lot of places that the printer
is in the same subnet as the client
it's not always practical but I see it a
lot
if you segment the printer off and put
it in a separate Network it's usually
much better and it is less of use for
for example a pen tester
on the other hand if you have an 82.1x
cable printer
you may actually allow it to join the
workflow and then it doesn't matter as
much that it gets
put into a separate Network or not
on the other hand
we also talked about Peep and Eep and
leap and other flavors
if the printer Department UV is usually
facility management and not part of RT
for some reason
gets told by it
has to support eight support 802.1x
then let's check a checkbox yes it
supports I have the spec sheet right
here
okay but which flavors of the extensible
authentication Protocols are supported
well you never ask me any of that it's
supported look it's a check in the box
and then you may have another situation
on your hand when printers can support
it but not at the level you want
I'm not going too much detail on this
one
because we're mainly talking about wired
attacks there's of course Wireless
attacks that's also possible
the one on the bottom left I mentioned
during previous ones the pineapple is a
rogue access point that has a number of
extremely useful tools the one of us
personally most impressed with was SSL
strip
that means you go to a page that has a
certificate an SSL on the back end still
has the encrypted site and it prints to
the browser the unencrypted site and
basically every username password or
whatever you sent over it is clear
texting can be locked interpreted
Whatever by the pineapple it's local the
version now I believe is looking much
nicer with more antennas and
probably more processing powers and more
throughput it's a very simple device
It's relatively cheap and it can perform
extremely well in less secure setups for
example with reset keys
the one on the top right well which I
don't know a single hacker wouldn't like
to get his hands on this one
it looks like watch it looks like a
smart watch and it can do wireless
de-authentication attacks you mainly
select
the network can say yes start now and
it's going to send DL frames kicking
each other off the network and the
cheapest
the for the uh the hacker on the budget
AliExpress this one is about 20 euros
it's nothing you might have to wait a
couple of weeks for it
when you have marvelous piece of
equipment
and
and Panthers usually you have the even
less conspicuous one because it looks
rather nice it still looks like a bit
weird
and there's the what you can use for a
wire detect then now it gets interesting
because form factors are a thing
if you need a bit more power and
throughput you can use an interlock it's
still reasonably small you can easily
stash it away and it probably has the um
the processing power to not increase
latency and it allows for a certain
throughput that it can actually be used
there are also things like Cloud compute
or even compute six but this size with a
couple of USB necks make sure you pick
the right one not every one of them
supports promiscuous mode
and don't forget the Callback
the texts that were done way back in
2005-2010
in those times cellular modems were
rather expensive
so it wasn't really not an option and
having a third network card where you're
going to stick it it probably was more
widely used to have a an AP there that's
transmitting its own signal to the
hacker in the parking lot
and allowing access to the bridge is
basically what it becomes now
into the system
and but it's also possible if you're
very careful
to have the Callback done in line
towards the authenticated switchboard
but the chances are you're going to
trigger some other attack
let's make things clear
this is a physical attack Factor only
well it depends
the hacker is supposed to be nearby and
the place of the hacker is between the
supplicant and Authenticator
so it can
basically not intercept the extensive
Authentication Protocol but allow that
one to go through so this Rich Board
gets actually authenticated and when
it's authenticated
the hacker is also going to make use of
that authenticated pause for every
nefarious thing he wants to do
or pen tester or whichever
you're going to run in a couple of
challenges then
switchboard security
if you go to mess around a bit and your
nox sent its own Mac address instead of
the client behind it Street Sports
security kicks in
if you have a security conscious company
it's a manual action
and it gets locked and alerted
and someone's going to look at it say
what's this then
and it'll cost you your neck
so sweet sport security is something you
take into account
ARP is also something to take into
account
because if additional measures are taken
and some sort of weird harping is
observed by whichever intuition
detection system intrusion prevention
system whichever
you might trigger on-site security again
depending on the level of security the
company has implemented
a good company can do a lot but it can't
do anything because budget will
Skyrocket very fast it's an exponential
growth
that's the thing of rooting
for example the client is supposed to be
operational or otherwise if it's not
going to
remain on the network port for very long
well that's not a really big problem
because if the port is authenticated and
the clients disconnect
the hacker device is still connected to
the switchboard as long as they are
linked the switch port
depending on the setup design
configuration Etc does not
re-authenticate that often
it might it might not but if you set it
to re-authenticate every five minutes or
so
if you have a large extensive Campus of
20 000 users it's going to generate a
lot of traffic and you're going to need
a very briefy radio server for that
so timers are usually set this less
strict
but it might kick in
then is the the Callback traffic if you
want to initiate traffic from the Rogue
device either towards the client or
towards the rest of the network you're
going to need an IP address
if things like Dynamic ARP inspection
are implemented you know the IP address
because it lives on the client and we
have to you want to use it from the
hacker device as well you have to do
some clever trickery
see I've forgot one of the most
interesting ones here this setup is
usually built upon a Linux Bridge
Linux Bridge has been around for a while
and it has changed quite a lot
at the very beginning Linux bridging
dropped EAP ol traffic
it was actually a kernel packed to make
it I think most more secure and more up
to the standard
but people who want to utilize this
let's call them pen testers for the sake
of they're the good guys they found out
and they found out they could roll back
a kernel patch which could add problems
later
or do some other trickery what they did
both
and I think part of the Linux bridging
now lives in a user space and it's much
easier to circumvent this shortcoming
and it's actually possible to relatively
easily allow EIP ol traffic to flow
through a wireless bridge instead of it
getting dropped which usually the
default
so a lot of smart people have done a lot
of smart things that's why I added a
credit slide at the end of this
presentation because without all of
their findings this would be a much
shorter talk
so one of the challenges is white gay
use a white use case
then there's the pen tester
if it's going towards the desk or for
example a secretary is going for lunch
and he's going to need an hour to set it
up
gets spotted and is quoted out of the
building
so usually it's drop and leave and don't
touch you usually don't have the time to
fully configure it sometimes you get
lucky
you you do some dumpster diving you find
a printout with the configuration
settings of the printer including Mac
addresses or pre-addressers Gateway Etc
it all depends
and there's automation one of the
experts who I will credit at the end of
the presentation did some Automation and
their Bridge started down in a down
state that means no traffic
then it gets brought up then it sniffs a
couple of packets
actually gets the information it needs
from the first packets then it
reconfigures its own network breaching
configuration with it restarts
and then uses those parameters so the
there's automation for the win
then there's the phoning home you can
for some reason allow some traffic in
towards you running SSH server you can
see where traffic out is or you can use
a salary or Wi-Fi modem on the back
it all has its ups and downs if you
don't have
close access to the device Wi-Fi is
probably out
the phone home inline or a dial back is
usually a bit problematic because a
callback in from outside to inside it's
rather rare to see inbound traffic
allowed towards workstations
and for good reason usually some
internal hosts are allowed to
communicate with workstations for
example there's the management platform
for mostly Windows environment
those are usually allowed but from
outside from internet forget it
and phone home traffic does it that is
initiated by the hacker device it also
runs into a chance to get seen by
firewall oh they think it's a commander
control traffic they think it might be a
bot they think it's passing through web
proxy it gets hosted to uh
um a machine generated DNS name there
are all sorts of reason that it might
attract attention
so it really depends on what is the
purpose of the probe do you want it to
sniff traffic do you want to try and
initiate an SSL traffic do you want to
breach the host and make sure that
there's an entry point there
and there's also many many ways to
prevent against any of this
but it's going to get expensive
in a nutshell
all of these types of traffic depend on
passing through Erp oil traffic through
the Linux bridge between the actual
client
and the switchboard
what's another easy way when this setup
doesn't work well the workstation stays
empty for the day there's a whole day
without a switchboard getting
authenticated
you do need a legitimate client
it's not the end of the slide but first
the credits I mentioned
there's a couple of people who did some
talks at Defcon that were a major
inspiration to this talk if you want to
know more in depth about it I should
just just take a picture of the slide go
find them the the movies are on YouTube
there's something between 45 minutes and
60 and one and a half hours or something
and they really go in depth into the uh
the matter also have here some
demonstrations some more successful than
others it's one of the other reasons I
usually don't demo because the demo
girls hate me
there's a Gabriel Solstice Ryan who did
an excellent presentation on a decent
tool Alpha duck will wrote one of the
best functioning
probes is actually working as a pen test
and it developed his own tool including
the automation I mentioned
is creator of Fenris sorry fenwir one of
the most recent
802.1 X tooling I'll go step aside and
see a couple of people using a camera
there's a d-stike an ESP Enthusiast who
is responsible for uh making the basis
of that awesome watch you saw
paftrinos did a wonderful
presentation on 802.1x how to secure it
and how to uh what's what's what to
watch for uh to uh to spot breaking and
easily to hack stuff and that's Mark
Simon he was the only name I found
for the IEEE with relations to the
creation of 802.1x there might be more
but I wasn't able to found them within
five minutes and then I got bored
okay a lot of people especially
management don't want to see this one
it's a couple of harsh truth
it will cost a lot
it'll cost even more if you're up
against a state actor
most of the people here in the room said
if you're working for the Dutch
government
you're going to fit in the first
category
there's budget constraints
and chances are you will be up against a
state actor are a bit higher than for
the average Enterprise
keep in mind will happen
mattress authentication bypass is a
famous One Like I said it supports 802.1
X but doesn't support the right a22
phonics implementation
cameras are also an attack point because
they usually
are an afterthought and they're usually
not even part of the facility management
procurement process they usually part
of the security process
and most security companies especially
when it's concerning physical security
they don't know anything about
networking except hey this is network
camera I need Network
and whether we're not it gets plugged in
I just need outside Internet it's
managed from the cloud
I have stories to tell you never mind
this
um in short they usually depend on an
extremely high amount of ports going to
outside usually to Cloud instances you
can't even limit the amount of
destination IP addresses because it's
the cloud
you blink an eye DNS get re-rooted and
it needs to go to Northern IP address
having a better lock than your neighbors
does help
for a while
if you're up to speed you have decent
Security in place you're on a large a
Terrain with lots of facilities lots of
buildings you limit your Wi-Fi from uh
not going too far outside of the
building
you don't have that many crown jewels
that are digital for example they're
physical and a lot tight
it's also a thing that may help
postpone you getting hacked for a while
at a certain point of time you're if
you're not keeping up you become the the
Target that people will do need to do
the least amount of effort for to get
the best results
and this also doesn't help
for the preparation it helps afterwards
prepare to be hacked just make sure that
you know what to do if you get hacked
sure it's a bit unpredictable but you
can't think of it beforehand you can
have playbooks
someone got the main admin
someone reads their Wi-Fi someone took
off with a server
all of those things you can think of
them beforehand
you can write playbooks you can review
the playbox every once in a while you
can dream up more playbooks you can
deviate from playbooks it says this
looks very much like Playbook 5 but with
a small twist fine we'll grab the
Playbook we're going to adapt as we go
but we do have a solid basis
there are fortunately some mitigating
measures
one of them is Design Network
segmentation for example the printer
port I mentioned if all your printers
are on a separate network with only
allowing access from the printer spooler
to the printer you're in good shape
of course it doesn't work that way
because there's some process automation
who needs an app direct appear just for
the printer in order to print the daily
reports so you need and where is it
located oh is it located in that subnet
so it's usually get
brought up a bit
then that's the training and user
security awareness
if users know
that there shouldn't be a knock under
their desk
and if people are told it could be a
tech if you see something odd report it
as soon as you can don't wait till after
lunch lunch can wait
user awareness especially this being a
mostly physical attack
the reason I set an asterisk there was
Wi-Fi there's also a Wi-Fi point of view
and with good antenna you can be a long
time off
still
be somewhat vulnerable to this attack
in essence is still a physical attack
you can't attack someone from 100
kilometers away
but you probably can't pull it off 100
meters away
this is um
training security awareness it's a very
important one especially facility
management and other people who purchase
equipment that gets plugged into the
network
all right it gets completely segmented
off without any exception for example
the printer situation or the IP camera
situation or whatever situation
or is it going to adhere to the
standards that were startup implemented
regularly reviewed updated and tested
and then you can get usually can get
away with the property implementation
and there it is again logging and
reading them you don't need to see every
time a switchboard goes up and down but
the switch Port security kicks in or a
probe or your ethernet monitoring or
your network management solution or your
its or IDs or IPS kicks in
you may want to look at it
and you may want to look at it faster it
doesn't mean every company should have
their own socket their own Security
operation Center but they feel important
enough it might not hurt
then there's multiple security tabs and
layered security
if you have a building that everyone can
walk into and you have a door for
example like this one
with a large gap
I can see some room for improvements
make sure the security is layered on
every level make sure not everyone can
enter the building or gets close to the
network equipment gets close to users
because this is an attack that can
perfectly be done without even seeing
the switch you just need need to go
somewhere that's between users and
switch and whether that's a cable tree
or a wiring closet or a satellite
equipment room
if you're in between then you have
something to that you can pull off
physical security is remarkably
important for physically based attacks
and then there's of course the layered
security if you have 802.1x mate it
doesn't substitute all the other things
of security you can do that's the port
security there's Access Control list
there's fire warning this IDs tires IPS
it usually is a combination of all these
things that make a network more secure
then there's tunneling
it's also I want to point back to the
very first one design
I see it don't buy a lot of companies
these days they say all our clients are
interested
we're going still going to isolate them
from each other
where they get internet access or they
get allowed
to initiate an SSL VPN with multi-factor
Authentication
so we're not even going to bother with
802.1x and the only thing it's allowed
to do is initiate an SSL VPN
and then there's nothing going to and
from the wired or Wireless networking
that you can learn anything about
because it's usually encrypted
especially when coupled with proper
certificate management
it might be easy to set up a SSL vbn
concentrator
than to implement a full-blown 802.1x
implementation it all depends
then there's of course
the behavioral indication of compromise
which can run as an antivirus or
whatever product on your workstation on
your server
and it says why is this client
performing a port scan why is it trying
to start some application I don't want
it to to start
it can be as simple as starting a
process that's known on a workstation
behavioral indication of compromise why
is that engineer trying to contact the
finance server
all of these
can be done on multiple places in the
network
it's usually more the more place you
want to implement the more expensive and
complex it's going to be
it's a major part of your total security
posture those ideas IPS maybe even a
sock and there's of course just throw
enough money against it and it'll
probably limit the chances you get
breached but not everyone is I.T at this
core business so there's nothing wrong
with getting outside help
just make sure you have your
requirements in order you know what you
want you make sure that all the relevant
people are part of the process
and you make sure you go with a
Dependable organization and you can
easily go for outside support for
management security operations center
and similar the ways to make sure that
your network and security posture gets
improved without doing every single one
yourself including hiring the people who
want to do that
now for the most intriguing question of
them all are there any questions
sure
between protecting the perimeter in the
last list with mitigations are going
to processes
exploration
okay sure
um
you initially talked about network
access control which is protecting the
premises and the gate around the
internal Network
and the list of mitigating measures were
more about internal segmentation process
that one yeah tooling Etc
but do you see a trend into more
Management on the endpoint like for
example centrally managing and also
actively the Windows File on endpoints
not only for inbound connections but
also outbound connections so you can do
like a bit of micro segmentation
centrally managed on the endpoint
oh I hear two things here one is is a
proper endpoint security which includes
one or another flavor of
agent usually and whether or not it's an
antivirus agent or doing more there are
products that's got I'm not going to to
make this into a commercial or sales
pitch but our products that do both
antivirus and do some behavioral
analysis and they block process pure on
it because that you shouldn't do that
and then it really blocks it that's one
you should implement it but depending on
a scope budget Etc I'm not really at
place to uh to advise anything and micro
segmentation can be done but it's
usually uh called for as a Data Center
Technology but with a few simple things
here you know what to do you can for
example use a VLAN Access Control list
in combination with some Access Control
list and with the field and extra
control is you make sure that traffic
with any Vlog between clients is not
allowed and certain clients only get
access to a certain other
networks and the combination of those
two are relatively lightweight if you
design them properly there's also scale
and without even using Data Center a
great equipment you can still Implement
micro segmentation at the client level
it really depends it should be a
combination of both a user age user
desktop protection and endpoint
protection and a network
protection for example the segmentation
and you couldn't put it back as small as
micro segmentation
so the client says only allowed to talk
with the Gateway on an Ethernet level
and only attack allowed to talk to
certain servers associated with the
function usually if you answer function
derived
uh at the data center and not anything
out of that in fact you can even say for
Envy if it tries anything else raise an
alert by simply logging anything that it
wants to do that's outside of the scope
of the design
thanks
any more questions
are you still awake
just a few seconds please
thanks
maybe an odd one but we shouldn't forget
our
list at least thought but most
used networks our home networks what can
we do
well aside from me and a few colleagues
we don't have 82.1x implemented
um what you can do
the the bad thing news I have the best
you can do is also training so make sure
you know what to buy you know how to use
it and when you you usually have don't
have many millions in Digital Data uh
located at your home at least I hope not
but the solution should fit the purpose
and for a home network the the the bar
usually isn't as high as for the
scenario company I placed at the
beginning of this presentation but open
wi-fi is usually a bad idea preset K is
probably best used uh it's a small
things I mean we're all hackers here so
if you have a sign in your hallway
that's readable from outside with your
Wi-Fi password is probably not a good
idea
but if you can have it as far as best as
and at the inside of your front door to
make sure it's not visible from the
outside but it's still easily available
for people putting down the jackets oh
that's the Wi-Fi password
another good one of course is not to
make it too difficult but also not make
it too easy so no reuse no make it
welcome
um
maybe change it a couple of times a year
what's the worst that could happen that
people need to ask for the Wi-Fi
password when they visit you again
It's usually the small stuff that
prevents the big hassle this is also a
specifically aimed at accessing a
network
and usually
except when you're doing a long party
most of the access on the um
on the home network is done by Wi-Fi and
quite a few Solutions now also support
guest networks that allow for internet
access but no access to your local NASA
or whatever
so make sure what you're doing think
about it do a bit of research and then
just implement the best traffic and of
course what everybody keeps telling here
especially from an iot point of view
keep the stuff updated
it's sometimes it's as simple as simple
as it
you're welcome any more questions
no
then he would like you to thank you for
everyone for attending here I didn't
really expect such a massive turnup
thank you for that and enjoy the rest
foreign foreign