[Music]
okay welcome
Martin
[Music]
actually Started With A
hagaton that Webber invited to do uh to
test dus security of bodycams en eh
ben die Started Out We Are split into
two teams One Team eh was put on the
hardware part of the bodycam  and I was
prett with a View people on the software
part eh The firsting refund Out was that
uh The Management Software that was used
for the bodygames force brittanan.net eh
The nice Thing about.net is that It's a
manage language
it's very easy to  for example de
compilots eh except in certifications
for example When Dave eh used Office
station
die Compilation Technics eh Another
problem with the software was that
required the License to Run and we
didn't have license
the next per on was that uh basically We
Could See  that uh Olde
functionality That We Need it to
communicate with uh
uh de bodycam was Ashley Presence eh in
een Shepherd dll that game with the
application so The eh second Call became
eh Being able to Load eh Parts of the
original managements software s eh
Library in  Our Own software And then
Talk eh en communicate with eh and his
fairy you were communicating with Any
regular other library eh however eh to
do this it uh it exley required a lot of
Manual work As you can see Here Ja The
resolution is on that Great  but first he have
to Load eh the Target would de
software that you actually want to eh eh
eggs extracts circumf functionality from
They you need to re Visual of the type And
then Turn The type into an object And
ben je kent talk to the objects but
Every single object that is in
implements in the original version Jesse
inplemen Manual Lee Line by Line in your
own couch
this Without writing a single of
coat en eh
with Ferry Little
Knowledge of eh How dot net eh works in
turtally eh zo is Blaze and other View
stir party libraries the first Wines
Zero Harmony ultracord Cold Harmony 2
Which is the main eh hooking library
that reals  take your was Mona mod Which is
Another hooking library Which is part of
Harmony 2 then we use monal sessial eh
native Sharp Newton soft Jason mqtt eh
net en costume of foodie so Little Bit
of background eh Harmony eh is actually
Hey patching framework for eh dat  net
applications That I Love You To The
definer Patcher The Very high level Way
eh zo voor example This Is A patch
you can see Forever Every single patch
that you need to do you need to Right a
Class whiten initializer and you need to
ride a Hole  by the foot eh zo The Other
goal becamed to eh
Create a Wizard that Woods generates
this basically All
eh zo
was Shower later eh moder 6 Cell eh is
de library That We used to actually
parts.net sm-lys en eh
there we Turn It  All in 2018
you woul get a list of all the name
Spaces That are defined we Dender
application All The Clock closers That
are defined Under the name namespaces Eh
en all the Mathers de constructors en al
de properties en you can actually
Interactive Every single function Here
and you can manipulate imperts you can
manipulate out perch You can Locked
input Locked output you can basically
deal Whatever you eh want Again Without
writing a single of code
eh Mother
library That We use but it's Only On The
Windows version
eh is native Sharp en We  used that to eh
to inject Our hooking library into
another.net process And then
interactives
not Newton Jason is basically Justice
genre purpose Jason eh library eh All
The Rules en de hoeksted we generace eh
are all eh combient into a single Jason
file en de Jason  file actually tells The
engine What to do in the end so eh You
don't have Any fixed eh code for
functionality Within The engine but you
can extend The engine Just by Sending
One shop eh
Jason
That's eh
protocol that is also used for iot
devices and
large Kill infrastruktion Management en
we Us this as a client as we loser
Broker
eh Den last is costume aphoudi but uh
dit asui apost Builds uh tools so eh
all the Shepherd libraries That We Just
disgust  will be merched after build into
a single libraries zo it's easy to
inject into Another process of the Wise
you
would need to in Jack multiple eh
files Allard want zo eh All combined eh
[Music]
he check.net is actually eh eh
mostly eh Sweet  Different
componentie After High jack.net Wizard
dat je Can Use To eh to start the new
project en Ad binary stewars en analyz
de binary starthoeks
eh en Dennis de core loader eh Witch
will be used to inject Into the process
that you want to in interactrits  en is
Will get Fats eh All The Rules and the
angle you defined with in The
Wizard eh denders the nation loader
Which is Only available on Windows en is
actually a Stepping Stone eh when i made it
easier to inject e.net binary into
Another  process
zo eh lessi out of process works
zo bij basically the first step when you
start The Wizard is Just click file
start a new project editargus
Denderleeuw to binary
and it will Look Something like this so
I took The NS Core library as ANAC
example than As  you can see
It will be Shower In A review with the
sm-ly name of top On Top them all the de
names of the mowgels contains with Indy
eh Simply as well is a list of all the
name Spaces en de classes defined Within
that namespaces  eh as wellness The
method's eh basicly Everything that is
eh in the binary en that you can interact
with
zo is
Select One Of The methage to the
to the
configuration en
Sony
Select for example Witch perimeters of
the function you want to Loch eh if you
want  to lock for example The Return
value eh if you want to modify the
reader value so in this case It's A guid
uh So you will actually get a witch
editor impert that you can use uh
to inputer New One
Eh who me this easier to Load you  can
also Right click and selecte file with
the content dat je one two eh
Loud enter there [
Music]
also
lochers for specific type zo in discase
It's uh for example RC
permerters dat is eh dit is a value
used in the RC in imponentation of.  net
self for example if you want you Fox
into Those libraries You Could eh
yousee to eh log
oranipulate someone's eh are you say
Keys for exempel eh but eh the niiste
things remain the type Lover is is that
it all so Works On structures And you
can  actually Select Witch Field of the
structure You Want To Look So if it is
not all interesting you can Just Pick
The Parts that you are interested in
eh Benders Old so custom type loggers if
you want to do really Crazy stuff with
eh with the stuff that  Comes in It's but
basically atten plating engine eh that
supports eh full interest caesarp eh all
the Coated You Right Here will also be
edit to the eh hooking configuration is
Will Be Saint to the process uh that is
Running The eh The angulation engine adds
eh Dead  Ferry moment en het wil compe
All Discount On The Fly en also appliet
in your workflow
nou
Once your finished creating one of these
angle sits relaxedly be eh turned into a
holebrunch of Jason en eh dish will be
compressed en base
sexy Four en codeton Danger can  feed it
to the engine engine will um package
apply all the hooks eh en dennisbal
start login or Whatever You eh
defined For The Rules To Be Doing
eh Benders also Another Way of
starting project with the targeting
Helper and the targeting Helper 2
options for eksempel you  can file
So you can Select a dot net winery in
then It will automatically extract
divisional The Run Time de Architecture
that is eh en de.net eh framework
version dat Unity use
uh and you can do anything off it
processor could you if we do  with
eh Running processor for example
A few Different ways of injecting your
binary Into the Target you can do Side
loading
configuration file That You put in the
Target directory and It will
automatically Load your ll sound is
start the application than you can applier
oaks
Another Way  of doing This actually
patching It Into the Target then It will
actually modern Target winery to first
Load your binary apply oldehooksen Them
continue to the original entry Point of
the bindar and the other tray two are
used for live process eh would you
actually injected into  something that is
already Running And then apply oldehooks
so Well what
would be busy I already didn't happen
is you have your High jack.net Wizard
used to create Rules older
Jason en push Todd Broker
eh The Broker has abrimes of clients in
the form  of eh Oil engine eh that you
have injected interior targets en they
will First get the configuration to use
from the Center Broker appliet en them
all the eh stuff that is dit is going to
log will be lockback to the mqtt brother
en nou de nice Thing  about mtg is dat is
very easy to Interface So you can also
Rides eh custom tooling for example 2
collect uh logs eh naar zijn hal-bandjes
of API calls you can
eh Sense to the dotnet loader you can
make it Stop Start you can for eksempel
attach a console to the process dat je
have injected in Which is easy if your
debugging for example Because you can
Out that all your
tracer sum to Dead
eh you can actually make it uh unhook
everything you just angle you can Clear
all the hooks you can  Load auditional
hooks or new hooks and
everything is underfly would you do it This
World The processor Running eh thenders
Old so Un Option To Safe the corner is
currently Active with in the
process So It will extract all the Hook
Turn Them Back Into eh Jason  and
[Music]
and the burden of is Execute code and that
yes yes
the burden of is Execute code in it eh
actually allows you to Just injector
that you have Just code yourself an It
will be executed Within The contracts eh
of the Target process and  then you can
basically talk to everything
you
connectionally Overload and make Them uh
reply With The Different value
eh zo dit dit voor custom tooling wat
sensites eh mqtt eh you
can eating Go More notes So you can
actually Connected to your homesystems
and then Again with Google or Alexa And
then you can actually  gift voice
commands to Whatever You have Running
There would that Could Be A root kit or
Whatever You fight
Of The ideas to
actually make the complete Wizard and F1
base So you can do everything that I
just show you but then For Your browser
Another Thing this Will Be Nice to be
able to create Who Can rule packages eh
a bit lik eh with eh Yara  that you
connectionally export and eh Share Bed in
the Community for example eh thenders as
the text beast editorser you can actually
eh Ride all the Jason for the Hoeks in
the Rules yourself If You Hate van eh And
there want our Bear native code API So
you can  also Use the engine I just show
you against native applications
support itself for example is There's
Another Architecture That We Don't
support that you can actually Right a
plug-in For That
zo Thank you That's It
and a questions
you
don't know the  Set an apple
[Music]
dat net is everything that happens in
memories
table
your basically just have to replace One
value And then you have an Active Hook
virus scanners think of this
to
measure execution Time
profiling eh you connectly used to build
shims for example 2  eh eh gif certain
applications backwards compatibility uh
you can beasts die even everything
you can do with dot net you can also do
with this but uh you can do everything
with your Mouse So you did you don't
have write Any coach yourself
zo ehm  Keep this Shoe get from project
with cameras uh to this
so That's that could Explain it a bit
so
we don't know yet
Riverdale interest
en
not to
powershell because Power
use this to
create song kit of firewall that uh will
actually capture all those  nice Little
One liners That will normally starte
Shell but Saints you can control
Everything that Comes In An out you
Crawl replace The eh the back door Shell
dat is in Calling with for example Give
of Rick Ashley
Secure
environments of the talking about the
world and we  have binaries
in memory
problems to protector application
It's Possible
You Need A Girl Driver
detect that someone this trying to open
a Handle to your process you can
actually lower The privileges would je
could Still allow it to for eksempel
reach your process but you could eh take
away for eksempel the right uh Flag
well Fun facts Mona mod and Harmony and
Zero Harmony wear originally develops
for game model
of Unity games
If yes
[Applause]