Nico dakins
thank you
thank everybody uh it's an honor for me
to finally be here I wanted to be here
for years but somehow my agenda didn't
allow it so I'm very happy to be here so
thanks for having me
um so I'll just start off with a little
bit telling about uh to talk to you
about who I am um so I'm an ocean
specialist I was trained by the Dutch
government so I was officially I was
trained as an intelligence analyst for
operational Technical and strategical
analysts and I think around
let's say halfway to 90s I discovered
that hey the internet might stay here so
let's start exploring that and at that
time I was doing analysis on youth ganks
in the Netherlands and I was I was like
hey maybe those guys and girls are
active on the internet and that's those
street cops know a little bit about the
criminals that they're dealing with but
maybe by looking at an online footprint
we can find let's say a different view
of what they are doing and what how what
connects them so that that's something
that triggered me and luckily I had a
team leader that basically said hey Nico
here you have card launch uh here you
have uh money for a laptop and start
exploring this there were no rules there
then so it was literally kindergarten
for me I could do whatever I wanted to
do so uh after that
um I well after that it's really brief
after 25 years I basically uh said hey I
want to do more and the Dutch government
said well we know you want to do more
but we can't allow you to do more more
so this is where basically our we had a
divorce a little divorce I still am in
close contact with a lot of the people
that I work with but then I moved to
bellingcat bellingcat an online
investigative journalist Collective that
do let's say all kinds of awesome
research when it comes to war crimes and
all that kind of stuff for example the
mh-17 Downing they did some awesome work
in there but that marriage again was not
good enough for me because I was in the
government and I was trained to have
very strict operation security and
within Bellingham that at that moment in
time well was different let's put it
like that so we were fished my daughter
was fished and and my parents and my
grandmother I was like well this is
looking at what they do trying to find
Russian hackers and Russian State
Nationals well I like to brief and I
would like to continue to do that so we
had to go away I was in contact with
some other people and I became a science
instructor so I built courses for
Science and Science Institute the United
States company and now currently I run
my own little shop called Dutch ocean
guy and I recently moved over to shadow
dragon a company basically that built
some scalable tools for open source
intelligence but enough about me at
least now you know a little bit who I am
but feel free to ask me more questions
I'll be here the entire weekend so uh
don't be afraid I won't buy it at least
I promise I won't buy it a little bit
about open source intelligence and for
those who have never heard about open
source intelligence open source
intelligence is
collecting and processing but more
importantly analyzing information that
is coming from open sources that
addresses an intelligence requirement so
it always starts with a question that
someone wants to have an answer or
multiple answers to and based upon that
you start looking on let's say the
internet but not only the internet could
also be traditional newspapers or TV or
a library and open source intelligence
does not limit itself to let's say the
service internet the Deep Web the dark
web but also resources that you may need
to pay a little bit of money for so an
open source for me and we can have a
large debate about it but it will not do
that now an open source must be a source
that is accessible for anyone around the
world depending of course a little bit
on their budget sometimes but it should
be a source that
your neighbor should also be able to
find as long as they have the proper
skill set and the proper hardware and
software to do that
so that inspired me and I've been doing
this for well almost 30 years now
already yes I'm that old and you can see
by this little uh Google graph that
there is a a little Trend when it comes
to open source intelligence so the blue
line is open source intelligence and
open source intelligence has risen and
it has to do with a lot of Wars a lot of
um other things where people started to
see opportunities with exploring the
internet to mostly for accountability
kind of research where you want to find
something maybe in hacker group maybe
again a criminal group maybe something
related to war and you can use those
sources to tell a story in essence so
it's a used growth Market but everything
starts always for me with the General
open source intelligence or let's say
the traditional intelligence cycle I
cannot do any research without a
question so without questions I will
never have answers for you so it always
starts with planning and Direction so I
talked to a client I talk to someone and
I asked him what do you want me to find
out and on average table tells Nico I
want everything
yeah but what's everything yeah
everything you can find on the internet
yeah so okay give me a couple of
petabytes of data storage and I will
collect everything and you can short it
out yourself
but that's not how it works so you need
to take mostly clients by the hand and
deliberately ask them hey
if there's one thing that you want to
have an answer to what do what would
that be well for example did Nico visit
hacker hotel in 2023 that's a question
that I can work with so with that you
basically start building your tools you
start scoping what's in limitations
what's out of the limitations how to
secure my computers for operation
security is pretty important because I
have something to hide for a net from an
adversary and then we start collecting
the data and collecting the data means
that we will look in numerous places to
see pieces of the puzzle and those
pieces of the Apostle very often come in
sub-optimal for formatting so we need to
process and exploit the data then we
analyze it and most of the times we take
a step back because when we analyze the
information we will see that we have
gaps in our information so we go back to
the scoping and so on it's an endless
loop until we have satisfied our needs
so very brief but mostly when I look at
my research and I really love off this
quote by Einstein because it says hey if
I had an only one hour to solve a
problem I would like to use the first 55
minutes to start thinking about that
problem properly thinking about that
problem preferably with a group of
people that are not always necessarily
open Church intelligence specialist
because I like to listen to different
angles different perspectives and with
that potentially then I could solve that
puzzle within the five minutes because
now we have a good attack plan we know
where to look but more importantly we
know where not to look and that's I
think the biggest challenge within open
source intelligence because there are
too many too many rabbit holes to go
into
now when we when we look at the history
when we look at where well this was
before I was born but open source
intelligence has its roots
um probably around World War II so I did
a lot of research seeing looking at when
people starting started to talk about
open source intelligence the actual word
so we noticed that mostly during World
War World War One people started
gathering information from newspapers
from radio from libraries from other
broadcasts or singles interceptions that
they could do and that was the first
start of Open Source intelligence this
is how it started it was a lot of manual
work a lot of manual processing of data
and that became more and more
challenging
um of course the early 90s when the
internet started to begin and started to
become a little bit more let's say
mainstream open source and Jones became
more standard became more adopted and
but also it was still mostly done by
governments within the intelligence
Community not necessarily by let's say
people like you and me that do normal
day jobs and just like to spend time to
puzzle puzzle all the time because
that's what I do the entire day so when
I look at the past 25 years we look at
the 911 Tax we we look at the Arabic
spring that was around
2009 where we saw that people used
phones and internet connectivity to
spread the word to show that there was
something going on in the world and with
that we can now help certain groups
accountable for certain wrongdoings so
with that it gained way more momentum
and we could see that the rise of social
media became wider and wider it became a
global adopted phenomena where people
wanted to use their devices to
communicate with other people all around
the world so that gave me eyes and ears
everywhere that's basically how I look
at the internet because if I want to
find someone a criminal so recently I
was looking into some Russian spies that
were caught in Sweden so there was
nothing more than a news article on the
Swedish news I was like hey I can see a
villa that they're lifting I can
geolocate that and then I could
geolocate it I found the location and
then I could point maybe some
geolocation tools on it that showed me
that there were telegram users active
in those coordinates of those building
so with that I found user accounts those
user accounts had usernames those
usernames were unique and with that I
could find new people that we didn't
know about we found businesses we found
so much more that was originally in that
news article and with that you now know
where those spice were active for at
least 12 years in in and around Sweden
who they were with who they did business
with because all those businesses are in
open sources all their traces on social
media even though they used aliases
still are traces which I can use they
leave behind so much valuable nuggets
that I can use but we see that the
landscape is Shifting this is in the
time where there was little to no
encryption there was people were not
that aware of people that they were
looking at them
um could be me could be a nation state
could be a law enforcement agency but
things are now changing so when we look
at slowly where we are going
when we look at the past it will always
matter to me because a criminal or a
hacker was not born as a criminal or a
hacker that was doing let's say wrong
negative things because that's mostly
what I do I try to trace down let's say
the back people or at least I think I
strongly believe that those are bad
people
but when we look at that
they order pizzas so bad guys order
pizzas too so we can find information
about that so we can find their human
footprint we can find their company
footprint before they were operational
security aware so with that I could map
out maybe their Network their friends
their connectivity the devices that they
used and with that I can learn more and
more about those targets to specifically
pivot into that intelligence requirement
now when we look at the present and this
is kind of mimicking my younger's
daughter they are so sensitive for shiny
new apps and they never read the terms
of services but most of those terms of
services will clear state will clay will
clearly state
what you are sharing what kind of
information is out there and that
information very often I can find in
open sources or open databases and with
that you find again a human footprint
maybe company information before Labor
operation should secure little small
little funny Side Story since I'm still
talking about my daughter my oldest
daughter she's now 15 she's in high
school she just texted me 10 minutes ago
that we need to talk I think I hacked
the school system and I can change my
grade I'm like oh and I'm I'm definitely
not a hacker there are a lot of people
in here that that are way way better and
I'm like well stop
email your Mentor tell them what you did
give yourself a 10. so the highest grade
in Dutch and we to our Monday morning we
will go to school and I will help you
out here we need to do some responsible
disclosure here because something might
be misconfigured but just for me that
also shows that
when you look at this she used some
techniques that I taught her because
well I've built courses and I've been
like hey here are the course books go
explore and she was like oh I could do
some URL manipulation to find something
and with that she probably discovered
some but I'll need to find out a little
bit more details because maybe I need to
confiscate her PlayStation just to make
a statement No hacking
um
so when it comes to open source
intelligence the present for me when you
look at some numbers that I that I've
that I've basically looked up
um
this is my biggest problem now the
population in the world is around 8
billion people we have more than 5
billion uh unique mobile users all
around the world we have 5 billion
internet users and we have
um almost four and a half or just over
four and a half billion active social
media users which means if I need to
find that one little nugget when someone
is saying hey I am planning a bombing
because I did a lot of counter terrorism
work I'm part of a terrorism cell how do
you find that one person that makes that
statement somewhere online on one
particular maybe hidden platform how do
I find that that's my biggest challenge
now in the presence where do I even
start to look and if I know where to
look how can I hide myself in such a way
that those people are not immediately
alarmed so that's one of the biggest
challenges so when I look at that
concept the present is also for me
looking at best top devices versus
remote versus mobile because mobile
devices give at least for most open
source intelligence partitions A new
challenge it's way harder to step up
your operation Security on a mobile
device because there's a lot of more
Telemetry going on GPS chips building
that cannot always be turned off by
default so that means something for my
investigations wearables also a new
challenge the emit all kind of singles
they connect to all kind of stuff it
gives us chances but also challenges for
me to find information but with that I
can now also use the power of the crowd
and that's something that for example
the the group that I was part of
bellingcat uses they use people all
around the world armchair internet
investigators what what Elliot Higgins
calls it to basically spend time and
help out in certain investigations but
that also brings a risk because do you
know if you can trust the people that
are in that crowd that are helping you
so there are a lot of challenges I can
also see that
when you look at the early stage of the
internet it was mainly text based that
is for me way more easy to look into for
example when we compare two pictures or
videos
so with videos it brings new challenges
because one minute of the video that can
happen an awful lot in the video that I
now need to find and geolocate yesterday
there was a um a Nazi group that was
streaming a laser kind of uh thing on
the Anne Frank house in Amsterdam so I
I'm under cover in that telegram group
where they are and
there is no coincidence but I was
reached out by a Dutch journalist
earlier today and he was like hey I
found that video and they stopped at a
gas station that's a very specific gas
station Nico can you help me geolocate
it and there's no coincidence I was
filling up my tank before driving here
and I was at that gas station so he
literally I was like how do you know
where I am man how so I took a picture
of this location yes that's the location
we found it but also if I would not had
that luck I could have found that
location in under five minutes because
it was a Shell gas station it was
clearly a Starbucks visible in the
reflection of the mirror there are only
nine Shell stations in Netherlands that
have Starbucks and with that it's just
well basically excluding the ones that
do not match up one-on-one with the
picture and you can find that location
so funny story
um
things that I need to deal with that I
will
also show you some examples of in just a
moment is for example artificial
manipulation so deep fakes or filters
that we have on Snapchat those are
becoming a real challenge so everything
that stylegan or Dolly orientated will
form a bigger challenge for people
trying to tackle for example this
information and there's a lot of this
information going on and fake news going
on digital Warfare where we see a lot of
groups all around the world attacking
infrastructure and that kind of stuff
again every move that they make they
leave behind traces and those traces
could be in open source it's definitely
not always but it's least something that
I can work with maybe we have a red team
or another team that can feed me certain
pieces of information that I can use and
do my let's say skill set upon to find
maybe a little bit more
but I think the biggest challenge now is
for me that I used to be able to do
everything manually but I need to start
automating more stuff because there's
simply too much information out there
for me to deal with
so when we look at that I need to make
use of hackathons so hackathons where
well just like an event like this where
you get a group of like-minded people
you throw them a challenge and you say
hey let's solve this puzzle we need to
find the people who are responsible for
the Downing of the mh-17 here is video
footage here's some other footage now
let's find some stuff so Community
Driven research is really helping in
that and with that you also have Global
availability 24 7 365 because well I
like to sleep every now and then but
someone at the other side of the pond
can continue my work but also they can
maybe deal with a different language or
different different character sets that
I cannot deal with so that brings a
little bit of power back to what I need
now just showing you one little example
on uh the power of working as a
collective on an open source
intelligence case I'm going to show you
a case study from uh my time at
ballingcat where there was an execution
by a rebel group a rebel leader called
Mr Oliver Folly and this was the first
case where open source intelligence
information led to the conviction with
in the international crime court so what
happened here there was a rebel leader
who had a bunch of captives and they
were brutally executed at a given
location that footage was found and
basically handed over to bellingcat and
basically for accountability we wanted
to prove a point and say we want to
prove who we're involved where but more
importantly when exactly because we
needed to find evidence so let me show
you the video and I will slowly walk you
through that
so what we used is a bunch of let's say
leads and pivot Points so here you see
him basically reading his sentence to
the people who are going to get murdered
we will not show the horrific stuff but
based upon that we could extract Stills
so we could extract little screenshots
together that we piece together in a
panorama because we wanted to have a
good overview of that situation so if
you grab those Stills and you stitch
them all together you basically get a
broader perspective and you use that as
little pieces of the Apostle to
geolocate that specific location so
there are things that you can see you
can see for example
um a fork in the road or you can see
some specific buildings we can see that
there are so is a wall there are some
bushes and there's a fork in the road
all these things added up create a
unique fingerprint of that location now
we knew that it was somewhere in
Benghazi but that's a really broad
province that is let's say 500 500
kilometers in square so that means that
we need to find that so we've tried to
look for similar looking building
buildings to narrow down that rough
location
so we found a rough location but we
still needed to validate where exactly
did this incident happen so with a team
of 10 people 10 hours a day at least we
started basically Scavenging Google Maps
meter by meter so we created little
grits and we gave every team member a
task look at this part look at this part
look at this part take notes if you can
find it Well in the end one of the team
members said I think I found the
location and then everybody got excited
again after hours and hours of looking
and we then we need to validate we need
to be sure so we find those buildings we
see the wall we have the fork in the
road but if we zoom in a little bit more
we need to find a little bit more
because we also want to know exactly
when so if we find that camera position
that we found in the original footage we
can line that up with what we see on
Google Earth so we can actually do an
overlay and we we can see those bushes
and we can see all kinds of details that
match one-on-one with the location from
the footage
it gets even more interesting because
when we looked at the satellite imagery
we could even see the blood stains in
the ground
from the execution
so with that the international crime
Court had some people going over there
on the ground and take ground samples to
make sure if there was actually blood
and yes the blood was there so with that
we were let's say confident enough that
this must have been the location now the
next task was when when exactly did this
happen when was the most likely time
when this event happened and the Sun is
basically the oldest clock that we have
so with some Shadow casts and some
calculations and a specific tool called
Sun calc which again is nothing more
than a free website online we could
calculate when this happened so we line
it up so we determine the time and if
you line it up we could say that this
event happened roughly around 17 July
around 6 47 UTC now if we do that we
could also see based upon satellite
imagery when the blood stains were not
there and when they were not there so
with that we could say well we find a
time time frame where we say it's
confident that this time frame this
happened so I think this is a a perfect
example on if you have a group that's
persistent enough that has enough a lot
of tenacity and a laptop and an internet
connection and you can solve these cases
there were no pay tools involved here
there was no specialized software
involved here it's basically critical
thinking and a lot of time where you
need to solve the puzzle so this I think
is one of the best stories that I could
tell that shows the power of Open Source
intelligence when it comes to
um yeah holding people accountable for
their wrongdoings
now when we look at the present I need
automation I cannot do that heavy
lifting myself anymore I'm getting older
I'm getting sick and tired of doing
everything automatically so we need
certain tools and certain capabilities
that can scale up what we do because
when we look at the evening clock riots
during the pandemic we haven't Rotterdam
in the Netherlands we had some very
pretty disturbing evening clock riots so
you could only imagine that for example
Law Enforcement wants to analyze that
footage to make sure that the right
wrongdoers are being caught but if you
now need to analyze let's say four or
five hours of footage it means that you
will spend months analyzing that footage
but luckily there are techniques out
there artificial intelligence and
machine learning that you could
basically generate an overlay over that
footage that will help you speed up your
analysis process and it's a little
spoiler for tomorrow because there's a
little workshop that I'm giving that
will walk you through how you could
scale that up now here's a little
example of that what I will show you
tomorrow so there are some tools out
there from which you can use an API for
example the Google Cloud Vision API that
will allow you for free to analyze
footage at scale and it will show you
when persons appear in a frame when
certain brands run certain logos it will
translate text in real time in any
language it will show you a foul
language it will show you all kinds of
interesting pieces of information and
you can only imagine if you need to do
this all by hand you would spend hours
and hours if not weeks finding that
information and this simply speeds up my
process now I can spend more time
looking at hey I'm looking for that red
car show me in these three hours worth
of footage where this red car appears
instead of going frame by frame through
that footage
now when we look at the present
criminals are begin becoming more and
more aware of what we are doing here I
have an example of a telegram group
where a bunch of far right-wing Nazis
are telling other right-wing Nazis how
they could give me a hard time so
they're basically telling many
organizations nowadays have open source
intelligence analyst in place and what
they are basically saying here is is
that if they flood you with enough this
information or fake news they can keep
me occupied for months and I see this
happening and particularly since chat
GTP I hate to say it TTP but it's
everywhere I see a super increase in
this information that is heavily being
abused to spread let's say a false
Narrative of any subject matter now I'm
hoping of course I'm seeing some
companies that are building chat GTP
detection software that that will help
me in the near future because it's a
it's a con and rat race when it comes to
these Technologies
now another thing that I need to deal
with is deep fake or manipulated videos
so here we see a small boy walking
against a fence in a rig and there's a
waterfall what oh I'm hoping he won't
fall down because that will be let's say
his last day of breathing
and this looks super real
but this can be done on a smartphone a
cheap smartphone you simply download an
app you add a little bit of a green
screen and you can manipulate this to
look like something else and it's super
hard to show if this is manipulated
you will need more sophisticated
software that could do maybe counting of
pixel levels and depth to to show you
that there may be something wrong with
this footage so that's these are the
challenges that I need to deal with now
and you can only imagine that this is
just starting this deep fake technology
10 years from now we won't be able to
tell what's wrong or what's not wrong or
what's manipulated or not
I'm hoping that we will still be capable
but I anticipate that that will become
increasingly challenging now another
thing making a deep fake super easy you
download the smartphone app again I
think some of you are familiar with
Snapchat or Instagram filters and you
can make someone appear to be someone
else I use this also myself because I
need fake accounts fake personas online
to move around because well you can only
imagine if you're trying to trace down
FSB or Gru agents that you don't want to
do that on your own name so you need to
create a false persona so with that we
can use these techniques but I also
perform they perform a big challenge for
me to to at least try and prove if Mandy
is actually Mandy or not
so we need to deal with this
president
so here we have
solenski well and this is a really
crappy deep fake because we can see that
his body is not moving
um it's only his hat moving the blinking
is really awesome when you look at the
eyeshadow those are still those little
Tails but what if I told you that this
video went viral in 15 minutes and
reached 17 million people in Five in 15
minutes and there were actually a couple
of thousand people in Ukraine who laid
down their arms because he's basically
calling to the Ukrainian people say hey
lay down your arms surrender and people
he actually did that based upon this
with a video that certain groups made to
go viral on numerous social media
platforms
so with that it's not only for me always
trying to prove hey there's a deep fake
but also sometimes I need to stop videos
from spreading as soon as possible
because things can go sideways really
fast
just showing you that it doesn't have to
be Advanced now with stylegan
um you can make basically make anything
here I'm asking to to generate a bald
guy with a hoodie and glasses I was
trying to get let's say a false persona
for myself
I use these faces because social media
accounts need a profile picture and I'm
not going to use your picture because
first of all that would may get you into
into trouble and also gdpr that could be
a little bit sketchy so I use these as
well myself
but it also again poses a challenge for
open source intelligence investigators
how do I know that the profile that I'm
viewing is actually a person or is it
being puppeteered by someone
now when you look at this concept you
can also flip this a little bit around
you can also use this again to spread
this information so I started to explore
this a little bit and the next example
I'm basically asking this style Gan
daily kind of Technologies hey hey show
me a picture of a war aftermath show me
satellite imagery of a warm aftermath
and again it creates this out of thin
air based upon a computer algorithm but
we get now
satellite imagery that looks awfully
real
that I could spread on social media
saying hey the ukrainians or the
Russians did a lot did a bombing again
and people like me may spend hours and
hours investigating a satellite image
that has never existed and will never
exist
but again people use this I see this
happening more and more particularly in
the last half year this technology is
heavily being abused within certain
groups to spread this information and
fake news so again it's wonderful
technology but it will definitely be
abused for wrongdoings
now when we look at this scalability I
need to graph out certain pieces of
information so a graph is nothing more
than a data structure that contains
entities so entities could be all of you
and nodes so we have a connection so in
this case I could be the speaker and the
connection that we have is to do our
listeners and we now are connected
together in a graph in a picture so for
network analysis I need to do this
because I want to map out certain
connections and see who knows who who
has certain access to certain data or
whatever it really depends on what I
want to find out
so with that you can use a lot of tools
that will help you connect the dots and
this is where I'm getting it in the
present and in the future we need to
scale up so in the good old days when we
had hives I could do this manually I
could find someone's profile maybe that
hacker that was doing kind of let's say
illegal stuff that need to need to be
mapped out or I could find let's say
that cocaine cartel criminal or maybe
some other criminals I could do that
manually but now if people having so
much connections on numerous social
media platforms it's nearly impossible
for me to do this manually so you need
scalable tools that are capable of
automatically collecting data at scale
from open sources so the data is already
out there but these tools make it
possible for me to collect the data and
spend more time on the actual analysis
to answer that intelligence requirement
so when we look at that
um one of these things that helped me is
that there was an anonymous tip that um
someone said through
um missed that underneath shall calling
crime anonymously
um hey we have a link to a streaming
video account kind of like twitch where
someone is making a statement that he is
planning a school shooting in the
Netherlands now there were a lot of
smart investigators looking at this but
they got stuck on the dead ends in the
end it was all about persistence or at
least that that's my humble opinion so
they reached out to me and said hey Nico
can you help you know a little bit about
open source intelligence can you help us
find the guy who was claiming to plan a
school shooting so I'm saying well send
me the information that you have and
they sent me the link through the
streaming Channel and on that streaming
Channel there was a guy what we call in
our world a typical incel so someone who
never leaves his room I think there are
some in cells here like myself I also
tend not to like my my little hacking
room but this guy was almost I think
it's safe to say almost 14 hours per day
live streaming sometimes he was just
sitting behind his computer doing
nothing you could just see him sit there
sitting
but in one of those videos he made a
statement that he was planning a school
shooting so I needed to go over all that
footage and see if I could find the
information at that moment I was not
aware of the techniques that I will
discussed tomorrow in the workshop so
this was manual work so I watched I
think almost 24 hours worth of video
units until I found a statement that
confirmed yes he literally sat on Mike
on camera I'm planning a school shooting
somewhere close to where I live that was
there was a little statement just to
give you an impression impression of
what I had to look at
shake it
this is moving footage by the way
you just need to be more careful
yeah
especially in regards to like
drinking outside I need to keep it
low-key for a while
you get the idea this was hours and
hours of footage and here is basically
saying hey I need to stay low-key I need
to stay under the radar I think people
are on to me
um
so I looked at the footage I found
evidence yes he made that statement but
still I did not know who he was we
wanted to know where he could be found
because well I think if someone's
claiming to plan a school shooting you
may want to at least knock on that door
and say hey is everything okay with you
should we should we talk or something
so I watched all that footage over and
over again and interestingly I found
some at least some proof that this was a
guy that was most likely in the
Netherlands or spent time in the
Netherlands so I found a Dutch bank
account pass so a debit card so that at
least could say well this might be a guy
that lives in the nails I'm still not
sure and I found a location of a Albert
Hein in Amsterdam so this is literally
if you have this picture and you reverse
images that picture it will tell you
immediately Google will tell you hey
this is the albertine in Amsterdam so
with that I found again a little bit
more confirmation that made me a little
bit more confident yes this guy is most
likely in or around the Netherlands and
he had maybe living there but still not
enough
so I watched the footage the footage and
in the blink of an eye this guy hovered
over his account in his Google browser
and with that it exposed two email
addresses and I was like yes finally I
don't do not need to watch this guy
anymore so with that
I found two usernames and two email
addresses and I will tell you if you
give me an email address or a username
the likelihood of me finding something
about you is pretty high so with that I
use some in this case some automated
Tools in multigo to pop in that email
address and say hey can you show me what
social media accounts are used to set up
this account and it told me hey I found
numerous with that I was capable of
founding finding a Facebook page that
gave me his official first and last name
also confirmation on where he lived and
where he went to school and with that I
had let's say enough information to hand
over to the authorities and say well
maybe you want to knock on this guy's
door and with that I think it's safe to
say that we might have prevented a
school shooting somewhere in the
Netherlands so I think that again shows
a great example of how powerful open
source intelligence in certain cases can
be and of course that we need
persistence tenacity but also tools that
will will scale up and speed up my
overall investigations and Analysis
because if I needed to graph this out
manually I would probably need again a
couple of days and we were on the time
constraint because what if he picked up
that firearm now and went out shooting
so there was Timeless of the essence
now things that I need to deal with
is nft so nfts are being used by
terrorist groups in this case the
Islamic State use nfts to spread let's
say the propaganda and why do they use
it well it's sensor resistant so you put
up your prep propaganda and there's no
Authority in the world that could take
down that content and with that it gives
them extra power to spread their message
and spread all the horrific things that
they want to do
so I can still find it but again for
your 40s to take this down this will be
a big Challenge and I need to learn and
hopefully talk to people like you that
are way smarter when it comes to
cryptography and that kind of stuff to
tell me hey maybe Nico if you look here
or do that that could help people and
other investigators all around the world
to prevent let's say terrorist groups to
become active and do all kinds of
horrific stuff
now when we look at the future uh well
the future is for me impossible to to to
see but I can give you my perspective on
what I anticipate upon when it comes to
my profession open source intelligence
what should we be aware of well the
metaverse is coming so Virtual Worlds
that mean something for investigators
all around the world I it also gave me a
good excuse to tell someone hey I need
to order those Facebook goggles because
I need to also give give an excuse to
again
get a company credit card out or
something
but what if you need to show your
government ID to get access to the
metaverse how could criminals use that
and have used it I could how could now I
search there anonymously so there are
challenges web 3.0 is becoming more and
more decentralized so more
blockchainized it means that traces will
be transparent but who basically made
those traces will be pretty hard for me
to pinpoint to say Hey you are the
person who's responsible for posting
this information online because
everything is decentralized and also
encrypted pretty happily
artificial intelligence and machine
learning is also blurring my sight just
like chat GTP is doing I do not always
immediately know if this is you behind
the keyword or some kind of algorithm
but also keep in mind when we look at
for example what Google does is they
will tailor your results based upon your
searching Behavior particularly if you
are logged in into your accounts so that
means that they will Custom Tailor your
search results but if I get back custom
tailored search results it means that I
could miss information that could be
very valuable for my investigation so I
need to figure out ways to blur out my
digital fingerprint by rotating maybe IP
addresses by set setting up ad blockers
but ad blockers by themselves will track
you so there are multiple ways that I
need to deal with to tackle the future
to get unfiltered information and that
is a huge challenge to get unfiltered
information in unfail to church results
because every search engine out there so
Google Bing Yandex the big ones they
will all give you custom tailored
results based upon your device
fingerprint and your overall Behavior
online and that again is a big challenge
we've seen more and more devices being
connected to the internet I've recently
ordered a new dishwasher and the guy who
installed it in my home he's like can I
get the Wi-Fi password I'm like why and
he's like yeah it's for your dishwasher
I'm like why does my dishwater need
Wi-Fi well you can turn it on and off
remotely why I'm not that lazy but it
means that again we have now a device
connected that could be vulnerable that
could be exploited but also could be
maybe used by me to fine maybe again
someone's email address or someone's
username because we have a user account
now for a dishwasher and at least behind
traces that could be used to find
something
so do never forget that those are things
that we need to deal with one thing that
I think will give me an advantage is
that we can communicate as humans so
virtual human intelligence
interpersonal interaction is really
valuable for me when it comes to finding
let's say stolen data sets or breach
data I sometimes want to communicate
with those people and say Hey where's
this coming from what's Happening what's
your interest why are you actually
sharing this date of reach so we need
that in essence the biggest issue that I
have is that I need to deal with data at
a very large scale and I need my
traditional trade craft techniques but I
also need to learn how to scale up what
I do and I will tell you beforehand that
most open source utilities investigators
are not programmers they are not
Developers for example I teach a course
and the most demanded feature that
people want to teach me is learning how
to program in Python because that can
speed up and automate certain stuff but
if you never touched a terminal on your
computer or a shell that's a challenge
to teach people how to program something
so those are things that we need to deal
with or maybe the open source
intelligence world needs to team up way
more with developers I like to sit down
with developers and just explain them
hey this is my problem you know how to
code I know some fundamental principles
of coding but can you help me out can
you give me a different angle or
perspective can you maybe whip up some
code to show a proof of concept those
kind of things that's what we need
now when we look at web 3.0
um we are becoming more and more
um
entangled in the augmented world where
the mix between reality Universal
reality becomes Blended and with that
um again I think it will become
increasingly more challenging for us to
stay Anonymous in what we do but also it
become will become way more challenging
for me to find criminals online
um now the other thing is when we look
at the near future I also think that all
the things that are now giving me
trouble can help me
um become better and more efficient in
what I do so when I talk about goal and
scoping talking to my client I can use
those machine learning lessons learned
and integrate them into new cases so I
can use those algorithms to help me make
find early warnings or get other things
it can help me automatically gather data
that is within the scope of my
investigation I can get
um automatic monitoring or alerting for
certain keywords or certain things so
think again if someone is planning a
terrorist attack and they may be using
certain words or keywords I want to
monitor for those keywords to get that
early warning on also processing of data
large scale I can use now object
recognition facial recognition natural
long language processing to again scale
up my processes and efforts and with
that the analysis the pattern matching
and the trend detection of visualization
will help me be more efficient in what I
need to do I simply will have more time
to do the factual analysis the int part
within open source intelligence so with
that I think all these techniques that
are forming hurdles within my
investigation will in the near future
also be capable to help me
now when we look at the near future web
free.0 challenge for open source
intelligence uh decentralized stuff will
become increasing challenging the
semantic web smarter web so computers
that will
think for themselves
um will become a problem blockchain
technology
um great technology but not always good
for finding something or someone
and of course evolved Ai and machine
learning will perform and maybe even
bigger challenge but we're already in
this state because when we look at this
we are already living in an Internet
connected world where every device seems
to have a connection to the internet
just like my dishwasher cameras
Bluetooth everywhere so with that it
gives me also those eyes and ears
there's a lot of opportunity now going
back a little bit about open source
intelligence and virtual human
intelligence I think that the human
intelligence World which is basically
tradition traditional spy trade craft
mostly where they talk to someone in
exchange for information or they are
willing to share some information well
we can move that to the digital world
and we can use that to maybe get access
to open sources that we do not know
about because we can literally talk to
people so virtual humans is nothing more
than virtual human intelligence and its
intelligence derived and information
from Human sources that we can talk to
and this is particularly useful or at
least where I move use it mostly for for
breached and leaked data the people who
offer that or the hacker groups that are
involved with that for example I'm now
currently heavily involved in trying to
trace down the people behind kilnet now
some of you may be looking at it from a
different perspective maybe a more cyber
threat intelligence perspective but I'm
going to look at the human aspect
because in in the end it's people
operating puppeteering what they are
doing so I want to find those guys and
girls who are responsible for those
killnet maybe ddosing of a hospital or
something but I want to want to position
myself covertly in maybe their telegram
channels and learn what they are
planning and with that I could enforce
someone else or where they are talking
about that they want to have a certain
box yes five minutes I'm uh I'm almost
there
um so why is this important well the
internet is here it will not go away uh
there is simply more and more cyber
crime all around the world and these
online numbers will keep climbing and um
your sources are online so if you need
to do good if you want to fight the bad
guys and girls all around the world we
need to do some traditional work
combined with human intelligence now to
wrap this up slowly
um what is important we need to educate
people all around the world we need to
have tenacity and we need to have Nur
time and I asked for neurotime in all
the companies that I work for it stands
for never ending research and
development so I need time to explore
new stuff I need time to learn about a
new app and a tool how I could leverage
that within my investigation I need time
what a new M1 processor on a MacBook
means for my investigation because it
screws up your virtualization and I
heavily rely on virtualization so these
are all little hurdles that I need to
take I need to build personas longer
term shock puppets that I need the
position I need your help industry
experts from a different perspective so
I need those Partnerships and you also
need open source and gelatin Specialists
to perform what you need to do
so uh distant future web foreign
basically bigger data we have more
digital alter egos but I think a great
example is and this is kind of tying it
into a jet jet TDP is doing Google had
Lambda and the guy one of the guys at
Google who was behind Lambda basically
said hey we need to stop this because
it's getting a conscious
and that by itself
is kind of disturbing because if
computers are going to start thinking to
themselves we might see those
Terminators pop up here and there
so these are things that we need to deal
with and this is open source
intelligence so in the future the heavy
lifting will most likely be done by
machines in the form of algorithms
Hardware software wise but we still need
that traditional trade craft because
humans understand sarcasm idioms figure
of speech computers still have a very
hard time in interpreting that critical
thinking within open source and
challenges or in any form of
intelligence is to key to success doubt
everything
assume nothing check everything and the
final decision who will make the final
decision will it be a human or will it
be an algorithm
so with that to wrap it up
we need open source and challenges
investigators that have nerd time
they'll need to understand the trade
craft they will need to have proper
hardware and software now a lot of
companies will not always give people
the proper hardware and software so they
need that they need education budget of
course we will find more blind spots in
the near future but it also opens new
spots with new technology and actually
internet growth we basically need more
power in the form of humans and
computers and we need to be able to
adopt adapt and become an adapt of those
new technologies
so the future
well it's actually now not tomorrow
thank you
[Applause]
thank you so much my pleasure we have
some
a few minutes left for maybe a question
here's a question Chris
hi Nico as an ocean researcher how do
you prevent your confirmation bias in
the beginning of your talk you said well
you thought about a good question yeah
but there's so many data available on
the internet so you might find an answer
how do you reverse the process that once
you have an answer you say critically to
yourself is the false positive or do you
have reviewers or you just cut your mind
in two that's a good question
there are multiple playbooks to do that
so I like to use crap analysis and
that's something that I can discuss I
cannot go into now that the analysis of
competing hypothesis
critical thinking just in a group just
simply saying hey this is the evidence
that I found and used the power of the
group to point out maybe false positives
so there are uh two hands are not enough
to show the the possibilities that I
have to tackle my own biases and logical
fallacies yes very good question and
really important within open source
intelligence
any other questions yeah in the back
wait I'll come to you
so uh what are some of the more ethical
questions you asked yourself before
taking on an assignment so let's say I'm
a operator of killnet and I want to see
what you can find out about me so like
uh kind of a counterintelligence
perspective like how how do you get
through that before taking on the
assignments
yeah that's a good question I'm um of
course I don't always know um who well I
always know who are my clients because
I'm I only will take in clients that I
can meet face to face to face otherwise
I will not work with you but on average
um you could put in certain choke points
in your investigation where you set up
certain processes where you make sure
that the other end of the line is
actually the person that you are
communicating with and not someone else
so there are multiple techniques
hardware and software wise to make sure
well nothing is 100 certain but sure
enough that you will have let's say
enough confidence and comfort that you
were actually dealing with the person
that you want to deal with or not
okay one last question Maybe
yes
yeah Nico during covert times some Dutch
companies were scraping telegram groups
twitch groups whatever as a business
model and selling the data to other
companies what do you think about this
what my opinion about that is
um it depends on the goal that's making
money
yeah but um also keep in mind a lot of
companies are technically not capable of
doing that themselves so they are
willing to buy it the same counts for
breach data some people buy breach data
because they simply want to have it
stopped so yeah my personal opinion I
don't
I don't ever want to deal with criminals
or don't pay any criminal activities but
I do see that there is a need in the
market for it simply because well just
like I stated there's too much
information out there and if you're a
small company you need to do this on
your own or if you're not capable you
will probably need to go to certain
vendors that will do that
okay thank you so much Nico my pleasure
everyone give it up again for Nico
Jenkins