it this this talk is basically for you
guys because what we do as IT
professionals is we're really good at
the tax stuff
and we can understand what's going on
with our network but really sucky at
explaining that to managers and other
people
and explain that in a way that is
defensible so
while we can say that yeah arm you
should probably update your SSL certs
and you should probably like these
badges: we can't really
say that in a way that makes them
understand it to the dollar line
so hopefully with this presentation will
give you guys a framework
to to you explained that risks the
to managers and have them understand so
just a quick warning
arm a risk analysis is intellectual
process and if you're not intellectually
rigorous
that process the product you make his
pal crap and
I've seen a lot really bad right now
since risk analyses
cell just be careful when you're doing
this that you need to make sure that you
are pigeonhole yourself to one specific
threat work
just focusing on one set of ideas but
your
your including all them all the ideas
that you will get it
than a minute the other notice I work
for confidential stuff sack but the same
here so the FBI doesn't impress me
now this is classified circle so
what's terrible story a friend named
Nate networks for an IT company
Nate was recently visit by his boss who
if you
with if you've ever read the bastard
operator from hell that his boss
so he trembles and and ask Sam so I read
this thing last night but hackers are
attacking our network I want to know
what the risk is
post-war network by hackers and the
walks out so they said their
is like while so
I'll so use that service the framework
for talking about
how we look at risk in the situation
because we all in 20
in intrinsically apparently no what's
risky
and what the risks are but we're not
really explain it like that sup
what is risk
can anyone hear shouted out please
explain to me what risk is what do you
think risk it
sorry that's actually forget
probably even adverse event
end-users Rs brilliant
breaking up is a risk so
things that need to be matched alright
so a risk as as works when you're here
seems to be things that might be adverse
in the future
but the definition rest that's used by
at least Italian zucchini and used by
the academic really is that risk
involves
only in certain to get the future so it
doesn't waited
batter good good things could happen in
the future too and that's a risk that we
take
right so the return I love
and investment could be less than we
want but it still
a positive investment so there's a rest
that you that it will come back to us
so if we like the standard distribution
curve which is over here
um the green is good stuff and the red
is that stuff
so in security we generally I like about
stuff
so we accept that %uh the definition
address that we've given we're only
looking at the bad stuff
now when your managers asking you
something about risk it's generally
wannabes six questions
what can happen how likely is it
happened what are the consequences
what can be done for the benefits and
possibly jobs in and what he in tax
so everything that ever question about a
risk a possible your future
boils down 26 question so if you prepare
to the six questions you'll be fine
and today we're going to talk about
these three are here
that the risk assessment we so
sup don't know
I see it in your eyes are glazing over
you think this is actual map iraq this
is not mad this is a sentence explain in
fancy terms
so how do we explain
the three things that the three a
same as we just said that risk
assessment it in
that Sol go through it slowly resque
which is they are is the combination of
which is the segment
the probable even affect so it's
initiate and so
new goes up in Times Square so that's
the missing about
probably even outcome given that event
new cause oftentimes work casualties
the valuation of that outcome a that a
event now compare become a
cell given their new plan of and their
casualties how many casualties are
for every event now come this is
generally where we get tripped up a
little bit because
knows where it says every that includes
like zombies in this space aliens and
zombie george bush so
so you know it gets kinda big the the
set
%uh sliding be online later so you can
get everything you want I'll have a big
slide with the website
arm so how do you skill that down
and that gets to be one of the biggest
sticking point is how do you make that
gigantic
list of things that could possibly
happen into something it's manageable
they can actually look at
Scandic sorry scott and it's not
a group for Asian don't do that so still
the the scenario that were looking for
the scope
is the Sat Nav the brackets are set a
protector
a threat an asset so let's look at it
from the backwards here
an asset an asset is something that
either you drive profit from
as person or company or an entity or you
are
in charge of safety this could be a
database
if you're accompanies could be people if
you the police department this could be
your hose if your camp this could be
anything
literally anything that you drive profit
from or you're in charge in safekeeping
for
so you would be the protector
the key so you can even skill that down
inside company to
okay this might be the network
operations center this could be the IT
staff this could be the managers this
could be
the finance department that we're
looking at specific terms with and the
company or the company as a whole
or the United States so if the threat is
to the secure the nation
United States is the protector not just
specific people
and the threat is anything that's trying
to
lessen the amount of profit you get from
the asset to
tarnish the asset somehow or destroy the
ass
so this is basically what to say
yep sell for neck left
if we go back the the boss asks
what our risk was from hackers so we are
the protector
natan the NOC because we're the only
people that can stop it so
the finance department isn't gonna step
in and start running
and map scans on the network and setup
cigar box
it's not so they're the ones that are
ultimately protecting that work
the threat is from hackers
not you guys that happens arm in the
asset
according to the boss is the company
information so
at the end a day he doesn't really care
about the network secure about the
information that's where he gets his
dollars from
right so that equation
imagine probability what has probability
so
however will probably is best described
as all the things that can happen how
likely is
each one so thinking more abstractly
think the universe as a big box big
two-dimensional blue box
such as the one up here so let's say
were wanting to flip the point
alright and if point let before picking
you become a hazard
come up tables right so there's only to
solutions
there's only two things that happen so
our universe
if we flip that coin gets divided into
it right
so there comes up Hazare comes up tales
so given that comes up heads
what's probably it comes up as again you
buy that and
into another half so if you want to
think about this visual concept
if you're thinking this is a dartboard
it's a lot easier just to get details
and hit the heads and hands
or hasn't s right so and that the size
of each box represents
its relative probability
watch them and you always want strive
for me see
me see it means mutually exclusive and
collectively exhaustive
so no events overlap so there's no
for in this example arm you can't have a
point B Simon test simultaneously on
heads and tails
technically up and also you have to
account for other things I have like the
coin rolling away
so you're trying to make the box as
cucumbers is possibly one fill the
entire box you will make sure that your
universe is as complete as possible
given the scope
right this is a great quote from Isaac
Asimov
and his his second foundation book
you must not say never as an actual as a
lazy
slurring over the fact actually and is
word was there
cycle history but risk analysis which is
and the same thing if you think about it
predicts only probabilities a particular
event maybe even a test with probable so
massively on probable but the probably
is always greater than 0
the world could hang tomorrow that
should probably be in your universe if
you're thinking about
you know a large incomes at univers
zombie killer could come back tomorrow
not probable but parts
so when you calculate probability the
best thing to do is to get raw data
raw data is beautiful cell
generally it's number successful attacks
per period divided by
the number for taps purpurea which will
give you
in that period how often you have an
access a successful attack
I'm so if you have three successful
attacks have 30,000
camps in a month say then you have
probably have point
0001 that's a 100 per person
and that that's a lotta numbers are so
are
especially if you don't have raw data
like we don't really have good
data on terrorist attacks because there
aren't a lot of terrorist attacks the
United States so
and terrorist ok talk to us about how
they do their attacks in such
so we don't really know what's going on
with the terrorist attacks
so what we use mostly is week
Khan subject matter less stations so we
talk experts for experts
in terrorist attacks that tells the guy
the rest of this is
low medium high whenever right so
there they're putting their gut feeling
which is what we all feel about you know
networks is that
into one of these three best low medium
high
and while you can't do math necessarily
on low medium high bans it's really good
for
showing for showing managers
its when you don't have actual did
so remember that the probability for
this must be calculated for both
the event and the outcome given the
event because those were two separate
probably parts in our big question
that's not a question
so makes you calculate the
so what is valuation matter is that
little part the stack-on against the V
you can hope and the reason is
think about it a lot of people here
had to come from very long distances
would you rather have
driven are taking airplane a lot of
people will avoid taking airplanes and
taken said trains are cars or buses or
whatever
because they fear die in a car at their
dying in a plane crash
so much the value their death in a plane
crash
higher than their death in a car
accident so we're talking about people's
response
and you use it as a valuation valuation
metric
the way to go is is to you to understand
that the valuation matters
so the risk might be higher in death in
a car accident
but the valuations lower so the overall
risk that people perceive
is lower so the questioners will there's
another site layout
disputes while more but a the valuation
can be
based on money so I'd attack
a happens how much my dealers I can be
best on
time how much time you lose goodwill if
your iPhone is a crappy product how many
people will be pissed off at you
whatever is a must concern where you
start getting her problems where you get
to the sort of statistical value of life
stuff
where you start assigning numbers to
people's lives like your was 6.4 million
dollars where
yeah there's a moral dilemma with that
because then you're
you're signing onto your values to
people's lives and people don't like
that
so I try to avoid that but some people
like Anna
so here's the process in general now
this is a very basic process
and you can do this pretty quickly it it
might take a couple weeks to get the
data and then use live together in Sun
so along the top your best to make the
chart and
along the top you're gonna put
things like you know tack and successful
attack
so this leave a comment came up with
three categories
no tak unsuccessful attack successful
attack his foot last car category into
internal external
because he could and you want to look at
it
and on the other side your input the
outcomes concerns %uh the
initiating events from top they were
talking and the outcomes concern
are long left so he was looking at data
loss
data exfiltration which is someone came
and grabbed a database
now has all your customer data or data
corruption which is someone when an
an altered the last number America
credit card to the plus-one
or something so if we look at it
and we think about it the probably that
no attack is it wouldn't happen is very
very low
we're all being attacked all the time so
you're never gonna have a day
were no attack happened so the
probability that happen is low
given that you have no attack happened
was probably in half day loss resulting
from that no attack
unless you're an idiot you start
deleting all your tail yourself it's
probably not gonna happen
so that probably is very low how much we
care about that work reuse that the
valuation have how much do we care
for this a particular example so how
much do we care
that you know because I've user error
there was dale's we don't really care
you know it happens it's
fact of life we move on
given that there's unsuccessful attack
now I'm he def back
me in a defined unsuccessful attack as
someone
got through the first layer defense but
didn't achieve their goal so they may
have
you know gotten through the border
routers but didn't get to their final
destination
so the probability that someone
unsuccessfully tax
is pretty hot we all have unsuccessful
attacks all the time my website it which
is pretty crappy website owners do is
probably getting attack right now
and it just happens so no
given that that happen that in
unsuccessful attack happens
so someone's bumbling around your
network what's the probably they're
gonna do something stupid and
drop a table months it's pretty high
it's not
massively I but it's pretty high so we
rate that is medium and then
we value that canelo because they didn't
succeed
this attack but that in 68 so we don't
care
and we keep doing this for the rest the
tape
so we do judgments based on what we
think
in addition to raw data that we have we
come up with
step and this is a man who were you
present your managers
and this form a because it's more
colorful
you and if you look at it there's
there's
kinda the pattern to the to the risk
analysis how can how
and when you're presenting data managers
it's very important to have a pattern to
your day
say can instantly recognized okay this
is the hot spot this is where
we have the most risk based on the rest
now sweet 'n
this is where we should focus because
generally
people like decision-makers won't look
at a graph and say oh
you know we can reduce more risky
rattled say 0 this is where the most
risk is this is where we put
all over money see you want to be able
to give them that
instant gratification of knowing this is
where we should final all over dollars
this is not a risk matrix if you ever
heard the term Ismet risk
its for put it on your mind forget about
it there's a better
arm yeah so let's let's
say that for example we took the the
last Graf
and only did actual hard data in terms
of the problem is that we did so we came
out with actual numbers that we use
right so we have statistics on attacks
and ask us where we are we can actually
have a probable
a problem the probabilistic chart such
as this
that shows the probabilities each's
specific event happened
combination now one side
along the outcomes concerns I do miss
notice that there are some
values theirs and dollars that's the
value
the suppose value that pull out my house
I love
a company recovering from such-and-such
I'll come
now that we have numbers that we can
work with actual hard data
and a number that we can work with in
terms of value that it weakened
revalue all of that all of the the risk
assessment that we just ate using money
instead love how managers feel
comes out some like this and notice
it shifts right the valuation we put on
the risk assessment you vastly changes
the outcome that we give so when you do
you risk assessment always make sure to
identify what they're looking at stuff
they're looking at how much money they
can save
use a monetary base valuations are
looking at live safe use lies base
valuation they're looking at
how much the episod he's how much they
pissed off as a valuation
now so whatever makes no sense because
thats a at the end of the day what you
wanna be giving them
you wanna be showing them in terms that
they want to see
risk assessment
so yep
now that that was up something called
annualized
loss expectancy so given that in for
example the problems were with an EU
so let's say the three successful
attacks 3,000 unsuccessful attacks her
for a year
and the money that you lose is within a
year
you can do for that year so annualized
every year how much money do you expect
to lose
from the specific event now compare in
that's lost that we did his question was
so we get the probability from adding
it's actually
we multiply the prowlers together having
the problems together is
ins never a very good idea multiplying
bro is together gives us a better idea
have
the actual competition probabilities arm
that
with the money gives us a good idea of
how much we should expect to lose per
year
so over a given period what's the
expected loss
and is going less than the full a van
but it accounts for the probably that
this event is gonna happen over a
certain numbers so
eventually it'll happen and what happens
you lose all the money
but I'll be like you lost all the money
all the apps so it's more like
if you shovel this amount of cash
towards me now I can fix it and we won't
have to worry about it like
so given that that takes a pretty
lengthy process there are some shortcuts
and some methodologies we can use and I
will show you a couple but
should be forewarned these are what we
call factor his moms
in fact herb is miles are great for
doing in
instant risk assessment I've a number
items but you have to be aware that only
gives you
relative ranking it will not give you a
definite final probability for each
event right
so you'll still will go through one and
we'll see how it works in a cup second
such as
there with weaker so first you have a
factor is my let's go have a number of
factors so
criticality accessibility on early when
I'm and you can assign a range numbers
to those factors
so like 134 try to use even numbers
using even numbers a as humans we tend
to use
135 skills we use number three whole
helluva lot
and that generally doesn't tells very
much about the rest
cell forcing yourself to use either
higher or lower number
will generally give you a better idea of
what you're looking at and will force
you to
categories the risk has higher or lower
and also
generally provides
a an impetus for figuring out if its
Hiral so it forces you to be more
mentally
prepared for that question I'm
the higher the number is it should point
more towards
the whenever the the issue at hand so if
you're looking at
up won the examples is how
much a community contributes to the
crime rate
so the the feelings that community
perjury her there
situation community contributes to the
crime within a community
so the more it contributes the higher
the number should be
so it shouldn't be that the first four
numbers all represent you know
one is it doesn't create for attributes
and then suddenly switches that for it
doesn't determine why doesn't and
it contributes is that mixes thing
outlook toward them second value each
factories in that range
and then you had a combined score so
this is my favorite one this is one that
the Navy SEALs use for a long time
call carver its for target selection so
if you land on a beach in alone I
and you have to take something out in
order to achieve your goal
and you've got a list of things you just
you use a stall and I'll give you a
pretty good idea I'll
where he should attack so criticality is
arm
how critical the system or item is to
you whatever you trying to infiltrate so
if
you're talking about you know you could
just picture
Navy SEALs on a beach in the middle of
the night there's a hacienda in the
distance with the lights on guards
around with ak-47s and
you in your scrappy team of SEALs have
to get in there and rescue some
prisoner and you have to first thing you
do is turn off lights
so criticality how critical is a power
station
up power lines already cell battery
sitting on the desk
the power stations me massively critic
because without you generally can't
get your power the power lines are kinda
critical because you know they could be
alternate power lines
the up the cell battery is not very
critical to be
house being led accessibility
the power station will not generally be
very accessible the power lines will be
massively accessible
the D cell battery will probably be
sitting next to some guy named pokey
who's watching TV i recover deleted
hours it'll take a long time to fix
power lines there's a string ones up D
cell battery no one really cares
volatility I how vulnerable is a power
stations by well defended you down
Scott lost a conference power lines
because Kobe got them
the cell battery hmm the shooter from
while a note to readers:
affect power station
power goes down done up
the power lines cut them power goes down
done D cell battery
your so you get the idea you go through
any value
each single one 4 whatever you're
looking at
and eventually come up with a number and
that number will give you a relative
ranking so let's do this
for us the next hour
so given that here's here's this copy is
this is just a little exercise
arm protectors hope staff the asset is
the joy many attendees
yes the enjoyment of the attendees can
be an asset and the threat is some rogue
attendee who Hannah was jolted and
somehow
so were his skill 126 6 being
contributes hi least the x6
attack success probability one being
does not contribute in the slightest bit
and and blesses you put a a real love
possible targets there so we can attack
the knocking take down the number
we can attacked the elevator and
immobiliser weekend attack the
projectors in
knock them out we can attacked the
segways to eat knapsack Windsor
axle be attacked the segways an knock
those out
or we can kidnap a man so
we evaluate each one for
all the all the the items and
surprisingly at least for this now says
the elevator will actually cosmos
consummation
and if you look at it he's my fancy
pointer here you look at it index a this
is
accessibility so how likely is it that
you'll be able to get to the thing
for the elevator you could just walk up
and walk in that's kinda the point of it
but I haven't seen a manual we have
today
so East not really a bell that's where
it was the most points
so based on all the factors you can come
up with a relative ranking
how like up which ones will accomplish
your goal
everyone with me so far excellent
here's a couple more I'm just go from
here pretty quick evil done is for
target selection it's like armor
but different D sharp is known for car
for target selection a
its it's a little bit more on history
crave
is for attractiveness assets were
talking like burglars so someone breaks
in your home which things are you think
you see
steel the concealable and removable a
really big in this
because you know walking out with the
flat screen TV is
not as easy as walking out with some
time rings right
murderous is for weapons Lexion he told
the names cannot fit with what they're
talking about that's kinda the point
that's like ninety percent of getting
your your factory smile
%uh agreed to buy the rest the community
is having a great name
so murderous is for weapons like to sew
al Qaeda wants to kill some people what
weapon to the years
murders is yours for Fitz
out this is why I was talking about for
facilitation crime for different
communities
so if it's easy save excuse what has a
warning to do crime
build a crime this when I cooked up this
afternoon
so how easy is it to socialize your
summer
what are the days it is it midnight Nate
are can sleep ears at high noon there
while a are the overseen by nazar to
they have some oversight where they
can't really say anything or
are they allowed to say where I want
pressure how much to pressure them
encouragement that this kind like that
the Karen the sticking right there
so factor is mile for social engineer
now when we're talking about factor is
models in and other things in general we
we want talking about scales as well so
what skill we use determines how we can
do math on the specific
item we're talking about I'm
so ice time before you know about made
him the clarity I love
scales sorry about the word a mate
making sure that higher means
thats it's contributing more towards the
excess eg towards the success
and lower means contribute less so
what about the range the scale so let's
assume factors multiples people C pas de
Aizawl just 134 vulnerability these
dollars in damages see is time to return
to operation seconds India's lives lost
for server this might make sense because
seconds out of operation could be
you know fifty seconds was rebooting
other stuff but what about for a
Christian
to take a long ass time to make any
Christian and that in seconds is going
away outweigh
the 134 vulnerability assessment
see see how choosing the right scale
making sure they
big the mashed together makes for
basically all
love the risk assessment you can sway a
risk assessment however you want
using the RightScale but having a
intellectually
appropriate scale is massive
and he'll maintain your your
intellectual integrity
give you a ass for that is actually
defensible
and is the key to caress risk assessment
so use race go here sometimes skills
there's nominal scales which you've been
things there's
no order no higher the apples oranges
pears there's
no hierarchy right it's just different
types
then there's or which is like I mean
life you've seen
that the Department of Homeland Security
has their red orange green purple future
whatever up bars for risk assessment
that is an ordinal scale right because
higher doesn't elevated doesn't
necessarily mean that the risk is two
times better than
batter whenever right it's not tell you
anything quantifiable about the rest is
just tell you that
its higher so while
there's a hierarchy involved you can't
do any good real math on it
expect to get a meaningful answer right
interval scale however you can do both
hierarchy calculations
so a threat that's a sixteen
are or threat thats us happened sixteen
times day
happens more hot twice as often as a
threat that happens it comes to
happens twice as much as the front dam's
four times rights you can do actual map
on it
and then a national scale is countable
items so dollars
human lives stuff like that so you can
also view calculations on a
suspends all the other I'm gonna show
you it needs presentation I gave to his
company at the end
and it brings together all the factors
that we were talking about and you can
see how it feels weird
plans together this is actual
presentation so I'm sorry further
the theme
so the problem at issue he outlines so
you get the scope in the first light so
this is what we're talking about
so attackers attended a penetrator never
to steal destroyer article
better right there tells you the threat
the protector and the asset
right so
getting that out on the first slide is
is monumental you want to make sure that
your your audience understand where
youre talking about and as
the scope the assessment they've done
anyone getting an idea I've what be
threat the threatened fireman looks like
so get this is I made that shit up cell
given that given what you're looking at
once the probability that can happen so
how likely is it to happen
what can happen how likely is it happen
you see we're going back those
six questions arrest we talk about to
begin
they want to give them something about
you know this is have no other people
news what's happened so what can happen
how likely is it happen what can happen
you know so give them something about
the outcomes
something that happened other people
and then you plug in your ass now since
here's the problem: leave everything
that happened here's probably what will
happen to us your house premiere
yeah
and that s it guess it's it's very a.m.
was a chick reply hamlets are like Emma
sup six questions
right we talk about these in the inning
he answered all three questions
in a short numbers lights so
in the site he answered what can happen
he gave the threats they came up with
how likely is it happening at the
probability is why the consequences it
happens
he gives the problems people the
probabilistic table
with the analyze loss expectancy so over
a number here's this is how much on
average we expect to lose
so now I was pretty quick
in doing a risk assessment there are a
number of things to remember
use common sense is the biggest one it
looks wrong
it usually its
make sure you check olive your slides
make sure you check all your
calculations make sure someone else
double checks for you
I've had a number of times where I've
had the wrong calculation on she'd
and stronger the of make sure that you
check it
make sure you scope the question because
you don't want to be sitting in your
cubicle for the next three years
thinking about a threat that's a year I
today
so you wanna make sure you come up with
assessments timely
you are make sure yours that assessment
is complete and you want to make sure
that
you not biting off more the kinship so
scope in question
is definitely something I remember using
proper skills like we talked about that
will make or break an assessment
run the six questions arrest if you
prepare for the six questions arrest
you're almost guaranteed have no
problems and presentation
you'll be prepared for all the questions
that probably answer ask you
factor is miles a quick and easy but
remember their
kinda dangerous in that you know they
don't give an absolute probability they
only give
arranging a probable ranking love
rescue scenarios and check your work
academic integrity before making answers
happy so
it happens more often than we like to
think that managers will just
ask for something like I want to see a
problem
I want to see risk assessment where X
threat is the biggest threat
and they'll ask you brewster and
personally I just refuse to do that
because my academic integrity is higher
than getting paid
and thats something that's completely
moral and we shouldn't as
as risk assessments individuals and IT
professionals be stooping to that level
arm we should be producing risk
assessments
that are based on probably is there
based on data that are fair
and explain all the risks and it should
be about
you're making certain manager happy
and that as best they on my slides are
up on that website
family has a question for you
yeah
you
in
he's asking about if you you've already
used arm
a risk matrix in your workplace what's a
good way to transition from the worst
matrix to something like this and
using this chart is actually pretty
visually similar to some other s
matrices AVC so
visually moving them from the risk
matrix to the probabilistic risk
assessment
is just as easy as changing the data
behind the church because visually the
managers are only care about
thus lies with the the grass on them
I've I've literally seen briefings where
you walk in and they flip to the first
page with the the graph on it
boom that's their answer they wanna see
they don't care about the rest the
announcers
they just one see graph so moving away
from risk matrices should
be pretty easy in terms love getting the
managers to sign of
on probabilistic risk assessment there's
a lot of
a.m. has lotta work I think that's been
done by
SRA
the their professional organization for
risk assessment
arm day do you really good white papers
and such
that should have a lot of information on
how to support problem was aggressive
thousands over
iris matrices go
%um yeah and that is the problem that we
run into mass times
so in that prop in that scenario he is
asked this question is
what we doing when there's no data so a
good thing to do is
if you have the proper if you have the
ability to put like a small box on your
system
are on your number can just watch the
data coming through so you can identify
okay deserter
attacks like a man that didn't weren't
successful these are successful attacks
get some data
but he can't get data you think that the
subject matter less stationed
subject matter expert Liss stations so
you talked a whole buncha hackers
about what is in your opinion the most
where is the most risk in terms of
attacks and then
you have read out what they say cell
five people say
Anna insert attacks here
for people same courtesy a certain tax
why here
free people say insert agassi its XYZ
right see
right so in said you use in the bay near
got nothin so you're saying okay this
attack
we believe that it's a high probability
that'll happen or there's a low profile
and yours using the the seven matter
experts that the hackers the people who
know it
and using there got and the more people
you getting that
group the more accurate your results
will be because then the more
samples will have people saying this is
the guys this is that's the one
got yes in
I personally
deal only with risk assessment that is
what i do. that is my trade
I was later I'd I don't do the follow-up
stop I have no idea how to do that I
haven't figured out
so sure her question was you know if
you've done the risk assessment how do
you go back to follow up to see if
what you've done is cracked or on track
or whatever and
generally in terms of the government
they'll go back
eventually eventually and I'll do
another risk assessment will see okay we
tracked
there is risk properly this is where the
the Cedar shifting this is what's going
on
but in companies especially that can be
really hard
because managers want to do a one-time
risk assessment that gets them that
check mark on the certification
for whenever they doing so PCI I think
as a a risk assessment
requirement or some sort and they just
want that check mark they don't wanna
follow up at all
so you have to hand it in to them that
this is a risk assessment snapshot right
so that it's only for this
specific period time and some change
hands
their product agree with him i'm for
that part
that's missing yeah
you
right and that's going to into risk
management which is that the next three
questions
which might be another talk some other
your arm and
it goes into how much can I reduce my
risk I put in this amount of dollars
I reduce my roots this percent and
that's why use the probabilistic risk
assessment and set up the
factor is miles because you have a
number
you can come back to later right mean
we you
see I would personally I'd
I think there should be a a greater
mashing between risk assessment
penetration I think a penetration test
myself
is not necessarily an actual item for a
corporation
but a risk assessment based on that
penetration cast will give you a lot
more
data lot more insight on what happened
and
assessing more where okay so these are
you risks
this is how it affects your business
this is your bottom line I'm
cell I think a risk South a penetration
test first and then risk assessment
based on penetration test will give you
great day to
okay we fired excise tax we see at night
axe
your life from these types of attacks
these are how this is how vulnerable you
are
so
personally I think I would use two
different teams but
in reality with you know budgets and
such good the same person could you
pretty good risk assessment given that
they also did the penetration test
because they're the expert on the matter
they've done it they have the
information and knowledge
they're probably the best suited to do
it
in terms of you know knowledgeable about
matter
aka yeah
now
or a
yeah I deal with the government you know
you do risk a son he dove hunters yes
thank you and
I you come back later reassessment and
do they care
if I this is this comes from a Coast
Guard body in mind he walked into a
a briefing and someone had done a risk
assessment people probabilistic risk
assessment
and laid out on the table and at the end
the the risk assessment
I want the people in briefing stands up
and says this is be scrapped this
doesn't support what we want to do
for to do something else and so you know
in some parts the government works like
that in some companies to work like that
but it should and the more we do real
probabilistic risk assessment
more than it might hammered into their
brains that the other aliens
yes yes a lot it was the next generation
actually it was a
you there's a local horn quartet
that a comment and they did you know the
standard comments or concerns all that
stuff is as a walking down the aisle
and it's a it's a big cock auditorium is
a Penn State the
Eisenhower auditorium is huge as we're
walking down the aisle in it switches in
Psych
attorney person actually is is Star Trek
thought damn straight it was pretty damn
yeah
I have not seen his question is it if
there are any
semi-automated processes or programs
that will
take likes more dating give you a
probabilistic risk assessment
and as far as i've seen its
it's gotta be more human interaction
because as as we go back to the first
slide the first of its lies
its not only get the data you have
but he its process that was your
imagination at sea
the more expert you are in the field and
the more your imagination compasses more
of that
big blue box that is the universe the
better your risk assessment will be an
escort
a small boxes only give you the attacks
that you've already seen
what if the next supermodel attack comes
and it only happens once but it's really
fact
yeah in back
generally the way that the government's
worked in the past is
a bunch a guy sat down in a table like
three or four guys and
one guy says I think we should do axe
the other guys are like
well you pay my salary so I agree and
it's been
a sorta beating them over the head from
the top
a fact so see this is the part my job
that sucks I can't really tell you about
all the things I do
cell I can tell you specifically in
answer to your question
but in general beating them over the
head from the top so convincing someone
higher than them that they're an idiot
and forcing them to use the
probabilistic risk assessment generally
works
so the people higher than them if you
can get to them and show them listen
managers have been doing it this way but
if we do it this way ill save money
money is huge and it'll be more
effective that's
be and want to get them bought on the
idea your goal
dip
yeah
and the Black Swan raises its ugly head
not you personally this this is a
theme has been going in especially
intelligence communities for a while
there was a a general %uh the question
was
how you count for a situation that you
don't vision so things that
so right so that you don't have repair
Clemens disperses for
the probably that this will happen and
the in the Black Swan
at the reason I bring up his if you've
only seen whites ones in your life
you can't imagine a world where there's
a Black Swan and so you have no data
backup that there might be a Black Swan
and there's a book by a sample at that a
general
just had stacks up in his office and
would give out to every single person
came to office is at
we sit we we look for the Black Swan and
just sorry did nationally
internationally
so arm unknown unknowns
so in general we that's where the
imagination comes in
right so you can't like he was asking
you can't just take the duck the output
down from small box
run through a program come up with a
risk assessment you have to
Server Manager imagine World where a
supermodel virus will come along to kill
you all
right so you have to imagine that and
what your vulnerability would be from
so it involves sort of imagining and you
have to
when you do something like that if you
explain it
in your methodologies right when you're
presenting to
when managers or whatever arm how you
came up with this risk assessment the
first couple pages on your part
should be okay this is what we did in
detail this is how we got to these
results
this is you know we made these
assumptions lead to these conclusions
and we thought that these might happen
and if you explain it
up front and account for that in your
imagination
that will think cover
the blacks but as you know
September 11 and all the other crap it
out and we can envision ever
so she just happens yeah
of
I'm sorry but I cannot discuss this
topic view the national security reasons
arm not I
I hate my job sometimes I I seriously
can't talk about that
like I I just read it can talk about
that so I would love to answer your
question
kid
welcome apology accepted
please jump
for
said the
mean me
absent just saying that
in doing a risk assessment you should
you might consider including situations
that have not
occurred in the past if you're risk
assessment
if you scope it so we're talking before
about scope in question
self as one slides are online have fun
%uh
were talking before about Scott question
so if it within the scope with your
question
it comes up that you might wanna include
be
I situation that might happen in the
future that haven't happened the past
this Black Swan events September 11 to
the world such then
and you think that might be helpful this
is where be human comes and ball
comes into play if you think that may be
helpful in the risk analysis
you should probably include that but be
being the Black Swan events are so
infinitesimally probable
so minuscule in the probability that
they almost never happen
a sometimes washes them out the entire
houses
you
again this is where II his he's talking
about like
if you plan for one Black Swan event
another one happens what your house
QWERTY
and this is again we're being a human
comes into play
so if when you're thinking about it you
include these locks wanna dance
your including events that you're
thinking about your mind
right so it sometimes the decision
makers will actually ask you not to
include
so depending when he now says ask for
when the house is calls for
so if you're looking at just a risk
assessment based on current threats some
subtle
Aladdin the current resting or based on
threats perceived will be specific
West's
love threats that you're looking at and
I'll just stick to those less
I'll just keep going but the Black Swan
Inn involves a paradox
Sophie look at Black Swan events were
just become massively paranoid
and we become completely immobilized but
we don't look at Black Swan events
than you know September 11 Saban and
people die
for and that's definitely another two
another discussion
for another time I'm sorry to have to do
that to you but there's other people
I'd love to discuss it with you more
please come talk to me I love discusses
work yep
governor
and questions
yep
that how do you how do you right and and
we're sure in time so I had to cut short
the undead he's talking about
so what if the past you take rates were
risks
and how do we iz how we account for
our deterrence how to account for the
fact that just do something changes
people's
ideas what they're gonna do how do we
count for happy things that people do
how to remodel the human mind in a way
that we can understand what to do
we have no idea we're just getting to
the point where he we can use
probability properly work were
like taking baby steps here so that's
something we have to look at
in theory
a risk analysis should be baked into
everything we do so every step we take
should have a risk now says at the
beginning and middle the end right at
the very least
so we can understand okay your address
we've been here the risks
we've got where the risks and we're fine
so
in theory everything should have a risk
assessment but I get them again you know
that
it lacks streamline my lawn
yeah have meant and now for 10 further
take college courses in statistics
rock called course this is six are a
huge step on this
%uh Sarma Sarma the some things on the
Parish Council's
is a professional organization I can
help you get more
training in risk probabilistic risk
assessment and things that measure
there are risk assessment courses their
risk assessment classes there are things
online
there's a whole buncha studies have to
look for it and I be happy to
point you in the right direction offline
because that I'm to thank everyone
okay fine