school like say some things that people
do here wouldn't let that are now
resulting in students being expelled
being fined tens of thousands of dollars
and
and the peanut butter knife okay
I don't know I I really
answers in that sense other than to
absolutely agree that people have lost
their minds they've lost their bowls
you know I mean
in in the Marine Corps we have
non-judicial punishment
we have non-commissioned officers
punishment each one is a step down from
really serious punishment we've lost
we've really lost yes sir
so a how do we find it well we found
here a lot of us are maybe a little bit
maybe house college some others are in
jobs
I hate to keep going back to a few weeks
but we have jobs that
and may be exposed as information but
how do we fit into your
vision its for stuff
not my vision or a vision yeah I mean
tear
here tell Hardy shirt on the idea spear
HG Wells world Bri there's
number books I've reviewed world mind
global mind Howard global brain
I think what's happening here is that
information
communications technology is
leading to the ability to connect human
brains
but we haven't matured or social skills
I certainly haven't
and we haven't learned how to manage
ourselves it's almost like
like the human that is being given this
transformer uniform or whatever but we
have to learn how to use it
okay so I mean
if you look at how people using
cellphones
it's like to increase idiocy up
i mean i i really if I had the money I'd
buy one of those jammers it's good for
100 feet around
and I would just drive around with it
you know
make yes in
restaurants would not be fun
let me find that would be a fun hack is
just everybody go out with the phone it
close to the city
but the fact is the sponsor
argues for a Valley Girl bullshit when
in fact they could be used for
geospatial coordination
weather testing biochemical sensing
linking up
this some what we could do so
were WAY WAY behind and this is because
the engineers haven't been talking to
the humanities
just like the computer was invented
without a clue as to what people would
actually do with
you know i i I fought my wife on this
with my kids grow up
grand theft auto and they're better for
a min amen yes sir Cardiff
actually they didn't learn how to check
carpet they learn how to think and
service
and press triangle I
up and laughing because I know that
supposed to be fun am actually clueless
I guy I just wanted to say one thing
which
I mean I've been here not necessarily
since
midnight but long enough getting you
know near the end of my rope
you said that cell phones are bringing
idiocy I don't know if you're talking
about Americans as I told you before I'm
not an American so maybe all have like a
brain defect
you also told me that okay okay I'm
sorry I'm really sorry and Canadian um
but you've also said that cell phones in
North Korea are
kinda placating them you're also set up
placating them revolutionizing
okay cellphones are being used to access
information that sensor
on because cell phones or 11 channel
right hand
unless you jam them all you actually let
information through
and networks is turning 24
thanks okay
just go back to that that's also a key
factor right here
because and him over there
maybe a suspected terrorist I've no idea
but now we're all in the same room with
him for six hours
and now we're all possibly under a watch
list
because we've been in the room with him
back in
for six hours to you call it good
Yorkshire aa actually he's a vet and
recover
when I had a that makes me no difference
being than having this offer track that
the fact that we're all still here
12 hours later than when you started I
think it is highly suspicious that
you'll stay
I hip
on I think I'm where you guys down I
don't think you're gonna last best 6:30
by of
I had a head downstairs to free beer
myself
and impact they sell beer at this hour
the day up
it was borrowed okay so on in passing
overheard a conversation
on about someone talking about operation
condor
could you just go into a little bit on D
Tom and explain why I don't remember the
operation
really know anything about it so you're
better off
googling for signed I need to go to
Wikipedia well depends I mean you know I
really to be Wales is a brilliant
brilliant man
but when I appeal to him
to stop the destruction of the open
source intelligence pages plenty of
I mean Wikipedia is a phenomenally
powerful instrument but
their sisters there's a
there's a destructiveness when people
get it editing
wars and we haven't figured out how to
handle that
and Wikipedia hasn't figured out how to
give people like me
karma points were actually knowing what
you're talking about
on open source intelligence I mean I was
I spent five days
working up the open source intelligence
page in
a journalist who is now dead and the CIA
group became an interest destroyed my
work
and then when I went back and fixed it
they banned me
okay soul
sisters one issues there I ball you know
weepies kind of a double-edged sword I i
did.
a friend of mine does a lot of web
development for a Republican web sites
and
a a pastime urges was actually inventing
political positions in a New Jersey
yeah and then invent basically creating
fake buyers for them and then
texting scandals for them get mad I
and I love it and then anyone who
removed or edited one of the pages that
he did
he he created he would just say that it
was vandalism and put it back up
n if the page had been there for more
than six months
it took ligaments man effort for someone
to prove that
the person he created in scandals that
he invented didn't exist
that's actually the beginning have an
absolutely fascinating topic
I could go on for about two hours on
biggest no not really I think this is
really cool
because it's the whole issue love peer
validation
and I forget what I was looking at that
there was this answer site for one
specific thing
where people would accumulate karma
points for being
right with yeah well as Slashdot but
there's others
and what we don't have is kinda Slashdot
for everything
I and yeah that's good and and the other
thing we don't have
is a way of harnessing the energy of
both the published in the unpublished
on because I found in my own experience
that
the top 100 people who are published are
not the top 100 people actually have
their hands dirty
you have to get both of them into the
into the discussion I think the whole
idea of how do you
how do you self correct and had self
validate as a group is absolutely
fascinating to me and I don't have any
answers but it's something I would love
to hear others talk about
like as far as Wikipedia concern seems
like it went from the winners
riding history to those who go
unchallenged
rate history and new that really sorry
that's a quote those who go unchallenged
rate history
its interest weighty
my last name stop if you want with an
ebook
lleno I'm not allowed to write books
anymore
for the time being anyway his way to
have you here some spy stories
sure a
for good well yeah I mean does anyone
remember with the most important skill
spying is
you well listening is good typing is the
answer
four hours a typing for every hour aged
meeting
and if you doing it tears meeting you
have to record it then you have to take
the transcript yourself so eight hours
typing is absolutely essential
CIA hasn't discovered voice recognition
huge
up here
coolest thing I ever did was get a list
to the senators that were considered to
be supporting a ser
tonight area power that went to reagan
personally
years only
scared to stay ever was had someone
else's diplomatic pouch in the back of
my car
police stopped me two in the morning but
I had broken the rules
kept my diplomatic identities
was little saving grace
most drinks in one day think
10 that was in part because I had two
lunches with three drinks each
on the same day to different people
for 5
well then I had drinks in the afternoon
in the evening reception or whatever but
I actually had to
complete lunches with to different
people on the same day
no but I have seen russians spit red
wine on the state
you know it's it's it's this KGB thing
we both
with red wine in this is supposed to
like flavor the state
you know can't get over the fact that
their saliva
has been burned off yes sir
I I can't hear you so let's go to the
guys in the microphone
guys in the microphone year
a sela tear
if you would like me me I'm somebody was
a
said do maybe if given up more
information WikiLeaks and
and is now possibly in prison
but they had diplomatic pouches possibly
are access a diplomatic
here that guy transferred that guy
whoever it may or may not be
and what the
able make are into what's the problem
are that the wrong said I'm in with
yeah mooted a bouquet I
yet thank you a
station to station information getting
out sell between
Middle East and an american let's say
get well
I think where we're getting into
interesting around here
because what you're really doing is is
your balancing
the right of the public to know that its
government is evil
versus the right to the government to
keep its evil secret and for me it's a
no brainer
i winner on the right of the public to
know but
right now the government is earning on
the side
enforcing secrecy rules that apply to
stuff that shouldn't be secret
sold if I were defending that geyer
fiery defending the two people that just
got sent to jail for telling the cubans
with the US was planning
I would her on the side
holding the government to a higher
standard of behavior
with respect to anything it's revealed
but sent like
week I'm clueless
we go okay gonna leaks yeah
well you know i mean WikiLeaks s to be
responsible also
I mean they favor alienated some people
basically just
going in and exposing some corporate
stuff that
really was not there's to expose did
really reveal anything that was
illegally was just it was
was like stealing a car to joyride
okay rather actually having a serious
purpose so
if wikiLeaks is pissed off Steve
Aftergood WikiLeaks things to worry
about that
because i text even after very seriously
he's the a primary force behind
Federation of American scientists and
publishes the secrecy news
which is a very high value
commentary on excessive secrecy
government their
accept that you have to go one you go
Google for WikiLeaks Steven Aftergood
and see what he said about it I
questioned him on it because I was
surprised
I knew that we had Julian is a keynote
speaker and he gave me a very balanced
account of why he was upset with
WikiLeaks
and so on just saying just like Jimmy
Wales needs to listen to me when I
complain
WikiLeaks the explicit Steven Aftergood
would he complains
okay so I'm not sure I speak for
everyone
personally I'm not a spy and I've
conference wondered
what spice sex is like and I'll
but could all I does like what I seem
two games behind like
so do spots but success
and now to feel spies
how was fixin kill people their rights
figures
I should be so naive here
I was gonna ask the exact same question
except for the fact that maybe could
outline like the typical day I mean to
use your %uh
do exit on 280 in sweat to death hoping
for your contact to show off
30 maybe like you know go all the way
once up to a typical day but first let
me answer the sex
question %uh here it depends on your age
it's generally very sweaty very drunken
and very be still
and it only happens like once a month
because the rest attack near Taipei a
yeah yeah
and and and I have to say that there's a
double standard
because the boy spies are allowed to
fuck around as much as they want to
spend the government's money
seducing women the girl spies are
supposed to be very chaste
held to a higher standard so basically
see a treat women like shit
and jeanine brookner Road a good book
litigating against secrecy
was my deputy chief station overseas
she was basically discriminated against
for doing what boys do
she won a lawsuit that pay their way
through Harvard Law or whatever
I'm glad for she's a very good person
and
basically CIA's outta control
they use fitness for duty physicals to
pressure people
and their management in the deal the
TI's
essentially on ethical and
by and large it's a fun place to be for
a while
wanna live there
Oso typical day let me do the typical
guys this goes on the first part is
is the sex martial arts in any way with
other spots
no we we we like our women totally
placid
the yeah
warm plastic okay
now now now now absolutely not I mean
if you have to fight you failed
up so a in the a
you know community aged 38 I we spend a
hundred thousand dollars a month
benefit gunnysacks in part because I had
ethics
I wasn't doing it wrong I was on
no actually we rode the bus
you know women
I've never been there
and now you know what I mean spying is a
bureaucracy
and spying from an official installation
is idiocy
biggest everybody knows who you are
all you have to do is keep an eye out
for anybody who works
more than nine to five if you catch the
chief stations party you've got the
entire station plus all the
communicators
and maybe the Knox non-official cover
officers
the inside officers are slobs they will
read liaison to the non-official covers
in a heartbeat
yeah it's just it's bullshit really is
who are now a typical day
I was unusual I worked 80 hour weeks
most guys work 60 hour weeks
but I would start my morning with coffee
and maybe a brush pass
and maybe a colon do a quick our meeting
going to type it up and I one due to
develop else over lunch
maybe have an afternoon meeting at a
hotel room or another safe site or
whatever
somewhere in there I might take some
photos for dead drop site
then in the evening developmental
cocktails in a late-night meeting
with a particular I it was worth needed
one or two hours at the briefing
said generally I slept from troll 26
11 26 something like that shows a full
day
so so what category exactly as
developmental cocktails
well write that off sometime on
a developmental is someone who you think
has potential
your your leadership has approved as
having potential
and therefore you're allowed a certain
amount a latitude in terms of
entertaining them
and cultivating them I mean you know we
do
socal chance encounters like where if I
think you really important run my card
yours just so I can get it fixed and
develop a relationship with you
in the I was gonna ask you would you
have to develop bombers leaves a relief
aid to you
learning 50/50 nobody feat do anything
in fact
a lot of people make up cases and
pretend to have recruited people who
haven't actually been recruited
deal bill fabricate stories
I was recruiting five people here for
five six years straight
25-26 recruitment left after three tours
that's almost unheard of most people are
lucky
wanted to recruitment tour
but but its
you know it's unfortunate because
station has what's called an objective
memorandum
which is what you're supposed to be
doing and nobody
REITs that what they do is they
basically the down the street throwing
money
the air and than anybody who grabs a
dollar bill or your nation
now so the right it up fun
nobody reads the newspapers probably
nobody reads
newspaper so a lotta for agents are
are basically recycling stuff you know
this
my cousins cleaning lady in the foreign
ministry
this is what she said they said they're
actually just reading
a local media that the case officers
agreed
and I don't know how it is today but in
my day
case officers were way too important to
do reading and training
so we would basically have 0 files slow
burn times
and we would just take stuff at face
value
Sahar your perspective change as as a
new
you know into the field verses perhaps
OSM
how was like you know one to three years
on
I mean sound rude awakening to this yr
do just say
love my man Jeeves Ron ING's
fun to drive in action yeah I have a
Walther PPK limited edition
shoots AC p38 K
on I
%ah pink
alright I won't do that again at Franks
next from goes into the crowd FAP
who is that guy that had the slide
romantic
%uh Gallagher it's like I'm at a you
would get plastic Taylor
doesn't no no I'm not I'm
not you're you're you're safe here
it's okay there's some I'm a
non-threatening short fat balding old
guy okay
so alright on
anyway what was the question arm
all about joão yeah it was a very good
question when I would
all school answering a question so when
I first came and I went into a war zone
where the station has been closed and so
we worry activating agents
in recruiting new agents in HS shows how
shortsighted CIA is because it close the
whole buncha stations in Africa and we
needed them
it has never played a long game and
plays a short game
and and so I mean I thought I was doing
God's work
and I walked on water I was like a
Jesuit
with the really big balls and a gun and
the and I loved it I did three back to
back door switch is extremely unusual
and then I came back to washington and I
worked very hard in washington three
jobs here when there was told to go case
of certain other case officer:
and that was code for go down the hall
and go to another
employee if this agency in like cheese
stealing bring me back the answer i won
and I was kinda the end of my contract
with the CIA intellectually emotionally
and then by the grace of God the Marine
Corps came to me because I've been a
reserve intelligence officer all this
time
and in offered me the chance to create a
very quick delicious command
and ideas and I loved it got a two great
promotion never looked back
and effect it's kinda funny because
everyone runs hip pocket operations that
they don't tell CIA about so
when I went over to the CIA the Marine
Corps would tell me about their
clandestine operations because they
thought I'd read them out to the CIA
and when I left the CIA went back to the
Marine Corps City 14-7 likely sources
you like a marine corps penetration the
only Division
I you know so it was fun a.m.
but I don't regret a minute I actually
believe that spying is necessary
but it should only be 10 percent the
solution and
it should be done on the cheap anybody
throws money around as a spy in
and should be persona non grata
it really needs to be done responsibly
right now spying is a voice came
anything done out of an official
installation is absolute under
bullshit and
we should have analysts in the secure
spaces in our embassies
they should be doing all source
intelligence and they should be doing
open source intelligence
ship budgets with which to buy legal
ethical information for journalists
I'm gonna take a break I want to go to
the bathroom but then I'm gonna tell you
about my second thesis on three
embassies in the amount of information
that they did not collect is that
alright
her
here
the Jeep
burrows underwear this
hissy yeah okay
over
alright the the second graduate thesis
was for public administration I look at
three embassies
basically an embassy the diplomats are
in the minority
and the representational allowance for
diplomats is 50 percent for the
ambassador
fifty percent for the four councillors
and the other 50 percent spread among
the
2230 embassy employees
this means that a junior officer
generally at best gets to take someone
out to lunch once a month
and maybe has one small party one
Supporter
the rest to the embassy
consists of apart from whoever's doing
clandestine stuff many individual
representatives have many different
government agencies
agriculture commerce Coast Guard
whatever
and so what I found was your average
embassy was severely handicapped because
the people who wanted legitimate
collection
or legitimate open source information
had no money with which to buy
commercial intelligence or pay
journalists for special report anything
like that
they were limited to the physics of a
24-hour day
and who is willing to be seen with them
the spies in contrast
demanded be a traitor before they would
listen to you they have no interest at
all
an open source intelligence or
commercial intelligence that is legally
and ethically available
and so I found the result was when
combined with the fact
had to coordinate your electronic
messages which everyone would see
and you did not have to coordinate your
hard copy out shipments back
what I found was that we collected at
past 20 percent
have the relevant available information
and in the process
sending it back to washington spilled
eighty percent so that basically leaves
us I think with roughly 2 percent
love what it means is if you send hard
copy back
it goes from the embassy to one desk
officer
one agency who doesn't have time to read
it and therefore he just throws it away
or files
it doesn't become part of the electronic
common space
okay but I realized
recently that it doesn't matter were
only getting 2 percent at the end 21
intelligence because nobody's making
decisions based on intelligence
making decisions based on ideological a
commercial interests or
whatever so that was the second thesis
any questions I think you guys here
falling down here
I have a question yes sir um you
mentioned earlier
a constitutional convention up
in in this scenario I think there was
with
allow any amendment or any even
destruction of the constitution to occur
is
and I don't believe there's any
mechanism by which to limit the scope of
such
cheryl's so I don't feel that we're at
the point yet
such a thing would be necessary I'd
understand the
emotional response to and I doubt
there's any
I doubt the congress Senate would
actually at
amend the Constitution to create clause
for
some sort of scope creation by the
state's
for such her statement up
for also for
controversial legislation
that Congress would never past like
something like
recall election mechanisms were
repealing the 17th amendment
how do you think anything like that
could ever
going to affect well I
my understanding is that if enough
States agree to it
congress has no choice but I agree with
you we should have a constitutional
convention at this point but we should
use it to get
electoral reform mean we should use the
threat to the Constitutional Convention
I think a lot a state should start now
will find federal laws
big is the federal government is
creating ceilings rather than force
for responsible legislation such as
environmental
you can't go above this demand whatever
on I E
honestly be very nonviolent by
inclination
think that we're gonna have to have some
kind a swarm
pressure on congress I mean I
read with fascination a story about a
mob around call rose house
where they would chase him around the
house from the outside
and knock on the window and it scared
the shit outta
but I'll tell you something every single
congressman is vulnerable to that kinda
swarm pressure
particularly if they can't go out in
public without the swarm appearing
and so I think
word point now we're the
dysfunctionality has gotten our
attention
and the Tea Party is one manifestation
but it's not sufficient
I certainly would like to see the black
population
much more aggressive about demanding
Obama
he release all the prisoners who are in
fact slaves they're performing
labor for furniture and license plate
another commercial
things getting pennies on the dollar
I really I don't know but I think we're
getting close to where
it will not be possible to be a
congressman in the United States without
being held accountable
may not be five maybe five years maybe
more but I think we're getting to a
point now
where congressman will not be able to do
secret deals where every penny will be
/c
I'd love to see much more whistleblowing
vertically to to free web sites rather
to specific government agencies don't
really seem to investigate as much
yessir
do you care to discuss some have your
elicitation techniques and meet some
basic things
with us would you like another drink
okay that's what I sorry there's other
social engineering going on all the time
yeah I'm sure you're quite good you know
well yes and no I mean I
kind if would like drink works very well
yeah it does in
and you know those are those are
absolutely fascinating
thoughts with you entertain writing them
down is kinda the former journalism
give you 1000 dollars a month from now
on
you know yeah ride
I mean we just throw money around but
but I E I was at
hackers in 1994 when they did the first
social engineering telephone call
and they got the operator to give up the
pens and stuff
I mean as 750 people just
roared and up in front was the AT&T guy
who knew that his operator Justin had
at he was just there is smoke was coming
out of his ears
a some social engineering is something I
think actors do better than spy spy's
just throw money at the problem
and and and they get what they pay for
which is often
stuff that's not worth it in the back
first here
I'm not surprised that we get to talk
about these things
and not get bothered too much but and
very surprised that no one is
bothered you were taking you higher
ratings hoops
X expand on that and share with us well
for the first
for the first from 1992
to about nineteen ninety will for stuff
I've held SAT K
compartment crypto clearances for thirty
years from 1976 to 2006
on my loyalty is beyond question have
passed to lifestyle polygraphs for CIA
and one for the united nations
on
and I have no CIA pension they can be
held back
so there's not much they can do and
they're really don't
kill small pests and I'm nothing more
than a small past
so what
no I actually have a very interesting
loyal following in sight see I
there there people there that really
wanna see the place work
but so initially I was called a lunatic
for thinking open sources could be
anything
better than spine and
then I became an annoyance but all look
behold
my first book and the forward from pass
chairman of the Senate Select Committee
for intelligence my second
who is a democrat my second book at a
forward from the contract
chairman of the Senate Select Committee
for intelligence at this point you don't
bother me
because if you do will have political
implications
at this point he said shut up grit your
teeth which is what you're doing now
Dana priest does this new series on the
icy
I mean she's ten years late I rewrote
the book 2009 other guys read a book
called spice for higher
which as talked about how seventy
percent over money goes into contractors
rather than real spine on so long and
short of it is I think I'm considered to
be
a Brillion pain in the ass
who is right but is so annoying
and so threatening to the current status
quo that there's no point even
considering
ideas and
so it goes now the sad part is a lot of
other governments have taken my ideas
run with and
well it is I mean actually Eastern
Europe just was an explosion
open source intelligence centers and
things like that
and where where I have not been
successful is it getting the
eight tries to talk to each other
because I really want to get just one
country
we have a common center have the
academic
commercial government law enforcement
military
media non-governmental and civil society
all
like the chambers of commerce plus the
journalists Association's plus the
Academic Council
is just amazing you can do if everybody
talks to each other
all right sir let's go to you this
mace mean I me you can answer some the
you've dealt with
security is what you've done this for
selectronic security
and also bit like drug surveillance
systems families that sort of thing
on I obviously something to be talk
story I mean ship
these days you can you can buy for 250
bucks
wonderful GPS you put on your wife's car
let down everywhere she's been less than
that actually yeah
yeah expect the point is that is that
stuff that we used to have to pay
three-peat we stepped pay six-man teams
in
two cars and a motorcycle and one foot
guy
and to that stuff now Scotland Yard
implemented all of my ideas and they
found that
where they used to have to spend three
thousand pounds a day for surveillance
team they can out 230 pounds for credit
check report
and get the address the guy they were
trying to get all
okay and so
the really I mean they've they've given
me everything except the silver plated
clock
and last year two years ago I gave them
money well the
Bobby had in the night stick that they
gave me with her
but Scotland Yard has been putting away
more tears
arms merchants faster better cheaper
with open source intelligence and that's
why Sir David Van Ness got my did
and one of the interesting sidelines
come back to electronics around in a sec
make this point one of the interesting
sidelines is that we ended up
confiscating
more ill-gotten gains by a hundredfold
because spies don't do real estate taxes
and so open source was able to identify
the
the French Riviera house a whole bunch
of other stuff
and so lemme Scotland Yard made out like
them banded
with post-conviction confiscations now
on electronic surveillance
back in the day it had it have cell
phones
and you had to have clunky radios when
you were trying to communicate
and stuff I mean these days I think it's
absolutely wonderful you can pop a
webcam in front of an embassy or in
front of a place in
and do remote surveillance from anywhere
and really very very meticulous about
watching stuff as yet bugs and taps
well it that way yeah you know and and
and frankly most I mean I've done bugs
textbook cases bugs and stuff
most the time they're not worth it
because you end up having to have
I mean first of these past looks so
probable source
those days blood had to have a receiver
with like
150 to 200 feet typically which can be a
hard
issue in some places where can they be
that have a transcriber who was willing
to sit there and spent his life
listening to noise or recorder lisa
price list here
yeah and at the end of the day when I
found is it
is it for every hour 340 your
lucky if you get one minute anything the
bottom line is it's a lot better to just
have a few minutes or sick
cut to the chase and so most electronic
surveillance including
most NSA does is worthless
are as yesterday read what's the what's
most interesting store you
came across such a situation agency
involving this type of thing
was withdrawn archives was for that
matter
most interesting story I've heard is
that there was once a night here your
country
knew that we were very good at looking
for electronic devices
so they built some very complex ceramic
sounds tunnels could not be detected
actually faster well basically acoustics
yeah I mean why the ceramics I mean if
you look at the Irish am so impressed
they
they did a national survey or whatever
they were thinking about how to survive
how to resurrect Ireland they do they
were good it's ceramics and then they
discovered that ceramics a useful
in electronics so that was cool
no no no I'm talking to different things
the Irish drink ceramics
someone else to but you know you most
most electronic surveillance I've I've
never been fun
and in actually today digital
alarms are a lot tougher in the old days
you know
almost a foot CIA does is
worth paying for yeah
you good I'm good Ridge
because you only got an hour left i mean
to you to your deadline anyway
he has to keep you going till 10 I think
they'll quit
10 minutes think today I mean
I mean daily breakfast no I'm fine I'll
pick up some donuts on the way out the
door
again all I have to do is get those
boxes in I asked to tell the guys to
order the car up
and get the boxes in the car give the
porter 20 but bill
and for and itself with my GPS
I should be fine on
and you and i cant talk of line about
whether someone wants a ride
driver on balance a I tend to go on my
own but we'll talk
okay and I just want to make sure that
and just a quick announcement for
everybody here
on because housekeeping is not really
going to get a chance to do a super
thorough job with the room
if you could just pick up all the
bottles the broken plastic cups whole
Rab racing yeah absolutely ask that you
get it's also a great way to wake up and
keep going and so the
right you guys could just don't you keep
listening keep asking questions but
if you're leaving the room try to pick
something up to take it out and that
applies for everything
the rest the day to make Teranga year
thank you I'm inclined to stop at seven
because I see people falling asleep here
so so why don't you guys
1890 know why don't you guys come up
with like three really cool
questions and let me answer them think
is an
using it worked as well the same day
fella
we heard
RAM and talk about you know privacy is
that get over it
and and all the different ways that were
all using privacy
and earth and the US the industry let's
say almost ten years ago
how much is what RAM and five min being
used by your current
or by any current first of the the UN
dozens find anybody
but I i urge you to read my
might human intelligence monograph
because it distinguishes between the
four classified slices and the 11
unclassified slices if you meant
on you know the bottom line is that the
intelligence community will use anything
that costs money
and they will ignore anything that
doesn't cost money
so a.m. love his businesses like you
know you're eleven dollars this database
seven dollars is that a base in all laws
is given a
it's no big deal as long as you have
great potentials it's all yours well not
really
actually intelligence analysts today who
want to do interagency database checks
probably spend a third of their time
this negotiating
the password ship and they're lucky if
they can spend the third time actually
grabbing relevant data
in the words of one of the Int'l Inc
administrators
few years ago it's a crapshoot
K
I mean really you gotta you gotta
realize that the intelligence community
database system
is a whole series is still fights built
by a hundred different contractors none
of us wanted
any other contractor to be able to
connect to their database it's a
nightmare
because secrecy it's almost impossible
to resolve
which is why I wanted to create an open
source agency that would set the gold
standard
for what could be known shared and then
from there we would move to
creating a completely new classified
system
that would have attributes on each datum
for who could see yup
okay so now when I was in college I I
joined like I guess you could say was
like a secret society in
you know from when I was younger I will
talk about it but
when I was younger you know like I had
watched movies and you know you have
this whole big ideal what that's going
to be like
and I would say for a good three month
period I walked around with my dick was
two feet long
soho like so that what I'm wondering
dog a person of and you tell us how do
you know
you grew up in a major where you know
like
there were spy movies there was james
bond like
mentally michael Mosley what was it like
that first like
three-month period where you were like
in
no now if you if you ever want a good
time go to
go to Williamsburg in the springtime
look for all the kids with Pentax
cameras
you know the take pictures love dead
drops in
foot tosses car tosses stuff
I mean it's a who because I when I was
doing it
its so when I was when I was the right I
could look up
and I saw these two lawyers and they
were looking down and i cant kinda hear
them saying only the new prop this
arrived
you know on
I felt like I was a Jesuit priest the
sacred order
and I mean it viscerally hurt me to
leave the clandestine service for his my
identity was all wrapped up in it
but I am grew it and
there's certainly some spying that needs
to be done and some others terrifying
and the fact I based on my own
experience I I we're going to law
enforcement but that'll
the average law enforcement life is
ninety percent sure boredom in 10
percent sure terror
and that comes pretty close to my own
experience ninety percent
border and 10 percent sure tear
no I don't miss it in fact I love
working for the UN
because in Guatemala I feel doing some
good
and I'm doing it without breaking any
laws and doing it very inexpensively
and at the end of the day my integrity
is
vastly more valuable than my clearances
ever
so so you did to fill up
purpose for the government if you were
to be the
pose this is really a stretch perhaps
now it's not very few
a poster child for your position you
were like go on
you know let's see the all you could be
for the
the of few the proud the parade the
or you know all these other slogans out
there for
their government recruited how would you
crew you Rob sorry how would you recruit
somebody
to fill a position like that arm
in in perhaps try to be as honest as
possible saying look as long as we are
worry its all time you're going to get
lead every got the mileage as one
well first off I mean it's too easy
doing it in the current ways still
that the current wave recruits young
people are US citizens who can be
cleared because they've never done
anything interesting
and they don't speak a foreign language
I mean see a serial secret is like 16
percent
their population speaks a foreign
language with its
unbelievable if I read the T&I
the park from practicing for apart from
changing the position
eliminated
I would recruit people in mid-career
there is no cover that can be fabricated
that will stand up to 25 scrutiny
in how would you entice them though
because mid-career was like money
of course and you pay and and basically
what you want
what you want is a mid-career percent
who has spent 20 years
becoming a top person in the region with
rolodex that only twenty years can
bill you mean I'm sorry you mean region
overseas alright year
%uh and and so you find someone who
spent 20 years in Latin America has a
rolodex to die for
%uh and basically would like to at 10
percent spice to their life
and you basically have them continue to
live the cover that they built
unwittingly
and you really manage them very very
carefully for very very serious things
for example
no resident not should ever do a
recruitment
they should only handle people who have
been recruited by others in third
countries in
properly vetted dinner absolutely secure
me this is not how we do business we
have a few really great change fund
types and we have a few
really great non-official cover officers
but really there's like 45 CIA's there's
a white house CIA there's a wall street
CIA there's a bureaucracy CIA
there's a safari club tradition torture
sodomize kit CIA
and that is probably one other CIA sons
now SAT stuff and just different stuff
so science and technology for
I'm going on I'm known to people who
grew by the CIA and
in general background is is Benny the
lived in the country previously
or their father has some kind of
diplomatic for overseas less shipping
never US
citizens a so you're saying dole
recruited a young age
go for the people who were are basically
establish their well
I actually I actually was part of trying
to think through the future the
clandestine services
published this II had five slices
slice number one is young people who
were recruited
to be part of the blue the system will
be there forever
that's one-fifth one-fifth
are US citizens recruited mid-career
to be non-official cover officers slice
number two
i three the third fifty is third party
nationals who were recruited mid-career
to be
career case offices but never touching
classified materials
never coming back to headquarters sites
number four
the fourth a 5/5 is clandestine case
officers from
other countries who were recruited to be
part of a regional station for example
the committee
the strains the cambodians do very very
well
human trafficking penetrations by using
cambodian case officers up close and
Australians in
with money and technology and then slice
number five
would be it's just business if you've
got
a PC here going into a sensitive
insulation and live your someplace you
go to the west german business e-cell
give you a million dollars
I'll give you half upon insertion the
device here and I'll give you half when
I get signal on the other end
and never see you again and we're not
gonna give you lie detector tests
ship works for AT&T
but but is only considerably different
than the current model who are you know
you've grown people
well the current model you don't grow
people you views
good point
your welcome young you know I'm enough
sorry but but
it's pathetic I mean I look at these
young kids
I mean CIA analysts I I flew back from
the room with the World Bank guy
and he said that the CIA analysts it
come to see him
and they were so young and the
hypotheses they put forward to explain
instabilities
done were so ignorant they were
frightening
K the Boca CIA's analytic population has
less than five years an adult good and
even that is questionable
post-college
beatty about 21 it's called 21 I so
they're under 30
there under 30 they don't know jack shit
about the world and they don't speak the
language in the country responsible for
they're only there because they can't
get a clearance
and they weren't good enough to go to
wall street cheat the public
all right sir little shift um the
tsunami that happened a couple years ago
killed yeah it was great the people
intelligence I'm pretty sure that
that you had mentioned even the last
hope how that was orchestrator
there was some thing there and number
thinking about that kinda
but that's in my mind last couple years
and it was only recently that I heard
some
that information I'm hoping you can
verify this one the other
about some ungodly amount of minerals
that world I'm brought up from the sea
and landed on the on their on he takes
up no harvested
I haven't heard anything about that it's
fascinating I know there was a lot of
interest in
in in mining the sea in the seventies
but I know nothing about that yes sir
sorry go back to the spiced up again
sure no problem
on now how often do
spies like the you know but the the
double legions
or spies the power goes ahead to a wall
or
they still are often start doing like
clandestine things on their own outside
the government like such as
like movie stars were does that happen
well let me let me is that several
levels for example
CIA CIA made a huge mistake in the last
few years
and they authorized their case officers
to do outside consulting not to
interfere basis with their spine
does it make sense course says it's
stupid
don't think if you distribute what's
former times a month
I'm not hearing this wrong yes
clandestine services allowed its
five days to do private work on the side
AFP
Yemen mining is a complete thats
completely unbelievable
I'm sorry but you heard it here
word the so
did those people ever like you know what
screw the US these people are gonna give
me 10 million this month drugs do well
actually
we we have had issues with non-official
cover officers who went to corporations
and found out they could earn a million
dollars
instead for forty five thousand dollars
could you explain what
the that to officer does well basically
they
the non-official cover which means
they're not operating out of an embassy
unofficial US installations
so the 100 caught the US says
are we don't know what they're doing in
theory aka year
in theory I mean we've had we've had one
not contrite for
forty years in a prison and
me there are some very sad stories spy
swaps
a well yes and no I mean
the other day the this recent thing with
Russia
was the FBI fucking Obama and then the
CIA
knew that they were going to do it so
they spend some time thinking about who
trade and I think that's a very good
traits
what to you could you explain the trade
on no because I'm not familiar enough
with the
disk or read about it see that they got
some people that deserve to be done now
so I was I was pleased and please don't
misunderstand me I mean CIA's fuller
really great people including my wife
who we're doing the best they can with
in a very
that system okay it's it's a horrible
system
yes sir yes hi am
we've you've talked a lot about
reforming the
American system am I'm I don't know if
you mention may be reforming the UN
system because I just visit there
and their crown on merging you about and
so did
organization chart and was just
horrifying complexity
so you think that there's change to be
made
disprove Pressey well yeah I mean that's
what my latest book is about
and in there and have a chapter in the
United Nations
and I actually look at the United
Nations topics on their own website
United Nations is
coherent online and it hasn't got a clue
I mean it's so disorganized
most people don't realize this but the
secretary-general United Nations doesn't
have any authority at all
and there are a number of specialized
agencies that are basically run
off-budget
their run by contributions a combination
of allocations
intonations
however and I think the book
properly credits the United Nations with
being a potential force with the United
Nations lacks intelligence
in every sense of the word Brahimi
did this very well the for him the
report was a superior
piece of work and then louise for sure
Canadian yeah
it good I mean Louise for shit came into
the united nations
horrified I mean they didn't have staff
processes that
briefing papers they didn't have a way
of supporting
decisions and one other things that
published a book on peacekeeping
intelligence
you know if you don't have strategic
intelligence you don't get the mandate
right
if you don't have operational
intelligence you don't get the force
structure right
if you don't have tactical intelligence
you lose people and don't get the
mission done and if you don't have
technical intelligence
you're basically incapacitate on and so
all number of a sieve worked very hard
over the past few years to try and
develop a concept UN intelligence
professor Walt Dohrn is one of the
leaders in this field
on and General Patrick compare myself a
few others
basically the United Nations right now
suffers from the fact that it's
depended on member nations for both
money
and information and personnel and
a third of the UN is that the two
Stickley incompetent a third of the UN
is spies who were fine as long as you
take people to launch but they're also
uncover jobs they don't understand
and so the reality is the UN is running
on the backs of one third of the people
who are real UN
and that's a problem but the other thing
the UN hasn't figured out how to do is
how to become a harp
for multinational information sharing
and sensemaking
and I honestly don't know if I'll
survive
I mean there's every chance that I will
be fired by the UN on any given day
because I am is
and medical to the UN cultures it's
possible to get
and so we'll see how this goes but if
you want to help me talk my book up to
anybody this with the UN
elements free online would love to see
the
the book it spread around yes sir you're
shaking your head
I'm see my head the at my behind he's
excited
on I wanna talk about out about four
years ago they found the CIA plane that
hours trackback to
shopping mall or whatever and now its
track back to a drug-trafficking cartel
and as you watch the Great White hype
hope
up what's a whole bunch of crack back
into you
South Central America are LA
i think im I made a misstep fired but
fantastic if you are if you slept
through it that's okay there's a lot of
drug dealers in
Ricky Ross yeah I love about him early I
mean basically
CIA that's an honor to jail and we put
Ricky Ross in jail and and that movie is
probably ten years old and they found
that airplane
five years ago so sup still going on
obviously
yet bill this still small aircraft
braking large amounts of drugs across
I continue to speculate that CIA and DEA
are running drugs in the United States
I do you think it's for money or do you
think it's for some other
profit Mar like is there another reason
they're I'm sure there's a series of
complex reasons
and can it be enough volume to really
you know make a difference
yeah I mean just three
re read my review Dark Alliance okay up
here that will go back to you
can you speak about you work in
Guatemala and you know there's
is it know the short answer is No I mean
it's it's a miracle they let me come up
here at all
so I'm very pleased to be part of the UN
this conference has nothing to do with
the UN
my remarks on my own on but I will tell
you that the UN
is experiencing some serious success in
Guatemala with the hybrid organization
which is helping the government to learn
how to put people in jail in do
investigative work
and how to be effective because
unfortunately when
governments failed gangs prosper and so
what we have to do is help governments p
legitimate and efficient and when you do
that
it has a very beneficial effect on the
economy because investors and gain
confidence
what senator no
but mexico desperately needs it so does
the United States
I mean really corruption is
scorch corruption is what enables crime
wanted provision professional
provisional 1
well i i think the legalization of drugs
is certainly
an important part of the solution
another
insist on this very successfully but
that's not my real
feel so let me go to you on the back
yeah I was actually morning with
what column baseline training
techniques for instance the to the
briefing if you like
basic marine training any martial arts
combat
special weapons training the no
Taipei I and how many words per minute
with this the
yeah guy you wanna be up to over 200
you get bonuses for combat
you know if your gonna 14 years on no
no of up but you get to take a bathroom
break
now you know I mean
its inner CSI New York up in New York
cops get 6 months training
Marine Corps infantry lieutenants get 6
months training spies get 6 months
training
and it's basically covers the
what's called the intelligence cycle so
there's there's
recruitment well actually this finding
in assessing
and then there's recruiting and then
there's Hanley
and I i'm sorry spotting assessing
developing recruiting handling and then
termination which just means
paying them enough so they don't talk
about it afterwards and so you get
training in those things and
the biggest the biggest part
is is making sure that you understand
how to debrief somebody and how to take
notes and
how to not be discovered doing all that
and then how to type it all up
get back I was good I was going to add
that
you know six months training is
generally when the Gunners mate on a
Navy ship
com has to point you in the right
direction
alone Southwark right that so what do
how do you supplement that
are you house do you feel naked when he
finally like reality hurts when he's in
fact years
their Easter several books by young CA
people
CIA after training wrote books there
beneath contempt
on the training is actually a weeding
out process
and if you graduate from training then
you really learn your job
the first tour overseas you learn that
under Chief
station chief operations who actually
walk you through doing it for real
so so the biggest hit a guy hit the
streets after training
your your advice would be one what what
what supplemental to that
that you've learned well it's not advice
that I followed because I probably stood
out like a neon sign
police now now then I was the gendered
riser bunny
and the throwing money around like it
was going out of style
and you know so and going in and out of
an official installations
so I'm quite sure they're liaison new
every single person I was talking to and
so I was basically just
living fraud and
and that's what I don't think people are
really willing to accept is the fact
that most of what CA
does is known locally a sign they're
controlling the information
they're fully aware of what's been
called the CIA they're probably feeding
some
and we pretended am in fact this is
actually true
when CIA found out that at least one of
its major soviet agents was being
controlled by the KGB
they did not tell the president they
actually continued to feed intelligence
from an asset to the president
and not tell them that it was a
controlled source being run by the KGB I
mean this is this is
attacker is just mind-boggling
okay I got a different question for you
here mom
what can you tell us
whatever you can dollars on any type
extraterrestrial contact that the CIA
where for you dry
well I can't speak for CIA the I
personally was on loan at three
yesterday
yeah now %uh
I read a number of books in hidden truth
and
is these two books by this guy answer
whatever he just had a very interesting
conference
Midwest and there was an MIT book
on on encounters with extraterrestrials
and
I'm quite satisfied and also governments
are starting to declassify
their UFO stuff the government of Brazil
Chile and so what's what's happening now
is we're starting to see
a serious massive evidence come out
that there have been extraterrestrial
contact since the 1940s
and the government has been keeping it
secret in part because they've
harvesting technologies and I really
don't know the details
and I certain
yeah I do like him horses books
mars MA RRS
yeah bottom line is I don't know what
CIA knows about extraterrestrial but
frankly that's most the Air Force domain
they've kinda claims that area
and it is
it's not something I was privy to its
not something I'd
violate if I were privy to but based
exclusively on open source intelligence
there is extraterrestrial life out there
we scare the shit out of them
and we have been abusing the public
by keeping all the secret all these
years was and
said if
the fact that we're nuclear don't know
how to handle it what's at
they have
daily others though sonya
of Milan
out I was initially asked about the the
election cycle here
and how someone a sheeple a every four
years
you know I like them yeah every four
years the Canada side after all you know
me some little bit of hope little to
change out there
is on theater I mean Chomsky wrote the
book on it manufacturing consent which
actually has to offer some so how do we
get
how to get around that though because I
know they're other countries I've heard
there are other countries out there
perhaps these Canadians here
but but I've heard there are other
countries out there
Rev %uh different electorate arm
criteria for instance where job perhaps
majority doesn't rule was based on a
percentage above your life
I I personally like parliamentary
systems
because I really do not like
winner-take-all it really messes up
I like parliamentary systems and
I certainly like systems that
absolutely do not allow committees the
whole secret hearings
or secret earmark hearings are secret
authorization for preparation and what
would that be
just as a reasonable me like are
are they really going on right now I
mean I honestly don't
lover actor perhaps I have not really
studied this
I just know that secrecy is a cancer and
we passed feet these people accountable
and transparent and that's not happening
know obviously
but but the problem is up guess what
we're not like
the old guys who were like there are
four years before because you're short
term memory only goes back like
for the three years and nine months back
you can talk to me like that all people
I does does this reach into the restroom
because I i wanna miss you every time
we're on
who'd
said or
in the problem two-party system
by wondered
for said
here
are during his rest period lou would
like the
see some show tunes here I don't think
here
I i do believe
technically 616 if you look into
local history governor
or whatever you want but no I mean
really amazing guys hung out but I'm
kinda take a pic that that we made it
eight hours
results I guess basic i'm saying is
every four years ago through the site
where people can I forget what happened
during the previous four years
in the administration walks in there and
says whole way to me here
were eight new administration know I
know that's why I think
honest to god the hack is to basically
get the public to understand that they
have to vote
out every single incumbent do you think
there's something wrong with the
two-party system and and how we fix that
it's a two-party Tierney
it represents fewer than thirty percent
of the overall american Public
it is absolutely one of the most corrupt
systems on the planet it's kinda soft
hit
corruption so I'm
I yes I think we have to get rid of the
Republican and Democratic parties
and i frankly you know I'd love to see
how our team
or sam nunn I'd love to see sam nunn get
together with lee iacocca in
create the American party so so which
one takes his place we give real
two majors whether 63 others which
course never get heard of public TV or a
news story
great I meet for me I love I don't know
if it's true or not but it said that
when eisenhower came back
from overseas Marshall said
this is from a DVD enactment so Marshall
said
everyone's trying to get you to run for
president where are you a democrat or
republican and he said I'm American
and that's the only acceptable answer
soul bottom line here is I think we need
don't politics and elect people and hold
those people accountable to their
constituencies
and they need to understand that we are
on them like stink on shit
and we are all over them every single
day
anytime they have a secret meeting it is
a big black mark that's on the front
page
yes sir could you
I'm your considered opinion about
Goldman Sachs and financial capital
now the game the system go home welfare
benefit might my knowledge is strictly
limited to open source is that I've read
but Goldman Sachs his game the system in
part with with high-speed trading
on manipulating markets lying
two governments and generally betraying
the public trust in such a way that if I
were gone they would lose their charter
tomorrow night bankrupt every single one
other executives
forever
but certainly the last twenty thirty
years and in fact you can really trace
all this back to the roster
trials introducing central banking and
sponsoring the Civil War
to basically get the north and the south
the fight each other
this is really ugly shit and it's not
taught in high school or college
yessir your front
you okay and do you think by
giving more visibility to or other
parties would be enough to change their
no on in fact I really don't like the
party system
all because I think what we should be
doing all the party system can in theory
be used to organize people with like
preferences
the greens for example although they
don't seem to know much about green
are but I think that what we really have
to get to
is participatory public budgeting
which is to say the public as to be put
in touch with reality we have to put
dollar signs on our choices
and we really have to understand what it
meets
to be a citizen and to be a democratic
polity
which every citizen has a state in the
truth
the integrity of every decision that's
made I mean what we've been doing is
making decisions based on ideological
fantasy
on and special interests corruption and
we have not been making
we haven't been doing
intelligence-driven democracy the
so you're saying that people through
vote more often
about voter or yes as a matter fact I
would like to see
almost every major issue put to a public
ballot
and and then that's simple to do
particularly if you have libraries are
actually the same
voting stations on that are there at
cell phone something you could make
cellphones
be arm you know a form of
authenticated personal preference the
bottom line here
is we have abdicated our responsibility
for being informed influencing
government
yessir I am not too long ago we we
test a nuclear bomb and we discovered it
worked and then we
immediately after that dropped to
another country and since then
the United States is tested more than
1000 the restaurant combine is also
has additional 1000 how come
materials and that technology has in
fallen and been used
outside those additional $2 for were
wise it only state in
testing for the most part
really don't know the answer to that but
I do believe
those who think that nuclear basically
nuclear if you if you if you accept the
the pieces this war is a racket
in the war is a wave of looting
populations both the
for making population in the war victim
populations
then nuclear
was a wrong turn because nuclear
all the sudden was a lose-lose
proposition
and so I think the powers-that-be said
Oh shit
we made a mistake we should never gun
nuclear
and I I was in a in a harvard class with
other sess including can manhandle was
the had a Venice a one-point
and we were play-acting congressional
testimony
and someone playing acting a senator
said
so how can we be sure we will win the
nuclear war and the perfect class answer
was from this one guys that senator
there are no winners in a nuclear war
on and I think that was the right answer
I think the
powers-that-be understand that which is
why low-intensity conflict became so
popular
because it's a proxy that can be managed
a nuclear war gets
outta control too quick all it's one
thing for the the powers that be to
choose not to do it but what about like
Tucson a rational person going to a
country where scarred by barbed wire
fence and one guard
to just speared away the materials is
just dumb luck that that's not happening
are we just
or is it being actively being staff
now I don't think it's actively being
stopped except for the isolated
recall those FBI operation sting
operations
on
there is so much money to be made in
other ways
I just don't I can't give you any
speculative answer
it it comes down to only an idiot would
try to obtain
its get caught well i I always love the
annual Darwin Award such as the guided
sat in front of the microwave to be warm
you know
I mean nuclear stuff a and one of the
things we're worried about is
radiological
because you could contaminate you know
an entire city block for
a long time with with radiological
trash I'm really concerned that
pandora's out of the box and
and the only thing keeping a safe is a
modicum of legitimacy
and really were about to burst
legitimacy
bubble particularly in relation to the
United States as it's perceived overseas
I would not want to be an American
tourist traveling in a Muslim country
anytime soon because there are just too
many people
that did hot well they
you know I mean there's the america the
beautiful ideal there's there's the
american public
I think most people understand the
American public is a big-hearted public
but they're also fanatics who feel that
any american is a target
you know knows I don't have any answers
sir
so this is going to sound like a
softball question but it's it's
completely earnest
on because it's manifestly obvious that
you read prodigiously
so so there's only there's only so many
hours in a day how do you choose what to
read
it's a good question
I use to use to buy books at airports
in in I've been pleasantly surprised by
how good
the this election has been but when I
got hooked on Amazon
and I was an accident I basically
my first book was just gonna be an
opinion piece
and then a couple I said no this is the
reference work you need to do an index
and they said also
you need to do an annotated bibliography
because you've read all the books
so so I did one and it was a 150 entries
and then I did my second book it was a
150 entries in an Amazon reviews opened
up so I loaded all three hundred one
weekend like April 4th something
April 4th 2008 was instantly one of the
top 1500 people out other
1600 where on and so
I didn't really think much of it but
then I was invited to speak to a buncha
parliamentarians in Europe and I was
intimidated sorry rate fifty books
arm and review those as always keeping
notes
and now it's Kanika the habit and since
I had my own company and
in on a good year would make 1.7 million
was nothing spent five thousand books
so I would generally read two books a
week more or less
and I i have to say above those books a
third of them I start with the index and
and work my way to the footnotes a third
of them might
really kind i read the book but fairly
quickly in a third of them I just
scanned over the book in like for
instance the
the 2600 book in the the Emmanuel book
it took me less than an hour to kind of
develop an appreciation for that book
and then publish something that would
help other people say they're
gotta own it so I certainly did not read
every word in that book but
enough to do good review
so I think
its what
okay was that a farter
birth now now we've got
26 minutes on
basically an average book I can read it
for hours
so early talkin you know two hours a
night four nights a week
and there was a time when I did a lot of
traveling I was a double gold card on
American
United 94 to 97 and so
I would read books on airplanes and in
hotels and
and stuff on and now is for picking my
books
%uh the Amazon feature that when you
look at one book it tells you what other
people have looked at what other people
have bought that's actually pretty good
Amazon recommendations to not work for
me
but when I stunts one book and that's
the other thing I generally
books and twos and threes so for example
when I decided to look at climate
AXA gone the whether makers and one
other book and so I read like three
books at the time
menopause for dummies there were two
other books on menopause okay
I actually wrote the memo on menopause
if you will go look for a steal
memorandum menopause
you'll get two pages shit every man
needs to know what the age of 30
its
free here you didn't get them you didn't
get the memo
that's RTFM probably
he didn't pay enough for me to spend
eight hours being tortured by you guys
but up no I can't remember what the memo
says site I just remember that
I didn't get it in time to save my
marriage so
you know but it's useful information and
and you should
you should read that memo
okay I have two questions a short one
and a long one K
short question among books have you read
the works Sun Woo
no okay he created a
book about 2,000 years ago the art of
war
I'll send zoo yeah on your own you young
tomatoes tomatoes the long question is
this: imagine a world for a moment or
nation
where direct democracy does take root
prospers flowers blossoms
and everybody runs the country through
managers like congressman mayors Council
men inside edge
how would you you were put in charge of
the nation's spy networks in such
how would view protect the country
an open-source open democracy manner
adhering to the words of Sun Woo to
protect our country
Sunwell I mean the most important thing
he said was the acme of skills to defeat
the enemy without fighting
what that really means is don't have
enemies
I mean the American government has done
everything possible to piss off just
about everybody on the planet
and that's just plain estupida we've
also then gone on to do everything we
can to arm everybody on the planet
including the Taliban including the
shiites and and everybody else
on and then we've gone on to basically
dumb down our population and disarm our
population
so for me what it boils down to and I i
calling this term in the nineteen
nineties
is cast a wide net you absolutely have
to pay attention
everything all the time and we didn't
get a chance to talk about fourth
generation warfare
but I've done some slides that go all
the way up to the seventh generation
and I've written a book and a monograph
it's called information operations
all information all languages all the
time
basically the best way to protect the
nation is to educate the citizenry in
turn every citizen into an intelligence
professional
someone who consumes and produces and
Galax
intelligence or actually information
that can be converted into intelligence
as and when needed I mean snails
St Vincent's cell crashes great little
book
and and what he didn't understand was
that combining CA in the library
congress was the worst of all possible
worlds
because you know one is da man the other
one is totally messed up
would send free group
are sold for me I really believe in 90
I really believe that if work to get out
of this mess we have to become a smart
nation I wrote a book called the smart
nation act
public intelligence Republic interest
and i've to find
how I would legislate a smart nation
and what it boils down to is the party
goes the legal ethical understanding
and the party goes to educating citizens
so that they
are in fact the brain Housing Group for
the government
we should never ever have allowed
staffers and political appointees to
become the thinkers in our government
because that's not what they do
very well
on if you go back in time to like when
democracy first came to fruition you
basically had a a caste system where you
had
a group of people that said around the
forum debating whatever they need to
debate
and then you had basically entire
population those with no rights
tending the fields and supporting you
know those people that the right for
them to set their debate the wealthy
landowners ur
really have to be how do you how do you
create a society where
you know the world needs ditch diggers
and people who
can pump gas to make sandwiches and you
know everyone deserves to have their cup
of knowledge fill but
some people have very large cups and
some people have tiny thimbles
so how does that work
going back to Duran one other things he
says
is in the lessons of history is it the
only revolution that is sustainable is
the revolution in the mind of man
and one other things are really believe
is that
and I have certainly not been good
practitioner
I have been arrogant and I have been
angry and I have been
disdainful but the bottom line is
everybody deserves dignity and everybody
has a point of view that deserves to be
heard
and when we reach the point where we can
listen to everybody and come together
and decide something without killing
each other
that's what we will have become
unconscious civilization
and I'm not sure word that far from that
but I'm also not sure will reach that my
lifetime
but we're definitely moving in that
direction and
just back to you say real are are these
are there any like
things that we recommend that everyone
should read
my reviews I'm serious I mean you should
never buy a book without checking to see
if i've reviewed it
yeah no I'm serious and and then
my advice is to read twenty of my
reviews for every book that you buy
I'll save you a lot of money aka a
comment on the last
question about how to I guess give
everyone that
sustainable world on the dot said
movement in russia is a good example
with the Russian government basically
said anybody who wants land its Russian
citizen
can have a gentle and and you do
whatever you want with it
you can't sell it you can make money
from that but you can live on in that
can be your families kids two main
and and this really interesting results
I think we can all really benefit if you
take a look at that system
it's interesting the other thing I've
been reading about recently is
multi-generational trusts
leverage compound interest to avoid
the inherited generation from
diminishing the trust and
using up the inheritance
we've we really I think we've really
failed
to leverage our knowledge to create a
world that works for all and I really
I mean I'm not particularly inclined to
say
reincarnation is is a fact that I think
there's some interesting ideas there and
I feel buckminster fuller every time I
think
on because he said that our task was to
make a world that works for all using
technology resources that exist today
I think I think we can do that which is
wasting too much
which is which is killed ourselves
so as a Canadian from
Toronto sure your in a i think is an FBI
jacket lol
I a at the guns hidden but also in the
ceiling later
and I governor see that's under a time
no
the
reconfiguration trains everywhere
this city currently for me seems like
it's a it's a melting dying city
and my go to Buffalo its it's the same
thing it's it's at it seems like we're
and
were at the end at least for those two
cities their their city state
possibilities
and the person I love is also coming
a got it right every every year also and
the person I love it is from Michigan
in in North Flynn and its we're at these
big beautiful cities that massive
steel structures that are all just
slowly melting and if you're in a room
at the Hotel
and you know it's its at the melting
room that's
in 10 years this is going to be slaw on
wait where do large cities fit into the
the future well
I'm I'm certainly not the original
thinker on this but I've seen some very
interesting suggestions
return all these office buildings in the
condos
and basically
create cities where people live and work
in the same building and
we green all these buildings and then
somebody sees maybe need to be
me be abandoned her or there's actually
a lot of literature on how we need to
terrible the strip malls
and and put all that concrete in the
landfill
and and basically restore the whole
concept of local sustainable agriculture
he also deep fruit farming
Allen yeoman's written a wonderful book
copper 31
on I don't have all the answers but I
think there are a whole bunch of things
we need to stop doing and that's a
starting point
yes sir ya know can we turn on this Mike
up front okay I just gone back to that
one
please um
you a have any impact on Lake
intentional communities
her to know that sir %uh no I'm assuming
that you're an upgraded former commune
your business yeah no I don't but I need
Tom at lives in one
and and again I say I come back to this
whole thing that we've we've destroyed
humanity
line of Tiger did a wonderful book
called the manufacture
evil which is basically talked about how
the movement away from
kinship cottage industries toward
manufacturing turned people in the
commodities
basically destroyed the single most
important thing in the hidden wealth
nations which is trust in and
relationships
overall intentional communities
I'm E are sorta failing but
for the same reasons that everything
else is failing so they can provide an
answer
with the same shit consciousness that we
where we've been talking about
but there are some intentional
communities they're doing well in the
similar to the Dutch movement all those
are two things but it exactly what
you're talking about cans means that
kinda stuff
I can tell where you guys down I think
we can do like three more questions
maker 8 o'clock thing here
said as a as execute this rowing because
um
one their disease be essential conflict
here because on the one
on the one hand on technologies an
essential part
up creating wealth in creating
prosperity for everyone's agreed but on
the other hand
arm most or all of the high-technology
that we benefit from today's produced by
industrialized economy
so how does that square with with
restoring arm
trust and community to as they were
before industrialization essentially
destroyed them well
there there's let me answer that on
multiple levels all levels the first is
we were completely unaware most of us
love the
the high-tech trash in the toxins and
and so forth
I think we need we really need to
understand the true cost in
and true contents have everything a
second
I think that we really have failed
to focus on connecting humanity and
I mean I see the day when every
individual as an embedded cell phone
all bit is also a memory aid
recorder in a little bit on and
at hackers in Silicon Valley over 15
years ago we talked about how human
reputation was going to be the commodity
in the future
and that individuals who basically
establish karma points on
X were churchill would rewarded
and look to mom again technology the
problem
is that there's two kinds of
technologies there's tears
information communications technologies
which
Michael O'Hanlon this point it out as
the only revolutionary technology out of
all the technologies that the Department
of Defense is developing
energy doesn't even come close and
second there are technologies
that we should question such as air
conditioning entire cities
rather than using a simple buckminster
fuller construct which if you have
the the bottom of the 10th open any have
the two with the topic chills
to like 15 degrees mom
with send yeah
I mean to all of this is is we need to
be much more conscious and
I I think the court comment on
technology is we
really need to understand all of the
all of the implications of that
technology all
tell II don't I don't see a conflict as
much as I see
challenge
on he's a good guy
and i've reviewed his book The
Singularity
but anybody that does 245 whatever is a
day and tests blood twice a day is
absolutely a super geek
now it's up to 400 in the book it talks
about 200 but
you know I mean the thats obsession
yessir I'm not the mikes down on
apparently
okay I
alright everybody come up front and hold
hands
and we'll sing Kumbaya and then to close
the day at a perfect perfect fashion
yes sir right the
them be
you month
for Turner law
comes from this box chrome
you what's left
like what's left for people to fight
over nor you about the gay if technology
gets to the point where
everyone wants for nothing then a I mean
philosophers foresaw this many years ago
and and the force of the challenge you
using our leisure time on and I don't
have the exact quote but I i have seen
in Austin and
in depictions a Benjamin Franklin
talking about how
his generation had to do the military
art so that the next generation
do mathematics the next generation could
do you know
humanities eventually ended up with
poetry up but
the whole point here is the one and
exhaustively resource we have is the
human brain
and I think that
I don't think we're ever going to be
out of challenges particularly if we do
try and
looked outer space in the cosmos and all
that
others also inner space we haven't even
begun to explore the sea
we haven't begun to explore the under
terrain stuff
so I would be thrilled if we got energy
and there are people that say that we
have extra terrestrial technologies that
solve the energy problem that we're
keeping under wraps
we also have pizza indestructible
engines will run you know on on water I
mean it's just amazing to me
that we have allowed capitalism
to really pervert the whole idea of
common property and shared interests
and so I think what we were really need
to do is
is take a close look at all over
conventions because I think many other
conventions throughout the day
well i i the questions about my crew
credits I think micro everything is very
cool
on especially if you can reduce the
transaction cost
to almost nothing like an SMS message
yes sir
on
no I I have not written in that area but
but my
book for ten dollars which is still
available in about six copies outside
on is a is does talk about a global
range appears stable
and the whole idea there is to connect
individuals
at the item-level at the flyswatter
level
and cut out the intermediaries thats
intelligence for
earth clarity diversity integrity and
sustainability that's a ten dollar book
yes love money slow food so everything
I mean that's that's good it would be
very hard for me to adjust but
but vermont's got a lot of people with a
lot of common sense
yes sir now wait a minute we got seven
minutes ago
do we want to spend the seven minutes
kinda self-identify
okay
do you guys wanna tell me who the hell
you are okay
on me who's in the room I open source
warfare
him well I'm not a software guy
soul I'm not doing anything an
open-source warfare
what are you thinking about them
my kids okay
global Correa's for what for forward
finding information haven't read it
on mmm you know one other things is
really distressed me
I mean what when I first started this
open source intelligence was in the
evening Google
on and now of course its its millions
and millions of hits of which I own at
least 30,000
on but so many people have been so quick
to pick up on
on terms like information operations
cyberwar
in all this and they build multi-billion
dollar budget surrounded and they
do with a ser recalls virtual
engineering which is
code for lie like a mother fucker in
your your briefings and then get money
in
and fake it on and
up it's distressing how many people are
touting themselves as open source
intelligence you know this and that and
so forth
mom I think one other comments that I
would end with is that the intelligence
process consists every quirements
definition
you have to know what you need to know
why collection management you have to
know who knows
and and how to go get it source
discovery and validation i mean to us or
should be like it artwork for you know
the Providence if that source you know
the biases in the personalities and
and so forth multi-source fusion
compelling presentation
timely actionable delivery on this is a
process that is not secret
and the problem that we have right now
is most people are not doing
rigorous intelligence process and most
people are not doing
rig research discovery and integration
they're basically doing fly by night
you know quick as he can. stuff and so
they're missing a lot and most people
are not working in the war the one
language
and so when you go look at the view the
Spratly Islands
my vision is I wanna see the Philippine
Vietnamese Chinese and Australian
views on any different issue on one
screen alright just
going back to saying before in reference
to re
things being suppressed in the last
year's example about which apparently is
accurate from
I could is back this far because the
sixties
date figured out of all things a dental
decay back vaccine that pretty much stop
it
forty started it was pure ever call it
festers we're talking about it the other
things it was known
was documented Annika totally swatched
because with
pretty much kill a helluva lot of
business for dentists you learn about it
after that
another example of freedom from but
before the debates whatever
well let me let me take that big is it a
really raises two points the first is
then home
the the whole issue of fluoride in water
yeah I didn't realize separates it's
like it's like in alone on
waste product right and and
okay and so so you know why I am we
figure this out this number one number
two
from the tomato growers just work up in
arms over
over efforts to control the amount of
illegal immigration that they
were exercising but eventually they
develop tomatoes that could be processed
by machines and
everybody advanced here
and so mmm I think
I think we really underestimate the
adaptability of individuals we
underestimated after bility of society
enemy machiavelli had every right
although there's much about machiavelli
I don't like
when he said that on the
the people who were touting new methods
have no supporters
where is the people who were beholden to
all methods have all the supporters
and so is it really is a crisis that
that is needed and that's why the
Chinese revolution for crisis is also I
think a symbol for revolution i mean for
opportunity
so I I don't know I I've got this now I
know what I
do I've got one of these for everybody
in the room okay
if you don't have a on it's a membership
card 58 Ohio to
girl and and the troll principles from
the sun sea on a
Institute around the back and the first
one is motivation based on love and I've
worked my way up to number two which is
really important an attachment outcome
I really think that no matter what
happens it's gonna be okay
and we're gonna figure it out and I
would bet on humanity every single time
incidently actually done before it
actually the worst you may realize
because first awarded in studies in
other countries which naturally in the
water if it went down there wasn't
yep they found little if any difference
in in dental decay all timidly
as wind and it gets worse because
the want meeting about for that your
bones to and teeth to take
up instead of summer the calcium which
belongs there now
florida is harder but it's more brittle
soap for
so even if there was a slight
improvement indicate which really isn't
you end up with teeth and bones that
break easier
is pretty much agreement back
no up
of point
quite quite quite a bit it's definitely
nasty business it's highly toxic not in
others they use
the said what if there is any benefit
its its in all rates would get the
benefit
drinking in water is just more on it
period it's a toxin it doesn't help
inside the body anyway
big scam with get the idea to scam
K if you will do me a favor let me get
to the front door
so that I can give each review one of
these the membership cards with the CIA
RFID chip
or you there and
or else someone come up day
year
here your job is to get
everything
ladies and gentlemen
congratulations the time is now aids
05 yeah this is officially the longest
hard
in a hacker conference history yeah
thank you very much robert
and also guys don't forget on your way
out please
tried to pick some up some trash clean
up the room because we're not sure if
hotel that I housekeeping is going to
get a chance to claim a lighting is
someone rated R I have one two three
four
567 89 I have him carts know what I
wanna do
is trying kinda given to the people who
spoke so everybody who s to ask the
question
kinda come up here and in all recognize
you
way
of
for
once again we have 100
thank you very much should be in
information security content provided by
www media archive stock
comment www.pbr cardstock CB
thank you for watching up