and ho said
pennsylvania is a small suburb out of
Pittsburgh
and I it's affectionately known as the
rust belt
because the entire economy of the area
relied on steel manufacture on
to sort of sustain itself and in the
eighties I
that industry went away and that's when
I was born
so there was no way my parents were
going to
be able to afford to hook me up with the
computer for
any cool gadgets or anything like that I
mean a a talk
probably 15-16 years for more is a lot
to make it possible
for my family did to a to
get the computer that I wanted arm even
though I put it on my Christmas list
I every year up until that point
I'm what was easily available to me
was pencils in paper and
I another sorta aspect of the area that
I come from
is that gang culture started to become
very very popular and that was a scene
that I obviously was not
I able to fit in with and there were
shootings
outside my house all the time when I was
5 I saw
on the police issued a guy in the back
of my head in a be my backyard
found when I was 12 grow back
killed in the alley behind my house we
moved
from the first place where I saw a guy
get shot remove the way
and down you know a few blocks away and
somebody got killed in the back my other
house
on and shortly after that my next door
neighbor the shy so
I was afraid to leave the house
no computer no online access lotsa
pencils and paper
and I basically just escaped in my room
arm drawing constantly um
trying to figure out how to our
basically make way I see in my head
appear on paper which I'm still not
successful at
but it's getting closer on I
and I also escaped and in comic books I
really I
enjoy the idea of telling stories of
paper with words and pictures was kinda
magical to me on
you know you look at one image in the
next image and there's a passage of time
that intuitively takes place
arm without any sort of exposition or
dialogue like you know five minutes
later tennis later anything like they
like your brain scan process information
in its a
it's a communication attacking
communication tool that sorta has been
around on
since late cave paintings and stuff like
that I mean
I we've been telling stories the
pictures forever
arm at a certain point
I E in high school on I start again
a little bit better at arm drying in
making comics and I ended up going to
art school
are not too far from here actually arm
and really
sorry to pursue the idea of telling
stories with pictures and words
and thankfully I kinda bet my life on
the idea that comics could be considered
are a a viable former literature
that arm could express
any sort I love subject matter it didn't
have to be like
this superhero shit with our guys in
tights and
flying around punching bad guys the
walls and stuff like that I mean I kinda
like summer that stuff too
wat found in Japan
there are comics manga
that on explore any sort of subject
matter you can imagine there are
there are among the four housewives
who you know group regularly go to at
the grocery store
and that's what the stories about 10
there are among about fishermen in
all sorts of subject matter I'm this
idea is catching on
and I America and
sorta in tandem with my
coming to the gene Tom
actually developing the ability that to
draw comics in a in a reasonable way
on bookstores and
academia have even to a certain extent
on accepted the idea of comics as
more than just escapist fare
forearm four dudes who live in the
basement or were in a myspace matter
what I
I'm when I was about 20m
21 22 years old I really started
submitting my work two different
companies
to our to try and get some more
professionally
drying comics which what I've always
wanted to do
and like I said I sorta bet my life I
itself
we'll see how that ends up in a couple
years I'm
and I i kinda got rejected from most
other publishers just the stuff that I
was doing a just
VM the writing doing catch up with the
for work
arm and its so the stories were a little
juvenile law and
is not very good on I sent a lot of the
stuff to
various cartoonists who I his work I
appreciate it
am just for some sort of feedback figure
out what the heck I was doing wrong
because I was trying my best blah blah
on and I sergei some interesting
responses
I'm whether those responses was from
Eiseman in Harvey Picower a fire
American Splendor
it's wonderful %ah
and yet he he passed away Monday
I'll which really sucks I
and this is this right after the
American Splendor movie came out
on so he was at at sorta the height of
his fame
and I was looking through some old
American Splendor comics I've
appreciated his work pretty much my
entire life
and I thought I the artwork was lacking
in a lot of
those strips arm
and that on one of these American
Splendor comics I had
it was like a facsimile the cover was
like a facsimile
time magazine who cover with up for
Travis face not try it was a photograph
and you know when you subscribe to a
magazine there's that like on mechanical
type that has your subscription
information like
landed on it well it had his like a
fellow version of his
subscription information like his name
an address on the cover this thing
and I was will like wondering you with
is this
address still valid or did this guy move
to a to a castle in beverly hills or
something like that
so wire just through my routine of
sending
my failed comic strips to
various cartoonist whose work I
appreciated
and I started sending
less trips to that address not really
expecting that it was his real address
or anything like that
and I didn't hear back for a while arm
and the after months and months of just
sending
maybe 50-60 packs love
strips like every month
on a gotta phone call
from P car and I like I said this is
after the movie came out
and I had to drag some friends to go
check out this flick because
you know didn't get any sort of
arm any sort of fun commercial
distribution or anything like that in a
way there was no trailer on TV
for this flexo my friends really never
heard of it and it was a tough sale to
get them to come hang out with me i
didnt really wanna see it alone I don't
wanna be back kinda Peter
a and so I brought a couple buddies a
along
in when a peak are called my house he is
a very very distinct
groff Boyce and a
I have a buddy who could do i mean peak
or a person nation
and I thought to myself you know if this
is you HB column my buddies names HP
this is HB call me that this is the most
vicious prank
that you can pull on me because you know
I wanted to draw comics so much
and I didn't believe him at first when
he was on the phone and I expressed this
to a certain extent in his fight what
the hell you talking about is how
above the what can I do I've
I'm so it you know i i obviously I
believe them at that point and I'm
we corresponded of for like a year
before a any real actual work came down
the pike
and eventually we started putting a
project together and
called American Splendor our movie year
in a July 20 pages of this
like two hundred-page anthology book
on it was very cool um it at first day I
did like four pages
and and towards the end of the project
they needed
a quick 25 page story done in like under
a month
and when you drop comics I'm
you know that the standard size is
fairly small
but the original pages that you drawn
are pretty huge at least twice the size
of the final printed page so the work
that I was doing was about
11 by seventeen that's a lot of pencil
mileage as they call it
and it takes a long time to do a page of
comics
are so after doing our move your stuff I
E
he and I set to work on a low form
graphic novel called massive Donia
on that you know receive some mixed
reviews because I mean this subject
matters little
a little complex in crazy on it's a it's
about the geopolitical destabilization
in the Bakken region
if you're interested on
ants you know he adapted this work from
I a woman's thesis at
University California Berkeley so it's
very very
heady to sit to say the least on any any
way when I was working on that project
IOM
assertive ran out of all DVD audio
commentaries that I was listening to I
memorized everything I was tired i've
every piece of music that I had access
to you
on I really a mess around with like to
peer to peer stuff at that time or
anything like that and I
really know about it on
podcasting really starting to become a
thing and
I was added to get member tech TV rest
in peace tech TV
a star love that stuff and then you know
that
that channel one away and and those are
the people from taking feel a lil afford
they started
podcasting so that I was introduced to
the two that idea
and I happened upon off the hook
on you know was tagged under hacking or
something like that
and packing is always something that
I've
romanticized in my mind on
it's something I A thought about and I
movie
ideas that I had about Hagel who were
certainly ideas that were put my head by
mass media
arm that movie where Ferris Bueller I
you know hacks into you
the the the government computers in
order at or something like that in
0 cool and all that bullshit
um when I came across off the hook
arm I literally was hooked on
and i ended up listening to the entire
twenty-plus year archive
of that show what you which I if if you
have time available to do this
on you know because usually I'm but I'm
sitting there drawing comics
all day I am the mass Dhoni graphic
novels like 150 pages
took me 14 months to do and an F
fourteen months I was able to listen to
all of the
off the hook up
archives on and if you listen to it all
you can fast-forward through the
fundraiser episodes and I'll tell them I
say
said that %ah
yeah there are some at BIC
sprawling stories that take place
with in that show if you listen to in a
linear fashion
on and is so much so that there is high
drama
that took place on this show on it's my
belief
that show should be our public in the
smithsonian I i feel that it is so
important
because on it really captures a moment
in time
where just that government was so
not that there were any more you know I
in the know nowadays but they were so
clueless
back then and its it's laughable and
on you know just you to follow the
history of high technology
through that show on there is like an
episode where a man was like
know if you go to your local community
college
sign up for one class and you will have
access to the Internet
its amazing I'm
and just you know buy it buy his
privileged position to as being
publisher 2600 he obviously had access
to some
really interesting personalities I
within the community
and day have you guys listen to a lot of
that show a mic
de my telling something you got
something that you already know
um where I was fascinated by the stories
are flake
Bernie s where you know he is on the
show for years
and then eventually he's like pinched by
the cops
and he's not on the show the the United
that
that week or whatever and then he's on
the show again talking about his
upcoming
case and then he's gone again
at Denny's in jail and they he they
figure out an elaborate away
for bernie to call Emanuel's house and
have their number I'll medically
forwarded
forwarded to WBAI because
it sort of gets a rules for bernie to
call the radio station /a br/
broadcast by that's a good tricky
workaround
and he was like on the show from Joon
you heard like a little be
every every I couple of minutes that to
let you know that the
calls being recorded or whatever this
this is our
fantastic story fodder on
fiber-optic who was on the show
for do for you know years before
the forearm other stuff from
what will masters of deception ever read
that book on
the stuff from masses and inception took
place
and then up fiber had a court case
and he was still on the show but it
became weird to me because he was
allowed to really talk about anything
when before he is just
very I who is very happy to speak about
any so love number of things he
was kinda flaked his lawyers advising
the childish trap
Lake about these particular issues with
our regarding this case
and then he went to jail and
the sheik they they played a show but
like the day before the
took 'em to prison and
it was emotional I was sitting there
drawing a little comics like dropping
tears on my paper
I'm because this poor kid are
is going away for a year I mean I was
there was unbelievable to me and the kid
is a i mean
you note you got to know him as much as
he let you
get to know him by listening to the show
and on you know so fiber disappeared in
because he was in jail and Emanuel
continue the show with a few other
people here and there
on and then they the the year goes by
you know enough in a matter of like a
week if you're listening to twenty
episodes a day or something
and you know they play I rude boy is out
of jail by the specials
on during the show where they're
bringing fiber back
to Manhattan after he's out of jail
you know that after his release and it
was epic Amin it was
it gave me two tickets give me chills
just thinking about it
on obviously the mitnick stuff was
really interesting
another interesting thing about I off
the hook when I was seeing
drunk on its all day listening to the
show was that
arm I and the annual whenever a new
book online hacking or specific more
specifically on particular hackers like
porcelain
mitnick fiber-optic in those guys
on Emanuel would it be able
would have access to interview these
guys about them for the work
and so after listening to the entire
archive
that arm I decided to skip to explore
those books there are at the local
library
and you notice upon further research in
reading
on I A come across like
work like people and tap frack
2600 I all sorts matter in a
I'm just as all just reading for
pleasure arm certainly inspired by
interesting stories
that I've passively listen to while
with I'll you know absorbing I love the
I off the hook archive
and I start develop these
and I felt it psychologically
a lot of the more sort of observed
hackers that were written about on the
at the All Share
fairly similar psychological traits as
far as I could tell this may know
in true-life might not really be the
case it probably isn't
on but I answered a lot of similar cycle
psychological traits
and to be honest a lot of the same
mental energy
mental energies I kinda fun
identified with as being an obsessive
crazy cartoonist who
I never sleep either and I'm constantly
working
in the same way these guys are costly or
our energy is just
split in different ways and maybe if I
had access to such
technology when I was younger first you
know your formative years are big deal
to cover your formative years for a
reason
and for some reason I just really
identified with
these guys a benign a romantic way like
anything I was like a call fugitive or
you know a suburban MacGyver or
something like that
I just on I really can't explain
articulate like how I
really identified with with on these
individuals
with their mindsets when I played on but
I did
and on I sort of had this idea like
you know I really wanna do my my own
comic that I'm reading in trying myself
because I was working with peak are I've
just drawing for a couple years
and I felt like
through osmosis a reading all this
information
and listening to the off the hook show
and all that sort of stuff
honor that in terms of being a
cartoonist this
this is a story I could tell that
arm probably no other cartoonist could
because maybe the
you must these guys are not interested
in such stuff I'll
maybe they don't have a four the for the
fortitude to listen to twenty-plus year
archive of this radio show
arm whatever the case may be I decided
to maybe take
the stories is that the most interesting
parts have all
I love the hackers that I was reading
about and create a kind of pastiche
snare it have I compiling all this
information into
one character in seeing what would
happen
if he live the lives I love
wake a young mitnick Poulsen fiber-optic
Bernie s
all these people II in one
body so that's sort of how is the week
developed
and arm I i set to work to put put the
comp get I sort of had an idea of
the audience and I it was weird because
I really didn't expect
anybody tit to dig it I thought I was
gonna be like the one volume I i kinda
left it is like a cliffhanger
just in case people found it sort of
interesting or something
arm and
it for some ways I I did it as it was
calling many comic winning many comic is
is basically
like you're you're a your hope program
book it's just like in a half mile in
peace taking paper
folded in half that's initially
what was the way it was arm just really
there
the card many comics & in the biz on
n/a make money xeroxes is no big deal
it's like a dollar day to make the
things Angela for
a dollar fifty years something on
and just saw the way I like it was
getting to be nearer and nearer
christmastime and wonderful was asking
you know what do you want for Christmas
and I could I think anything so I was
just like you know it
how about if I no really plug away
and it put this who put together would
you
by Neil a a hundred copies at this thing
arm
you know it's a print-on-demand place
and you know she
said yes and so christmas comes along
and
I receive this box actually like five
boxes are
these 100 with the wake volume 1 comics
and I it kinda the kinda fucked my head
up
because I was located now I have a whole
lot of like a excuses for insulation
and my bedroom or something like what am
I gonna do it they ship
I'm I mean I could give a couple copies
way to my friends in the there then
there's still
ninety copies I'm I had no idea what to
do with these things
whatsoever and I just sort of had the
idea of maybe
you know I listen to all these podcasts
and surly off the hook in
things like that and on you know they
certainly inspired the work
in a big big way so maybe they would get
a kick
out of checking these things out or
something so you know I sent 12
2i the 2600 PO Box
and sense stuff too the different
podcasts
that I am that I've enjoyed and listen
to allow while I was working on
illustrations are comments or whatever
and then what started to happen was on
I surgery to receive orders for
for the a the comic say I just just
email
at emails KK man like you know it do you
have these for sale
and I think a manual took 'em took
with the way to like the 2600 meeting
locally here
and on little reviews here and there
started pop up so
just II generally have then the
knowledge or are they
the serve on I I didn't have much of an
idea on
how tit to sell the stuff online I
didn't know about leach
shopping carts another so I dislike set
up a simple paid how
button on my website and down
and if these things just started to sell
it was kinda interesting
on on the a E the been Rev
forums II kinda wanted to let those guys
know but I sort of felt like I was
spanning
and I i sorry let them know that I had
this project
that I didn't I had a whole bunch been
online
and all these orders start to come in
and when the people who ordered the
comics was I Jason Scott
he ordered the stuff animal I was blown
away because I use his site for
reference when I was creating the work
on and I we're told him this
and he was like whatever did this not
any it's our can influence
you know your nice words not an
influence my review
arm so I started to kinda like shit
because my column and if there's like
you know 5 reviews and Jason Scott Hall
people's
says that my my work is crap then these
hundred books are just going you know
the seventy books I have read just gonna
sit here forever
I've he reviewed favorably and
a lot more orders came in and then this
guy and in the
bail Bioware waxy da Torre keep read a
little something and we're orders came
in
and I the guys at at the revision at
revision3 like
there's a show called the Totally Rad
show and pack 5
on those guys get a hold of copies and
they reviewed and then
more more thing so arm Boing Boing
listed
the comic-con their site a few times in
more more copies sold in Wired magazine
did a piece
to is steven levy who's hackers book is
awesome in the celebrating its 25
his twenty-fifth anniversary that book
if you haven't checked out some for
everybody get
a cities like all these weird things you
start having to stand
I was kinda like in all watching
watching like word-of-mouth travel and
thought it was very interesting
on and I was getting rid of
these conduct and it when I would do is
get rid of those and then
maybe order another one hundred and then
get rid of those in
just keep going and going and going and
then it soon became obvious to me that I
can continue this project
in people like there's enough people who
are interested in it who are
who wanna see where the stories going in
people were emailing me asking me
you know what happens next it's its
kinda the tease at the end
on sewing you know will come up to the
third volume a day the
its with the wake is over
it's good it's supposed to be a before
book series but it's really is one story
but each volume arm
handles a an individual part love the
hackers laces like the first
volume is called freak and it
specifically telephone stuff
I'm in at the end he gets his first
trash eighty
and died the second one this hacker and
deals with like the early days at the
BBS is
on ARPANET to internet stuff
arm war dialing and in things like that
and then that certainly miss
fugitive which is its it's not really a
romantic
portrait I love what it must have been
like for a hacker to be on the Rhine II
SAWW
arm did other research outside of
hacking
ass have like many couples in to to
figure out like white
it's really like to be a future in that
shit sucks I mean
I tips or to pick up from your family to
always at Texas or have to think of
yourself as a different person I mean
it's
you probably better off just going to
jail or something
& the nu-notes sustained yourself are
and I've yet it to put a the final
volume together arm
bites you'd that that's pretty much with
the wake on
II through through arm getting talked
about on point where that no Corey
doctor a little bit he sorta hit me too
at Creative Commons and are
that idea makes perfect sense to me to
serve increase readership increase I've
also there is a
is a PDF of the first two volumes on
that you can find Addai
at my website at his core dot com on
and you need to check those out I life
recently figured out
ways to make like smaller files file
sized
I like CBR files which seemed to be a
what people like three
arm this or to the program that people
like to read comics online with
on so wanna upload that at some point on
but through the Creative Commons
aspect I rule when doctor let people
know that I put this PDF out there like
thirty thousand of them got diluted
like during that that like tonight
after arm and I it's it's it's been a
really cool thing
on the response within the community has
been very
very are favorable add to it a large
extent there's a lotta
I N Acronis text after I did in the
story that if you're a purist
or very strict on my end
you know they they the factual aspect
over everything you're probably
be disappointed because I wanted to
switch certain things are a just to make
a story that was interesting to me on
so I'm aware that fact and some people
were a little weirded out by it
on and I you know last year I was
I was i asked to us speak at nada con
which is my first
hacking conference I ever been to
anything like that I was
terrified because just reading people's
comments not about my work per se I'm
online but just in general like flame
wars that would happen and I
with kinda freaked out because these
people obviously you know speak their
mind in
on you know went when he saw me face to
face the world they were just gonna let
me have it or something if they
didn't agree with something and I have
found that was the case in ivory base is
very positive
on though the one negative comment I got
personally
ways in the elevator and not a crime on
I saw bernie ask you to get on the
elevator and my little named hey
you know it had my name on it and I
recognize that it was bernie is because
I solomon freedom downtime
and I referenced him in one panel in the
first with the way book
and arm he he saw me and he said
to score here the guided the dow comic I
have a bone to pick with you
and I I got freaked out on
in in the Wired article the way they
should the one panel that bernie was
referenced
and its arm there's a there's a a
strip were its
it's called the misadventures of Stephen
Steve that I put in their end
our its Steve Jobs and Steve Wozniak but
I
you know I don't include their names a
but I have been dressed up as a marcia
panels from that moment
I have them dressed up in there like
Alice in Wonderland outfits because they
work at like a local more
on as you know it the Mad Hatter and the
White Rabbit
and so Steve Jobs's is on this pay phone
tie and you know the so blue boxes and
I'm
jobs is talking the one in the act like
yeah I have this guy bernie in
Philadelphia he wants to buy three these
boxes from Earth
so bernie catches me into an elevator
and he is like you make me seem
so lame I have to buy these things
I made these things before they knew
would blue boxes were
and I was I was like mortified
because I was this guy's axle
mythologized im in a big way
and say the section of the story that I
wasn't
really didn't bike I I was able to
squeeze an incall
bernie as references at that point but
you know it that certainly is gonna
change when characters in jail with
some bullshit he went there but I wanted
to give at least a little nod
to him in that first book in SF only
place a good thing to like squeeze it in
and I it meant it with affection and I
with a with with with positive fives
and I sorta little know this and I i
think he saw how bombed-out I was when
he like
when he when he said that to me and arm
and I have you know at this last night a
kind he and I shared a bed
are hey
by not her head but on
you know yet we became very friendly
after that her head
I kinda dug myself a hole I'm
how we doing on time
wow I actually spoke for thirty-eight
minutes this isn't typical for me by the
way and a very very shy
and and I wasn't expecting to be able to
fix the filibuster this long
I'm does anybody have any questions or
anything like that's about this work
were whatever
up I was asking about the
future work that he might be due in and
arm
are you and about how that was the week
series was fictionalised
based on the 2600 which is all great but
arm
are you considering doing anymore
non-fiction type stuff for things either
based on
you know the true life stories or even
some in a more technical type hacking
stuff cuz I think you'd be good at that
I think slight and that's a good
question because and to be honest
initially I with the wig is a product of
me not being able to get in touch with
the actual hackers
to do I like I was very interested
in it telly in doing like a Bernie s
biography because
nothing sorta exists about him in his
particular situation
and he went through some bull crap you
know a lake I'm not sure everybody knows
but
when he was in prison he got the living
shit beat out of him
and he's got like a bionic arm now and
like
a wired jaw line in the end he got
completely
screwed up and and i really wanna tag
Ted do
a biography a non-fiction biography
about him but the only way that I would
ever do
a piece of non-fiction is if
I can work in collaborate with the
actual person
because I don't wanna participate in
creating something that's like that
takedown movie
that just is sort of skewed
and the opinion of one person and you
know for the inaccuracy said the reason
why I didn't do this fictional story is
I always feel like my comic is with that
takedown flick
should have been inasmuch as you know
they used mitnick's real name in you
know this ski
all rich played him in and it really
romanticized a lotta stuff and I think
the guy was still in jail
when the flick was being made in the end
they had this these
for drawn conclusions about how his
situation was going to end up in
existing fuckin
crazy that seemed like so on so
irresponsible
and evil and there either
in the in the was he would books like a
look at the end for the nine
v9r for the comic
crowd actually on I sir describe a lot
of
I S irv have and an annotated section in
the back
that lets people know sorta like some
other stuff I snuck in there
and I even feel bad about on including
people's names like Kevin Poulsen with
certain situations are kinda popular by
bike
if a but I didn't for myself here from
his mouth
said that it was factual and I feel late
now
sorta looking back on it I feel pretty
awful about then I am
I'm going to take that stuff out on
whenever I
put the entire story together or
whatever but are
but get like
II I would love to do apiece non-fiction
by
maybe waif with with you and out there
that would give me some sort of
arm legitimacy with with the actual
hackers
who whose stories I'm interested in and
maybe they would be
interest in working with me and if so I
would be more than happy to
by Tom you know I and I just don't want
to I have such
are such a positive feeling from
researching in and I
finding stuff out about the tax that I
don't wanna do anything negative
for a responsible with on these people
or you know with these people's lives
essentially and and perpetrate
messer anything like that another
weird thing that I really didn't intend
on is having like two different
audiences with with the way going i
really didn't think because I i just
imagine that people furry comics are
just people who creates it's like this
like match
and that's it and other people really
can be introduced to comments because
maybe eight years now and it's certainly
when I go to a comic shop in IC like
these aka Big Red Hawk
in Lake with these ripped muscles in
these
chicks with huge boobs and wastes like
this in a big way it's like
I it's it's too much it's like sensory
overload in and I could see why people
are turned off by the stuff
by Tom within the community that there
is a
a the audience it has developed from
from these comics which on very proud of
and on a lot of people are being
introduced the comics
for the first time through easy with
which I fill up huge responsibility for
because
and there are a lot of cartoonist his
work I hate in in the reason why I like
I have
such vile feelings towards him is
because their comic might be the first
comic that somebody reads
and it's shit and I don't want that to
be somebody's experience I believe this
is like my livelihood and I don't want
your first experience to be reading
something crappy
um but what has developed with these two
with these two different audiences that
the book as
its its it's a almost like a contrived
scheme that I developed
because with in the comics crowd they
find that the story is fascinating
interesting and to a certain extent I
mean I have the annotations in the back
describing like the real life
if answer technological things that I
serve
storefront and by
day they think that it's like a really
cool compelling story
and on with the packing crowded
technology crowd I'm very interested
in I the way the stories told
and I just or storytelling techniques
from my favorite cartoonists
so like in on both liking niche
audiences I have people typically think
a pretty cool
when all I'm doing is taking aim for
ants and like
stuff I learned from a whole bunch of
other people so basically I'm here to
tell you that I'm not original
at our but if you wanna check out my
comics
I wanna be I downstairs at the mezzanine
come for free take a look
and grab a sticker its ticket someplace
on
I'm gonna be serializing I the to work
on I decided to go back and re real
right
a lot of this the stop just to tighten
things up I feel like I'm
like as a kid when you're learning to
draw there's an exponential growth
that happens at a certain point where
you are drawing stick figures
and then you could draw passable stuff
that looks like more structured in
an awesome in that happens in a very
fast span
and while writing the wish he would
comics
I feel like I had that exponential
growth in terms of rating
from the first line to the third volume
that I felt like I had to go back
and taking things up so that it it kind
of like I
matches %uh the whole way through I'm
not saying Inc
I'm a great writer anything by the way
but it's it's better is it's gonna be
better than
there when I initially had and I'm gonna
be /c realizing that stuff at arm
I'll with the win comics dot com
and put up like two pages on
but about two pages a week of on
the story and you know take like maybe a
year and a half for something for the
the whole thing to to appear online but
on
yeah for free if you come come hang out
if you wanna check on your comments or
whatever
and does anybody have any other
questions or
comments or anything like that
if you do please step up to the mike
do you have a question sir cool
there's the mic
boo
pic am my question is more technically
how do you
have you what techniques to use for
drawing
and how long does it take you to use any
templates or
to you what kind of technique do you use
and how long did does it take you to
to make this is that say one panel okay
on via can bomb
on each page
of with the Wake is structured as iraqi
for panel
page kinda like the same structured as
the comic strips that you see
in our the newspaper and
those are I'm originally like five
inch by 5 inch squares each individually
on
takes me like a whole day to it to put
together a page
are those comics on the writing
sort of takes me for ever HS there so
much thinking
that goes be behind-the-scenes
that arm it like before I hit the final
page
with what I wanna do arm have today is
already passed
so then I dried and was like a a non
repro blue
color pencil because our when you're
playing covert op then you scan it
on ya see the pencil lines and it will
save me like maybe a year's worth the
time eventually
I've a racing on so I
each book took like probably close to a
year
to come to fruition because this is like
my moonlighting think on
I did the American Splendor stuff and
other comics with harvey
arm during the day arm I pieced together
with an income when all
weird sort of ways like by doing
speaking things and
doing illustration work in magazines and
stuff like that
was at ok on
by doing industry is so I would
have didn't have to do that stuff to Sir
live and
arm when normal people are spending time
with their loved ones
and while watching television or
enjoying life
then I it like go to the basement and
start working on my was %um comic
because that brings me the same sort of
pleasure that other people get
going fishing or watching football and
crap like that I'm so so I
I would love to work on a full-time on
but it is it is not a possibility
on so as it stands I each volume
has taken basically a year I
to come out are any other questions
USF up to the mike
i was just curious about the response
from the kinda traditional
a.m. comic book seen other
a lot of people like you said that they
they find a story
pretty and like really interesting and
it's sort of
the people who have decided to create
really opened up
there their mind to the idea of
when a hacker is another thing I wanted
to get across in the work
is sort of doing I'm my best not to miss
met is not to misrepresent what it means
to be a hacker assertively
was imbued with this idea by
the words have a manual Goodstein
throughout that entire archive
of off the hook where you know they were
that the term hacker started to mean
you know basically criminal and that you
know that seemed
extremely wrong in in the word has deep
roots
that that are very positive on
so there's response has been pretty cool
arm publishers were interested in the
work
icons publishers and its overall still
are and
they they seem to like where things are
going so maybe I'll have when these guys
distributed because I feel like
I've done everything I could in terms of
getting out there
that I could do on my own terms but but
maybe a at I don't know is %um
sir play around with the idea but
initially when I had this idea
because publishers a few guys were
interested in publishing my work and I
describe
with the wing when I wanted it to be and
I
they would would say stuff like you know
there sure are a lot of telephone
conversations net photo freak
section of the book Andale
are you fucking kidding me and and get a
these characters sure spending a lot of
time in front of the computer console
and you know i i certainly did not wanna
do won in the east
like I you know the kid types where the
keyboard in a satellite falls out of the
sky
your kind of kinda via you know the
hyper real
bullshit you know fictional pieces
garbage like that is not what I'm
interested in
so on but a bit as AC sort of the
audience said it that is
that is growing that I'm serve
cultivating I feel so Press speaking
this way to you by the way
it's it's all it's all happening by
accident on
by town the ISS or developing like the
publisher sure is showing up in our like
becoming more acceptable to the idea of
playing the sound like you know there
are people out there who would like to
see this thing in like a nice handsome
volume
as opposed to my like print-on-demand I
you know flimsy copies or whatever so
the response has been pretty cool
and I think that
them might be it arm so I'm gonna go run
down to the mezzanine
if you guys wanna come hang out
throughout the day I'm gonna be there
all day
are thanks for lending me your years
and thanks a lot for that I'll bed that
a little clapping ovation from my pal
har who passed away and i really
appreciate that
I know he went to yeah
do I use I was kinda like