the next in there more less than what's
up with less spend of
on how come I can't get enough let's
spend so forth
and I we're gonna hear all about the
answers those questions right now mmm
better dressed than I am
some people recognize this in
home
this is my third ho
my first presentation maybe sixteen
years
not at all either
page I just put the laptop around
only one he's good enough excellent
switch that perfect
no
good enough right you can read now looks
like crap
whatever thanks for coming to the stock
expected maybe a quarter the room
but it is 6 o'clock so sorry very
the stock is this field is linked to the
future
which could be a grumpy old this
person's
you're excited about aspect-oriented
programming to solve that twenty years
ago
but no one bothered aspin's onto the
information
title sounds like a pretty tall order
but history link speak for itself I can
give you
in the history of the language for this
to be a
worthwhile talk
maybe a little dense and content mister
wrote that before I
find out how long it takes to make it
slide hopefully there's enough content
in here
not care for you just might learn
something before it's there
I am sorry
is this better tackle louder
you know
maybe you know something about list pry
gonna say parentheses
may be sought a magazine article
when you come across in a program worker
program language surveys course
experimental in college either you
thought it was too complicated too
simple
to weird functional style isn't for
everyone
and most the languages to send from
alkyl and look like seein
UFC and pearl PHP it's all basically the
same
because it's old
fortran came out in 1957 was with 58 and
couple was 59 you know it's considered
when the classics
but because it's so weird and was
was slow for a while because the
hardware wasn't there didn't compile
very easily
into machine code Justin really catch on
it's been stigmatized
as being only for AI as is a bad thing
you would think it's for a are you can
use in everything but
here we go here's some nice quotes about
less is all come from
number of years ago when people reading
books about it has a
any resurgence now at first one is if
you give someone fortune yes fortran
which is true but if you give someone
list P as any language he pleases
and while this is in the afterward to a
a book about scheme
hope will be able to show you at least a
little bit how this might be possible
typically when you're reading program
unless you will write small functions
that do what you want and then you build
on top of it until
eventually you've built language towards
your problem instead have
in a lot of other languages where you go
back to the boss and say well we can't
deliver the sun-times
so let's cut this feature or well the
spec isn't really clear on this so we're
not going to do it that way
second quote here all problems in
computer science we solve another level
of indirection
the addendum is except for too many
layers been direction because this is a
functional programming language
functions are a first-class citizen
so phrase that bothered me because every
time I try to look it up
I'll just get more confused first class
isn't just means
that in the language a function is on
the same power as a variable
you can pass functions to other
functions functions can return functions
you can store function in a variable
name
although mister actually called symbols
not really variables last quote
also speaks to the the ability of you
too
right language how you want build your
little utility classes
and eventually you end up with something
that is ideally suited to solving
whatever problem you have
is indeed rather hot in here
his jacket isn't helping
but it's part of the stick home
I
so is it through the books that are used
for
this talk and in case I do a terrible
job
you can read them to the the one all the
way on the left is probably the gentlest
it's a a gentle introduction to symbolic
computation
if you've never programmed at all this
book is good
they don't even start with the West
syntax but the gradually introduce it
has a very good
explanation about recursion the nice
picture the can happen that's only in
the print version didn't make it into
the PDF
fractal coming this by a puter Sibel
maybe
the one of the reasons why there's a
recent upsurge in interest
in the language was published in 2005
you get a Google Talk but
in like it that much don't tell 'em and
an anti-communist by Paul Graham is
woodward hardcore live code in there for
ray tracer
and there's a good reference in their
for the common with standard
is the titles again
and then this last look at the bottom I
wish I had found earlier
but have twelve lessons in there the
basic go over everything
starting from the syntax
all the way up to macros and different
functions and
all that other good stuff
these are a little bit harder core from
the
when all the way on the left is the
but that was used to teach the m86 RR 1
class also known as the weather book at
the purple Booker sixty
on middles programs on West which is
really good if you wanna
really understand macros which I'll get
to later they're not like see macros
and when all the way on the right the
%uh paradigm
artificial intelligence programming is
probably the toughest evolve them
be a examples in Common Lisp
until the point where develops a Prolog
interpreter
then all the examples are in prologue so
missus this is mmm
so common list a gentle introduction
available online in PDF you can buy it
if you want Pratt Common Lisp available
it big monkeys dot com
slash book in C come on let's go up to
buy
I must disagree successful this
the for publishing dispute so that's
available free on his website
I'm sick P is available free at MIT
and they have a whole bunch of to
to have the lectures from 1986 at HP
I hope this classifies as fair use
yeah
so well
let me let me have a good few pages on
this but
you know this isn't the first time I've
tried to learn less
its like I mentioned before with the
first-class functions
first class citizens language if someone
doesn't explain it just right
you're stuck you never gonna progress
past a certain point without the
understanding and 30 physics teachers in
here
no okay maybe maybe you've come across
the phrase in a science textbook where
they're talking about neutron stars and
how
a teaspoon material way 10 tons
amazing but then they never explain it
you know it took me a
numbered years until I read a book by
Robert Castro
red giants and white dwarfs which I
guess was popular science in about
nineteen fifty-six but it never made it
into the tie-ins text books
so they could explain that when they
went to the periodic table
we don't have any elements their dense
enough to a 10 tons
that could explain what nuclear fission
no
what happens in a clap star is the
gravity in the pressure
compress everything so much to the
electrons get stripped of
you're you're familiar image min orange
in the middle of a football stadium
with the electron pair going round the
outside round the outside
that gets all smushed together
see all these other neutrons and protons
come together the elections get stripped
off to become a plasma
eventually the star gets dense enough
that it explodes and that's where we got
our heavier elements from
like I said they never explain that the
could done it
in five seconds missus always this hole
in my understanding
anyway back to list Saregama catch
phrase in
from
whenever the just in case something
terrible happens in your learn anything
from a speech line
so here's some misconceptions
hopefully I will
allay your worries about less I guess
it's good that
to let the the text on the bottom got
cut off because it's not just good for
AI
you can use it for just about anything
the other funny thing is
whenever problem is solved in AI it's no
longer a I
to some useful computer program we
thought the chess was intractable and
we've got machines to be very good at it
suddenly it's you know a whole bunch of
heuristics and up for searches and
you know once a trial in air
yeah no
these is kinda speak for themselves so
in the beginning was the lambda dateline
Princeton New Jersey 1936
mister missus American all the ships at
sea one's a church
was sitting at princeton along with
another interesting people like
could go to land other interesting
people
alan Turing's studied under him and he
developed the lambda calculus or if
you're studying formal
systems you'd say he discovered since
formal systems exist
be on anyone needing to perceive them so
lil bit later I think the year two later
Alan Turing worked out that the lambda
calculus was equivalent to his Turing
machines
they define the same class a function's
and were therefore for this along with
recursion makes up the church during
thesis which covers
things which the computer consoles even
though it's
it's still a thesis slash hypothesis we
can't prove it
there we're accepting it you know we
we've got all our computing systems on
it
look few years later 1958
John McCarthy invents list he was
part iv: a project to do list processing
not sure for what but months log tables
are military applications or whatever
and they try to do with Fortran
and didn't work out too well when the
problems was the
the conditional in Fortran require you
to evaluate the art
you know of both trees in the argument
regardless of whether you're gonna take
them or not
not generally a good idea
if you only want one of the things to
happen so
wanna weird things about the the syntax
is the prefix notation where you put the
operator in the front
a few arguments and this appeared here
you know we've been
doing math since kindergarten with the
operators in the middle
and which is fine if you're something a
few numbers but if you have a whole list
of 100 even after
put the place in the middle you know
what you screw up once
where's your bug no idea on
you can thank list and mister John
McCarthy for the conditional operator
fortunately had effin go to which worked
out pretty well for the
machines at the time but the funny thing
is that it was not
designed right away as a programming
language
was supposed to be way too axiom a ties
mathematics
that they could write expressions in it
proven mathematically through some other
system
and you know
to call Matthew things with eventually
the yes expressions are supposed to be a
lower form %uh
expression that you would write in med
expressions which took a little bit like
ask and the compiler which aims Mendes
expressions in the ass expressions when
it turned into machine code
there we go like that the
the project time frame was about two
years to actually get working compiler
until Steve Russell with him
was also at MIT realize that the valve
function
you could just coated up in IBM 704
and 20 code that it was
able to actually evaluate these s
expressions into
values suddenly we have a programming
language
little nerd the bottoms the Russells
wrote space for
I don't know what really popular means
in the context for 1958 1960
computers but over the years there were
whole bunch have
different dialects the developed
numerous incompatibilities between them
and run about nineteen eighty-four Kyle
still published
economist language book and that became
a major part love
the standard there was actually doctor
by and see
in scheme which came along in between
also helped
influence
parents so this you know made such a big
deal about India
description of the talk
these are some other features that new
may not be that
impressive but one conditional
expression
yes had to come along sometime to on its
functions are showing up
in a lot of different places JavaScript
being one of them
that sorta surprise me but Javascript is
not the JavaScript you might know from
ten fifteen years ago
logo was also based on list which
hopefully after the talk you can look at
and say yeah that makes sense
I do still teach logo to kids no
that kinda sucks well stop teaching the
MIT
programming class in scheme but it's
okay their place with Python
still MIT
hope mister randall Munroe got my email
about using this comic
while he does have a blanket license for
for presentations
I mention it's gonna be film so
please don't sue me
so now it now we finally get to
to the syntax eventually you might think
it's not really used anywhere
but this bronze runs the max
before he can take the code in the max
outside the max without dragging us the
editor along
other some people call it an operating
system not just an editor
this is bad have totally outstrip my
notes
I'm let's back up a little bit
was using AutoCAD
process possibly one of the most
successful programs the eighties
still going strong still uses twist in
it
the scheduling system up the Hubble
Space Telescope has written and less
haven't been able to get the story but
because I've
a server side-effect
or benefit of the way that was
structured they were able to
update the code while the machine is
still running from the earth
and cracked bike that was causing
something to screw up
confined to much you didn't have to
reboot it
just replace the code the only other
place that I've seen that touted as a as
a features Erlang
which rulings kinda hard core
but there was a there was a dialect it
was called terminated
incorporated the Erlang message box
sorta paradigm in it and I was kinda
impressive to
still looks like this but you get the
idea the concurrency benefits and being
able to hotswap code and things like
that
21 right filters and Kim you can use
long time ago there was a
groundbreaking anti-democrat shirt blue
have this later
nope alright unfortunate this this might
have been
1 I've the reasons why there was an AI
winter was
for Sony you know they they did such a
good job that everyone's
expectations for what will happen five
or 10 years
or assertive inflated the
the suffer company Naughty Dog also use
to a space systems for the Jak and
Daxter games
wasn't quite the same kinda list but
when the benefits was that you can swap
out
models while the system is running
and just garbage collect the old stuff
but anyway
tulis the
the weird syntax is actually an asset it
denotes a
a statement US begins when ends with a
parentheses the circum- posed Adams and
other lists
and by its definition
uses symbols it's for symbolic
computation you would normally
describe see is a generalized assembler
that you could 42 whatever machine you
want but
you still you know just a few steps
above the hardware
list is much more abstract and
you know slowly languages are getting
closer and closer to that
so when I go to the source the other
weird syntax it's not that weird if you
understand it
but the first for symbol after
a print disease is typically valued as a
function
and then the rest to them are the
arguments
in other languages %um function outside
the fantasies
it's not that different really when the
benefits I love
well this could've been done wrong
by the way that things usually go is
very well the site is missing a few
things arm
with things usually go is you have a
function
it's a functional language you have a
function and you pass in the arguments
and the arguments not changed
the arguments should be the same
when the function returns the value as
when they came in
this gives you some benefits that
you won't have side effects which is
typically what you program for in other
languages
and anyone who says that the
the syntax is insane well
syntax is very regular and grammatical
sense
you have a statement after Pence's
and you have all the arguments
afterwards here you have
in fixin tax you have assignment left
hand side
prefix postfix object oriented stuff
tacked on
array access or pointer access
it all looks about the same interest
kinda cheated these two aren't actual
functions there
special forms but I'll get to that later
should probably keep in check but I'm
begin wants to stay in this room me
longer than they have to
me especially
so here's this big googling terrible
equation section on a question to form
on forms gonna be evaluated although
evaluated
artistically for a display purposes
and so what the
what was machine will do is it will see
the form to find the
left must print the season and find
matching Ramos parentheses its building
its
blowing up a tree in the parser
with all the arguments and it just
applies the function to the arguments as
it goes through sexually prime
factorization
of 2600 anyone still paying attention
no I tried arm
like I said this is a little bit
creative because the earth
the seven multiply by 12 +91 would have
been evaluated for since it's the
deepest a
it's the deepest expression the other
cool thing to note here
is dad arm list has a lotta love
embedded data types that you get free
you have managers which
I hope you'd expect but you also have
perfect fractions or will you have
rational numbers
these will not produce to sum up with a
small
I tried in Python and the first one game
easier on the second anyone
not what you would expect or not what
you would want
will reduce it for you but will still
maintain the precision there's also
native support for complex numbers you
don't have to write that
really outstrip my notes here
so the list data structure
the native data structure is a list this
programs themselves
are lists
this feature the language is called home
or icon a city
which just means that the representation
of the data in the program are the same
this will come in handy later when we
discuss macros which
are not the same a/c macros
so here's some list manipulation forms
the court operator delays evaluation so
ordinarily we've gotten there saying one
is not
a function crack down on you
car in kidder pronouncing that right
car is stands for the the content to the
address portion the register
which on the IBM 704 made a lot more
sense by
common thing was a 36 bit architecture
and
whatever but so car gives the first
part of a list and killer gives you the
rest a bit
their offensive shorthand for
in a second third fourth fifth if you
really wanted to say CA addi
a are to extract something terrible
you could but that's that standardize
usually
their first in rest as synonyms for
conquer
so concerts means construct
you can actually use to make lists but
thats in the ass so you can just use
list
or use the code operator in specified
yourself
the this how you define a function you
have the
PD fun keyword its like you read it
function name
tingly to macro I'm and had three gets
added to the symbol table
as a function you have one argument and
the
last guy that gets a value added in West
gets a turn as the value cool thing is
that the documentation comes inside the
function
and the company's been fireman has ways
extracting
the documentation for you so if you're
lucky
and there is documentation for the
function you can find it
you can also use a command called
apropos animal
search through only available
documentation
give you names functions that you might
want kinda annoying have to you
program something and find out that came
with the distribution
but anyway
her
is there water yes there's water very on
isn't going quite as well as I thought
but this it's all true so far
hurt so as I sorta touched on earlier on
when the goals a functional programming
I'm of is not to modify your arguments
and the the primary way you interact
with the method
where the function is through its return
values so it's sort of like a black box
that you know what's going on but you
call it
you don't care what it does as long as
there's no side effects and you use the
return values
this is good because he won't have
you have mysterious bugs showing up
somebody characterize the the average
imperative program
as someone posting that how my function
takes 316 arguments
well if you consider all the global
variables that
you may be exposed to its technically
correct in a few have the opportunity to
change some other than in there
you're not going to get the same results
every single time you call the function
well that's nice an ideal way
you're not going to
be doing terribly much programming if
you rely only on return values
you need some side effects and really
get things done
so
this is a council one box one block
the a the car in kidder on conventions
make a little bit more sense now
basically these two hold
register values and the
first part of the list points to
whatever it is could be a hash table
could be single value could be a string
and in the second
points to the next on the list and
yes they are linked lists says where
maybe
people think it's slow and you do have
to go through each one of them if you're
doing something like that
a good thing the side effect is that you
end up with
being able to computer arbitrarily long
sometimes infinite sequences young
consume them you could soon as you need
to word you just
you don't care you're occurs through it
or you can read through it but
the good thing about using pointers is
that when you change a pointer
the come in the system will garbage
collected for you see you have to worry
about that either
on a proper list the last element in the
mail
damnit
sides must be complete Marion
no no no parent just a moment
let's
now would be a good time to leave
if you so desire anyway
here's a national program that is hosted
on puter cycles website
on its
called Lisp in a box 75 references
notwithstanding
I'm is really hot in here
me
this is how you defining global variable
put the asterisks around it so that you
know that you're using it
whenever
do is feeling much better about this
talk before I started speaking may be
doing one thing that scares you is no is
the best idea so whatever
the great thanks so I have to find it
returns the name the variable I'm if you
evaluated
at the prompt will return the values for
you
so if you're not supposed to
change state we gonna do have you get
all your variables
so there are few looping constructs
iteration constructs
now going to cite check the time
on do list as macro
getting a little bit had myself
by lets you chop up the with you chop up
the
the arguments that you pass into the
function home this way you can
you can do things like apply function
across all the arguments
conditionally or supply the test that
you want to use
for sorting algorithm say had a whole
bunch have
entries you got go home under files of
your
video camera but if you sorted
alphabetically all the pictures gonna
end up before the movies
so you could write a little function her
the lost about the first four characters
and sort only by the numbers
return a list for you
obviously made a shambles and my notes
but at least you're seeing real code run
some people don't Mike the I don't like
format consists not misspeak
although at this point in the speech
have no idea what looks less fear not
but obviously defines its own language
which is totally is are arbitrary
but still call it's not what I wanted to
do
married
yes
excellent exactly what I wanted to do
right alright
that sucked try this again
this latest wanna iterate through the
list
using axes temporary variable you have
any number variables here in the front
perform you can also
have their start forms that allow you to
reference other variables
in your declaration the
the do and lead forms usually
don't let you do that if you use an
Astros the end of it
you can reference values you just
defined
so I'm not doing this on the radio
I guess technically I am with radio
statler lots of dead air
so if you'll notice that the
print the Seas flash when I close them
that's really the only
yeah sale I
it's really only fijian you know what's
better although
this virginity max has a slime installed
which is the superior Wis
interaction mode free Maxx it's not
helping me too much right now
by you can do cool things Lake
compiled from a buffer and will
automatically put it into the US
contributor for you
yes
arm this particular
me do something simple this particular
I'm what's been fireman is a c-list
its is a little
easter egg you might have seen in the
beginning it's only activated during
certain calendar year
calendar days by couldn't find any
reference on an online so
to turn in the source code though I'm
married
cutting it took notes I'm so
it's not going as well as I thought but
seal it is
see less is designed to compile into a
bytecode there's another
interpreter that I have on a on a shell
somewhere that I was gonna show you
other applied equally disastrous class
b/ci which is still being common list
and that completes its designed to be
very fast and it compiles into
in tombs machine code
or assembly language and you can
actually see it
has has compiled
yes I'm going to give up now Kors this
is terrible
but it's supposed to do is a print out
the list
on each line I was gonna sort it but it
turns out that sort is destructive
so the
the list would have ended up with the
list would have ended up
chopping itself off at I guess desktop
no very well looking at the council
first so
yeah there's something very wrong here
out
I remember okay good I get to show you
functional programming
and passing in the name of the function
should be doing this passing the new
function
as the sir criteria on so it sort said
as it should on she really wanted to
you could change this to something else
switzer verse
I'm or what you could do although I
don't have the mental capacity right now
to actually do this I want to get to it
otherwise I'm you know your rights on
the call and expression
and if you come across lambda says
another one the stumbling blocks and
nobody could explain properly
member just means function to function
without a name it's a
the same thing as the be defined in the
previous previous one
here orders at three let's try that
maybe that won't fail
yep
it will show you love the debugger
tonight expect that to happen
home let me just give you just takes one
argument
prefix notation plus
3 axe the ex's a binding
inside this function definition it does
not exist outside the function
definition but that's okay
so we have had three very well women
apply at three
to I don't know 6 7 and
it this laptop sometimes
we get 10 great if
you think that was too slow maybe you
should
take a look at went
it's actually doing and like I said
the see List is designed to
compile into a bytecode I guess which
helps with
in cross-platform I'm SPCL will
compile into actual assembly code which
looks really cool
you read this it's really knowing when
you know everyone can
can squint the screen the person giving
the presentation you really just fine
to when it's an eight-point Council fun
hope you can read it cuz I can make fun
any bigger
in a what's been a box all right thank
you
let's go back to the presentation now
this presentation will change on me
supposed to have a little more code in
it here's the joke that started the
entire
presentation arm
one unfortunate fact that I discovered
yesterday is that you can still sick P
without ICP
so when I should have gotten to
earlier is a that the the regular syntax
list
where it's not entirely out of symbols
in parentheses
which may drive you insane is actually
an asset because
it's very easy to parse you can validate
it very easily
the editor has had the matching print
the Seas
to help the programmer for quite a while
it shows up in the 1986
susman Abelson talkin HP
arm I'm glad that
wrote these damn pics can't quite get to
them earlier just
some people say that the only
requirement for functional language
is for it to have functions that are
first-class citizens
arm with a macro
you can the Macker you can
change the syntax you can basically
right whatever you want it to
arm and hopefully it'll approximate
english
on and you'll be able to program much
more efficiently
once you've gotten all the nitty-gritty
syntax on the way
the
entire the language itself has access to
the symbol table
while you're running it you can redefine
functions
strum that peace accord again it will
dereference the pointer pointing out to
the new codes and the old code
and hopefully have some bug
you won't have to shut the system down
you don't have to
compile it now the price should compile
it for Speed
I know
this the slide speaks for itself which
is good because
I'm having trouble speaking
huh
away from the mic 23
so I got to the slight much quicker than
I thought
hopefully these make a little bit more
sense to you probably not considering
the way that I
rushed through it but the cool thing
about macro is that you have access to
the entire language in C
or I guess BB Rex our whatever macros
kinda
kinda boring and a simple arm mistype
were there with double quote
no nice it um the
the macro has access to the entirety of
the language
and you can string together macros when
it comes across another function it will
interpret that function as well
comes across North America can expand
that macro in see you
often run into problems where you've got
a print the season the
macro definition and it just as a
DirectX substitution suddenly over by
you know anywhere comes from
is not the source codes in the it's in
the a the macro definition
I'm this I guess the unofficial
Lisp logo good thing and have to ask
permission for it this a
this MD this doctor cum drippers cases
yes that we use Palin said macro because
other languages sort of polluted let's
see if I can get this to run
there's a
very good it's good very good
demo he has on his website whisper Rd
that that anymore
that more home miss Lena venture game
and when the cool things is that you can
structure data how you want it to how
you want it to be
and use different access methods to
only get what you want so here we have a
nice global variable
called map and just looking at it you
can
sort of understand what the a what the
structure is
I'm the
the plot love this story is that you
wake up
in it was its house and he's passed out
drunk and
you have to revive him in order to get
the magic a low carb donut I recommend
you read this
because it's a very good tutorial this
way I can at least
have benefited you a little bit but
he goes through all the
all the steps to build this program up
from the ground this with a list looks
like
this is the command the guys in front of
a list I'm
you can read it yourself I'm not not
here to read to you
so
this is this what america looks like you
have this weird syntax for you
are slipping in and out
love whether you want to evaluate the
argument as a symbol
or get the name arm or just passing
through
the the macro doesn't
on very
but macro side go well
makers return forms to the compiler did
not return values
and so the the interpretation of the
macro happens
before it's compiled previously using
code generator more code for you
and
you end up being able to abstract you
code
much more if you have a lot of functions
that are doing basically the same things
you can just read it once you have less
code less bugs
and if you need to change it you can
change very easily
it's not
self modifying code as cool as that
would be this is not a virus programming
workshop smackers basically
spit out forms to the compiler if I
could have gotten the indie project work
which they have a ever talk going on at
the same time right now so I'm gonna
blame them
and not the fact that I'm programmed in
this language into yesterday
arm one of the
when the languages that's gaining a lot
of attention is closure
cynics I didn't it the name isn't funny
to you because it and explain what a
closure is
arm but it's it's basically a value
trapped inside a function
and it doesn't get garbage collected
because the function is globally defined
in Summit
it captures that value news for you do
stupid things like counters or use it to
you
cue track in the state in the state
machine
you can use it for an infinite list
where you don't have to care about
creating the entire list I'm
anyway causing a closure side from the a
knows the lambda in there does have a
clever logo
I'm its list dialect with powerful macro
system running on the Java Virtual
Machine
so you could write you could write code
inclosure
and deploy it a JVM and
the boss won't know because it just
works
I'm
if I had had time to
write something I was gonna do a live
read out of all the badges in the room
but the MD side is still returning test
data
but where the improvement
this has over Common Lisp is that and
they're using the the Java thread model:
on
along with its own built-in software
transactional memory to
avoid deadlocks you may end up with a
lot of contention
by nothing's gonna stop over each other
and this is
a side effect if you will pardon the
language with side effects but this is
this is a benefit
love functional programming where the
arguments are typically immutable and
when you do change them
any code that goes back to reference it
is gonna get the new value
immediately so you won't have to worry
about
the data changing in the middle
had this talk on a little better I would
have delivered this with
a little bit more enthusiasm but
I'm sure everyone has a has seen the
scope for where the music makers and we
are the dreamers of dreams
you really are gonna think willy wonka
by in fact it is part iv:
in nine stands a piece which the police
and public domain
we are the music makers and we are the
dreamers of dreams wondering by lone see
breakers and sitting by desolate streams
world losers in world for seekers on
whom the pale moon cleans
yet we are the movers and shakers the
world forever it seems
it morris dancers services not the end
this is just the beginning
thank you that is off