I don't just willy-nilly show my point
everybody
chef when I'm sober
No
no I haven't started yet okay
thank you every speaker deserves an
introduction
we like to welcome to call new elections
can talk about hey don't call a guy I
knew
toward more welcoming hacker community
and
as you notice for an hour behind in this
room will continue with that
and also have the ackerson in here
one so welcome tuneful you
as he said my name is Nicole new
westech Nicole Nikki rogue con he blew
I mean I answer to just about anything
am here to talk a little bit about how
hacker community can be more welcoming
to new people
for small few words about who I am
on I E live in Chicago I helped start
pumping station 1
which is hackerspace in Chicago on got
involved with that
December 2008 have been involved with it
ever since
on no more pertinent to the stock I'm
still
fairly new hacker community I
didn't stumble across anything
particularly hatchery and tell
early 2008 on a night of random wiki
pedia
fucking at you know 4 a.m. when I was
law school
four out of my mind let me do
fundraisers America
sir posting on that forum started
talking to people
that and got clued into things 2600
meetings and hacker con
discussed so far from there on my first
hacker con was actually
the last hole and you know I've been
going to quite a few ever census going
on meeting
people but yeah it's the really only
been around for about two years
ish so being a newbie is
really fresh in my mind few words about
what this talk is
on its 7 ideas to keep in mind in order
to
make hacker community less mysterious
and more open to people who are
new to it or just trying to figure out
what is the hacker community
where you do it hackers to who are
hackers
what can I do in fact community on its
applicable to hacker group
all kinds of hackerspace she is
organizations more informal meetings
know they're certain pieces myself i
little better in one context
other but it's meant to be a general
framework away if
thinking approaching 100 do with new
people and bring them
make them feel part of the community no
matter what kind of an organization
that your part if you weren't about what
the stock
is it as much as it's a free market way
of thinking
I'm not gonna be able to tell you step
by step how to make it more welcoming
you know I can't sit here and say do
this thing
save these words go through all of these
steps
and your arms we going to breed this
much more
welcoming culture i mean it's to
interpersonal sort of thing
and their different ways to approach it
just Center general principles
now me give you a little bit of a road
map out what I'm going to be talking
about
for I can't for small I'm going to talk
you and your role in making hacker
community more welcoming place
then I'm going to talk about do you
within your organization to make it more
welcoming to people who are
experiencing you experience your
organization for the first time
I'm gonna talk a little bit about what
you can do outside if your organization
on
units possibly a little more towards
publicity even if is towards
how to run your organization how do your
organization culture
but part love going out and trying to
meet people
and tell me back organization is
conveying
what the culture is of your organization
and convincing them
K maybe this is a place right feel
welcome maybe this is a place where
my skills would be well you live and I
would have something to gain from coming
here
finally I'm going to talk about special
responsibilities %uh
organization leadership just because you
know whether you're an officer or
director
were just longtime member that people
look up to you as a leader
you have some special responsibilities
in your in a special role to make people
feel
welcome in your organization for some
gonna talk a little bit about
I guess it seems kinda year to start our
about how to feel more
how to make other people feel more
welcome by starting with you
but it is an extremely you
it's a process that you have to
internalize it something he did
put yourself in their shoes your all
ambassadors
the hacker community on hacker community
is global
their hackers everywhere but what new
people experience is going to be very
local you know I wouldn't walk into a
2600 much I walked into a 2600 meeting
in you know
there were some people feel really
welcome in some people that now maybe
not so much ur
walking a any meeting really I'm not
going to go there
think 0 some of these people aren't
being very nice to me
me hackers lender nicer mi vida hackers
in rush are nicer packer somewhere else
I'm not your you to the hacker community
I'm not
somewhere to try and find nicer hackers
I'm going to you
see that local through as know as a
microcosm is an entry point
and if I don't feel comfortable there
I probably wouldn't want to export any
further
and no matter how long you've been
involved you are an ambassador
hacker community I don't care if this is
your first ackerson
for or if you've been around for twenty
years
the point is you're here you're putting
yourself out there
hacker conference and you you're in a
position that you could be talking to
people who were
interested getting involved hacker
community
and you you how you treat them
is going to be crucial on whether they
decide they want to be involved
now become a bit about you were coming
into the community your first
meeting your first event your first
convention on
I'm sure it was really exciting might
nerve-wracking there's all these people
who you don't know
the hackers such a loaded word
you come in there wow you know where
these people all these people criminals
are these people you know stand up guys
everyone here has the story you for me
it was a little bit
is my scary when I started getting
involved
just like us I was I'm still moscow you
know
we all know how well that turned out I
work in nineteen of by
you know it was my last year law school
i had basically
background check from hell coming up I
just taking
barring part of that the test only
you also have big background check after
left and each the form and tell them
everywhere you ever lived
you know everyone you know everywhere
you working blah blah blah
and its and the last thing I wanted was
after
you're going to school for three years
bust my ass in
you're going into this career detained
because I got mixed up with these
hackers Aaron they thought yeah I didn't
have the right
moral fitness to be a liar and
no I eventually got over that of course
it didn't stop me from
passing the test but it was still just a
really
it was kinda scary and it was I was not
apparent
and you i'm sure i love u have few
when you when you got involved in
packaging you for the first time you may
have had concerns like
not you may have just had concerns as in
you these people I don't know you're
using these terms I don't know
on everyone's been involved water I have
they
except me and it's a little
nerve-racking
so you need to keep that in mind when
you people start trying to get involved
in your organization
but you all stay why
he stayed in part at least because
there probably were people that we're
welcoming to you
there how are people who treat you as if
you had something to contribute
and you had something interesting to get
you figured out
date hacker community is for screw
and people are up to all these different
things you're pushing all kinds Arts and
Technology Center
limit and you wanted to be part of it
now how do you make people feel welcome
the need to feel comfortable they need
to feel like there's something they can
take from its
making gain any need to feel like
there's something make
kid that Laskar is probably a lot less
cynical
are a lot more neglected something they
can take
if you think I'm now I'm gonna go to
this I'm gonna learn skills
AB and C by learning skills isn't
all there is it's a lot easier to
feeling gauged if in addition to being
able to learn skills
you feel like you have something to get
because otherwise you go in there and if
you don't think you have something to
give
feel like a leech and few each is
extremely uncomfortable
now we talk a bit about what you can do
from within the organization
3 C's to welcoming organization include
teaching you people
learning from new people and encouraging
other people
in the organization to engage new people
for some talk a little bit about
teaching new people I'm
I've already started on this a little
bit general principles for making people
kam but you everybody has some kind of
reason they get involved in hacker
community and start exploring it
and a lot of times it is because they
want to learn a particular skill
you maybe they wanna learn something
about computer security maybe they wanna
learn something about
art maybe they heard some kind of cool
project that somebody your hackerspace
or somebody in your group has been doing
and they wanna learn from the principles
are technologies behind
so figure out what they want to learn
and cultivate
this can be done formal basis in this
can also be done on an informal basis
I'm formally you can teach classes on a
broad range
topics and teach classes aimed at a
broad range skill levels
I mean that's generally good practice
whether you're dealing with people who
are new to the community are not
kiss you even if you've been around for
10 15 20 years their skills
you built-in become very expert at and
there are always new skills to learn
there are always things you don't know
sometimes back to you because you're
doing a new project
on and and the classes
are a good way to you you get people
haven't
you can idea %uh love what sorts of
skills
people in your organization hash no they
don't have to be these formal
ongoing I'm going to teach a class every
Thursday at 5
yoga classes can be you was informal as
you're giving talks giving presentations
you wanna
2600 meeting or something about
something that you're interested in our
project that you're doing
but having that platform to be able to
shoot each other people
the skills that you have is important
and it helps make people feel like
they are learning what they want to
learn when they're getting involved with
your organization
not an informal basis it's probably even
more important than having something on
than having a formal basis because sure
you know it's
all I wouldn't say it's easy but its
you can sit down and plan out a schedule
say I'm gonna have these classes at
these times
but you're not having classes all of the
times
and your classes are the only avenue for
learning
just offer to explain your interests
your project is someone new
walks into the hacker space walks in
your meeting in asks what you're working
on
don't seem busy come back later just
talk to me a little bit about it answer
their questions on
no you'll be able to tell them something
that they're interested in that they
want to learn
and they may be able to give you some
reporters to
encourage collaboration on projects
collaboration
is really cool because its
it gets and exchange ideas going and
you something really cool can come out
and act on
not only in the Andes informal things
collaboration
explaining interesting projects I mean
not only
argue doing teaching but you're also
getting to know each other and just
making a more socially
comfortable place for people to come in
and feel a part of what you're doing
secondly learn from the people
even though their new your organization
they come there with the background
they come there knowing certain things
and you're not only do they come
curious about what they can gain from
the hacker community
on you see a new person coming in and
it's like what can
I take from that what kinda skills are
they bringing into
our space our organization v8
you we may not have here yet
again this can be done formally and
informally
I'm you needed Institute multiple
formats for sharing knowledge and skills
on talks lightning talks classes
on and your something that's and
something as important as far as be able
to give talks or give classes are share
that information
is keep that platform as open as
possible
on of course you need to have some kind
of person you'd have some kind of
setting i mean you need
no what the person is gonna come in and
talked about
and you offer them assistance if their
proposal for a class is not point is
refined as you'd like it to be but
the offers there you people need to be
able to come in and
give talks give workshops on skills that
they bring
because that will make him feel valuable
it'll make you feel like the other
people at the spacer and the
organization
are gaining from their presents which is
just as important
as the new person gaining from your
presence
also on an informal basis ask people
about their skills
you when they come in on coming session
1 does something at their meetings that
I've always thought his
really cool if somebody know it
beginning in a meeting
our presidents like okay who's never
been here before
and everyone has never been to a meeting
at the hackerspace before
they've raised their hands and
no they introduce themselves say who
they are
say what they're interested and learning
at the space
but they can also talk they're also
encouraged to talk about
what they already do you what their
hobbies are what their interests are
so that way when your people here not
say oh you know those persons interested
radio I have some questions about radio
maybe I'll talk to them
and your provides good conversation
starters
and it gets people on putting love not
only expecting
shoe learn things at hackerspace
but also you expecting to you contribute
expecting to you
you people know what their background is
ends
can ask questions can get help from the
new people
and again encourage collaboration on
projects
like I was saying before you cannot me
you teach
teaching new person is collaborating on
a project with few things that you now
but you can learn from no if you're if
you decide to collaborate on a project
together
that means that the project probably
take some kind of skills
that no wonder the both you haven't want
to learn
and you put you on a more equal footing
finally encourage others to engage new
people
no culture welcoming is not just a mask
you put on any time a stranger walks
through the door
it's something that you've got to keep
in mind I'm not why otherwise it's going
to come off
as forced and just
no con a mask you don't want to come off
that way you want it to be something
that's constantly
on people's minds and ingrained in the
culture of your organization
on just make sure to express the
importance of teaching and learning
to other members of your organization
and
recognize signs exclusionary behavior
of an exclusionary behavior isn't
necessarily something
people are doing deliberately I mean
I know I'm guilty of it if I'm having a
bad day
go to the space you like I don't wanna
do it people at my do with anything I
just want to sit down on a lot of put my
hand down
and read this book are on this project
do something
but you somebody's been involved in the
hackerspace for wyler known me for a
while
they know it's Nikki on a crank okay by
if somebody comes in who's never been in
a space before
are only been a couple times and doesn't
know me that well and doesn't know the
difference between
Nikki on a bad day Nikki on a good day
on
they may take not and is know me being a
jerk to that maybe
crafted and you again
like you don't wanna be a jerk about
calling people out when they're
not being as friendly as they could be
but you just say
say hey you know what doesn't hurt to
stop for a moment
answer their questions say a few words
you make me feel like
its americanization that they can be a
part of
as opposed to you something where you
have to climb
push your way and and finally
highlights in everybody's interest to
have a welcoming
culture I mean something it's the same
few people coming around and doing stuff
picking up release stale and you've gots
not to call hacker community at all a
call the hacker community is to push
ideas to their limits and come up with
new interesting ways
to use things to do you think he and
know a lot of times that impetus for
pushing something new
is know it's going to come from someone
else who comes in with a fresh
perspective
who's not necessarily use you the way
you or your friends or your your people
in your group
are you still looking think on one thing
I wanna talk
on the I wanna talk about here on the
concept love
paying your dues and yeah
there is a kind of respect for people
kinda level of respect for people who
have been around the community for a
long time and that's definitely
well but there's a difference between
that between respect being around for a
long time
and the basic respect love this person
is going to love this person have some
ideas that are worth listening to
and yeah even know the person coming it
hasn't been involved in
Yorker for that long or you may not
have John you a certain field a certain
skill as much as you have
that doesn't mean dates they're not
worth listening to in general
it means that they have something to
learn it means that they may come in
with
other skills that could be useful to you
and it means that
it doesn't mean that you don't have
anything to gain from that person
what you can do for outside the
organization on most surfaces
focused on what you can do you inside
the organization fight
there's a certain level of conveying
your culture
you when you're talking to people who
are outside the organization or when
you're going to some other kind
love no hacker maker artist or whatever
event
on for small making an effort look to
see what other similarly inclined
group gatherings offense there are gray
area and
good on talk to people
bring up your organization in
conversation
and get people interested in it
discuss your projects discussed that
you're working on
personally on but
track try not to make it sound like an I
mean don't
say all you need to come here our group
is so much
ass and then this other that's gonna
sound exclusionary and it's going to
sound dismissive to
what they may already be involved in
what they may be truly love
but now talk to them about their project
showing interest in what they're doing
ask them about what they're doing and
you know find commonalities
what you doing what they do or what they
do and what may be other people
group to you and also don't get caught
up in semantics in terminology
I've heard I'm absolutely sick
love the of our conversations about you
know I
are hacker maker level like labels
and I don't feel like every week
necessary especially they're necessary
to get into
get tied up on especially when you're
just introducing someone in the
organization
I mean you know if your if there are shy
about
oh no they call themselves hackers
don't put the focus on each Werner any
other specific word
put the focus on common interests on
creativity
on you know what they can gain from
being a part of your group and what
you can gain from having them is a part
of your
fine a little bit about public relations
on
don't church don't shy away from media
on there are benefits to you
their view media exposure especially in
the case %uh a hackerspace
on it's a way to reach curious and
talented people
you fair reading the newspaper googling
around there
more likely to find you and it also
dispels dispel the idea
hacker community is something covert
on you may see a news article about you
like wow you know they're
not up and on up to the shady
hackers cybercriminals whatever that I
thought they were they're open
they're talking to people and they're
putting themselves out there
on it makes people more ready to embrace
you contribute your organization
and also you know maybe we'll inform the
future work
%uh media outlets and dispel miss
reporters have about the hacker
community being
scary scary thing now and finally
stand up for yourself you can you tell
her for all you want
summer good lesson you might pull a bad
apple
if you pull a bad apple get stuff wrong
match not a reason
to stop putting yourself out there but
be respectful
crackdown sent a letter to the editor
something in your blog
just do something to you new dispel that
debate
that and you keep your organizational
image
as something is no on the up and up
that is ready to you you embrace new
people and not something to be
afraid of finally can get all bent
the special responsibilities %uh
organizational leaders
for stuff transparency transparency
transparency I cannot stress this enough
mean there are always going to be issues
especially in
any kind of Fair Mall organization the
hackerspace or any kind of
group that puts on events there's gonna
be like
nuts-and-bolts day-to-day tried
that is legitimately best dealt with by
leadership
by elected officers fight
do it openly it helps to fund them if
the Packers
as secretive and also encourages
involvement
you make your Board of Directors
meetings are your membership meetings
open to anyone who wants to look into
on you know any email list state
decisions are being made on on make him
open make readable by people yeah if you
have a board of directors list like
you again going back to example
compensation 1
there is a board of directors email list
in certain business does get down on
that list
but even though it's all me a smarter
people that are allowed to post on it
anyone who wants to can market anyone
who wants to can
read the discussions that are going on
and if they have an issue
they can new email somebody on the board
of directors list personally
or talk about it on the membership
mailing list
or on the public mailing list on
something else is open to a larger
people so there is a level of
transparency for people to
see what's being two-disc being
discussed know about decisions before
they're actually made
and put in their two cents about your
or about where the organization should
be going and
know that's important for new people to
know from the beginning vaped
they have access to you the
decision-making
mechanisms of the organization also
be personally accessible that goes back
to this team that's popped up a couple
times
love now as important as it is to have
form of things in place
its even more important for people to
you
have some kind of informal by
some kind of personal bond with people
who lead the organization
on just be. come to the meetings
be at the space frequently be you answer
your email
be accessible have a membership liaison
on it's nice to have a person who's your
point person for
you answering new people's questions but
now again you can't take that to an
extreme the membership liaison is never
going to be
you owe me Peter who interact with new
people it's good to have a point person
for
questions for new giving
giving tours the hackerspace that's the
kind of organization you are
but you need to make sure said all of
the leadership
is accessible and all the leadership is
receptive to the questions and concerns
of new people
finally make it clear that you value
their opinions
on the organization's direction are all
I am so
I'm sick appearing your people dismiss
their own opinions like
oh I'm only new here 0 I'm only an
artist I don't do that text got
blah blah blah as soon as you catch
people saying that
need be like no don't say you're only an
artist don't say you're on the newbie
you you're here you're interested in our
organization
and you have valuable things to
contribute and
know if they have a suggestion for how
to run something and it's something that
you've
tried already in it very much has it
worked you know feel free to bring out
feel free to have a dialogue and talk to
them about
now why the like your idea may not quite
what implement fun even then
your listen to rate your open 28 and
you can have a discussion about
know how to how to proceed from there
how did
possibly change things tweak around you
did for Twitter on
date suggested me I'm definitely not
trying to say
every idea put forth by a new person is
automatically better
because it's put forth by a new person
I'm not trying to say that at all
but what I am trying to say is you need
to give
their opinions for the organization's
direction real
some weight you needed consider them
logically consider them fairly
and you let them be part of the
discussion
now one thing and talk little bit about
is
not everybody is going to be a good fit
not all of these new people are going
cue workout
in your organization on some these
people are gonna work out
cuz the hacker community is just not
their thing
maybe they're not know they thought they
were going to find what they were
looking for in your organization and
turns out
they dumped that's okay hacker community
is not for everybody not everybody has
that inquisitive spirit
the hacker community is built around and
you're not everybody actually wants to
be part of a group when they're working
on projects
not OK your people will come in come out
I mean there's really nothing you can
you deal with on the whole she's not
there things that other thing
day no biggie and
that's okay when things get a little for
any
is if these people are not a good fit
because
vere disrupted you there either
verifiable disruptive as n you know they
have
you they're breaking safety rules are
becoming if right to
you up themselves you and others
on you for example if your hackerspace
this comes into play with
you to the tools on maybe they're
causing friction but it might be
subjective
like most of the people don't get along
with them but maybe not
all of them or now
they're just difficult percent deal with
third they interrupt people all the time
when they're working on projects
that's that's a little difficult to deal
with and i cant say I have all the
answers are not
if it's something verifiably disruptive
then
you have a purse have a procedure in
place I mean this
if you're you've got a fairly formal
organization you hackerspace or
something
have a grievance procedure in place you
give them a written notice of what
they're doing that violates the rules
give them a
time period to you fix their behavior
on keep everything on paper if it's
verifiably
disrupted on if they're causing friction
but it may be subjective
probably the best way to deal with that
is here
just sit down one-on-one and talk to
them arm
you say K you know your
I'm perfectly happy to talk to you at
some point but could you could you
please
let me check your let me try to get my
project on figure out a time
to if you got time to talk later or you
know
tell them yeah people were getting a
little annoyed by you doing this not me
other
be be tactful about and it's hard
and it hurts to do that but know
sometimes you have to you for the sake
because they may not even realize
they're doing it sometimes you have to
do that now for the sake
love making the organization a
comfortable place for
you for everybody else for all members
and for other new people who may come in
and also no if you have these bad
experiences
don't impart these bad experiences on
every new person who comes and mean just
give them the benefit of the doubt if
they turn out to be a great fit
excellent
if they don't turn out to be a good fit
you cross that bridge when we come to it
but you assume that people are knows who
the people honestly wanna be there
and are there to you get involved in
your organization
and be awesome and be excellent do cool
stuff
until it's proven otherwise
a finger in conclusion discussion how to
build an organization it has to go
beyond recruiting
yeah you know if you got the same like
five people coming to your meeting or
the same like 20 people coming to your
space
the first images of in oh here we needed
me to get people in here
but know beyond that you need to you
beef thoughtful be mindful about making
people stay
and remaining focused on the concerns
outlooks new people in mind
will leave the field valuable and
comfortable in your organization from
the first time he became acquainted with
you
on you know your you need to make a good
first impression
and a good first impression involves
being open
being welcoming making them think that
there's something
18 give to the organization as well as
making people feel that there's
something they can learn from your
organization
the questions
I actresses comments grievances
I had some common law professor
and whenever whenever he was finished
with 20 go question
comments grievances
Capcom's and I thought that was really
funny coming from
you know eccentric 65-year-old professor
I
I can't see if there's anyone lined up
and yeah okay show
I can't see a thing from here the lights
okay
so i'd at like like to bring up
something bad I think you might have
overlooked or taking for granted
and that the importance of communicating
shared expectations
and that when you are bringing new
people in your organization
you have I long for self-rule to find
what is acceptable
is an acceptable within your community
and within your space if
an I don't know if you wanna speak
anymore
know that that's definitely a good point
I mean that's probably something
that I your took for granted more than
anything
but mean I don't know how necessary that
is if it's just
if your organization is like in fact
meet up
fight if it is hackerspace sure it is
you and your family organization
that puts on offense and does things
your you need to have a clearly laid out
mission you need to have clearly laid
out rules
and no thats ads that's absolutely right
they need to be
you're certain things are important
enough to be you in the bylaws are your
corporate
com foundation document some may not
you be quite bylaws level but they
should still be
written down they should be static and
they should be in a place like a website
that's accessible for anyone and
everyone to read cuz
yes it gives she gives eighty
known opened shared expectations when
people are coming in
and also no going back to my point about
dealing with people who were difficult
or possibly detrimental
it does give you things you can site
being liked
okay what you're doing violates your
this
that the other brown wall of the
organization
hmmm I would I'd share with that that it
should be on the job
web page as far as mission statement
watcher what the organization is about
but also arm shared values
as far as like a value system as far as
I what is it that the organization
values because at Minot fit with them in
another organization
their values to fit with them so what is
it that you're
about as far as with regards to that I
i'm
were things a house is that do a
conflict resolution when you have
members who are a little bit more
challenging than others
and how to go ahead and stepped that up
on
the language that is used and how you
step that up is really important because
you want to keep
that person if possible a
contributing member that community and
if not
dan you 1 I've go ahead disengage
inez constructive ways possible sore
word questions after use how do you go
through that process
what is the language that you found to
be the most useful
and conflict resolution in you
keeping that person a contributing
member the community if not
how to go about having them find other
communities that may be more suitable
for them well if there's a if there's a
difficult person
on sorry skull just water
sorry about that on I think what what's
in what's very important when you're
what you need to do is give them
no very clearly very specifically
Wade out reasons why there is a conflict
om I don't remember off hand like know
exactly the words
used but there's there's a written
letter now come to our attention
good we have the following concerns with
you citing
the your behavior specifically as
possible
and connecting match you something
and the you know the rules are the
values written down
on that's important because he know it's
not going to come off as
arbitrary you want as much as possible
them to get a feeling
on okay this is specific they can cite
the reasons why
as opposed to you they're ganging up on
me because they don't like me
that something you want to avoid all at
all cost is coming off
coming off as over there came a funny
because they don't like me
and as far as disengaging
on I mean honestly I'm honestly not sure
I mean it's never it's never got to that
point
where we've had it's you forcibly
disengage someone from your family
kick them out the space on when we've
told them
that they've been breaking certain rules
OMF
you know sometimes though sometimes I'll
clean up her act
but now sometimes dole few on cocktail
feel extremely uncomfortable the week on
the mound on their behavior
and don't even know how and I mean that
sounds
that sounds bad by its you know that
that's what happened
and know if they're uncomfortable with
being call now
on doing things that violate the
terms of the space then you maybe it's
probably better in the long run
day didn't end up staying in the group I
mean
as far as finding other things that
maybe
a better fit I don't know if that's
necessarily with and
disco I love the organization's
leadership i mean you're not necessarily
like
I yellow pages for other similar
organizations have someone asked me you
know 11 hair there any other
organizations that do this that or the
other I'd be perfectly happy to tell
them
but I don't know if that's necessarily
something we we deal with is an
organization like up to someone and be
like
an offer for a good fit here maybe you
could be a good fit Tupac's
sorry can't see if anyone of a sign up
for questions I can't say anything
okay face
so arm one thing with it
I guess I see
Carson leave but arm is rarely spoken of
is arm future gender imbalance in
the vast majority of hackers anything
arm do you have any eighty years
concerns et cetera regarding that
arm now it's it's definitely a concern I
mean I've
then in the minority and well pretty
much
any hacker event that I've ever gone to
you
and now mine my feelings on that would
be
your people people do need to be
conscious of that people need to you
you make it a culture I love not
now incorporating sexist talk sexist
actions
didn't you v you into their behavior at
the space
they need to come in and now assume that
someone coming in regardless of gender
is has something to contribute
has no good ideas for the space
and you know Nazi woman come in it's
like she's probably just to see how
you're looking for
guy on you people just need to be
cut people need to be conscious on on
gender blind honestly
and the way they look at and assess new
people coming in and
you stop and think okay is how i'm
behaving
going to make you man women
anybody feel welcome in open it space
oh yeah
no I'm definitely not I'm definitely not
saying there's a difference between
sexist language in crash language
I don't have a problem with I way
you know I'm you're given a talking to
Connor anything but you know you talk to
me
casual conversation you know your shady
fucker fly outta my mouth a mile a
minute
but there is no difference between Matt
and you now
hey look at that time on her
you know one is tau
without him last night I
for
me I'm I'm definitely not saying that
you know casual or even
crashing wage is a bad thing because you
I feel more comfortable in that
situation to
although now I know that some don't
bonnet
known being fair being very careful
about
arm you gender loaded or
you sexually explicit language is
probably a good thing
and the questions
this is all well and good and I
understand where you're coming from
courage to a hackerspace environment and
really would support that but
being the sea 2600 conference having
2600 meanings
and for myself having Ryan probably 2600
meetings at
for five different cities they're still
there
wall we have to put up because we don't
know showing up
having had to deal with certain
leo's showing up that just graduated
from the Academy trying to make a name
for themselves right off the bat
by busting some evil hack or I
that was a direct quote pic
its it can also depends on the
environment that you're in
and who which getting exposed to
what's going on well yeah I mean there's
definitely enough
ubat 2600 meeting a hackerspace
well was in a meeting a hackerspace
or anything else I'm not saying that
you don't have to hide your I'm not
saying that you don't have to have your
guard up
I mean yet there could be unsavory fed
like characters walking into a 2600
meeting
or hackerspace there could be unsavory
non-fat like characters walking into you
your meeting her hackerspace I mean we
had a guy
show up to you and one or two far
formation meetings for coming station
one menu he came in and was just
of the back pushy about oh you know you
need to run things this way you need to
be a politically charged organization
it's your duty to do so
blah blah blah and you know we
disagreed we disagreed with him and told
him so in no uncertain terms
but did it in a respectful manner I mean
there's a difference between on being
between being welcoming and you know
thinking that
know everybody's gonna fit in your
thinking that nobody is a threat
but what's important I think being a
2600 meeting
or a hackerspace or anything ask is
to you no give the find out find out
what you can about them
but now give them the benefit of the
doubt if you find out pretty quickly
yeah I know he's a he's a fat and you
don't really wanna
you know talk to him and he's up to no
good going to be disruptive
yeah proceed from there but
don't assume that everybody walking in
is gonna be
now offender is gonna be a threat to
your organization you
given a fair shake. find out what their
find out what their deal is first care
enough to do that 'em
I just want to add into in addition to
that involve the net tax base in in like
you can also involved in now
some more activist political type stuff
and when things on the political side
things we don't see so much in
hackerspace I things is this concert up
security culture
where there is some very worser
have developed sir pretty clear
guidelines on how to deal with the
social situations where you do things
like
Tom be very clear that unites in
community for getting people about the
things that they don't miss it when we
were measuring too much information the
first place he said it was very
assertive in advance at a at a cultural
level
so if make some people in your group
doing things that are
you know grey hat back at tech stuff or
whenever the context is
you know you make sure you keep that
away and and down
disorder as a cultural thing don't
expose those things and then
with people coming in wanna get involved
in that there's sort of processes that
that you can see happening in more
release that I see happening
activists areas is really something
where 2600 group coming from Zazzle
obviously the similarities but is the
concept that building in security
culture can get around a lot of those
problems as well
I think just you know the word that
that other cultures and agriculture's
were involved and have them
these problems we can learn from them as
well no
well it's an interesting point I mean
talking about things as
as simple as a an ambush on Flickr
bookstore where is a radical bookstore
and you know
people there of other projects and you
want people coming in volunteered
because they like
you know involved in the community
bookstores like that you don't want them
to necessarily get involved in
in other things things like that so yeah
things I find interesting hackerspace
where I live
best is in the virtual discuss our the
virtual hackerspace
for me it's IRC channels that's weird
and
you know I side the hackerspace in some
I find it interesting you know for
myself
I I am work best in my own my head so
UN where I bounced my ball of that
virtual wallets and IRC channels and a
half years
everyone in this room many bus early
years in our respective communities
technically I mean
very few of us here followers cell when
I see
news like to go back to the top if
you're talking I see group work entire
see channels
you know what I see my peers going I try
to help them but I I am
I am mace a I'm in the minority when I
find that a lot of people are doing is
RTFM people are click ish
they try to socially engineer themselves
into the group
just by trying to make small talk they
failed miserably by the way
also FF unfortunate enough to be in a
bed
mean I can name a couple they just get
automatically banned even if the night
you know I don't know who you are but
you're in a bad domain show on you
you know bad luck for you anyway the
point is I'm just trying to get across
Eastern how not to
label people is nudes and to keep them
involved in the community
very difficult because very few people
will goal to the hackerspace first
if they're interested in the technology
the IRC channel first
and that's where they'll get turned off
because when they walk in CRC channel
and they get
talk down to an RTF m2m make it
you know completely isolated and they
find they can't even approach that
entrance ramp onto you know a person to
speak to about anything
what they'll just get it may be a couple
from the people for them a couple links
you know say just look here look there
they just cant get themselves in that
rotating revolving door of people just
walking and walking out
arm I find it that that virtual
hackerspace
in the IRC channels where most of us
live our quote the silent majority
arm and that is where also i think is
the most unfriendly place
I have of course I'm I'm in the industry
a long time but I i've cut mighty so I
have my friends I mean my little crew on
my next find makes me happy but I feel
really bad for everyone else
an I I was hoping you would address that
I know you didn't but
that's the hackerspace i think is much
more also important that's my opinion
Vandiver decried the real hacker space
because I think that
it's the people who already succeeded in
the virtual hackerspace are trying to
take it to the next level and end up in
the real hackerspace
I think the real place for us to be more
inclusive
as leaders respectively in our
communities and icp-aes I mean
geographic communities
to help those who are trying media
interested in me and i wanna get scared
away
is actually the trial will be a little
bit more closer perhaps less click ish
in a little more mature
and I find that severely lacking on
freenode
and on 2600 and II to add I'd done it a
couple times myself but that's just my
opinion
I think I was just take it for what it's
worth I'm sorry if I offended anybody
%uh you make you make a really good
point they're actually I mean I was
focusing on real-life meet space if you
will on the top but
no I spend it on a time on IRC is well
on
on freenode on 2609 on more
now IRC rooms and I can count and now
they're is
there is a lot I like they see a new
person walking into the router minutes
late due to hell
this I've never seen them before and no
I
you are you are absolutely right the
people need to be
more welcoming to new people on now on
IRC
or forums on the internet I mean it's
really easy to be a total
asshat online cuz you you're not
you're not paying out there they can you
reach through the computer and punch you
if they get pissed off at you so it's
really easy fights now you're probably
going to turn you from week
you're gonna turn off a lot of people
who were you knew when interested in
trying to delve and
by the you re putting them on IRC
your you're absolutely right I would
just encourage anyone is a saying just
simply be a little bit more from leakers
I personally feel really bad for the
guys who just trying to learn something
China ask couple questions and Fink
they're gonna get that benevolent tech
guy who's going to answer the question
instead again if you are a fan or they
just simply just get a
RTFM Hypercom I just seen are all too
often it bothers me and soul
in a in the end it talk at this context
I just wanted it you know
now and get your thoughts on a bit just
take opportunity to mention except or
all over I say yes leaders in our
respective channels
should probably just got a little extra
thought maybe speak to our own
friends about it just on the back of
quick a comment about just had another
comment um
not remember that not with the RTFM
contradict me nuts because
everybody is the first 1000 learning and
not everyone learns best by reading
so like personally for me learn I can
learn by reading but it's a lot more
for rewarding to me to learn by asking
questions and doing in working with the
demand for something so that
just the RTFM culture is really really
negative to those people who don't learn
best by reading and it's really rough on
those people
but what i was gonna say is combating to
the thing about the sexism earlier is
that to also be aware it was
orientations
because you know if I go to a place and
people like let's shoot game where you
know your soldiers a faggot blahblahblah
I would be to return of a not come back
because it's like you know there are gay
hackers and it's very important to you
know not use that word as a put-down
yeah absolutely agree on you
ornamentation
at that's another thing and that's
another kind of language that I think
should be avoided
make people feel welcome his one it's
just
not good practice to call bad things
Gary whatever but
it is going to make people feel
unwelcome
actually wonders to the stuff
I wanted to remind all the new people
that your much less likely getting RTFM
if you demonstrate you actually have
done some research ask your question
may not be able to find the answer if
you can say
I try to hear it right there and I put
some level fun into it
then you can ask mortality question call
you better answer
and for those it are tempted to tell
people RTFM
give them the right things to go
research instead of just on
researcher and I think that those who
can learn by research will learn better
yeah I know thats that's true I mean you
need to you
time RTFM isn't going to do anything on
tell them tell them where the manual is
maybe give them a link to something to
read
and you know it's good it's definitely
good to act to
do research first NASCAR ask more
intelligent question
but new even if someone that comes in
and asks a fairly
you have a question like your response
respond maybe responded another question
in turn you know like what have you done
early what more specifically do you want
to do you want to know about like near
near on the topic
what level to you believe should hold
new people accountable
for making that first effort beyond just
simply s question arm
now I think its I think I think it's
definitely a new person's responsibility
to you
no they come in and they say they're
interested in you learning
act in learning XY and z. I mean if
their after interested in learning and
I'm
you know kind of and have expecting that
they've
you at least John you track tried to do
a little bit
love new reading you're talking to
people or starting to suss out the topic
but now honestly I don't fold
like I don't hold them to fax ha I don't
for them that high of a standard
especially when they're just starting
out just because
you maybe they are not process if
figuring out if they're interested in it
and
just something out the topic and you
maybe they do
if they learn best by reading they can
easily do not own their own if they
learn best by talking to people
maybe they're trying to find that person
or those people to talk to you
you to mentor them are to give them you
even just a bird's eye view of this
thing that they realized they might be
interested in so
now I I find it really hard to I find it
really hard to hold it against someone
that they you don't now anything yet
about a certain topic sign a whole lot I
don't know anything about it
am moreover comment and a question
although I am extremely respectful every
culture
and orientation and everything out there
I have
great respect for everything about it I
gotta say a couple things because I I
gotta be honest here
on a start really quickly but just
asking a question
how is copper wire invented two Jews on
the same penny
I and you wish I can tell a joke
okay look let me be very blunt let me be
very honest
you're in a hacker world hacker world is
semi survival of the fittest
if you can't take a joke go find another
world
there are their
sorry there are abuse and nasty and
that's wrong
I agree with you on a per cent but a
joke is a joke
deal
I'll have to its ok welcome
I'm not I'm not some this welcoming
thinks
I'm saying respected enjoy but I'm also
saying
understand that sometimes people make a
joke in there were only two jewish they
won't know you're gay they won't know
whatever
okay so if you feel upset then taken a
sign in to him looking to do that upset
by Paul and I say you know did that
upset him
you know it I honestly didn't mean to
upset me and if you did we need to talk
different pretty potentially buy the
building but it upset me
that's cool that's fine okay but i mean
there's an extent of their there's
there's a level to which
you don't need to be politically correct
and then this extent to which you do
need to be
to so looking forward to next year re
planning on giving the talk
hope again home and and so
you I'd like to see this turn into a
panel discussion
to get more ideas from your community
because what works for you doesn't work
for him which
doesn't work for him which doesn't you
know are I
we haven't got know that her head fight
you're right
a panel discussion %ah a panel
discussion on this would be very
valuable in my opinion and
sounds like my time is up so thank you
well