cue
so many miss college here I am from a
cover
I'm as someone else's to you okay so I
just Lego
two and a half million other people we
managed to survive the Olympics
on years old question how many be ok she
ever been to
Olympic event before research and and I
can see
I Stice cream
no of their ego so
yeah back in a 2003 vaccine for hosts a
decir won the right to host the Olympics
and in 2010
me hosted the Winter Olympic so the
topic is compromise exploits
the vendor 2010 Olympics my whole goal
at this content with this topic
is basically to discuss the social
issues and the technological
Obama I would say any problems or
observations that were made
by 12 per se your neck silver so there's
no brilliance
exploits involved in this event actually
it's a rather unfortunate
title I'm so the slogan for at the
Olympics was with glowing hearts are
typically brilliant exploits
and and probably for announcing that
wrong forget my high school friends
but basically it's just an excerpt from
the
Canadian National Anthem and basically
that kind of goes into a topical a copy
which was on explain a little bit later
and 10 unfortunate item that came up
during the Olympics when I was at a
curling match where something contact
radio
have any beer familiar with curling
probably knows that the term hack
means i'm for the life of me I can't
remember now because
I'm on the stage cells Fig go figure
so wanna do is an act bring across five
points I and talk about how the city
becomes lockdown I how the police iraq
to the people
and that sort of thing on probably you
see a the protests as a good example of
what happened but also discuss other
things that came up
and also look at the Olympic branding
and copyright how they all relate
I'm then a look at it out to security in
terms of an
ticket sales and so forth sign it and
its kind the same topic here
and they're gonna talk about lastly is
how we teach
thought we might and I am against the
CCTV network and what we actually end up
finding out about in the end
to a further ado gonna go into the
efforts for the topic
and that is the security so if you take
him to put this in perspective and how
ridiculous security was at the 2010
Olympics
I'm Salt Lake City which was only a few
months after 9/11
spent a total two hundred million
dollars roughly around there
under security in that included you know
things like having the noticing a safety
I guess you guys gonna military but I
guess the National Guard
and links are events on a course having
your say police and so forth
in the case %uh 2010 Olympics am the
caning government's one with the
provincial government masses and almost
a billion dollars on security
and I don't know where the money went to
because one explain ticket sales it's
good it's kinda baffling
but as you can see here you go to a
typical events and you have yourself a
screen as if your gonna fly an airplane
because
you apparently are going to bring in NYS
into the sea
in this is dis is me waiting in line to
go into a curling a and so basically I
would pretty much just like going into
an airport except there's no plans from
there
and there's an open field operator now
I don't understand why they had operator
and militarily
drink when there's nothing going on
inside that were hires
good weather but as you can see here at
sign open fields my presumption is that
they're using it somehow to keep to make
sure the number is wondering if
I don't know operator enough to actually
explain that sell somebody could
potentially tell me that afterwards and
a force field were very paranoid to
think that people would bring boats into
near the Olympic Village the also had
scuba diver swimming around the waters
around the
the olympic sites and this is general
insanity the even had
am see go back serious was that was
actually another order
area they also have a you know if i
think is a free get here actually funny
reimbursement
thing that makes me very curious about
this is why would you have a large ship
trying to control
people are terrorists is a smile silly
things and Percy had police with
you know swat teams roaming around so
forth
and make this even more absurd the brown
and police officers from all over the
country to
handle security journeyman so we'll send
a private security but they're spreading
outside police
and it was really silly about it was
that the offspring corrections officers
to actually handle some idiotic sites
now knowing the police and how they know
the rates and so forth
I'm slip weird to have corrections
officers who handle prisoners
I'm patrolling the streets says where
the silly things that observed as I was
I wonder around
and a course there's this whole level
paranoia prior to the Olympics where
on this is where the transit police
upright out these
at sea know if you see people taking
pictures fire cameras
she called the police now I don't know
white
sort of thing that some terrorist one
quote would actually do with a pitcher
%uh VA
a camera but you know what do I know I'm
not a police officer
so with all these all the security
paranoia from the police and the
government
I'm there is worry meant there was going
around that you know
rates are gonna be circumvented as you
can see in this photo here here's why
the Olympic mascots
kemper's name I think it's Amy camera
whenever there's a whole bunch mascot on
bring up something later about them am
basically
live from everything you can see here
live rights are being trampled there are
slots applause introduce such as some
homelessness initiative act
which basically if your hometown
homeless on the streets please to pick
you up in 4c go to a shelter
or even supposedly jail and it was
actually really serious because
I'm up until then homes for China not so
much but really left alone but as you
want extra
closer online he sings became became
prevalent and
some sort of political issue of a sign
so we have and there was another
initiative it came out worse if you were
to have a sign on your property
that would basically something and he
anti went big for
something that didn't really jive with
the I'll see or the veteran with the
committee or VANOC
excuse me on you could be either
arrested or you could be charged
rest and put in jail for up to three
months or even still
beater find something like a couple
thousand dollars just for having a sign
in your lawn
now there the law isn't
really the sorry BB the provincial
government panel out the
typical thank you for counsel to
actually amend the pilot actually allow
certain
men they're cut constitution the city
charter excuse me
to permit see certain rules but as far
as I know was never actually am an
active
fortunately but you know things like
this for passing in this is
sorta the whole kind and nature that was
going on here so
have to excuse me there's no water and
stage here
here sorry
sorry missed you so the image in the
city so I think I know if
tired so as you can see here's a little
poster from mom wanted the ante on the
group M
for now I'm you can see here the
attitude from the
people against the sort about action was
pretty appearance take back through the
years
our city was actually when the events I
was organized and I was actually
supposed to coincide with the opening
ceremonies
sincere the 31 main Olympic mascots for
their and they all got together and
actually protest
now so about 3,000 to 5,000 people
converge not too far from where the
Olympics are if you look in the back
towards the left there's actually the
parent the count down the other side was
the Olympic countdown
so this the exit but this clock appear
in it was always a constant target for
people taxi to face and now just 3000
just constancy roseanne doing nothing
but yeah basically they had
mean if there's a ton of people organize
actually outside it was known as a cover
gallery
and it's sexy common experience protests
there
so my the things at the BC Civil
Liberties Association did because they
are fearful that the police were in a
doozy brought in the some legal
observers
and the activities people had was a
factory to ensure that the
rights and privileges he had with the
cane Turner rights and freedoms
were were kept in line police which
means keeping themselves online
and well there was a lot a contrast
between the protesters and BCCI
afterward
hum overall from from this protest
nothing major actually happened
and you can see here people are marching
towards at BC Place Stadium which is
where the Olympic ceremonies were held
and foreseen actually met with the
police now these are mostly RCMP Amaker
police officers and to even though it
kinda looks like they're pushing on
the protesters there from everything
I've read from the front lines
nothing actually happened the police for
corneil
an the the protesters never really got
outta line per se
on this goes and master contrast to the
g8 g20 protests were as if you're five
years away from them you will be
arrested
self big difference there and its kinda
silly
& Coursey can see they're not that far
away from the actual see him
let's go skate to next day where 200
people decide to March and downtown
and if you're if you're training for
military the term black bloc town of its
use the term using United States
but these black brought protesters have
basically we're
im involved in this here and there made
teams basically denies later by the
media
and you know the %ah protest through the
city and so forth by throwing
newspaper boxes and mailboxes across the
street really might not know much more
than being a nuisance more than anything
but then it turned to axis keep your
senator new cracks keys here by 37 the
windows
this is the worst thing that happens
really this is there's nothing worse in
this there is some glass broken and some
stuff spray-painted
on the worst you know this was the this
is the bay 12 largest companies
sponsoring the olympics within the
country itself an elitist smashed
windows
so that was worse think so where did the
billion dollars security actually
go to you have to wonder while
take a look at that and the second here
so after the class is massive police
came in
and I'm don the right here and you can
see here the round protesters are back
backing away at this point product out
there
their machine guns sorry a
semi-automatic
anyone know what the Gunners
okay so you can see here they brought
out the heavy artillery at this point I
probably should
riverboats I hope am the didn't
the peace process come really deep into
was northwest as possible as intentional
but it was also cited
the Olympic family hotel which is in the
back releasing see here
and police were more concerned about
keeping away from their
am this one person's a course getting
arrested at all the two other people I
think
a couple dozen attacker arrested in
Maine the last laugh
remember I like this photo most because
I he's wearing
Canada boxers I don't know I why I like
that for a lot so I but I did
and as the videotape term everyone else
everyone else took photos of themselves
figures tit-for-tat from
now this how many your hockey fans
and leave your Rangers fans
case oh about sixteen years ago there
was a certain team from certain city
that might have mentioned earlier
playing against a certain team from a
certain city that reason to stay in that
may or may not be across the street from
here
and I it went all the way to game 7
and that certain team that I was very
fun at it very young age
lost a sad and a Corsair
when one little thing happened in that
city then i'm talking about.
a ride belch their numbers are always
very on what happened here but about
anywhere between 10 and 60,000 people
converged on downtown
thank you for the mall cinema drunk
after getting the game 7 and the largest
ride and anchors history after
whatever that right I can remember outta
my head
basically erupted tear gas everywhere if
you ever gone YouTube DC search for
think you're in nineteen eighty four
Stanley Cup riots and you'll see how bad
the situation it is
let's skip to the Olympics how many
people were downtown for the games to
watch them well
their wrists the on average that was
asked me to any between 100 to 200
thousand people or anywhere in a
downtown core any given time during the
two-week event
and you know everyone Spencer skip n
everyone's been all patriotic
happy and the one thing that was kind if
I kinda feared and kinda expected or
to happen was I can United States land
up and a gold medal hockey game
and they did on Canadian soil
so the I worry meant I thought that
site where me that I had was that we
would have a review 94
if we lost not enough we wanted the same
thing would happen either but didn't
by any en banc sorry the the Canadian
team did win over the americans and
overtime fortunately
by I not revenue guys faces or anything
than to say
but basically that was my main I was my
main thought about what was
ignored by the media in terms of what
the security costs for going towards it
was actually going to towards prevent
things like
on the 1984 cuts out a cup rights from
if you know
rearing their ugly heads again a lot of
things actually we're done the prior to
doing that so they actually stops liquor
sales past 10 p.m. and so forth
or that has has 6 can excuse me I just
prevent the
consumption of liquor in the open
kazakhs illegal just like most
I am North America to drinking water in
the open western about our
Mexico I guess so now is a main concern
but I don't know see how
a billion dollars was needed to stop
that one really there's
is this really seems answered some
magazine idea what the decline it was
like in terms of the
policing and sell for them I'm gonna go
back to the security on it and again a
bit later actually here when I talk
about how
tickets Randall and passes for staff
rambled
so wanna talk about advertising in
Olympic branding so
the IRC is very very protective about
their brand
now case in point there is a pizza place
or
replace a camera where it and what's
which one it serves
column MPs and the western and a bank
said at a downtown into work or
and they actually have the only big
rings actually on their logo now
other companies have had their Olympic
rings external as well
now sees manage to force anyone to
misuse is the brand
the Olympic rings brand to remove it
from their signs
so an international organizations been
going to %uh any host country for that
matter taxi have these a slow these
locals removed
but you the real reason for that is not
because they're just may want to make
sure that the sanctity of the Arctic
brings her cat because we all know how
figure skating works
it more or less has to do with how much
money these companies put into
with the advertising its lot on as you
can see here this is one about eight
hours and down in the downtown core
and Samsung for the crappy on the phone
actually
on the power now this is not the only
add it was on the towers like
manner as thrown on top for like
scattered all over the bay
which is he is a professor downtown
pretty much any any
be able any people advertise its was use
and you can see here companies that want
to broadcast the games
pay a lot of money to in the xy in turn
have to show the Olympic rings
for like dino during the year that they
received broadcast the Olympics
and in this case here the exceed on the
Olympic rings rate on the outside at the
outside the the brats are the station
itself
and of course everything as I was saying
earlier every single sign-on
advertising spaces by I've could not
even leave the transit system doesn't
matter how far away is from the Olympics
on without running across 1 it's all the
transit signs are all the Transit has
been replaced with
Olympic at C&C years at these Adonia bus
a stop there but it doesn't mean that
you can't
0 advertise relating to the Olympics now
if you it's kinda Wearhouse for example
in order to not get in trouble with the
IRC urbana
QFC were not advertise anything where
Olympics or Vancouver I think winter is
also part is awesome
you can make any mention any loss for
words if you can advertise anything that
could be
misconstrued as a part of the Olympic so
if you're in itself
flags are you still sporting here are
you gonna sell things like
anything that in general that could
somehow come back to be an Olympic thing
you can upload those words in there so
in this case your neck he just decided
to allow people to summits
phrases to exceed on on this %uh
projected wall here which is not too far
from
with the baby was his accent on exxon
the Sears downtown
and you could just basically some in a
message would be shown on is the
projector as you can see here or you
could be really creative
and actually sell products am
that actually remember sorta semi
branded as a be an Olympic but they're
not
so in this case here a little lemon
athletica basically decided to
sell these are clothes that were colored
in the colors a effort is being with the
team so you can see your sweet and his
woman here is dawning
painted black tooth which for some
reason must be attractive
and I and basically you know
all we have is like sweet in Canada the
United States and their colors on there
but they did make mention of any those
weren't so
nothing about winter Vancouver 2010 her
at the Olympics
Lululemon action kept this on the market
for about us
having was I I might be wrong but i
think is no more than a week
and there's a lot of heat generated
towards them and eventually the
buckle down after spending all this
money on ways all this scene on
all these all this material making this
I want the kearsarge quote-unquote
Olympic year
and you know they stop selling it after
all this pressure from the icy so
you to try and get away with it so
easily you know
the IRC in vanna will or sorry in the
Olympic Committee for that particular
country will actually
clamp down hard on mix like say later on
it with them and decide they want to be
the official
pics a fire for I don't know 2016 or
whatever
when pics are coming out he is they may
not be able to do because they screwed
around them
when the Olympics so cynical very few
hirsch
can go back to Napa some major point at
the half has I actually got to see him
live so is actually pretty players but
this bit here is pretty straightforward
if your watch this video he was doing is
talking about what can I do
fun to talk about the Olympics and
grocers whole process explained
can't use the Olympic rings you can make
any reference in with the crazy can
change shape for the Olympic rings
and this case here you can have the
colors donning the Olympic Cassar the 12
colors and some sort of
flatline going 90 so
it's really it's really silly when terms
how the copyright for example this is
what he did so into coming up with a
quick quadrennial
I am cold weather athletic competition
or something like that as we refer to it
as
and missus it mind you it was early
winter is more Spring exit during the
Olympics is here but
in this just give you 90 the absurdity
that the whole copyright aspect is the
Olympics
see nicole there was pretty bang on
about it
and it's kinda sad though because with
the Olympics I'm comes a lot of problems
like in this case here when they do come
to town they do get rid
anything graffiti like in this was not
we feel like this was actually in our
project
on the Citibank you were actually trying
to get ready this art project
and eventually backed down on it but all
it was was just
something is enough for quite a while
but the times graffiti cuz it was
painted on a app
you know cart Sorry plywood board over
when no one really was actually but
there's a
Archies miss the exceeded went on one
thing at a really one night's
I'm somebody plastered blue paint all
over an existing
euros a nice profit that and then a
course for the controversy came out the
penny sign up says new mural coming soon
and has been like that since then
says kind of awful but
tries he must protect the Olympics
Olympic I
try to protect the Olympic brand on it
doesn't always work self
pedobear apparently became a party big
brand
and II and when I'm telling you when I'm
telling years is quite true
the he did become for tonight big brand
inadvertently
because he was featured in a Polish
newspaper
so I don't know how this came to be
exactly
by my assumption like everyone else i is
pretty much the 1i Google Image Search
did Vancouver 2010 mascots and that came
out
and said sure
mind you they hated us later on when
where it was its now I was actually
serbian I think actually that had an
accident but
some Eastern European country had this
poor guy I see crass but nonetheless
gash jokes joke's on us
so retirement tickets here on
tickets for the Olympics were gonna put
this is where my question about where
this one billion dollars and security
when because I actually thought that the
sick tickets were
in secure there is nothing redeeming
about them in terms of security
amount of any beer ever seen Tom be
25 C three ty on bar codes before but
I'm probably gonna tell you
everything you wear the burqa their
prize to the Olympics in Vancouver
so these are your typical tickets you
would get minus the
data fear 0 exe standard center here on
that's it
you can actually there's nothing there's
no real security others no water prints
the is our No water yep sorry watermarks
excuse me
and the only thing that authenticates
quote-unquote that it's a official in
the ticket is the
the hologram on the bottom right there
or you gonna buying why these tickets
here which is starring in it ha grams
there
which is what I end up buying that
actually has nothing
you can see here this is a standard scan
ticket there's no water marks is
pretty much the exact photocopy have the
tickets iPod
except for the hologram there which
doesn't copy over but I explain in a
moment here wanna holograms stupid
and there's the back nothing on the back
there
or you can Olympic pass once again has
no security several perforation goes
down the bottom anyone with a
me to land at a time could replicate and
the friend was
nice enough taxes can his in
you see here no security no security
no security so how do you copy a pass
well thanks to high definition
television it's not that hard you can
pretty much just watch TV
and way for the past two come along
and you can become in part iv: the
Olympic speedskating team in this case
here
really it is that easy reside remember
couple missus is watching
couple matches and you to see those
passing you in one case I was able to
read the tax on the bottom but
if you go back you know you have to do
is just you know
come out with some bullshit name like no
cleaning cleaner cleaning services which
was real
sorry to say like janitors something
like that and all that mattered was that
it looks real now
you going to be wondering what do you do
about the mohagher in there
well that's very kind of silly
and also talk about this in a sec here
actual bring this up shirt some needed
actually masses KK to pass now
this is not this is from my
understanding not the past but this is
the past that supposedly the media was
told about which was
some difference in a pass from Yahoo
Canada said all access
massey get within 10 meters for Vice
President Joe Biden
there is somebody who surprisingly is a
huge fan of a job I and that he had to
meet him
and fifty came in within ten years after
going through all the security check so
this is really are doing dollars and
security in action and you know
cut 10 meters away from now I don't know
in 10 meters is and
yards as by way 30 arts and that's fair
that's pretty
okay so tenure same years you know
that's ballpark right there
so you got really freaking close see
teary eyes vice president itself
always was supposedly passed like this
but thing is though
not secrets don't see secrets for a
while and why the people who worked in
BC Place
when the 10 concerns were going on when
this incident happened
on only heard was that no it was in that
pass it was actually copied
staff asked that had a Marco stolen from
a Visa card
so pretty much answered my question I
when I heard about this did they
actually care about
markowitz really good time to care about
the bar code is when he answered into
the Olympic Stadium
or its original a big event now I am go
back to explain why those tickets for
Steve in the first place
in a moment here but even if you can
grab the
americans are the hologram from the rob
a bank had a Visa card here you could
just as well go buy something from the
omitted from the ritz asthmatic
merchandise
and just you know will blow dryer pull
off the sticker off the label it came if
you're quite see their
so should this is worry comes down to
Kenny copy a pass in the answer is yes
he could have done that there's
no are fitted to be that was the first
thing that we thought of when we had
decided to exit by around these tickets
the bar codes really don't have anything
security Sanders security number
conserved
don't go on one hand in hand and there's
no real watermarks on the mitre so
go back there per se sold what was the
other problem with the tickets well
to talk with the ticket sale system now
metonomy slides for it but
and BC is ax and most can it is legal to
scalp tickets
but there's a way to get around it you
get a license to sell tickets resell
tickets
now in the past on the banker connects
try to lockdown
ticket scalping and all they ever all
the intercom bliss was everyone got
themselves license so
prior to that everyone is hanging around
the streets down there hockey tickets
for you know
300-400 dollars no and says 70 bucks for
the paper the tickets
so when they try to track down everyone
said oh screw will just legitimize
ourselves
just get a license to sell these tickets
and now is multiple companies inaccurate
actually sell tickets
resell tickets after the gym but so
VANOC knowing that this would be a
problem answer president ready a lot
passport but
decided that they would create their own
ticket sale system so if you buy a
ticket for you know
this curling your cock yourself like
that and see you can
make it well you could just go and sell
your tickets for the van Ark accredited
ticket cell site now problem with that
is that you is this you would sell a
ticket
but if you're one of those people who
and others fancy tickets which I showed
a little bit earlier
which has will nicely art on and so
forth you actually got to keep that
ticket
even if you sell on the ticket online
exam we just go to the ticket vendor
and actually have just by Ken ticket
printed out
it was a souvenir for you now the
problem with that is that
you could just go and resell that ticket
to
so you did make money off it for 60
never was nice if you want to buy the
ticket you know vannatter taking a 15
percent error where the hell is charged
and you Jeffersonville ago the game
where they paid for
but then you still have that this will
take it so you could either a
your scalp in the outside risking arrest
her be just on Craigslist and just go
sell your tickets that way
and this actually happened several
people they actually plans
and poppy signature Craigslist and found
that they were deactivated because
somebody
had already sold the tickets prior to so
you can make twice as much money back on
those tickets is because
VANOC don't think this whole system
through
and if you want going back to the whole
Olympic
terms you're pretending to be a big step
it's actually not that hard you can see
here this a.m
water ocean blue kinda jacket and the
red gloves prexy readily available
pretty much any
any the bay for sellers I'm start
shopping oppressors
stew part minced or so if you have that
passing the have the jacket he had those
clubs which everyone in the country seem
to have during that time
on you probably could just got away with
it known about the lanyard but the Jacka
definitely
so last heart you're my sis prize a
Mexican much faster
well okay I'm so last part in this is
all about the CCTV camera network
and this for pretty much just had a lot
of us and thank you for who were
interested in security and privacy
I'm pretty bothered on this one can
using MCT was the official broadcaster
the Olympics and I see happen like to
slow that some be found there
but throughout town Bankura they had
several cameras some setup
basically just watch every move and
every person in the game's
made Andy skin he risk
ahead here to see another camera here
actual back so entire
security camera system a set up
throughout of element at Ross roll all
the sites and thank you for now there
are some
my cam the people that I say
sorry so imagine normally there's about
900 to 1200 cameras in the downtown core
ons when the cat when we want pics came
in the added an extra 2,000 cameras
and just all the Olympic events and
that's not
that's quite a number when you think
about the size of the space at the I'll
take
and the system was adopted was a some
economy cast which is Micah back from
coconut in it
sorry Jan attack which is really stupid
name
and this is the sort a diagram that they
gave out with it so it's pretty simple
IP camera system on but it's rather
interesting because
you can actually be integrated with
something called out a view which is
some certain places plate reader
or the center just which is an IP
is another I keep a system which you as
you do elevator control access control
that's really think so
it was like a whole integrated system so
when I first heard this system serving
in so I kinda wondered if this is gonna
be a permanent thing because
if the took these cameras and integrated
with the on a few systematic or seeking
cue track your movements through
license plates and so forth so it's kind
of interesting in that respect that they
are adopting a system
but and as you can see here in this the
whole map that was actually
mills are the cameras prior to the
olympics so that's fine its website was
in there
in that order excuse me but this is the
thing that kinda guys interested so we
figured out it was you know your
standard camera set up you know mp4
h264 that sort of thing and
it was you know had IP now accounts for
now is OK
uses standard IP camera but then we
became process transmission methods and
discovered 0
it could be doing it over wireless so
three we got really excited over this
was taking your ok great you know these
guys are really stupid how could you
implement a system that you know permits
you know wireless camera sry
and you know you decide okay three three
of us from
other three of us decided that we're
gonna go ahead and do this year's Cano
go and see if we can sniff out these
cameras rakes the wireless then
theoretically week in view them me so we
decide to go for a walk
so we walks from one point the downtown
core 2
was no scanty Street Bridge which sexy
basically covered
am where the hockey games were at have
held
and then where the Russian
Russian pavilion was and that long where
the
the olympic village is unable to build
is on the left side of the screen as you
can see line this low around here
and you know we probably should have
thought this through before we did this
by
when you're in a highly densified area
you know trying to track down wireless
networks
is I'm a specific groceries is a pain in
the ass
I'm when we actually finished the job we
want from there there we found out there
is now known as a good day to
and you know is painfully hard to sort
through
now again backtracked will be here in
are served as back up a lil bit here in
before a say anything here I can mention
what we found only 13 because
how Canadian realize we're gonna
non-lawyers I descend
getting this understanding ron is we can
listen in
but we can tell you the contents what we
found as we walked alongside can tie it
what we said what we saw happen along
the route or anything like that
when I can tell you is we didn't find
anything now
which is kinda sad but I can't I we
didn't find anything
so you can see here these were the years
we targeted
and is easier to low I'm ready area down
there was actually close to couple days
shortly after we done that little job
there
so magazine with an idea for what these
ordinary working with them
what was happening but you know it's ok
for walking for inner-city
see what about the closing is a few days
after around here so
masa said recovered from a heavy
drinking few days for four
am were willing to do this walk we want
to go to the cameras you know their
standards
you know wrote you know your standard
fixed cameras in your standard dynamic
movement cameras animee you know so
little boxes there
and if you look towards the bottom
lawyer thing there from not mistaken is
actually
amor para alla so you know probably
week we've had a dismayed you know the
Paris probably not running to them you
know is that we can't do anything with
this
is nothing broadcasting you know we did
see the lines being run our place we
don't know if they're
eater netter their five yr what's so be
rather disappointed find out
we did find out though that this Lee in
a top is actually a giant Iron Lady Mary
River
trying to figure out you know we thought
it might have been some sort a radar
system the combat with because reason
wireless but
in the end we figured it was actually
I'm some sort of
giant I R flashlight so to speak
but one of the guys so we would so
whenever sexy took a walk to work one
morning and found them setting up a
camera
and lo and behold it was actually 3.net
so basically all needed to run this
whole network was just make one giant
me to network is just nothing special
about it
and yeah it was that a sweet ride
against the CCTV network early scan
understanding if in the end it turned
out to be nothing fancy
which is kinda disappointing by yeah I'm
pretty much that semi-hollow overview I
hope
that from the stock your neck and
inspires people when they're in London
or there and i'm sachi I doubt there's
anyone here from Soji here in
be interest there or if you're in rio
you know I've crowing clergy to just
take a look at the systems at the No
implemented or even ask if they actually
manager systems properly and not in
half ass it like they have turned the
Olympics see you think three billion
dollars it would have done a better job
but
yeah and also thanks to everyone who has
helped me and some
people from a turn organizations help
out Chris R
for instance thank you sam free and
pretty vocal about me nance Olympic I'm
not
anti when picking up for Olympic to see
as now but
yeah I just hope that I'm this can only
set with Sumter inspiration
some thank you
going on as a question okay
so a I just came from Canada to I wasn't
rano
so I got to experience whole t20 thing
full force
and not a lot of the things you
mentioned it struck a parallel with me
because
Tron audit but to the next level we
spent ten billion dollars on security
10 I think that was the number now 11
because what to say
I I'm getting up now but Tom right
I was wondering if you've heard much
about Bryant's on
and his arrest as he was doing similar
things in terms of mapping out the
camera networks and
detachment you can assess kaya yeah I
don't know much about him actually to be
honest with you I but when I found out
he was assessed and then somebody
being a dick actually wanna go to assist
right-handed
I was very impressed over that but I
don't know much done the same anything
but I do have the same rather impressed
that trust and doing dollars in three
days and we spent a billion dollars over
three we scattered over two months lol I
guess ron is all about spending more
town of this this meant US
okay um I'm actually from Mission BC and
arms
yeah I was there for the entire Olympics
evens
run out was born raised their and lights
around
right after 2003 to when
2010 hit there was just all this
pandemonium in
media and it was really the media more
than it was people mike night
friends family did not give a shit like
I really did not know anyone who was
afraid about kato rainy
terrorist organization coming to BC and
start step up
I can save it for everyone but the
people I knew terry but there was like a
great pandemonium in the media
up the crime ok Gabrielle ready when I'm
ready and knife
per se talk to like RCMP officers yeah
I'm really scared about
Sen like went off without a hitch I just
where do you feel that fear and anxiety
came from from the government
that you know there might have been
something really large coming to because
I did not see it
ID with a December that has come from a
prior politicians
and everything makes sense to I think
the whole attitude really comes down to
what's going on in this country for
instance and I think kinda reflects upon
what most the western governments are
doing these days which is
you know this whole you know fear
uncertainty and doubt an
realistically in the end Tom I think
lot of people have become conditioned to
the idea that they should country down
nation but their heads in the sand Cyn
sprayed it nothing bad goes on and
let you know other companies who sell
the security products to
run amok and you know keep us from dying
but honestly
you know worst things ever happened
during the Olympics is actually no
it worse things are happening when pics
is what happened Atlanta 96 which is
worry
pipe bomb went off UNIX Munich is a four
unit was Ian that was before that is
correct
with the idea the Israeli Air kidnapped
from an estimate correct
Munich yes so but I really think most
the Olympic security paranoia is gone
were since 96 but I think with 911 and
all these other things that come along
the governments have decided well
it's in our best interests to go that go
to the extreme you know it's unnecessary
ditches one more quick question do you
think you should been handled the same
way
if it was done all over again do you
think thank you have done the same way
you know it's funny I I think you would
be because it's so
thank you wanted so see what people
think so she's unprepared and has a good
chance it could come back to Vancouver
if you were to come back to make her
come back to North America which she
might
actually would expect it to I would
think that same level turn I would come
back
whether or not the Spanish as much money
I ever spent more
I don't know thank you looks like you're
getting all the Canadians asking
questions
it the first film mission is it the g20
and g8 intron recently
and the point's been made that a similar
cost for security was spent on
post that in the Olympics but at least
in the case %uh Vancouver
they got the potential a economic
benefits of being on the Today Show
begins:
seem cauldron that so I wonder if you
give us your thoughts on that
and also with regard to the the block
block tactic city pension
that happened on the first and thank you
course we saw entrado please cars being
torched
but prior to the olympics the head of
Olympic security was asked if
he would rule ok the possibility of the
using the agent provocateur toxic and
cucumber sorry and would not rule that
out
it seems that we always see these these
people like kurt
and we never fight off with your butt in
the media it's reported that protesters
torched police cars
in a scuttle it reminds me of when you
know some some company allows
a you know the security to be breached
it's reported as hackers
you know penetrate security when they
don't know who penetrated the Securities
ok
it starts or whatever but your thoughts
on that as well with regard to the
via block tactics well and black bloc
tactics
I speaking exciting own speaking as a
for a history major i don't really find
their tactics is really weird
life it's not unusual see the sort of
thing whether or not agree with them
its its kinda you know gilbert et cetera
situation I don't know
how to address it really is they give
you for proper answer that going
and 20 if you feel that was in fact
people that were
I'll be taking over was possibly I'm in
assigning a 50-50 on I like I think he
is very likely did actually have that's
relevant but
at the same time I can give you an
answer at a rate so and little contrast
in Vancouver's
security 00 dry I would say that was
better value for the money even
I don't know whether or not the Olympics
and it will spin off anything good for
the city
but whether or not the it was better to
spend it in Vancouver or Toronto it's a
banker definitely
researchers at least it was for the
people enough for no
forty reynolds guys who I don't give a
damn about
yeah I'm just wondering if from if the
Vancouver city environment was
was restored to its initial state where
were all the cameras taking down where
all the security mechanisms taken downer
all
for trying all the walls disappeared so
that was a good thing but with regards
the cameras
measure policeman to my to keep them and
they're really not pushing for
unfortunately this current city council
seems to have some serious im 17
Telligent seem no its kind to be able
and they just voted against devoted to
keep the cameras could not keep them
on fixed so basically what the man is
they have the camera still but they're
not in place in the morning
bring the mounds parent name on their
special events going on
I kinda take that view as in the the
they want to just keep it around and see
reconsider implementing and kisses
always been that talk to bring cameras
into downtown core anyway
as a common topic comes across the whole
country to be in with so
I I'm hoping that the camera see is go
away and they don't come back but like
they could wear
rear their ugly head again so
hi I'm I heard that there was a lot of
trouble with the weather
in the Olympics and I was wondering was
there any interesting technology
deployed to
dump trucks just in time for it to snow
I kid you not so the said Beach they
weren't lying when they said it was
going to be the greenest Olympics
because
it was plain green grass everywhere if
you sign it first photo if I was going
to the growing Matt
kids go to curling oh that Greenfield
there that was our
that was the first-ever spring Olympics
on now that's for sure
but they didn't they had a snow event
the executes all these people have
standing to actually watch the games cuz
resist
months no over the place but what they
did is a
brought snow from place commanding Park
which is about 203 and a climbers' away
from
thank you for itself run all the way
into the city centre into the
that's why the mountains north to the
city just so people could ski on
so yeah they were green olympics ever
whether but he had held the term
footprints of
so yeah I'm there's nothing else I thank
you very much
my