actually not as good times as a resource
sleep I think doctor
you're up for the talks not important
part good quick announcement I wanted to
make
of 5 o'clock vere was sniper friends ex
Park has been cancelled
it's actually can be replaced by the
white man talks on the way he talks will
be in here
Lovelace are 5 o'clock tonight also
mentioned for our amateur radio
exams going on now are done ima on the
sixth floor
I think these go until about one o'clock
information about them
is in the program so that said
mom GPS some pretty cool stuff
as far as i'm concerned. are it's just
some magic that
tells me where I need to go and I'm
staring down at my screen on my your
GPS my car it turns out there's actually
a little bit more to learn
and now Caceres you're gonna give us
really interesting details in
in not only on how GPS works but really
starting to
talk about had actually interact with
the data comes out a GPS
from maximum
my newscasts learned chairman-elect UN's
year
I give a similar dogs a Trenton computer
for stallone
couple years ago hands and I
correspondent was burned the SM he may
some
very nice it s since sanctions for
modified to talk for sounds
is bad and yes hearings audience yeah
okay
how I think he deserves a round about
flowers
%ah Kb
United this is my business card I puts
my
card in its own it so people can find
I do a family but the sense she emailed
to jihadis am showing here
who worked at Monmouth dot com I would
gladly send you a copy absurd view
graphs has put into the subject line
times 90ps stalkers homes
as in going to the trash
first said we
talk outline hours I would give user
general specifications 72
GPS with tacos about a different
kinds have GPS units how
and if when if the important things I
want to show you is how you
how you are part to believe you need to
order to catch a unique
figures have drums in clock information
from the satellites where you really I
Tim Hudak a literally owe you some GPS
for high
Kenyan for geocache and what's in the
future
is somehow I
whom he faring to GPS a lag the last one
then learn how to use them out how to
use a compass
you wait for the rescuers now is the
basic design
we have GPS develop
died Department of Defense we also have
said
long mass man developed by the National
federation which was so the market bond
now D
with some extra satellites for 10 Jack
10 11 Sat lies
out apt 221 and taxes and the Sensei
gave you a she very sad said fun Tuesday
to
put these dogs Susan so they can I slow
cages dog
however damn I don't think that too many
reasons a few receivers for glonass
but said no term up to an American man
consumer type standards toussaud's Oh
God
video system and develop my dear
European Union
which is in development stage she when
it was a problem self
GPS is that it's operated by im
did the Department of Defense and he was
a very few that I
turning it off in case have any conflict
him
his ass no signal so calm so
bases give 24 satellites seem
he-man twelve-hour are bits it's about
20,000 kilometers from
from hours and so on twelve-hour RB
twenty-four satellites usually every
for dirt five satellites interview on
Sat time sometimes
have to six or seven depends on where
you are
and and to specific now time off today
two justices said that more or less to
scare you CJ arson
and went to satellites are solangi about
tears to diameter is them
soon 6,000
for to you train about 6,000 kilometers
diameter years and here we have about
20,000 kilometers
had two heart beat so two-shot nights is
sad
act is horrendous numbers satellite
which arson background
now he said Jim main operating modes
have the GPS is GM
precise mode used by season and by Jim
Department of Defense him some federal
agencies
it so soon qua
to resistant to jam to civilian Mon
he said used to be very inaccurate
Mt puts it in the facts factors
scarred selective availability and
president clinton decided one day to
hand which
I'm and select if I remembered it let's
make it useful for
everybody should the current precision
up the civilian system is about the same
has so often military system except its
him prone to jamming X backed
normal come and in normal conditions
it's it's quite precise at about
10 meters accuracy nazar
two modes nazar two modes are hen
2 a.m. names differential mode
and say phase comparison most useful
surveying
on soon vein for surveying you can get
them
accuracy switch could go down to
centimeters really
them cm the financial markets was quite
see popular be farts is dispatch factor
was removed
currently it is have no doesn't give you
an extra precision
am since a few years said a new mod was
added
said weas and practically on new
receivers have his capability
and Zack capital of geosynchronous
satellites
whenever the SCO's 10 visit Wesco Coast
hi to be geosynchronous seen as a wrist
revision arbatov
24 hours you need 10 arbatov about
to 50,000 kilometers to consume
twice as high his as a twenty-four
satellites
I did gives you some extra precision
zones are some ground station
which to which I'm have your system will
respond
now this is M pad to which
in a few skids a hot dog to this is the
most important part of my
dog how you determined to positional
vertigo
how you have extremely precise clocks
on two satellites Shaw to be determined
cesium clocks which
are to it in like one sec games three
hundred years
kisses accuracy in addition sad being
controlled from the ground
says how I switch in Han fume
nanosecond Sotirios time and CM
says satellites and signal switch had
received by you to GPS say you need
and its SS now its you have no clock
one minute being have no clock domain
that's being
and denied they should do it says
satellites and
to as it can serve information someone
is the clock information centers some
so-called
FML this information which gives precise
location of each satellites
day specific time soon if you get if
coming over astronomy if you know if
Emery service starting in no way to ice
is where its
where is his sis when it arises when it
goes down
and where it is said any precise time
during its passage hun sky
handing that issue get almanac
information
which give said the shin which
as you uses said with music clock is
not working on a reef if to something
wrong quits in with your
satellite and disinformation is
received by your by your GPS unit
sahnoun that's it to make things simple
they assuming
just too sad stew satellite seen any
change
and she added 24,000
kilometer sub-par now it's three hundred
thousand kilometers per second fiscal
response to a
the milliseconds K now you measure
you you check you compared to a clock
since that time signal coming from
satellite why I'm
which this second with a time signal in
your review need
and you find its ninety milliseconds
compared to
the clock signal coming from satellite
to do you do you need
and you find its them
it said his 60 milliseconds to ninety
plus 60 is 150
no de ti so what's what's a reason for
that reason is that your
local clock you saw by an
would be a
89 to the song by
him 75 milliseconds
CV now subtract from 90 75 height 75
millisecond you come
which 55 from
6235 25
so if you he just your local clock
by 35 milliseconds
San to distance would be correct
matthew is now you know you clogs
your local clock is readjusted and now
you know that you are
55 damn sorry hand which is
16 and a half thousand kilometers from
one sideline
and 25 times 375
100 kilometers from Zaza satellite so
you can
exactly determine your position on
signal of notice
I just made the simple it's a
two-dimensional
two-dimensional track nation shirt off
English US vs three things and
in the reality you need for him you
need at least four satellites to
to give you time signals saw from for
satellites you will get boasts in
position on the globe and your hide
about few ham
time now to see them
so here I showed jurors them
should PDF what I was saying
here here's a little picture which shows
said so on
basically you you get your clock signals
from
from satellites you note widget
satellites I
you know what the satellite's position
is and from geez you can get a knife
how we made our fast your local clock is
good justice stock o'clock now if you
know
you taking out a difference between your
precise
satellite your precise knock knock used
as three hundred thousand kilometers per
second speed
and you know exactly where you are in a
relation to two satellites
hands FFM a race information issue we're
just satellites higher
newest spec to to jurors for now you
know where you out in two years
who dis is basic self to satellite
navigation
now to have various sources of error and
there soon I seem to
them to sing are coming into
and when is a major source is a manner
is said his urine signaled bounces
descent
ham Jack to frequency currently being
used
1.2 gig and it's an 1.5 on prime
its kind and one is to 21.5 you see
is used by the military you use it and
one which is from one point to give you
a heads from one point to give parents
is about to our
25 centimetres sewing this gives you
some feeling
House is signaling proper propagate how
it will be
reflected from various ham
from buildings from surfaces
and seldom to to know exactly where
hand where you at warehouses Signum
pound
con connects to you you have to
make a model of its it rapport Spears
who is a signal has to pass and as some
had earlier seen it
in fact if you do some hiking through
Swarts who receives it is sir which can
nap you may be owned by a fifty meters
for 250 meters
13 open terrain you are with him five to
10 meters
she she said to various sources a manner
now s you can adjust your room
your day time signal your local time
signal
extremely accurately through just super
precise clocks on the satellite
and can be used for synchronizing
networks
and to synchronize networking me am
that she hoped in HS for air few
milliseconds spices signal inside
d can be used for crypto Gadhafi for
passing information at the very specific
time
various and not so applications for
really precise time information which
can be
received should quit everywhere
un siglo
now GPS interactivity cm
season am number one
this lol good have a kid 20,000
kilometers in
Jr's are zones in clocks and moving
I'm JM satellites moving quite fast
twelve-hour RB around here cars
so I just affect said time signal you
probably hard to know if somebody would
call on you to speed up
like he would to stay
10 min young d said actually measurable
effects
and symposia 10
special relativity theory and said
general relativity theory affects their
clocks
and she actually get the job state
fordice effects from taking down
sheen admission to the satellites same
Department of Defense has a number of
stations which communicates which is
satellite images made his cage as the
Clarks
sense ephemeris information on my Mac
information
it's in this area they 22 users
had was showing today said document
48-page document
which refer to which am
using and back offered by the Department
of Defense which
explains exactly what's how to activate
its theory
affects the time seems
now won once you get to YouTube position
and keep you have a sequence of
positions enough cause your speed
and unit part W Nate's have have
have man ok and so fair little
computational
programs so you you'd say will convert
his position to that the 22 longitude
into GA you TM if you are
doing some work which them where you
would want to know exactly distances
in you TM is idea because it
game both east west north south each
unit is one meter
wearing when you going uses Sacaton
to that it didn't longitude cuz when you
going long-term going onto longitude
one second is it's a by manages one
nautical
how one there my non sequitur backed
it goes to 0 new nodes you to Paulos
words in notes I would say launch a not
the duties
the same second this is second with you
music poner
equator a tu Compu distances
me get a little complicated
so I'm once you have to reading self you
to position
cuz you get speed divides them
just as bad time months ago to
to speed you get then position you can
and now plan now decide where you are
going to you can get said that action
get heading marrying hunting formation
required for
navigation by followed by Keiron and by
by a hike
now in how okay quickly about the
different types of
for have GPS you hand has you
watch you on Etsy him
on the jet ascap luv years Chicago units
became
why to resume be prize he used to be a
seven thousand dollars how you can get
one
couple hundred dollars
sedans and sanyo zio Hampshire survey
and surveyor types which
hand night you talk about 100 s how
surveyor
top you go talk about 10,000 and the
military has
known 90 of GPS units
and god only knows how much 22 DeCoste
to you soon they've built in
cryptography it is
and systems and so if I don't know when
remember the crack
how decides in Maine futures have GPS
receivers
your Identive panel in the inputs you
can get to a
to hand 215 satellites
and the same time your some have
fam you can get
to him depending on to costs to you have
door-to-door communication you have
your fair Spain left-right Twitter
sorry
them varies them new
genuine hey to make sure him do you can
start
waypoints which meeting dvd-video point
you can start places where you are
you can start track where you walked
are where you draw of you can go to
college
to you can you can build two-way
pointing to a row it's
sense when you have a number of it out
you can because have
how is a memory getting cheaper and
cheaper and
for what was squad today expensive
hope impossible to get few years ago now
and now you get
you you get day you get maps
you get base map see a detailed maps
and him you can
view you can name chains ohs maps
you can bite him my I was talking about
maps late have doctored our navigation
is became popular in the last couple
years
separate all good on its way which few
short days
pass out to go to his sons ham
I worked once on something called mentee
at a Korean
CJ if you want to go from A to B
you can't really do an exhaustive search
to of on possible doubts it would
be I'm even for a simple connection with
its
history city would and into billions
have possibilities
so you use various algorithms
which him mostly just look at situation
past and selected chart this one
of course there has his you will see in
their
near that road video I have a GN does
know is
lead you to we would like to go sorry
never see if you have your favorite way
of going
stick to it can't back to if you have no
idea how to get from A to B 10
in you soon use go to know
don't navigation cause him show
regular programs running on your GPS so
you see it on and then expand her under
Windows
mobile platform you can
down proprietary program sir
you he isn't it may be a.m. group of
users switch
an which can act sick all weekend
who so is some kind of trap door now
here he adds various types here
hand-held wats hand mostly
for hiking use special specialize you
image thank my wife uses one
this is for geo caching our talk about
it little later
it actually download scrimmage you could
be geo caching sites
to very soon a.m. posing values
places where you cash is sound start
so it's so you can to geocache US
any GPS bed is so gives you a little
hedge standard %um now
here you have a car unit which
I'm to the show's to pick to know to
Harry I were to make it turn enters
intersection senator this dish and
military units
them services donkey I don't know where
this was a.m. is he weird two years ago
I'm talking about tens of thousands of
dollars for
he choose from the one billion in many
conflicts
to two soldiers and ask you you and your
family to send him
has civilian units return should be more
user-friendly
how he adds various
him on each a.m. GPS you have been
numbered of
screams hand and you use
you can cycles through the various
schemes
said this is Aaron screen which shows
you the satellite
coverage and UN's it made land use ito's
circles and you see how many satellites
out a visible to the GPS
it's in various circles and
saying to sing but isn't this cert
circle which can still be received by
your GPS
the distance to the service clues over
5,000
I'm better have over 5,000 miles
this is a compass who knows him as a
now as it display on your GPS which him
will show you soon he if you move
it will show you where note since houses
am somewhat say units now have bouncer
electronic compass about
to pay nines in egg because he he said
to have to
very reset it once in a while very
welcome in this circle
TG Sharon his son as a screen which
use quite often chose who goes left to
eat shows you that this stones
to your destination for your speech hem
now used on the plane shows retail as t2
into time to you get
this is an as a popular hams display
which is set to relax three-dimensional
saint is Casey's Egypt
should go slightly dizzy left to get to
destination
soon as it's clean this is a
jazzy when was so the way and says
swear you wear little got synthesis
harder
more elaborate unit and one problem is
that
since a call or scream and allowed to
unit two required
so lots of powers for the smaller units
with an aunt
on to Savio's to AA says where and for
hamp sorry phone towers were here you
would have to change your batteries
quite often as soon as it popular in
screen you will see top commenter
commenter odometer
so see where you were how fast you are
going into to comment they're scared
changes
issue speed increases so let's see if
you own a plane it will go
600 miles if you walk goes from 0 to
maybe
20 mines this is
time screen which shows a local time
possibly today UTC time
hose surgeon time to: to you knife to
to do this nations and
time to 2 a.m. time how long queue to up
now
to GPS
every GPS his is easy USB or serial
for
certain
this is how a GPS unit converses with
CPC
now you can you can use these
part to update your use software
if you hiked the computer you can a few
high Q GPS you will know how to
how tune getting to it see in there it's
now this usually a trap daughter
yes shades im
basic communication unit communication
protocol does
NMEA National Maritime
Electronics Association home 20 183
and you can find him I have it to him
to brought donuts usually act 15 20
pages
where do you have an discredited the FIM
if you descriptive characters you sent
the information to the GPS
and to you check some and Janet to
response how
give South Gate give some examples
showed ziff farm at Dove Sen holtz's
phrase is being sent to jail GPS unit
and received from the GPS unit his
city's
nm yea and it starts with a dollar sign
when you have a descriptive words and
you have to date can you imagine you've
been
hostilities scans and you have it
checked Sam an
if you can make you GPS to an
save its ear
some kind of 10 min them emulation hands
through
28mm nation program ten you can easily
send
information to GGP is miss you
Han
however to be accepted by DGPS you have
to
give each XM he wrote a letter to
programming basic you can easily
translated
to to any hazard language
so it's ok to have reached the reach you
for days
between two dollar sign in to ask that
is
and tack to work is done
he's done and to next screen
line 970 you
you XO order each successive
for him he successive ask you in it
and chain once you exiled from left to
right
you end up with well I'm one by
ham so high no and
you have to send sis by after disasters
to any content information will be
accepted by
Bay GPS you and he fits
in contact 10 its and
to sentences faces silly check
here is set in
hand an example you are sending it is
to topline to to use GPS to find same
to find 2 a.m. to see attentive version
of your version of your software and
to him to identify you who you need
and what comes back used to be you know
its
them it gives you 2 p-8 P which is
product by defeating
identification this software
identification
two incomes characters stewing
which is steer name a few units hopes to
see you
match and then it was a hands magellan
sparks track
hands and sentences serial number of
your unit
Han this is important because
many software companies
now in use a cell use of 20 guy to your
specific
unit sorry if yourself to receive said
wrong
here serial number it one it won't work
now usually do you get the GPS unit it
is a biz p.m.
basemap when them when you go to a
different
today a reality go to Europe his base
map will not work
you want to get in as a basement to him
GPS manufacturers chance you probably
modes into
GPS units should have areas hacks
to install base maps on on GPS units
and Jack defendant Louie
you need specific now to us what works
with
I G and then they will not work which
Garmin with no
works was Lawrence to where you find out
about it
town newsgroups and
people people just hacked your GPS is
and find out
exactly worked work to do an
I have imagined sparks react so you
tests
and you hold the power key engine
navigation go to navigation keys in the
power key Jenna
has a window into with Dalton with 00
and now you can
chain sieve al you scenes is changes led
to the window
to what you want so I had no chance to
actions actually how to
he stole a base map on UT on your
I gym and GPS had
whenever it to them manufacture attack
magic and finds
had some words pace maps posted a cheery
mood to try to remove him
I
one word of caution you have to know
what you are doing because you
put the wrong number into it said
that to the window you may completely
disable your unit
had many times you can recover from
now
GPS is out great for high Q you
you space you wouldn't know where you
are
want to call you follow a trail you
him it will tell you when to turn left
or right
hey you have to keep track of something
called heading in something called
daring heading is say direction in which
you are going
I mean Norris will be heading out 0
sows who'd be heading up 180 and bearing
is dead angle to you re to your
destination so if you
fewer hey if you can traveling
directly to your destination debating
would be zero
he few have to go to try to bring
maybe twenty degrees its own
if you know what's heading what's
bearing
you you will get to know some of its a
unit chose a turn
tell you too was it to turn left or
right pay a specific
number to a decrease okay
how here i connect and who made a high
Keymer hubert words it's in Monmouth
County
New Jersey and
him to big GPS keeps
three cards to track how you
how you walked so you can 10 transfers
to many software programs is
you know you stop for USA from alarm
and you can transfer cue track
to do to your no I'm
to your PC which is a topo maps continue
can see exactly how you
how you walk how you high stood this is
a great
things you connect your GPS few computer
where you starlets
Topo USA are many other programs
and few you can study
your apt now it's a builtin compacts
say take on passage reading from your
on your GPS see required sick you move
because you know City
satellite doesn't know which weighs
nor suicide case you position who speed
back
to get an idea was is if you stand still
fans is no speech in you done he won no
ways in North Versailles
where noted houses so a compass
this headphone how here I show an very
nice compass
I had one was stone from you tonight
harder one from Germany
deceptive compass Co said our and eight
hundred fifty dollars
packets in compass which is good do it
in one or two degrees
and and TM
you can has a little prism sea view
where
so you can locate CA at your destination
is you turn your compass
and at the same time you can read sick
compass rose
on Thursday ons a compass to it in 102
degrees
if you can afford it whose this compass
is fantastic
II preferred much more to electronic
compass is
which I don't last and does an
electronic compass
came be if you do something wrong kid
with a really mislead you
magnetic compass will not one of the
features of this compass it's quite
heavy it's made
to a with big ass so it
kids who owns it local eddy currents
I can use it on the plane and to him
he it is not affected by aids
beatty action from comes in various
fields
now few words about geocache use a
worldwide sparked
and save this I game it's free
once a special privileges a payment 1525
.se
year it gives you location so a little
cash is so all over the world
it's all on public ground sewing parks
in the recreation areas
ham and T you you will find it easier
you you getting location and the you go
to that place you
look around you will usually find a
little box with some
some knick-knacks inside so
you may take something you put something
in NZ
Loughran logjam on their website Q
discovered so whose and I
hair currently up to about 120 of those
cashews
and that was a big things you do geo
caching is
said you this copper areas in your own
backyard
whenever it where did exist family
beautiful
nature preserve area switch out so
hidden and to tell you discovered Sims
through through an Aptos posts
every week to end new POS showing today
ham same you cash is in your area
here in Maine and Minnesota
have family and friends do some geocache
POS system this is far too rich pose a
kid singer
adults inside
here is so I'm cash we found in New
Jersey seen a tree trunk
to ship talks said I mean this is a
large box
frequency Sara Hammel boxes at you can
also find
some of those caches answers
maybe one centimeter across
maybe hang you 103
also sometimes you have for him give him
switch an like you we went to
an to watch a good as invasion
him Union County New Jersey and we had
three locations
sry site survey tango and
got now you had to do it all away find
fish center of say
center comes hyped Serica and the center
of it was
was without cash to have to do some
computation because
you can't work with latitude/longitude
have to convert to you TM
do with you TM and find your cash is
GPS on a commercial flight it was my
experience I always keep it
it's a good tests how good to use GPS is
if you hold it against the window does
it kasinga
satellite so you know where you are how
far to go how
how fast you are going how you guys get
to it everything
and ham my experience was said
to stewardess yeah I was holding is in
stewardess told me to put it away
I put it that way man just two actors
went ape wicked against singer when
doing
game and then she now she not this stage
show you and our departed the captain
miss him
what can I do and chic and basic captain
said
if you well I'm not super outgoing of
course you can use it
his sorrows you can also find out the
fear if officially today and now you to
use it
as his side am work sweat suit
but that's a very sad Lance policies
hinge and RJ let you use it if you have
to have 10,000 feet
same see with his cell phones
now GDP some GPS on the web at: said
various sites
them jazz shows us some to date magnet
yeah if you have access to Usenet
issues become more and more difficult to
get to
to say good geocache Inc am
am site on Usenet
to manufacture to keep to posts and then
some
churn out your cache Inc hey I'm Geno
ham GPS sides
you can find reviews so various units
says owners yeah
towns are some ham
some 28 magazine you most subscribed to
he said the various ways say Angie
operate am into
power supplies
rechargeable cells Han the manufacture
of course tried to convince you to
subscribe to some service and pay and
pay and pay
GD says the current trends to make its
subscription
instead of I'm time perches
I'm Hosur to you soon
battery switch can be replace
where do we go from here to save him
most of the current satellites reach
their design limit
so it is them ham take new ones will
have we have higher powers block
three satellites now it's the end I
would like to show you deserve this
and my slideshow and with I would have a
little
hair this on
cartoon from simpson's I would like to
show it to you
sure you did showing its age
you can do is rely on third
happy this is the neem
dade document simpson's
thanks to a new GPS don't have you would
green okay where I can
50 major and aviator and media speeches
many yeah I
which is 30 feet encased out picky
divided by kicking nine times can you
take
well you at Miss Georgia Tech
recalculating turn right
and 4.5 meters back now can go
construction I
stupid kid think he's smarter than a
computer do you feel
kids do
do you
do
secret elevation tantrik
entered iraq you have reached your
destination
okay my try
in 2.3 economic your
recaptured a go cold goes home
this a little
audio synchronization problem so
the reason he throws it into the water
is that she's given in the distance
commenters which blows his mind so he
throws it in the water
if you have any questions
go ahead
yeah how is a
Galloway 0.2 g/t thing is that going to
be different from GPS the European
Callao system
were wellhead this and this stand is
still in the planning stages so on and
do that
am I think the so anti shot a couple of
him to us for testing agency shocked why
I'm
when unit out by I'm not sure it's a I
doubt it would be compatible
to provoke you would need a difference
said different
set of receivers teams who is good on us
it's not compatible
good on matthews's said elliptical
orbits resident circular orbits said
said
to Sat russian satellite Sarah
more spend more time over to
Russian federations him
him went to the rest of the world
hello
I'd like to know what company makes
their German compass with the brass
housing
and word order had how Kate's K
if you send me e-mail I will try to find
it and he took me quite a lot of
searching have it's a fantastic compact
cute skinny
and node see to cater in fact I audited
by fallen and
and they said they don't accept any
credit cards
type with 150 hundred dollars in
Antelope
and send it to Germany in network vision
I it's probably more than you need for
I it's great for hiking and shit
fantastic
compress year
in yearly be because it has a
his a.m. babul so you know you get
he'd it is the way you can put it on a
tripod
church it's a really nice unit the
the GPS is used for military and
civilian and so it's obviously subject
to
being it's being its subject to being a
destroyed or tampered with or injured
and also it's also subject to
radiation such solar flares and that's
our thing so if that happens are we to
rely on GPS if it's being used
everywhere and we're all pinned on GPS
Shin
don't you think that sort of a a
dangerous situation
where it says in gode so that dust is
civilian
using gives the soon it says gives him a
favor
Sir JJ done promise anything to do with
keep it going whatever so that's
that's the reason why see European Union
is trying to develop soon
Terron you need 2d did GPS is basically
a military
catch it issues on missiles
you stone for an artillery purposes
and sidelines they give it to today
civilian population and
use it's the way you want it and
to give you no promises since it will
keep it going
I have a question is there any
regeneration from officers stores in
like if you have a storm
lives in her care when I is there going
to be more
error being generated devices today
I i guess im when
he missed army you you will get slight
distortion
to I didn't notice anything and it's
more incidences
in jeans that would send said
to leaf canopy will affect your
reception
much more in some in this storm was you
I'm and I don't really need subsidized I
was
time thinking that the single coming in
from the GPS satellite
from space down there are those curious
if any kind of like
storm a crazy atmosphere phenomenon
mites
I guess you see bands than that or
affected her some
or somewhere with otherwise massive your
yes it made by quic receive like at
least forty five satellites
I guess we have to your his
expect where finished quick one houses
okay hey if you want to have any
question would be outside
%ah