drag me to bed the way girlfriends
typically drag people to bed and I
should probably stop talking about this
right now
okay so how many guys
have been to a previous help before okay
let's
let's let's do the count down here how
many guys were at the last hope
the alright how many okay ted we're not
talking about Burning Man here you can
calm down
how did you guys were at Hope number six
difference somehow many guys were at the
fifth
hope h2k to
HQ K
beyond dope did I forget one
which which one did I forget
oh the first hope for
hackers on planet earth who was there
okay I wasn't so when one person
one one person to 3
up for a course Robert Steele was
therefore oooo of course in Coupeville
was not doing a very good job of being
backstage um
awesome that's great how many guys I
know traditionally the tradition has
been hope happens every two years
and a manuals probably gonna kill me for
asking this but
how many guys would attend hackers on
planet Earth
at this time next year now
okay
yes finally I can win that argument on
the mailing list now
cuts um
other announcements yet this is the last
talk
%uh the evening um and I'm gonna
introduce
a mister steal and give my my story
about and
in just a second but cupo actually
hasn't
up Kush see I'm thinking couple because
I have to give the last person to have
to give teachers to %uh that also
reminds me department heads and people
who work for open and the
network um radio statler and everybody
else is not part of the Corps volunteer
corps
were distributing t-shirts also a
regular volunteers that have gone
gotten their ten hours n can also get
their t-shirts also were tracking
volunteer hours you've had certain
volunteers who have worked
in excessive 30 hours up to this point
on the second on government in front of
for is a statics in the room right now
okay no escribo in the room right now
coupe where is it not here okay
but no actually chris has a couple
things %uh to talk about so if I could
get caught up on the stage a real
quickly
um and that's where you got your radio
of everything like that
in okay Corp
on CL what what what was this
announcement that you had something that
you were
desperately talk wanted to talk about
bacall
you come up here please
relationship is taken many many turns
for the good for the better the past
I love you and will you marry me
the
thank God
she said yes
yeah
yeah absolutely perfectly
I thank you thank you guys
in
okay so so I have a little story about
mister see everybody knows what they're
in for here right
how many people have been witness to
this
Saturday night tradition that hackers on
planet earth before
ok how many people have managed to sit
through an entire one
really how many people are
are where the steel drinking game okay I
got I got a bigger one that but actually
um I I have a personal connection here
turn XP can I tell the story a
arm hackers on planet earth where we
leave the internet lying around on the
floor
traditional isn't
yes we do keep the tubes from leaking
don't Lee
unless wikiLeaks is involved but I'm not
going to get into that
um so it was actually my first hackers
on planet earth conference
I was here with a couple friends mine
from Detroit
um and I've forgotten
all their handles right now because I
call them all by their real names today
Rev render man's everywhere
I remember the whole render men must die
stickers how it does anybody have an
extra render men must die sticker
does anybody know what I'm talking about
am i dating myself right now
okay I sorry but that's ok it was our
very my very first section planet Earth
and of course I went on a hotel room
with a bunch of my friends we ended up
in this
really weird oddly size shape truman
that was really big and that had like an
extra couple love rooms attached to
which were
just totally empty which he thought was
kind word in this course being college
students
whatever first times in a hotel room
this big without we have to throw an
awesome party
see found all over France from Def Con
we found all her friends
that we need from Meijer seen it really
doesn't everybody bought in on a
gigantic cash have liquor
at about maybe 8:30 we went around and
we
literally drain the ice outta all the
machines in the hotel
and filled up the bathtub just
completely for Vice
and then put all the beer all the liquor
everything in there and we actually for
some reason had this crazy Australian
dude who is
and only I don't know what his deal was
views on speaker something but his whole
function
for like 4-5 hours that night was to
continue reading all the ice machines on
the rested for keeping our bathtub full
of ice
now we wouldn't have had a rocking party
had still not brought his crew from the
talk
into the room people who just want to
talk to a more and more more and we were
partying
I think until seven or eight AM I think
actually hotel housekeeping
was the one that stopped our party
because there's nobody else on our floor
to clean the rooms out so that that's
that made my personal experience was
how many guys have collected a story
something like that at this conference
her previous actors and planners
conference
relief that that's its
up
alright so just everybody this is it's
this is a
going to be a phenomenal phenomenal
experience I have because the ground for
everything and prepare to have your mind
blown
I proudly introduce to you mister still
given the huge round of applause
and get sick of it for doing the real
audio
audio here okay home
know this is good if this works for you
on
I'm getting too old for midnight starts
so we should try 10 next time
2200 anyway what I'd like to try to do
is be a little more interactive and
and maybe a little more responsive to
what the group wants in the way of
question areas
so we can go everywhere from whodunit
for 9/11
to dick cheney's cross-dressing to
anything at all that you want
now do we only have one microphone there
why don't I i just want to do a quick
round of kind of shout out what you
wanna talk about tonight
well as at alright JFK
what else JFK
dick cheney cyberwar
okay and we can talk about the cyber
scam
where perfect
perfect citizens well thats you guys
okay 911 be pay
bapa big-time okay
was a tossing 1 for
dwarf tossing
for I was not there
okay faking at the moment it was fake
yes it was done in a TV studio here in
New York
wire for
I'm up the seventh generation warfare
but OK
what for Halliburton okay
nobody's mention their of Charles here
anybody interested in in no
offer
all right all right now all the lunatics
be quiet and just a few serious people
room service
absolutely fair
okay alright alright we're good we're
good
okay where there
group
you know what okay I will announce that
I'm running for president this is the
only time
I will announce that thank you
on but there's a difference between me
and ross perot 1 I'm not a little shit
and to on you've got to get me in all
fifty ballots and no I won't come if you
don't
for alright let saddam
it's gonna take it from the top as best
I can tell
the United States
is run by Goldman Sachs on behalf of the
rock dropped
on in all of our income taxes are
basically channeled
in a manner that disconnects us from the
way in which the money is spent
and in essence congress has been bought
but actually in fairness to the people
buying congress it's congress that
shakes them down not the other way
around the standard rate
on the hill is five percent any project
any earmarked to congress delivers
they expect five percent into the pack
up the member that sponsored
the program at the contractor whatever
okay so we not only have a corrupt
congress
but under Dick Cheney we have a congress
that
consists of foot soldiers they have
abdicated their article one
responsibility
which is why I personally recommend to
you that you
vote out every single mother fucker now
in congress
a
it's called the Constitution it starts
with a C all right now
the bad news is congress
and the governors have show host the
electoral process to make it impossible
for independents libertarians and others
to get on the ballot and I strongly
recommend you a book by one of ralph
nader senior rates called the grand
illusion
on understanding the two-party tyranny
and even here in washington there
I mean here in New York there have been
a couple breakouts Peter Peterson a very
wealthy man
%uh wrote a book called running on empty
how the two parties are betraying
American what we can do about it well
unfortunately nobody in New York and
nobody in washington actually wants to
do anything about it
and one other things you have to
understand is that people like
Ron Paul however much we might love him
a part of what's called the controlled
opposition
there there is window dressing O'bama
was a roadshow okay
Obama broke his promise to make a he
took
money and he has an account it for $300
million to the $750 million he spent
on buckminster fuller
said the white house's fear and he's
absolutely right
on and I did not realize this until I
myself found that my misplaced
confidence in Obama
a was utterly destroyed by rama manuel
on one hand the David Axelrod on the
other this guy is surrounded by a public
mister a pollster
okay and his decisions
are articulated in a manner that is
every day
idiocy a a there is nothing sensible
about Barack Obama for
there's nothing sensible about Michelle
Obama it troubles me that she tells
everyone to go on vacation in louisiana
then heads for me
for these people
are hypocrites but so are the Bush
family so the clinton family
these people are all part of a mafia
that began with macarthur's capturing
the Japanese cold
a story told in a wonderful book by
Peggy and
sterling city grapes cold cold warriors
there's been an illicit
gold fund run out of Treasury since the
end of World War two and it was used
issue gold certificates
and two whenever so that was gonna come
with their
ok good okay things I need to mainline
some caffeine here
I was gonna do it you too it for that
stuff but then they told me it tasted
like shit so
again but drink it anyway
up
alright so the bottom line here is I
think we're at a point in American
history
where we literally need a general strike
on and by general strike I mean a
nonviolent stay home one day
on and unfortunately I have tried very
hard for the last
eight years to get people like Ron Paul
and ralph nader and it may be that I
don't need this if you guys decide you
want to take a tour the internet which
will try it but I can
talk from memory on I've tried to get
ron Paul and ralph nader and Cynthia
McKinney and Jackie say let
to play nicely together and they won't
do it
they absolutely will not come together
and do the one simple thing
that would basically nail congress which
is demand electoral reform in time for
this is not rocket science electoral
reform
there at least four things we can do for
4 2010 including instant runoff
voting on a holiday so the poor don't
have to juggle bus schedules
and of course ballot access for anybody
that can come up with the minimum
signatures this is our country
and we I have allowed it to be carpet
backed
up out of our possession so electoral
reform is the one thing
that Ron Paul and ralph nader and
Cynthia McKinney and Jackie sale it and
Mike Bloomberg if he ever decides to get
serious about running for president
on should all be talking about electoral
reform
it's very very simple Barack Obama
was elected by 30 percent the eligible
voters
I think it was 54.6 her 56.4
the eligible voters that voted and
if John McCain had not been surrounded
by bush's whose job it was to sabotage
his campaign
he would have come out and sided with
the house republicans who were
demonstrating a modicum of common sense
and said over my dead fucking body will
you bail out Wall Street
I would have frozen evictions and
foreclosures and I would have ensured
every american from the bottom up
and I guarantee you it would have cost
10th
above what Wall Street has cost us so
that alone
is treason against the american public
by both parties and that alone
demands that we eliminate the Republican
and Democratic parties from the face
this electoral
process I'm on my best behavior the
medications really are working
owned I so starting at the very top
we've lost control in the United States
we've lost control
the Treasury the government is out of
control
and we're at a point now where stuff has
to be done
for
do you want to try and get video were
that's my power cord this is a really
shitty connection that won't screw in
for you want to get rid of it okay I
guess I'm not using my computer
on
I i really was hoping to give you guys
some
some interesting sites and stuff but you
can help me
I'm interested in being helped I need
help i need a lot of help
I alright so
so basically what what we have in and
it's really remarkable
the Huxley really got it right in 1984
and Animal Farm
on we've become a cheating society
and by the way I speaking book titles
okay so when I kinda have a phrase like
cheating society it's really a book I've
reviewed
on Amazon and if you go to Phi Beta iota
done net
and I simply pick that after my free
Obama done net site
didn't arouse a lot of excitement on 58
iota done that is where have all my book
reviews and I have pointers to the
30,000 pages in OSX dotnet
and to the start of the earth
intelligence network which is in there
IRS a 501 c3 we can give you a letter if
you wanna donate things in
jay Z is selling what's left of our
books back there
and he's based in New York and encourage
you to look at his website
reconfigured out or real so as the
T-shirt he spent a year researching that
t shirt I have never seen anyone do a
better job
deep research that he has done on the
true cost to that t sure how many people
are familiar with the true cost me
holy share you're a bunch of dumb fucks
%uh okay sorry I know you come here to
be abused by me and I i do it with love
on let me hear let me bring you up to
date on what's happening in the world
%uh what do I need to do with wireless &
cell phones
oh absolutely absolutely endemic
I really wanna try and be a little bit
more interactive but I do want to get
the questions on the air
and I also wanna say thank you whoever
it is that took my last
spy improv and turned it into like 50
really cool audio sound bites with text
captions
I have some books to give you on I'm
really
grateful and humbled by the fact that
some would spend that much time making
sense out of
four hours serve stream of consciousness
talking on
we
half kind if been put into a position
where
on we have no se
I mean we the reason I titled my brief
your
two days ago when they don't packing
humanity is we've taken the humanity of
politics we've taken the humanity at a
business
we've taken the humanity and everything
and what's really cool is that the one
inexhaustible resource we have on the
face of this planet is the human brain
and the human brain can create
infinite wealth just to digress back for
a second the cell phones were finding
out that cell phones are killing bees
which is going to wipe out our
agriculture pollination cycle okay
and I'm serious this is the one
intelligent think CNN is done in the
last twenty years
are okay
it's a start fake here
a.m. and i won a fake Nick to
are he he he's the head of volunteers
and I didn't realize he was gonna hold
it over my head for the rest of my life
but the we did in fact meet over bath
tub
and in Nick
let me have his bed for two hours man I
didn't use the sheets
%uh cell make your bed still claim and
thank you for giving me a nap
really that just showed some
class there thank you on so I think we
really have to take care of to get a
grip on yourself and the kinda make this
plea about humanity in its potential
CK Prahalad who should get the Nobel
Prize I mean here
but two or three nobel prizes given
recent leader that are really good one
was to be honest
on Press election get another one I
won't mention the two idiots
gotta nobel prize is one of them for 10
days in office
on I mean these people are shameless
they're prostituting themself
buckminster fuller wrote a book titled
integrity
integrity is about more than honor its
about feedback loops
it's about data without errors it's
about I subtitled my new book
clarity diversity integrity
sustainability
show coming back to CK Prahalad he's
pointed out that capitalism is based
on the one billion riches aggregate
income is one trillion
you know come back to true cost in the
second because I am shocked
that a group of this intelligence
doesn't really have a grip on
on the four to five billion
poor people have an aggregate annual
income of
four trillion so if capitalism
based on $1 billion rich $1 trillion
market they're buying sub-zero fridge is
every two years
and African refrigerator cost two
dollars and consists of the cement pond
with a long neck and ear cap another
cement pot with a long neck in Newbury
this in the ground and it keeps me fresh
for five days
and Genesis latest book on social
business is certainly worth reading
the bottom line here is we have been so
busy screwing the bottom of the pyramid
we haven't
realize that they're the only thing
that's gonna save us
and so that's why the earth intelligence
network came together conceptualize the
idea
both educating the poor oneself call at
the time
and Nokia now has a cell phone that
operates on ambien energy
so it doesn't need an electrical
recharges night this is very cool
on the chinese have cell towers that are
solar and wind-powered
and at Burning Man which I'm hoping to
go to my first one
I'll be in the village that's being set
up by doctor doctor
Dave Warner wheaties and mercifully
worse Leslie he's an md/phd
neurosurgeon was some real psychological
problems
on and and I love them for that on he's
really one of the coolest guys I know he
and Eric Rasmussen created strong angel
he created choose a which is an analytic
tool kit on a flash drive and I want to
improve on that
because where I'm going with the world
brain is we should all be part of the
world brain and we should all have a
a structured method for for information
sharing and sensemaking
on so we really have got to get a grip
on and now to just talk about true cost
for a minute and then I'll
let you guys intervene on me a second
want them all to JFK
arm again when the gas costs 350 four
dollars whatever
that's what you pay at the pump prior to
BP
exxon and these others were
externalizing
twelve dollars a gallon and costs
so jay-z when he did this t-shirt in an
absolutely
totally blown away with admiration he
did the true cost that
white cotton t-shirt in terms of water
the number of gallons it took to grow
the cotton
washer chip so forth of fuel
the fuel that was used up by the
machines harvesting the con
and so forth the fuel used to transport
it child labor at fifty cents
day on that's what's true cost okay so
true cost actually gets down i mean
it takes more water to make the plastic
that the scope comes in
then the the water contained in the coke
in fact
coca-cola stealing water worldwide
Minnesota just threw them out because
they want to become an addict down into
the act for export Minnesota's water
as coke a new hampshire's well thank you
and we are part of a collective and I
really wanted
to encourage on interventions from the
audience
a a if their sensible shout them out
%uh so that we can get kind of a
collective back and forth going here I'd
like to see this work
I shall I go to JFK
alright up a little bit a BP first up BP
by the way was responsible for the Exxon
Valdez
on and one of the interesting things
about BP is they've perfected the art of
making promises they don't keep
on essentially the US government which
is trying to micromanage stuff and we
can get in the complexity theory and all
that other good stuff
and I can also view some mighty stuff
some security stuff some cyber scams
stuff
home logical people in the federal
government
understand the risks associated with
undersea drilling and so forth and BP
and others when they're given these
leases are required to commit
to having 24/7 emergency response teams
within four hours have any possible
breach
fully trained crews ready to go up bowls
and everything ready to contain this
within
you know 12 hours whatever and what they
do is they
they set all that up and then they let
atrophy to the point that it doesn't
exist anymore
okay so essentially BP violated the
public trust and of course BP is
operating under public charter
what's at cushion for the wall
want it one
I'm sorry I'm sorry just poured a spirit
stick is what he said
if I hope she likes beer up
alright so JFK
up my take on JFK based on reading a
number of books including a book that's
very popular 5800 to the review of JFK
who killed a man why it matters:
I believe that JFK was killed but cuban
exiles trained and equipped by
the Central Intelligence Agency and that
at least select members at the Sentul
intelligence agency were actively
complicity to include individuals in the
office of technical services they
created fraudulent Secret Service
credentials
that allowed the perpetrators to escape
and I believe that will come out
in time just as it is now coming out
that
the we all knew the Gulf of Tonkin
was a fraud on and it's now coming out
that the Gulf of Tonkin was seriously
debated within government
enormous doubts existed in secrecy was
used to deceive Congress and the public
now in the case of iraq dick cheney
didn't bother with secrecy heat issues
935 documented lives
and we let them get away with it okay I
highly recommend a book called the
weapons of mass destruction don't be
fooled by the cartoon cover it's a
superb book
on so JFK Martin Luther K an active
state I believe the FBI ordered him
killed in the army helped if they
provided the sniper
on so we've got some pretty bad things
not only to ourselves yes sir
room more than one
on small tit not test at all us what was
a patsy at least one
I mean but yet to and one and I think he
was killed from in front
okay on and so all this stuff is
starting to come out what's actually
fascinating to me is the way in which
the public sit silently and allows
whitewashes to happen
me talking about the 9/11 whitewash that
the National
technical security whatever the hell
they are won't release the findings from
the World Trade Center controlled
demolitions
by Larry Silverstein who had Rudy
Giuliani who had the dump trucks lined
up the day before the accident
books and they all had GPS
so that they can track where the rubble
went and the firefighters rioted they
call them school but don't call you on
it because he was coping and don't think
and we have
and we now have courtesy of German
hackers we now have all of the
cell phone calls on 9/11 and all the
reports of bombs from 9-11 and that also
came out across the radio waves on the
TV channel said
there were a number of news broadcasters
that basically announce things before
they happen
because they were being fed news feed
when you get down to doing a serious
time analysis
%uh 911 I think you will find that it
was not only allowed to happen
but that dick cheney three months in
advance schedule that counterterrorism
accident so he could control our
response
and ensure that we did not interfere
with their this is serious possibility
that there were unmanned aerial vehicle
controls on those two jets
and the WTC 7 was the final control
point and it was brought down by
controlled demolitions
on them by the way was a hit by anything
okay on so I am very concerned and I
like to try to keep my credibility with
with those who view their
did think conspiracy theory is evil on
by saying that we don't know for certain
but I absolutely agree with Mike Rupert
and others there is more than enough
information out there to tell us number
one it was whitewashed and not properly
investigated
and number two Larry Silverstein rudy
guiliani and Dick Cheney should be
indicted and I would like to see Dick
Cheney Hunger Force guys ask
what's there I actually I'm told he
likes leather
a a very prominent bisexual who is a
really great party you're told me this
personally and I think he was speaking
from
I
we won't mention any names up no
but he does two 14-year-old boys %uh
okay
a no more guessing a
I let's talk about cyber or for a little
bit is there
alright I'm a dumb shit that doesn't
know anything about technology but I'm
smart enough to
count how many people are doing deep
code research in this country in the
number 67 there are 67
people in the United States of America
doing deep code research and 12
those are doing defensive decode
research
how do you spend $12 billion dollars and
sixty seven people
you don't this is a cyber scams
you and I have written a detailed
article in Homeland Security today
that identifies the sixty-seven people
by Research Center none of which have
major grants
from the Department of Homeland
stupidity or
from an essay or any other party the US
government I'd like someone in the
audience to define decode research
humph
the way it was explained to me is source
code
Ruth I mean right down at the very
bottom which is
where do you hide shit at the very
bottom in source code
like I say I'm not a technical person
what who wants to define
decode research okay
binary analysis works for me also
I mean you can't hide a lot of stuff in
hardware
on that's why I believe in open source
hardware not just open source software
on open everything so
I'm really in concert with the details
what matters to me is that they're only
let's say five hundred people in the
united states that are actually doing
serious code research
and Washington is planning to spend $12
billion dollars on seic which totally
fucked up Trailblazer
for NSA on an SRA and
csce all these companies are
scamps they basically higher what we
call
butts in seats these are US citizens
with clearances you don't know jack shit
about anything
but they can be built okay
and this is a scam on
and part of the problem we have is that
the US government is now run by
contractors
contractors now occupying final
positions at every level of the National
Intelligence Community the national
security community we even have the
occasional Australia
who's given away too much authority on
just because they like his accent on can
call it comes to mind
you know he helped vitreous hose up
counterinsurgency
we should talk about Afghanistan to
IT security
is a very very serious in 1994 Jim
Anderson from an essay and when Shortell
and bilk alien I put together a memo
to the National Information national
and II national formation infrastructure
okay and we sent this to Marty harry
said we said Marty you have a problem
coming up this is nineteen ninety-four
now
back when I was told that was on the
lunatic fringe for thinking things like
this
we said Marty you need to spend a
billion dollars an information security
we need to make sure that SCADA systems
for example are not on the Internet
well I don't know whether party ever
read the letter but it is on my website
if he wants to read it
if he hasn't died since then on
stuff people know I mean the US
government was briefed about peak oil
for
and and the in 1974
and it knew about peak oil in it knows
about peak water in congress is
basically separately that for someone
else because we don't wanna make our
decisions
so I think information security is very
very important
and the easiest way to achieve it in my
AK
uneducated view is by going with open
source
I mean I love the Linux guys when they
say put enough eyeballs any bug is
visible
and I think the same is true for true
cost information the same is true for
corruption
%uh the same is true for absolutely
every aspect managing complex affairs
and let me just make a short a creche in
its complexity and resilience
the world has gotten too complicated for
Berrian
stovepipe management okay
basically Washington is trying to
regulate things it doesn't understand
and can't control because it's not in
real time
and they have not done the bottom-up
resilience building that's needed
alright so what we really have to think
about
is how do you make the whole thing open
and had to establish standards for
example I've tried three times with john
chambers
on to get him to build an individual
router
why can't we have application-oriented
networks
at are individual laptops
so that we can apply the rules to who
sees what
and how it's handled and so forth and
I don't know much about growth and
things like that but I personally
believe that we should be able to
install
information security including content
control and
and attributes and reach back routing
and all that
at the point if creation
soul somebody smarter than me is is
gonna figure that out
now does anyone wanna jump up with the
burning question are showing both 22 of
tossing
yes sir yeah I can use a microphone
eg got the go-ahead is a microphone and
checked the topic and you know there's
so many have you here I feel so bad
that this isn't some kind a circle how
many have you know about open space
technology
home I'm going to help you
on what do you can inject I with I was
thinking arm
the national debt yeah and um possibly
legalizing substances to
eliminated
I love it I mean marijuana absolutely
should be legalized
n/a and but
but hear me clearly it should not be
legalized so white boys can't get high
legally it should be legalized so we
stop putting blacks in prison
okay yeah aunque
I mean I personally want to eliminate
the personal income tax
on because it's a it's a fraud I mean we
should be doing consumption taxes we
should be doing the Tobin tax financial
Texas things like that Energex air
freudian voting machines and its use in
subverting recent elections
%uh its massive anybody stupid enough to
accept an electronic voting machine
deserves the result they get here
on and that there is a member in the
audience here
you is telling me that some very good
things are going to happen in that area
and I'm really excited about that
on you know computers were built without
talking to librarians
I mean this is the problem I have with
engineers is they don't recognize that
there are people out there that know
stuff
that's relevant for to the metal that
their ben de
on and so we've kinda lost sight of what
computers are energetic sharply
what I don't understand is a you know
real stuff about the
vote a king and and made sense to me
what happened in 2006 in 2000 and i'd
did did did the you know Republican
Party have
the ability to steal the election and if
so why did yes I mean first of the
election
in 2000 was stolen up by Jeb Bush and
everybody knew this in advance
on great pay last a friend of mine who
admire very much as a journalist he did
the story breaking it in the observer in
England three months at a time
and I am told by someone who knows
someone who was in the room that warren
christopher
brought the offer 24 from wall street
which basically said if you fight this
we're never gonna give you a speaking
fee in your lifetime
if you don't fight this you will be rich
beyond your dreams and
I don't think they threw in the Nobel
Prize for so it came to pass
what senator okay hang on it that's a
fraud
very strong as a criminal on
and dove but in 2004
the Ohio State Governor basically put
all the good machines in the probe which
districts in all the bad machines in the
black districts a democratic districts
and that election was stolen also
however you have to give
John Carey credit anybody with a fucking
haircut like that
is not qualified to be anything all
right for you
and she's married to a world-class pitch
okay
so the man is toast and and that's what
I mean by controlled opposition
okay I mean Carey was basically a fall
a staff always a very smart man and he
knows it george bush's sexually
conflicted as other ships okay
are because he was there up
but the reality is these elections he
just played out I wrote a book
collection 2008 lipstick on a pig
on and it's all free online now I notice
there's a group that you're so very
quickly let me get your questions and
interjections and then we'll move on out
there any other microphones
I was where the front when the middle
okay go ahead
so I'm from Toronto we just had the g20
and I'm just wondering what your
thoughts are on the Black Bloc
if you know about them on the black
block
cell some other people have said that
their a allowed to exist
or are are fed by the police
and which is a black bloc energy yes
they they they break windows and there's
some reason there's no cops around but
hundreds of cameras
the sergeant police commented that the
they couldn't disclose their uses those
techniques
here well I don't want to bash the
Canadians
its okay yeah
good a look as soon as global warming a
writer take it over your country okay
for we're just waiting for it to get
warburg
a to a and by the way folks Quebec and
Scotland are the only two places again
have clean water if we don't get our act
together
on so I'm starting to learn French %uh
she Indiana decreed that clear a
so K look I'm in Guatemala where the
police
are a major part of the problem on and
if you read the
wanna my reviews so that Lance tales
book the CIA has a long history
up creating false insurgencies including
the Red Brigades and Italy
in order to then turn the government
away from so-called communism
toward their preferred fascism okay
on and the CIA also important so many
nazis into this country
that that we have our alright can call
Rosander
and others of their ilk on we also have
way too many
double national israeli US citizens with
top secret clearances in policy
positions
%uh where I think they should be
research firm size to whatever the
opposite is
a you know and so what if we miss a
little
%uh I you know but really we're still
fit
%uh so quick interjection they're quick
interjection here and then let's come
back
sure I just wanted to talk for a moment
about
probation kinda visit school to maintain
at a press conference lysed underclass
and
in reference what you were saying before
about intelligence being outsourced
an interesting thing to note i think is
that Erik Prince
was just not just recently but were it
was revealed that at one point in the
not-too-distant past
he was actually on the payroll the CIA
he was doing intelligence work artprints
being the founders
yeah plan water yeah I A what you know
CIA's not very discriminating and who
hires
on they really do you deal with a lot of
fools
and they throw money around i mean CIA
had to close twenty of the twenty one
company said it created to do
non-official cover
they don't know how to run a business
arm
this is true it's in its in the media
and up by the way I'm way too smart to
make the security mistake appear
okay on sober or drunk on
and so nothing I say is a secret it's
just common sense it's out in the open
I honor my secrecy my lifetime secrecy
agreement
them and bringing drugs gun
I am so disappointed I
was sitting here breathless with
expectations fits just got them pay
okay so a a you know
CIA throws money around an essay throws
money around a
we're wasting $75 billion dollars here
in general tony's anyone other one other
last
serious adults that we have on says that
that provides
act best four percent but what the
president others need to know and when I
did my second graduate thesis on whether
US Embassy collected what got back to
washington
I realize that washington was running on
two percent other relevant available
information
what I did not realize was that
washington doesn't really give a shit
about whether it has information not
because it's running on ideology
okay and it's running on who pays for
what so come interject here
and just curious on and we talk a lot
about the puppets puppeteers all its for
the stuff you know
and and ultimately coming down to are
taking back the government
and with this is a thought that I gone
over a lot in my head
and I'm all non 90 answers and I'd love
to hear more
your real deep thoughts on how we as
people can take back to local
governments and build up from there
we totally I mean with out that because
I'm tired
giving my energy to have that system if
thank you and I hope others that have
deep passionate concerns will bring them
out here because
you know I'm I'm not the guy with all
the answers I just read more books in
you
on in it's because I have no life
on but
what did he say
for on
I'm working on that I'll I'm figure in
about twenty twelve
%uh you know but that's right actually
sex is way too much trouble unless
you've got the affection to go with it
in my humble opinion on flaw I i kno
don't feel sorry for me it's good
on you want to get deeply personal
for it
alright socially come back to the second
american revolution is still focus on
Mike got
for a on
this system has gone to show for it down
the toilet to
X that I'm not sure anything less than a
tax revolt
and a general strike will do home
I also believe we have the power I mean
I deal with some extreme
brightest in Latin America and and
they'd like to think that
the the higher and the wealthier guys
like to think that machine guns will
solve it
the lower and likes to just take a
machete and leave a severe head in front
of whatever ministry you're pissed off
at their
day on there aren't enough
machine guns on the planet to kill every
cockroach its gonna come out of the
woodwork
and where the cockroaches okay
on need more machine guns yo no
precision machine guns start was working
on that
little cockroach bullet okay this is the
place darpa hi I just can't believe it
darpa is spending money on a row but
that won't violate human rights
ish
I don't make this stuff up a you know if
we spent if we spent a fraction of what
we spend on war and peace I can solve
every problem on the planet for $230
billion a year
and we're spending 1.3 trillion on on
not just
when I think that spending on or we're
spending on contractors
okay on and we just had a wonderful
report come out
on the small arms were still playing
with take your choice on the battlefield
the the m1a1 whatever the hell they're
using now in Afghanistan is basically
affect about the three hundred meters
and the Taliban is picked us apart from
five hundred meters
on and oh by the way these are the guys
we train because the Taliban runs
everyone through the US Army training
program
so they can fatten them up a little bit
and learn all over tactics and then they
go back out and give them back to us
comment that makes no sense it'll but
we're not smart enough to figure that
out that's why biometrics is so big
you know on hand here in the US we like
to trade
the gates okay I mean Mrs now might good
buddies in the mars they figured out
it's not cool to have tattoos because
that kind of highlights the fact that
you're majorly criminal
who's willing to kill for ten dollars
okay on so now they're learning how to
dress up and get haircuts
on and they joined the US Army and they
become really good at this stuff and
then they go practice their trade in
Central America
on you know what could the country
trains its enemies to kill us
on cell I'm sorry I i've gotten
distracted me sick to our
tossing on interjection what
I have something I have yes us so you
already my big fear factor right now is
water
Marcellus Shale drilling slavery water
so the Marcellus Shale drilling oh yeah
thats idiocy
the AFC please talk about that and how
it started with
other companies that are now stealing
art can somebody get this computer to
work so that I can show some slides
on all stand here
all right let me out I'm turning it on
now I know how to do that
my kids laugh at me
my oldest son just got accepted at the
rust just raced through the technology I
just have to figure out which banks to
rob
so he can't go there a but I'm very
proud of him
his the son that I brought here was a
two years ago or four years ago
to here Patrick James yes
can't we let's see it should just work
now that's what she said
I'll cachet pick someone up here I
all right now show me the Internet we
have livor
okay
I okay good good good now
it says its connected but I i couldn't
get online
I really love
water I'd really love the water question
you know what are the things I'd like to
talk about
and and I really encourage you smart
people to go look at Oasis that net
forward slash
here thank you thank you
have a soda they're bringing
thank you on
alright this is Phi Beta iota but
you okay
%uh this is 580 iota and I read in
ninety-eight category so you can go down
and job and fine book reviews
okay for instance Empire sorrows
our games modeling future information
operations
101 books information society
information technology
so this is these are like cliff notes
for smart people on
and I write some material use so I
encourage you to go there now what I
wanna do i think is go to graphics and
that will give us some stuff to talk
about
on water is one of 12 core policies yes
interject on looking
on sure all I'm never gonna finish on
water but
okay this is true
actually I have I have to be in
washington at three o'clock for cookout
self I from three is what 10
okay no problem on I really am
I'm here until the last man standing on
okay
here are the 10 high-level threats the
humanity
and you'll notice that let's see if this
what senator alright can you guys see
this
now you can't can you on yeah you're
right
okay all done here we go excuse me
alright a you know everything I do is
free online
if you decide to buy the books jay-z is
out there selling the books and the
t-shirts
and and of course I'd be grateful if you
did
but but everything is free online
alright this is the ocean staff briefing
which has some pretty cool graphic
Senate
and I'll just use one and then we'll
come to you very quickly
on the problem where with government and
with corporations is
number one they don't have a strategic
analytic model on and number two
they %uh they don't actually do analysis
this is the
this is the graphic the UN it's not as
bad as it is is bad actually as most
people think but only because it listens
to its member states
arm wants the UN separates itself from
the member states that lie to it and
populate it with spies and I don't mind
the spice taking people to launch
bike to mine the spice being really
incompetent at their coverage ox
because what that means is the UN is
one-third nepotism
and one-third spies it don't know what
to do in a humanitarian crisis and that
one-third real people that are carrying
the entire you want on their back
okay of but the UN came up with a high
level threat panel came up with the 10
high-level threats the humanity
and i really respect this is Brent
Scowcroft as part of this group
so poverty disease ecology can all see
their
in the back F
500 you're teaching me shit alright hang
on
up please don't talk dirty
alright control shift I tried now
is a great briefed by the way
a and unfortunately it did not get me
the job that I wanted
which okay so
10 high-level threats humanity and then
I
I was about the summit company for ten
million and I was gonna give $5 to my
wife and five to my non-profit which
Casey is running
but I recruited 24 really high value
people including that Radcliffe said
John Roemer bunch a good people at a
Seattle and
we basically looked at the presidential
transition things for the last 25 years
and came up with 12 policies that really
matter that must be
addressed intended from agriculture
through water for example it makes no
sense to use water we don't have
to grow grain we can eat to fuel cars
that should be running on natural gas
from Canada or should actually be melted
down and turned in the train wheels
okay on so this is this is holistic
analysis and I've created four major
strategic analytic models in my lifetime
and I it stuns me that the US government
and CIA in particular
and major corporations are completely in
apt
on
that's a really really good question on
the question is how do we fight Monsanto
and so forth i mean this whole thing off
up one generation seeds is criminal
that's that's a
you can't you can I write look at some
point hang on you gotta stand in line
because at some point at some point
we're gonna have to understand that the
laws are illegal
okay on
and we're gonna have to go with common
sense now please interject here
you were are talking about Afghanistan
allows a massive
fuck his name is Kay few general in just
recently got fired
you might think that all McChrystal
address the area
crystal is an extremely
competent colonel the cup promoted above
is great arm
and that's most of our flag officers
most of our address
they've won the beauty contest their
house broken
%uh they're willing to confuse their
oath to support the Constitution
with they substitute loyalty to the
chain of command
alright when we swear an oath to the
Constitution we swear an oath to defend
it against all enemies domestic and
foreign I do believe domestic comes
first
okay so that for me basically means the
Republican Party the Democratic Party
every political appointee and government
on and most certainly
any president dumb enough to not
actually trying to intelligence-driven
government and it's not about Tom
Obama's very smart simply been bought
and paid for
and so this bill bradley bill bradley is
working for one of the top Wall Street
firms
on he basically sold out and all these
guys kinda see the tea leaves that they
decide we're not worth fighting for
K that's the bottom line on bill bradley
we were not worth fighting for and that
really hurts me
I take it personally on interjection
related to the topic a fiat
Kuroda upstarts pick up please related
to the topic a fiat currency how much
your
current control is there in this country
in the government military perhaps
business
by the Masons I don't know up but I will
tell you that I think the rock trials
firmly control
%uh the New York Federal Reserve and the
national federal reserve which is
neither federal or reserve
and the secretary-treasurer if you look
at who's been secretary at the Treasury
for the last five or six
administrations'
it has always been someone from Goldman
Sachs arm
and soul what what I really see
is a very deliberate plan to devalue the
US dollar
but they've already both the other
assets overseas these guys are building
bunkers and Dubai
okay they've already got their 75
urchins
it's a I think they went to West
Virginia or someplace you know
maybe that's the right state but I
they've got their virgin set up that
waiting for the medicaid is case both
%uh you know it's only a our money is
worthless
on and really for us maybe I still
remember and no camp dating myself now
I would get 35 cents to go see a movie
and buy popcorn
25 cents for the movie at 10 cents for
the popcorn who else remember set
II we got 48 guys in the room okay
what
what it is
that's a hard question %uh
go online the reason about the
mason's I ask when we look at a map
Washington DC
course good being Google Earth Gibson
you see the big pentagram
refine his power to the white house yep
plus the other Masonic said well I do I
do believe that
I do believe that Washington was laid
out in a masonic patter
and I absolutely love these so these
dan Brown movies and stuff
and I you know I mean it's really
interesting because number one
the the Rothschilds and company did not
plan on the nuclear bomb the nuclear
bomb
messed up their plants because it kinda
made
or unprofitable for large number of
people and so they had the backwash from
nuclear
and and event low-intensity conflict
okay and if you read my review of the
book on land sale where the Philippines
basically we invented terrorists
and in in vietnam we bombed buddhist
temples okay and so basically we've done
a lot of evil
lot of people has been done in our day
on there's a book that I reviewed
I I think it's called ruled by secrecy
and the last chapter
you know the last chapter is about
aliens and and Emmanuel as mentioned
on and %uh its
it's a very very good book in my review
I did not mention the alien parts I will
tell you I absolutely believe an
extraterrestrial
intelligence and I also believe with the
gentleman who was on TV a few months ago
thanks were under quarantine
because we scare on I mean we're just
like an out-of-control
or work you will be assimilated yes sir
in your lifetime do you think that
you'll see ya
North American Union the short answer is
no I think I'll see vermont secede from
the union first
alright there are 5,000 secession
movements around the world
an indigenous peoples and I really do
wanna talk about
what we can learn from indigenous
peoples and how much we've ignored sir
would you like to interject
sure upset a a couple questions um the
some tell apps book
the Black Swan did you read yes was
thinkin
I liked it honor it was for me very very
interesting
on one of the problems that we have is
an industrial society tends to build up
its attention
capability toward what it knows and it's
really
rock at weak signals and it's also
really rotten
at forecasting and it's really run
sharing information or making
connections across
a boundaries so I liked it on
one of the things I also like is the
precautionary principle
but let me ask you what did you think a
bit and what kinda point are you trying
to make
well besides him being a bitter blow
hard I think
it was ponders usually are yeah up
it was a a very interesting read but the
reason every night as I got this top
question my talk I want to pose to you
in doing risk analysis
have what at what point do we stop
adding
like the ridiculously improbable events
that are massively
value so Ian he's going of things like
that
is there a cut-off point at which we
should stop worrying about them because
they're so impotent as my probable
or should we include everything
including zombies well
it's your night some of my best friends
is on pace on
I actually would flip thing on you
I me take this cell phones & B's on you
know there's a scientific principle the
precautionary principle
or and I mean we're our own worst enemy
and soul what I think we should be
focusing on is the obvious what can we
not do that we're doing to ourselves now
and until we've cracked that one forget
about all the infinite s cool stuff
%uh there's an excellent book by Charles
Perrault who also wrote high-tech
what is your rate was the first title
high-risk
living with high-risk technology
whatever but he's written a book called
catastrophe
in which he points out that one chemical
disaster from one Cory
tank that is already %uh rusted out at
the bottom on this New Jersey Turnpike
on in the new york city
I mean that is worse than a thousand
terrorist incidents
on what we do every day to ourselves and
toxins not just
electronic trash but what we do with
food
the subsidies that we provide but to
cattle that shit our spinach
what yeah I mean oil spills you don't
love this stuff
is insane I mean it really is literally
insane
on and so this strategic analytic model
these two little red things here is
where the US government is putting all
of your money
and it's not really putting your money
against the threats
it's putting your money in the
contractors who pay congressman and in
fairness to the contractors is the
congressman there shaking down
the contractors not the contract is
trying to bribe the congressman
okay so I mean america is the root of
corruption on this planet
in my opinion and that's what we've got
to get it
so I would change your question and
basically say let's get back to
fundamentals
and stop putting the ball in our head
lol we worry about syphilis in our toes
that kinda I'm sorry I overreached on
that when I blew it
you over here sir
well I kinda have bernie keefer in class
and ask for
I also with he likes you you get your
slides
and to you hear you talk about work
tossing self
action gonna do we have a dwarf in a row
a small girl will do and that's a wrap
up this round make
but that's all right he said okay
double what's your burning questions go
with it
go diversity matters okay
its okay dude is just that fight dude
and the call dude since the sixties
you well took a good guy
I'm I'm feeling you I mean I've been
reading your stuff I hope you're feeling
me
a okay
he said a you have a basic truths I like
the human level
okay I get that I get that for
attack in you know they've reality-based
community seemed
have waived putting think out there as
like
factual that just art so
give me an example so for well for
example yesterday you're saying that the
Obama campaign had gathered $750 million
in financing which three hundred dollars
$3 million is
unaccounted for so
that was also today perhaps in case I
felt I think that a try so
other are you saying that's untrue I'm
asking you other than your own
ass do you actually have a factual
source I read it
factual so rich was I'm very very sorry
K
did not take notes however do that
things to making a very heavy
very heavy-handed additional united go
to bed
that this now your answer to Question
one so I'm actually I'm actually gonna
go look for the answer okay I know how
to Google for the ANSA lead-in comes on
and so on are going to Barrie
okay good I'll let me just get to
yeah but I mean you know I mean your
offensive
in in a way because %uh I'm here to try
to delete you
and I'm so sorry I didn't bring a wall
street journal to stick up your ass
on
hold on will get their head and waiting
here
where it was at hipster
you think a it says boy it then it's you
have to go to let that means you just
really didn't even really you just kinda
thought this was true you did
yesterday but when you've read all 1600
my book reviews get back to me
for
an hour that's so more like any raise it
on
I
I you know it's it's a it's really up to
you
up because I could spend the rest of the
night doing this kind of stuff for Aiken
move fast %uh
if someone wants a search for it and
then bring it up here
that would be a public service at least
one so
you know a it's out there
%uh I mean are you aware that he
promised he would use public campaign
financing them broke that promise
no I'm asking you are you aware of that
okay so that that
fact few if you got some to prove it
alright
let's move on yes sir go on and yes
health care we should talk about health
care im adding that
right after drawers I'm I wanted to ask
you a question regarding a
afghanis on an oz props drawing on your
experience
oz was an intelligence officer under the
former infantryman
and that is doesn't the wesson presence
in Afghanistan
kind al Qaeda exactly what they want
the first of all kate is not there
anymore %uh it's just the Tolly bon
Homme we created in 1990
and all by the way every dollar they get
comes courtesy of us
%uh we took opium from zero to eighty
percent of the world's supply
we enrich Musharraf in Pakistan because
that's where the number for opium
I mean with the open becomes number for
heroin on
and the bottom line is we should not be
in Afghanistan or should we be in Iraq
on I will I will I will
go a step further of the US haiti is an
excellent example of how screwed up the
US government US military are
on day one in the high 80
I started blogging about peace jumpers
which is a concept
have been discussing with the colonel
who created and I'm getting you guys
will go through your whole line as soon
as we're done here
on basically high 80 was an immediate
problem
love water on a basic food
followed by sanitation supplies followed
by
10 th and then it was a secondary
problems
upbringing in a ton of stuff through six
airports and six ports
the US military was only able to find
one port and one airport
how they miss the other five I do not
know up but the reality is
SOUTHCOM decided that they needed to
send in twenty thousand troops with
rifles in a long logistics tail
rather than focus on delivering the
basics okay
on soul what we have in the US
government and bob gates should know
better okay
got you sir X come on up here come on up
here
I want them to see your face up
here I want you to take that and this my
might be goofy I when I'm reading is
wanna wait there's another way to do it
I will gonna leave that there and I look
forward
on my own because you've given me Obama
should
can somebody get a picture okay
on hold on hold on I need a I need the
title arm
bookmarks see this is an example of
collective intelligence
on the group is greater than the
individual
on just Obama what
let me do the title that's that's more
fun because it's easier for others to
replicate to
most likely 48 48
FEC on it here week
all done and dunno
it is second one
0 Obama shrug if you guys are wonderful
okay thank you
very research you wonderful okay
on I think this'll do soul
there it is yes bro
from file you know when I
when I wrote the article at Whole Earth
review no
up call the 3i ethics ecology evolution
and intelligence an alternative paradigm
for national security
it was circulated in a 7-4 at CIA
and ross stapleton Grey Goose now
very comfortable in California told me
that Santa Cruz when said this confirms
steals place on the water to crash
on I am used to being called a lunatic
I'm used to being questioned
on and I just hope that this crowd
is having fun because I really care
about trying to get this kinda stuff out
on the table on
and I believe Obama has missed a
precious opportunity
because had he actually done a good
staff in Haiti actually chosen to play a
nonpartisan game
he not only could have been reelected he
could have repealed term limits
for himself he had an opportunity
22 bring the country together and so did
Bush
I mean bush is a well-meaning adult and
he really did think of himself as a
uniter
but Karl Rove and Dick Cheney just wiped
him out
so there was nothing he could do alright
still
very quickly going hang out very no
you're done
very quickly going back to water on
you have to do the whole thing your you
be sick and
I okay arm
let me let me get back to that briefing
because there is some what did I wanna
show you guys
shoot alright I'll
I'll leave it alone for now are I wanna
very quickly run through your points
back there and they come up here and
then will do little to our thing and
some health care
and after a water on
oh yeah you know what I really do want
that briefing hang on a second
DOD DOD
073 because it's such a fundamental fake
on you have to analyze everything I mean
Robert aikoff is one of my favorite
people he likes to say
that you gotta stop doing the wrong
thing right here
which is what we're trying to do and you
gotta do the right things okay
and ice just see we got here
I want you to I want to see this one
chart
so said human what's going on here
popular poster both all-time
and seven days we are
these are these are the ones that really
recommend feel like my human
intelligence monograph
the book intelligence for
free online here's the one on WTC
collapse stated that the US government
release okay here we go todo sent
leadership and staff briefings
are these are the ones I prepared my in
my competition for the position apps are
for open source intelligence
I was not even interviewed even on the
pope for open source intelligence
and general clapper and general Burgess
basically gave up their integrity on
that one on
and I feel sorry for them on now let me
just show you this
this holistic slide which I hope is in
this briefing
up because what you have to do is you
have to see the 10 threats
and you have to see the 12 policies and
then you have to consider water
or corruption or energy in relation to
all of them because what's good for one
part of the system
may be very bad for another part of the
system sections using water to flush
oil or you know there's this wonderful
book diet for a small planet and its
basic point is that
a pound of beef requires five thousand
pounds water to put on your plate where
is a tomato requires 20
and oh by the way the tomato doesn't
shape your spinach
okay on so it's it's really quite quite
fascinating on
no I am NOT on
but I have given up close on and
gambling and I never smoked
on and I'm moving toward being a
vegetarian I'm just waiting for to taste
better
I can help with that if you like are you
can
what no ni gotta stop the soil so is
is still asking if I yet
why what's at f5 stuff
alright
look at this look at this and this will
close kinda water
on energy time time is the one thing you
cannot buy nor replace
on it comes at a colin grace modern
strategy on
changes to the planet that used to take
10,000 years now take three years
so we have to get to real time science
the problem is
and I have a slight I can show you that
take leave an impression created
we fragmented knowledge I mean the the
old adage we know everything there is to
know about nothing
the humanities are all over the lot
sciences all over the lot
the social scientist Sir and I think an
appropriate phrase
from
a incredibly stupid
on is I'm sorry it's very weak but I me
social sciences just nothing it's it's
it's abysmal
are and so you have to look at all these
things in connection with one another
up because everything matters
for example the poor are the biggest
threat to environmental degradation
okay not corporations
the water that we as individuals waste
while shaving is much greater then what
corporations waste
effect corporations are starting to get
in touch with true cost
mom what was the other thing that you
guys didn't know about
biomimicry no open space technology
if forgive me I'm gonna take just one
second to talk about the space
technology
on Harris said no one has a brilliant
man
and he invented open space technology
and I'd love to see hackers do this one
of these days
which is basically everybody shows up in
one big world
everybody who has a compelling issue or
topic
and maybe we could do this with my
session in two years
for what senator I don't know
but basically everyone shows up everyone
is a pressing issue right sat on a piece
of paper
you take an hour to read the issues and
then those are posted
and then you sign up and based on the
sign up aren't you
do groups and the person who posted it
then brings a report out and ideally you
also have a wiki
so you have a distributed worldwide
network that's also participating
and so it's a self-organizing collective
mind and it works
Peggy petty Holman has a new book out
on emerging evolutionary consciousness
time at Lee has reflections on
evolutionary consciousness are to really
works
so I i encourage you to think about open
space technology
I I don't know why he put the word
technology in their
but it's basically open space
community-minded building
and its extraordinarily impressive and
it's vastly better than that program
structures are let's run real quick
through your issues and then appear
and then I'll go on again on our talkin
now ur talkin thank you
okay just very quickly you guys and then
we'll come up here
her thoughts on Jesse Ventura I love
them
I love them Jess even turn Sarah Palin
are my dream team
on now come on I take Sarah Palin
seriously
on the bush campaign and I'm sorry it's
the McCain campaign but the bushes
you know I tried to get through to
McCain on a couple things and failed
miserably
Sarah Palin should never never
ever had been represented as someone who
reads okay
this was a tactical mistake
and I think it was deliberate it was the
bush campaign's way
love kind of demeaning her Sarah Palin
has her own woman
she is legitimately won the governorship
and
in alaska gets the couple male assholes
on she should have been america's mom
and after doing her wonderful species it
is a look folks
I don't know shit about showing all but
I absolutely guarantee you I'm gonna be
the last person the neck John McCain
before he goes to bed
and he will hear from you through May
Day
and that for me works I absolutely trust
Sarah Palin to make a pain in the ass
ever self
are all day in front of the president
and and the president meets someone like
that
are when lee iacocca was thinking about
running for president someone came in
and said well these are your positions
and he kicked him in the head this room
at the door
that's the kinda president we need okay
and so
vice-presidents should be heard from and
unfortunately vice-presidents today or
one down from the guy that cleans the
toilet the White House
a so it's not good gonna get let's clean
up their own
I got a little late so much recovered
this I didn't you may have discussed
corporate ineptitude its governance over
a blind society
much ur butter did you mention the
extract disaster
no what is it the ex stock the stock oil
disaster
1979 no happen it happen a little thing
called the
JMX away we miss that one yeah in a good
have
have people Wikipedia that it was
basically verbatim exactly what happened
with BP happened in June love
a 1978 of the Gulf of Mexico in the
government's goal of a Mexican
side same company owned the well
same problems and it took them 10 months
to stop the oil from spilling into the
Gulf I and the use things like
jump shots and attempted kidnapping and
attempted
relief well drilling & and I'm ash I'm
not sure if sciences
really caught up in know is done earlier
years it's not about
it's not about science and and my
briefing is now online
at 580 iota on
and I'm just gonna show you one slide
because what we have is what's called
information asymmetry
on and these are deliberate and what's
interesting is that the cell phones
are are starting to eliminate those
information asymmetry is
on and real quick though if anybody want
to check it out
X stocks okay how to thank you how the
hell ain't you
how do you spell that sa stop stop nah
XT oh stop
next next
the question is is al Qaeda the at the
best-case the CIA these
people gone bad %uh shooting the AM the
short answer is No the saudis funded
okay to see I did not
we didn't we create a name find them in
training
well the base is a translation and I'm
not I'm not
a a supreme expert on this up but my
understanding having read most to the
books and and talk I've actually I'm
friends with no beer and Jack
divine and mill was the chief the
station for
Afghanistan and Pakistan and Jack was
the
Jack was the guy who manage the Afghan
task force which sent stuff and I'll
here we go
okay now this is a problem that we have
yah I shift actually mine does it on f5
but okay but it doesn't go right to the
page
on
what we've allowed to happen this is the
t-shirt thing that I did not have in a
brief the other day
on what we have allowed to happen is all
of these things
and these are all books there absolutely
wonderful forbidden knowledge lost
history manufacturing consent missing
information
okay this is where you guys come in we
had the truth
we get the truth on the table we use
cell phones to inform
we no longer allow CNN to be piped in
the elevators
okay
cell phone what hormone
well this is true but I but yes i'd that
that's absolutely true but in
and and Central America they've solved
that problem everybody has 10 SIM cards
and they trade offer like baseball cards
on
so there are ways around that and I
really do think that we have to protect
privacy privacy is absolutely vital
on and and I think that's the kinda
stuff you guys should be thinking about
from where I sit hackers have grown up
on and for they ignored me in 1994 when
I told them to create a
a public site that put every
vulnerability on display 30 days after
the company was given
notice but I really think these are the
tough issues that we have to deal with
cell phones are killing bees bees are
central to the agricultural cycle
we should be raising holy hell about
their are
but again this whole idea of controlled
opposition you know CNN does a story
about says okay that's covered
and we move on on so this is the stuff
we've got a deal with that
more back there and I will come up here
have you had a chance to read creature
from Jekyll I'm
no I have not for X
actually okay and one other thing such
started doing is putting
I guess the reviews on 58 I at all I'll
take a look at that book yes sir
Salem are you talked about yesterday I
open source intelligence
and I we had an amazing talks afternoon
from my
WikiLeaks I'm just wanna know your
thoughts are with you X
well on the one hand they've been very
responsible
on in in penetrating for penetrating
sake
on and they've done a few things that my
friend Steven Aftergood have secrecy
news that the federal
Federation of American scientists
doesn't like and I respect that
if steve is not happy with WikiLeaks
they should pay attention
however wiki leaks is inherently
democratic thing
and I personally support the individual
who leaked the
helicopter video and 250,000 cables
and the reason I support that individual
whatever his motives
is our government does not have carte
blanche to lie cheat and steal in our
name
and so we need to get to the bomb into
that and the historians for the state
department are very upset that CIA is
ignoring the law
with respect to declassify information
without which you cannot write the
foreign policy history the United States
if you really look at it closely CIA is
at the root of many over problems around
the world including
overthrowing a democratic election in
Iran and installing a dictator in
Guatemala
mom CIA is I'm very ashamed to say
Tom Hateley really screw this up big
time and I sent them a direct fax at the
time so I know he knew
what he was doing on the United States
America's best pals with 42 of the 44
dictators on the planet
I recommend Ambassador Mark palmer's
book or my review other
every every book I mention I review on
he's he's written a wonderful book
called breaking the real axis a vehicle
I can put every dictator out a business
in five years
we offer them a very graceful exit plan
that gets all of them
ten to twenty thirty million dollars
they'll never have to worry we can give
that to them
intergenerational trust 36 generations
out
and the ones that don't agree we kill
them are
but one bullet one man we should not
have to carpet bomb a village looking
for somebody
yeah well no no no no I really I there's
some potatoes are really good guys you
know
now the point is no I tell you what I've
learned what I've learned is you never
wanna put someone's back to the wall
okay and so the bottom line is it's a
vastly cheaper to have a nonviolent exit
strategy
than it is to put everybody on alert
because they think you're coming
together
year and so the bottom line is I am a
merciless bastard but I'm also a
calculating merciless pastor
yep a at No non-violence really does
work okay
let's come up here real quick a little
better thank you to
to exposing not not just exposing some
the truth and the reality but also
I'm charging us taxi go ahead and and
see them on our side
on you really inspired that means years
ago
but a big part of that which is better
to call action everyone here
is the I'm the clouds in fives
and it starts with our food I thought
you were to talk about Google trying to
be the cloud
I mean that I mean it start to their
food sucks hearings that we take into
ourselves
yes and these are the things that create
the deceptions but then
come up with the real world real world
is the matrix
that's been presented to ourselves so if
you wanna see the real world
we need to take out those clouds that
were seen
I'm not gonna hold hands with you but I
agree %uh
no actually you know food the we're
poisoning ourselves or poisoning our
children
I just reviewed a wonderful book by a
woman called
the it was basically
her kids didn't get to watch TV they
didn't get immunization and they were
home-schooled
and they turned out to be really nice
kids
and what senator
corner case well now that wasn't the
name in the book but but just
goal review look for on 58 I had a what
are the things I really like about word
presses the search engine works
within the within the thing so you can
go in the 5800 to and search for review
home-schooled and and get to what you're
looking for so let's stop there because
you've done your commercial
and and it's one I share love you on yes
sir
thank you sir a movie extra Bradley
Manning and the other WikiLeaks
yeah the curved area in regard to the
diplomatic cable specifically
I'm ground limb here and say that might
have been indiscriminate to recall
information having reviewed all
at what point should we be class find
the information because
the system's obviously the abuse right
now yes guidelines fracture classified
information a perfect
into intelligence was by Mina at CIA
they don't even bother to classify the
anything because it's assumed that
everything including your pizza order
is classified it it might reveal how
many fat people you have
up but go which is a lot are
the bottom line here is that Rodney
mcdaniel at Harvard
in the sixties it might have been it
might have been the 90s I forget
he came out and said publicly and he was
the executive secretary the national
security council he came out publicly
and said that 90 percent a secrecy is
turf protection
and it's basically covering up fraud
waste and abuse and oh by the way in the
$75 billion a year that we're spending a
secret intelligence
over $10 billion of that probably as
much as $15 billion if that
is so-called classification and so forth
now where I would go with this and I
think the judge
that just convicted the two people that
we're supporting cuba
was very ignorant because when you get
to
blanket police state %uh convictions
for leaking information that is actually
in the public interest
you've lost touch with your society
you've lost touch with your public
and this young man may have been
indiscriminate but I would give him the
benefit of the doubt
I would publicize all of those cables
and I would start firing some other
people who wrote the
because the fact is what they're doing
in our name is criminal
okay and they don't think that they
think they're being really cool
diplomats
you know move in manipulating whatever
but the reality is most diplomats or
messenger boys
and the and the the messages written by
a political appointee a 30-something
I love who basically we're out some shoe
leather on the campaign was made a
deputy assistant secretary of state
as a reward I mean I get these people
beneath contempt
up so we have a real problem and how
weak don't govern ourselves
yes sir talking to you have
actually all of your books who someone
at the DN eyes office and left them in
his desk and I
haven't hear them I
that was probably it Elliott Chartis he
doesn't read
a anyway I'll take that as a yes I am
speaking as someone who was an
intelligent sales
and someone who also help to write the
denies
class K games and has reviewed the CIA's
education guides an actor contractor
work for CAD
couple comments and I'll
one Bradley Manning complete asshole
he said reporters any war crimes any
thought was a war crime
to CAD to investigate because he pried
fucked up the prosecution have any work
right that might have existed
that's a that's a very good point are
however
I have found in my experience that CA
doesn't really exist
I'm scid and that most things you report
to see ID never get
investigate like I said I was with Sadie
and
every case that ever came up was
prosecuted
in successfully I've never heard anyone
go to see I D
with the claim there was never
investigated and prosecute
I'll take your word for it but I'm
pretty sure you never got a diplomat
fired
true by then again but the government
you cannot fire anybody for
incompetence they have to come in drunk
also a racial slurs
you know rate actually it's Roger rate
yeah yeah Irene
okay let's let's stop there place place
respect the crowd let's stop there
okay let's please ok well of of that a
regard open source us well comment
everybody
I think that few people have taken that
to heart as far as
water consumption is concerned no to all
public service announcement
smelling like a dirty nasty bastard does
not make you a better hacker
please take God Himself India
it to you have documentation on that
last point
yes sir in the back
I want to do not get your thoughts on
the mandatory in Bellingham
identification chips in humans and if
you still think we're heading towards
like
you will be assimilated for
could I'm serious %uh
know it look I mean I love the
the I forget what it was true lies or
whatever works
where this guy had to dig in and pull
the chip out in whatever I mean my son
just put in my youngest son just put his
US passport through the washing machine
on and of course you should put your
they are you should put all your
passwords in the microwave arm
but the problem we have is that the US
government
is full of good people who are
completely out of control
on the US government is basically trying
to micromanage shit it does not
understand
on and it is just
it's it's it's lunacy on
the the israelis I mean it you know as
much as I
get annoyed by the israeli manipulating
congress
lying and stealing and all this other
stuff there are some things they do well
I established a requirement 1988
for being able to detect explosives at
five hundred meters
are regardless of the container they
were in because we're still stuck in
container land which is why in El
Salvador in the eighties
on they would put their minds in wooden
boxes
on and I talked an Israeli official we
saw that prime years and I said what was
a says it's a dog
well he's right
and when the israelis put people on an
airline
they searched their luggage and a
question them and they make calls
to the phone numbers at these
individuals are required to give a
know who is getting on that airplane we
have something that
tells us if your vagina has expanded
lately okay
it's just nuts so let's let's go on
there
in the back and I will come forward
morning sir I was curious if you did
speak to
global monetary policy the stability
love financial situation in our country
and should I buy gold
well you miss the you miss the gold the
opportunity plus I te what there's some
very strong earnings on the market that
something's coming out that's going to
drive the price a gold way down
because it's basically gonna discover
all the gold on the planet
of now you know Afghanistan on the one
hand the Chinese know what they're doing
they're they're building roads and
railways to be able to mine the copper
and the other stuff that they want we're
actually invented
minerals to justify paying their
ten years later a the Arcade is actually
right here down at the ward of Australia
for
you know I mean it's just its its nots
upbeat with this market rumor maybe
AAA I i don't want to give it too much
credence but someone I really believe in
who follows cold very closely
and also that's the other thing the
there's some real panic over the fact
that the new york
fed evidently the
diluted a whole bunch gold and put some
titanium in the middle
yeah tungsten thank you tungsten
and there's also some real fear that the
chinese to play some
puts or whatever on gold are going to
demand the physical gold
rather than certo you know weeks and
then they're gonna test it
okay I mean talk about having us by the
short hairs
this is really interesting I personally
feel that we need to disassociate
wealth from fiction on and we really
need to get back to local ownership
eliminate absentee landlords the whole
bit just as a minor point which I made
before my lecture with so you may not
have been there
on William writer one of my favorite
writers has written a book called come
home america
in which he points out that arm real
assets grew by five times in value
whereas financial assets grew by
seventeen times in value
slow 17 -5 12 is the fraud index for
Wall Street
okay I mean how we can allow these guys
to give themselves bonuses
is only understandable in the context of
the white house being a subsidiary of
Wall Street and being absolutely
divorced from the public interest okay a
piercer
said quick question regarding I as you
say leadership
with the intelligence committees now I
have the
fun to people I know that have worked in
the past were very various intelligence
80s out there specifically are in a row
my roommate is currently
the intern with the NSA on I know
somebody who I don't you just got fired
okay anyway and so what's your question
hi anyway my point was
arm the every I actually know other
people were fast as well every person I
know who works for the essay
has said they're all the %ah Conway was
saying that they never one worker
full-time
after intensive the only way are they
are
they are also there are I'm paranoid is
all held to put it bluntly everybody to
the point where they actually
the rumors are that that is a do we
think the
on IMEI I really wouldn't be onto
skeptical them anymore after the mouth
cover for dove
and is a time people watch neighbor what
your coworker on what's going on
INR oh I've heard people claim complain
just has no central leadership
the well you know there's something
called Jim clapper scare
on basically in the nineteen nineties
and I was I was a GM 14 with these
people when they were four trains
there were a number people like John
Dempsey and
I forget the names but that basically a
buncha girls the gym adopted
and now they're running the intelligence
community on his behalf
and we just moved one very nice out
risch
long just took over the NRL she took
over the entire ok because she's 10 p.m.
Kloppers harem girls
on and I'm not talking sexually in most
cases
but in the end I specifics a list of the
last thing I read in the news about them
with their budding heads with the
director CIA over various control
various and commiserate
well the Deni is a faster child who
should never have been built
on I mean that and I is like 4000 staff
members and what we basically did was we
promoted every asshole that should have
been retired
one more time to the day and I staff
on and you know there's some good people
there there's some smart people there
but there isn't a single one of them the
could write the book that I wrote the
actually wrote in the 1990s and put it
together after the Washington Post got
me to tell them
that I had written a book on sold 'as a
funny story washington Post calls me and
says what your comments on these two
books I so what about my book at the
point at that point I'm it was a binder
with my articles but it had a really
cool title on intelligence pies in
secrecy an open-world
so they wrote about my books I decided I
better write it and go
and I did a and it was a wonderful
inspiration
so what kinda pointy trying to get to
other than the fact that the National
Intelligence Community
is the worst of all possible worlds
it's a bureaucracy with too much money
they can hide its mistakes for secrecy
as it was rosy what do you think is your
best your best bet on how
to fix how would you do it differently
but I think it's gonna happen but if I
were tea and i dont fuck that place in
ninety days
%uh and I'd start by making the
secretaries the
leaders have the various agencies for at
least 30 days
you know the but no yellow up the
secretaries are honest
and they know who is a bullshitter on
and I i
really have enormous respect for
secretaries who basically pull their
bosses alone
and and protect their bosses also in the
back there and I will come forward here
this is more in the spirit a PSA also
arm
you know a lot of people are just
leaving the trash next to their chair
and then someone else s the common
cleanup
and as just it's hard to respect that
because
we have to clean up our own mess before
we start yapping away about cleaning up
everyone else's math
you know i mean we can even pick up the
plastic cups
next our chairs you know who are we to
criticize
BP were I mean thats that's on the same
okay think
yeah up next in the back and I will come
forward
I'm misses a slightly different question
what's your personal investment
philosophy
if you had twenty thousand dollars to
invest in something
sounds like you're down on Wall Street
any by the you actually respect to you
take your money and do something good
look my wife gave me thirty thousand
dollars in savings and instead of
putting it in the Cisco in 1992
wasted on my company I really would not
ask me for investment advice
for up in BP is a good investment
right now arm well but
but again you know I'm really troubled I
think we should get rid of the stock
market
I'm not at all sure its its ever going
to be honest
and you know Mark Lewis wrote a book
called liars poker in the 1980s
and he was recently interviewed me said
I never thought they'd get away with it
for another 20 years
arm but they have and now we've just
build a man i mean the the idea of the
US government
giving wall street a trillion dollars
and and people not burning tires in the
streets just confounds me
I'm suffering from cognitive dissonance
right now her
so I wouldn't go to me for investment
advice but i'll tell you
if I had to do it all over again I think
all things being equal
I morph to day on
one-quarter inch down on the Pacific
Coast the Washington State
and start growing marijuana
mister
yes sir I'm I'm from South Louisiana and
I'll all those places you see on the
news i'd
around flu shot
Grand Terre all those places fission
I am that bird's foot you see the
Mississippi River Delta
when I was 13 and running around that
place
there was 50 percent more land mass on
it then there is now
we lose 25 square miles
your that's something like a football
field every
30 minutes while have 30 percent up the
coastal marsh
the United States with these Nini we've
lost ninety percent of it
the Gulf Coast is responsible for
something like fifty percent
the shrimp harvests per year
are coz we're I'm sorry we're booked
I'm mime muscling I want to move back to
Louisiana
and help make the state better these
problems existed before Katrina
all these issues with Katrina and
the Gulf Coast loss those are all the
fall
the oil company before work if he did
this
mister girl was one that the the
Mississippi River Gulf outlet was
me by oil companies to increase shipping
and they shut it down because it in
getting traffic in increased by fifty
percent
over its lifetime and the within trying
to push this
storm surge up into the Mill City and
destroyed it
well let me take care let me take your
comment well or my
my whole question is where do I have any
optimism like my state's gone we're
we're your that's welfare
been dogged for the united states were
were done we have no coastal town me
will NC done for us that's all we had
so where do you have any who that we can
corporate malfeasance has been wracking
the country for 150 years they've been
all over you know the the order for
engineers been doing nothing answer and
so where do you have hope for the future
that will fix any
shit up for stuff is a wonderful book
called
axo God and the point that it makes is
that paving over the wetlands was not a
cool idea
because that in fact is a major issue
I've reviewed a number of books on
climate
and weather change and so forth that
what it really turns out is we destroyed
the Mississippi River Delta area
and the Corps of Engineers has been a
major force for destruction
and it's all been done because nobody
thought this through
and the precautionary principle was a
followed and
and as horrible as louisiana is
is matched easily by major problems
elsewhere
on because I A can't ross perot's book
catastrophe is really excellent mean
we do more damage with industrial
misbehavior
then any terrorist ever could in fact in
the in the book that I just wrote
on a really good I really admire Steve
Carmel
the firmer chipping he told me that
basically a terrorist incident like in
Baltimore Harbor
is nothing more than a train wreck for
the shipping industry
but the idiot decisions that the
government makes in the thirty days
after that
cost them billions of dollars because
the US government overreacts and
and so forth and i was a smart enough to
think a bit on the day but 911
would have been a lot cheaper if we had
simply said to every pilot tell your
passengers any asshole that gets up in
the next 30 minutes is dead
%uh and will give the Presidential Medal
to the first class passenger the kill
zone
%uh I mean
it's just weeks weekly so overreact
I mean TSA is is pathetic
up and and these machines etc and taking
off my shoes from having to take off
Mike Bell
I mean I'm kate is laughing when when
when 9/11 happened I i wrote a short
blog piece on how
no we sped for every
for every dollar that al Qaeda or anyone
else pens to fuck this up we have to
spend five hundred thousand dollars in
re
in return it's now up to 5 million okay
I mean we cannot keep doing this on we
are reaching the limit over idiocy
%uh and II what senator
great movie great great movie absolutely
a wonderful movie I have reviewed it on
on so all you go have babies %uh
I we need your help with the Nationals