hope in previous hopes I think they're
great have a couple copies
pass around through it but when I
watched
about getting higher some fun stuff
learned last year in the kitchen and
we've got a few things to pass out as
well
you get some treating take-home Amaral's
experiment or two
with audience participate audience
participation
said so you know it's not working great
up in a minute my figure out why it's
not working
hold on
will get there
you
birthday common attic okay so
I will get the slides up in the meantime
I'm going to tell you what's in the box
he's out
I'm is a look it's all good to them in a
minute but what you want is one for
every other person
audience because there are actually to
test strips each skits and I only have
50 bags and it looks like
50 people here so again
pass out there's no difference between
the two different types that is
one's cooler looking
okay
cool just
so high I'm just Potter authors could
ever X
on looks I'll hand around your you can
see it looks like
that's a different Carl
I would call to them he's a really cool
guy and he actually the first person who
showed me this fall
concept called to beat cooking I heard
one of them to the one
else you know it's you cooking is haha I
like you guys
okay so that's an
it's been cooked sous-vide on basically
when you can it this way
it's amazing texture where the egg yolk
and egg white have come to the same
texture
camp plastic count manny's test
amazingly good on here is a little video
me like cracking and you think this way
to see you can see how they can to come
out the shell
on really cool thing about them from
cookie point of view is that you could
you crack can't drop out you know how to
do this whole
you're trying to skew of world the shelf
thing
on and it's magic scan it works really
really well
and this is questionable why is that
when it comes to
and a you know 30 proteins and and the
ache begins to cook
at different temperatures and this is
really really narrow band
where eggs early perfectly cooked below
to
Iran runny above that the overcooked and
that bans 144 258
when you droppin a into boiling water
you can imagine that eg getting warmer
and warmer and warmer
and eventually no it overclocks if you
take a hard world
and let us use it in water is completely
well is completely cooked
on the actually overcook it nope they're
still good but not dislike ideal amazing
a the question is you know how you
actually get that nice
texture a we know when you do a soft
boiled egg drop it and you pull it out
after about
57 minutes you know whatever it is
trying to catch up on that luker
runs up before it gets too hot but what
if there a way to actually cook and
where couldn't overclock where you
actually cook
in an environment that is about 158 and
it scared the main principle love
viewed cooking on one uses a water bath
and is in a piece about electronic
equipment
called immersion circulator basically
keeps water bath
at a particular temperature missus
capital
at the chemistry world where they need
to do particular experiment so whatever
it
a controlled temperature and in the
nineteen seventies actually this French
dude figured out hey
I can to get into the kitchen and is an
interesting stuff like that repurposed
chemistry government
to actually working in the kitchen if
you think about it cooking is really
nothing more than chemical and physical
changes in food
so every it works in a wet environment
from what that when you
works in the kitchen so this is really
probably the most successful most
popular things to get cooking is being
done
a lot high-end restaurants definitely
here in New York per se is a budget plan
others no I don't know where you got it
from but most likely your hometown
there's at least a couple restaurants
they're using this technique for cooking
I'll little you
eggs cooking I mean it is shows you
there's little agitation the water
came nixon the water upset you don't
have a secret I'm
it works not just an exhibit also works
in steak
so does it have exaggerated photograph a
normal process take its been
cook dispensing you see there's really
nice you know
grading Afghanistan as balls I think
we're the middle rare out that the calf
well done yeah fundraising
yeah make you hungry sorry
I'm so the same thing for stake is true
as exist really narrow range where meets
actually really really good
120 degrees one protein in me my ass and
begins to the nature and change texture
RAM 250 degrees is another protein
called actin
also teenagers and changes texture for
really no particular reason other than
just your dumb luck we happened for
when my ass is denatured including
Acton's native which
ends up being from Science Review
caymans 142 153 degree fahrenheit
temperature range if you thinking here
that lines up with medium rare steak
absolutely right on be a mistake is
pretty much
in the ideal band let's see
so this will greatly a tennis star
Keisha roughly you know
you dinner under normal circumstances
when you cook things you know she goes
and
outside in an outside eventually gets
hotter than ideal temperature
as in most environments that environment
actually harder your target temperature
but when you do things to feed like two
peas in the right
what you get is one entire block me
that's medium rare
whatever you set the temperature to onto
the whole thing is that was amazing
texture amazing flavor
really good textures it's great on now
of course you know you know is the piece
in the left side has a nice brown crust
the outside in the piece in the right
fingers can degrade it's not so good
looking yeah
so what we do in cooking the stuffing
after actually see the cooking you take
it out
and drop into pan you see really quickly
just to get outside nice and round up
yeah sees my friends and Jamie and what
they're doing is they're taking at the
Sydney
into a vacuum bag in feeling the reason
this is done perceive it stop
is it prevents the water from coming
into chemical contact with
food the waters only about transfer is
just a backing
energy into the system it's not about
actually you know
do anything with me so my ceiling in a
plastic bag with you get something where
you know he flavors banking washed away
essentially
also like easier to work with frankly
abusive state foreign waters can have
big group I'm so that's what it looks
like
uncooked that looks like a lot
and that's just a little photo me you
know pancer me
I'm you can do other things this richly
lost a richly world
you can actually see other stuff in that
bag so for the lobster
I'm actually did in this mom underwater
mixture
so you know lobsters of you imagine it
shall try to get back in sealed
to be impossible but if you put other
stuff into the next year
you can like to marinate whatever else
so this whole thing is stupid stuff
on you know it started out with
industrial controllers
which are really pricey other cabinet
thousand-dollar territory which is just
insane for somebody home on the company
called to the
that came up with this unit policy
supreme as last year I'm it's about four
hundred dollars but you know we can
still do
see what supreme to
s US the ID two words
you own one who's that you think yeah
earlier I did you mean: do things a
great many of you have no idea how knees
I mean like Trader Joe's sells fish back
impact in bags
marinate in it it's like can't get any
easier you take the backdrop on the
water you go to the gym or go for a walk
I mean thinking about that girl with the
ideal temperature the waters hotter than
that
can't overclock so you can just let it
sit in there for like an extra half-hour
site from a tiny point of view as long
as it's been a long enough to actually
cook
it's good so it's like yeah stuffs great
I mean it's so easy it's like
go trust me tried on you can make your
own Rick you can go buy a dealer
controller
drop them a couple into a crockpot
interpose on the power make sure you get
it done. crock pot one that you can
switch
on that doesn't mean like decide to turn
off and not turn back on it you got the
power
you mean so you can definitely
seventy-year
eighty dollars which you don't have the
Roma pay I actually went to train
and do that it's definitely worth it
so that's a really quick primer happens
if it's tough on
more generally why do we cook like
what's actual purpose a cooking is kinda
traditional stuff
there is you know some now it taste
better from a technical point of view
but the real question is that why learn
to cook why do we actually want to go in
the kitchen
likes it here in New York it was
probably cheaper to go down the street
and buy something
from County reference the good cost you
X seven dollars
you know think about the reasons why you
got me you guys like to cover
wanna learn to cook your girlfriend
K what else it's fun
meditative
dietary to choose to live in New York
where you live
solely Ohio you so once you ve man
trust me on
you by night so you can do that without
cooking just knives
on so there's a scam my soul simple
model about cooking you can think about
it as imports
is all your ingredients things you
actually go and buy at the store
cookies actual you wanna change things
slice it to some chemical physical
modifications
law sensations are like how it smells
how it tastes
can if you know what the objective would
agree that thing is pink for example
and their scam perceptions be things
like your motion reaction to it his
remains in my childhood or my
grandmother's brownies
like this so there's this researcher
down
for now any brand one thing did the
study about a thousand cooks
awsome a buncha questions to the scheme
is cluster analysis in
came up with this really nice little
apology like five types of books
and actually turned out to be really
fascinating useful
I'm talking to somebody about y de klerk
I can pretty quickly go oh you're like
just have a person any really kindly
developers five question quiz
which I just so happen to have so the
way this works on the run three to five
questions
just keep track which later you're
answering so if there's
fight despite questions if you answered
say a on all five
your Taipei think not that difficult so
you don't have to write down but you can
see one
on sega's ready okay
when I cooked meal I typically top
I'm good she gone you wanna see no
was a dumb question
some of my favorite ingredients are none
of the above
on then just don't count that letter I'm
so he did the research
we actually eighty percent of the
population unlike some people dislike
hybrid plan between different types the
don't think this is like on my god I am
this type
never like it's not exact next one ready
my free time I like to
okay well for this crowd on this product
F which is sleep work with me here
people
wait what yeah okay
just answer D make my favorite things to
cook
are no soldering iron references you
please
you don't cook some food
Jan extruded flick okay ready
other people describe me
I should go to the slides and
type just like next opportunity
okay so everyone can have had a chance
to get letters down
to get where you are general
okay secure the types so I'm
giving somebody like no shoes nurturing
and affection three like baking in
taking into their work you know
whatever I'm healthy somebody like you
know brown rice veggies
steam stuff I could care less about you
know how it looks hottest methodical
this is something like no
can make it look just like the picture
the like the kitchen will look like a
nuclear bombs going off
it looked like the picture on innovative
sabino read a couple recipes goes into
the kitchen goes i'ma try this instead:
you know either comes out work doesn't
bother happy with it more than on they
don't care
on last text competitive no intense
protectionists people like to grill
generally on a category
not that there's anything wrong with
going to go to so does the show handsome
was a be see
d d
so the interesting thing is the general
population is like 20 percent for into
these
so here we have scientific proof
you guys are not like the rest to the
people out there going back a little
chart earlier
you can kinda roughly map that type onto
your motivations are
so for me like you know I'm coupling
between
the health given health-conscious Andy's
well
but definitely not cooking that and
thinking about the input from you is
really important
is also your other reasons and
understanding that you go in the
kitchens really important because if
if you're like say health different
person and you know broccoli and
brown rice does it for you and that
you're dating somebody who's
use person wants to be big with all the
time like you just
your your by definition on was going to
set up this can have
aggressor type thing between the two
love you so
understanding that it's not you know
it's not her son from the fatwa for
whatever it is you know it's just
people have different types on sit
beside the
you know psychology is also
physiological differences no we we
taste in how we are that's where this
thing comes in
some people will txt things are I should
say some people like this things more
than others
for actually interesting physiological
reason called Super teasing
who hears her to this before ok cool
because well-informed who has occurred
the better question Galecki people
because if you've done it before skip
actually doing it and how far back to me
get with these who does not have
are sitting next to me who has my these
who
sorry back after the room consolation
prize for you later
so we're going to do is go ahead
opens up a minute of this one back
system we can catch a tiger
maybe on
so yeah pasternak answers to those trips
a paper in there
hand the person sitting next to you one
of those don't put in your mouth and do
you think that yet it's worse now Alice
T
on yes grip candy apples have the paper
that early
could with chemicals and giving out
white powder like and surprise have been
arrested yet
okay so to deal with this is
it's Tom is basically a genetic test to
give you two warnings
once I love you won't like this slick if
you if you don't want a bad experience
potentially and there's a lil candy in
there
you'll know if you need that on the
second warning us
technically it's a carcinogen so really
really matter dosage that
slip into anything so is the fight to
get your she says
the flu a case against got your mouth
the paper don't swallow it is in the
front on who said that
candy 30 she's like this it is Lexie
head if he horrible
okay so people are thinking horrible
like this make my own person
on the left here so you can maybe it is
something
but you can taste like you don't get was
that people complaining
white evil
aftertaste aspirin sour bitter
better okay an interview at the person
on the right
John who dislike joked is like my paper
right okay
to deal with this is that some of us
actually taste
certain that the compounds really better
on
there's a first capabilities that and
some others don't is that all
on this is guilty for testing
if you're looking at the personages here
it is genetic is
two genes if you've got both dominant
then you are super tasty
got one or the other
would come affect this I am slant on my
I don't think so by
interesting yeah your non texter sorry
not a lot to be like oh I had to my
mouth as you do it again it's like now
you'll know if you if you tested on so
then
yeah it's genetic thing on you know if
you've got both Tom and allows you to
test your if you've got one or the other
than your medium
I met you don't have either in your non
texter on
it is differ based on gender females are
actually more than three times
likely to be a super tester and also
differs based on ethnicity
so asians actually more likely than
Caucasians I'm to be which is urs
on so on a piece of paper was just a
mobile computer for carmine
see that six times fast I'm doesn't
actually exist in nature but it's
similar enough to compounds that do
exist
no different sliders on yes a tasty noms
is just one many thousands of compounds
that we were able to taste
like it was discovered completely by
accident in the nineteen thirties by
this depart- commits to expel them on
the counter he didn't notice
like with his lap meters like which has
better taste I'm
like on the researchers the 1930s start
testing on family and friends you know
before ocean like I think the
researchers to their jails in the sky
cuz he could just like to hear try this
on so that there are other compounds are
probably more
more significant than feel our car made
but it's one that we happen to know
about
missing some with the laundry knows a
lot of genetic but we don't actually
know
yet specifically what it is but in about
11 percent people's
it is like ivory soap
as we discussed this is a guy here
happen to like it so
its objective in this is because the
point like if we were if we work by
screen for you
like I'd have to know that there's
different physiologically the you don't
like it
keep that in mind you know I love it so
you know that because the point
on when it comes to fan of her car my
two dozen eggs out because naturally but
someone up the compound that do exist
without on people who are three cases
are less likely to smoke them like a dad
sugar milk to coffee or tea to cancel
out that bitter flavor
on they're less likely to eat green
vegetables and there's some thought
that actually more like we did have
certain forms a cancer because
growth colonies never say
actually supposedly help certain forms
of cancer
I'm sugar tests up to twice this week
was other differences for secret issues
as well
things the capsaicin what makes hopper's
hot moms
carbonation soda things like that tend
to be more
irritating quite literally missile level
to people who are super tasters
do my my poor friend shimon
immortalized in this great photograph
and if you don't have one use testers
you really want riders you can put blue
food I on your tongue
because the PA little taste buds your
trying to actually staying blue
you can count number dots like
three-hole punch area
its cover-up we have been as a proxy so
if you like watching us like
on a video you can try doing this on
it kinda works but it's kinda hard to do
but it's doable just put out the came as
a No
um when it comes to better me
complaining when it comes to better and
cooking
and we use of the council bitterness to
things like when I'm
I'm this is what's in solar tonic sorry
on if you put salt and that'll actually
become less bitter
actually literally council that out so
if you're someone who can't a certain
bitter compounds it is the more
yunis more soul so if you exit cooking
some brussel sprouts
and you throw salt on top of it thank
counsel bitterness
and you taste Brussels but as more
bitter than somebody else
to them said he's too salty so
keep that in mind to you could hear
somebody you know it's not a bad thing
necessarily leave like
the sole out on the table for people can
adjust the seasoning to their own
personal preference
because really are Lee genetic
differences
five tips to make things taste great
yeah is to just be
so what I mean by that is t something
doctors blindly follow a recipe teased
as you going to think a look at this is
more
you know what's missing balance assault
and acid so we tend to think about you
know seasoning
has been just saw but there's actually
five or so primary tasty
have a just so you a little bit %uh
vinegar little lemon juice and some
income of Internet at the dimensions
missing
in a dish on PRIMERGY Salton Sea I did
this demo
review this week with that a cheese and
watermelon that you just make a salad of
cheese in water in a little Friday onion
its really really good most well-liked
out everything he sings ago well
together but economies in the well
a lot that comes down to you well his
primary taste you know certain things go
well together as primary combinations
and a vacay
any double of primary taste ends up
having something that matches
with exception I think it's like better
and
have to look it up was a wanna couldn't
find an example for both have a good
thing to keep in mind but you've got
things very can have one dimensional
think about it from teaspoon you not
search miss Miller order plenty view
and think about what are the other
primary teeth that might be good at in
there
on thermometer for timer I'm going back
to my CV but little while ago
when you're looking at SIA appease a
stick your cooking it what matters is
the chemical reactions and at stake
the proteins actually in a tree and
those things happen at certain
temperatures
and yell to be to be for of tool to be
clear you know
its plan at two mature reaction but it's
not like
your you're checking with the best
expansion can you burn
and your times as forty-five minutes
like forty-five minutes matters that
matters is the central temperature the
chicken
for this chemical reactions so when I
see them on the river timer
times a good reminder hate and check out
the really using at the mom is a great
thing especially in cooking meats
and finally don't forget these their
searing you got some stuff in a pan you
know you're trying to see you outside
let's take
its conforming to the panel really well
you drop it initially because
well outfits wrong conforms well if you
disturb its not have good service
contacts
input as well so here nope starting
veggies or cooking me for saying
anything
to solicit pressing the panic one most
common mistakes I've seen with people
cooking is a good
constantly like they have to do
something stirred on saddam
okay I'll take a break here from in and
I'm sure probably some questions
enough had a few people look at me
before to questions
CV to 143 okay
can you overcook me after 24 hours at
1:43
on missing know with a little Astrix
some no you can't overcooking in fact
you can make really good brisket that
way
settings the collagen actually take a
long time to hydrolyze in D major
breakdown
on this is why like to comfy like you
have to cook but at least 46
hours before anything happens because
it's not literally just a temperature
reaction to time and temperature action
something will change interval after
there is that there are some types meet
especially fish whether certain enzymes
that are present this enzymes to begin
to react
break down the flash a few you to fish
you'd actually official or two metrics
fish man standing as to the nature and
he asks if there's a comprehensive chart
thus in the book
he says looking for the book here just
look at this
next question
a key if you want a really good
reference receive its top dog that was
Baldwin
just google to view the primer eso US
space
the ID primer I interviewed him in the
boxers
his interview with him in there you can
email me my email to secure the last
slide I'm happy to answer questions the
email
because that's great you know can have
char have thickness have me
time and temperature and we'll get a
little bit into the food safety stock is
urs
a little bit of stuff you need to know
that's don't just go do it
143 given sufficient whole time you're
totally fine
sop cancer better he asks
is at masking or canceling out I'm not a
physiologist that's a really good
question
I don't think it's actually educated
guess me up different receptors on your
tongue
for Sol the early I and cap receptors
it's not no I don't I don't think
they're actually bonding unlike forming
a different thing
I think it's still there but like but
that is an educated guess
other questions got the benefit and turn
black with her clitoris
you know see the question question was a
CV cooking useful for veggies
on I personally don't find it so
normally there are people that you know
if you look at under pressure by Thomas
Keller he certainly got stuff in there
for like
speakers and stuff veggies
undergo this really interesting
phenomenon around 55 degrees
celsius 62 resources 130 140
on actually get I'm firmer
the counter intuitive if you like to
carry you cook at 60°c
the cell walls actually
those crossings occur in calcium ions
the cell wall that actually fortified
stronger so if you actually
lookout and carrots in like commercial
soups
you can see to think think think think
can see have you know is that is in them
with you to get home you heated up my
the Kercher still firm
but how do they do this because the
notes on terbaik the carrots
on the ground the ground in if we do
that ourselves at home normally
you try prints and carrots and it's too
a kappa related or mushy
mom and what they're doing is they're
playing at 60°c what happen our
which firms up the cell walls some in
there are some like industrial
applications worth can use phone kinda
cool
but I don't know if I've like making can
see been storing it
usually on some are thin on if you
really do with Sudan
veggies is like optimistic bok choi Mike
cut in half in the drop in the water
along with maybe some steak tips on
cooking minutes its waters
at you don't back in CR that point just
basically kinda parking
and then I'll drop into pants team ever
see really quickly
and there's just well it comes the
temperature faster is basically preceded
but from actual coupon you I personally
haven't released anything it's like when
we got this is you seem easy and he's
really good
mean if you're from the commercial list
earlier absolutely there things they do
but
to kind of be on what I found worth it
creature
cam psyches pick up
economic at them separately me you
wouldn't want to vid is in that bag
with the me me just doesn't really I can
with the inning applications for you
wanna do that mean you maybe you would
like you know a
an Osage on outside thing we want flavor
present in the me
with the actual thing about marinades
and me managers actually get very far
into the meet going to become the first
millimeter
so in terms of like King the flavor into
the meat miss your brain for one pretty
time like
the flavors like a transfer from the
veggies to me and in terms of like
the videos themselves beautifully
written me in a pan sear the meat
probably afterwards a Taser medicine
that can if you want to do that but in
most cases
I haven't really no I haven't noticed a
big difference
put it that way
see are you can ask you what about the
juices from the me
and what to do with them all when you
take that back at the Seaview bath
Houston Open for the meet up there will
be liquid leftover
you can take to reduce that down the pan
sauce whatever you want with it so if
you want your mixer veggies and not
that would certainly work and a much of
a answer your question
tool for combating afterward pusher
sure
so you can ask you about om I
you know I look at it came from the
science but if you
and I'm to be clear I'm only talking
about like
10 pages at a four hundred so far to the
book itself really has a lot of
different stuff including have
discussion i've hey
environmental impact say no beef
versus chicken versus fish versus
veggies I'm
I understand you're coming from and I
capture all the same concerns absolutely
Schur on well organs some more
other topics that are less me based on
more fun from
from that media thanks for the question
lecture
looking at sufficiently low times you're
asking if the bacteria and material but
back to your concerns are
so that 131 will get there
actually I'm how much and where be a
you're halfway through
okay I'm gonna go on to the next section
and all your questions
so five key temperatures in cooking
you know when I first started the
project at don't think I would have
thought the Sabine whether things would
come out if it but to me either
is five temperatures may go out these
are really important temperatures happen
ever
here them talked about this way so 122
started about to meet for a while but
there with me
on is when my ass and begins to nature
in me this is mainly me
i'm for for Fisher 204 206 degrees to do
131 this is when the highest reported
survival temperature
bacteria in the literature on so this is
for
particular pathogen called be serious I
don't know who names is things but
that that's in a minute on so
thing to remember that bacteria is
likely instantly die 232
the food industry campuses danger zone
rule that says you're not supposed to
hold feud between forty fahrenheit and
140 found it for more than
to or four hours depends on what state
you're in but the assumption there
is that you know bacteria basically can
multiply within that range in outside
that range basically safe
but the reality of it is it's not like
the bacteria
are reproducing like full on exactly
forty degrees in at three nine doing
absolutely nothing
it's much more covers curve depends upon
the particular bacteria
how quickly the multiply what food
scientists and ice
food safety experts are worried about is
the quantity a bacteria
pathogens in particular dish whatever it
is so it and it also depends on the
street bacteria
or parasite but with Petrino sometimes
knows me
as she was 55 is enough to actually
cause infection yuan
other cases you know it takes like
100000 I'm so really it's not just like
are the present early not
on a binary it's a question home how mom
how much exposure is there there in with
the probability years so for food safety
pointed you know
the numbers that they give publicly are
really all about probabilities game
trying to make sure that from a
probability preview you're safe because
really been at the you know it sucks to
have food borne illness
and you see be some numbers and
foodborne illness
on CBC estimates about $75 million
Americans a year come down with
something
from foodborne or so most likely you you
personally will have
two or so food-borne illness incidences
in any given decade
spike your healthy young adult male like
me but if you're you know
pregnant or really on a really old are
immunocompromised you know it P
complete and much more serious
complications so
when it comes to bacteria and actually
holding stuff a temperature on
this is a curve for time at temperature
this is from the FSAs which is a group
under the
FDA for are USDA for how long you need
to hold
in this case predicaments for mean
chicken breast poultry
you have to hold that chicken breast at
103 six degrees fahrenheit
for over an hour almost an hour and a
half to actually sufficiently kill
any some know that may be present and
the reason for that is that they don't
die instantly
having allergy like to give us a magic
been in a desert note 120 degrees
actually met a hundred if you are in a
desert it's only get three hours and 59
minutes
Evans will be alive in four hours on
suddenly die on this week as some fall
off
and so they're looking at sufficient log
reduction bacteria present
in particular me and arm it just depends
on it with the temperature in how long
you hold it
the last the meat-based temperature
here's 115 this isn't acting begins to
teenagers I mentioned earlier
can I saw a picture
hey this is really no good range worst
us really really good and
you below that you got food safety or
undercooked issues
in about that actually overcooked last
two
my reaction on this is really one-on-one
this is a brownie reaction in proteins
with simple sugars have things like
bread when you actually look at Braden
other than
units are to turn brown the service at
the bread is like three hundred ten
degrees
this is like when the best moments from
in writing the book was have a IR
thermometer
it's basically looks at service to
mature things that's like best eat we
have early
go get one on an acquittal of the bread
is baking like its registered to 110
degrees as a
yes science lines with reality again so
mean
this is the same thing on on me on
different types a cooking methods will
get you
into the temperature range so if you
think about brussels sprouts you know
boiling them like they can't get up to
203 sector in water so they'll never get
up any reaction
always have has mild flavor whereas if
you could come with the method that can
get the hot
then you're able to actually get those
reactions and get the Associated flavors
and last 13 56 criminalization
basically sugars breaking down when they
break down the then like form hundreds
of new compounds in
basically like this there is some
bizarre reason um
where the cool things is that you can
actually show see this reaction occurs I
picked about sugar cookies at four
different temperatures and at 3:15
Bullock have lighter blonde curly
colored
and 375 400 be the starter color it's
not like a
trigger point where that criminalization
really know someone turns brown bits
campus
ramp 356 up to 380 Shirley gets darker
and darker and darker and
you more complex and more bitter favored
but sugar itself actually melts exactly
which is really cool trick to you can
actually caliber your up in
using it secular lucia glass form for
your oven 350 like
might begin to caramelize intern like
the brown but she's still be a powder
at 375 should not much just class bill
see through it
so cool trick you can also use for sugar
into a pan and melt it
there's nothing else in there but sugar
and when it comes like making caramel
sauce a
in the standard players take sugar and
some water you know at some other stuff
you carefully Boyle
other stuff you can use the sugar into a
pan unaltered
Alba cream you want to be a little like
caramel sauce big a caramel sauce is
Kevin medium brown
it's actually really fast and easy to do
so quick summary of
temperatures
be coming next line yeah I can get there
on
are stopping here for men technique
questions
toughie making toffee from condensed
milk
well I'll need to check this but on
sugar by itself Bama 367
but we dissolve into something you is no
longer a simple
structure that you look at things were
going to promoting some
not mislead lactose I think back to
sleep action against crime was around
like 230
but for tourism doctors if your sugars
again on this
like higher temperature range minutes
across
yet to come until sugar Richard
me temperatures
veggie proteins well not proteins but
yeah on
things likes a Los well gonna give you a
hand with the answer
140 degrees on veggies are a lot more
complicated than me
which is why from a food science but if
you it's really easy to talk about me
and really hard talk about people's on
so I actually interviewed her 80s
for the book Anders talk with him about
this in his lab currently studying
like festivals like a lot a submersible
because frankly there's not a lot I
researched on
in part because well who benefits in the
research into funds that
it's just really hard to get funny for
some cancer research for
it's not applicable industry have to
some degree so
yeah there's a lot of things we don't
know about food really surprised me
actually
is like how little we know about food
science yet how much
you know it how important it is to us
from cultural pointed you in from
industrial funny view and from you know
earth life balance preview
yet at the same time you know it's
really complicated so
stuff like coroplast
I think it is and veggies like you'll
succeed reactions around 140 degrees
so you quarter 3 on
to fix a loose in Lincolnton exiles at
the fire and the biggest account like
300 thing to be celsius Mike it's not an
object in your kitchen
/url should say but any breaks down you
don't want to eat on
with our industrial ways like granite
and cycles powders but like you not want
got chain
changes in yeah changes in taste
overtime ok now you're asking I'm super
tasty does not change over time you
either are or not
at the genetic thing on their is the
Lex loss sensitivity of tastes starting
having early 40's early 50's and it came
gradual
with think will kids with bitterness
ya get there is an aversion to
bitterness from a physiological point
you just because most
business things taste better when is
camp like survival thing us
om but it has been that we can learn to
like better things it's a thing that you
know
wheel with exposure learn to like on
and it was 100 rights
hot things hope things are really
interesting actually
missus neurotransmitter called substance
P on
P stands for pain go figure basically on
because depleted so eat spicy food like
this neurotransmitter that helps your
body
recognize haters make hot here like its
Louis depletes in like it takes a couple
weeks but after a couple weeks you cash
can deplete levels down
and it takes a couple more weeks for
your body to replenish if you stop
eating spicy food
so this is where the stories is really
great stories
love Indian students back in like the
eighties coming to
you know United States study in college
eating dorm food going home
your mom's cooking and going this is too
hot I can't beat it
and their moms going what is America
done to you nothing are then they didn't
serve you in a heartbeat
your such as few levels didn't deflate
your replenished I'm so you can actually
build a tolerance to like
specifically capsaicin hot hot things on
something after there's that as well
which is
actually really cool on good back to
meet
TomTom TomTom you now means a very nice
yes I'm well it's basically me 6125
primary teeth that we know we have
receptors for Tom
on doesn't break down T so there are
certain ingredients
have a lot of good to me in the
naturally things are going pizza
just happened to have a lot to me
tomatoes Parmesan cheese
mushrooms the reason why I think it is
or so well-liked
but yeah I mean in this cheesecake
gotten a bad rap in this country
but if you want more good make my small
amount of it mean
its in has receptors on
to the answer question lecture
hopefully custom 150 on yeah I mean if
you put chicken in the oven at 350 your
chicken
actually got to be 350 degrees is a
charcoal been on with your life to be
dry much
he would be the most perfect chick in
the world sectors really fascinating
patent case happened about a decade ago
these two different patents are written
about like bikini think it was
baking bread
like one patent likely the process is
baking bread at 350 degrees
I was baking bread to 350 degrees and
the like
seen each other in court and they're
actually found would not be infringed
because the only ones that you get to
bed to 350 degrees which means a piece a
bread baked to 350 degrees for
like gotten with your left B&W you
cooking chicken
on you want internal temperature how
Jesus can be recorded as an
newsweek analysts say arm you want your
own child to mature chick media 165
degrees
input marks the reason for that is this
room that
well from as one-fifth scientists put it
from you
the numbers are for dumbasses I'm
quoting somebody
I'm and she justified and said that with
those temperatures
they assume that you're monitor was a
doubt the Mamas miss Calabria by maybe
five or ten degrees
so now we're talking about 135 degrees
may also assume that you miss probe the
calls pardon me
so you were actually in the call part
you may be near the phone but like
Justin like it cause part sonar five
degrees south can get a hundred and
50 degrees learning is that numbers and
instant kill temperature
so the what that means is it you see
chicken at a hundred sixty-five degrees
the bacteria is present will be dead on
that lockers thing
circuit that die officer vast but you
can cook it
what if your community look at the
industrial food processing guidelines
you can cook chicken at a hundred and
forty degrees
as long as you hold it for sufficient
time an actual it's really good
I'm cuz I mean same medium your chicken
sounds really gross
if you be checking you had many american
chicken by back if you could like
ATP your you know downs or use places
where you get the chicken salad
and the chickens can moist might not dry
like they're cooking at
at a lower temperature textually and
from what your body you
it taste better we have to hold it for
surface sufficient time so it the
guidelines that consumers are
you know the air inside a food safety
which is absolutely the right thing for
them to do
because when it comes to know would
rather have it is good or we'd rather be
safe
kinda well who wouldn't want to be safe
is really interesting little
footnote to that which has to do with
ground meat with things like chicken
their generally the temperatures are for
the entire chicken personal can actually
permeate through me
unusual Paul chickens are actually that
sick aside
but is potentially possible with things
like steak that works for muscle intact
hasn't been
cooked I for has been cut order carted
on it's on the surface that they really
care about as long as you can see a
pizza steak
since I can be you know uncooked
clearer from a food safety point of view
it's definitely fine
which is why you can order things that
your steak you
rare but you can't wait to your chicken
rare on
but when it comes to you say hamburger
with me ground-up
the whole thing's outside the is now
inside so orderliness hamburger
like kinda silly wanna go to the if
insiders convention
asking this question like how do you
like your hamburger Scott collect
anything other than she answer anything
done because you know unless you
actually fall in CV bath 104 degrees for
sufficient time for bacterial
kill of it you could actually really
good burger that way if you're going to
go through the pain
work on and safe be a state
answer questions probably won't answer
sorry okay
um I'm eager for one more question on
gone lecture in the back sushi
even a bacterial when you do okay so we
yet will I me from a bacterial point of
view
i'm concerned. aggressively on things
like tuna
are actually excluded by the FDA from
needing to be cooked
has to do with for tonight has nearly
bacterial pathogens that actually
but someone are just doesn't exist in
the deep waters have
ocean like trying to get infected with
that and from a paris that point to the
same things to you as well
things like salmon actually can come
down her sides the community was pretty
rare
but in that case you can kill parasites
but freezing them
so if you really concerned about food
safety and stuff like fish
on you freeze it on there are certain
time to mature hold guidelines that the
government publishes
for fish its I think -20 for seven days
are like
insanely called for one day on be a tune
is actually excited to sign
when I go to a restaurant I'd really
like your daughter made tuna sashimi my
salmon sashimi after
Twinsburg on then answer your question
okay I'm gone for want the more
oh man Africa really fast like 30
minutes left like a really fast like
blast through the source I dislike
Cup blast that out last okay
annual temperatures that may 11 145
degrees in fit the lock
of it you can't put on clean cycle open
the door for UPS in
really hot amateur its weekend awesome
and the reason for this is that stuff
like pizza if you actually get on your
local pizza joint and it's really good
black crust pizza tonight if I was like
a hundred to a thousand degrees
action went down to the pizza joint in
Cambridge where he live like took that
buyer from a letter looks like
athlete wherever they send arm immediate
and there's like 1000 degrees
I'm you can compete in about 45 seconds
and it comes up fucking delicious
but you might break your oven
so on the left is the surviving pain for
my oven on the right is a key supply
routes around three
it's what the US military used in the
nineteen fifties on a news comes
missiles
its he created in stable to like I think
1500 agrees
fahrenheit so basically I i crack me up
into thermal shock
with little drop of pizza sauce like
fell hit the glass in
young
so yet people I talk about dry ice
and start looking at it and actually and
ice cream by don't get is why no one
thought to take a bottle of like
Goldschlager next yr because you know
ethanol doesn't freeze into a really
cool temperature
the connections colder so you can make
is committed an entire shop
sq Mike hangover some ice cream its
really really good
I wasn't good enough for you guys today
but
I don't have a liquor license for New
York I am
so there's a single integral that's
basically a plea it's really called
you can do you like a griddle but so
many things hot mix is called the really
expensive I can get my hands on one time
in my own
on dry ice with ethanol with AP six inch
square place a steal from McMaster Carr
on basically could you call to rescind
my handy dandy IR thermometer
tells me like hold you can do things
like spray likenesses in stock on it
and like get this thing up like a
pancake where the the middles like warm
in like
good now that the cartons that like to
capitol sandwich yet
on if you look at what matters putting
stuff like many
are coupley over and Spain like they use
the stuff to do
unusual things meant temperature twenty
view but we cool
by be keen I love
double the and a linear and factor
companies like that on to hear her to
hear his for the term length astronomy
who here likes the term like astronomy
so
in the corner world its pre much
despised as the term
which have mom it's been interesting
thing to learn more about
pretty ciskei responsible for cleaning
the term themselves as
that like a strong is what you do in the
lab study physical chemical changes
in food and that we might in the kitchen
be maybe like they're cooking
home you have heard somebody else a
modernist cuisine:
but you know playing around with stuff
in the kitchen
in town like fashion on the Paris from
my ninety percent came as bad
and 2 percent it's really awesome so it
just had a bad rap sometimes eating
unusual things in the kitchen because a
lot trying to see the knock offs were
really work but when you see slimmer
really is magical
it's amazing so
a lot of on miners getting stuff for
lack of a better term
relies on food additives up these three
things all have food additives in them
she is an excellent idea on the table
miss getting the book
on this little video of me taking on
these
joining agents in actually like just
play with it so it's
water ninety percent water and 2 percent
kerrigan you can do stuff instead
love water you can do stuff like this
what we know your mind is
so this is ninety eight percent room
unfortunately it taste like 98 percent
from
to but to cut it with on issues like
forty percent eighty percent murchison
forty percent alcohol you can the really
nice jello shots that are like
unlike anything you've ever had you can
also email them to a wall
on when working with the stuff
basically boil it on this particular
temperatures agar and its nice little
files agar for you guys to take home did
irregular hando through it to deny could
hand out yet you get did not get a hand
up
okay who has the power handouts keep
your hands up latency
on your way out you can pick one is up
I'll be a cure the table them
on this is two grams is a recipe on the
handout to make
on chocolate panna cotta using agar
mom chocolate panna cotta basically
throwing
liquid you boil it and a good thick on
assist bumpers: in solution there's
different types
some dominance produces really firm like
fixing which
just balancing the spoon and other types
captives flexible gel
but they they retain their memory net
other shape United the the two gels
that's what I panic artist would looks
like I am
with other fun things in the a.m miners
causing world
the Suns on is a steak cooked is a
chicken cooked been impounded together
with transfer tennis basically meat glue
on
it takes to her proteins and literally
like cross-links them and actually from
like a level does come in on Bynum on so
yes actual scary to work with because
you know
Vermette approaching well
yeah cassidy's as he went things that
surprise me you know
so we probably just have time for
few questions before
favorite source for buying things the
Internet
on it depends on
come see me afterward I've got a list is
actually when the pictures above
scandalous two pages
next question lecture when I commend the
contagion from
egos welding supply Richard
him
widescreen turned a better
I can give you educated guess so much ur
on that populous
in the in the milk your actually sharing
parts them off
and they can stick to each other as you
get a minute structure they can actually
the globules tampons big one chain
mccaffrey much much
when is the booking I love you
so I have galley copies you can pick a
I can give them to my publisher was a
rally with chill me
on its due out august 3rd you can
pre-order on Amazon
you're cooking for geeks the common the
big buy a copy but in a love you
more I'm here take a look preacher
good source
for food science but thats doubles I'm I
have not found it sources for nationals
as I seen earlier
is when he sees a few times world has
not studied as much on
I mean you can get in the journals
me to look at for times-journal is
returns
run arm yeah I i realize
you know based on German comment earlier
that I have talked a lot about me
which really sucks for you returns but I
swear there's a lot more interesting
stuff in the book
like it's not like me having on concerns
I'll have to think about that to me know
and I will take up more Richard
yes helping is but confident cooking
yeah
pitch is really important actually so
%uh the temperature things I mentioned
earlier differ by pH
likely to affect it down think that my
attractions
pH will def with a temperature that to
happen at
you can actually get down to room
temperature self-tanning
instant any stuff is my reaction
battered
I'm sorry but I'm being told that
we have to wrap up this rat I'm and come
see me afterward
I will be out around the corner on
please come pick up when it is if you
want thanks