I just again I i apologize. not so
you've heard this but maybe not everyone
has
for few scheduling updates where I still
an hour behind in this room will remain
an hour behind
and then at 1 a.m. there'll be a few
films
in here and our selection leave getting
the full details on the films but there
are
film zebra haven't seen before can be
pretty interesting hacker
history culture taxes thanks I'll be 1
a.m. Robert Steele
is going to start at midnight not in
this rumor was scheduled
but in the next room in a Tesla room and
the only other change
arm to this hour of thing in the bell
room
the smaller room back there is that tied
the
telephone folks are just starting up
right now
so we moved and after social engineering
and everyone else form an hour behind
schedule
there and I wrote this down son she a
paper on the on class size case
we have a concert starting up your gun
club as well
starting at 11:30 down in every 138 same
way down the mezzanine
I if you check out last night's concert
you know you can check out a nice
concert it was
really good stuff see have basically
three four five places to be
are for release next year for five hours
on media
conference Laura on 18 down in the
second floor
I think does a program updates and on
so it's good to serve their necks
offices circuit bending with Jimmie
Rodgers
so
live everybody an ass I'm Jimmie Rodgers
and
I've got a lot of stuff to cover in a
little bit less time than initially
hoped for but I am
it worked really hard on this
presentation so here's the first line
oh yeah think thank you
thank you and that that actually did
take me 20 minutes 0 and usually when
you have the whole presentation like
this but I am
edges you know went with just comic sans
sir and same Jimmie Rodgers I am
a full-time hacker in Meeker on May
basically travel around most often with
Mitchell man and I am
teachable cider and make things I have a
number a bomb
open source electronic youth and Dom
I've been teaching circuit bending and
running
and workshops and classes for the past
like three years or so
om anti-muslim the Boston area
marianna then calmly site for a while
sorry about my voice I've been talking
pretty much for two days
on so it's on the skyline um
so here is actually ran going to dump
all the information if you have to our
code you can to snap a picture that
there will be another slide at the end
for questions
so on you don't have to take picture now
if it's not available
and that it'll just be on the website
offers a slides in everything
um they are so for software is sickening
I it's just modifying ways electronic
instruments are
radios even on some the first half was
on displaying and noticing the he get
interference of %uh via
a radio that was sitting in a middle
drawer you notice our kids weird things
it's essentially causing interference in
a signal I
shorting circuits on building where
the electricity is going to be going in
that changes with that supposed to be
doing
am the the first more that the person
you is I credit is being there for sick
for other sickening as I read is Allah
our mother he takes no claim to that
title
om G coined the term in the sixties sign
for
some radio and electronic experiment on
I instruments it was doing at the time
arm but there are two books that are
incredibly still have
I if you are interested in com creating
electronic instruments in general and a
sickening in general I am
the first one there was more useful to
me was a handmade electronic music and
the second volume in sound and
it has about one chapter on second
inning but all the other chapters
pertain to a lot of what I'm gonna be
covering very quickly in this hoc
which is arm essentially how to change
timing on circuits how do I
like how to filter it how to change
waveforms all kinds of stuff and it's
extremely useful
a circuit bending my read is Ali he
covers a lot of very specifics
farm instruments arm as Wilson the
generals and some the tools and think so
on it's also a good book to pick up if
you are interested in um
so first off some they're really common
a simple
easy seconds om a a guess
I should show you Anna most things leak
the Sables easy button here and you can
at least get a timing
pitchman each so you can kinda slow it
down but also I
if he slowed down a lot you get quiche
and um that's actually pretty common to
find in most ways you can find a sec
event it's going to be like that occurs
most
things are you gonna be playing with are
two simple simple type things
on but not everything relies on that
circuit
%ah sometimes it's a voltage train our
you actually
decreasing the amount a parent available
for the circuit mom
so the way that the timing circuits work
for these oftentimes is I
the they wanna make these things as
cheap as possible so a crystal was
actually gonna cost
3 45 cents dad accurate timing
am so these issues EI a simple
capacitor and resistor so capacitor is
an electronic component that's right to
charge
and in the case the circuits are
actually filling them up with
electricity and then letting
drain so it's kinda like when those
Japanese water fountains you know
seen in the gardens fill up with water
again Indy out in a dunk
um so that dunk is maybe I'd thousand
the secondary 10,000 the second or
whatever the computer the
microcontroller
on in that way is declaring asiana a
period of time
um but the thing that's laces even
though he can change really on the
flight the size in a bucket
the size of the tumor the size capacitor
you can change the REIT
of current that flows into that both
water and electricity the analogy works
both ways
um so kinda like how you take the water
not late the water faucet
slow the current be slow the rate that
it changes you slow the rate that the
microcontroller makes it sound so that's
the kinda basis if timing circuits are
you change resistance
you change the speed but the things
really nice by resistance is everything
is resistor disavow your resistor
resistors to Chalmers everything on
voltage train works in a similar way
where
am the it actually
affects the same circuit because sorta
like you're dropping water pressure on
the sudden so it's gonna move slower
because there's less water pressure
ID output is really really good at your
toys if you can easily very
any kind of audio recording and things
are done on covers antifreeze and going
out later
and power switch and it's really
important because oftentimes you can
crash into a
and Dom you need a power switch turn
on/off were
um just a lot a lot a lot it's wages
their always online in its kinda
annoying cuz you do it in a bag in this
is certain
76 singing your um
weighs 60 pounds and tells you how easy
it is the left which is completely ally
com so some more advanced fans these are
not always available in two ways: arm
if you have a really complex we can add
a patch may hear
am so the passkey acts actually lets me
get to you
a couple on but
on
so it allows me to you on the fly and I
change a couple things are more advanced
ways like a
Cassie keywords and things like that
that are well-known on these a patch PEs
for that
arm having glitching crash configuration
so the glitches or to play come
what was going on there with the easy
button weary kind of calm
you bring the circuit to a point where
it doesn't really like it also it just
freaks out it makes a lot of weird
noises
on says kinda glitching out crashing is
actually
I as the circuit is just completely
falling down
army will make some the more interesting
sounds as a kind died
if Tom then you have to reset the switch
a surgeon dr. crystals changing out
things like that are you can change it
dramatically change the speed
the toy and change your capacitors kinda
the same way I can change reforms that
and a few other things
and something the really against his
MIDI controller will
oMG or addressing at three sequences so
I am
there's a Furby use choir out there
that's pretty friggin hilarious
um so it's a sequence addressed
series for bees Tom so unfortunately you
didn't
the speed the stock and is not can be
able to show Lake all these video clips
and sound clips played
it's all on YouTube and things and I'm
gonna put some stuff in the link dump
on probably today or tomorrow om
so what to look for when you're looking
for something to circuit band
battery-powered is way preferable unless
you really know what you doing
um so now being said
you need to take any new web voltages
you're working with the toy
because and some tweaks you can
absolutely kill them I i've
heard a lot of people say oh six innings
easy all you have to do is just a couple
wires around
and that's true for a lot of toys but I
for things specifically like the Furby
where they have motors and things %ah
they have a much higher current
to driving the motors I am
that if you cross that nine volt motor
driving current over to the three volt
Voice circuit it pops and its 10 mom so
units revolt and 4.5 volts those are
pretty safety like this can poke around
in some wires
its exports you should start using some
two geometries in series on
get to that later an 89 Baltimore you
definitely need to have protection are
you gonna kill you toy
om you don't care that's fine but did
something that was really hard to come
by and in this case is collectors item
so
com I wouldn't be able to get another
one am
so I toys with kinda fun sounds samples
arm something that's neat about that is
you know first of two something the fine
it's interesting something that says
something interesting for you
om but you really need to play within
can see how it works because there's a
lot of things arm
deter not very preferable simply disease
even if I hold it down
it does nothing let it go makes a stash
um specifically pressing the button
it only ever plays out once they can get
to lubricate get a repeaters can have
refractory period of sorts for the delay
and Dom thats not very pleasant have to
go through external circuits to get a
tulip
but other two ways I
missed that's kinda much
um more preferable can situation so if I
had their hold on the bundle repeat or
five press a multiple times I can get it
to trigger multiple times
I'm so that's really great for sequences
or dis alternately having its way they
can be on in the background
um but they're oftentimes limited to
very few excludes there's nothing more
that way than is making sounds
on the Deccan oftentimes you worth it I
so that easy but
even though I can only present once I
can get some crazy town Saturday
I can write that early two minutes or
more om
and it's great for samples I if you do
any kind of on digital sequencing a
computer
arm background noises neck and stuff so
toys and audio input are amazing Tom
kinda my favorite either their sleep the
party karaoke machine which is kind of
hilarious
has assigned echo effect in it that's
just spectacular
um but also I in a lot of the joystick
microphone inputs
and others are sometimes I P amplified
so you can actually run a guitar Stewart
Street
without having a lake actually amplify
it so in this case %ah my have run
guitars through it and I can use the
patch be to have kind of a modular
guitar synthesizer
mom and things like that affects panel
that's pretty crazy
but and so I ease monetary fund consuls
oftentimes as EI frequency oscillator
%ah the
serve yeah it's really nice that the IDM
for because you can't I that way to get
there
and that which ones with the faxing it
has and
and in this case it's a changing them on
your voice to sound like a robot or
something like that I have a
if it as echo effect delays and things
like that is really great
am so another thing that's really
important his ID to the 2a
I recently went to China and i cant ive
purchase Lee although the twins are
defined and Dave
my room is overflowing with joy is a
douche keep buying them
om for finding them in very serious and
now that I'm new and it's a given
people's leave them for me but I when I
find general these the nineties TD early
2000's are kinda the Bascom
it's for the really perfected the chip
on board I think it's
you've seen it if you've ever seen and
second part com fairly cheap
manufactured goods it's like that black
epoxy blob
so they're actually making the circuit
on top the board and that a pox easier
to protect the circuit
om so
in their early 2000's on that process
really got more refined
combat a lot in factories and then
turned over but now they have
and so now even like that she be cheap
toys ease to be able actually do
something with their
like completely useless because om not
only do they have
on the timing circuit is underneath a
chip on board
hours previously wasn't good enough to
actually have the capacitors in there in
to the other stuff but um d have drowned
out protection for my anchors on
parents don't tickle me ongoing
hahhahahah
her as the batteries die um
so lemme yeah it
so what ends up happening is as Elmo
goes through puberty a little bit I it
just eventually cuts off
and and it seems like it's dead even
those credited you slash
mom so those are things you definitely
need early look out for in two ways on
the more sophisticated the 28
on and the newer the toy the more likely
you can run into the situations that
doesn't mean that it's completely and
bendable but
com you gonna run into a lot of fun
problems along the way
on be a things look out for is novelty
Lake
my listings speaks Esperon to really
that people actually that is awesome um
but does it have audio output a lot of
times keywords and things like that how
did but occasionally you'll have
destroys it put headphones on in town
which is means is me I guess parents
like that cuz
you know you can to see you can the
corner and have them make sounds and
doesn't bother them
and but does the case have actually have
rooms for sickening I had this weird
thing where I like the two ways to beat
always
om so what is a good manners take the
the components out in re case them in
do really cool stuff and that's there's
nothing wrong with general I've seen
amazing artistic pieces
the no way that I actually preferred
that way ask on it
and even dr. breakup occidental for this
one com
this is the original to in this is the
breakout box it try to match the color
and everything
to the original to as opposed to the
other way around
um but also how small mason new is that
way because the smaller it is a smaller
the components
and the less room you can actually have
to work in that space or
com a harder time you're gonna have us
honoring two components as you're not
used to dealing with service not
components
mom you can have a much more difficult
pending hands
um so where do I find ways and usually
secondhand stories unless you live in a
really really read treated state like
Massachusetts
and cuz they passed this law we have to
test all toys from had
and that also applies to you on second
hand stores
essentially like they can't sell them
anymore second hand cuz he cant afford
to test all the toys to the get thrown
away
om so actually have friends you get him
singing all the time and I'll
me go behind that could well and get all
the toys and there but
for the markets a great %ah because you
can actually sit there and tell us that
way simply with them taking its roots as
well the usual and the batteries in them
so you can play with them see if that's
what you want
um and if anyone lives near
Massachusetts her
near Boston area in ninety as a flea
market there's a few other people who
cater to circuit benders and bring toys
and other things like that in there and
that's really awesome
on the EVA um usually you can find stuff
did
just by looking at the two way
high-minded see if it's going to be
something interesting and thus allow
heart that moms need for like really
really young kid and
om it's actually the cutest thing ever
see about a few a few bucks on eBay and
when you turn it on it says I love you
in ages actually haven't had a hard to
lead changes the only then they could
find was just the I kinda the timing
circuit
then bed it's so cute I just had the
idea how plane they just use it as a
sample
I in it but I after holiday sales agree
so um
specifically in the big box stores so if
you go to Target or whatever
mom like December 26 is the best day for
sickening ever
am cuz just all of that crap is
their am so
some other things you gonna need I it's
not terribly complicated new might
actually already have it and that things
for opening
things thats pretty important oscar De
Vries
com miss you doing high-tech toys you
don t make Exeter
on the turks grease or anything like on
com
but you do need a lot of patience if you
don't wanna break the things cuz they
often times he's a snap to fit
can it adds and I can be pretty annoying
um
various resistors I'll sue
potentiometers various sizes a generally
sick linear
Qassam get the gradual change but in
some cases you might wanna go without
analog which has allowed rhythmic
scale it depends on that way an
alligator clips are really good cos you
can be easing out to connect thanks for
testing purposes
I'm wired various sizes um
a generally actually go with that 30
gauge speaker wire Amazon going with the
structural thing it's
really then why are you can break it
very easily by Tom
it's great for sneaking around things in
a
just a double hockey you gotta data from
resistant so it is a break off so easily
a soldering iron of course the better
side earning have the
more easily you can be able to work with
the smaller Comte ways
cider I go with the leaded stuff I
the lead free is really bad cuz I just
takes more heated tome get it to melt
and Dom
here you're more likely to break
connections to be more frustrated to get
the lead star
a driller drop row say usually dude he's
a dremel
a multimeter but the best to love all is
ninety per hand reamer
I have to have them downstairs you can
see their majesty
an essentially use these things to you
get holes to fit
on that's how I get everything in all of
my cases to look exactly like they
should have always been there
because om their only is big enough it's
the park as you to scan at Lake
hand drill it out in the Eve test the
party and without us the part to it
works
om their amazing girly 15 boxes get one
arm so now how to kind it's a cabin
and the first thing I like to do is play
with the toy and
I mean really am thats at my excuse for
in US
baby I just how does respond I can test
the buns occasions before
mom are the sounds actually something
you like am
do all the buttons work D need to do
some work with it I actually prefer to
is it looks like it's a playoff with
Italy
buttons have sleep and rubbed off the
first thing I sometimes have to do is
text the two-way
mom so things like um friendly plastic
or Styrofoam
plastic and whatever you wanna call it I
it's really get really breaking some the
broken of tabs and things like that
on can you get a crash regardless
offending so like the %ah
a good example is the come speak n spell
like there's a couple button
combinations he can get it to freak out
for a week minutes at a time
on without ever actually opening the box
it's pretty cool
um then you just open up an exploit
but use your hands first so the thing
that's
really important news om you.re
resistance
are you are resistors so you provide
resistance is circuit so like when you
touch
making shredding various points in
circuit I am
it's not likely to try anything hi
unless its
plugged into the wall which he shouldn't
be touching any means om
but they usually have a a beer or other
cool beverage on hand in disc and he's
cool condensation from that and
touch around on the circuits I wouldn't
advise looking it cuz the
somebody industrial things depend on
their
ambit looking for resistors get either
really quick kennan second enzyme
kinda getting the timing changes and
seeing if they're there
I am they'd take notes breakdown
anything you see
I'm usually after three or four points
Acer writing things down for that you
can remember it
I am and when I find interesting things
or does competence and fresh leaded
solder
on to that point an insider in a bit a
wire that we can curb in alligator could
later
com be a so the way then start exploring
is an alligator clip with them
one meg I linear pot in series with its
own have a
live in the middle of the on the side
and essentially goes through that
because
Acer catching around in even that one
may kill
here like a little debt will be late any
Rory and so
League that's just enough that you know
that that's appointee should explore
answer the needs keep turning it down
Mike Corder by half until it does
something interesting
um be a I if it's like a soda and 3 vol
4.5 all weekend is can only keep
releasing indefinitely but if it's %ah
on like a much higher voltage to you
really wanna watch out cuz you'll
definitely pop something
bombay at insert tying things to ground
randomly
on the this is a point it's interesting
at this other point and just bring it
over to ground 0 depp's don't ever tight
to the positive voltage
mom unless you really have protection in
the way
because you'll definitely try something
and the train appearances
start touching around just see what
happens om
until you figure out what's going on
with the circuit
on and just because it stops making a
sound as minutes then I love people like
that way you'll get it to crash in all
make
really cool sound and then it doesn't do
anything usually just bought the
batteries have mac n
mom but also if you've removed any
resistors anything make sure you still
have resistance to complete that circuit
because it's not completed its not going
to start or if your resistance is too
low in my not actually start either
on so reset switch is ur peaceful kazi
kids go
toggle toggle and the to research
working again
I am so tuning the resistance for the
two is actually a little bit complicated
but
so once you're below that crash week on
there's some point they
you need some amount of resistance there
for the circuit to start
whatsoever arm so some say commanders
and a nearly
they don't like to put and anything in
series with their stuff like they let it
go into that crashed on it right now but
I like my two is to start
any time regardless om the caisson
disease even actually
at its lowest point I press the button
and it's actually going to take a while
before it starts combat this is a
comfortable
setting for me yes some pitch
so what was going on there is some
the timing at the circuit was slowed
down so much
that it was taking you know seconds to
start say kinda founders on that was
comfortable where
on it was a arrange that it started
enough time that it wasn't too bad but
also um
I can explore that kind its own even
lower once it does start
and so essentially keep Brees
reducing resistance until it stops
working in a measure the multimeter and
then kind of
pecan solid resistor com to them put in
series with that said you know
drop below it com but %um what use are
finding interesting things
take up the original resistor and just
start exploring answer get with where
you found a previously see things change
see i dont does
mom but there's Kenneth remain
controls that you can use on for
changing their resistance at
potentiometers is a sad for early
generally to linear kinda movement om
upper down for how you're changing
resistance and thereby changing the
circuit
and then the timing and circuit but I am
other findings are fed a resistor so
comforters a series connection can give
you a
Carman Stella fact speech Kings
but that doesn't work in all our lending
conditions this is great because I've
directly ding and their actions
not fluorescent cousin the fluorescence
is thing you hear the 60 Hertz bus and
it's really knowing
and so that's something you need to keep
in line with voters as you say can be
awesome but
not always really reliable control a
touch can
contact sir my favorite because you can
learn them over time
so Lake learning any other instrument
you actually learn how to play years ago
been toy
on and I actually prefer to use easy RCA
jacks
on and automate ways cuz you can get
them and large patch panels are really
cheap
everybody has those RCA cables that you
have to look to really see ours and
things like that
and but also the metal quality is really
high
so they make great touch contacts but
I'll see can become of forearm
you can at that photo resistor leader to
those such contacts
in things like that she can make a
modular system other things
they should decide be subtle how the
sicker performs on how to control skins
they'll respond a little bit differently
am like I said before unique you may
need
the resistor in series so that it
doesn't drop below that om
and basically pick a potentiometer often
with the controls you
one ours if you don't wanna make
potentiometer and you might get Lake
really slow the Lakers like are
the main act not actually be useful to
you you may not want that you might
actually wanted to be a sound simple so
you get that into you the 500 gained it
certainly I N
you know can have a little bit more
interesting on the big financial matters
you get big sweeping changes
om overtime and I it's really hard to
get direct
controls unless it's a zone that just
makes really nice Tom
really nice sound because an what might
be only
10 degrees I love interesting I if you
go to a smaller potentiometer it's like
you know a 180 degrees and interesting
zone the you can play with and get
different sounds but that always ASM
doesn't always matter on sometimes I'll
actually use two different
potentiometers one for the slow and
winter 13 p.m.
the short interesting zone one for adult
larger sweeping changes but that depends
com so I D out is important
om ITF
really good and to be able to bring up
the sound samples and
tight came another two ways on
blakey have to going to be a little bit
careful because
if you wire a positive and negative in
12 way it's not gonna really matter if
you plug it into stereo
it's gone on to equalize Kors on the
ground is actually what is referencing
of love
on but if you do that same thing and
plug that into the input in another 20
they're both my turn of you my friend
one or the other see need
to be careful about that this measure
with the potentiometer
she was positive she was negative and
where things get in the way
um oftentimes a lot a tweezer
the the signals really hot so I am
what I mean is when you plug into sounds
system you're actually gonna see it like
pickin read the whole time and that's
not really good for getting any kind
have
on coherent audio out about orient you
om
performance or anything so I that the
simple as we doing this is just
take a 10k potentiometer have your
signal coming in
when signal going out you're out with
the other going to ground com
and you have mine control in no time you
can learn a lot of
and it's just one additional part you
know after Lake am
do any calculations on that on also
kind of tax to be pretty interesting I
am
so without a kind of Jack if you'd high
street to the speaker
you can actually use your speakers and
microphone it's a poor make fun but it's
a microphone
casting camp some doesn't work so well
but
you can usually get some sound out of it
on
usually for these even they don't bother
with the kind of tax plan on for other
toys you definitely do when your mom
having audio output am hey
directly connected to you on what's
going into your
sound system chiasso pick up
interference and things like that
I so I template is awesome its present
in the toy
on their coupled with out there that on
his recordings plane back and have a
blue can do some things
um yeah of the times they have a jack
not always arm those sometimes have the
microphone that's built into it
on if they have a jack and the
microphones external and it's a tweet
that is has like a little I'm
teabagger phone then it probably has a
preamp
and that's really awesome cuz like I
said you can play guitar into it and I
use that as an effects pedal a sensually
mom but did the Los ok enough
its yeah it it'll cut off some %uh the
craziness
will happen when you input some from
other two is on some some from the two
is
be I usually just if it has Mike
descended across the microphone pans and
you're good to go
mom other times after tie 2-1 in the
microphone pins and
the ground actually to ground because
I'll be referencing of the pen on the
maker controller which isn't so good
well-meaning an not if you wanna bring
in but that is a microphone and
US com so some in the event stuff that
is around
com gad these
always take a lot more time a a call in
advance City Court I'm
on but it's usually a lot more
exploration to be honest
so the patch bays are for when you run
into you fifty points did
are really awesome so some the keywords
to see people with these hugely 16 by 16
patch panel basin leak they don't even
know with the stinking the only
there's only so many times you can
explore in some combinations for
the cyst in cinemas in this one it's a
four by four so I've
learned pretty well mom what I can do
with this one with the couple alligator
clip sir
on things they can am but
patch fazer awesome if you have a
complex story
and it also confuses are the people so
it's kinda funny
and so exploring with capacitors on
Canon changing amount so
actually if you get some mom various
size
ceramic disc capacitors zone don't play
around the electrolytic unless you
actually know what that means in know
you doing with them
am because oftentimes the large big
passengers and their
mom can shock you when you touch them
and especially did something with the
flash League
you can actually turn those things in
the stunning San guns sound you know
just
be careful with the large capacity so
nicked a little ceramic disc ones are
great
and dis bridge them with other capacity
sir bridge them with diabetes are things
com essentially urged her like you are
before
but now using additional components it
takes way more time and I am
I only do that when I find it weird that
actually does interesting things when
I'm exploring in the first place
on also there's a lot of ways that have
video output on special nowadays
am plug into the TVs and things like
that and I am
said karaoke machines those can be
pretty fun
but you can get a lot of interest the
artifacts in things like that
gay even open and game boys in thirteen
get some we can if
it is the fight is touching on circuits
am
so triggering button presses is kinda
picky
am so like in the case in this easy
button
from getting this to loop when you want
to loop is
for that way it's a non-trivial task UAE
an external chip for isolating a couple
things but some you can get away with
just a simple ol a cum
transistors a transitory to signal and
then either open or close
a larger voltage her larger signal
am so we can often times do is just
tirade the transistor to you the speaker
output
and if there's no kinda delay period
between when the sounds hurts when you
press the button
you can actually get to live very
quickly easily because what'll happen is
when you flip the switch on the
transistor reads at the speakers and
doing anything so it opens the gate
so that makes a sound happen which then
turns a speaker on which the transit
CC's that
there's now sound dampening silly closes
the gate
and then this is a speaker turns off
there's no longer sounds it opens the
gate again
and that that's a cool dude but that
doesn't really work for all the toys I
does work for the easy button
so way I have to do is get some kind of
an external
oscillator I'm so I there 555 timer
om he's had Schmitt trigger murders
switcher an
if you're really interested in a
Kentucky lied about its just a really
simple way of making
a square wave and then also make a
controller's canada.com
and essentially you couple that with an
outdoor ice leaders are not toys later
is AV component did mom
essentially as an LED and a photo
resistor coupled in a very small package
sOooo
when he ran a very small voltage across
it it will then drop
entirely the voltage across the other
two pens so um
by you know tying way a positive
voltages across a button to the apt
choice leader to turn on
closes essentially divine axes a button
press are you can read these relays for
that as well
I relays are expensive and com
dentist not really necessary miss Italy
have
on that's what Radio Shack and so that's
what you got and you can use them
on the tacit Eagle I quite a bit more
amperage
and powers so that some it uses a bit
more electricity essentially
so MIDI control is something that's
extremely exciting about.com
some other relief and sickening to is
because arm
like I said before you can have the up
to a slater's for remotely triggering
button presses so you can directly with
the keyboard control
the buttons that are being pressed on a
toy so that's like a little guitar with
buttons up the next you can map that
your keyboard you cannot that you MIDI
controller he came out that
anything mom but you can also I
within the MIDI a cancer she can
actually change
with the pitch is free to those commands
day they make these digital
potentiometers that
on three digital signal you can change
with the resistance is that it's
outfitting so
mom you can actually change both the
speed
and the triggering and that by om
through these digital circuits but also
if you have the maker controller
om you can generate square wave output
which you can actually replace the
crystal for the toy
and then you can with a bit of work and
believe coding can actually have you to
weigh on beats per minute
on which is really really freaking cool
mom
so you essentially have a completely
control to a and I
pointed out we know on here because
there's a MIDI library that's really
nice
you have access to these com all all
these commands her
available and it's pretty easy to
program and getting to you but you're a
couple other
com dedicated many boards that are out
there the Deacon lookup
om did add them in fairly quickly easily
om say ya there's a lot of
really great resources on the web mom
did
constantly have on
links to interesting things I get low fi
is a great website
hi they cover not only makes a convening
stuff that's going on around the rolling
sure really cool
mom and the people who see you too but
they also have %ah
they weekly um week any free albums that
are out there
cock is there's a lot of chip tuning and
circumvent and all kinds of other
electronic music stuff that just
given away for free that's that's
wonderful part the culture
on Casper electronics he's actually here
in New York
I am and
she doesn't want a very interesting
downs and publishes very clear
instructions online on the counter
replicate this thing so
om that the kind of interesting thing is
anytime somebody finds a really cool
circuit and
oMG you'll watch the yday president
thing gone from like two dollars to let
fifty dollars
Tom so said Berg karaoke machine
Anna it's this kind have really cheesy
pink plastic thing
wonderful and how completely horrific it
is an
went a girl with Mike Tom
and you can get the most ridiculous
sounds edit this thing because it's on
the attacks
hearing your voice term and that's a
given in dot com is a kind
interesting website that has links to
examples
and a couple other things a lot of
pictures its sometimes hard to navigate
but
and there is a good bit of information
there om
and been fast happens here in New York
every year
so you can talk to other like-minded
geeks
and shell this is all done and share in
treating people buy and sell toys and
all kinds of stuff
mom say %uh that's really awesome so
tomorrow at one o'clock in the hardware
hacking village
mom I'm gonna be doing circumventing the
easy button
and sides 25 bucks has all the parts and
access to my part dans om
so what are the things about and Kenneth
getting into hardware electronics is Ana
CA certifying
potentiometers to support my own habits
so my friends you can ima pot dealer
I am but yeah it's kinda truly K
have hundreds and pots is just all kinds
of values and things like that and my
friends will
literally contour like a dude I just
need some stuff from you
and yeah an
so you get access to you all those vans
and I will on
help youth room exploring the San
vacation before you can get some pretty
interesting sounds into this thing
register online if you're interested in
it as people screaming out a bunch easy
button so and run around Manhattan on
Thursday and Friday and I found
11 apparently not so man has 11 easy
burns
um so bring your own easy button if you
can find one outside then
Manhattan area 20 bucks in New get the
same parts
comforter is a seasoned on Kansas stuff
%uh right there
so I that's the QR code that will bring
it to you that hope talk things are
right now all there is is the
pre-registration
and Om also Deanna
com the link to my outlined above some
in the south today
mostly covered and I'll put the slide
show up once I have it and alter some
links up there at some point
thank are there any questions
it there's maker funds after
have you updated all with routing the
audio output
jack into an audio input jack producing
feedback loops like that
I had built into some to its
p
so that's exactly what I'm doing here
and it's just that early switch that
I tried talking about on Disick is there
a time delay in answer could
I own little bit but I'm not so much it
really kind if
an turns the whole thing to garbage so
much
I if I talk to is a car at like fair
the robot voice you heard me understand
what it's trying to say but I am
get it it really does digital stuff
so well and also stick around here to
see me later you can play with these two
ways
there out and available free to play
with me and some as second question you
get back to the video circuit bending
have you worked at all with feeding I
audio input into
video output I have not personally that
he was not one of my knee
and I direct interests among my friends
do it but
yeah I'm a sleek audio paintings
blade do that would be probably leary's
an awesome
I'll get on that yep these tried
actually
yeah oz or if you go into more detail
about the Barbie karaoke machine
what did you do you defend that and
results Egyptian
so hmm
and yeah I am explaining that to my
roommates now now I'm just
doing something kisses my job Central
Time Acharya have to play with toys
reliving
um so I gave it the bad touch
Space Wing mom when it was %ah
Noy it really that when
um it's mostly to get at those delicious
echo affectionately affects
on because you can actually the their
couple points you can change
%ah essentially like the decay in the
echo and all kinds of other things like
that
com through entirely analog means the
not
purpose whatsoever but I
Peter from Casper electronics really
covered it quite well
and %ah so that that is not one that
explored personally
am a lot as a given news really go for
like that way that people have never
seen before
on which is pretty calm but a lot of
other people just do you
but they have seen foreign that's fine
okay
so I am yeah any any other questions
him
so you talked a lot about vending toys
especially simple toys
arm to any of these things work on
really complicated systems like
game console yes all computers
yeah and actually there's a whole
aspects upset at the Argentine seen that
as a good bands a lot of cum
things like the %ah they give a fag I
actually sells a mod kit for the Gameboy
so that you can change the timing at the
Game Boy
and Om
did the homie control aspect and really
ups the game a lot cuz
oMG that that's a highly technical kind
of thing that you doing
arm and arm
yeah and summer the early stuff is
actually month finally accept the size
urs and keyboards and things like that
I am so the Cassie whiskey one is really
one
keyword an that's where that 16 by 16
patch panel being
has come from because they're really are
that many points that you can tie into
you and I don't think people in still
explored fully with an issue we can do.
om
and it's pretty crazy stuff so yeah
for okay
his movie but specific to
I'm they hear the funding for the BBC TV
series Doctor Who
okay and there is one specific toilet
came out
term 0 some insight maybe
years to go and which was basically
a remote-controlled toy it was actually
force controlled
to know if anyone has tried been that I
haven't seen that directly
but um like I said like some the
problems they're really modern toys and
saddam
there so sophisticated and trying to
protect you from
messing up dead and you can get a lot of
stuff
om so of times if you open something up
in you see the black blob in ICC coming
out of his league speakers and batteries
coming in and maybe the button
they disclose it you know you're in a
confined anything there
I'm but depending on how complicated the
toy is
I don't know I haven't seen it
specifically but if you have one week in
get the bad touch so to say
you push me I don't own one thing is
someone who does help then open it up
it
area and got about Lee use every more
minutes
any other questions are
I'm you win over the Barbie karaoke in
the air
speakers fellow to smother I guess like
really infamous
toys that have been then the the Fermi
pops up a lot
cuz om their kinda creepy to begin
and mom with many skin them Lakers youth
and its kinda Cavaliers but
yet it does have only a few few points
you can you billy
Dave definitely been sequenced and other
things like I am
play it gather there's a number by
keyboards that have are well-known TV
rate for bending in things like that
that circuit bending dot com website
covers a lot
love the really popular things and it's
out there
but actually the entire speak series
their speak in math um
and I'm sorry oh yes we can read
on they all use the same kind of TIA we
ship and they're all really really good
for
for getting some crazy sounds Nov om
p.m.
Teddy Ruxpin have you besides
sound many have you ever have any
anything to deal with the mechanisms its
okay articulated
yet a little heey doesn't do he doesn't
do too much
ADF myself and receiving data and my
speaker being on
on which actually GSM interferences can
fun to play with him
animal sometimes good web sites is to
get the nutrients Benin's
um so Teddy Ruxpin specifically is
entirely mechanical
and I he displeases and antique
and that is directly translated in the
mechanical movement into the job
but there's some really really weird
ones out there let ya know
am nobody in this room should know what
it is because it is the creepiest toilet
ever had and I i cited the MIT flea and
I'm
I had this for a don't pay more than
like I D ten dollars on two ways
other ways like when you go to the
circuit bending swap meets and things
like that like Wendys if you don't like
crazy thing show up Lake
I would buy all the damn on but ya know
should at least twenty-five dollars in
it's like this is the most uncanny
valley disturbing
thingies a storyteller but he has the
cell full-feature features and controls
and things like that
on yes so there are two ways out there
that you can get
these weird damage chronic aspects to it
by
like I said before com usually the motor
circuits
and voice control circuits are very very
different voltages
sleek dramatically different voltages
and you have to identify which is which
they're usually separate circuit board
so that makes it a little bit easier
om but you just have to be very careful
when you're exploring those stories
on always have an
potentiometers in series with what
you're exploring when
on even if its on the when is obviously
the voice control board still
explore with protection they're
concerned the Furby you can kill in
about
have the second on cuz it's all on and
at the same circuit board
9 am
I haven't actually play with the Tickle
Me Elmo
but thats a if think it's entirely just
electrical and there's like a little
vibration Center
vibration motor in there but in is
probably the same deal
p.m. antonin has been I'm sure that
to get a letter from somebody com used
as I said this amendment that some
products now
happily who in its own you with three
parts
gathered speed they put a pox the
anti-government views
I me old Michael toys a recent toys
things had this is like now cream or
more
what's it's because that manufacturing
process go out cheaper
I'm so it's kinda the same way that they
do you i on
integrated circuits in the Cure
processors believe I did see those
pictures like the pentium chips where
they're just thousands of processors on
this big huge circle
and some percentage the bird is going to
fail
but they know that percentage in and
they just cut them out
so they actually manufactured on their
and then they just put the pox
top answer to very quickly have can give
not being able to use with some
essentially with the photography
is how they're building the stuff up om
but not anymore they'll do it for is
fuse cows in our class on Merkel China
Mikey you know something doesn't exist
you send an email and the next day and
we love to those
you known since com but yeah that'd
that manufacturing really sorry getting
a much cheaper in the past few years and
especially
recently cuz a lot more factories are
capable of doing it now
and Dom gases that that's way that the
future and second inning is
is nine com there's still tons tons a
mid nineties to mid-2002 a sitter really
really good for
and stuff in
now and i havent anti anything specific
to that but that's only gets rate for
hacking period
cuz usually can reverse engineer those
protocols for a couple things
get the doubt upon am leaders said the
Star Wars II kind of
mind control generating om it actually
talks RS 232 use
heaters hack into the thing and is for
them
unique is here for you suddenly getting
late be really really really low level
like brain waves can
stuff but yeah I mean
that's like anything that I wouldn't
even leaks are given for seventy like
when a kid
Sniffen to make you get to do and see
re regardless com
anything else gif
oh yeah um eat you just gonna have to go
online could use a
like 45 benzene you decided you and if
you have an FTDI cable leadership that
makes it
really really really simple but om
essentially reeking of tx/rx
and its simple RS 232 Syria which is the
same thing it's
in the back and a lot a desktop
computers laptops have those anymore but
I am
and yet just with the serial
communication protocol you can actually
does get roddy to
from three different values at Lake when
it's Tom
if you know what it is like house wrong
signal is
with signal integrity is in and make way
this
actual signal is you know how high or
low it is
number its pretty cool he can see it
online so many as
a couple of programs in l.a desi
graphing information
and then now you have different up to on
the slot and
what it's like it's very funny and then
the next thing he just a kid
and then it still speak since even finer
cell
create anything else
okay sound that second inning
am if you get any questions I'll be down
hardware hacking area you were
absolutely free to attend just hanging
out in the
so give anything a watching people
been the easy ones if you didn't get to
the registration in time
to get one I am but also bring any other
toys you have
because I really do have parts and I'm
just gonna you know
encourage people to explore and play
Kors sickening I even though I have
a bit of electrical knowledge that helps
me get into this easier you don't have
to have that to get into it and
the hockey years to have fun and explore
and
10 some on