let me ask me if you want I'm for
3i we have a fascinating variety of
people who put a whole lot of effort
into making information available turn
off love the stories
this is another one of those %uh stories
that I know you're gonna enjoy
if the rummaging the government attic
and this is so for with Michael
and Phil so please God
thank you for money was Phil Lapsley and
for the last several years I've been
researching a book on the history a
phone freaking actually presented on
that topic
a at the last open I'll be presenting
again tomorrow
at noon gonna related topic on cats and
mice
history a phone phreaks an FBI and and
the sort of thing I'm but
as one other research tools for the book
I've filed
a whole bunch a Freedom of Information
Act request with various federal
agencies
and in the process I started looking at
four and how it relates to
how I was trained as a hacker as a lot
of parallels the guy that I learned more
about four then from any other source is
this gentleman named Michael redness key
who is standing
right here and so and I thought that we
were talking today about
for how to file for your request and
what you can learn from
I cover my name is Michael Ravin its key
and
although I now work is a on attorney in
the communications field
for many years I worked as a journalist
investigative reporter and as part of
that
I use the freedom of information act as
a tool and
in doing so over the years I filed about
10,000 for a request
and a what came to my attention was that
there were some folks that were filing
for requests and posting information and
documents online
at this website called government attic
and
they're shy people but they agreed to be
interviewed by Phil and I and we learned
some
interesting lessons we opened we want to
share them with you today
imagine if you will
a vast library of documents and records
billions documents every document the US
government has ever created
that database exists it even has a name
for
it's called every document the US
government has ever created it hasn't
gotten around to throwing out yet for
you can clear this database by using an
obscure search engine
a powerful search engine called foia
hathaway's the Freedom of Information
Act
there are many parallels but there's
also some differences
Google's electronic fully is mostly
paper although it's changing to become
more electronic
a Google is based on the web for his
based on the postal service with Google
queries or instant but with flair
the queers can take weeks months years
many years with Google the search
algorithm
is this the search engine is a computer
with an algorithm
and with way the search engine as a team
of humans who are usually helpful
up they rely on computers to and the
information is spread through a whole
number places
Google tries to be helpful way tries to
be helpful mostly but it sometimes comes
across as rather hostile
petulant arbitrary every document in
this database has two things in common
first they were created with taxpayer
money
they're yours they're put away but
they're yours and
and every document stated a shed some
light on what the government's up to
but those documents stay hidden
unless you ask for them there's no
mechanism that's been developed to
systematically share these billions and
billions of records
with the public requesting documents
under 40 is a socially useful necessary
and perfectly legal for my packing
for example what happened with the BP
blowout
well we can find out we can learn what
the
email traffic with the minerals and
management of Management Service was
the weeks leading up to the blowout are
the days after that or the
phone conversations that may have been
recorded
with when this thing happened and so on
for
so kids are going to look at today
relook at what is a for a request
how you submit one what are the tools
and techniques for for hacking that is
how do you create
a you well-crafted and hopefully crafty
request is going to get you the
documents and records that you want to
find out about
array do that with a little bit of
lecture up-front covering some other
background but then
Michaels gonna talk about examples from
this website we mention government
addict out or
and we spent a budget i'm looking at
that website and
and talking to the proprietors are the
website try and figure out what are some
tips and tricks
but first we'll go with kinda the basics
of what is the fire request hey submit
one that sort of thing
so a4 request is as simple as
4 sentences this is all you need it can
be a fax it can be a letter it can be
email and you people say all the time
Michael constantly get that we can you
give me an example for a request
here's an example for a request dude oh
my god this is totally a request under
the Freedom of Information Act
I request you provide me with a copy of
all records regarding whatever
whatever has to be specific as to enable
the agency to figure out what it is so
for example
I want to copy of all radio traffic that
was from the Deepwater Horizon between
this time and this time that was
intercepted by the federal government
not that we'd ever interceptor on radio
traffic on
I'm an individual requesting this
information for non-commercial purposes
I'm willing to pay up to twenty-five
dollars if necessary
thank you that's all it is four senses
that support request
K but you have to have those four senses
and their has this is a poor request
has described the records you want has
to give information for the fee category
about what's more the second
and has the state your willingness to
pay reasonable fees for
now here's what the fire process looks
like we're
you start off by mailing or faxing or
you're emailing in a request
and the government gets it they'll all
get
um they send you acknowledge my letter
probably you probably get that in a few
weeks
then it goes into a queue government
gotten better about this but
it takes a while for them to process it
and then they're gonna do a search for
records
now if they can find the records are
gonna send you a new records response so
you had a letter saying we search we
didn't find anything
now at that point you should be
scratching your head if you get an A
record response is thank
really did you really look for me did I
may be inadvertently word my letter in
such a way that
that you know maybe I made it to narrow
maybe I made it you know
the wrong in some way and that's where
you'll see there there's a feedback loop
because when you ever get a response
from the government usually it means OK
what can I do differently either to get
more documents or maybe that one didn't
work
a that that's the way it starts off the
back with their
assuming they define some records
they're gonna then it sit down look at
the records are gonna figure out if the
classified ad to declassify them first
then they're gonna go through and redact
out a bunch of stuff and the new to get
your documents and when you get your
documents
after you you know get done doing a
happy dance we having actually having
documents in hand
you're gonna look there is a 12 I this
mentions this thing I never knew about
this thing
let's file another for a request right
and I honestly think I mean I think
every time the FBI has given me
documents
for my phone free book I think every
time like God
you know we're gonna send in this
document lapses gonna send us twenty
more for your request me know exactly
how it's going to work this process
doesn't ever converge does never entered
for now how long does this take well
you know it'll take you a few weeks
maybe to get knowledge but later if
there are no records assuming that it's
not too burdensome
research is going to be a few weeks from
maybe a month
may be several months today if I'm not
out if it actually if they find
documents
that can take a long time especially for
classified especially if they're
voluminous
um I think the longest for your request
I've ever had
it took about three and a half years I
was from the National Security Agency
but Michael
for Woodford
but still have a couple that are hanging
around that are 10 one is 12 years old
and they tell me they're working on a
there they're making good progress
but they have a number of them that are
older than her in front of me in line
the MMM the good news is thats
thats unusual right I'm it does happen
just to set expectations so for example
if you want to file for a request for a
project that's due in school a month
from now
probably not the right thing for again
let's talk a little bit about money
about fees and just very nice both here
agencies are allowed by law to charge a
reasonable searching duplication fees
so they can charge you for the time that
it takes for them to search in some
cases and also for duplication
in some cases the fees are based on what
are called the categories there forever
there's not commercial requester which
is most folks there's representative
the news media there's commercial and
there's education or scientific
organizations
for most requests end up being either
free or a few tens of dollars but if you
have a big voluminous request
or you know it's a really complicated
surgery can actually
you know the several hundred thousand or
even more dollars two things here want
is you want to limit your exposure
you wanna state up-front how much it is
you're going to pay in your letter and
tell them call me if it's going to cost
more than twenty-five dollars whatever
it is
and then if the fees even reasonably
high call up the foyer officer at the
agency get him on the phone and say hey
what's up with this
with which P services is the part that's
causing the fees
so you can modulate the request
appropriately make changes
right is and the the r2 this is being
able to thread the needle so you
basically do not charge fees for
anything you ask for
if you're a reporter they don't charge
for search be so it's very limited and
they give out
waivers the fees but if you're an
individual looking for stuff
the art is framing the request so you
get what you want but you don't paint
for now
for Mike on have this theory we got the
toll booth they re
and it is that many agency is not all
but many
use fee is the way to dissuade
requesters on
now this is even just talking about
legitimate the is right for you file a
request with say the FBI and you wanna
know about
oh I know UFO's and it turns out that's
going to be
let's just say hypothetically 25,000
pages cuz the FBI don't know if it's
true or not was just a hypothetical they
have a lot of pages on your thoughts or
the CIA or whoever pick your favorite
agency
well if the church attendance the page
you're now looking at twenty five
hundred dollars for twenty five thousand
pages
so that's gonna dissuade you unless
you're made of money
um so in addition to that some agencies
charge a reasonable fee is or they will
make mistakes that make things all the
more expensive and so
week jokingly referred to as the toll
booth near the tollway keep people off
the highway
knowing the fee categories being willing
to reframe your request like mike was
saying to thread the needle
and discussing years request with boy
staff and especially the IT people are
requesting a database
that can go a long way towards making
sure that you don't end up paying extra
fees
one at one of the things that happened
is a lottery agencies have to improve
the processing and save
be become more efficient have actually
gone to electronic reduction in
processing so they scan everything in a
think manipulate electronically and they
can now put it as a PDF what that point
the duplication fees are essentially
zero
so the ability to dump stuff onto a CD
in mail to you or even better yet
email to you which is happening more and
more frequently is actually getting mad
at toll booth which
may seem like a good thing cuz they
don't have to photocopy hundreds and
thousands of pages if someone asks for
something
but the agency's get nervous about that
because they say were giving out
thousands pages but when I'm a toll
booth anymore
this is an easy pass system in someone's
getting a free ride so
sometimes there's there's a little
discomfort at the agency level with how
the how they control
people asking for things when there's no
way to charge fees for something they
think they should be used to control
wrote that made for get so let's talk a
little bit about exemptions
on unfortunately for us you know you can
treat you can request any document you
want the agency's don't have to
necessarily give it to you
because these things called exemptions
certain things are exempt from the
Freedom of Information Act
so they're allowed to black out a redox
some sections third
don't even have to give you anything if
the entire document is exempt and
exemptions range from national security
to privacy concerns to
go away thats internal stuff that really
doesn't years concerns the internal
operation ever agency that doesn't
concern you
there's nothing to see here move along
exactly right these are these are the
document you're looking for
honor for now
I'm not gonna go through their there 10
exemptions I'm not gonna go through in
detail
I have even Google them whatever you
want to find out more about I'm at a
point out though
what they look like on this is here's a
document this is on tap which was the
predecessor to be able and both which
will present predecessor to 2600
magazine this is an FBI file on it
on and for you
redactions look like Swiss cheese
sprinkled with gibberish and the the
Swiss cheese is where the blacked-out
sections a doctor in this case wideout
the gibberish you see down on the margin
on the right hand side there is little
letters that say things like b2 b6 b7
see the directly telling you which party
the Freedom of Information Act the
specific statutes
are exemption so be to its internal be
sixes
for but it be personal private personal
privacy
be seventy years its criminal stuff
perhaps having to do with an informant
et cetera
wanna be other reasons that they
withhold things sometimes the right big
letters and/or which means
non-responsive so on others they have
these documents may
they white outer blacked out big areas
and call them non-responsive so some
requesters have gone back and said give
me all the stuff that you felt was not
responsive to my original request
but you blacked out on stuff you sent
your does it look centrist
so for some exemptions are questionable
um the fact that an agency has exempted
something doesn't actually mean they
were right about doing it
and there are some exemptions in
particular their problem areas were
going to highlight them
when it comes to the Freedom of
Information Act for whatever reason
bless their hearts
agencies inadvertently make a lot of
errors one
now it's not say every time he an
exemption is really a lot exemptions if
you file for a question is the latest
effort acted out
many many many probably most of those
are correct but you have to be skeptical
in particular when you see these three
exemptions these are places where you
should be particularly skeptical
b1 is national security information be
too is
internal materials and b5 is legally
privileged material for
I likely won't talk about privilege from
through the resident lawyer sure
for the for
the b5 is is probably the most commonly
misused exemption
it sometimes serves as a catch-all for
all the stuff that they don't want to
get out
but probably should under the law the
law says under the case law that that
material to be withheld under this has
to be
beef produce this pre decision must be
before a decision is made as the lead up
to some decision
as the real decision and has to be
deliberate has to actually weigh the
benefits of what's going on has to be
opinion it
has to be an opinion not fact if it's
factual has been released
if it's deliberative but its if it any
wonder though if it's not any one of
those things put together
it's theirs and commands between if
there's anything missing you have to
give it out but they often say well the
whole thing just
withheld so flooding stakes there and
and they don't trained very well in that
area
oh one other thing that happens is they
might withhold something in full
basically says we found stuff its all
withheld and folders nope nothing we can
do about not usually blatantly wrong
because there's a requirement
that they give out what they call all
segregate ball really small portions
that sounds like a terrible thing
up but it's basically says you have to
look at word by word sentence by
sentence figure out what to get out and
just hold on to the stuff that you
really can't give out but give it
everything else
when the ones that I like recently was a
request I found I got back
all I was asking for was a list of
documents and they said oh
know the titles of the documents
themselves are classified
for K great for okay so what can you do
when you get these exemptions
well you send an appeal letter you
appeal to whatever the appeals authority
is for that agency or not gonna teach
you how to write an appeal letter here
even Google foyer appeal for more info
but the denial letter will tell you
the letter you back from the agency 29
you access to the documents that'll tell
you where
you should send your appeal and you know
you have actually a pretty good chance
with an appeal you're not really gonna
get everything you ask for your gonna
get more
frequently so if you can just kinda
explain like this look this is where the
confusion seems to be no need to be an
attorney to write this it's not a scary
thing
you just write a letter for can out some
good news
I started doing this in 2005 under the
Bush administration i've seen a lot of
changes
now under Obama under the Bush
administration with regional ashcroft
essentially the order to agencies was
use for exemptions aggressively to
withhold material
under Obama and Attorney General Holder
the new the New World Order is
release as much as possible presume
release when in doubt
and release even material which
technically may be exempt that is my
phone or for exemption
if there is no foreseeable harm so
that's great news has made a big
difference
Philip
literally under the a under the previous
administration
the the rule was if the Justice
Department said we will defend in court
any agency who legitimately can use it
an exemption it was a very powerful
statement n
1 I've they think it's Obama's first
official act in office was to issue a
memorandum saying that's nonsense and we
will
we want to presume release in actually
took about a year for to kick in at the
agency level that too was a bad there's
a lot of inertia at the agency level
they're not connected with her
a very close court about a year later
they started actually I've heard from
people who make a lot request that
they've started
actually releasing information much more
actively now of course it's a huge
change its
it they release things that ordinarily
they put up a fight on a pair
okay so we have some examples withdrawn
from the people at government attic in
the stuff is all online you can look at
it there's a lot of things there that
are
quite interesting this is a
non-commercial website that was founded
in 2007 they've
filed numerous way requests and the
fruit to those requests are posted
as a the as a public service they post
documents that are unavailable anywhere
else
and they're shy people but they agreed
to be interviewed
the first item is and FBI confidential
room dossier between 1950 in 1972 they
had this room where they put sensitive
documents that were so sensitive they
could include them in a normal file
scheme
and the room according to the memos the
room got so heavy
because it's so many file cabinets that
it was threatening the building was
threatening to collapse
he's not joking thats in the valley in
the member you can read it online
and so they started to weeded out
because every once in a while had to go
through and pull up things that were
or no longer a sensitive as they were in
there was a real variety of stuff that's
described in this
in a series memos and they really serve
as a roadmap that
map to historically significant FBI
files that their documents that point
other documents
and it shows the tension within the FBI
which is probably too and other agencies
where they wanted to be able to use the
files to do investigations and there had
to be connected with everything else
but at the same time they wanted to
limit access to them so they're they're
pulling in different directions and that
same thing happened a few years ago over
last year's when they're trying to do an
electronic filing system
electronic document system and that's
one of the problems in
in wife it ultimately failed they they
gave up and they had to start over again
because you can sequester that you have
to sequester certain things with a
witness protection program details
but you can't sequester too much because
then you can't make any use for
so the interesting thing about this
dossiers they released enough material
their permits
requests for particular interest in
files that they identified by file
number you don't have to ask for the
name you don't ask them to do a search
is a
I want this file number and even if they
took out the name
these people ask for summer have asked
for some up the files by file number
alone
and the prefix tells you what sort of
I'll it is actually so one of the items
in here was a file on the smuggling
atomic bombs or parts thereof and other
weapons of mass destruction to the
United States
it contains highly classified
information and and
estimates the soviet developments in the
field together with skip suggest the
countermeasures basically with this file
talks about his guys taking suitcases
into the United States
a or small boats but but mostly
diplomatic personnel carrying in big
suitcases
with atomic bombs in them bringing them
into the country
and the weapons of mass destruction is
not a new term it shows up in these old
FBI file sixty years ago
the FBI also the another item posted on
government eric is the FBI's
high-visibility memos these were
produced
every time another a famous person's FBI
file was released or something
a a high profile FBI files released they
produced internally what's called a
high-visibility them on they circulated
within the FBI and
and notify the families have anyone that
was rude affected because they got some
complaints after some files were
released that someone famous
and these memos point to a whole bunch
of notable files they gone from
decades and there's hundreds a items
mentioned in a course there
interesting file so there another road
map to more interesting stuff
the web meisters asked for them after
they saw a mention of hype is files and
some other
in another document here's 1i John
Lennon
the book at the documents to be released
or from a security matter new left
investigatory file the investigation was
initiated upon receipt of information
that Lennon might engage in activities
to disrupt the 1972 Republican National
Convention
third time is the DOD resale activities
border view it sounds like the most
boring thing you can imagine but it was
established by Congress to review which
videos and magazines could be sold on
military bases
so these guys heard about this and they
requested the meeting minutes and
agendas
and the decisions they made and this is
an example of where government a free
speech collided
and government eric is published a
number of interesting documents that
show that collision
for example religious activities in
prison where prisoners are asking to
belong to the Church of the country or
something and and
these DA intersection between government
and free speech in for religions on
those are always really
interesting junctures so the Board met
six times they reviewed
during this period they reviewed 207 I
periodicals 59-58 films by body
recordings
and it's a tough job but somebody's
gotta do it and they did this
year after year for several years and
the results are on the website
for so that the result for
160 magazines no good
ten others were okay that the the ratio
for videos was probably about the same
some the titles were a things we
probably would show here
the interestingly enough the people at
playgirl magazine
the editors filed an appeal they were
the only people who ever filed an appeal
on a Sat playboy
is OK but why is our magazine ban and
the afford I can swear this cuz I
I don't remember exactly but I believe
the board turned down said no
but the answers on government addict
answers on government actor
the Air Force and all the military
services head
have hollywood offices they still do the
Army Navy Air Force Marines Coast Guard
they all have these
yellows and Nevis office in Hollywood
and their jobs to talk to all the movie
producers
all the TV producers anybody who wants
to do anything
that involves any military assets or
once a descriptive you don't want to
a cost uniform across team information
was any kinda been put basically if you
want to hear if you want to use an
aircraft carrier
your movie you want jets flying over if
you want to show anything
you really gotta talk to them to get the
help and they decide whether they want
to help UN if you don't
and they also by the way want to see the
script had a time they wanna make sure
anything
that doesn't portray the military in a
proper weight is corrected its
you know it's their prerogative they're
supplying all the toys so
the government at ICF ok said that there
must if they're doing this there must be
something that says what are these guys
on hollywood actually doing how they
just define their distance out there so
they must be periodic reporting
there must be this and that so they
asked for the periodic reporting and i
got all these weekly reports from
the Army and the Air Force that the
other services were a little more
reticent
and it really shows a window into how
DOT has influence in Hollywood for
better or worse it shows how the
military build his brand for these
movies and television
and how much activity the they are
involved in
hundreds and hundreds a project to cheer
for
so here's an example gumball 3000 the
public affairs office at Edwards Air
Force Base
referred to the pentagon a producer
whose project involve music in
entertainment stars going on a
cannonball like Grace Las Vegas to Los
Angeles
asked if they could race on the Edwards
Air Force Base runways which is the
longest dinner
in the world I believe and according to
the producer the event with the NMT be
made into a feature
the the Air Force at the Pentagon said
no
for there's not enough air force
involvement or the help at this time
plus the race plans to end at the
Playboy Mansion
your and there are literally hundreds of
pages on the entertainment liaison
office quite interesting stuff if you
book for
the the Federal Emergency Management
Agency keeps a set lessons learned
up from disasters and hurricanes
tornadoes space shuttle crashes
everything you can imagine these are
things were something went wrong and
people are trying to figure out what the
lessons learned and the
people at government had asked for the
copy the database and I got a printout
of the lessons learned
so one suggestion was in there said that
in support a recent hurricanes
CR's primary functions and up fliers the
victims if our disaster
victim with the without access to phone
electricity or any means to get to a
disaster center and I received the flyer
informing me this information I would be
inferior
so we looked at all the stuff on
government attic n
we put it in four buckets the first book
it was documents pointing to other
documents
is guys seem to have gotten better
records access into a spin or here
the the one of the big things they have
a section on for
way case of Freedom of Information
caseloads are basically a system
activity log
for each agency that says who asked for
what what they asked for
in some cases how successful a word so
list a baller
attempts people have made to get
different things and how people have
asked for things what
with the magic words that used and its
it's really remarkable stuff
for up until a few years ago no one use
this but they seem to have
made in habitat asking for this has
become more popular enough where
community understand
but they've asked for the conference at
the agency internet sites
the internal intranet sites and and some
agencies have so many
internal for net sites that they don't
know how many they have
there literally do not have a count of
how many there and
they what they do is they asked for
these guys ask for the home page and
then
all the pages connected to it by one
click and then sometimes all the pages
connected to it by two clicks
so they work their way down the
hierarchy and along the way they found a
lottttt stuff
and they ask for those things to in some
cases so it's a very productive it turns
out that ABC's post a lot a really
interesting information on the internal
sites
and so because it's posted it's very
easy for them to find get to and so
these guys seem to mind that pretty well
a inspector general's in different
agencies do lots and lots of
investigations that when they close them
the titles are available on the reports
are available these guys list for
s just asked for a list of all the
closed investigations that each agency
something the 'it's never made exit the
provided for
the ID's have a dual role they they're
supposed to watch out for bad stuff
going on with an agency but they're also
supposed to
sort watch out for the agency itself so
it's a little tough for them to promote
their
all the bad stuff they find about the
agency they work for but
if I can jump in here for second Michael
this goes to the point you made earlier
about
in the introduction that the one of the
huge
socially valuable roles a four-year is
to pry information out the government
that we should have anyway
but that there's no mechanism right now
for distributing
right so there's just no mechanism
currently for a lot of the stuff to get
out
to the citizenry and say you have to ask
for another great example
so the inspector general's they would
love to have this information out there
but but protocol dictates they really
can't make a point of telling people
you know how many people were looking at
that stuff on their internal computers
during working hours or something but
but
there's a lot of interesting information
so TSA had emergency amendments
a all kinds of things about restrictions
on travel and getting on airplanes and
and they've got this so that
the next categories agency
self-identified interesting documents
how do you find out what the interesting
stuff is a disease you tell the eight
you get the agency to tell you what's
there
so for example people if they ask these
guys are best for the list at the all
the still classified documents at an
agency
they go back sixty or seventy or eighty
years by the way the old is classified
documents by the way that I've been able
to
ascertain are about a hundred and
ten-years-old
for it's a long story but but they're
still this is over
there's still class by the Office
documents at the National Archives about
ninety four years old
happy with invisible ink but but so many
things just never get the class but
a list a restricted opinions different
agencies produce all these these reports
& opinions and their restricted so these
guys asked for a list of all the
restricted stuff
reports in a city congress that were not
post online you can see an example of a
complex query here which
they can do and that provides access to
all the stuff they gave to Congress but
didn't bother to tell anybody else they
were doing
would let me just jump in there think
about the request letter right
you know gear agency please send me
copies a everything that you
everything all your reports to Congress
but you didn't bother to post online
right you would think that the answer
would be none we both did everything
but of course that's not the case right
min it appears that
for an agency to postings online they
really get the information a docking
attempt at an internal champion had
overcome some bureaucratic inertia I
don't think there's anything
evil going on here just that it takes
some effort to get these things going
because they produce so much material
there's a there's a little bit %uh very
over
so too are the two other categories
working behind the scenes
for example a asking for the contents
but the tracking number
processing files for other flee requests
let's look behind the scenes that they
at the activity log and see what they
actually did and you could tell well
you seen a request and I for it shows
where
agency found stuff but it technically
wasn't
they interpret a it to predict that to
say that it wasn't relevant they can
give it to the person but the all that
back and forth
chatter traffic is in those files and
that's sort of an interesting diagnostic
tool
and internal agency newsletters
correspondence with members of congress
articles from National Security Agency
technical journals going back decades
which are quite interesting
but no red 911 air defense recordings I
think that
vanity fair actually got those first but
these guys posted all 100 hours online
and agency memoranda of understanding
those are basically the
agreement for peace treaties between
agency and everybody else in the world
or other agencies
and then pop culture is just a couple
examples they asked for lists the movies
and books
on the space station and they got that
got a lot of press I understand I saw a
lot of articles about that
on all these people were upset that
their particular favorite movie was not
on there and some people were
criticizing
region the astronauts for their choice
of movie watching their
for can you know a firefly was on there
you think that would be on the space
station right
and complaints to the FCC that
particular TV shows up
which there's a whole section on it's
quite interesting and it turns out that
there's a lot of people complain about
shows
and how they're watching the shows that
they can't stand to watch is another
story but they
there's people will find complaints
about just about any TV show
bill after
we talked a lot we talked a lot about
documents tonight
and general anything for you think paper
but you should
database is an electronic records are
fair game under the Freedom of
Information Act
and there are a bunch of advantages to
asking for stuff electronically one is
even if you're just asking for like mike
was saying earlier for asking for
documents if they've actually process
them into a PDF or something like that
you know its that reproduction costs are
much lower in its then much easier to
share with your friends or post online
or whatever
but you can also request entire database
is right to the database is just really
a collection of records and so it's
subjective
where so and these days pretty much
anything that any agency does
there's a database associated with the
database may not be anything more
sophisticated than a excel spreadsheet
but it's there and you can request it
and you know an example that is a
my commission for activity log that's
really just a former database
filled his me one of the things that
happen sometimes and erstand from these
guys is that the
agency for a office says you can have
their database because it's a
proprietary software running it
and we can give it to you and often they
say a talk with the
agency IT person helps resolve that into
Word
downloadable format that they can look
at bright
and similarly if you sometimes there may
just be some fields in the database that
they're freaked out about
and so if you talk to them about white
biking to process my request so we can
give it is the author
but that's great I don't actually want
those fields about now I'll
well yeah I guess so there's a there's a
famous story about a state department
database that that
either these guys were someone else
asked for and they said we can't it's a
in
in such an antiquated database system
that if we can't download it because it
would break the database
just or a true star look it up on google
it is it is a we'd never database
so here's an example this is not
government at it but this is a a foil
web mashup that's really kinda cool
on the I Air Force historical research
agency after a
which is basically the Air Force history
branch a
maintains a it's an internal database to
550,000
historical Air Force documents that are
sort of like you think it was like a
card catalog I've
Air Force documents and so some
enterprising folks
filed a FOIA request got the entire
database and put them on the web
and so you can now go to www dot Air
Force history and extort
and you can see this entire database
and it's really it's really quite
amazing we've heard the air force itself
uses this database rather than their own
internal version because
they can't remember the past they don't
wanna remember the password to get into
their own system and they require smog
in so they use this one instead
that bouquet of the interface is
probably better okay
so one of the problems that face is all
of us as for requesters is
where's the interesting stuff where the
goodies in it's a problem in two
different ways
first of his tough for us as individuals
to know where the stuff is
or even how to ask for if we know that
it's in there and then on top of that
the agency has no actual incentive to
tell us
rate than 100 all the good stuff is
right here
rights organization requested or what
magic words you use to retrieve it
so the solution like we should've been
alluding to what the government added
people seem to be very good at
is to get them to tell you by various
kind of signaling mechanisms
so you know the government outtake folks
seem to be submitting queries that's for
the agency itself to signal where it's
interesting stuff it's
so examples are identifying restricted
around published reports we mention
you know reports to Congress that have
been published on your website which you
can actually to send a follow request
saying
plea 7e all the restricted reports or a
list of all your restricted for the
first five pages have each restrict the
report
right to looking down at 2 p.m. the cost
you can look for a missing report
it great your see a web page oh here's
all the reports that we did
fiscal year 2009 and its report number
one
to for 5 like huh for
was report three have a report three
guys let's have it
so um you can ask for the
you know please send me copies of the
oldest historical record your agency
that is still classified um you can
focus on materials is withheld as a wave
signaling right when you
making request requested some broad set
of documents when you get back something
with a whole bunch redactions
that's what it tells you that some
important area that may be worth your
attention
if their documents which have been
released previously and have big
sections which are blacked out you can
go back now because the rules are very
different than they were under the Bush
administration
and their 10 till 10 to release more
much more yet this is a key point
frequently I will see even in my own
request this is another reason why the
FBI probably hates me
as a look at our request I filed in 2005
or 2006 I play I bet if every request
this or get more information
now so again another reason from their
perspective while the slaps the guy just
his request never and
I'm finally the other thing is seeking
documents
that identify other documents we talked
a little bit about that but you're
getting them to give you this
documents that are that are interesting
I should adhere one of the things that
happens is the agency for a offices are
inclined not really sensitive documents
but they don't mind releasing
interesting documents which are not
sensitive and people who request them
probably would prefer to get interesting
documents don't care for sensitive or
not
so there's a little bit of an overlap
with their weathers the mutual interests
have the foyer office
and the requester do merch and so that's
helped helpful room for
discussion and negotiation to when we
were working on this talk Michael sent
me an email saying how do you have an
diagram and PowerPoint okay so here's
some places you can go for more
information
on filing for requests um the National
Security Archive
at a sure Washington were
George Strait George Washington
University and its archive dork
has a great a said information both on
how to file for a question a lot of
examples
national security security-related for
work with a blog called
unredacted dot fourth are
there's also to web sites get my FB i
filed a common get grandpa's FBI file
dot com
and these will help you file a formal
request with the FBI
either for yourself get my FBI file or
for any deceased person they don't
actually have to be your grandpa
some people have proposed the website
get my
at IRS audit file that comets were
that hasn't been implemented yet but if
you're welcome to try that as an
experiment
um open the government or as one
a there is another %uh group called the
a
there's a informal group it is the FO
i-80 for oil
this survey and you can google that is
it at Syracuse University is a very
active mailing list lotsa
really good experts on there about all
manner of oil and there's an archive
which you can search which is got in 15
or 20 years old it's got thousands of
postings on any subject you can imagine
and it's worth exploring and then forced
government addict outworked we should
also mention
oj it's Michael you talk about that yes
Oj's the Office of Government
Information Systems services
and they've a they were authorized a
under the law cheap the legal change in
the law couple years ago
and they were just set up by the Obama
administration the bush administration
had funded them
and their job is to help for your
questions to get stuck with agencies and
the located at the National Credit you
go 20
if you Google ok just so GIS you'll find
a very helpful people and I understand
they've been remarkably helpful and
effective in
are fixing arm up blockades between
agency in a request during
in getting the requester the help they
need on some difficult to
conundrums okay
so before we take questions I'd like to
leave you with the party challenge
gonna questions the first challenge is
this I'd like you to take 30 seconds
sometime this weekend just 30 seconds
that's all I ask
think about something you've been
curious about recent news story
could be anything figure out what
government agency might have something
to do with it
guess what documents they might have and
then request them
do it today do it tomorrow due Monday
but do it soon because one thing ever to
vote for your is
although flip request may take months or
even years to
come back to you guaranteed if you don't
request for two weeks that's two weeks
longer before you're going to have this
document threats I'm constantly looking
back I think I wish I had requested that
way and Harry find the address to the
agency for the playoffs you just type in
the name of the agency
and then where n your shop the foyer
page for that agency in or give you the
address in probably an
email address to send in a request by
email and
to request one is poster experiences on
the hope for me if you do request
something let us know what you get back
and you know your mom raised you right
thank you notes were always a good idea
not to us but to the foyer officers
involved
they have really kind of a thankless job
it's really nice to say thanks to them
Phil Simms really nice Christmas cards
to them
yeah but I think I'm a sucka
alright questions hi
how you
thank you so much for the the charming
entertaining and informative talk
%uh it I was kinda piqued by your saying
the old is classified documents and it's
on like at a little story there but
after you know it's kinda curious what
they were or something like that seem
like a beacon of a little anecdote thank
you
a lot of them have to do with things
like gas masks for forces
gas masks for dogs a things along those
lines
so there was recently a number in SA
technical documents posted on Cryptome
yeah that come out before a request now
after they were posted someone
realize that they've needed request for
the same document number: years back
and it turned out their actions that you
documents were entirely different and
combined to give a lot more information
then either of them alone and there's
also a lot of interesting
information it matter what was reacted
active and wondering how often that
it seem that the sovereign actions have
a difference of opinion
you get more information from requests
this is actually quite common it's a
it's a useful thing to watch one one
story that tonight's dinner I think
there are two gentlemen in Blackpool
escort you out
I there's one interesting story someone
had requested
document from the justice department
about how certain program was being
conducted on diversity and and the
justice department's particularly retail
strewn about releasing they finally
were pressured into releasing the
portions they could release but they're
equipped they released a redacted
version which meant somebody over wrote
some black on the docket without taking
the underlying
meditate out and of course the the text
was still there someone copied and
pasted it was all there
and it showed how ridiculous their
reductions were in it
it it caused a big stir because it was
clear that they were using exemptions in
ways that were totally legal
and this was a a very prominent events
but
1 comment on on that specific thing that
is a that is a thing that does happen
night the reality is that they're human
being he just got back that first page
about your Google being an hour the
minicomputer versus foyer being a team
people people are processing these
documents and deciding what to redact
they're going to react different things
and so if you compare different reactor
documents you're potentially learn more
and for sitting here in D
when his first pass the act was first
passed in nineteen sixties
%uh up but it's been it was very weak at
the time
and I think 67 and it was 66 and it was
strengthened in 1974
it's funny because it was strengthened
by people who weren't necessarily favor
that they made it stronger so would be
killed
as an amendment and I got past anyway so
it getting stronger and
actually what happened to the into the
bush administration was they passed an
executive order which
which helped requesters to try to fend
off an improvement to the Freedom of
Information Act
and it has the freedom Ave Information
Act improvement as well see at both
so that the end of the Bush
administration that was a big push that
actually helps but the Obama memo was
more effective in making changes
and as he leaves the behavior that told
it and
answering in either UK comment on what
he thought the
future have the system was it seems
really
and say counter-intuitive pay people to
and reach create anything a than that
build the database
Osher and that to me
his fat ended it complicit in this
so it a big question right on n I do
think one thing is
as information becomes increasingly
digital I mean they keep promising us
the paperless office
right fed um it becomes harder and
harder to justify any sort over 30 years
or whatever
at and so I think you're gonna see those
tend to go away and that's going to
result in a lot more
open a somewhat more information being
released at the same time
there is a problem right there is a
there is a something's actually I
believe
country to some people here I'm sure in
this room there are some things that are
legitimately secret
and that the government may not want to
release a may have good reasons for not
wanting to religion so
how you deal with this I don't think
we've we as a society or
or they as a government have figured
that out yet I think it's gonna get
better but
something new able at times I said again
but through that
the theory is released 21 released all
if they release the one person that goes
everybody
benso but in some ways rate from their
perspective will look for
here here's some document that we have
we couldn't spend time putting us on the
web for whatever
right Picasa certain amount of money
some fraction send two dollars or
whatever to do that
if instead we let you ask for them we
know it's actually now important for now
will spend the time
so that's very true what he say for
for this thing fisting
ever requested information on how much
people you keep employed
and how many manpower has been flowing
to your requests that would be
interesting I
I'm I I'd really rather not know that
I'm not going to request the head
we didn't ask the government at people
that question as I got here the late so
I may not
had got the Spartans beat but if you
have a security clearance
you were cleared by someone and there
was a process that they want you back on
such so
can you for your request your own
background check
your yes certainly there's a what is the
logic behind that if that's a good idea
its it's not only if where there is
built into the law that you can request
records about yourself it's called the
Privacy Act easy when you're requesting
records about yourself you get more than
a few requesting about other people and
and
the background security check that's
something that is is written in that
you're allowed to get a copy that went
at the conclusion of the security
clearance for thank you very much for
his question with you where
agency request when you're trying to
find information about yourself
and also do you think politicians are
changing the ways on that they're
keeping information to hide it so it
doesn't want to be said
and to these apartments and is
eventually found the you guys there's a
lot of the
well we didn't do this so we're not
gonna take credit for that but there are
a lot of agencies that have the key
personal information and there's
something if you
for if you google the term Privacy Act
compilations each agency is supposed to
provide owner
annual except for biannual basis a list
of all the data sets that they have they
have personal information actually the
huge list and is what agencies that are
involved in a few
find those agencies and up and look up
there for the office you can add you can
ask for the record the request under the
where for your privacy act I might have
missed this set to
but on disinformation to be released in
trying to protect reform
that's happening much more often now
it's much more often that you see this
stuff released you can tell from the
files that are put on line sometimes
there
there had texted in ways that make it
clear they were released in some other
and some electronic form and the
agencies are
moving more toward up the specialized
processing systems that allow them to
help with the stuff electronically it
saves a lot of paper and
photocopying one comment on that is
every agency is a little bit different
for forever because every agency has its
own flair processes and
and give people who do it in the butt
different IT equipment and everything
else so
one agency may give you the entry is
another agency me very very good about
emailing
phil was once told that he couldn't get
a paper copy of a record had to get it
dick digital copy because their
photocopier was broken the FBI I'm sorry
the FBI photocopier
3 true story we we've been saying agency
over and over again
%uh is that correct that foyer only
applies to executive agencies
so not the legislative or judicial
branches yes there's
it applies to the executive branch
agencies in the federal government the
some other states have
all the states have analogous laws but
some other weaker summer stronger
typically of ways uses a catch-all term
or it sometimes they say Freedom of
Information Law but
each state has some law about that if
you want to run down all the different
states and one loss they have its
it's a treat RC FP reporters Committee
for freedom of the press has a what
has a page called a the
the something about tapping if tapping
offical secrets or something like that
and it talks but each state
but the arm there's about seventy
agencies
and a number of components within each
agency that halfway offices there's
probably about
I'd say about three or four hundred
forty officers and the government for
do you think there's any credence to the
fear that if you make a
for a request you may actually be
drawing attention to yourself
that seems to be the reason people give
to me when I
encourage them to make for a request is
the if they don't have any documents on
me then
now they're gonna be interested
wondering why I believe that's entirely
folklore its totally untrue how much is
a pic 7 that except for you
yeah
it that's a tough one there right
because it's proving a negative so
but I i agree with Michael typically the
operational aspects of an agency are
quite separate from the foyer
aspects of the agency so I think you can
be reassured on that point thank you
very much
for you aren't we doing so schlesinger
engineering and here overflow is back
and bill
we're starting so sanitary or less on
time the Telephone Pioneers
are going to go after social engineering
back there okay
hang out this better for