they wanted a three were I anticipating
changing all our lives and losing a lot
of sleep over the upcoming weekend thank
you in advance for your participation
couple quick analysis for get started
without owning your own phone
I one is we have some live concerts and
has some details on these
I the concert series is called beyond
that the welding our
and itself music characterizes chiptunes
and circuit bending
and basically this will be danceable
music created on Friday bitter sting
devices
we have a couple concerts going on
tonight in the video temple areas on the
mezzanine area you can see the
map in your program for location that
11:30 p.m.
going through probably told least 2 a.m.
so if you're looking for something new
on long overnights
that is a good choice we're doing a odd
coupley for our site
couple different artists much more night
Saturday set so
circuit bending concerts live
performances down in the video temple
area tonight
also I'll that he saw the lightning
talks it happened after today's i dag
kamensky keynote
we're gonna do those again after
tomorrow's keynote
and if you like to submit a lightning
talk email on projects at Hope got that
project that ok got nada make the
subject line. include done
lightning and about and will monitor
that
your get a response back if your
lightning talk has been non
accepted up next we have %uh the talk of
it for himself
psyche profit talking about owning your
own phone
%ah thank you it's a good to be back in
New York City
%uh for the next up I thought the last
one was the last one but
turns out it was just the one before the
next one on
so if you're left over from the last
strike at this
talk unfortunately that doesn't have
anything about
sacks or dong sir phone sex tongs or
anything like that it's kinda
abhi ish sorta ish drive a
history lecture I & phones stuff but
if you like phones then you're in the
right place so
cool my I'm T profit I'll a freak
%ah thats the kinda person that likes to
play with phones
I write a column for 2600 magazine
called the telecom and former
us so if you do you read the magazine up
it's not online
but it's printed on dead trees and stuff
you can buy in the back
on every issue I have this so
column I do it had a cranky persona for
nearly retired telephone employees
obviously
I'm like quite there yet myself but
unite read it try to be faithful to that
on I believe technology gives people the
power to change the world a very
strongly believe this and that's a part
of why we're all here
and I believe the people accomplish the
most really when they build communities
and so the stock is as much about phones
as about communities and the direction
that I think that we as a hacker culture
need to go
us so their spend a really incredible
revolution that's happened in my
lifetime and in many of your lifetimes
on spend disrupt disruptive it spent
destabilizing but for one I wouldn't
have it any other way
on and what's happened is that we
as a result of having very cheap very
available communication technology
available to us
I'll by having resources like the
internet available
we've been able to communicate in ways
that we weren't able to be four and its
lead in a very real way to
actual political revolution among them
the Orange Revolution and the Ukraine
other Rose Revolution in Georgia which
supplanted a very brutal dictatorship
with an actual
supportive mostly functional democracy
and not
in the bush administration sense on
there sa bennett you know you'll hear
more tomorrow about we keep wiki leaks
and some of the things that
%uh for that resource has made possible
and of course %ah for incredibly
disruptive at least in terms of how we
deal with
content and you know being in the
publishing industry
ourselves at 2600 we've had to come to
grips with things like that tore at
and the Internet I as part of this
communication digital revolution us so
on it hasn't always been this way and if
I
government Telecom's and Sarah Palin
have their way at night not always be
this way
us so what we're gonna get to is a
little better
you know a rewind and I'll be talking
about what things were like
kind of when I was a kid there's a big
period in the middle that we're gonna
skip over because it's I kinda lost
decade I think
and then we'll get to now and a call to
action as to why I think we need to go
on sir twenty-five years ago roughly you
could communicate with virtual at on
Amity
and a way that is not possible now and
here's what I mean by that
on when you make phone calls there were
things like class features
I and a class feature is things like
caller ID and call waiting and voicemail
out there was no communication systems
since for law enforcement acts so
if the government wanted to tap your
phone or monitor your movements it was
actually from a technology perspective
a very difficult thing to accomplish
they had to do real work send somebody
somewhere
to clip into the frame and you know have
a have a real to reel recorder going
I'm some areas even stole used analog
switches including Seattle where I grew
up when I was a little kid I i
would call the Seattle Public Library
storyline and
you know I would hear the unusual
clicking and ringing and wonder what
that was and
you know was later when I got toward the
end development re school went to middle
school but I really learned what
what those switches were and started to
hear them go away
and in 1984 the bell system was broken
up but one of the things that we
I really need but don't pay as much
attention to is perhaps we should is at
that time there were a lot of
independent phone companies and they did
innovate and interesting ways
but you had on in Oregon a number of
telephone cooperatives that were
community-owned
and they were actually way out in front
for the bell companies in terms of the
features that were available to their
customers
and of course there were other things
going on in other parts of the world
that france in particular with their
groundbreaking many tell
which in many ways is so kind of the
predecessor to what we now know as the
internet so
there was an evolution and that
evolution was spray significant up
I think probably the most groundbreaking
thing that happened
was in the late 80s I sprite built the
first nationwide fiber optic network and
so for the first time
it was possible over the same class in
the ground to
March voice data and video all over one
network
I we began to see over the years analog
switches retired and replaced with the
shit all
I as I mentioned before and also as I
mentioned before class features were
added and but that became more or less
universal
a party lines which in summer the
independents in the rural areas were
still commonplace I even as late as the
early 90s
began to be retired %uh we sought
touchtone service added
first is an extra cost service I and
then standard
we saw voice messaging and we saw
Centrex become available
and we speak and to see some long
distance competition
and all love you know that anytime we
have something new
available that's a lot of new things for
freaks and hackers to start trying to
figure out
how to take apart and use in different
ways
and so
this gets us into the 1990s which I
think we're the most disruptive Lee
innovative decade in human
communications really sets the invention
the telephone
we saw equal access and we saw
competitive local exchange carriers so
what this man to
was instead of only using AT&T for your
local and long distance
on and you know AT&T me so that's office
Pacific Northwest fell one
bellsouth and and other our regional
bell operating companies
post the 1984 divestiture but really
it was affectively one network still
even though there were different
corporate management structures
when we got under the in into the
long-distance space
there was a further break up an AT&T had
to allow competition
up for long distance so we saw companies
like MCI
companies like all that companies like
spread
become available not just through
dialogue around services
but actually you could pre subscribe
your home telephone
to an alternate long distance carrier we
begin to see
with the explosion a personal computers
and interest in PBS's and
like many tell in France PBS's CN the US
and much of the rest to the world became
to some degree the predecessor of what
we now consider the Internet
2600 magazine was really at the
forefront of this curve
and I had a service call above 2600
Voice PBS
up the 2600 Voice PBS was particularly
interesting because you didn't even need
a computer to call
anybody with the telephone could anybody
with the payphone
editor for a device called the red box
could and so what you really ended up
with was
this amazing equalizing factor on the
2600 Voice PBS their side
a guy who would call and on who was
developmentally disabled didn't know the
computer was from a poor family and I
upstate New York on aim to make a delete
one of the best freaks that I've ever
talked to work dealt with
I he was fantastic but social
engineering he knew a tremendous amount
about how the phone system worked in the
background who to call
I do accomplish things and this is
somebody who
most people would look at as a retarded
not let's be frank on
a service like the 26 404 s PBS
really allowed even somebody
who nobody would take seriously the
ability to communicate with other
like-minded people
I we had cops and I give a talk couple
years ago on
called freaks cops n chale I think it
was here
I'm so its online feel free to refer to
that
if you want to a more in-depth look at
the cops seen
but this i really think was a very
important part
a freaking culture and even remains
today to be a fairly important part a
freaking culture
and this gets to with the community
peace which are getting to you later
a it was possible to perform new me
elaborate prank calls it turns out that
if you have all of the services that you
can break into like voice mail boxes for
example
on and people trust those services soup
which they perhaps shouldn't
it became very easy to convince people
to do things
that they shouldn't necessarily do in
the more things change the more they
stay the same
and so we'll get to that later and in
the nineteen ninety is one of the other
destructively innovative a things that
happened
I was on the government and regulatory
side and
this actually was the predecessor to
what we see I
a lot of governments around the world on
no matter what
whether democracy sir not up try to do
in terms of controlling content
call the air was the foundation at the
infrastructure to control communications
and it handed the government that
control the communications for
assistance for Law Enforcement Act and
if you go to asks you Alea
I dot con that's one by the FBI it's a
site for carriers to you understand how
to implement
on this lot there is literally a back
door built into
every telecommunications network that
our first public
telecommunications services in the
United States
this backdoor is built in fundamentally
in the background at the government
doesn't actually have to do any work to
tap your phone anymore they can do it
all. remotely
through a remote monitoring in dial
they just dial up a voicemail box at a
red pen
and they can enter the number they want
to monitor and listen to what you
are saying and it goes even a strep step
further than that now because with
wireless communication networks
all you have to do to track the location
if somebody if you're 14 Smith the
physical location if anybody
even sitting in this room is like unto a
web page
and the true extent up this came out
recently when I it was discovered that
spread
had responded to literally over a
hundred thousand requests for location
data
I and provide at this site on their
website to law enforcement
this is infrastructure that's been
implemented now
it is monitoring everybody potentially
now
any accountability is very limited
because in the bush administration this
dramatically got expanded
so there's been an evolution
%uh and there was also an evolution in
the ways that hackers
oz began to look at telecommunications
networks and use them
so we had things like PBS's but if you
wanted to call a PBS outside if your
local calling area and it was all three
dial up at the time
you would need to make a long distance
call obviously if this could be quite
expensive
by I don't know I how many if you were
around then but
just a quick show of hands who's ever
gotten a long distance bill more than a
hundred dollars
okay so over audience obviously
on you know the for those have unique
guy who are younger probably you'd be
shocked that
there wasn't such a thing as unlimited
free long distance from your landline
that just came standard on it used to be
you paid by the minute
and you could pay an awful lot by the
minute I'm so
we as freaks a good look at ways to get
around I how it what
how I how we would have to pay so much
for these calls and you know calling
cops
similar story so blue boxes get a lot of
press
and blue boxes stability and if the
eighties in the beginning in the
nineties support in Essen
brought uses they were in the seventies
on
and early 80s but you could still use
them on C-five networks and what that
was his
if you could get if you could hit air
routes that would go over satellite net
didn't cost you anything
you know this is a thumbnail sketch it's
really more complicated than this but
if you could make a free call that hit a
satellite in some way and that satellite
you see five signaling
it was relatively easy then to seize a
truck and go out from the other end
and so it was fairly popular to do this
from
on you know certain countries in Asia
and
in Israel until they upgraded to a
fiber-optic link
on but that wasn't very practical for
calling PBS's because you get so much
wind noise side you know transiting
through an international location
up you know there was no error
correction at the time that
really it was only useful for four hits
and even then only if the delay was
acceptable
on so around the time that I started
getting active the preferred way to
commit to a fraud was coats
and the overcoats was written you know
in code
I k0 t3c year something along those
lines
and code was was either a
and open tee support on a PBX that maybe
you found by scanning
whether it was a stolen credit card or
stolen calling card
or sometimes I'll bond distance
companies would use
if they give you a discount if you
didn't you see full access if you dialed
a local number and
entered the code and then dialed the
number that you wanted to call on
you could get a cheaper rate if you did
it that way so if that were to leak
um while you know maybe it could be
useful to freaks
and then there was this entire where the
scene there so we're seeing today
I wheres being pirated software if
you're not in that scene
and remember back at the time we didn't
have the internet so to move these
things across the country somebody had
to call long distance for
you know to the next city over BDS two
pts
and these guys were called whereas
careers and Wesker yes we're always
looking for codes because they didn't
want to pay long distance build upward
although where's
are so if you were a freak you could
have all the where she wanted really
just by supplying where scorers with
code and this is something that was
comment
so in addition to just outright stealing
other peoples information you know some
breaks a bit more ethical than others
and on
I would put myself in this category at
the time and you know hopefully the
statute of limitations is up
by having then you know twenty-some-odd
years ago at this point but
I'll I I thought I I thought at the time
that
if somebody got a bill as a result of
something I did that I wasn't being a
very good freak
I wasn't being very good from the
perspective of number one somebody
getting off for a bill that I ran up
was probably going to be pretty mad and
the phone company
itself would probably be pretty mad as
well and also you know these things
didn't end the last very long
so oh what many freaks would try to do
is weed
obtain service in a way that it would
only generate phone
I have billing internally to a phone
company I'll
were it would be just an outright
subscription fraud
us so there would never be a real bill
that what you real per cent
on so one example of something that
wasn't that
what's you know identity theft is a very
common thing today
and you know it tends to be drug addicts
that are doing it now because it's a
relatively easy thing to do
but you know ten years before that
became commonplace freaks were
committing identity theft up
corporations
on and so one such number was one eight
hundred jail bond neck out rather do up
a caf and what that was was an
attachment
to an existing account so some company
had a very large account with a lot of a
hundred-numbers and a phone call away
and not to the telephone company serving
them
%uh ordered a new number to be added to
that same ok account
and you know just like that %uh a new
number was nailed up to a cop from this
was
you know that's that's what are the more
memorable numbers but there were lotsa
lotsa lotsa
these things that happen on another
example of a subscription fraud
how many have you would take an order
from a company called scam
modeling no nobody
on well with a name like that how could
you go run
up unfortunately for Sprint
I'll they did accept an order from a
company called scam modeling
on yea there's a certain a freak that
wasn't me had set this up by i'd never
do anything at RBS
but on anyhow I this is that the the
story apparently where to
that scam modeling had offered by Shiv
Russian models that frequently needed to
call home to Russia
and so they needed calling cards to do
this and you know
because they be traveling all over the
place that there might not be paid
exactly on time and so
you know the cards would need to stay on
for long periods in between polling and
somehow you know the person that set the
site managed to negotiate
10 calling cards being sad up for a
large large number
you know thousands of dollars worth it
calls a to Russia
on and the bill just never being paid
and eventually a few months later spread
caught on
on and shut down scam modeling but
on for whatever reason they accepted the
the order it said I don't get it but
this is these are some
these are some methods that freaks would
use to get around going and
you know that the real point here is
that
until the internet came along and it
really became popular
people still found ways to communicate
and they still found ways to communicate
for free
and things happen as a result a free
communication
better pretty important yeah
some cigs something I missed a shot
spiritualists so
along came the Internet and there was
sometime this a bit %uh not
understanding from certain
alaskan politicians like Ted Stevens
on understanding what the potential was
so I'll
in it's not like a truck but on okay so
this is the one
thing that's sorta parallels the
previous stock
up foreign companies really had no
understanding no trouble at all
understanding the potential
up the Internet and so when you look at
any technology that get striven on
and it happens to be around media if the
porn industry isn't behind it typically
it doesn't happen
so we begin to see a lot of streaming
video and
really I'll what got us from dial-up I
think to broadband
is streaming born %ah suddenly a free
instant worldwide communication became
possible and
a guy named Bernie Ebbers I envisioned
integrated voice data and video and
bernie is a really interesting story he
up
started a company called worldcom he had
this vision a police state a video
actually being
an integrated service that he'd offer
any literally what made a whole bunch of
acquisitions
I in order to put a company together
that would do this
there was only one problem and that was
in order to make the acquisition see
committed massive accounting fraud
I'm and the you know that resulted and I
a N
mister roberts. landing and a federal
penitentiary where he still lets but
the vision was good and Rio and it
actually is
you know oh where we use sort of more or
less
are today where if you look at something
like the Comcast Triple Play for example
you can get an integrated voice data and
video package
all from one provider up bernie ever saw
that
ten years before you could buy ad and
it's really because if groundbreaking
pioneering work by people like em
that we are able to enjoy some of the
services that we are today
on I think I've 2000 to 2010 largely as
a lost decade
and so that's why I haven't focused a
great deal
in this talk on by anything except you
know 1990 to 2000 and then where we are
today
on the tech crash caused up
a serious player back in innovation
around 1999 things got very property
on we saw for a very large amount of
investment in companies that should
never have been started
Dutch selling products that shouldn't
have existed
on and you know we all saw the logical
conclusion up
the pullback was more severe than it
should have been
and so the amount of innovation that I
think that we've seen
really in the last 10 years hasn't been
to substantial it's mostly been
evolutionary
except for surveillance and we put this
crazy massive surveillance
infrastructure
without really even thinking through I
what the social implications for the
long-term implications
are up this man radical societal shift
that's happened
on but there were some things that
happened we do now have
a GSM deployment in North America %uh
and
it more or less I covers the majority of
the population
we didn't have this before we saw amps
retired
toward the end love the lost decade
I amps was the at the old and a crackly
analog cellular network
we no longer have that we suck growth in
VoIP services but the interesting thing
with boy
if you ask me three years ago what the
most exciting
groundbreaking trend-setting thing would
be in telecommunications
up you know in they in that decade I
would say play
and the reason why was there was a lot
of really exciting things happening
around flight
I it was possible for us says peaks and
tinkerers
take get access to some very very very
cheap
up with services and even today there's
things like magic jack where you can
call anywhere in the country for
basically for free
with certain limitations and I did write
a column on magicJack a few issues back
on and I believe the back issue is for
sale so
if you're interested the in you know
some magic jack tricks in a little bit
more information on that product
feel free to pick up the issue but if
you'd asked me a few years ago I would
have thought that that's the direction
we all would have been going
and I I would have thought that probably
that would be
on the most exciting thing today I don't
think so
because really what happened with Boyd
is what we use to do
on circuit-switched networks on the back
and
is now being done with port on the back
and but it's open transparent to you and
me as consumers
and the Boeing hasn't changed that's
gotten cheaper for carriers to provide
the service but this troubling you the
same or more
I it's kinda funny how that works on
so there's been growth and play it's
exciting it allows us to make better use
of the existing infrastructure we have
now
but we haven't really grown that
infrastructure in the last ten years
I at a real level beyond incremental
up this Ben broadband adoption at a
pretty wide scale
we're now seeing most the majority of
people who have internet access in the
US now have broadband
but its fairly small in terms of
majority
at something like sixty four percent the
last set of numbers I saw
this tremendously lags behind other
developed companies like
putney other developed countries I like
South Korea
I were pipetted option runs in the
nineties
and we've seen a lot of the you know
anybody who has an iPhone
knows that there's been a lot of new and
creative ways to bill for the exact same
service you've been enjoying
on and those creative ways always seem
to be
more expensive but we haven't seen a
tremendous amount
really oath at the at the network level
fundamentally a innovation and it really
sets 2001 to today
so um where we are though is this
interesting place where
it's possible now to communicate
virtually anywhere in the world
for little or nothing and that is a
Pandora's box
governments want to control online
speech in content
and you know it if you believe there's a
first amendment
that stole meaningful I'll I have a
bridge over they did over there to sell
you
the United States government is just as
guilty out governments that are more
overt in these efforts I it's just
behind the scenes
%uh for example %uh there is a strong
desire
in the cyber security community within
the United States federal government for
what they call a kill switch
where somebody in washington DC decides
to flip a switch
and we don't have internet access
anymore in the United States
and we've already built the San to
the telephone system with kaleah it's
possible
to kill telephone communications
it's not net not yet possible because
there isn't yet Cody and I
in the routers that are the core routers
have our Internet infrastructure to do
this
but one regulatory change and we have an
Internet kill switch
and the United States has that and
anytime they say that they need to stop
terrorism or political dissent that
could be terrorism
somebody in washington could anonymously
decide to you flip the kill switch
I even in the US %uh if you want to look
at a
where ry 0 unq right example when ghetto
some people might call conspiracy
theories YouTube is frequently censored
we have internet censorship today in the
US with the MCA takedown notices
I carriers want to slow innovation that
they can't control
by defeating net neutrality initiatives
and that this is a very important debate
that's happening right now
on should carriers be able %ah to
prioritize some traffic over others or
charge you more for certain types of
traffic than other types of traffic got
there by discouraging innovation
in a particular direction on many people
like me believe that
carrier should treat all traffic equally
I a common carrier should be just that
other people largely with companies like
Comcast and AT&T
a belief that they should be able to
control content
that reverses their networks and thereby
slow innovation that they can't figure
out a way to bill you extra for
on or control and innovation show called
I think is an American competitiveness
issue no I don't normally stand up on
stage in with the patriotic flag and I
and wear red white and blue bikini on
but
we do most of us live in the free world
and the United States
II yunus book from all over the web
obviously I would say them
the audience here as majority american
and
believe me South Korea isn't standing
still
Japan isn't standing still companies up
countries that we compete with
are not standing still and so if we
allow
american corporations to decide what
our policy is going to be as a nation by
and they're allowed to decide this in
the best interest if next quarter's
earnings
what happens is the long-term
investments that need to be made it may
not actually be made to keep America
competitive in this space so
I normally don't encourage many people
to become politically active
on I think that sometimes it does more
harm than good
but this is a mainstream issue and if
you feel
like this pandora's box should not be
closed
then please make your views known to
your representatives and senators
there are two exceptions to the lost
decade I
you know they're there were things that
happened on
that I think we're actually disruptive
and I think actually
do you open a lot of interesting
possibilities
%uh the first is social networking and
that actually now because he mails
become so useless in show put span
for many people it's become the default
way to interact with friends and
sometimes even family
and smartphones I really began to take
off
and so on let's have a little fun
up quick Showa hands who in this room
has
a smartphone and by that I define a
blackberry
an Android device or an iPhone
okay so I think there were maybe four
people that don't
on so leave your hands up
leave your hat k cuz I wanna see it
where where this goes so I and if we've
got anybody here with the camera like
I'd like to watch
yeah I'd like to see a video at this
later cuz it's hard for me to see from
the stage
on leave your hand up if you know
exactly how that phone works
okay I'm taking mine down cuz I town on
do you completely trust AT&T and Apple
if you have an iPhone
for no okay um
do you trust the vendor up every
application that you have installed on
your phone
such as Google for Facebook or myspace
or any those things
or it does anybody have I fight like
that thing where you press that button
on your iPhone farts
like do you trust that guy I ida okay so
it's so we've got
so we still got a couple hands up I do
you trust a caller ID is reliable
no does anybody do any SMS banking
do you trust us some ass
on okay is if anybody's hand is still up
would you trust me with your phone
okay so if you trust me with your phone
bring it up here all have a back to you
in a couple days
on but I think that that side you know
if it's gone the direction that you know
at least from the front that I can see
that's a pretty powerful exercise right
we have these computers in our pockets
and we don't know how they work and we
don't trust you
who wrote the software that runs on them
and we don't trust
the network but they're using
and we don't necessarily even trust
the calls that are coming and on that
they're really fun
who we think they are and we don't
necessarily need
you know trust that the SMS is that
we're getting a real
and so you know there's some really
interesting things here
on and you know I kinda like to to run
through
for a couple of scenarios on so
SMS is a really interesting I is a
really interesting piece
on so cool here uses text messages
frequently
and that would probably be the majority
if you I know for myself
i text me more than I talk now and
do you know where are your SMS messages
actually
go when you send them
either copies of them anywhere on is
their privacy policy Associated
and you know I'm asking these
rhetorically we can get into it you know
into this old and worn Q&A
but on my friend broker Chris here in
the audience and myself I
you know we actually went through an
exercise so a few months ago where we
try to figure out just
based on what SMS volumes are right that
a public
how much torture would take because
kinda one of the things that I do
professionally as I deal with
large-scale storage
how much torture would take to just
archive every SMS message that sent
you know to from or through the United
States on
a on any given day on and
you know it's a trivial amount of
storage particularly if you're using a
technology like deduplication
now I don't have any reason to believe
that things are being archived
when they shouldn't be here that anybody
in particular skewing at
um but do you know that that's not the
case
and have you ever said anything an SMS
that maybe you wouldn't want to
I you know posted to
a Twitter feed somewhere on and so you
know this is a
this is an interesting question and I i
really just you know that I'm
bringing this up not to make you
especially paranoid although I probably
should make you paranoid by pointing out
that
on some love the surveillance
infrastructure that's been implemented
that does allow
with the government to track your GPS
coordinates at any given time even if
your phones off
and some phones I'll are able to turn
themselves on and listen to what's going
on around them
when that the appropriate commander said
to them um
and you know I love this the government
or somebody
using these commands you shouldn't okay
well would have today would have to do
but you know the technologies both tend
to
I to your device and there aren't people
really looking at these things and
seeing whether they're secure
and seeing whether they're really being
use the way that they should
and there doesn't seem to be a lot of
accountability for things like National
Security Letter so
which can activate all this technology
so
in the name of stopping terrorism world
governments have created a massive
surveillance infrastructure the likes of
which have never really existed in human
history
but in the neighbor be more popular you
have probably given even more personal
information to Facebook and Google
and your privacy really is for sale when
you use social networks
you were not a customer a Facebook
Google or Twitter
you are the product that they sell to
their customers
and if you feel like deleting your
account after all this while don't
bother because they still on your data
have any have you actually read the
Privacy Policy for Facebook if your
Facebook user
K which one is that is what I would ask
because it changes every other week
roughly
and this is part of the danger with
trusting privacy policies to actually
secure privacy when the interests of
services you use
are opposed to your own address and when
the operator of the service can change
the privacy policy anytime they like
affectively all your base are belong to
them
for so
your freedom really is at risk and this
actually is gotten fairly serious you
know what if this guy on the screen
where one if your Facebook friends and
decided that you were
probably a terrorist on that could end
very badly for you
it ended very badly for somebody
recently um
now I don't know whether the guy that's
alleged to be a terrorist is a result
I don't have that information I'm all I
can look at is well
there were some social networks involved
there were some blacks privacy policies
in place there were some trust
relationships
that maybe shouldn't have been there
that were there and what that resulted
in as somebody sitting in jail right now
and you know whether or not it belongs
there on
I'm not Revie a qualified to comment but
what I can comment on the is that if all
of these tools weren't there
and if they weren't being widely trusted
I in ways that shouldn't be
then maybe that sequence of events would
have fun not happen the same way that it
dead
so here's a call to action and
a really why we're all here
is this is a socially that we're coming
together as hackers to bounce ideas off
each other
we're coming together to learn things
that we don't already know and share
things that we do now
out that other people might be able to
drive even further
where more connected than we've ever
been before and were less connected
than we've ever been before online
communities are useful
but there really no substitute for
direct human interaction so much more
happens when we come together in
communities like 2600 meetings
I like Metrix create space in Seattle
I'll or like conferences such as hope
or deaf con I'm with the rapid advances
in smartphones and social media
we're inventing new technologies said a
faster pace than any time since the
1990s and this is
really gotten out of hand I mean we have
a different you know
iPhone application every hour
practically I Android applications are
ramping up for going to be having a new
smartphone platform watch that I expect
what a popular
on these technologies though I think
are largely not secure and they put way
too much personal data and the hands of
corporations
iight you guys need to be taking this
stuff apart
you guys need to be showing the wear bet
to out you know did you know when your
phone that your GPS coordinates are
readily available and could be misused
people taking this stuff apart is what's
going to make the technology better
and the last pieces really think through
the social implications when you're
either inventing or consuming new
technologies
on there could be additional collections
that
in the focus to get a product out the
door you don't necessarily consider
and we r innovating at a very rapid pace
%uh so I understand that it's necessary
sometimes to be first to market with the
product
but when you do that if you haven't
thought through
what the implications really could be
you know two or three degrees out
then possibly it could come back to bat
to bite you
and so with that on
open up the floor to questions I just
want peace %ah
I live in Beijing so any discussion 05
China
or China the Chinese government policy
in any of these areas
unfortunately I can't address but
anything else
particularly the US or anywhere else in
the world is fair game so I
love to hear your any questions you may
have
and thank you for being such an awesome
audience
their side yes so there was some
microphones in the I always
a surf you line up at the mic some I'm
sure the
this Heather sum up in the front as well
I guess I can't really see you know at
this point lights in my eyes so
maybe if the people with the hope this
on security going out there a cover
grass is this on its on I got an
infrastructure question yeah what's up
how much fiber is still dark how much
fiber is still dark that's a great
question so
on fiber optic cable when it gets laid
basically has insight ovett a number of
strands
and so in order if laying fiber is in a
very interesting thing to do
I mean you take attraction you drop the
cable and it nets you know a few dollars
a foot
on what's the hard part
is getting enough fiber what we call let
in the telecommunications industry and
that's where you have
of a bunch of equipment that's very
expensive on
that all-state 01 fiber and it uses side
a technology
the most popular one currently is called
DWDM so typically what will happen
is a carrier it that's laying a
fiber-optic network
they walk necessary you know this
technology can be changed out
relatively easily with wind carts on so
as we come up
with new and better ways to transfer
data faster I you just pull out
you know every couple 05 miles out one
car to drop another n
and you know this can be done in a
return that way but
there's so much fiber in the ground that
isn't let
because typically what your only doing
is lighting one strand in the cable
and you may be leasing others trance
other companies
so there's a tremendous amount of dark
fiber I
dark fiber though is in a very useful
thing
I you can't do much with that you can
run some you know we've got technology
we can run some metropolitan area
networks at relatively low speed without
lighting it up
but until we come up with a way to use
dark fiber
across so long distances without this
very expensive equipment
I doesn't do a whole lot a good EDS my
question your question
so the question is so for every mile
fiber that we have
and for you know it's it's like
basically you gotta hate you
you need to know for each on each truck
how many carriers are using that fiber
strand
so some companies don't actually lease
any fiber
to other companies some do I it's our
proprietary information internally
so all I can do is conjecture but
I can say on average cable I'd be
surprised if more than 10 percent
evidence let
the into the nineties it was something
like ninety seven percent was dark and
all that is potential
infrastructure that's band with waiting
to be used
it isn't being used well its potential
infrastructure to keep in mind so you
if you light up fiber you can change out
that technology with technology with
newer technology
that is able to move data at faster
rates
along the same fiber strand and so part
if the incremental innovation that's
happened between 2000
and now is that we've gone to you faster
speeds
on the existing fiber that we already
have so
I don't see that incremental approach
changing
we're not gonna see each I norm St play
mezzo lighting up dark fiber I mean it
cost billions of dollars to do that
so what I'm guessing war and we already
have more bandwidth
on the backbones then we really can use
I mean the problem
the pan with problem that we're having
currently is how do you get that last
mile
not spend the problem for the last
fifteen years I can say that I run a 2.4
well ep at work on
I can't get into too much detail of what
I do at work but I will
I can say that we have %uh some backbone
networks at work that are
grossly underutilized and it's largely
on
it's not that we captured a day at other
carriers sets that they can accept that
quickly enough
this question is mostly semantic but I
think it's kinda important when
discussing these issues
here for two arm company same DMCA
takedown notices to YouTube is
censorship
those one company telling another
company threatening them with legal
action constitute censorship for
would you say something I've someone
argued something that comes Pacific from
the government
that I believe that it's censorship
on so you have content and that content
is taken down
and it's taken down through a legal
mechanism so
that to me is censorship I you can
reasonable people can disagree on this
right
on I happen this is my personal belief
was wondering what your thoughts were on
Moxie my own spikes work with our
Android applications for secure text
messaging and phone calls I think it's
our red phone and Dom
tech secure I can't forget the name the
other one I haven't seen it but I'd love
to %uh send it to me
sure ever question on
sorta will what are your thoughts on the
thank you for that
locally it's called the truth in caller
ID bill
for that year the caller ID will yet
what do you think about that we would
hear thought so what would be the
benefits are disadvantages have
requiring that caller ID is
legitimized somehow from its source so
let's talk about this little bit because
that's a really interesting topic
arm you know living in China right now
when I call somebody from my Chinese
cell phone
usually the number comes up unavailable
and apparently the majority of people
that I call
on in this may or may not be up you know
representative
people overall it's just you know my
crib befriends believe that when the
phone says unavailable and there is a
number that pops up
it's a monster calling and they don't
answer
arm so E you know caller ID is one of
those things that is an especially
reliable anyway we haven't even really
figured out
you know how to make it work across
international boundaries yet in some
cases even
you know within the United States it
doesn't it doesn't work very well
on so
a true thing caller ID bill I'll me
that's
thats it's going to be difficult to
enforce because
what has to be proven I in the
legislation as it's written now is that
you intentionally
obfuscated your caller ID somehow I and
that you did it with malicious site
intent
on so what are the other interesting
problems with Caller ID is that
if you pass a law in the United States
will the phone system is global
and so what I would expect to happen is
that the malicious people that are doing
malicious caller ID things would just
move outside the boundaries the United
States
and then what do you do to enforce the
law against somebody who isn't
particularly known because
with the world of weight it's very
interesting I mean it becomes very
difficult to see were calls are actually
coming from and who sending them
on we've opened with what the genie out
of the bottle on ss7
and you know when some sleazy VoIP
provider in Romania has the same access
to
the ss7 network says for rice n
then you really aren't safe anywhere us
so don't trust caller ID is the bottom
line and if there's a lot that gets
passed
you too early no laws are always
effective when they get past rated
super presentation you talked about
government monitoring phone calls but
there's cell phone spyware
is a very scary thing and you can be
downloaded
if on your phone I can track your
movements I can watch
on this into your phone calls I can turn
on the
microphone to listen to room twelve
telephone calls it's not getting the
media attention I think it probably
deserves
we know it sure would if Sarah Palin
download its cell phone spyware or
better yet if Bristol Palin dead then
ito I think Fox News would be all over
that so
the and that's really part of the call
to action right we have these devices
that have
ridiculous security for us in anybody
who
really knows anything in this area is
well aware of this
on their APIs that leave I'll
large swaths if things that should never
be open open
and Brady what we're not seeing is
these platforms spell you know there's
an attack surface this is because coat
see
and nobody's really doing much with it
please somebody attack Sarah Palin
averse to pay on let's let's not
call for attacks on specific people army
I don't wanna be whole topic here in
handcuffs but to
oh what a what I would say is that on
the re vs as hackers as freaks as
security people we need to be looking at
this stuff and we need to be talking
about this stuff with people that don't
know as much as we do
I arm in my phone I have a setting that
says I'm like don't send identification
and when I call somebody it'll show up
as unknown number
is actually something in my phone that's
preventing my phone number from being
sent out where is that
done by the provider so what you have is
a GSM phone presumably
yes and what you're doing is you're
setting a flag it's it's itchy GSM
feature where you can
instruct the GSM network not to send
your caller ID
that can be honored or not I and it
isn't controlled by your phone it's your
phones just the interface through which
you can select that
I if you have a on if you have a CDMA
phone
if you dial star 67 you can selectively
block your caller ID
where you can have your carrier block it
for every call okay
thank you there
going back to infrastructure and
community for a second
I'm curious your thoughts on what we can
do as people
liberate ourselves from these
corporations actually build their own
phone networks to the wireless or
otherwise
so the scope of my talk really is a call
to action
but it isn't a call to any specific
action and
I have to leave things open ended on I
don't know how all this is going to
shake out
I don't know three years from now how
this is going to work
and really that's up to all of you and
it's up to you if you're passionate
about this issue
to look at a way where you can leverage
where you're awesome and what you know
and how you can inspire other people
and so really all I can do is encourage
you
said take that forgive you that
understands that part if this issue that
other people don't
and shed light on it make it public
talk to other people you're here at hope
that's what this is for
I have time for one more question and
then we have to go
when you think routers will be a thing
of the past
and the internet will be wide open cDNA
or something like that with just digital
signal processors everywhere
as long as we need to push back its and
as long as we're still using TCP IP we
will need writers
so I don't think that's going away
anytime soon on
you know what the transport is before we
get to their and I think
I don't think Chrissy Wireless is a as
what we're using for our trucks I mean
that's gonna be class on the ground and
its
its gonna stay that way at least for the
foreseeable future I think
on I you know that's that's an
interesting question
but until we get away from that
in using TCP IP I don't see that
happening
okay well I you been a fantastic
audience thank you so much