when arm I guarantee we will not fill
the whole hour but the V-twenty time for
Q&A at the end
%uh so here's
I'm about three quarters the networking
came arm
I let everybody themselves in a moment
but a but people think that's in the
work
for are
as I love right now I believe it's the
first time we've ever not had a major
network failure during the con
so for and a
other people introduce themselves and
we'll get started so I'm my car driver
Noah
and WiFi stuff and overall you know
wrangling
network stuff I am bill on the network
manager adultery or 11
more than a few devices here on Nick
binary
Nov 15 years experience with internet
pumps I'm centered
general UNIX me and again i'm fred
drugs in the queue here and take some
photos I'm porch up
hear that some the wiring and otherwise
I might never come in Madrid
and also holding back tears Cairo
wrangled wave more stand-up
stand-up embarrass you he's the man
franklin et al.
the Santa Claus hearing go to all the
dishes the uplink
the band with the IP space so you know
the fiber it wouldn't work without him
so I'll
alright alright
%uh basically this year we have over 50
megabit up when can act on it
this is a pitcher the antenna the dish
on the roof
it points to time square on anymore
pacific Sunwear
whose office opposed to raymond Anderson
yes it's all going to Rainbow as the
other provider which is also the
provider that the hotel uses for there
are commercial internet service
arm and they did a great job getting us
a link from a hotel that doesn't have a
lot of a point capability so
anybody remembers you know six years ago
overlooking a DSL lines
and %uh a megabit and now we have 50
shot across Manhattan its prequel
is pretty stable on the harbour
the network this year consisted of the
core 6509 Wilson two's
says you give it and copper line cards
in there the edge consisted of buses
Cove
3515 3516 purely switches and the
wireless age is 18 Aruba
87 the access points as a pitcher
servings that helps call the switch down
as it's vital for
yes for the next on
a packet filtering was Donna pics 535
and services provided with BST jails run
in a few BST
its picture the river access control yet
so everybody's life I traffic went
through that one wire to the one little
box
was a simple fact pitcher than ever
architecture
basically we have far 59 but when coming
into a switcher on the eighteenth floor
another switch located under the stage
13 access points are strapped to the
various peoples around here
and then we have multi-mode fiber run it
goes from 18th floor down in the second
to the stairwell
on hotel really didn't have any
infrastructure to do
anything else on there wasn't any risers
or anything like that with a runner on
other are risers in the hotel
unfortunately they are on the other side
of the elevators were thirties walking
accessible risers for us
so we could I have everybody welcome a
network cable break it cuz theres
you know 2,000 people walking over ten
times a day or we could run it on
stairwell it
so the car than ever unit consisted of
the 6509
on is a the X 535 various view and a
truck between it
on edge switches on the second floor
with no colour cage
which to mezzanine switches that
attracted to the various data jacks
on the second floor there if the 587 AP
seventies deployed
MD project a dedicated switch and
there's a controller
are also up on the eighteenth floor
people might may have noticed or not
arm we we learned in previous years ever
gonna run cables every AP up here we're
looking at about 8,000 feet
cat-5 are so what we're actually running
is %uh
dual channel 5 gigahertz mash so the
AP's on the polls in the back
act as a mess controllers that pipe to
one of the AP's suck balls here
but then tunnel the other AP's back in
if they're plugged into Ethernet
it's pretty cool so yeah
we saved on a couple hours worth the
effort and a couple hundred bucks for
the cabling
largest bank in the head by the way
getting
he's being as the person who got told to
do the cable in
break so here's a
basic breakdown of the IP location
services
we had quite a few more viewers than we
had in the past hope
discusses the various services in
different access levels are people
required
on everything I love the wifi except for
the public networks was paid to this
X 535 on which had
not when it faces and what will you
answer some questions any Cisco
employees in the audience right now
no okay just wondering so one of the
reasons for these interfaces I found
this really interesting
issue where if you go and span the same
feel into multiple contacts
the fire all the stops processing are
and so I figure that out
around 4:30 in the morning on Wednesday
not a really good time to figure that
out so it's got around that by just
basically attention more physical
interfaces to the fire
so far lots of is carved up and 23 three
different contexts here
on admin that's completely isolated from
ever any other user traffic
on heard the data plan other just so you
know higher security there's only one IP
letter
manages from there was another context
on there just for admin traffic
and the rest were the very experienced
to BPA
and the open in a wired on network
services are deployed through FreeBSD
deals with five been running
bind DNS I see the HP a syslog service
MRTG and a netbook workers in in time
we have some stats on the wifi side
everything ran for the RBA controller
and then a all the WPA stuff was
terminated on the year before as well
using a %ah an internal user
%uh you can you can do it externally
whether
up love RADIUS server and and dedicated
user accounts but
I you know cared a lot of his gear down
love it got shut down
in a in a car so we we want to get
creamer here
and I'm just talking we're all reading
that fluctuates a lot funnier
rights never stats
on we showed our round 1200 unique maxi
dresses that were handed out by the HP
server
around 100 2200 season arm around 220
million flows throughout the weekend to
the netbook liquor
02 mesh networks is try to explain for
the 18th floor
on also on the wifi we normally saw
about a
about 200 people on at any given time
are so about 10 percent
everybody here is using the the wifi at
any given point
%uh but there are some no obvious
significant peaks and valleys throughout
the day for that
you don't talk about the there so %ah
her running idea stuff on the wifi the
whole time
%uh we saw about 50 a piece moving
attacks
which is no alright big deal good work
guys up
about 10 DoS attack some Thai people
finally figured out that it's kinda
boring to do that so
just annoying yeah also we had so many
AP's up that'd be pretty hard for you to
take them all at once and thats
really not a challenge to go ahead got
an hour left yeah I think the load on
the 6500 up 32 percent max throughout
the weekend so
other about our twenty non ho babies
that were plugged into the network
somewhere
up mainly that means Rd a system set up
to probe the cup replicated out the man
went
well your plugin or network somewhere
arm so
alright people did that does have an
interest in number and the most
interesting number is others 198 please
R&R summer overlapping with us right now
so hurray for new york city but we had
enough power to
drown them out pretty effectively other
shows the ballot use the
over 24-hour period on much winning
really go over
we had forty men over 40 megabits for
the speed test once and
as about it up I think we're pretty much
getting the other packets per second
woman
on the link by more than her hitting the
bandwidth limit just cuz a know we're
seeing you know 4,000 5,000
8 housing packet second just traffic
hammering out
and this graph shows the overall
throughput the network and its host
talking amongst themselves so we headed
when a massive 29 48 mega bits really
interesting stuff
for some more points lights traffic
distribution protocol if anybody cares
if she pees you know down the protocol
followed by
much when those boxes speaking about us
and
ok as those on the intro on the external
acres in prison break out as if BP is
number one by factor about
15 RHPS came right after that SSH came
in third for the outbound traffic that
was kinda nice to see
unfortunate the fourth out on traffic
with pop 3 really
really people puffery not pop 3s
mind you pop 3 yeah are we also saw
telnet come in a row number ten yeah for
I really soon people are like tunneling
something over that but I didn't bother
to look but yeah I think we're coming
stupid overcome it pretty re:
but also the amount by map again I'm at
this just the time ap
should be their talking about addition
he was
some I'm another significant hop pop s
and I'm at best but
does not as funny as the fact that there
is also significant
on Krypton rate
and which
so we made a little video that was a
15 minutes love the the network so this
is %uh packet a medic dumping all the
images are going over unencrypted HTTP
for
for about 15 minutes little the day
yesterday that's what this
that's exactly what we said
where's the morn that there's a couple
crutches that flash by
for you vote no
you hope here
so that was about you know
gonna have images that went by re:
so we didn't counter wants you to look
at that was before the concert
started and that made us realize a few
things up
pessimism is the new optimism
so
the first thing we have to do is run
that riser five her from the team for
the second floor
and we ended up by using a new fiber
last year
which was just i duplex Jack did not
emerge to really really on patch cable
and I'm assuming that the club had some
weight on it when the strands broke so
it's been a while trying to troubleshoot
that
on couldn't get it to work said to go to
a backup fiber which unfortunately
wasn't long enough and really wasn't
terminated very well
so arm ended up at this
and that's a banister xscape to and
that's pretty much what the entire
network is running through all weekend
well we hoped and prayed that nobody
bumped into it
determination is really but it works
and that's it for the slides 15 minutes
it's pretty good
any questions %uh diabaly
our microphones on in the middle okay
yeah a very big guns are on in the
middle so if you have questions q1 up
a.m. known for minister we don't have a
photo for the next ft backing the router
for anybody who was a
no hoping to see that for yet renders
offering to run downstairs and and and
get a picture taken for sputter
a suck up one man's in the network
traffic did you shake Nutella its entry
into oblivion
or to you had like some other one oh we
handled it with our
from there there's a big pipe and a
it's a hacker con so whatever yeah
me be it's just there wasn't any
filtering
protocols actually a at filtered
bias and down just reports can well
but I was off the porch of actually did
bring a package here and then we went
wow it's four in the morning care too
much
does it was necessary anyway I think
we're gonna do is your
make it so that everybody uniquely
except for the speakers are you get a
little bit a priority for
but that was all wherever planning on
doing with another
shakedown any here but as it turns out
you know
hit the max at any point so we had a
plan but
wasn't needed never let you know if they
were able to get a big enough like that
we didn't have to worry too much about
problem arm
any throttling that went on was most
likely caused by people die from the
white fire just packets per second
so high that the the uplink starter
little bit or something like that
%uh one other problem we did see Fig a
provision was
apparently OS X doesn't like to be paid
to all that
well cuz or watch people can complain to
nine
had kinda said I have a Mac a pic
he says Windows seven do more shit as
Mac drivers windows 7 either
I my networks good
minded
after setting it up that I just had to
use
stop the wireless turn it back on and
then
then found a certificated you're able to
import so a
all I do is run TCP down to try diagnose
the problem and a
it just works segmented enter okay one
question that arose during the first
part of this conference
why did you only have legacy I P the
four times that I've real internet
here are so where you from
from German and where we're at your
for on
eventually would be nice abut on the
really just isn't
the demands to deploy v6 nor Joan
be able to get an allocation for that on
so if you with the effort that it takes
to get what we have today
are up and running in it could be six on
top of that on
the number people over probably utilize
it would be pretty low sure it's fun to
play with but
on if not us Google start using it
are you volunteering for for
if you ask me in the next open the
whatever scored possibly
but I wouldn't think it would be good
even if its stomach but just to provide
for people in their argument
on German confronted with doing it for
the last year's and of course
not everybody knew that but it's Justin
a good option to tell people you try it
out
the future share as a point of reference
arm not the last men are meeting but the
meeting before that Dearborn Michigan
the ipv6 tough ended up being a total of
2 percent or so
up the outbound traffic was for the
North American network operator
the people who would probably be using
the sixth most the people who have it at
their corporate offices and stuff
and yeah for that the great but yet
you're talking about a
for meaning by time yeah I mean I think
the six is fantastic
for but play with a botch but the
allocation were given for this weekend
to
was just so big that other than just
people playing with it
over there was much needed you can
always is set up you know
four to six Tomo yourself laptop
naturally greatest prevent automatic
on such a good people want that there
would be six they're just set up their
own
little you know later told
faith are you guys for school %uh thank
you it was really they said
come here and have it at that worry I
think in person
are
my texts were sent me for dancers walked
and I have no problem with DHCP and
owning the day
are there any attempts for exhaustion
already
you know you things that you guys saw
did you plan for
people who do use DHCP exhaustion or
anything like that and
follow-up which actually has nothing to
do with it I was a deal with that happen
JavaScript to on bad start hope that
were you looking for nah I don't know
what the best people for their
yeah we are just a weird replied arm
and for just a common care okay that
governor I'm sorry I cannot let me know
that I had a job
kinda are but says I I don't know
I don't know we'll just do what they're
setting up so up
I don't know I think the program have a
talk during closing ceremonies or maybe
sometimes
questions for them then home so they
could probably tell you that
I think it was an attempt to look at
your browser history for more CSS hacks
to our
this bill profiles of people but yeah
but it will be noticed sour under
have a bf first question that might
answer question on
as playing at a point each piece moving
on from the switches and I just didn't
see anybody doing anything on it which
is great
on you know I wondered if you could
expected because we would have liked to
play with it but I did not a little this
work want it up doing was
you notice on the open and it'll begin
assigned flash twenty-two's
as well as the public are and that's
what I said
really really lovely studies on the DHCP
server the only issue the issue
I did notice is on the nasty cheap
implementation
sometimes we get unhappy if you switch
networks on
somewhat quickly on
it would have issues on the ATP server
would send an act that it's a nice on
the site PNC
you can have it just keep going I really
want and images go through that
iteration
five or six times and finally on get it
but
we do have a couple plans you know if we
did see something theirs and that his
hands on the river a key controller to
on controlled the cheapies on
leases and ready to be servers and could
have just play the DHCP snooping
lesser Russell marginally more difficult
for former DGP flood attacks with WiFi
because you have to have the whole life
I can check first before the mac Address
is acknowledged by the AP
arm I mean not that would really stop
someone with particular determined but
you know yeah anything given a nature's
environment I didn't really wanna
good too many armed security you know
controls in place
this is the first year at the port
security and everything so you couldn't
flood
camp it was on the switches and I didn't
really see any evidence
details on that too which is good did
you trying to them
on not going to the gym good
hi I got a record as a hacker con we can
expect people to screw that so yeah okay
i'll know protected anybody else
treasure and every
NASCAR I noticed on some respectable
hey this guy's thank you once again I
this is my first hope
and I am just amazing what i've seen
here I saw heroes on this stage before
and I'm on mars
guys
just just one more vote for v6 that the
deal is that
if you never have if no one ever turns
it on anywhere that of course they'll
never be any traffic on it because after
all no one ever turns it on so they
don't have it
so they but but the thing is if it's too
much of a pain in the ass
pain I I will get the application and
turn it on and configure the router
week end up looking at my money where my
mouth is it really up to the upstream
provider
sure you don't you can't you can't on
all the people on there are people who
for weekend I'll be happy to do it
yeah for for the record this is
something that I'm interested in
in seeing at some point as well whether
it's
whether it's the next time we do this
think you know tearing
year
something yeah but right-center
gonna follow education you can send
emails to
you can send an email and get chatting
you know as per the preparation process
for next time
see what happens okay is a
never getting myself I know that
sometimes when everything is
miraculously working for once
and the day is a bit slow your one of
the fun things you could do is kinda
poke around and see what everybody else
is doing with the network
and I remember somewhere between home
Crean
6 while the guys in an hour gave a
little half our presentation on
interesting
unencrypted messages: the caught while
hanging out
I was wondering if you guys head found
anything interesting anything noteworthy
talk about as ever heard anything like
that it sometime
I noticed most people ports getting
everybody else and in turn towards
getting
their bills that there was you know
probably 30-40 port scans going on
continuously throughout the weekend
for good but I ended up spending most of
the
free time I had on fighting the tent on
getting out working
as an emblem under so in a little bit
too much but
on basically that the pitcher catcher is
one thing that but we should have a bit
on official policy in that what you
don't log can be subpoenaed
I yeah sure you know
Draghi regressing the building
was logged on our side and that's just
for that same reason
I put around a lil bit like I V draft is
watching the
then the the the protocol rates and what
not arm
and Iran dramatic there and don't all
the images out on the ps3 business here
see what was going on with that home
yeah out things didn't die this year
but I know we per we kinda kept busy
looking at things all the time
have another was gonna fall down so
there wasn't too much digging around
like that in
but I guess so up
I would assume the girls one by their
whole lotta Twitter feeds in
and I wanna
i'm for Twitter and a
how much BP interview you'll see traffic
did you notice up
well so if vs was the number two
protocol message with the number three
a either one of those could be VPN
tunnels arm
I think I saw Alex understand if you
can't work show up around like eight or
nine
arm saw a few ninety sessions and
knows about it again we were married and
looking at the traffic
this for the help looking at the traffic
is anybody doing anything that might
have been at work to go in service
speaking a VPN
ID try to use it PPTP VPN
on both open networks did connect on the
open open one
but fail consistently on them added one
on he doesn't like to be
yet reason the reason for that is that
is it doesn't cross inactivity is very
well and that's part of why that
why that now open public network was
there
the we got to slash twenty allegations
about sixteen
lassies whatever I'd right there
so you know few thousand IP addresses
right and so
impacted the public when you go one of
those many IP addresses
and you just had a straight-up public
Internet IP in work just fine
yes thing with thing with BP's the GRE
tunnel
and its when it crosses now
there's just nothing really
help injury traffic it says how to line
it up
it doesn't even try to call members and
it's on time I checked some garin
and basically just breaks protocol yeah
see at them
protocol help with make some educated
guesses for that's what the net helpers
for PPP do
make educated guesses so basically if
the protocol helpers
is installed on acix way then you can
reliably worked for
you know one or two people but beyond
that one session and most of them
night implementations will can identify
when she retired online
and that's why we have different works
also for the record PPTP
is relatively vulnerable so if you can
l2tp better yes probably
good in a minute at some point at
yeah my provider offers a choice of that
RSS Alan I was just being cheap
to the SSL being a tad more expensive
what is best coupon world
if you to protect the public eye peas a
number times I P to location
and Kate coming up with that domain on
that's prolly lastly the netbook
you have there would have been an old
that there would be no swim for that
like they would have had that before gun
registered in the air in database and
stuff like that
and so but they're gone now thank you
very much
any other
questions/comments flames in willingly
give much
for the flames something
for goes
your kid is just coming to your basement
studio borrowed from work
or it's another question mark as I think
you might cut in half waivers are
hour to get the kit arm so on wifi stuff
came out my test lab
I work for networks are so arm
let me bring all that gear down here got
help from the cons
and field test I weigh on my page on my
own
runner large campus when large research
computing environment
si la to hand me downs sometimes a
switch to get discarded
the bed our spine another such get
started with a this post
bring together networking switch to seek
Amy wood
Watson what's up hardware on
am able to use for something like this
so if it to mention on may be interested
all the Cisco harbors for sale
I'm come see me after talkin have
something out I don't drive it home
him
will moment will negotiate offline or
any other questions
are just the
thanks again for all the other number
cuz I hope that this all going
and I love for the other guys that I
prolly for gun because even though I've
been sleeping this weekend I'm
completely not awake right now
so I'm sure I'm forgetting people to
think in my apologies to them
but great work for everybody on the
network team cuz
in and thanks everyone for showing up
would have been real weird thanks
think that cuz you about half an hour to
go get some food for closing ceremonies
ones
nom