it's highly controversial in didn't seem
to have ever been covered
any other hacker conference that we
wanted to turn into a panel
with a with an attorney and maybe
someone for the BFF
so that's what we did but we didn't
expect wish it to be so difficult to
find people who'd be willing to
participate in this panel because it
that controversial nature
the topic I talk to think about eight
different attorneys the
didn't want to touch it with a ten-foot
pole on
Alex months for philadelphia has balls
so where
here I can explain why here
he decided to do this but bottom line is
that I thank him for
for being on this panel because it's
it's a worthwhile topic and then
us that shown from my BFF technologist
and a is this deal with a lot of the
cases where E seen a lot of the legal
side over of cases even without a lawyer
he said
he seen a lot there deff I'm Ando
we had regional a after it the panel was
put together we got contacted by one of
the year
that the wife of one the defendants in
the case is gonna be discussed here
on Robin feel which was interesting
Michael feel is a wife she contacted
very interesting in somehow helping out
with ish and
such is all set to combat that after a
long discussion with her husband she
he he decided it's probably not a good
idea for talk about it on
he has a gag order even though she was
said that all the charges were dropped
he was sort of or less forced to sign a
gag order in exchange for rent them now
press the government to prosecuting him
so I she's not into that restriction but
here
here nervous breakdown he said had a
heart attack
three ish during his case and a he just
didn't need additional stress for the
coverage but it is worth covering
because a
this could happen to anybody as they say
I'm so without any yet more delay I'm
pretty if you say
to Cicero ship Shonan and Alex months
we'll be talking about the need
for a computer crime Innocence Project
thank you
alright to I'm II
I've been this my first hope and i
notice that not a lot of people were
doing bio so I have three biotite sa
you've probably seen Alex and septa talk
so we'll just go through the BIOS
there %ah thanks to bernie for talking
about the talk that almost wasn't
one thing you didn't mention was that I
hope selection committee even contacted
a Innocence Project
and they were interested in coming and
talking about the need for computer
crime Innocence Project Soul
very controversial subject up my
schedule for
my part the presentation you know the
disclaimer that
everybody does I wanted I want to talk
about whether or not a problem exists
and if it doesn't work we're in for a
very short talk today
up some cases in the news that you might
be aware of her might not
%uh a research project that I recently
did that that
prompted me %uh in in the belief that we
need a computer crime Innocence Project
cost if the defense and there's a lot of
just not
a monetary costs other little review
what I talked about that Alex is gonna
take over
all right down the views expressed
during my portion of the talk are my
views
alone they don't necessarily represent
the views are Alex are saffir the hope
selection committee heard
the hope conference or my employer so
there's my disclaimer
I like this quote I'm going to just do
it for
verbatim I'm not in favor of imprisoning
the innocent
but I'm not enthusiastic about freeing
the guilty this talk is not about how to
mask downloading your kiddie porn
with malware this talk is about how
you can use for a proper forensics to
find out what really happened
on a system so that innocent people
don't get convicted of crimes they
didn't commit
%uh another good quote out on the web I
found was call me naive but I believe
the two competent diligent computer
forensic examiners acting in good faith
will usually agree upon the digital
evidence and what I found in my
experience in what I found doing my
research on the web is that never
happens
and that's disappointing you would think
that too
competent forensic examiners would say
yes
I agree that's what happened on the
computer but the defense and the
prosecution
rarely have that happen alright so does
the problem exist up
it doesn't matter whether way in in my
limited experience it doesn't matter
whether you work for the defense or the
prosecution
I believe there are a lot of for Anzac
examiners out there
that are incompetent they claim to know
what they're doing but they really don't
know what they're doing
and I'm not saying that either side
commits perjury
but if you're not a competent expert and
you testify
what you testify becomes expert opinion
and it's up to the jury to decide
whether or not you know what you're
talking about
and I want you to think about the
average twelve people on a jury and
highly technical information
0 I guess I am saying that some experts
to commit perjury
alright here I have to I %uh
two quotes out on the web I one of them
is from an expert
%uh who runs a forensic company and the
other one
is from our a Oregon detective
%uh the first one is I love the computer
forensic experts I've encountered
ninety-five percent
are dangerous this is somebody who runs
a forensic
company now that what I would hope that
if you get convicted
or not convicted if you get prosecuted
for computer crime
I'm sure that the other five percent
will be who you run into
now the other quote was viruses could
make folders and say favorite images and
catalog them that was by an Oregon
detective was a forensic expert well we
all know that
viruses and malware could do those
things so here's somebody who's an
expert
well that just can't happen and if you
went to the talk yesterday
about crime where you know that a botnet
could easily make that happen on your
system
I hear some great court transcript this
court transcript is actually from the
Julia marrow case
which we'll be discussing I some good
questions that the question was does
spyware and adware
generate pornography and the experts
answer was
I'm not aware that they do now we can
have a long discussion
about whether or not the attorneys
question was proper
does spyware and adware generate
pornography what he really meant to ask
was
the spyware and adware cause pornography
to appear on your screen
now I'm sure that the twelve people that
might be on your jury are going to
understand the difference
when attorney asks a question like that
another question whether viruses adware
a spyware on the computer and the
experts answer was to the best of my
knowledge
there was not have that on the PC yet
just before he was asked that question
he had testified that he didn't even
look for spyware and adware
but I'm sure that a jury where you're
being prosecuted
will understand but he just said
something else that they won't be a
slight
asleep when the experts are are I'm not
talking
okay so where do these cases happen is
this something that just going on in the
United States no
here's a case this is this one up here
was Julian bream %ah Julian Green had
are 172 indecent images on his system
a defense forensic examiners found that
there were 11 Trojans on his computer
and and the quote I found on the web was
that they were
capable of downloading the images well
I would think that a forensic examiner
would know whether or not
I would would say whether or not they
did it
or they didn't do it now I don't know if
the if the person who wrote the article
change the word from we found evidence
that these
that that the malware actually download
these images or
that the the defense said well there
were there was now we're on the system
and the malware might have done it I
don't know that cuz I'm I don't have any
up inside knowledge on this case when I
work read the word capable I thought
well that's that's interesting so
he was eventually acquitted
I here's another case many have you will
probably be familiar with it was the
case of Julia meryl Julia mara was a
substitute teacher
who went into the classroom I believe
she was told not to turn the computer
off
%ah some students either login or use
the computer and all of a sudden
their was soft porn popups that were on
her system
she was actually convicted of impairing
the morals other child she was convicted
because her system had porn popups on it
%ah the that that you we were we
previously heard some other testimony in
her case now
luckily her sentence was delayed four
times
and she was are she had a new trial
and then she ended up pleading that
trial and I believe it was for
disorderly conduct
I we're gonna talk about what happened
to her and how many problem she had
during the whole course this
at the end my presentation here's a case
this was what were the one that bernie
talked about earlier
%uh this is the case of Michael feel his
laptop I believe
his laptop had something can happen is
laptop and they reissued him another
laptop
and %ah that laptop ended up having
child pornography on it
%uh defense forensic examiner after he
was being
up prosecuted for this went in and found
that that there was all kinds of weird
stuff going on this laptop
up very interesting I found on the web
that two exams by the state attorney
general office concurred with the
defense forensic expert so here's a time
where
all great the the prosecution
and the defense agree on the evidence
the problem is
how long that took to happen and what
happens to somebody's life
when when it takes a long other court
ended up concluding that he was
up not right at the court ended up
expunging him
his case another case this this case is
Matthew bandy
and not up this was really tried in the
media
up Matthew bandy ended up having
or I don't know how many images yet
buddy I guess the prosecution was for
nineteen
images which in Arizona is nine felony
counts which could be
ninety years in prison now this might be
a case of an overzealous prosecution
I don't know up but it was it was very
adversarial
from the beginning the on the Arizona
are Supreme Court had to rule against
the county attorney's office that didn't
want to allow
the defense to do an analysis up the
computer
so right away the up
Darke County Attorney's Office that
didn't want to allow the defense
to examine the computer started being
adversarial the family
went out and got burstein crisis
management to build a website to start
discrediting
the County Attorney's Office up
it was just a back and forth in fact you
might have seen a twenty20
up report on this exact case
now I did a lotta research on this case
found a lot of information out on the
web
and since then the prosecutor has
reexamine the system
at least two more times and there's a
lot of information out on the web
that really points to Matthew was guilty
but again I didn't have any inside
knowledge on this it's only what I've
read out on the web
art so little bit my background every
year I do a yearly research project I
like to stay busy
and some of my research projects have
included penetration testing educational
software
analyzing now where and using of
forensic products to test security
when I did my analyzing now where up
project
I learned a bunch of things %uh some
love them I used in
in the last up a project I did that
first to follow it just because their is
malware
doesn't mean that it downloaded certain
things we should all be aware that
there's all different types of malware
just because
there's now we're on our system does not
necessarily mean that it downloaded
illegal content.
more importantly just because you didn't
find now where does it mean there isn't
any on your system and gain a point to
the presentation yesterday about crime
where
there's very easy ways to make your
malware
be be able to be installed on a computer
and not find it so
if up are prosecutorial forensic expert
says
I search for malware on your system and
I didn't find any so there's not going
to be any
in Europe they call it the PhD defense
or
of the Trojan horse defense and in the
united states they call it the saudi
defense or
some other dude did it are that will
identify now where so there's not going
to be that well
that's not the case it's it's quite
possible using normal
up ways to find now where anti virus
that you might not find them our on the
system
I'm gonna show you in my malware
presentation
I actually would the what I was trying
to find out was I had heard
that if you download a screensaver out
on the internet this was about two years
ago
that nine out of ten of them have a
virus or or are now where
so I thought that's interesting I'm
gonna prove that so I went out and I
downloaded this dolphin screensaver
and I shot it out to virus told one at
this time buyers total would
search search it with 39 different virus
protection packages
and 1 %uh the 39 found something wrong
and what did they find wrong it said the
file is damaged so how many have you
when you saw this we're just go ahead
and install it
right 39 different anti viruses say this
this this application is fine
I'll go ahead and install it after
analyzing it I found that
it was doing something on my system I
went ahead and did a right Wireshark
capture
and it was in cryptic day two of my
system and sending it off to somebody
outside that was a nice test system so I
wasn't concerned about what it was
sending off
and in this particular I project
I actually figured out what it was
sending off and if you're interested
in in hearing about what this what it
was is a botnet
was doing you can talk to me after after
the stock
art so has that defense ever been used
has somebody said yeah but you're not
going to find now where on my system
and yes I agree my system was used to i
hack
certainly in the end the case apparent
mccaffrey his system both the
prosecution and the defense agree
his system was used to attack I think it
was the Port of Houston
well the case hinged on whether or not
the jury would believe that
someone else had taken over his system
and indeed they ended up believing that
and he was acquitted
art so the latest project I've worked on
I was I was asked to come in and do a
forensic analysis
I took the prosecutorial report I read
the entire report
and I and I found this quote and I read
this quote and it just didn't seem right
to me
the quote is it is unknown if any of
these buyers files were allowed to run
on the system prior to being caught by
the norton antivirus software or
if any of them were in any way
responsible for any other child
pornography files located on the
suspect's computer
if I'm the computer forensic examiner if
I'm the expert
I should know these answers I should be
writing this in new in a report
I should be able to say this these
viruses
infected the system after this
pornography was placed on the system or
before the system was
placed on the system so I went to the
defense attorney I was working for and I
said
I've never really done this if it turns
out that
the malware downloaded this I'm not your
guy
but I can tell you that I'm going to
instantaneously start working on how I
would do this
if I needed to prove it now where was
was the problem
so my latest project is researching
if it is possible cell whether malware
or the computer user downloaded files in
question on the system
so I started by going out on the
Internet and there's all kinds of
information on the Internet on how you
might go about
proving whether or not malware download
illegal files on the system
or the computer user downloaded files on
the system but no one I could find
nowhere
that someone would tell me I actually
infected a system
and I conducted aka computer forensic
exam
and this these are the steps I talk and
this is how I prove that
the malware did it are those of you that
our are big into reading there was a
book a while back called
hackers challenge and that's what
happens challenge did
it gave you all the log files and it
would bring you to
this is what happened in this is how you
could have proved what happened so
that's what I was looking for
I couldn't find that so I decided you're
never gonna send out emails to a bunch
of industry professionals and if I said
their names
that you'd know them and basically I
asked out three questions
first was are you aware of any
documentation that discusses what
downloader malware looks like from
a forensic examiners point of view and
if you do could you tell me where it is
and the other question was if you don't
do think this would be a worthy project
now I was disappointed just like we had
so many people who decided
we're not going to touch this with a
ten-foot pole
I wonder how many of these forensic
examiner said I don't even want to be
involved in this project
and that's why didn't get a response but
of the replies I got
no one could point me to any
documentation so I thought this would be
good documentation to write
ended some respondents thought and that
would be a worthy project
up other respondents that that said I'm
not aware of any that documentation
thought I should do some other project
they said but why do you do this
instead of analyzing I whether malware
or the computer user
project so I worked for college
and normally when I do these projects I
do them on my own
and then I go to college and i say i
would like to present at Def Con I would
like to present at this technology
conference I would like to present I
hope
do you want me to present as independent
researcher Joe Cicero
or northeast with Northeast Wisconsin
Technical College instructor joe says
throw
and always in the past the college's
said now you can do it as a as a
employees have nWTC but because I was
going to do this project
on nWTC computer and I would be
installing now where
on in WTC computer which is against
policy
I thought it better that I ask
permission to do this one
so I set off an email to my executive
leadership team that's what yeltsin
stands for
ric rac requesting permission to do this
project I asked them three
simple questions tonight conduct the
research is an nWTC employees
which I always ask after the fact but
this time I was asking
before can I get an exemption to the
Acceptable Use Policy
I'm going to install malware on one of
your computers
which is against Jerry your acceptable
use policy and I need an exemption for
that
and can I publish all the communications
because if I can't publish the
communications
between us that I won't do this project
is an nWTC employees its stock
this is part of the research project if
somebody wants to go on with my research
they might not want to know what the
steps I talk
the executive leadership teams response
was
you have the support to go ahead and do
this project
now I want to make it clear all I ask
them for was
I'm going to install Mauer I didn't say
anything about what the malware would do
so they said go ahead with your project
I thought great now I can start
my next call was to the EFSF great
organization if you haven't given
if you've got an extra couple a box just
go down and give it to them
if you got 20 40 60 100 go give it to
them
i cud I I can't say enough about how
nice it is to make a phone call to an
attorney I spent about a half an hour on
the phone with Jennifer Granik
pocket just a wonderful organization so
I'll
I made a phone call %ah one of the first
things I told Jennifer was I haven't
told my executive leadership team that
this malware might download illegal
content like troubled child pornography
and shit the words outta Jennifer smart
where you're going to tell them that
right
I said yes but I wanted the I wanted to
back up everything that I was about to
send them an email
what by talking to an attorney first out
that conversation
to primary outcomes came first of all is
that the law
in regards to child pornography States
knowingly
with the regards to possession so as
long as I don't
pick-up become aware up the child
pornography on a system
I haven't broken that law so I could do
a forensic examiner look at an image
I don't need to look at the image i'm
looking at all the meta-data the image
so I thought
that's very easy to do the other thing
that I had not thought about
this is why you discuss those things
these things with attorneys and other IT
professionals was
you should probably address what will
happen yes if you do become
aware up the illegal content. they might
have policies and procedures already in
place
but they might not so in the event you
become aware
you want to have that in your protocol
that was very important
so after I had that conversation
I did an executive leadership team re
request
I sent it off %uh an email and I said
do you want to revoke my approval based
upon the possibility
that the malware I install on your
computer might download illegal content.
in an example would be child pornography
the second question was
I do you want to review the protocol i
right before I conduct this research so
that there's
other eyes on it and another question
was do you already have policies in
place
should someone become aware that are
there's child pornography on a system
I sent that email off to my executive
leadership team and what do you think
happened
I work for a great organization
my executive leadership team said Joe we
back you
and we're going to allow you to proceed
but we're going to do it with caution
how many have you have an employer like
that
up yeah I think they do ok
I here's a college you wanna you want to
talk about a college that allows our
instructor some leeway
they didn't say now we're not get
involved with this like all the
attorneys and the
I and the Innocence Project here in New
York they said this is a worthy project
and we're gonna just proceed with
caution so what they wanted to do is
consult with their own attorney so the
next thing we did and I love meeting
sorry
the Alex but meetings with attorneys are
not on my
high regard here
I we I had a meeting with the
I with the attorney now this was very
interesting to me the school's attorney
said you know Joe
courts can lower the standard of
knowingly
to should have known and your computer
expert
I can easily see II court saying
mister Cicero you should have known so
we're going to go I'll goal forward with
that understanding
additionally they said you know there
might be safe harbor an exemption there
might be an
a safe harbor exemption so we might have
something that we can work what and you
can do this project and we don't really
have to worry about it
are they also said we should talk with
the people we deal with with a night
anti-virus there and I might now where
vendors and we should say hey
how do you guys deal with this because
if it's going on it must happen on your
computer's
and there might be a procedure or
protocol already in place for how to
handle it
and then they said you know what we're
going to schedule a follow-up meeting
with
another attorney of who does computer
forensics and
and get some of his thoughts so the
answers to those key points before that
meeting happen
they couldn't find a safe harbor
exemption the anime our vendors were
unwilling to tell us how they conducted
testing I want you to think about that
its it it happens we know what happens
that
malware whether it's a botnet for an
hour or or virus or trojan or whatever
has downloaded illegal files well that
means that all these
anti-virus vendors have to have systems
where that's happening
they were unwilling to tell us the
protocol that they used to handle when
that happens to them
they contacted other colleges to say do
you have any instructors doing this type
a research and how do you handle it
and the college's got back with are my
college in basically said let us know
how that goes
or are you sure you want to allow this
instructed to do that
so again other colleges really not doing
this type a research
and of course there was a follow-up
meeting schedule now
prior to the follow-up meeting the
attorney that was gonna be called in
to meet with me on the follow-up meeting
said you know what I would have a
meeting before that meeting so now
lucky me I get to have meetings about
meetings
I get called into this meeting and and
this this attorney who's also a forensic
examiner said you know what
I will hike would not be able to render
an opinion on this
until I had a formal research proposal
and the protocol written so I looked at
him and I said
what do you need in the formal research
proposal in the protocol just tell me
and then that's what I'll write
and he said not all I'm not gonna go for
that's all
so we ended that meeting and I went back
to my office and if I do say so myself I
rather a very nice for more research
proposal
and I started writing the protocol but
what I felt was
I was kinda been a catch-22 I
the formal research proposal was easy to
write mean all kinds have
a information in it and sightings
but the protocol every time I thought
about how I do a forensic exam
IFI I realize that I do a lot of things
exactly the same
but then what I end up with his new
search leads so
I Titleist new search lead new search
Lee and then I have to go
analyze those new search leads are I saw
this I'm gonna go on a man I'm
find out what happened there and what
the realization I had is
when I write down these new search leads
I'm then going to have to write a new
protocol for them
I'm going to have to submit them to an
attorney I'm gonna have to wait for that
attorney to make a decision
because I can't bury myself from this
protocol
at all this is going to take for ever
I won't be able to conduct this research
in years
because it has to then go back to the
executive leadership team
it then has to be approved to come back
to me and it would taste just take for
ever to do this so
I basically scrapped the idea of
installing the malware
but I still wanted to conduct my
research so
what's a guy to do K use my own
industry standard malware so
I made the decision rather than writing
my own virus what i'll do is i'll go
find out
how people are doing things like but
Nats learn how to do a botnet
create my own but they had and then I'll
just
upload my own inner images images of
cars
and I can still conduct my research cuz
I don't care what the images
I care whether or not you can tell what
put it there the malware
or the computer user so I spent a
considerable on a time
thirty or forty hours learning how to
create a botnet
I was able to create a botnet I'm able
to upload image files now to my Tascam
test computer and my research continues
now I did not I don't have anything
officially written yet
but what I've done so far the evidence
points me
debtor the what I found is that the lack
of evidence
is the evidence itself if you find these
images on your system but you don't find
any other relation to that evidence
then it was probably malware that put it
there remember
I i want to be able to analyze a system
and not know whether or not now where
exists
art so why is this going on well if you
go out
a what wire experts having problems with
determining this
well I found this quote on a normal out
on the web there's a two-year time limit
before your soul dies this was an
article I believe it was on forensic
focus
written by a gentleman who deals with
child pornography on a regular basis
and he basically says people who do this
on a daily basis
either after after two years their heart
is black and
they just they can ignore the terrible
things that they see on their screen
or they just can't take it anymore
now I want you to think about a forensic
expert
thats prosecuting you or thats thats
dealing with the prosecution
that has less than two years experience
how expert were you when you add less
than two years
experience so that might be one of the
reasons for their previous quote
ninety-five percent other other forensic
experts that that gentleman met
were dangerous additionally I found a
quota law enforcement agencies are on a
steep learning curve now way to think
about this I was involved in a case
last year that was Windows
98 so
I have to know Windows 98 Windows XP
Windows Vista Windows seven if you're a
small shop
you have to know everything and now
think about how many small
forensic shops for even even even cop
police and forensics
examiner shops there are where there's
one or two guys
are they going to know Linux Macintosh
all the different versions a macintosh
all the intricacies have Vista and 7 XP
in ninety-eight
so law enforcement agencies are on a
steep learning curve
art so what's the cost of the defense
there's a there's a cost that goes way
beyond monetary
monetarily a monetary cost are Julia
meryl miscarried her baby
she was hospitalized for stress they can
barely afford to keep their home
her case took four years of her life
this is all over porn popups
are she lost her teaching license and
she lost at least one job
because her employer didn't like her
arrest record
Matthew bandy I was reported that there
was a quarter million dollars in legal
costs
he was on probation for 18 months it was
a two-year nightmare
Michael Feola he was fired from his job
received death threats this case cost
him a quarter million dollars in fees
they had to liquidate their savings
take a second mortgage sell their car
they lost friends
and what was the what what what what did
I do you remember what I
found out on the web that the
prosecutor that that there were two
exams or something like that
that agreed with the different defense
for a forensic exam
this is what it cost him
up there's a cost to the taxpayers to I
want you to think that
that that prosecution is free the
prosecutors that are prosecuting people
they that cost you money others a belief
in the legal system
I think we all probably have our
understanding that
you might get a raw deal if you end up
in the legal system
and then there's the cost that guilty
people go free
up I am NOT in favor of anybody who
deals with child pornography going free
I want them prosecuted
alright so how many of you have a
quarter million dollars for you defense
fun
right these people they the they had
that kinda money
up I don't have that kinda money so what
can you do well
defendants gas courts to pay but
sometimes the judge balks at the price
of forensic examiners are not cheap and
Europe a really good attorneys probably
not gonna be
cheap so this is gonna cost you a lot of
money if you're innocent
art so does a problem exist yeah I think
a problem exists
and I think are a way to handle this
problem is is a computer crime Innocence
Project
innocent people are being prosecuted and
convicted
and guilty people are not being punished
they're saying hey them our did it
an incompetent friends prosecutorial
forensic examiner saying I can't defend
that may be a dead
and somebody was guilty goes free
if you're in interested in conducting
this type a research hopefully some I
prepper
preparation work some like prep work is
done and you don't have to start where I
started
learning all this you can start where I
am didn't say are you I need to get all
these different type thing
to all this different types of
information and
not everyone has the the capability of a
quarter-million dollar defense
I want to thank Alex in South because I
would have been able to talk at this
year's hope
without them I want to thank the hope
not talk selection committee
I want to thank my nWTC executive
leadership team for allowing me to
conduct the research
and I want to thank those %uh view who
attended and now will have Alex come up
that's about as close as I'm gonna get
to a pile
okay I most the crime we're going to
talk minutes per session
our distribution of child pornography
are I'm citing federal law
the course given that we are a federal
republic there are fifty states out
there that have their own slightly
different rules but
the federal the federal laws in nice
cunt overview
I'm okay when I'm talking about on when
lawyers talk about
elements up in action elements of the
crime
each of these has to be met for there to
be a crime
so I the child porn law is
you knowingly and knowingly doesn't mean
knowingly
there is a term called constructive
knowledge
which is you should have known given the
given what you knew
that you you were acting in such a way
are you were doing such a thing
up possession is generally a
knowledge-based crime
in that you have to know that you are
holding contraband
I usually the example for constructive
knowledge for is I we talk about drug
offenses is
I'm gonna give you thousand dollars to
take this box
and run it across town and give it if
any
you don't pay a thousand dollars to run
a box across town if it's legitimate
there for you have constructive
knowledge
something is wrong okay so you have to
knowingly transport receive distribute
his ass solicit for
offer our duplicate child pornography
and it has two for federal law has to
use
are effect interstate commerce now
the Internet is interstate commerce even
when
it is two machines in the same state
ob because our explain later
up actually it's because that the rule
is if it can affect interstate commerce
it is if it it affects the fed's it
affects the it fits the interstate
commerce clause in the Constitution
and we because the federal government
allowed to
are regulate interstate commerce
eighty-five to 90 percent of federal
laws
base are based out of that clause so
interstate drug laws firearms laws
arm help tobacco in explosives were just
you know to the whole that the whole
agency arm
cut step at that one clots
okay so what is child porn
I child pornography means any visual
depiction
including photograph film/video Bob so
basically an image
out where the production of the visual
depiction
is a minor in sexually explicit conduct
and great I'm
basically it's its sexually explicit
conduct is used in the image
are the image is Ulf and I i was tryna
work a hypo where I have a cardboard box
inside as a child being molested and
it's a photograph of the box would that
be child porn
and then it's like why my talking about
this it's never gonna happen
okay but all these go to
sexually explicit conduct
what is that and I've read numerous
cases where they discussed this in Sec
I'm gonna sum this up as arm well you
know what's actually
it you know it when you see it are it
does not have to be
actual sex it could be just a pose that
is
sexy I II when I teach a class in in
computer crime
are I will often show pictures of fun a
child beauty pageants
and say is this child porn because you
know there's an image of a kid
and I don't know many four-year-olds
that look like I i
dancers at at Las Vegas Review that's
not normal
and is that an exhibition at the
genitals is that
sexy okay
thankfully they came out with a nice
long past to determine whether or not in
image of a child
is child pornography called dost
notice it's really very weak because
it's week we
we balance all these factors to
determine whether not
this image his child pornography
now how many people have seen nude
photos of themselves when they were a
child
okay is that child pornography
probably Wed
not necessary under the law now of
course I going to get to this step
as we've seen before just because this
is a defense doesn't mean it's not cheap
to get to this point where you're
debating this
in fact that's hideously expensive cuz
you have expert stalling over
is the image the focus of this image is
it meant
to 21 I'm excite the prurient interests
are secure
is it a picture for kid in a bathtub
so what REALLY isn't child pornography
under the law
arm young-looking actors or actresses
and you look for the 2257 see of
approval
out 2257 is the well those of you who
look at pornographic web sites arm may
notice that there's an 18 USC 2257
will rule on bonham it's a registry of
everyone who appeared in this
if you saw their junk we have their
names
arm animate is not child pornography
on it could be obscene and us a legal
anyway but
it is not inherently child porn on
photoshopping is not a holy generated
computer image
it is if I use a child's head on an
adult body doing something
that is still child porn because there's
a that you can you can point to a
child's
image in the photo on
your baby photos are not missus are not
child porn least I hope not because the
focus in the intent the photo was not to
get a one-off
if they were I'm really really sorry
and Sears catalogs I make this is not
actually a joke
arm child porn case I worked on arm
they cited my guy
for images of child porn several which
were
from like eight mid-seventies Sears
catalog of
kids in underwear and sick but wait a
minute this is packed because you like
and i'm talking to friends the French
person other side
and he saying well it's it's a scan data
the sears catalog
okay how such child pornography any
wouldn't answer me okay so how do you
defend
against a child porn case you can attack
the elements
knowledge I didn't know the child forms
they are all
and therefore he did not legally possess
you had it but you can legally possess a
cuz you didn't know it existed
on your hard drive you didn't know was
real child porn you thought I just read
your tentacle porn
arm you didn't know style pornography
it was it's an you know it's sad it's an
image I mean that's on an image it's
like i dinos
it was I thought was regular porn I you
can defend on
yes I knew the porn was there bite no
actual children were used
in the manufacture of this I'm
now under federal law there's this
unconstitutional rule that says
its up to you to prove that they aren't
actually children
this is unconstitutional I don't know if
it's been tested yet
because it's the prosecution's a
burden to show all the elements so you
have to show
you knew you had it you knew as a child
and that the are actually children
the they switch this in federal law to
say
you have to raise the defense you have
to inform us before
you raise it and it's your burden to me
now the problem is how do you prove
that the chop that their that the image
is not that of a child you would have to
either name the child where and it's
really their defense for the
pornographer
because it's a well you know here's
here's all our 2257 numbers
that paper since nineteen therefore
we're OK
but for the person charged with
consuming or possessing it's really hard
to try and find the name of the person
so you instead have to do a a
an expert witness to say that's you know
that's not a that's not an that's an
adult that's not a kid
because you know proportion height
waihee
you know breast development whatever
there's also
this really strange good faith
affirmative defense which
seems to be a cut out for people who arm
are IT people can
actions at large a significant block if
I've child porn arrests
come out I love people working arm
at Best Buy are are are other retail
computer outlets because
person with child porn comes in saying
my machine doesn't work
I'm I have Ben that IT guy not with
child porn but
my computer isn't working what's wrong
with its cuz it's chock full of porn
you know there there is no space for
swap any markets all porn
that's why you can't burn a CD there's
no space left delete some if you're born
sir
I didn't leave that on the message to
his wife that would awesome
but forearm
for the affirmative defense though I'm
you can help you must be you love you
are identified
less than three images so you get two
bites
and back point you've either delete made
made reasonable effort to delete those
those documents
are you have prevented anyone else
reviewing them
and if and have called the cops and you
only permit the police to say
so it's effectively saying I don't have
it I'm stepping away from the PC
I'm not touching anything I I yeah I
kept everyone else
at the lab are out of I know I i'm
at the shop waiting for the cops to iraq
if
%uh which is why generates a few things
just deleted I made reasonable efforts
to delete it
gone and maybe then call the cops
maybe not I'm not really sure they're
really depends on
whether or not the police already now
okay another way of defending the child
porn cases you attack the evidence
the way he collected was was bogus the
way you
analyzed it was bogus your conclusions
are broken
on this is a tooling expert problem each
side
has their forensics expert each side is
caring apart the other persons report
each side is is and then the problem
with this
is one it's expensive cuz you just build
your friend six-person out for a bunch
hours
they build their salads
and you're going to if you actually go
to a jury trial
you're gonna have that person in a in
the witness box
for anywhere from day to a week
ever wanted jury watching really
detailed technical evidence
five-minute rule if it's more than five
minutes there sleep
I've watched jurors fall asleep during
this sec
so really unless you've
unless you have a expert witness that's
interesting enough they're gonna listen
are they crack jokes and really i cant
I look for good job porn jokes there
just aren't any stock material
I'm not me okay just to be safe because
I know this can be a DVD in this will be
you know brought up in some disciplinary
action later with the bar
on I am in no way making light of child
porn
very very serious bad
that's as well I can be sincere okay so
experts how
are we experts how do we how do we
promise how do we put you forward
are someone foreign say I'm a computer
forensics expert
arm you have to be an expert and under
US law
you have to be have to have specialized
skill training
our experience you can be a expert
witness about cars
and you say well-served how are you an
expert
way home I've spent working as a car
mechanic for 18 years
here my certifications here's where I've
worked
bang you can then be put forward as an
expert
the way this is done is side that wants
to push you forward as an expert
asked to certify we won a certified Bob
each side can kinda call will question
the person
arm now it's not just the expert
is is put on on cast experts feel
is put on a test to say is this actually
a field of expertise
is it relevant to our cakes so
putting forward you note the automotive
expert going
that's great but we're talking about
child porn the fact that you know the
times when the Buick in a shabby
irrelevant here go away now
the advantages once you get certified as
an expert field it's really really easy
cuz judge you know judges will say
well no judge someone selling the you
know in the Western District certified
you
good enough for me
okay I'll quickly go through the
standards for experts
the dobare standard is they test
if they test the science which is is a
test tube or is our
error rate is there some way of
determining that
you have done a method that's acceptable
and you've done it correctly
and you know the chances that you
screwed it up
how accepted is it how many times has it
been
Don arm and has that mimic
correctly applied to the case at hand so
your
you what theory you're putting forward
is it has ever been done before
I there's also no order stand which we
call the fry standard its
a lot looser its is a general scientific
acceptance of the field
up the method you used and why almost
there law review article about how fry
is stupid
all that its the law in Penn State's
including New York Pennsylvania
California so it's still really really
important
okay um I've seen a couple cases where
the use experts in child porn
one is arm proving that the images are
of children
and there's still kinda broke into some
some states like
you don't need an expert to prevent I
can see that their kids their kids
don't need to put it but someone forward
others are
know you actually have to go through
some a bunch hoops
about it which is I've doctor who
evidently their specialty is determining
whether not be poor kids
beware specialty but hey
okay I am prosecution
when they put forth their expert they're
putting forward I'm explaining what I
did I'm explaining what I saw
and if the really good they're going to
foreclose potential defense is that the
defense would possibly
raise arm usually they don't tell
usually they're just like this is this
is the truth came from God
to me to you corset and screw it up I'm
not going to discuss what they might
argue the defense's jobs come up with
alternext nation for the fax
are to critique and say he didn't get
the facts
and one quick aside before I sit back
down arm
child porn cases are different in about
the evidence any other case
the defense gets all the evidence the
prosecution has and they can go and
collect more
in child porn because
child porn itself is illegal to have you
can't just give it over
to the defense and say there you go
because it's true more that would make
the prosecutor
distributor child porn that would make
you assessor
child porn mister missus forensic expert
Fed's came up with a really bizarre rule
which is
its to use my hands the prosecution you
forensic expert go to the FBI field lab
use their equipment and
um we promise we won't listen in when
you're talking to the lawyer
are if the lawyers there and I don't
know I've I get a little
it she ran cops I can imagine talking
with my forensic expert being the
forensic expert talking to the lawyer
and select officer friendly would you
mind not listening into our defense
strategy
I'll be really nice however
I've seen with this is also helped the
defense in a really odd way
arm I worked on the new
I New Jersey versus year Lauren Series
Case this was
a oMG I got caught up in a perverted
justice kindness
kind of staying he had child porn are
he allegedly had child porn on his hard
drive when we raise the defense to say
we want to see the forensic analysis we
want to see how it was done
and we wanna see the images to determine
whether or not the child porn
prosecution said and gamers can leave it
as some
you know attempted child molestation
screw the child porn and ink kinda had a
guy dead to rights anyway
of
I don't have any slight so I'm just
going to it's a couple things
I'm one thing is that I don't have a lot
of first-hand experience with
working on this issue with the FF one
reason is that
until BFF relatively recently hired
Jennifer Granik
was really one of the world's leading
computer crime defense lawyers
BFF had never undertaken any criminal
defense if anyone
we have a large legal team but their
expertise was all
civil litigation and so we just had a
policy that we don't do criminal cases
now that we have jennifer working with
us we are able to do some criminal
representation
so that's really cool but it's really
recent development for FF actually
I'm in the past we always had to refer
all the criminal cases to other people
outside of our organization
but the other thing is that still
because we are a non-profit and we have
so I'm
so much work so little boyer time
we try to do you generally a strategy
called impact litigation
where we try to do things that will set
an important precedent it's also the
strategy that ACLU generally uses
I'm and that means to try to economize
or lawyers resources
we generally try not to get involved in
cases where we think there's going to be
a big factual dispute
where the sides will have to fight back
and forth about what happened we
generally try to get involved in cases
where
it's pretty clear what happened I'm
and there's a dispute about the law
what's legal standard that applies to
this and we've tried to set a precedent
about that
so that's not really what we're talking
about on this panel so it's a little
unusual as far as our experience over a
DFF
I have to say that the malware defense
issue
for the idea that what you think you
found on my computer
isn't really something that I did
because computers are in secure
is really not something that's limited
to child porn cases
I consulted on a case in Brazil
a.m. it was actually a criminal case
about defamation
it sounds really weird in the US legal
context but in Brazil
defamation can be a criminal offence and
you can go to prison
for defamation and I consulted on a case
where the defendant
was presenting this defense that someone
else had done it
and that perhaps their computer was
infected with malware and that they
hadn't actually
rid the allegedly defamatory things that
they were being threatened with prison
time
for having written and
the difficulty which is very typical is
that they couldn't afford a forensic
examination
on the defense side I'm so the
prosecutor had done
head contracted for forensic examination
the defendant was fairly well-off but
even so couldn't really afford the fees
that the forensic examiners would have
charged and I think
in all countries around the world
certainly in the United States
this is a real problem both the
panelists have mentioned that
proper forensic work can be extremely
expensive
criminal defendants typically don't have
the resources
to go through with that whether it's a
child porn matter or any other kind of
criminal defense matter
and so in that case I was looking at a
report basically
I'm as in the cases that were mentioned
before
the forensic examiners said well we
think that this person wrote this stuff
because we found the stuff on their
computer and
we didn't find any particular reason to
think that they didn't write it
there wasn't any report on the other
side so ultimately the person was
convicted
one of the difficulties there I think
was that the court had a difficult time
understanding why
someone would have written malware that
would have put this material
on the defendant's computer if the
defendant had written it
like what's the motive to put the thing
on the person's computer
I'm and I think to varying degrees in
different cases
that's the difficulty that courts have
with the concept of
malware you can say that computers are
incredibly insecure and they've been
infected
left and right and people have malware
and spyware and adware and viruses and
botnets
but why did they put the thing on the
computer of course one possibility is
that someone's using the computer as
storage cloud storage super cheap cloud
storage really
arm your dollars per gig
another possibility is that someone is
intentionally trying to frame someone
and I guess there are other
possibilities yet
arm but basically I think the economics
are
a real challenge for getting forensic
work done we were talking just before
the panel about
the issue that a cursory examination
might find files on a computer without
really establishing how the files got
there
one point that we're talking about is
that website
crude inline images that would never
even be displayed to user
arm skill them to one pixel by one pixel
me to do this from JavaScript maybe do
this in an iframe
I and then the images and up in someones
cash and a forensic examiner could be
trained to always look through someone's
browser cache
and they might find the images and say
work I found these images in the browser
cache
unless it could be true that the user
never intentionally downloaded them and
they were never actually
displayed rendered in the browser user
interface in with user could see them
and so a challenge is thats arm
as the other panelists have mentioned we
don't necessarily have
standards in forensics examination that
would
it make it clear what a forensics
examiner needs to do you
to establish intent to establish
how these images came to be there
whether they were displayed to the user
whether the user attempted to download
them
and so on and I think that challenge is
a challenge for forensics in general
computers are very complex beasts
it's not just something about one kind
of criminal case but something about the
forensics profession as a whole
we got a lot of calls over the FF people
in a lot of trouble
they need help they don't have money so
I think this panel has just identified
another way in which the process of
getting people a fair trial can be
quite difficult thanks
having of
couple a minutes for questions if
anybody has any questions
you're all afraid is as the attorneys we
ask
alright well thank you have a great help
I want to say that the a panelist can be
available outside the
outside the room here about where the
DVD's are made for a few minutes if you
wanna talk to them privately
on so thanks to come