first hackerspace panel and hope history
were every panelist is actually shown
up the from
safe which is good because we get to
hear from everybody for which is bad
because I was counting on to people not
showing like last time
so just give it one quick minute to
rearrange the slide
and will get started week
this
yet so how many people here have are
ever been to a hackerspace
I'm cool how many
how many have never been to a
hackerspace one
people remember how many how many people
are members of the hackerspace
think
member actor if you've never been yeah
actually a nice ridge we have a bunch of
people in that
can't even more keys
Nick review
and so forum filling time
hackerspace is not a word is an amazing
resource a if you live in now if you're
not a member of the hackerspace have
never been to one
and you're wondering where is one may be
near by you
hackerspace is got word is a place to
look
vere some to wiki anyone can add
a new hackerspace that these are
existing reforming
and you can see it's a very impressive
man
Google now with leanza pinpoints
it's pretty amazing some continents are
obliterated with pinpoints
for the maybe when you're you don't even
know about
if you're forming a hackerspace and
you're not on Hector spaces that are put
yourself there
%uh it's a great way to attract new
people to you that you may not even know
exist
but they actually a nice format for
reforming spaces
so when you richard actually does
earlier jobs internal amenity about
where you're located
time you have with your goal is and
there's a really good section
you can say that you're forming space
the journey space that year actively
looking for members are your active
project yeah that's the worst part about
on slides is that you never know watch
slide is behind you are when the slides
actually come up
you can keep going for a little while
you have to give me an um
I haven't slept in a really long time
so that free
just really how many of my volunteers
actually made it to the session oh wow
okay who get cute yeah I know I always
do this but together around applies to
all the volunteers all the security
well
everything this year i think is gone
really really smoothly
%uh and I hope that continues but
moving right along with no hi I am next
for a
I have been called the Johnny Appleseed
hackerspace in two years ago
I came here and I told all your excuses
were invalid and you are approved me
rights give yourselves a round of
applause everybody's building hackers
cases got well so what I'm trying to do
this year
is bring together a bunch of people
who've been working on pushing the
hackerspace concept forward
I'm calling it had her spaces for ever
the driving thing with the panel
basically in three parts first
we're gonna try to get as many
suggestions on how to grow your
hackerspace
goals things hackerspace actually done
hackerspace that have moved
from there for space to a second space
second points
how hackers spaces are connecting with
the community a lot of growth
is about connecting with your community
whether that's your local tech community
whether that's everybody in town whether
that's the global hackerspace community
as a whole
we're gonna be talking about that and
third the point that always comes up it
takes up a lot of effort
ways avoiding drama you guys for your
shoes are invalid
and the way this panel is going to work
each panelist is gonna have
three minutes to introduce themselves
and talk a little bit about the
hackerspace
and then I'm gonna ask them a specific
question about their space
following one of the three points the
goal is to try to get through all the
panelists as quickly as possible give a
brief review
and spent a lot of time on Q&A because I
know you guys have a lot of questions
about Tiger spaces now that you're
actually
building them are dealing with a lot of
these issues were wondering how to go
from the first hackerspace he started or
maybe the meetings you've been having
for a long time actually moving into a
space
or how to figure out how to grow your
hackerspace from forty members to 80
members
how to fight through attrition and all
these other things like that
the panelists have done that have a lot
of experience in that
and summer probably right where you are
and are fighting the same stories about
us
so let's just get right along with that
our first panelist
is from metal out the home attacker
space is not working convene tell us a
little bit about the little
I'm and you
%um lived closer in them
good up soon I'm them hi ok
I'm from ganem summed up like arm
man method has actually been around for
more than four years now
and have not been around when when it
was founded
sewn knows cutting hackers basis details
from me
it's good that we not moon buckingham
Drouin
um region
I was basis very open so basically
whenever remember is %um the key members
you
sweetie key member very literally
everyone who has the key is a key member
even
this approximates 24/7 and by
open I don't mean you have to call and
a before you stop by but everyone can
stop by
anytime as long as the someone present
with the key
arm this some
some spaces do this differently and you
your love
but those as well um
we have 200 square meters of space
we've been going strong for four years
now in the same space
um I think we're doing pretty well
%uh last year I made some statistics
um we had one even
birdie in average into space this can be
used in meetings
upward huge a Cox the true love
all the first base so it's very exciting
thank you in 10 things we're talking
about beforehand
is this notion sort of connecting the
two points together
what sorts of things about connecting
with your community
have helped fuel the growth than that 11
upheld keep it a very big
and vibrant space what is it exactly
about
can the way the middle that connects to
the community that helps a grown helps
continue to be a good space
mmm to be honest must suffer
connection to people use by offering
stuff that's really interesting
own we've we've had two use when
when there were a few even view open and
few knowns things happening and weary
diem
a.m. that was have significant
difference in growth
when we had do
um givens compared to when we have lots
of events
had lots of interesting book shops and
we've been pushing our members to
'em tell stuff %uh give workshops
because
the tagline is basically in one the few
here
has at least one interesting thing to
tell me done
know shit about simply Stella
things and it will be a very interesting
experience for everyone
a great thank you now moving on Berlin
space I am reading at my name is Karl
and honored have crash space in Los
Angeles
and according to our card and the
Collaborative Research Association
official activity at the hackerspace
located in Culver City Los Angeles
is a place where people who are
interested in a wide variety of topics
ranging from
science and technology and to electronic
fan art can get together
and see how things work and find things
that can be built from the park
and we executed a car because I think
as a mentor to many people didn't raise
their hand red
asked whether or not people have been to
hackers bases and we thought it was
important to have a little color
I my hackerspace when it is actually
here
outta New York because I was at the
interactive telecommunications program
for a couple years as a student
and then as I read a researcher there
and so when I left New York everywhere I
went I was like
where's the hackerspace give a new and
wifey resistor and where's the place
like
ATP program where people can figure out
how to do things and
I can find one and then I was in Los
Angeles
and I was actually at a party and I met
someone who I'm was like
well I know this guy he wants to pound
crash we started from a at my mom in a
crash
Fran that made a I'm
we have a for two hundred square foot
space in Culver City
I it we've been open since January
and we have our membership you get a key
for you 24/7 access
and people can stop by but they do me to
have a member with them
and their not in her I we've got a lot
of open event
I never tried it more wave and
yes that's pretty much something up
don't that sounds great
we're talking before and you told me a
very interesting story about the camera
in your space
butter very interesting tag give us a
little background about
that unique ways to circumvent its and
potential drama
your space I'm well you got on a
hackerspace is done word
website you'll see a lot of design
higher than 1mm is about the bike said
and you know having too many too long
conversations about like what color to
make
and I think it happens to a lot of
hyperspace is we have a camera in our
space right now it's mostly just a
security camera
I'm we don't publish the feed although
where
were again having conversations about
what to do about it
I whenever members actually within the
basin didn't want to be incorrect
he just imploded so I we had a
restrain the conversation a meeting and
but basically abandoned not
we're all like but this is ridiculous
and
so I think our about his organization is
really to engineer solutions rather than
legislative solutions
though if we don't want people to I'm
hunt the camera make it to you cannot
and when the camera rather than have a
rule about I'm hugging the camera
so we're trying to keep our legislative
ever had as
minor if possible because no one was in
force anything
so if we can't engineer in a way for
someone not to do it
then we can't make a rule about I which
is
you know actually keeping it on a pretty
low because there was like no you didn't
do this and you're supposed to do that
a legacy that someone can like hit
someone over the head with the were
suppose to you
and that it's not funny or I so that if
so engineering solutions rather than
legislating and it's what we tried to
do.
awesome SoCon you were big mover and
shaker behind
getting hackerspace open in Los Angeles
and you're also a member to hackerspace
in Singapore
right um give people a quick little
introduction
to you and then sorta explain that
dynamic the difference between being a
mover
and hackers facing a member hackerspace
and went to be
either one when am okay so.i
among the founders a the space in Los
Angeles and
I'm has actively been involved with that
the talks in Los Angeles to try to open
after space for about
four years three years or something and
then finally just said
bike fuck it Amanda sign a lease and
then hackerspace and then we actually
got one after that out but a pretty good
an and then and because the business and
stuff I travel to sing for all the time
and I am and a buncha guys there reserve
at about the same point
as we are hoping the hackerspace the
other this Singapore hackerspace
open about two weeks before we opened
our space in Los Angeles
and so joined them as well just to
you know serve tied to communities
together but also have base reckon
working do anything there but as a not
in Singapore nearly as much time in Los
Angeles
I didn't want to take on any seeming
ministry roles that I do in Los Angeles
I don't vote on what color the carpet is
our worry about like
which which room the walkers get put in
in Singapore
whereas in Los Angeles take more sir
active role in
side lockers go
awesome next hour match also anybody's
been to the hardware hacking area
I really have to ask for special round
of applause for Mitch
and the also program
so bitch tell us a little bit
about Noisebridge for those of us who
are not
in the in the dough soon Noisebridge
gives me by my voice is goes away and
conferences and it's already happening
sorry but a me and Jake
started Noisebridge after going to chaos
camp
and Berlin if every if anyone has never
been to such a thing
go way out your way to go to camp 2011
coming up in August
totally amazing a bit at the camp 2007
does the talk go giving the design
patterns for starting your own
hackerspace in me and Jake
were both there from San Francisco and
knew that we were going to start a
hackerspace when we got home
along with them a brief from NYC
resistor an
Nick had BCE and love
we did it are that's all it took so
all hackerspace is start from you know
one or two are a handful of people just
doing it
and you start by creating a culture that
you want
the culture that mean Jake wanted was
the you know hippie freak up punk weirdo
anarchists kind of culture
so that's what we created and
it's grown from there as cultures are up
to do and it attracts more
the punk free weirdo anarchists and
I love it and some if anyone is a hippie
freak punko anarchist type
and once to visit Noisebridge
Noisebridge is totally open to anyone
always 24/7 if any of you out there are
thinking you might come to San Francisco
on one a key I have plenty of them I'll
give you one
and you don't have to be a member to
have a key um
we're open 24/7 so it's really no
problem if anyone comes in and no one
knows them
they're greeted when they come in and
people show them around and if any of
them start leaving with any of our stuff
people kinda say 'em
Heidi up that's our stuff
so we have one rule only one ruling we
have no leaders
the one rule is be excellent to another
it it actually works
because we have a culture that's grown
that we have enough overlap for this
very subjective concept of excellence
but it's up to all of us to perpetuate
our culture and help it grow its
you know it's a work in progress and our
so we tell people
when when we think each others being
excellent as well as when we think
people are not being excellent
walking out with stuff to excellent so
mom yeah that's that's kinda Noisebridge
were very very diverse very open
and there's anything from electronics
and craft and photography and music and
video
and food we have a full kitchen slowly
the
building a bathroom over the last year
are we have 50 to 100 square feet above
total chaos that is embraced with total
anarchy
and it's wonderful if you're ever in San
Francisco you should definitely come by
you are totally welcome
while sounds great I i cant wait to make
it to the
the second space to say oh I think I was
there actually something the first one
so you it seems like a lot of what
you're talking about people
encompassing the term radical inclusion
what do you think the really big
benefits that why should a space
open up itself to everybody and try to
be as inclusive as possible what sorts
of benefits do you get from that
that a more clothes Thacker space might
not experience
Golino um nose bridge design definitely
the extreme side of total openness and
that's not necessarily the correct
approach for all hackerspace is
on not every grouping of people might be
comfortable with that and if you're
thinking of starting a hackerspace you
should
create a culture that you are
comfortable with on the Noisebridge
mean Jake started it this way cuz that's
the culture we wanted to be a part of
so for us it works incredibly well
on hackerspace is just like hacker
conference is all about community
which they're so precious little in our
modern day world
and being together on the Internet if
you can call that together can be
really positive experience but being
together actually
in person like all of us are here is
total magic what can transpire just from
a a little
love quarter to body language can set
something of a new direction in life
and when you have a whole hackerspace
full of people doing this for one
another and sharing in growing
it's amazing and the more diverse the
better I think
%uh for people who fit in with the
culture so when we make ourselves
totally open
we invite Ian the world
I mean literally the world people from
all over the world they land in San
Francisco Airport near first stop is
taking the BART
the subway to the station a block and a
half away from us and they bring their
backpack and they're at Noisebridge
in the smiles on their faces are amazing
and what they share
is amazing in what they're learning from
all of us there
is amazing for them I mean everybody
wins as things ideally should be for all
the love life
so people of all ages as well
there's kids from middle schools and
high schools as well as college in all
the way on up to
a know people in the eighties people
learning and growing in sharing from one
another in all these ways
which is enhance the more open we r
spaces that are more clothes might be a
better for them because they're more
focused
um maybe not as a ver so they can go
further with certain topics I don't know
it depends on the grouping
um but for us having this brought
everyone welcome has
in love really on apps
fucking cool
awesome thanks much so max for those
that don't know tell us a little bit
about NYC resistor just give a brief
overview
so NYC resistor is a one the older
hacker spaces in this new generation %uh
vector spaces
kicked off after %uh Triple C um
basically two remembers George and Bri
fetus
up went with her Mitch out to Triple C
camp
which as he said before something you
should definitely go to I'm Ingenium
mention it to a harder last a
last summer and it was it was really
special it's amazing to go to either
amended so they came back they
immediately want to get the space going
and they kicked off in it it's been
around for two years
we are different from my nose bridge in
so much as be
set up in a way that's actually
relatively different from most of the
other hackers basis as earlier on the
scene
we decided being in New York where you
have you know space limitations we
wanted a small group of people
more for the meeting more for the
managing space
when we hit 30 people on our last base
our first building we ran out of shelf
space we ran outta
access people would come and it would be
places to said
um so we started with a exclusion
up rule which was things like boy for ex
boyfriends ex girlfriends can be in the
space
nights anyone can be to anyone else for
a legitimate reason usually
a we don't go after like the best
hardware hackers are the best offer
hackers
%uh we'd be like everyone it's just a
matter of sometimes he gets when it
comes in is
maybe a little crazy day a geometry and
a
they've had to take issue with the use a
triangles you know
this can happen there's some pretty
crazy people out there so a
we week went with the marks was very
role and we also
incorporated instead going in as a as a
5-on-3 see we thought it would be easier
and it has opened options for us that
otherwise would have been there
however you have ends up being wanna be
more strange
Packers basis although successful in our
own right
and so in with your sister just like
Noisebridge
move relatively recently into its second
Larcher
space what sorts of things do you think
people should embrace
as they're preparing to move perhaps for
their first read more incubator space
into a second larger space both in terms
up utilization the space and changing
patterns within the organization the
people as a whole
well especially in any situation like
this where we had been around for two
years we've had been doing really well
we all know each other pretty well at
this point you're bringing in people
you know cherry picking them and we had
a really good community established
that's kinda a problem as well as for
the great thing
the problem is is you don't wanna rock
the boat and in moving to a new space is
a real big change so there's a lot of
things to be afraid there
in my case I was afraid we'd all burned
to death a
we had a really great place that we
could want start fires on the floor
would really be a big problem our new
spaces like from the eighteen hundreds
and I was kinda concerned with
we'd all burned to death is things like
bricks on the outside but on the inside
its like another self
for every person is something different
that is Evans got concerns and big new
space bigger space means new members
different culture %uh that's culture
shock
its just a million different things like
to change
what you know if your space but have
been word
I it's been amazing actually we've got a
whole buncha members who were
all great marceca looking for even more
which is another huge benefit
on the new space is allowed us to do new
things but I think at this point
we've kind of taken last month or two
just to chill after doing like a
three or four months build-out new space
means doing a lot in new work
lay down your floors new CNC equipment
is brought in
you know new projects are kicking off
because we have all this extra space in
this opportunity
so lower Knauer we'll see
awesome and I think you actually made it
the whole way through a presentation
about a blatant row against somebody
oh we do excluder gingers for
I was waiting for that and then of
course we go right into a ginger
afar from High City 6 tell tales little
bit about them
Phillies hackerspace the awesome I'll
have 76 is in downtown Philadelphia
were on the fifth floor in arts building
so that means we're through with a lot
of people individuals to use from artist
both hobbyists and people who make their
living doing that on we'll
about 1300 square foot space and
about eighteen to twenty members are no
exactly how many
om so we've been around for about a year
a few of us
decided you know we he's
wanted space we want to build something
you want to do some cool stuff
so we ended up just getting a Lisa knows
about three of us and we went around
you know weaver hands in the air we set
up a wiki set up a word press
set up an email account love and then
just are gonna tell people hey you know
come build stuff come hang out to make
things annum
had an open house every Wednesday and
then just one by one
to buy two people search showing up in a
in make cool stuff happen
um so this is actually the second
hackerspace Philadelphia
that you've had the opportunity to to
build up a little bit
and then having been involved in the
formation process to hackerspace is
water some lessons from both
you know it not only in terms of the
building is agassi's but growing the
whole tech community
in philadelphia is a whole that you
think you would like to tell
you know yourself maybe two three years
ago when he started out on this journey
all I think the biggest one out of
myself is something actually learned
from starting to hackerspace and then
serve getting I'm sort on the fringes of
the startup community in philadelphia
and Philly has a really unique approach
where everyone realizes that it's not
us versus you its
Blake its collaboration idea its
collaboration set up and you have to
understand it
there's other people that are doing
similar things and in some ways you may
indeed be competing you may be looking
for the same members
it could be three spaces and your
friends can only for to be a member one
a which space to rejoin are but that
doesn't mean that you should Clarion
that doesn't mean that as a whole
ecosystem if not a better choice it's
far better to have two spaces in the
area
then have no space in the area arm in my
case there is better than
unfriendly forget first between couple
spaces
and after a few months sll me realize is
actually better because there's
different audiences the different
interests and as long as you know
group had decided re: things are cool us
relax
it was actually really nice step two
spaces because one gives you incentive
do some cool stuff
and you know to it serves different
audiences and it was actually record
highs I think
you know there's enough people in Philly
doing this to support all these
different add two spaces
that are you know really the similar
idea the idea is
let people do things encourage people to
learn give them the tools to do anything
and you know we have four different ones
that are slightly different you know
all around the area alright
um and then gym shoe here up next to us
a little bit about makers local 256
and I am from mayors local 256 and
Huntsville
Alabama we started and 2006 there is
about 10 of us meeting and
different people's apartments decided to
get a shop in 2000 8
where we grew to about 20 members and
then moved again in 2009
to a bigger place where about 2500
square feet now
workability donation based we don't have
a minimum
membership fee and everyone's welcome we
have open events things like that
we make on things like portable for both
women forge to classes
parties things like that
a.m. basically Huntsville's really kinda
unique in the fact that we have a big
tech community that's
so it brings what I've like-minded
together
cool and then because armored serve
leading the way in one area actor spaces
in the US you guys actually through
conference agassi is made up
com almost little you know that you're
gonna and you're doing it again
and this is actually exciting
announcement that pattern and programs
the panel so tell us a little bit about
the
like a space-based US arm sold last year
we
decided that wanna see what would happen
how to create a budget hackers faces
together to
you know talk about things at work on
projects and and
October of last year we had about 500
spaces come down to
are our space on which kinda you know
threw a party with a big cookout
everything
and I'm just can announce talked about
things did a
did some panel discussion things like
that and so this year
and November 12 to 14 really doing it
again
on whichever hotel set up and maybe even
some
some camping is if you as my campaign on
so
her on we do have a space & Rocket
Center City Kan
stop by that also %ah the me more
information up on makers local .org
of course like hackers we are we don't
do things the last minute or something
up there yet but
it'll be up there soon awesome
okay and then um Alex from hack Miami
to deliver at Miami a going we are just
are meeting around the
around August 2008 right after the into
the last hope
on we are coordinated through the
hackerspace is that our website
and we start meeting at Florida
International University
arm we became very comfortable with
their facilities therefore up for about
a year
on they had a near pretty much
everything you need to
to give were weekly schedule talks and
we stardom
scheduling talks every two weeks and
promoting them heavily through with very
social networks Facebook Twitter
on the jet Google Groups and that's
primarily our building
people coming out we had about twenty 20
weeks have about 20 to 25 regulars who
come out
on and then about them we officially
became a incorporated non-profit
arm and February 2009 and then earlier
at the end
earlier this year we are hosting the
hacking terrorist networks talk
and arm a.m. from what from what I heard
I guess some people from
in for guard were interested in the talk
and they wanted to come out so they are
the they they gave a call FIU to find
out arm
exactly what the details were in all
assign FAA is likely hackers
terrorist some FBI thing get out at the
school
and obsolete quickly had to find another
space and
we we had a warehouse that was on
donated to us and we're able to
really use this the second floor it but
we're in the process of getting
electricity
into the warehouse so in there in the
meantime
wearing that we're in a transitional
phase where where where we are
a a pizza restaurant that has a
that's a very it's it's a good setup
though they have a very big Tom screen
stage a nice projector a whole buncha
tables
and really expensive beer and good pizza
and arm
we've meet there every two Saturdays and
we get a we get it
a decent crowd 20-25 people come out
regularly and on were
we're looking to hopefully get
everything finalized by the fall for
warehouse where we can actually have
go and have a permit space there so
that's a pretty unique story
going from meeting space to getting a
warehouse donated put electricity it
um well I'm glad I didn't have to go
through that and and helping
get back to see going what sorts have
lessons are coming out at that sort of
growing experience this
having a persevered through all those
various different steps
all we we definitely learned that on
social networking
is i'd definitely help because we we
found our space through facebook
comedian the
we found our the pizza the pizza place
to Facebook when we
didn't have any place to to go through
so jazmine
maintaining good contacts on social
networking sites within
love people within the local area you
you can search out on
they don't wear our primary focus is a
hacking in information security so we
just search people with those interests
on Twitter and Facebook
start adding them a majority them with
would follow us back
and arm and would start and began start
participating
and arm from an organizational
standpoint home we
did have a bit we did have a bit of
trouble arm initially after incorporated
citing on
deciding on bylaws and exactly what type
of a nonprofit structure is going to
have was gonna be a member-driven not
structure
a nonprofit structure a border nonprofit
structure and Om
initially we decided to go with the
boardroom a nonprofit structure where we
have just a few board members are kinda
direct the administrative affairs and
and everyone else's
would be considered a a volunteer that
and they pretty much
guide the direction the the space in the
talks the
no the the actual projects going on
where's the board is kinda
focusing on getting electricity in the
warehouse
rock on and then rounding outs for the
group a schedule panelists i tech for
alpha one let's talk a little bit about
New York's I guess seconds big
hackerspace
sure alpha-1 labs start out
here though was
my original inspiration for starting a
lab was
and all these inventions inventor and
engineer
and I had this invention night but I was
gonna take millions of dollars
may collapse you know with all these
women and I'm
two years ago there the hackerspace is
talk here hope
and they went through all the design
patterns
and I learned a lot from that and one
day I'd
call then money expects that or call in
and they're discussing few issues are
going on through the hackers bases such
as
getting her spaces a.m. stuff like that
and I thought well let me just put this
all together
and start something and we decide to
phone was rich I heard they had a
remembers a time I was like wow that's
awesome
so we took on a radically inclusive
method
and we try to keep the place safe and
clean for all ages
make it easy for people to sign a which
has been a minute major factor in our
growth
we have taken on the duo Chris the
method nose bridge where the more you do
the more infants you have in space
and during our meetings on Tuesday at 7
p.m.
we'll go around for six minutes getting
updates pretty much similar to this kind
where everyone has a voice to direction
for space
on for a move we actually sort out a
small space paying for a last month for
rounds
and this caused by an thats that give us
a could boost
to get going an hour in a six in a
square foot place
and we found during the move that the
most important thing to do is
but tougher right away get things
organized
and help us with our medical spaces that
consume we've all been proven
its from so is going better and for
today whenever sunrise party in the hope
everyone can make it
yep as a reason the fire system
recordings
they're they're up there homie have some
here come up get them
after talks over cuz cuz such action
bring those fires pretty hard for
perhaps present at
just a quick show fans who is received
or seen one at some point the conference
okay good I knew the Reach is bigger
than that
okay cool so wow we got to the schedule
pen was pretty quickly
and then we have one special guest star
choice from heat see clouds
um tell us a little bit about your
unique setup an approach
forum building your hackerspace there's
a hundred
a Johannes your highnesses extra extra
special
guess surprise start the ferry and
and plus he's also the end because he's
gonna wake everybody up with this
ridiculous Austrian antics but
but that not true that so much joy
stress please tell us about
heatsink labs hi I'm from Phoenix
Arizona
and are hyper space is called heatsink
labs I'm so we're a little bit different
a couple were founders got together and
they got excited about this idea
hackerspace and I'm so were based on
this place called gangplank which is a
collaborative
started incubator which they feel like
we have a lot offered to them so they're
offering us free space
there so are based on their we have a
rep wrapping your space project
and a lot of other people working on
different different projects
I public meetings are held twice twice a
month and then
members can come in and use our our
resources
also we hold an Arduino night every
every month to get people excited line
who don't know about crime aren't
for cool in and you're at it
during a unique space how how does he
sing connect
with the community around its like a
starter
talked a little bit about that the take
place if you think thats has its
neighbors
okay so I guess is a big eyes on mine
owner
hyperspace in 0 kind of like startups in
fact that
you are trying to run business but your
hollinger never
you never ever going to get rich I'm so
it does take a lot of work
and you get me to hold a lot of fund
raisers so that have the money to buy
the equipment you wanna get
so we hold a lot of administrative
meetings to trying
raise money for to to be able to
purchase things like a laser cutter
and how these resources that people want
to come in and
collaborate and work on
alright cool and we're doing really
really well on time so Johannes
don't screw it up tell us about how bus
.at and your extra-special announcers
gather it's allowed so know my name is
Johanna some part of monochrome
and I'm the only member of the panel who
cannot wake under the table
and not BC
so hacer just like a year ago
we had monochrome and/or but Vienna we
were thinking
there is a space in Vienna its really
awesome I member of its medal at
but we have to have a certain form of
mobility
and that say if the hackerspace is
to an embassy we need a
X certain form of like people going out
there like ambassadors
to spread the information the main
problem is
for we can be very honest about that
there will never be a hack space double
penetration
montana okay so there so many spaces out
there
that nobody gives a shit about but
they're still interesting places because
there are people out there
so for example a year ago we started
packed bus
in Austria help us .at and we finally
got a bus
we got it working and in June we toured
through Vienna just yen not going
outside be started in Vienna
and first the of June 21st district
second day of June 22nd district
up until like the 23rd district in
Vienna
and every day we had between thirty and
250 people
coming to us checking of whatever doing
DIY workshops
building like basic stuff like let's
throw aways whatever okay
and reached more people then be
belief that we could reach and most of
those people would never ever
set foot in a hackerspace so the basic
idea is
and it's an old ideas so many had buses
out there
especially in the United States you know
you know you've cheap fuel
more in a Anna so
the basic idea now is other various
hackerspace s dollar and today it's an
official announcement
a it's a quote from year we want to
start help us start in four
which is a community site for all the
heck buses
and mobile hack a spaces out there
so please go to help us thought info on
and registered a bus if you have one and
I know what I talked to so many people
here at Hope
yet couple of more by the heck spaces
and hike because out there
and the basic idea is it's a long
there's a long tradition of hex base
a mobile hex basis and help the cause
and help us this
and it's a real important tool to self
empower people these units a
should be everywhere you should start
one yourself you don't have friends
for done it yet a please go to our site
at your bus if you have one or check out
would be we do
it's a pretty plain virgin kinda side
right now because I just put it online
you know like twenty-five minutes ago so
for
you can be there from the start help us
start info
and I hope you'll join the movement and
good luck with that and I hope that the
help us movement can support
the hackerspace is movement yep also
Gigabit Router across the panelists
and the second round of applause because
this gigantic panel made it in under
forty five minutes agendas
ever been done attacker on ever
okay so now I'm sure you guys have a lot
of questions that have not
I'm going to throw them out the panel
and as well I'm also going to be
going to the website so I promised on
the panel said I would be visiting the
websites that their hackerspace is they
came up during the course the
presentation
now the slides are done I feel
comfortable enough that if somebody
mess the wireless I don't do it it's
it's still okay so we have
our first question and when you ask
questions you got a microphone up front
and a microphone it back please line up
and we'll try to get the questions as
quickly as possible and
I M absolutely encouraging a discussion
here there's something that
somebody asking a question strikes
a need to respond in you go up to the
microphone and
and speaker voice not be alternating
between the one up front and on the back
so
introduce yourself real quickly speaker
and microphone and 3 a question at the
Palace you wanna answer it
I'm from Calgary with the XP since been
open for
per year and I wanted to know how
other groups are handling collaborative
projects
are the approach that we've basically
taken is everybody goes off
and does it themselves up until certain
phase
and then we look at what different
people have working
and Trent Cole s it over there but arm
since we've never actually finished a
project at this point I be interested in
seeing
you know what your experiences are with
us %uh things that take this one from
the Middle up
we do it this way up
really most of these projects go like
you said someone has an idea
implemented and them up people cider
come in and ask around watch they're
doing and will join in
eventually but a.m. many project
actually a come
together cook in a collaborative way
thanks to our lunch face so
um if you're about to have a smoke
assume
um should try
having one and I'm a non-smoker
and I'm actually opposed to how we
handle this
in some ways but this has been an
incredible
source of projects and source of
discussion
for us those been to startups
no three start-ups up found that
in that room in four years and just a
footnote that
will also remember that the med lab
isn't Austria where'd
they have a smoking machine every three
feet on the street just like in New York
they have ATM every three you can buy
cigarettes
in just as many places and the end as
you can get cash New York City's
remember that about the smoking like
that
then from based insisted
written I don't maybe you can see
something as an alternative to the
smoking room
get in line and tell us what it is I'm
but did any other panelists wanna take
on the clutter projects question
for yeah arm behind his condition I'll
most people
are most of our products are from one
person's passion and someone comes and
says
I really want to do this check this out
I something going and a lot of times the
first time you again it's very close can
also show your
and by about the second and third time
somebody shows up to meeting with this
great project
it just people are attracted to that you
know like fruit flies on
Annapolis been to New York for a week
and just you know you see something
passion about something
and you really want to help them out you
really wanna see sexy succeed
especially if you have skills that you
can help them with or they're learning
you can help along
arm and we do have our share projects
where they get
you know authored a way through and
people like okay cool that was funny
when I want to learn they don't wrap-up
but almost four projects are really
there sir passion driven by different
individuals
and %uh they bring to the group and then
they you know pull collaborators from
from the group eldest
at footnote Noisebridge being the
anarchist on
weirdo and all that stuff kinda myspace
um
its when someone is passionate about
something it doesn't necessarily mean
that other people will be but if people
are passionate about it then it does
become collaborative and that's those
are projects that move forward
and ones where other person is just one
person may be the disc off on their own
and there's no collaboration
bomb or maybe just kind of falls by the
wayside in favor something else
and a with within our culture people to
think
except that is OK because there's so
many so many creative people doing so
many creative things
is always something %uh that people
confuse yes to get behind
and against my better judgment
but I did promise that good alternate
the Mikes Irish what's your question
so mister far do you really have a posse
hook
this I'm actually glad that their reach
if that showcase gotten
so little that it gets that little bit
at the lapin a Friday night
and and I'm gonna let
open flight role on this one just to
wake people up so
I mitnick bar at a begun three hi I
remember the exact not this story
I Moreno I'm serious he was the
organizer that conference
and a wonder because actually ended with
police dog sniffing everyone leaving
but a to give you an idea of how much a
posse
as the first night that I've we ran into
him his his posse was carting another
hotel with a blood-alcohol content that
probably exceeded ethanol I'll so
yes Nick far does indeed have a posse
he's still here today because it
next question
lil yeah so my question is initially
for far by if anybody else has anything
about it
are you talking about the different
the spaces been in your area
and I was wondering what the differences
are that drive people to go to the
individual spaces geography thing or is
it the
more operational differences like save
difference between
you know Noisebridge n/a more restricted
space or something like that
what drives that are mostly thing that
drives the different communities
is a different needs a different desire
from the people involved are
a little bit its geography which is like
head on a drive three hours
but most of it is am i'm looking for.
just sure our
million for are in really great
technology up some people they don't
want to be involved in a week to week
basis and there's actually really great
make
group called make Philly and it's a once
a month me for two hours
and there's a you know that that crude
really they don't want to be involved in
Akers base they don't wanna buildings
every week
they don't happy the need to pay to be a
member of a space that they use for two
hours a month
but for something like me Philly on you
know that's a perfect fit
and so we've done up actually creates
jobs very different gene yourselves
and understanding like how the different
groups you know if there's somebody who
really wants to start up a sale uk
come the hive you like our style stick
with it but we also have cordoned spaces
and here they are and you know they do
the same for us so
um New York's kinda interesting in so
far as we have so many different groups
alpha-1 labs a NYC resistor there's
there's other groups %uh
Madagascar Institute right near us the
book smart welding there's been other
groups that focus on
biking we have a ATP we have Polytechnic
University we have
a million different subgroups academic
are technology
office around all do normal things got
twenty million people in
a very small location so each animal
individual spaces defined by
quarter as her anything you know smoker
people get together and find that space
is so they're going to find it to be
what they think is the optimal design
pattern and
I guess I result in us having a bunch of
different spaces so
offensive question
and three into the back yeah I guess my
question would be
up for grabs arm high Kingdom is a
pretty homogeneous even
there's a whole lotta why the white
dudes that are predominantly straight
are yet hackerspace is to find
themselves as
community centered and open
so there seems to be a disconnection
between the two I'm just wondering if
you folks
identify that as a challenge arm first
the mall
maybe you don't see it as a challenge
but if you do how have you just that in
the context of your space
Noisebridge was started by two queers
so um
and a so I like being part of a diverse
community san Francisco's a very diverse
place
a.m. but the still its predominantly
white
there's Asian people love you know
Indian subcontinent included
people from Pacific Islands and arm
people from Europe whatever but now
predominantly wat
predominately middle and upper-class arm
and its majority mail but we're doing
pretty good as far as female
11 when I was treasurer keeping track of
all the membership it was forty percent
female
I watched pretty good so thing is um
we don't live in an ideal world and
what we're doing is creating not
necessarily an ideal world but an ideal
%uh aiming towards an ideal for the
world we want to live in
locally %uh leases as I see it and
inserting Noisebridge
so I want to attract all sorts of people
right now there's more females at MIT
than males
little bit I it's because younger people
growing up it just doesn't matter
with her before doing electronics was a
boy game only in now to grow game girls
were discouraged
when I was a teacher and electronics I
had for four and a half years of
teaching
three females in all of my classes put
together
arm so doing sort of our own minor
affirmative action kinda thing creating
stuff that in the past was predominantly
girl games
to bring people love not just the
youngest people were just doesn't matter
anymore but people
love 'em you know twenties for use on up
are getting more crafting things which
is prevent predominantly a growing make
love making sure that we had a lot of
activities like that
attracted more people who are female %uh
my you know Noisebridge has people
love in determine gender %uh and
we encourage that to %um I'll we make
sure that
we have holy zero-tolerance love
homophobia and sexism and all these kind
of things
um that is not excellent file
from we want to have a a safe space for
everyone and whatever people want to
teach
known again you not to be a member to do
anything in his budget but remember to
take classes or even to give classes so
were always out
up being ambassadors in the community
the in San Francisco and everywhere we
go
say hey we got the space you know you do
some pretty cool you wanna
teach a class there and if there are
other people who want to take it then it
takes off
and you know if it doesn't cause by the
wayside makes room for something else
but as a result of that we've gone we
diverse kind classes that attract all
sorts of different people
not just middle and upper class which is
the predominant thing but
since oliver stuff is free attract
people who don't have money to do just
funny thing but here's a cool space
where they can find community and
therefore it attracts them
and they bring the friends tracks more
so that's how you handle that
I you honestly want to respond to this
week but let's keep it quickly sink as
many questions as possible
just very quickly I mean yes I a I was
to go with my friend Frank a just like a
year ago something like that be
published
a small rand let's call it or like him I
don't like a paper on where we
we must said page we have to hack our
own tax basis because there's so many
spaces out there what is not a single
female member
or where like Germany for example
there's some tax bases
a in predominantly let's see Turkish
neighborhoods
because it's cheaper live there but
there's not a single Turkish member in
the heck space
I did so predominantly by et cetera et
cetera et cetera so there has to be
definitely some former outreach and this
outreach can be
either the old way of liked just like
talking to people
for I mean 50 percent of the population
for talk to them okay for
your and it works pretty well
a sometimes it scares them away but okay
your and thats I guess why
today we wanted two large double the
heck help us to infer sites because
that's a different approach to attract
people
for Mike in no way be interested in
hiking but
the have probably interested in like
tinkering around the doing cool stuff
people just like not call the packing a
whatever
so I think there has to be a fire
wider outreach projects for hackerspace
ok getting a good can
winning actually and this is beyond did
everything I don't hear community when
you're
when you're talking in your meaning your
offense think about that you say you
can't a
applications and electroluminescent
semiconductors are you can say build
your only after
and there this team subject matter and
you get way more
the second one and you can teach them
all about diode
to go in one way you know oh you know
there are two types have
material and what it's like sends like
turns out when
track n you can just you can cover the
same material you can get to galleon
doping you can get all that stuff
eventually
the redline have to be something
appealing like
through the internets as a busty like
electroluminescent semiconductors case
%um allotted was room get excited about
the first one
but if you want to bring in people who
are scared
honestly I think it's harder than it is
cuz honestly LED's are not rocket
scientists
like they're not like they're not hard I
and felt like making sure that your
language
is it is it the barrier
and I think I just wanted to choice do
you have anything to say about this and
also I i
promised you that output it's a class
website up on the screen and I did so
wanna make sure he sought
I but give a any kind of response to the
question diversity in her car spaces
I think just
as the female hyperspace community it
people are like females that definitely
are interested
but it's not a question on whether or
not way we can do this because there's
not a female engineers out there just
gotta
just like anybody on just tell them
about it
so that's what we're trying to do
cool back up front but
area um so have a question for the panel
in general
I know some guys have a love diversity
for your hackerspace is
werner said all you guys have two things
in common one you're located in a major
city into your lease near space
how do you feel about quitting
hackerspace in a rural community its
viability
and also using a member's house
its practicality for all the members
think as far as location it doesn't
necessarily bike
their major cities because that's where
there's a community-supported but that I
don't think that that's
necessity that have been a city that
this has to be a community supports
itself
if you have 10 people her if you decide
that it takes ten people to run a space
in your rural area
so the if you have the people the sport
it doesn't matter where it is
you know you could have one in in the
middle of nowhere if everybody in that
area was into it you know so
location is a matter for not everyone
just enough people rate yet uncertain
about but I mean if there's like on the
three people
and Mike 50 square miles you know and
all three those people are into it and
run with it
just through this one out the audience
how many people here are
members over /url hackerspace are trying
to start a rural hackerspace
okay week
okay going to get and how but I
I forgive me forget forget my and I
don't know what the word is right now
the top my time but
how many people are trying to start a
hackerspace not in a gigantic
goblets for crime and disease okay so
so few more than that's good and anyone
else in the pen want to pick up the
question for
yeah I actually serve the housing
cooperative in Rochester New York
because I concert a hackerspace
arm basically I found this group people
like hey we're crazy fun people who
wanna live together my counter workshop
and i ended up putting the workshop in
the basement and then since they were
cooking food in
rebuilding the house and doing awesome
stuff i jus got involved in that
so I think your things that hackerspace
doesn't have to be
I mean it doesn't have to be just like
stand-alone thing being in somebody's
garage
being in you know a business who says
you are you guys really awesome will
open our doors you know
Friday's you can come in userspace like
you know there's there's a lot of
flexibility people can have
and you know after you know you have to
start all over you can find a group
that's kinda somewhere has the same
values
and and work with them also the person
who owns the space has to be
really email does so there's the
hackerspace design patterns 10 the
patterns is
about sense of propriety of ownership so
if from one of the members is
a landlord um even if it's an incredibly
mellow cool person
some their priorities a
well might take priority over what for
rest for the membership the hackerspace
might be so there might be potential
conflict it doesn't mean that
up it can't be resolved but there is a a
lot I've
mmm situations that are right for
conflict in there
are so the design patterns are rules
their patterns for what is worth and not
work in a quarter-century of hackers
bases in germany
so there's a lot of experience behind it
but there are many hackers bases that
exist that violate
these patterns but to do so you should
do so consciously
I if the only barrier to starting the
spaces you can find one but this
person's offering you the garage
why would you not do that how is your
like Great Bear
like having a hackerspace is better than
not having acker space so if
if that's the only thing but britain
know that going into into something
where
rates at somebody's house or something
like that brings with it a whole bunch
of other problems that you wouldn't
necessarily have to us
starting from scratch someplace else
Alex even jumping in the car
you know it when it that's what were the
issues that's why the issues that we
weren't we're dealing with this arm
where it actually have a space in if
you're trying to start one up
i'm looking to the your local
universities your code
on community colleges libraries those
are a public facilities and if
if you're able to become a nonprofit
organization which
without the 501 C three stuff just the
nonprofit in your state
arm you'll be able to get free access to
that just you
I guess don't have weird law enforcement
subgroup scholar school about
acting terrorist networks and you'll be
okay but up for a vague for the most
part
from take advantage a public facilities
and also reaching out to local
businesses because they've been more
than helpful with us
a we're gonna throw it back up to the
back right
good evening I'm curious how much
entrepreneurship there is and the
hyperspace is and whether
that causes any problems a.m.
actually a we have a rather large and
successful business that's a
been growing out over space for about a
year and a half I guess now
a it started out in this extension of
the repre- projects one of our founding
members eyes ako can
was about the beat research guy word
wrap up foundation
one other members in the audience today
is actually one of the founders of
what's called maker bot industries
and maker bot started out inside NYC
resistor using NYC resistor
resources most notably our laser cutter
um
in the early days it was a huge problem
but a as they became more and more
successful and start growing
and demand for their %uh their printers
grew a
in our little space we suddenly had a
large amount of wood piling up in our
wood room
and said that suddenly they had interns
overrunning the laser 24/7
so the over the years I guess
they ended up buying their own space
moving their own without their star in
their own stuff and
eventually carting some of their larger
amount above
laser cutting out to outside vendors
but for a little while they're there was
definitely some a some issues
popping up where you know members can
get access a laser cats are waiting for
to our run the finish
and then just as I finish want their
interns with you know stake in their
quickly replaced with another two hour
run in it
it definitely I got on people's nerves
and was a
definitely an issue um it to get to the
point where I think people are starting
to you know
really draw some concern but in the end
I think a when they finally did you know
get their own facilities a it quick you
know it quickly went away as a problem
in our in the same building as they are
they actually found a new space for us
so that ended up being a great thing for
us and I relationship has never been
better
there great guys and they're still
members so we have
we have so how that from on other
perspective
is that we have a member who started a
company and
and had a bunch of a quarter I guess
the fact that he became a member and had
a space to put it was an excuse for him
to go get a bunch of equipment so he
wasn't coming into use our equipment
he brought a mountain equipment with him
that then
buttress the space can use as well as
sort of like his contribution to it
yeah I have to agree a make about stuff
like attributed large amount of
equipment
resources even technology in just
expertise in visitors
I'd choices here and is absurd incubator
do you think that on trip certain
influences your spaced it does that have
an impact you think
it's kind of interesting because um
their
45 other companies in the space that
we're working on and
they're starting up their own businesses
in we also have an aunt here
in our group who is hosting the servers
for
hitting clubs so um will collaborate I
think we
bring something to game-playing which is
where we work
and then they bring something for us
which is free space
and make sure to wrap it up yeah so um
I make a living off a my personal
project that became popular
and Noisebridge and everywhere I go I
encourage people to quit their jobs that
they don't like
and in favor of doing something you know
making time to explore
what you love if you find yourself in a
position where you're doing something
you don't love
arm you know when you wanna quit your
job you'll see me but to add Noisebridge
I A R I do this lot and
many people at Noisebridge now use nose
bridge as one of the resources
for their own kit business or a
using computers there with sorta like a
coworking space for people can
be in community while doing their work
and this has not been a problem at all
at Noisebridge we have 50 to 100 square
feet we've not grown at this point
so um I see hackers bases as a way above
all a bus freeing ourselves from the
yoke of cubicles living
okay next question
its the people at their actress case
love and miss you remember me
away Vienna you know constant Iran
hun I mean our I
the guy who hit the tech museum a
regular talk
yeah at that stage for say hi okay to
challenge is this
come to at one o'clock in morse room
tomorrow
I'm gonna put on a challenge to anybody
wants to work with me on this
idea now said dispute 1 o'clock
at the at the Morse room
thank you mister crunch and in back
for civil I had a our solution for the
smoking room was
which is built an arcade but a couple
really comfy couches it works pretty
good
so cover no drinking no smoking earlier
but arm
like mostly those stories I've heard
when we started off
we had a big meeting a bunch before
excited and
then over who's gonna be this position
is going to this and other rules came in
and
most people like we're done so just two
of us
brand started problem is we do need
people to do the treasure role when
manage all that stuff so I guess we're
not quite like North Noisebridge were
not
completely you know free love but we're
we don't really have a rule structure
you know latter
members and all that stuff seekers any
suggestions for trying to keep that
simple in nature gets done by EOD
not you know regimental
chrome to join
%ah
do when you're starting at be prepared
to roll up your sleeves de la Torre
yourself and
I'm hire me have
I you know I'm a man aged 83 funny but
it's really
I I think we try it we're trying to
harass you suppose to use like you
suppose
yes it's a pity that we're trying to get
it as low infrastructure as possible
at my be in town for three weeks is
probably get
make skated there is coming into town
will allow an act
what if things were trying is all I
getting things done on little no cars
and about to board
and stuff like that also you know be a
lower rate is
and I like what really has to get done
like if you're paying your rent and
you're paying your insurance and you're
being the things that need to get paid
I'm if the membership if you're really
open and inclusive and a membership if
they wanted to make it happen
he could be really clear like that it is
for the weak economy
organization where you know you're not
telling them what they can or cannot do
with a space but we've got some great
memories when this started radio Monday
he was really interested in all things
like ham radio or WiFi
or Xbox until he started radio mandated
aspiration he just started
I another member wanted to have a
handmade music night he didn't have
permission is like
basically I wanna do this let's begin a
I mean anything and making sure that
that posture
the people who are in charge even if
they're
they're not in charge they're just
getting it is getting get shit done
and if you a showdown and you could do
better than them you do it
and so making sure it like that posture
like
is clear that y'all trying to reach your
dog a screenplay
and no one is more important less
important but you know the do %ah crispy
on and just if you want to see something
happen make it happen
effing one exam I think the year the
fact that the
the members being interested in me
happen is important
because there is a bunch is definitely
opened up they're like oh this would be
this would be good for hackers