discussion that the command module a
service model the Polish spacecraft did
not fly
has 105 Boozer the Saturn 5 booster had
its own independent computer system
I was developed by IBM nobody talks that
because it is a very boring
conservatives
you know traditional am computer but
it was the one that was in charge of
getting Saturn 5
aligned till pitch roll although I kinda
good stuff so we get into orbit so when
you hear people talking about
%uh the command module is dead they
worry that was command much a crippled
the problem how the problem was that the
Saturn 5 am
computer was perfectly happy going to
orbit it didn't care if there was a big
paperweight on the top
the rocket it was going to orbit and so
that was the issue as well
do we stay for the ride am so Apollo 12
now was see the second
and moon landing and it had a fairly
veteran I started something kinda we're
have to it so this is this is the crown
to her transmission and this is what the
world her if you're listening in on nasa
channel this is the chat back between
the astronauts look at the Public
Affairs officials
you'll hear the am the Capcom who is the
only person on the ground who is about
to talk to the
astronauts I also hear some my ring at
certain point because I believe this
tapers from the honeysuckle Creek in
Australia where
ass with the engineers actually work
speed improvement on the mic picked up
to sound sorts
play this this whole incident only talk
about 23 minutes
thaaaat throw-in
favorite reporter or Thor
file
for ask for a second for a hard worker
yeah 592
for ass ass
for crack cocaine fact or crap
what happened here we get a hacer
proctor perform
fast
the
how hard rockers ferry over
for yeah
car
recovery 3 for Park
Charlie the pre-match go on to orbit and
after that and this goes on
they do some clean-up get a successful
staging sorry
well yeah terms with the confusion so
so that's what you heard you had a long
silence
pass people and this is however this is
a ground loop conversation so
is a little harder to make up the OU
because we're listening to is an overlay
up the ass not stocking you also
listening out for
the flight director talking to e.com
and the e-commerce a mission control in
charge of the environmental
and I he electronic environmental an
problems one point is also charged
communications but I'm a separate app to
cap the name same
and you sure kentucky come in most
importantly
you hear him talking a little bit his
backroom boys
and so the way mission control
structures you see that very classic in
all the guys in front of their
raise the council's each one of those if
you were to go out the door and turn
right
there many many other rooms remind had
CF
dei comes in is his counsel and hit
three or four guys who also had very
similar councils looking at very
specific subsystems
after times they were Chatham cells on
the loop before they would maybe
go back to talk to fly tractors a is a
little bit angled and but I think you'll
get
you'll get the sense for the world
so this this is this the the actual
transcripts from that
finish controllers face process thanks I
Asmar
fish ass ass
ass
thanks fast far
yeah fast
I got thaaaat like ass the
FAA for I don't know if johnnie feet of
say can't yeah of thingy to of
5 s C-dot kept out cellmark out here
said try a half
free a few of carry-over three
freehoff for cutbacks
50 fast and that's it
faces a mission am so what is happening
there was
laws the magic switch sc2 Fox
very clearly that wasn't common command
and now we really knew what it was but
but a couple things when on here one
defy controller
and it was a guy called them so 70 S E
1st so the SE is a p/e is what's known
as a signal conditioning
equipment and the Apollo missions were
very heavily instrumented
and a lot of problems they had to redo
to instrumentation problems but you get
all the signals you know from that
heater palm frond radar all these
instruments come through
they all have to be am normalized into a
standard range voltages says one they
can be displayed
inside the cockpit and to see that can
be sent back down
the radio feed am so what happened last
that when a lightning strike happened
all those fuel cells in the service
models I mentioned
at checked off and so the the
command the command module is drawing
power from a couple batteries
there are really only meant for reentry
and their emergency situations and if
you read the polls 13-story became all
about
an section of attacking became very much
in managing
those patch users but the problem is
that when I went to those batteries
divulges dropped below the SC normally
use
and there's little switch down how
that switching to exit a remote which
was not in the procedures it was kinda
their
holmes is a legacy issue from from tram
from how he built equipment
and that said whatever kinda crappy she
devoted you have gold
and and when they did that they got back
to name a tree
also that displays began you reading
meaningful results they could see
not that they have the entire command
module mounting down but that they had
3 disconnected fuel cells am so the man
who made that call the who recognized
the SE problem with this guy called John
Arran and he's also very important in
apollo thirteen in different ways
but at the time this incident made him
like the original steely eyed
missile and the reason he was able to
recognize that collin nobody else
could've made was because a yearly
earlier and a Pap test
he had seen this result and that's a
test guy had made a mistake of the
command module
the SEO thinking at these screwy
readings he knew they were screwy
readings because he owed
DBS certain piece of equipment that only
day he knew would only operate between
twelve and twenty eight full-service
reporting six-foot
was very distinct pattern scrimmage has
like you know sometimes if you look at
your
you get a blue screen of death and
actually and all those numbers appear
he was a guy actually look at those
numbers and realize exactly
what they meant am so in a sense you
might think well this is
of the lucky and really really was lucky
but it does speak to the culture
of Mission Control at time where these
guys went through every system
under said systems they were deeply
involved in developing operations from
there
deeply involved in talks with the
engineers who built them neon D-day
each with his car had man's death a
technical matters built up over years in
simulations
and the notice when he actually made the
call for sake checks
backroom guises do you think it's the SE
they don't know what the hell is
and he comes back and says flight
instantly flight try as he hugs ily
he has confidence to me to call the heat
but he thinks he sees
is when he sees I spoke to gene krantz
about this about how you take
this flight controllers men in their 20s
right on to college
how you get a guy to that particular
point we can make that call
this is well it took about a year to 18
months to make a flight controller you
start them off
gathering information do very simple
task adding information manufactures
helping the flight controllers built and
procedures isn't Asian
and you put them through simulation for
simulation simulation
and the thing that would wipe out flight
controller was that they wouldn't have
that level of confidence
required a certain level arrogance and
require certain level just go for it
and John armoires possibly pick me aback
really understand all the systems and he
has unshakable confidence
and later on again it's nice but how 13
we'll be talking about he developed
devices para sequence
at the Astros hat entry and without
inner-city are they had to turn off the
instrumentation
i would tell them if they're making
steaks or not see happen radio up this
checklist
in which the Astros hat entrant
perfectly first time after being awake
for days with me
your tract infection and he made a call
he had no problem with that at the time
years later an older man limb more
reflective
he still has nightmares bash because of
how risky
tax procedure am but at the time you
know
you need these cokie eyes who work
confident but not overconfident
so that was John R do you think I should
say that was soon as he made the call
notice how the flight controller who is
no idea what what's going on
goes well okay john and he tells the
Capcom I get synced up they had trust
they believed it really trained each
other
they rely on each other that's an
engineering culture
that is prime for success increase lean
years nasa pending trades
you know culture issues but anybody
who's involved in high-risk high-tech
enterprise concern
what these guys it so Paul 13 which is a
very famous
all kinds attacks in apollo thirteen
answer famous one there
pains get a carbon dioxide filters with
choc am recharging the command module
from the batteries now I'm
to meet all seen the movie am that
actual thing
of recharge T module from the command
module
to Mamata from the lunar module I was
actually something that was
had to have been working on for several
months previously am
ezel image before scriptures again be
thinking about that for some time
even the Mersey activation checklist
they already had a kind of a dummy
situation for these are all great pretty
good hacks and actually the carbon
dioxide filter issue again they had
then maybe twenty four hours to work on
that was never the ass just never really
broke a sweat about that
cousin you people working on the new
solution the actual kinda bit late in
the day
money put it together has had other
things on her mind thought this was a
lower priority I
all those richter him good hacks hacker
really wanna talk about this is among
his interview on
was turning me on to mind first place
I'm not talking about the activation
checklist which is
you know we turn on this benefit in the
sequence in again no your platform
lined up the simple act up during the
Lunar Module
from again a paperweight into a
functioning spaceship
requires power there is no way to turn
the lunar module
on when the Apollo 13's fuel cells
explode actually the auction tank
exploded
knocked off the fuel cells and
what happened at mission last apollo
thirteen service module
there was an axe there's an explosion
action tank fuel cells died
very quickly the command module was
running on those reserves backup
batteries
parallel systems couldn't do that and
they had a ready search shutting down
systems am in the command module
to the command marge was very little
power and mister to have this
for huge knock-on problem for the Lunar
Module the reason is this
so these are the lunar module activation
checklist
am I got this wrong with anybody really
cares that their module
there's the cradle aviation up on Long
Island has the Roman
archive so if you wanted to build your
own your module
most if it is in there and you can go up
in you can go to Emanuel's
this actually can also get online so
this is the official activation
checklist which
again was cut down very much shortened
but notice the first
assumption made the CSM has initiated
para transferir
be a docking tunnel actual umbilicals so
the very first assumption is now invalid
you could not perceive it anything on
the checklist because there is a false
assumption
the reason for that loss this simple
sketch
and actually the full version of things
as axis on this came on like three
gatefold the full version that is this
the overview the full detailed version
is
really be on beyond belief but so it's
divided to three parts you remember
the lunar module had the same stage
Sen stage on top and then it was
attached the command module for most
chip most check it was docked an to the
command module
so the descent stage in a bottle had
great big batteries lovely back trees
pollens what's up our
happily under marshal in order to get
those batteries activated to is
controlled by
junction box which is a powered relay
box see you could not get
sent factories on an issue it power to
junction box junction box got its power
from
home to an indelible from the command
module
so only way you could power the junction
box to turn on the descent
countries was be a switch in the command
module switch which had lost power
am
so why in her study designed to sway
why in god's name would you just have a
simple on-off switch
emergency switch captured hide it
somewhere it wouldn't matter will switch
took a turn on why in god's name would
you design a system
this way yeah so the answer is because
the batteries
and if you think back to technology
sucks today
have ish go back to 1963
are you 1932 even so the Apollo
systems used and zinc summer zinc
batteries
which were chemically activated the
lunar module excuse non-rechargeable
versions of these batteries they were
charged find their cab drivers time for
me she would fill them up with
electrolyte and they will be charged up
there was no recharging
you had a set amount ours so became very
much
had a lot of design decisions became at
conserving parents batteries
using them as little as possible am
hands D was up but because aged eight
and eight use everything
matches because everything patches are
very very energy dance
is actually some interest now and doing
a type-a servers it bashed
laptops and so on scooters lithium-ion
but
very transit dance very very heavy am
but one-shot comic so
there is also another weirdness so this
is that this is a schematic up to
descend batteries
again I got this from Long Island and
we'll see this works here
okay so there's actually two conductors
so the summer zinc batteries have this
weird
and when they did not give a constant
voltage
knows when you fully charged them up and
day produced
am 38 votes when they're fully charged
am them in the power went down the drop
down to 32 votes
am so what the walls in the descent
patches was there is attacked
happy 17 cells in which we just give you
the lower 32 voltage
and then the last batch was use low that
they would tap
so the full 20 cells within batteries
used and the reason to for doing this
was because he was certain equipment
in the command module and historian the
module I could not tolerate
38 folks specs top-rated 32 volts
relax so the same factories can control
them
junction box has magical voted switch
you needed to turn the lunar module
on otherwise would blow up important
things
that you would really want later on at
the ascent batteries
did not have this tack this and become
important
they only had it for you can only get
the start at 4:30 voters and up to 32
reason to get away with that because the
way the missions were sequenced the laws
were designed
by the time he had the ascent batteries
on you had enough for load
am that third
lower the full just drop enough to
damage them in the crypt
so you have this terrible problem three
and Apollo marshall the Confessor lunar
module I could not be turned on
am and that was truly was nowhere in the
procedures
and there are two guys were really
unsung heroes about this
am bob later and Bill Res Bob leather
sally has passed to a couple years ago
am I think bill resupply Phillies
eventually don't become a flight
director
and they had been sitting in their
little back room
and they had noticed that and so they
had a little paper trace
that was monitoring the five things at
the lunar module that were
damn lunar module normally
sorry for most of its flight by the
lunar module was docked the command
module
was in a very low power mode he didn't
have lights flashing
exceeded me the power however there are
like a couple things like ears and
glycol
pumps incidents rotation handful
equipment you kept on throughout the
flight
when the apollo thirteen explosion
occurred
they saw altered all traces just go to
zero and they knew they had lost power
the command module at that moment they
knew they were going to have to find a
way to turn on
the lunar module without using any of
the command module
resources so this is you can see the
back injured more detailed map
they pulled is out in the back rooms are
going through them
and working out when you get there is a
anyway to turn
am the lunar module on
without before the astronauts died
so the solution they came up with walls
again so I can have to send stage the
junction box
I did mention he had his ascent
batteries but again the problem was
if you just connect to PSN factories to
the junction box
you were fried all these pieces of
equipment in use send module
because sent countries will start
pumping after Eagles
was just too high so what they did in
about half an hour's work out a whole
series a circuit breaker throws
which is to Paul every piece of
equipment that was going out of town 38
fills
of am become a lot of the line
they cut power cheese through the system
again with a more circuit polls
K get to get power to the junction box
they're able to power the junction box
to chat box turned on ap from there then
they were able to get the said pat is
turned on
and dissent that is set to low voltage
setting turn of dissent actors
and then they could begin the full
activation checklist
am the reason it was too is it was
served up this way was because
$27.5 a sitting on the pad it was
connected via launch in bilkul
which was providing parents those
handful of credit systems a little much
always here to be a just before launch
the
umbilical to send the signal to the
junction box which would turn the lunar
module
onto its internal battery power take off
at some point
the command module a dock with the lunar
module and then they would cut taxes and
bills
and the first thing you do it can build
consensus turn of descent actresses
junction box
so that in a much as be parents to the
fuel cells and so they were able to
basically back into this junction box
and get the same countries going and it
was talked about half an hour
this is really that see the one truly
see the pants thing happened apollo
thirteen
and very much is a thing that saves does
acids to hang on the lunar module on
all the other hand his stuff there you
know
waiting for them to come down through
the city to the atmosphere
know that would happen if the old so
last great hack power 14th and
every fifth nineteen seventy-one so now
you have a situation where
and everything this time has gone pretty
well and actually gone to the moon
the astronauts are
have transferred over to the lunar
module to descend to the surface they've
separated from the command module
another I can basically a parking permit
an
going around so then how our mission
controllers is something funny
am what happened also this is a little
schematic up up the lunar module
and there's a Pam from the guns
command panel looks like this and there
was a
teacher to wearing the incident with
this particular switch
which is the abort switch at which is a
very bad switch to have a runny noses to
as a port is a port stage so the idea
being that if you were
say you're coming down towards their
surface and you discovered your descent
stage scrappy of whatever reason you
could punch Fort stage
which sever the connections immediate
right who's the scent
at stage back up into orbit am
a portrait is a general which means time
am the problem was that there was a
little
Paulus older had come loose inside that
switch I was floating around its your
gravity
every now and then he would tip contacts
and the guys who are paying attention to
the
to the two to the measure would see
abort
come up on their screens fortunately the
lunar module's computer was in a mode
that
was not paying attention to a Forbes I
so the hand at the Hope Center most had
it set so if you're just
if you just like flying along I V in
orbit you don't really need to pay
attention
to something that only is going to take
place during a descent stage
am an ASI ASI my you pressing the A four
button
there's no and they said extra attacking
you
and a they tapped on the poor little
thing went away cuz it not the solar
bonus great life because well you sure
tap nicely
now so but they had this problem that at
any moment during the descent this
little slower ball
could move around and have triggered an
abort
which was kinda bad news church
so this all comes down to what's
involved here is the Apollo guidance
computer
am you for this audience
you cannot underestimate the
significance of this computer
people talk bad you know spin-offs from
nasa program
this computer wants essential they did
not invent
integrated circuits for this computer is
that they did not invent
know the computer the small computer
for this mission this mission this
computer
had so much have an impact on computing
act
and power the reason was because when
integrated circuits were first
introduced
an kilby in moist on the reston
an engineers hated them
despise them if you read the Nobel Prize
lecture of them
10 kilby who got you for men to the
internet through texas with
he says because provided the
entertainment a technical conferences
for several years
an engineers hated integrated circuits
for two reasons
one you have this back box have
previously their job loss if they were
building say oh I know
B 52 autopilot am
you would have resistors and capacitors
and transistors and you could measure
the characteristics of all those devices
individually and they get a fairly good
sense of how to work together
so any understood how to build those
circuits and then you're asking them
said
situation where you could test
individual each individual component
separately and have confidence in our
system as a result
here's a black box it works trust me
really hard to get people to like just
trust the damn things
the other issue with integrated circuits
and my head was
unreliable they did sometimes crap out
yields are low they're very expensive
without the Apollo guidance computer the
only people willing to put up with them
were people building about people
building nuclear missiles
because they have they're willing to to
ever attack
amped bill small missiles took part in
the summary for example
by everybody else really truly hated
them
what was unique about the
apart kinds computer was a decided to
make it one completely
Adam integrated circuits am the block to
this is a bubble talk
this ATC I have here the block to add
like something like 2800
am NOR gates as you all know wat you
have in your gate you can build any
other kind a gate by simply enough
them together is here and and you're not
gates hola geologic skates
so basically Nash was wearing a boat
of and integrated circuits in the early
days at one point nasa his response for
something like forty to fifty percent
all the IC's needed world we're going
into
and Apollo program going into polygons
program
what this did was had to fax +1 nasa
that we're not really
nasa really anal about reliability
issues every time there's a fault among
these chips
nasa wants to know why stay with take
them up and it look at them and they
would look at failures
and doing that it dramatically improve
the manufacturing process
to as I mentioned integrated circuits
are very expensive
very few people want to buy them by
providing a guarantee customer
and for years am the policies really
underwrote
an awful lot out the early integrated
circuit manufacture
and the third point is is that began
people did not trust
politicians I'll all integrated circuit
computers by going to the bloody moon
and back
and began to set a value you can run
your chemical plant are your little tank
its fine cuz we went the moon with this
stuff and it wasn't until I really was
that was a significant I was this a
gift:
by proving you could trust digital
integrated circuits
on those highest-profile product ever
interview how came back
used and not really wants that really
was the purpose
up the commercial and into getting to
see the reason why we have all these
super cheap
and processes around our necks owes a
lot to this to this particular
device and Frank O'Brien very very
kindly brought me
in see this this is a
at prototype am apollo kind system this
is just a logic circuits
if you look closely I really track is
going to have this in the retro
computing section
really encourage you to look closely you
can see how integrated circuits are
polity and has a little bit
hand why iraq am going on and you're
very regional days
it was thought that be astronauts would
be will be able to repair
and the polygons be by slipping his
muscles in your see it's all very much
you know marge is a plugin then choose a
side of the house not can reach us with
a screwdriver
and so everything well so unfair but
everything was bus was designed so that
it was
it was completely sealed am unit
am so this is can you see that up on the
screen
bakery so I really strongly advise you
to please
and come down and visit Frank is that
this unit
he will also have what's what's called
dead disc E
Emily running and because you can you
can
tree much get know all this upset right
hander
running an emulation mode and it's
pretty cool am go back
it yes actually we should def of yet be
great to see in apollo iPhone
AGC application
sorry okay great let's have some
teleport
am so one important things about about
as well just to go back is that
use rope core memory so I used to know
you've of
sony's basically no fair i cor Kors
a topic long strings a copper wires and
this was programmed
by hand to me by hand by somebody think
he switches are very the for you
do I mean there is there a little old
ladies in the region
middle-age women in the record Patrick
who what
IDR if they pass to wire very thin wire
3 affair I call that was
one if they bypassed 0
solos literally these were practically
hand-woven memories
am each apollo mission had
it had to the program called had to be
delivered six weeks before the mission
is to to launch
you know you could not change it was no
catch
she could get a read your mind you know
here's an early dinner bro
she just stick it in there no do you and
I think a lot of the quality
of the softer was because they knew
there could be changes
you could in fact around you couldn't go
okays 1.0
the fight that said each version have
the
each version after the modules went with
a slightly different version
and impact us because admission promise
change
issues with hardcoded in part because it
to get better they did try
am eliminate some bucks am
but i've seen a that is good the MIT
Museum they have a distinction what's
called luminary
and it's about it's a piece a fan for a
paper which is about white
statistic which is a complete program
listing
all of which was fitted into about am
72 kilobytes 636
words three 72 kilobytes from had about
to kill a bite
am to the way it works was have this
verb noun syntax I was a little bit like
damn
the early Activision text adventure
games for you
as said you see a present for when you
type a2
Pacha digit code for suburban do
something now
would say water awesome might be firm
the firm I translate to load these
numbers into memory and now but specify
exactly
numbers where the works too damn unit
type in
just a on my little offices octal for
extra
extra fun and games am I should see also
one final thing on the disc EU CDs green
lights
lot of people think these are like LED
displays am
LED's weren't really around this is
built his reelection luminescent
displays
which ran it three hundred volts selves
kinda been a serious engineering into
went into for this display itself is
also
was also gramme broke bread rating so
back to our for Burger circling the moon
with a dodgy for fun
and Linda Marshall computer was locked
out from acting am
prom for now but as soon as the answer
was fired
dan the computer thinks he's had to pay
attention to the park but
am amateur where two programs p70 which
was a four-percent engine
p71 stage apparently sent engine the
normal
to send programs and take your cock 64
p65
so entered on my office the
to Hannah you know dashing young man who
working at MIT
am it received enough he says he came
out here when he credibly
undistinguished
mast agree and basic Draper barge was in
place would kill him
more or less he was involved lot of
people wrote
earlier models after where he was really
did allow the hardcore working taking
very few radical taking the fear act
like I Z creations
control equations and and conferring
those at the actual code
that would run it a lot of the very
critical flight reading car
gots flight control system you're
turning on the engine
turning spacecraft crashing to the
ground and
so he did he's alone at work
now muskan
ok area so hola 14 the ass not sir
art really want to land and they were
like a solution these
an to the first idea that O'Donnell's
who and they're always act that the
house has a story going round the
you know he was sitting at home in the
air force close up its big limousine
guys its soldiers and I think somebody
MIT much in the Andromeda Strain cuz i
think thats actually
from but and we still await like save
the mission fact he was in his office
as he always walks for mission and when
the guys came in it says haiti aboard
discrete
homes and businesses like ok to and it
was obvious we click here
to his first idea was well we'll just
using basic equipment up a pole command
were just disable the Fort Minor manly
Angelfire up the computer will start
looking for the import
code well just tell them to turn off the
bar code but that would mean that the
asset was bracing
the computer balance older ball you know
was being accelerated
taken anywhere if the ass or not you
know what his party at our fingers
couldn't get more sometimes there in
space suits and so that was actually
if gas I could not beat that
that the time the the monomer check that
switch hundred times before
the ass I wouldn't like it out so would
mean a real race condition
would not be good so now as for solution
which they radioed opportunities
particularly happy with
alan shepard was commanders marginal
does you no min
no bad from the asks we know that he was
not noted for his
general common good temper
Thursday pretty pretty grumpy about this
to the second solution
and is working americans love complex
damage in for time senator
fifty-minute okay great so step one
was a puter wanted to ignition and so
the computer is a okay I'm gonna
ignited there's a whole count 'em
process which would happen if we turn on
power ups and stuff
and so you would turn the AGC so that we
think it's already in the middle of an
abort
to school when you have time and you
would say you
program is so that it would repeat it
supports this verb
21 now one business program to what was
called
again was an octopus he said 107 at the
end
server 21 was basically the equivalent
army
poke statement so this basically kinda
results to
those you remember basic che Mike Connor
64 roots here
am for twenty-one was basically just
this crap is equivalent of Polk
1010 count 107 which was part
107 which was the October for 71 into
memory location
1010 and so with the computer resigned
as if it's already in the middle of the
port
there's no point in starting the import
mater because you've already
phiri done you must have address how
would you be in a min abort
and celebrating if your gonna sucks and
fucks you now
so they punched in this one and then
however
there's a bitter public as a kinda cap
on the computer and it will be your
place
for it will continue its countdown and
then but it won't
throttle up all the way if you don't
throttle up the engine all the way
in the way that the Miss designers have
done you land somewhere else
God knows where he will do weird things
to really think you're gonna
and am so we needed to do was 12 26
seconds after ignition
on their manual control they would
parsed throttle up to mack's
miss a manual everything was still being
flown through the polygons computer was
no true manual
million marge was you understand
everything was still done done through
but there was
the computer didn't know that if the
human being as pressing a certain
control
and you know let the human being have
his way and take a nap
sorry are max Manali who said that salt
maximum
to another blazing through the sky with
the engine rocket firing in Maxim para
hazard
using energy in a guy eavesdrop towards
the service
and now you have to turn on all money
first it is difficult to the second that
we should talk manana
and many simulated they realized later
Marshall didn't do anything
and is kinda state its position down
which is also considered bad
and chinita like turning and am
so they now needed to turn the landing
softer so again
am they did another they did another am
tree hack and this time they're sending
a bit so for twenty
tree five down seven is actually and
bitwise
operator and again when I wanted to
Hunter
summer fish that and bet that's being
changed his one
to actually sending a single bit flag
inside the memory with a one there
an when they did that so now they had
control
and now it was time to turn off the
former
and so this again was another
bitwise entry yes good ones server tree
597 uses both
that wise different memory address and
now they're saying it is your
to the clearing the vents and that a
court martial never start
am now I can anyone do little to clean
up
get the proper and descent program
running to you hands a greater kinda
good stuff
and again it's in other at Polk
statement and so you see it's the
opposite is very similar to the region
stately for centered
see first year they put in for 21 and
seven memory 1010
107 and then they punched in
for 10 10 10 10 77 which i think were 65
64 63 sorry ass
for the actual and descent catcher and
then you have to drop the file back to
minimum so that
you day where the computer no longer
searching the override
am to eke nears their times and it
needed the computer program you go down
to partial thrust
and that was when it send him at all to
Mac
let their computer really do the full
range
talk its so countries the end here
further reading am for like a really
great
you know what it's like to be a fly
controller in Mission Control
sign the burgh of am Polycom he was
e.com
who is there when apollo thirteen fuel
cells blew up and he's just amazing guy
and he's got a great story needed
just talk back for he thought about 15
just getting up and walking away
and then you notice that the consoles in
India miss your truck had his baby
capsules
and their dick to you could lift them
out into servicing but the controllers
colin powell candles
cousin moments like this and live as
ages you just grab those handles
and you hold on you just you and then
you get it together
and then you go on he's got in his in
his
in his book he's got like printouts from
I use on his screens during the whole
disasters
it's really great to get a Polycom
donald's who's actually
an hour anarchist now to see its nation
art am
he's got a lot of detail about the
Apollo the AG Seans
are lots girly things that happen Apollo
11 and someone starts protect manic
can't recommend enough the Apollo lunar
surface journal which amtrak also
am contributes to am just a huge air
huge array of really great stuff another
again cuz I said
at the start I'm really interested in
engineering centric histories space
program
am apollo by Marie Anne Cox is a very
engineering
eccentric ok it's because out of print I
think they have their own privacy
printing you can still get copies here
in there
it's really is ask nichols' right
through from Mercury to the mercury days
am through the pop program digital
Apollo which the guy called David
Mundell
which really goes into law the tensions
between the astronauts and some in the
engineering and decisions and how much
control
to the assets has asked us hated being
spammed a cap
they wanted loss of control as much
control as possible
and frances was a at a serious
idea for a while that an ass not with
Manly's we have these boosters
Saturn fiery Alice Tigers the ass not
would fly descend program
and manage in the middle like it well
gee much
an they were just waited from this but
there is a there's a huge tension
in the system between what you automated
and what you did not meet
and Dan David Mundell really talk spec
talks but that and second have to pick
and the demand book am cab chapter in
this book
which stocks bad learn more about apollo
thirteen risk for Prince the dust which
just came out
we just comes a whole bunch of the other
missions and just talk by the ass cuz
they were awesome in
I think apollo thirteen show there
really was a long wisdom having
test pilots because those are guys who
could after
days of no sleep entering command
sequences
fiercely here's so I think that is about
it so I would love to take
depression
it counters were here okay
ass when you have any questions I think
there i think is
microphone yeah thank you do you know if
a
Dymo label take making gun was part of
the
on board flight equipment I do not know
daschle expression very sorry
I know Seattle been a mix-up in the
beginning iOS 4's
what was it SC he was a leader in SC two
cocks work the astronauts
like Muslims ex-military people want a
dislike you will see your ako
you know lesser-known clutch well
someone and they also came from
different cultures I mean
am yet more summer military pilots why
did induce Erica
because a lot of wasn't but the two had
they had developed their own jargon an
and so they they tended not to use all
the phonetic stuff you see there are
some other so
for instance the an the the idle state
apollo
kites computer was program 00 surround
saying
Peter 00 they set up computers into and
so the
to the jargon is just was just they
develop their own jargon as you say made
a left then that this contract
a ser your your talk highlights the
value being able to construct an
expedient solution to an unexpected
problem using tools at hand and be
having
somewhat discrete components do you
think the systems they would put in
aerospace and space mission hardware
today would allow for that kinda thing
is easily or
I mean do you think that they're
thinking at that ahead a time that we
might need to do things that we didn't
know you need
I think I think no because because this
was a tense with the with the AGC
that it was basically a back box and
this was the complaint that made you
couldn't do anything with it
at the turn out to be the softer sex
porn after the realtor
to get around it so am I'm not shy
I think that yes you see stuff being
guns together the maybe you might like
to have
am the previous generation my treated
but
will open up other opportunities that
for different types of solutions
so I don't think we'll and the clues
future sorry I was wondering if the
only channel for communicating
especially all the commands
activist but his voice or if they also
had a redundant data channel now they
could enter the data channel and David
Mundell points at
Dimondale I think talks Donna to guy
called an
alcohol and he was the real genius
behind
the design of the AGC and
hall says this is proof that the assets
never really trusted the computer
because he could have sent up those
commands
on the ditch but because the ass has had
read it at a rendering it manually
it may be asked the EPA found with a
repeat of the situation and you know
key kinda want people who are you know
her finger on the moon to feel
psychologically comfortable
so okay I
I was also just can't quite remember is
is a man approximately
10 might seconds away or how how much
but I is not my thing
the rat like a sec how sex yeah
yes it's not gotten Osama yeah because I
imagine saying
wyatt's and having to wait for i've 8sec
you do get his little beep sometimes but
but it was he was he was close enough
asking country was close at this mission
controllers are really
they were very tightly controlled
they're always operating systems
on the spacious the acid know about am
so obviously we think about going to
manners are other places you have have a
slightly different
and approach it's gonna be teased yessir
when action stuff thank you 16 loved a
hearing
he said biggest-ever very seriously the
engineers
told also a bit of a sense of humor so
the from in engineers
after they had Michael had been rescued
had used to rescue they said the tolling
bells it is an offer from the
manufacturer of the other component that
fails for more details
pics II 3u I think am
our it was North American no I think
North American and
sent back a another bill saying get well
you owe us for
you know six in like nine lunar missions
over was pretty it had actually members
from
we did have a sense of humor this is
Chris Fisher after party in there's this
great
am you can get in some places when I gag
reel
made for the big party they had
afterwards and there's a free famous
point early our very early in the
disaster sign even got the come says no
peepers concerts happenings well I think
you may have had in sweet asian problem
am
which sanitary man is a funny in
retrospect ppl
African you that holding a blown-up to
say it was instrumentation problem
but you'll see from Apollo 12 when I
really happiness mutation so they were
trained
attorney Aldridge who is his head around
it they were trained to think for
singers have been sweet asian issues
gentle are on a date you didn't want to
like flushing entire mission
because you know one dodgy p.m. signal
on this very long transitory
but they play that loop over and over
again later on a gene krantz with tags
and he's well I don't understand that
such
I'm a planner over and over and over
again today
from the other they were their pre-fight
yessir
on the %uh the last %uh when the UN over
at the Apollo 14
are two questions our first of what was
the time
appeared there I think you mention it
but I for got it so how long did they
have to come up with ownership while
they're floating around noon we think it
was bad who spent 90 minutes
okay thank you cash and second how did
they determine or did they determined
during the event
but it was a soccer ball I'll take the
suspected it was a star on come on the
tapping
magic tapping am which Alexa but I
really wasn't
am and then they because he be sent Mar
did not come back to the CANopen that
switch
but everybody agrees that's premature
okay I think have time to thank you all
very much for coming
thanks please go downstairs rescued in
your area check at the ATC
it deserves our respect and love and
fence
said