- [Narrator] Whether you're
hyper-connecting your ecosystem,
empowering a distributed workforce,
rapidly leveraging cloud,
IOT, AI, or other new technologies,
RSA is here to help you
manage digital risk your way,
at every stage of your journey.
- Good day, everyone, and
welcome to this session.
We're gonna talk about API security.
I'm Joe Krull, a senior
analyst for Aite Group.
We're an independent
research organization,
and for 2020, we did
quite a lot of research
and reporting around API security,
and I'm pleased to share the results
of that research with you today.
So, why should you care
about API security?
Well, the reason why is that APIs
are just absolutely exploding
in our modern enterprises today.
Last year in 2019, an
organization called Nordic APIs,
which is a community of API developers,
they estimated that there
were more than 15,000 APIs
in use across the globe.
But what's happened in the last year or so
is that the use of APIs
has absolutely exploded,
because of the COVID-19 pandemic,
and the use of automated
workflows, and chatbots,
and all different kinds
of collaboration tools.
No one really knows how many
APIs are actually in use today,
but empirically it's somewhere
around the range of 100,000 or more.
So this is an area that
is absolutely growing,
and there's a guarantee that
if it hasn't touched you,
it's definitely gonna
touch you in the future.
An interesting statistic
from Akamai came out
that said 83% of all internet traffic
is somehow related to APIs.
We thought that was quite astounding
and the more we pressed on it,
the more we believe that to be true.
What are APIs being used for?
Well, they're really the
backbone of the digital economy,
and we have something in
Europe called open banking
which is a regulation that
requires banks to be able
to share information and
open up to fintech companies.
That's driving API use.
Also digital transformation
programs and initiatives,
and even IOT deployments
in the driverless cars.
You can't run a driverless
car without using APIs.
So we found that during
our initial research
that most enterprises have more than 600
internal and external APIs
present in their environments.
But, we found as we started
our research in early 2020,
that security awareness around
APIs is actually very low,
and it continues to be very low.
So we started off with an interview
of 20 CISOs, security architects,
and digital transformation specialists,
and we just simply
asked them how many APIs
are traversing your networks
in your environments,
and they really didn't know.
So at last year's RSA
conference in San Francisco,
we actually did a lot of discussions
with security professionals,
those were both scheduled and ad hoc,
and this question kept coming up,
and we found that a lot of people
that probably should
have known did not know,
and there was a very low
visibility around APIs.
So, another thing that we found
out during our conversations
and interviews is that there
was a general assumption
that traditional security
products like firewalls,
and load balancers, and
web application firewalls
were providing sufficient protection
against APIs or API attacks,
and even there was a misconception
about what API gateways do.
And so, based on that, we
published an initial report
that talked about lack of
visibility around APIs,
and I'll touch on that in
a moment in a case study,
but after we finished that
first report and research,
we kinda decided let's
go talk to the people
that are actually creating
and managing APIs.
So over the summer, we did interviews
with 53 application developers
and security professionals
representing 31 different companies.
These were mostly in fintechs, insurtechs,
and financial services
organizations, where we assume
that the level of security
would be quite high,
and to be able to compare apples to apples
and oranges to oranges, we
came up with a methodology
where we came up with a way to come up
and measure the maturity scores
against seven competencies,
and we're gonna share that
with you in just a few minutes,
but the bottom line on that
secondary research was, again,
we found API security
awareness to be very low.
So, what are the threats?
Well, attackers are going after APIs
for one primary reason and a
couple of secondary reasons,
but the main one is there's a
low probability of detection.
They're able to manipulate APIs
and use the API streams for all
kinds of nefarious purposes,
because most organizations
have this limited visibility,
and very few capabilities to
disrupt that attack surface.
So what are they doing?
They're stealing sensitive data.
They're messing with business operations,
manipulating data streams.
They're taking advantage of the ability
to abuse business logic,
get unauthorized access,
and even do denial of service attacks.
So there are lots of threats to APIs,
and that's why our mission
is to try to raise awareness
and help people understand
that if you're not securing your APIs,
it's probably just a matter of time
before you'll have an issue with them.
So, one of the other things we learned
is that this is not something
that we're talking about
nation-state attacks
and we're not talking about
sophisticated cybercriminals.
Actually, you can do API attacks
without having a high level of expertise,
and you can buy tools or
you can get them free.
A lot of these are no-cost tools,
and you can get them in
the hacker marketplaces.
They're widely available.
Attackers can use proxy tools.
They can even get services,
they can get low cost-services
to be able to support their attacks,
and the folks that develop these tools
actually update them on
a fairly frequent basis,
so if they are detected by
certain products or solutions,
they can keep avoiding
those detection modes.
And again, at the RSA
conference last February,
I was able to see a
15-year-old high school student
doing live API attack
against a gift card database,
and based upon his description,
this is not something
that requires a high level of expertise.
And if you just google
any one of these tools,
you'll find out that
they are really prevalent
in the domain, in the marketplaces,
and the places where hackers
go to get their tools.
So, we're not talking
about small organizations
that are being breached
or having to publicly acknowledge
their vulnerabilities.
We're talking big companies,
like Cisco, and Google,
and Facebook, Twitter, Salesforce,
Zoom, Waze, and Amazon Web Services.
Venmo had a particularly
damaging incidence
of an API vulnerability.
Also in retail and hospitality,
also in the automotive space,
and the most recent attack
was a few weeks ago,
was one of the dating services
that was a mobile application,
and they were,
because their API was
not properly configured,
you could actually
extract from the database
all kinds of user profiles,
or you could upgrade your service
without paying for that premium service.
So these are just examples of API attacks,
and public service as well.
The most recent one was the
Biden for President Campaign
had a very interesting app
for managing their potential voters
that suffered from a number
of API vulnerabilities.
And we have also seen in recent weeks
that a lot of the COVID-19
tracking applications,
which have been pushed
into the marketplace
very, very quickly based on need,
also suffer from API vulnerabilities.
So this is an example
of one that was found
as part of Uber's bug
bounty program last year,
and in this particular case,
what happened was there were
a number of security issues
with the API, which allow the attacker
to actually enumerate all
different kinds of information
within that database.
They took advantage of the fact
that there was really poor
authorization on the APIs,
so just simply by intercepting the stream,
you could do a lot of things with the APIs
that you really shouldn't do.
The attackers were able,
well could have been able
to see from the error messages
all kinds of sensitive information,
and what they did was
an enumeration attack
on the part of the application
that allows you to add a driver.
By simply manipulating that API,
they could actually pull
information from the fleet manager
and get access to all
different kinds of things
about the existing drivers,
like their email addresses,
like their phone numbers,
and all other kinds
of sensitive information related to that.
So this is just one simple example
of an API-based vulnerability
that could have resulted
in a pretty significant
privacy and/or security issue
for an organization like
Uber that really relies
extensively on APIs for their application.
So, what do we do about this?
Well, as I mentioned before, I can confirm
based upon our research that
firewalls, load balances,
and WAFS just aren't giving
you sufficient visibility
into API calls and traffic flows,
but there's good news here.
There are a number of solution providers
that are rolling out new
products and new solutions.
These are API security gateways,
which we did a report on in the
early part of the year 2020.
We're seeing the ability to
use artificial intelligence
to do traffic analysis on APIs,
and also services that
you can do discovery
and all different kinds of
ways to protect your APIs
available as a web service.
But from our first bit of research,
we recommended that organizations
just simply make API security
part of their cybersecurity strategy,
and acknowledge that they're gonna need
to go beyond the
traditional cyber defenses
if they intend to provide more protection
against API-based attacks.
So a quick case study here.
I had an opportunity to speak
with a security professional
at a large financial services company,
trillion dollars under management,
and more than 20,000 employees,
and their issue began in 2018
when they were seeing what they thought
were credential stuffing attacks,
where attackers were using
big stores of credentials
that had been compromised
in previous attacks,
and they were sending these in,
trying to go against an API endpoint,
until they found one
that would give them access
to the infrastructure,
and what they did
when they saw these
credential stuffing attacks,
they had all different
kinds of manual process,
and technical controls,
and they would spin up incident response,
and they would open up bridge lines,
but really, they didn't
know what was happening
with the API traffic,
so they had very limited ability
to do anything about these attacks,
and they kept changing time of day,
going up against different services,
and what happened was in
the first half of 2019,
they not only their web
applications were impacted,
but then it extended to their
mobile services as well.
So the security professional I talked to
said that for the better part of a year,
they were running around
playing whack-a-mole
trying to deal with this
different type of attack.
So what did they do?
They instituted an API-enabled
traffic analysis product,
and they put it as a sideband deployment
to an API gateway that was
already in their environment,
and shortly after they
put that product in,
they were able to see
indications of the attacks
against not only cookies,
but also against tokens,
and this gave them a lot of intelligence
about where they needed to
go shore up their defenses.
And the product that was looking at the,
this AI-based product that
was looking at their APIs,
they were able to produce alerts
and send those to their Splunk platform,
and create all kinds of new
use cases related to API abuse,
and this gave the security team
a lot of not only visibility,
but a lot of capability to rapidly respond
to when they saw things
that match these use cases.
And what also happened was
an unintended consequence.
They were finding all
kinds of network issues.
For instance, they found that they had,
there was a troubleshooting application
that was supposed to be disabled
when the application went to deployment,
that somehow never was disabled,
and it was constantly running
tests against the application
which was impacting performance,
and they found that through
this API visibility capability.
So what happened was they raised awareness
of API security by
deploying this solution,
and they felt like they
were in much better stead
to actually do something about it
by implementing this solution.
So, in the summertime,
we decided, let's go look
and see how API development
practices are done.
So what we did there was we
created this methodology.
We looked at what are developers
doing with regards to APIs
and how are they actually creating
and how are they managing them?
So, based upon the interviews,
we also looked at documentation,
we looked at presentations,
we looked at all different
kinds of materials
to be able to assess maturity
against seven API competencies.
And because we wanted to be
fair in our measurements,
we used the Carnegie Mellon CMMI,
which is a rating schedule
that you can be able to address maturity.
And at the end of our
research, which took place
over about a two-and-a-half
to three-month period,
we really found that security awareness,
even regarding what kind of attack trends
were out there in the
environment, was very low.
It was low at financial institutions
and it was really low at
fintechs and insurtech companies,
which tended to be smaller,
but were creating these
very powerful APIs.
These are the seven areas we looked at,
and I'll go through each one in detail,
but we felt that it was important
that an organization have
a central point of contact
for API security.
We wanted to know were
there tools or methods
to manage the inventory of
internal and external APIs?
Is there a defined process
to consume APIs from third-parties?
Does the company follow
application security practices
and those do those include
API security specifically?
Do they publish an API catalog
or do they offer an API development portal
to allow those that consume the APIs
to be able to implement them properly?
Do they have a security training program
and does it include API-specific content?
Does the company have a process
for handling security incidents,
and does that include AppSec
and API security criteria?
We felt that these seven
areas were a good benchmark
for how does the organization
manage specifically
API security-related issues
in their environment.
So, the first one.
So we asked is there a designated
API security point of content,
and we found that only one company
of the 31 that we spoke to
actually had a designated
point of contact.
17 companies said no, and we
don't really have any plan
to appoint a point of contact.
13 said well we have a decentralized model
where API creation is
done in the various teams,
and it's kind of spread
all around the organization
so each team is responsible
for their own APIs.
And we felt that from a
cyber security standpoint,
from a risk standpoint,
that lack of a champion
can have developers doing bad things
like trying to implement APIs
in a way that's not secure,
or maybe to contravene
policies of the organization.
So, we rated them about medium
scale on this at repeatable,
but there are certainly
areas for improvement.
So do you inventory your APIs,
and this goes back to
the visibility question,
now from a creation and
implementation standpoint.
So, nearly half of them, half
of the companies we spoke to,
they couldn't tell us how many APIs
that they had created, or
deployed, or were managing.
They kinda had a rough
number, but no real inventory,
and 13% had no inventory whatsoever.
They say well we create
and we manage them,
but we don't keep track of them at all.
So we saw inconsistencies
between the use of
external and internal APIs.
So we did see one area
that we considered to be a best practice.
There was an organization that says,
we treat all external and
internal APIs the same way.
We put them through the same
security controls and rigor,
regardless of whether they're
internal to our organization,
or exposed out to partners
across the internet.
And the reason they did that, they said,
well in a fast moving
business environment,
an internal API can quickly
become an external API,
and they just treated them all the same
and applied a very high
level of rigor to that.
We thought that was the best practice.
But still, because
they're not keeping track
of the number of APIs they're creating,
this poor visibility can really
contribute to cyber risk.
So our third question was,
do you have controls for third-party APIs?
And 19 of them were actually doing
some kind of due diligence on
their third-party providers.
10 companies did it on
a case-by-case basis,
but two companies we spoke to
said we don't do any due diligence at all.
The developers go out, they
find the API they need,
they contact the organization,
and they integrate these
APIs into their products.
So, what happens there
is if you're implementing
third-party APIs,
it can really have an
impact on the performance
if they're poorly coded,
or they're not properly implemented,
and that can also increase cyber risk,
and another thing is that
if you're an attacker,
you can pose as a
third-party API provider,
and you can slip into the stream
and start to do pretty bad things.
So, controlling third-party APIs
is something that we felt was a,
something that a organization
should really scrutinize.
So we asked, do you perform
application security testing?
And the good news there
is well all 31 companies
said they perform some
type of AppSec testing,
so we thought that was a great idea.
And we saw both DevOps
and agile environments
or hybrid environments
with different teams using
different methodologies.
Interestingly enough,
we did find companies
that were doing threat modeling,
which we thought was a best practice,
and two actually had bug bounty programs,
but, of the 31 companies that we spoke to,
26 of them were not
specifically testing their APIs.
What they were doing is waiting
until the product was done
or the API was complete,
and they were doing penetration testing,
and it was our feeling
that finding these things
during penetration testing
just shortly before going to production
or making the API visible
was probably too late
in the development chain
to really have much impact on it.
Next, we asked do you
publish an API catalog?
15 of the 31 companies said
they don't publish a catalog
and we don't provide a development portal
to help people implement
the APIs that we create.
So why do we want to do this?
Well, you do catalogs so you
can help your own developers
quickly find out what approved
APIs are already available
within your organization,
and development portals
actually help your
customers or your users.
You give them guidance
on how is the best way
I can implement this API,
and how should I secure it.
So, what happens when you don't have it
is that a developer may go out
and create a duplicate or a similar API,
and because it's duplicate, it doesn't go
through any kind of proper
testing and approval.
And we found that one
of the biggest issues
with development of APIs
is that the developers
continue to have questions,
or issues, or challenges
related to authentication
and authorization,
and this is an area that
can really be problematic,
both from an API creation
and a management standpoint.
So we asked about application
security training,
and we saw a wide variance
in how training is done for developers.
14 of the 31 companies
said well we do training,
but it's really high-level
training, it's compliance,
we do it because our customers require it.
It really doesn't provide much
in the way of AppSec guidance.
It's mostly around what
are the company policies,
and password management,
and stuff like that.
We really didn't feel
that that was gonna be
sufficiently targeted
for creation of APIs.
13 of the companies specifically mentioned
that they use the OWASP
Top 10 in their training,
but interestingly enough,
only two of the 31 companies we spoke to
said that they were aware that OWASP
had actually come up
with a separate Top 10
for API security in 2019,
and they were quite surprised
when we pointed them to go
to look at that resource.
None of the companies that we spoke to
provided any API
security-specific training
to their developers.
This was one of the more
interesting findings
from our research.
Not one was providing any
API security training.
So, do you have methods to identify
and report security incidents?
Well nine of the companies
had pretty good documented processes
that we heard of and we reviewed,
and it was good for
handling security incidents.
It was good.
Some of them even had RACI
charts, and they had call trees,
and all the things you would
expect when you were talking
about identifying reporting
security incidents.
But 11 of those companies
say well we don't have anything like that.
We'll just handle these
things as they pop up.
And 10 companies didn't
have anything at all.
In fact, it was kind of foreign to them
to even consider that they
needed to have processes
for handling security incidents.
None of the companies we spoke to,
and none of the materials that we reviewed
had any guidance at all
specifically related to APIs.
So, two companies said
they had actually had API
security-related incidents
that had been reported to them.
They didn't find them.
It was their customers that found them.
And 20 of the companies,
20 of the 31 said yep,
we had problems,
but we found it during
third-party penetration testing.
And as I say, that's
pretty late in the process
to be able to find vulnerabilities.
So our recommendations of
ways to improve API security,
these were the things
we put in our reports.
We think that every organization
that is either producing or consuming APIs
should have a knowledgeable
representative for API security.
We think that organizations
should implement an API
management platform.
This is beyond keeping track of APIs
in spreadsheets or other manual means.
There are tools that you
can use to manage your APIs.
We believe that they should
conduct thorough due diligence
on third-party APIs.
They should implement an API
catalog and developer portal.
It's not as hard as it sounds.
Organizations should expose all developers
to API security concepts,
and this includes what kind
of attacks are out there,
what are the methodologies,
what are the tactics,
what are the procedures that
the attackers are using.
To be forewarned is to be forearmed,
and to create and disseminate procedures
for security incidents,
and include API-specific details in there,
such as, if there's an
incident or an anomaly
that is tracked to an API,
how do you quickly
identify who developed it
or who is responsible
for managing that API,
so you can be troubleshooting,
and/or take the necessary measures
to stop that particular attack.
And finally, to include
API security testing
as part of the software
development life cycle.
So these were our recommendations.
We hope that we've been
able to raise awareness
around API security, because
APIs are gonna continue
to be used all across the infrastructure,
all across different markets
and different verticals,
and now is the time to start to focus
on how to protect them.
So, I encourage you,
if you have anything you'd
like to go deeper onto,
you want to enter that
into the chat window.
We can discuss that as we go along.
So I thank you very much for
your participation today,
and I look forward to additional questions
and additional conversation
around the subject of API security.