- Hello everyone from
joining us for this session
on Critical Infrastructure
Network Attacks.
and specifically the attacks that we saw
when we performed a utility
or industrial control system
oriented honeypot research.
My name is Israel Barak,
I'm the CISO at Cybereason.
So without further ado,
let's kick this off.
Now, looking at the
Honeypot Research Goals,
our primary goals were really
to expand our tracking, right?
of changes in the adversarial landscape,
the tools, the techniques, the practices
that threat actors are using
from a threat Intel perspective.
And really we wanted to
add threat Intel context
and analytics context around the telemetry
that we often collect from
both IT and an OT environment.
Now, to help accomplish that,
this specific honeypot research was built
to emulate an electric
transmission substation network.
And we basically use
the network identifier
as both internal and
external network identifiers
that are very, very similar
to a known large electricity provider
to entice attackers to show interest
and maybe even target this honeypot.
Now, looking at the outcomes
so far from this research,
I think the spectrum of cyber attacks
against utility providers
and the interest in protecting them
come as the profile of adversaries
who target industrial
control system providers
is really broadening.
And I think while usually
industrial control system attacks
are linked to APT or advanced
persistent threat actor groups
and nation state threat actors.
And those are probably still, you know,
the primary profile of an adversary
that would target these environments.
We were able to make that
assessment, I think today
based on honeypot data that we collected
that really, really shows the
profile of the threat actors.
They target these utility environments,
these industrial control system
environments is broadening,
and we're seeing many more
types of threat actors
getting into that mix and many
more tiers of threat actors
getting into that mix.
Now, before we dive into the
honeypot research results,
I'd like to set some context
on some key trends in
the ransomware space.
The work that's gonna be,
and those are gonna be
important for us to understand,
to put in context what we
saw in the honeypot research.
And I think those are gonna
be single-stage ransomware
and multi-stage ransomware operations.
So, ransomware has historically been used
in the so-called shotgun approach, right?
Basically distributing the ransomware
to as many targets as possible,
and thereby increasing the
chances of generating revenue.
Now, in these cases,
the ransomware operator
basically acquires a list of targets,
many times in the form of a mailing list
or an email address, a distribution list,
and basically distributes that email
to that entire distribution list.
Now, usually this is done with
very little customization,
usually just customizing the language
to the geographic location
of where that presumed target actually is.
Those single stage ransomware attacks
are usually very quick to detonate.
Usually when the target
receives that outreach,
the email or that link
and the ransomware lands on
the end point of that target,
it usually detonates on impact,
where it detonates very, very quickly.
It starts encrypting the data
and basically asks for money.
Now, when you look at
single stage ransomware,
there usually is usually exist,
there usually are very few
indicators of reuse, right?
You see a large variety
of strains in this space.
A lot of new strains are
being developed every month,
and the idea is that those are
fairly simple rudimentary
tools, really blunt tools.
And so there's not a lot
of need to reuse code
from previous strains
to actually get money
out of these operations.
And that actually makes it
difficult to detect those
with next generation AVS
and static analysis tools.
And those are single
stage ransomware attacks,
can be fairly impactful,
but usually when you
think about business risk,
those are actually the
ones that pose lesser risk
to corporate in larger
enterprise organizations.
Now, one of the critical
trends in ransomware threats
is the growth of a new
operational paradigm,
which is a multi-stage ransomware.
Now, those are essentially
multi-stage hacking operations,
where the threat actor
breaches a victim's network
and performs several post-breach actions.
And those actions are meant to result
in a fairly large ransom payment.
The general idea behind these operations
is that a ransomware operator
can generate significant revenue
from the relatively
small number of victims
if each of them pays a large amount.
And when you think about
all these ransomware cases
that we've been seeing on the news
that pay or at least
extorted for six figure sums,
those are usually a
multi-stage ransomware attack.
Now, in a multi-stage attack,
the attack itself typically
involves data theft,
stealing user credentials,
laterally moving through
the victim network
and compromising other end points.
And then basically
targeting critical assets
like domain controllers
and others in the network.
Now this operational attack pattern
attempts to impact the victim
in several different ways
including confidential data loss,
sensitive user credential theft,
disabling large amounts of systems
to effectively cause a large
scale service disruption.
And I think the idea behind these attacks
is really the create or
behind the operational pattern
of multi-stage ransomware attacks,
is to create as many leverage points
that the attacker can take advantage of
to facilitate a large extortion.
Now, ransomware attacks both single stage
and multi-stage are very prevalent
as we know in IT environments.
In fact, some threat actors
have turned ransomware operations
into the primary area of focus
and source of revenue for them.
But ransomware threat actors
that target industrial control systems
or critical infrastructure environments
are presumed to be much less prevalent.
Usually, when you go through
threat intelligence reports,
those are usually presumed
to be much less prevalent.
And while at the onset
of this ICS honeypot,
we actually did not
expect to encounter one.
We ended up realizing
that these attacks can very
likely be a lot more frequent
than we might be used to thinking
Now, before we dive into the
honeypot research results,
this is a quick overview
of the architecture
of the honeypot that we had set up.
Basically the honeypot network was built
to resemble an electric
transmission substation, right?
The network architecture is very typical
to a large substation,
it contains several different
elements here, right?
There's a DMZ area that is
facing the external world,
in this case, the internet
or the when environment.
Some of the critical services here
in the DMZ include typical services
that you would find in
a substation network,
like remote technician interfaces,
or for the station is currently
in an unmanned situation,
a technician would be
able to connect remotely
and support different types of issues
or analyze different types of issues
or if remote support is
needed by an escalation point.
And those are, those personnel
are able to connect remotely.
We'll see that component in the network
actually played a critical role
in the incident that we're
gonna talk about in here
serving as an initial access
point for the attacker.
Other components here in the environment
include the industrial
control system network itself.
In this case, you can
see here the devices.
Those are different
types of ICS controllers
that we had here in the in the honeypot.
ICS services segment in the network
was focused on HMI systems
that are based on an open SCADA
and other service segments
here in the network,
that are fairly typical
to a large substation.
Looking further into what we
had here in the environment,
the endpoints themselves were typically
windows or Linux based,
the way we collected telemetry
from the endpoints here
and from the ICS environment
was using the Cybereason sensor
that's basically deployed
on these end points
and collecting the system
user application behaviors
on these end points, that we were able to
essentially correlate and analyze
to identify potential attack patterns
and provide visibility into them.
Can also see that the network segmentation
was fairly typical to a, an
IT/OT combined environment
where the IT areas of the system
are fairly reasonably
segregated via firewalls,
in this case, from the IT network itself.
Now, one of the primary incidents
that occurred in this honeypot
is what we believe to be
a multi-stage ransomware attack,
likely by a cyber crime threat actor.
Now, at a glance, and
we'll take a look shortly
into the steps of the attack
and more details through
screenshots from the environment,
the timeline of the attack
started essentially two days
right after we've connected
the honeypot environment
into the internet.
So, basically our time equals zero,
the network was ready,
We had it connected to the internet,
and it took us two days
to get to the initial
compromise of the environment.
Now, in the initial compromise,
what we can see here is
the primary techniques
that were used by the attacker,
the initial access was through
the remote technician interface.
They use basically brute
forced user account credentials
and were able to gain access
with those brute forced
credentials into the RDP system.
They then ran a series
of discovery techniques
performing discovery on the
active directory in the domain
as well as the DNS server
that was in there primarily
doing reverse DNS look-ups
to identify where they are
and what assets are in that network.
And persistence was done
in a fairly rudimentary way
in this initial phase,
using a local user creation,
basically creation of a backup user.
The idea was that if we
would go and change back
or replace the passwords that
they were able to brute force,
they would still have
a way to log in, right
and get back into the environment.
Now, that was the two days
after we got this environment
connected to the internet.
The short amount of time
is very likely indicative
of some sort of automatic
scanning activity
that's going on, that
allowed the threat group here
to identify the new
asset that was connected
and perform these actions,
very likely automatically
on those, on the remote
technician interface.
Now, four days after this, two days after
the first access,
the threat actor access
into the environment,
we started noticing a
different set of TTPs.
We believe by the way
that the change of TTPs
that we're seeing between
step two and three
are very likely due to a handoff
of this environment between
two different threat actors.
Very likely a first one
that only got access to the environment
and then sold it over to
a second threat actor,
that continue to work on target.
Probably based on the attractiveness
of the indicators of which network
they believe that they compromised.
Now, in step three, basically
the threat actor here
started operating in a mode
that was very, very focused
on moving in the environment,
towards a higher goal, right?
And what we saw here is
a operational pattern
that's actually very common
to multi-stage ransomware attacks.
The first stage is to steal credentials,
basically steal the passwords
of every user that
logged on to the machine.
In this case, the remote
technician access machines
and the tool that they used was MimiKatz.
And then the second stage
is to basically collect and exfiltrate
all the data files that
exists on that machine.
The third stage was to drop a
ransomware onto that machine.
So at this point,
the threat actor isn't
detonating the ransomware,
they're placing the
ransomware on the machine
but they're not yet detonating it.
The idea is to wait until
a later moment in time
until they actually detonate those.
So they're very, very similar to a pattern
that exists in the multi-stage
ransomware attacks.
And then finally, the idea is to use
all these stolen credentials
from this machine
to move laterally to other
machines in this environment.
In this case, they chose to use SMB
and specifically PS exec
to move in the environment.
Now, this stage took some time, right?
It took them several days to move
throughout the environment.
In this case, they're focused on,
they're still in the
IT environment, right?
They're not yet in the OT
they're moving around the IT environment.
23 days after we started
that was 19 days after the previous step,
the attacker exhibited a behavior
that actually came as a
surprise to us, right?
What we expected them to do
is to spread through the IT environment
and then drop the, detonate the ransomware
in the IT environment.
Instead of that, they waited,
they kept moving laterally
in the environment.
And then on day 23 for the honeypot,
they made a lateral movement
from the IT environment
into the OT environment.
And what they used to accomplish that
since the environments were separated
in this case with firewalls,
they use the web service vulnerability
that existed in our open SCADA HMI.
And then that surprised us,
because what that showed us
is that the attacker
came in with a playbook
that they were able to execute on
for pivoting between an IT
and an OT environment, right?
What they showed us was obviously,
the majority of the environment
did not have access into the HMI
or to the ICS services environment,
only specific services
in the IT environment
had that type of access.
And what the threat actor showed us
was that they were able to move laterally
and they kept moving in the environment,
in this case for 19 days
until they found a service
that had the ability to
access the HMI system,
in this case, to see the HMI data.
And then what they did
with that level of access
is to pivot into the OT network
by exploiting a web service
vulnerability in our HMI system.
So that was a surprise.
From the moment they gained
access into the OT environment,
they started going through
the same multistage,
ransomware operational pattern
changing techniques and
procedures a little bit.
In this case, since the
environment was Linux-based,
the credential access was done via
pass the ticket technique.
And the lateral movement was again
via SMB not PsExec in this environment,
but SMB using past the ticket technique.
But the procedure from multi-stage attack,
a ransomware attack was very similar.
With each new host that
they got access to,
a ransomware was dropped, not detonated,
but dropped this time
in the OT environment.
Data was collected and exfiltrated
over the command control channel.
And the stolen credentials were used
to keep moving in the environment.
And then later on the 24,
the environment itself,
the OT environment was not very big
so they completed that portion
of their pattern of laterally moving
in that environment on the 24.
And when they completed, over there,
they exhausted their ability
to move laterally in the environment.
Late on day 24, they
detonated the ransomware
across both the IT and the OT
environment simultaneously,
basically encrypting all
the data that was there
and leading the system shutdowns
right across the entire environment
and then demanding their ransom.
Now, if we look at EDR
data from this attack,
and I'm using screenshots
taken from the Cybereason EDR console.
We can see the attack here,
starting with the attacker compromising
our remote technician, RDP service
by basically brute forcing the
local administrator password,
then using PowerShell, right?
To deploy the first stage of the attack,
and among other things,
initiate data theft from
this compromised system
and start performing persistence
by creating a new local admin account.
In the next stage, they actually,
we can actually see in
more details, right?
The creation of the
malicious local admin account
that is used as backup, right?
In case someone would reset the passwords
for one of the users that
they originally brute forced.
Their next step was to start downloading
and staging additional tools.
And specifically the ransomware drop.
We can see that they're using PowerShell
in this case to perform a,
the file download, right?
Or dropping of those initial tools
or additional tools on the endpoint,
where one of these tools
was the ransomware, right?
At this point, they're still
not detonating the ransomware.
They're placing it in a temporary folder
on each of the hosts
that they gain access to,
but they're still not
detonating it, right?
The idea is again, to wait
until the cycle for lateral movement,
data theft, credential theft,
maximum leverage, right,
has been achieved on the target.
And then detonate across
the environment as a whole.
The next step was performing
a system, a network discovery.
We can see that they're actually using
a commodity, network discovery tool here
as part of their arsenal of tools,
which I think is probably more indicative
of a cyber crime threat actor
than it is of a more
sophisticated EPT group.
And I think we'll see that
pattern repeating itself.
We saw it in the network discovery,
we saw it in that strain of ransomware
that was used the fairly
commodity strain of ransomware,
and we'll see it in a
couple of other places.
I think it's probably more
indicative of a cyber crime.
Threat actors in this particular space,
but what they're doing
with this network discovery
is first and foremost,
looking for assets that are
critical for the network,
like domain controllers, file
servers, databases, right?
To scan and discover for
us before discovering
other endpoints in the network.
The attacker is then
stealing user credentials
from the compromised asset.
And basically, as you can
see, they're using MimiKatz
right, to dump credentials
from this compromised assets.
And then they're using
these stolen credentials,
in combination with legitimate
administrative tools.
As you can see here with PS exec to move
into other assets in
the environment, right?
So they're taking encryption keys from LSS
or taking credentials and user
passwords from this machine.
The legitimate user is remote technicians
in this particular case.
And they're using these
credentials as well as
a legitimate administrative tool PS exec,
to move in the environment.
Now, the first spread points
that they're going after
are actually the assets that will pose
the probably the least
amount of suspicion,
but likely caused the highest
amount of impact to the organization.
Like domain controllers, file servers
and database servers that, you know,
these compromised end
points usually access
as part of their normal
day-to-day activity.
And again, I think it's the use
of commodity tool in this
case for credential dumping
and for lateral movement,
I think is probably another indicator here
for a cyber crime actor,
that very likely prefers
speed and simplicity
more than stealth and
operational security.
Now they will continue to steal
data and user credentials,
iterate of way right
through this environment
using these techniques that we saw here,
basically until they've exhausted
their ability to move laterally.
And only after they've
completed that first stage
which in this case,
in this honeypots environment
took several days,
closer two to three weeks
for them to go through the IT
and then make the pivot into OT
and then cycle through the OT environment.
Only after they've
completed that first stage,
Will they actually
detonate that ransomware,
and it will do it simultaneously.
And that ransomware that we saw them
dropping at a very early stage
in the attack across all
those compromised end points.
Now what this results in?
in many cases is a significant disruption
to the victims of business
and obviously a significant risk
of operational risk and
on and risk of data loss.
Now, when the extent of the
disruption is large enough,
and obviously, unless an organization has
full isolated DVR capabilities
that they can quickly revert to,
even recovering from backups
may not be a good enough option
because of the amount of time
a large-scale recovery can take.
And, and that leads organizations
and sometimes even insurers to
start considering negotiating
with the attacker.
Now, looking at some of
our takeaways from this,
from this honeypot, we
saw some of the mechanics
of the attack and we understood
how attackers get to the point
where they can leverage the attack
to try to extort large amounts of money.
And we also saw the element
that at least us, you know,
we found surprising was
that playbook for pivoting
from IT to OT, which was
very surprising for us to see
in a cyber crime actor.
For us, some of the key
takeaways from this research are,
you know, first and foremost,
the diversity of threat actors
that are actually
targeting utility providers
in ICS systems.
I think judging by how quickly
these attackers operated,
and their ability to pivot
from the IT environment
to the OT environment.
I think while we can conclude
that this is likely a cyber crime group,
they're still very familiar
with ICS environment.
The security measures that
utility providers implemented
and how to move from an IT
environment to an OT environment.
And I think what this suggests,
that this honeypot wasn't the first time
that they've done this
and they've probably
been implementing this
playbook fairly often.
The other thing is I think that
the fact that multiple tiers of attackers
find ICS environments interesting,
very likely means increased risk
for people who operate
these type of systems.
I think the security basics are really
what's gonna prevent it badly
from becoming a catastrophic
day in these environments.
I think, you know, when you
think about these environments
in most utility providers,
not all of them,
but I would say most environments,
these systems are old, they're fragile.
And even trained hacking
units make mistakes
that cause failures in these controls
and hackers seeking to
make a name for themselves,
or simply prove that they
can get into a system
I think are far more
likely to cause failures
out of ignorance rather than malice.
And I think this makes instant response
and attribution harder, but I think
it also is more likely to result
in an unintended real-world effect.
Now, second, I think it's important
that the companies where ICS environments
operate a unified sock
that provides visibility
into the IT and OT environment, right?
I think as we saw in
the honeypot research,
attackers are looking
to use IT environments
as gateways into OT environments.
I think we need to have an ability
to correlate activities that are starting
in the IT environment,
or starting in the OT environment
and traverse that bridge
between those environments.
So we can have a better understanding
of how to respond to them
and the nature of the
risk that they present.
I think often companies have a NOC
monitoring the OT environment,
but a combined sock lets you see
all operations as as they
move through the network.
And I think having that
visibility is important
because attackers, as we see here,
could very likely start
in the IT environment
and move to the OT environment.
And lastly, I think hunting is critical.
You know, this activity
looks for indicators
that attackers are already
in the company's environment
instead of waiting to react to an alert
issued by a security tool I think,
threat hunting allows defenders
to take a proactive approach to security
by detecting adversaries
before they cause severe
damage to a network.
And I think establishing
and putting visibility,
having behavioral detection capabilities
are gonna be critical for
effective threat hunting,
let alone for scoping and
responding to those incidents.
And with that, first and foremost
I would like to thank you
for joining us on this session
and open the session up for any questions.