- Hi there.
Welcome to pilots,
surgeons and developers.
How to improve your application security
by using checklists.
My name is Joe Kuemerie, I'm
a Product Security Engineer.
And before we get started, I
do wanna set a disclaimer that
this work is all my own personal work,
while I do security work for my employer.
None of what I'm going to be talking about
is relevant to them, nor have
they endorsed us in any way,
nor should anything I say
be an endorsement of my current employer.
Having said that, welcome to this talk.
I know that we're doing this virtual
and it's gonna be a little bit odd.
However, I am in the live chat
alongside the playback of this.
So at any time if you have
comments, suggestions,
feedback that you'd like to offer,
please feel free to drop it into the chat
I'll be happy to respond.
Additionally, there is
going to be a live session
following this, where we'll
have much more ability
to interact directly,
collaborate on some of the
ideas presented in this talk.
I'd really love to have
you stick around for that
and to have a chance
to interact with you much more personally.
With that we can go ahead
and jump right into the talk.
Scientists that study problems
have classified them into
three basic varieties.
There are simple problems,
there are complicated problems
and there are complex problems.
Simple problems are pretty
much what it says in the box,
something like learning how
to bake a cake from a recipe.
You have a recipe, you
follow the instructions.
And once you learn it,
you basically have a very high likelihood
of success doing the same things
and getting the same steps
with the same results.
Complicated problem is something that's
more like sending a rocket to the moon.
There is not a simple recipe for it.
Often it requires multiple
people collaborating,
coordinating teams with
specialized experience.
However things like the laws of physics
are pretty consistent.
So that once you've learned how to
send one rocket to the moon,
you can usually repeat the
process with similar rockets,
and expect similar results.
Moving on to the complex problems.
Something that is defined as complex,
it's like raising a child. Unlike rockets
that are constructed to
be virtually identical,
each child is unique.
And even more of the
environment of any given child
is different from any other environment.
If you have children, you
know that raising a child
does provide some experience.
But the lessons you learn from one child
do not always directly
apply to another one.
Indeed the techniques that you
may have used for one child
may be completely different and you may be
completely ineffective on
their brother or sister.
In that way, building software
is defined as a complex activity.
By definition, most software
is bringing something into the world
that wasn't previously there.
This means that like a child,
there are some common similarities
between software solutions
but there are also a number
of unique circumstances.
Building a secure application
is also something that cannot
be completely controlled
by a simple set of steps.
And it does require active
participation by developers
as well as those who help
to support the developers.
Giving developers freedom to innovate
while providing a usable
method to remind them
of what they know and
what they need to do,
is the purpose of building our checklists.
We'll start with some simple definitions
just to make sure that
we're all on the same page.
A checklist is basically a set
of simple, straightforward,
easy to assess criteria.
Should be a well-targeted, detailed enough
for a user to assess if
an item is completed.
But also not get bogged
down with unnecessarily,
overly complex details
or items that are not relevant
to their current task.
There are two major types of checklists.
The first is defined as do list
or more accurately
called, call do response.
This is what most people commonly picture
as a checklist completion process.
And the do list method, the
checklist drives the process
to step by step approach.
The user works the checklist,
performing each action in series
and then recording the results.
This method can reduce redundancy
as there is no need for follow-up process,
since the required
actions are usually taken
during the execution of this
style of checklist completion.
One of the disadvantages is,
this method can lead to
steps getting skipped
or emitted in high
distraction environments.
It's very easy for a user to skip a step,
and if the execution
sequence is interrupted
and not notice the omission
until it's too late.
While many of our environments
are not as distraction prone
as airline cockpits or operating theaters,
I think that in some
instances such as building
and releasing security fixes,
in response to an incident
perceived overhead of a do list process,
may feel like unnecessary
overhead for the stakeholders.
Second method of checklist completion
is called challenge response.
It's also better described as
challenge verification response.
In this method we're using the checklist
as a backup procedure.
The user performs whatever
actions they need to take.
In our case, developers
write code, building software
according to whatever processes
and quality criteria you have in place.
And then they use that checklist
to verify that what they
have done is in accordance
and meets all of the
checklist requirements.
This challenge response pattern
is most commonly used
pattern by major airlines
as well as other high
sensitivity environments.
Now, one or both these methods,
may not work for you specifically
based on your culture, your environment,
your requirements and that's okay.
The purpose of this talk
is to give an overview
of different methods,
how they've been enacted in the real world
and to give you a starting point
to take back and to build on.
There's not a one size fits all solution.
Checklists have to take into account
corporate culture,
development methodologies,
how your security teams work and interact
with development teams,
as well as your people's
preferred work styles.
Even in the airline industry
with identical equipment,
each airline has their
own preferred work style.
And thus a unique set
of checklists and styles
that are suited for how that
corporate culture works.
It's also well within the scope
of a checklist implementation,
planned on a hybrid solution,
where some checklists are do lists
and others are challenge response.
We'll cover a little bit
of what a checklist is now.
As I've said,
a checklist is not intended
to be a comprehensive guide,
nor should it replace a
well-defined secure coding standard.
Comprehensive security standards,
detailed process documentation
and strong security controls
are also essential.
Without any of those, a
checklist is essentially useless
as the purpose of a checklist
is to be a memory aid
and to cause the user to
stop and think before acting.
A good checklist will raise
high level awareness of risky situations
and provide a limited set of options.
But it's not going to
cover all situations.
Just as flight checklists rely on training
and detailed operational procedures,
application security checklists
must also be backed up
by good security training
and written resources
for developers to use.
All the checklists in the
world will not help someone
who does not have the
necessary background knowledge.
Checklist must be usable.
If something is too long or complicated,
that won't get properly addressed.
Human memory is fallible and
human attention to detail,
especially when working on routine matters
that are perceived as mundane
can cause items to be easily overlooked.
Especially in the midst
of complicated activities,
such as preparing to cut someone open,
attempting to get 200,000 pounds of metal,
fuel and people to fly through the air.
Or building a system to allow customers
to securely use their credit cards
and purchase things over the internet.
Good checklist must be precise.
They must be relevant
to the situation at hand
and describe actions
that are both meaningful
and actionable to the user.
They must be engaging for the
user and work as a memory aid.
Not a rote list of steps that
just have to be checked off
in order to get to the
next phase of your work.
Just like agile development techniques,
when you give the developers
leeway to innovate,
a good checklist will
empower those developers
to build more secure solutions.
In order to measure the
effectiveness of our checklists,
we need to be able to
verify their effectiveness.
Across multiple industries, aviation,
medicine and construction or
some of the major industries
with well-documented successes
in using checklists to
drive effectiveness.
While we in the security
industry are still evolving
our methods of measurement,
the effective use of checklist
will raise communication,
increase collaboration
and it should result in more
secure systems moving forward.
Can you absolutely measure
a reduction in security incidents?
That's a definite challenge.
It depends on your
organization's used cases
and security maturity.
This can be easier for some
externally facing products,
with the product security
process in place,
with internally developed
and managed systems,
it's a lot more difficult
to have that sort of absolute metrics.
Either way, there is still
some uncertainty involved.
This is straight up reduction
in number of vulnerabilities,
may or may not be directly attributable
to the use the checklist or
any other individual activity.
The aviation industry
has been using checklists
in various forms since at least 1935.
1935 there was a new Boeing test bomber
that was being prototyped
and being tested.
Initially after a smooth takeoff on its,
one of its first flight installed,
turned on one wing, crashed and exploded.
Killed two of the five
members of the crew,
including the pilot,
who was also the chief of
flight testing at the time.
So it's arguable that it was
not lack of pilot experience
that caused the sort of crash.
The investigation that occurred afterwards
revealed that there was
no mechanical issue.
The crash was simply caused
by quote, pilot error.
This airplane was more complex
than most previous models
including having four engines to manage.
At this point, the pilot
had simply forgotten
to release a single locking mechanism
on the elevator and rudder controls.
Newspapers at the time
reported that the airline
was probably too much airplane
for any man, one man to fly.
Boeing nearly went bankrupt
as a result of this.
When the Army Air Corp
chose a Douglas airplane
instead as their primary bomber choice.
Luckily the Air Corp did
purchase a few of these planes
to be used as test planes.
It was a dedicated group of test pilots
who were determined to prove
that this airplane was flyable.
One thing that they did
instead of mandating that there
needed to be more training,
because again, one of the pilots
that crashed the original
plane, was the head of testing.
He had been trained as much as anyone,
if not anyone else in the area.
So what they came up with,
was a set of checklists
to cover takeoff, flight,
landing and taxing.
It was a basic list of things
that the pilots already knew how to do,
but that could easily be
overlooked during complicated
but routine set up for a flight.
That checklist worked.
It demonstrated that the airplane
could in fact be flown successfully.
This airplane became the B-17 bomber
and it ended up being
the third most produced
bomber of all time.
The aviation industry has used checklist
for great effectiveness over the years.
The chart on the left shows
plane crashes per year,
along with corresponding
passenger and crew deaths.
You can see that after the 1940s,
even as the number of flights increased,
the number of crashes decreased.
The chart on the right shows a trend line
of United States commercial
flight hours since 2000,
excluding this current past year as well.
Over the last 18 years, the
number of hours spent in flight
continues to increase.
And yet crashes are rare
and noteworthy events.
Similar willing in medicine,
the use of surgical checklists
has been increasing.
The checklist manifesto by Atul Gawande,
which is one of the
inspirations for this talk,
describes a process by which Dr. Gawande
pioneered the concept of
checklist in medicine.
There've been studies that show consistent
and repeatable improvement
in surgical outcomes,
in locations where checklists are used.
The use of checklist provides noticeable
and measurable improvements,
regardless of the resources available
to the testing hospital.
The study has expand a
range of institutions,
from some of the top tier institutions
in some of the wealthiest
countries in the world,
to underfunded crowded hospitals
in developing economies.
The used checklists,
has resulted in improvements
across the board.
This is an example
of the World Health
Organization surgical checklist.
Some things to note are
the simplicity of design,
the questions that have
clear and meaningful answers,
and the categorization to
help people focus on the items
that are most relevant to
them at any particular phase.
Also note that the checklist calls out
that it is not a comprehensive resource
and the customizations by
those who use the checklist
are actively encouraged.
Collaboration and a feeling of ownership
are important factors in the
successful implementation
of a checklist program.
We use the checklist in development
and application security
can provide meaningful security benefits
in the posture of our applications.
We're not gonna move on
to the nuts and bolts
of how we can start
building a checklist for our organization.
There are a number of items
that we're going to cover.
We'll define the ground rules
and objectives for our checklist.
We'll define multiple checklists
as no single checklist
should ever cover everything.
We'll then cover the basic questions
that are likely to apply
to many different areas.
And also some situational
questions that are more specific.
Again I wanna remind
you that the chat window
is there for your use.
If you have any questions, feedback,
please feel free to put them in there.
I'm happy to answer them
as we go on through this discussion.
And there'll be some
time at the end as well.
The main idea that I wanna get across,
is that building a checklist
is a collaborative process.
A checklist cannot be
another set of processes
that we inflict on the development teams.
A primary purpose and value of checklists
that they contain a collaboration
between security knowledge
and development processes.
It must be built by direct involvement
and open to changes
coming from our consumers,
the developers.
We'll start our ground rules
by building an effective checklist
from the aviation and medical world.
Where our checklists have
been shown to work well.
Our ground rules will guide us.
And as noted in the previous slide,
our intention is to increase
communication and collaboration.
Our checklists are going
to serve a dual purpose.
Their explicit purposes of course,
going to ensure that rote tasks
are consistently implemented.
That the developer's execution
and ongoing reevaluation of the checklist
also serves as an important
communication bridge
between the developers and
us security professionals
who are supporting them.
We'll take some lessons from surgery,
where taking time for everyone on the team
to introduce themselves and their roles
results in better patient outcomes.
And we'll apply that to
application security.
If the developers know who
their security people are
and understand that the
goals we're aiming for,
then there can be a
larger sense of teamwork
and a willingness to stop
and ask about things,
rather than just plowing
ahead with development.
Let's take a moment to
review this block of text,
describing what the aviation studies
believe their checklist should achieve.
I'm not going to read
through the whole slide
and you can feel free to
come back to this later.
But essentially we're gonna boil it down
as checklists must be
standardized to a certain extent
and have to at least be consistent.
They should serve as an aid to memory
and a backup for our processes.
The process of working through a checklist
should be logically ordered.
And the checklist should
provide a framework
for both the inter team
and cross team communication
and collaboration.
Our checklist should be designed
to allow for any team member,
regardless of role, seniority
or technical skills, to detect
and call out anomalous items.
Nobody can know or see everything.
Sometimes detecting a
potential vulnerability
can come from an unexpected quarter.
Such as, say a project manager
who becomes more aware
of data privacy standards
by being exposed to the
concept on a checklist.
This can really help those
who are new to the team,
those are who lesser
experienced developers,
those who may not have
primary development roles,
to be empowered, to notice
and call out some vulnerabilities.
Essentially like in an operating room
where there is a checklist
and where there's this team introduction
and comfortability with
the members of the team.
Non-surgeons in general
can feel more comfortable
in calling it,
noticing calling out
potentially risky situations.
This is something that I
think would greatly benefit
in being translated to the
application security realm
and have that level of trust
among the development teams
or with the security teams.
Finally, the TMC use checklists
must have a sense of buy-in and ownership.
Those teams need to feel that
the checklist items are relevant,
that they can be effectively
executed and evaluated.
And they also have to understand
and be committed to the purpose
behind each of the items on the checklist.
Any irrelevant or ineffective
items on a checklist
can lead to minimization of use
or even outright disregard
of the checklist.
This can give us yet another
failed security initiative
and even more exposed vulnerabilities.
In aviation they don't
have a single checklist
and neither should we
in application security.
Just as there are different checklists
for different phases of
flight, pre flight, takeoff,
standard flight and landing,
as well as checklists designed
for emergency situations,
we should also have a number of checklists
that are appropriate
for various scenarios.
The cognitive redundancy
provided by checklists
can be a benefit in all phases
of our application security
development life cycle.
Checklists should cover our
standard operating procedures
and should be able to
be used by developers
as they go about their
day-to-day business.
Designing, writing,
testing and deploying code.
Just as airline pilots use their checklist
to ensure that they do
not forget to enable
critical settings during flight,
developers should use our
checklist to have a reference
to remind them how to build secure code.
Straightened on level flight,
still requires monitoring and adjustment.
Standard development processes
can integrate checklists
into their workflow
with minimal disruption.
There are also those more
complicated scenarios
that require more specialized knowledge.
These scenarios can also
benefit in checklists.
Development of high risk components
brought the indication cryptography
or any other high risk areas,
should either have specific
steps or even entire checklist
for their covering
their specific scenario.
Checklists can also be used
to effectively respond in
an emergency situations.
When there are mechanical
issues with an airplane,
there are numerous
troubleshooting checklists
that the pilots can work from.
Similarly, we can build
checklists for incident response,
breach disclosure and other high risk,
high pressure scenarios.
Having an agreed upon set of steps
that have been thought out ahead of time
and shared across an organization
can help prevent missteps
and mistakes in the heat of the moment.
Our checklist shouldn't be something
that we impose on developers
from the security group.
Collaboration is essential.
It provides both the sense of
ownership over the process,
as well as the feelings that
to ensure that the items are relevant
and can all provide the expected results.
Another benefits of checklists
is not just from going through the items,
a major benefit is
improvement in communication.
surgical teams that know each other,
even just through a quick
introduction of names
and titles just before a surgery,
are more effective and have
a better patient outcome.
This effectiveness is
driven by communication.
When you have names to put with faces,
it humanizes everyone in the group.
It increases the sense of ownership
and makes people feel more comfortable
with calling out those potential issues.
Checklists are not a one
size fits all solution.
Checklists need to be customized
to fit your corporate culture
development processes,
your tooling checklists choices
and to meet the needs of the
software you're building.
In order to build a good checklist,
you're going to have to collaborate.
You're going to have to collaborate
with lots of non-security
people and talk about,
let's talk about some
good ways to do just that.
We'll start with the major
consumers of our checklist,
the developers.
They need to feel both
encouraged to use them
as well as empowered to
change them as necessary.
There's usually, a bit of a tension
between security groups and developers.
We all know that the most secure system
is one that's completely
isolated and does nothing.
Developers on the other hand
have different incentives.
They get paid based on
how many potential security
vulnerabilities up, sorry.
I mean actual features, that
they can expose to the world.
When building checklists with developers,
we should work with them,
so that we understand how
and they understand how
every item on the checklist
helps their systems to be more reliable,
more available and more stable.
Just saying it's more secure to do X,
is usually not a winning
strategy for collaboration.
Having checklists that
span multiple groups
and include operations teams
can also help with both
day-to-day operations,
as well as incident response.
Risk comes from everywhere.
Maintaining good
communication with people,
keeping our systems
running day in and day out,
can be very beneficial.
Checklists are also facilitate
knowledge of people and
roles across groups.
Again leads to increased communication,
increased improvements in things
such as incident response,
where there is a central
cross team collaboration.
Using checklists also provides
more effective communication openings
between different security groups.
Good working relationships
with infrastructure security,
enterprise security, risk management
and others security eccentric teams,
is enhanced by the knowledge
that is commonly known
playbook for everyone to use
based upon these checklists.
We even need to collaborate
with management.
As the ones who set priorities
and sign the paychecks,
management needs to have an
understanding of their power
to cause essential security
processes to be circumvented.
Management should have an understanding
of how performing security
related work can be a benefit.
The benefits of a more secure code base
can be expressed in ways
that management understands.
What's one of the things that
management best understands?
Cold hard cash.
We can demonstrate that
more secure systems
are more reliable and
more reliable systems
can lead to more users.
More users leads to more revenue.
That's a direct goal that
management can get on board with
and help them to understand
that an investment in secure code
is an investment in good code
and an investment in the bottom line.
As we've covered a bit
of how to collaborate
and build checklists, there
are also some anti-patterns
that we should be aware of
so that we can avoid
specific problematic areas
as we collaborate with
the development teams
to build these checklists.
One of the most significant
anti-patterns is length.
Checklists have to be
efficient, not comprehensive.
This is where it helps to
have a good understanding
of your systems and your major
vulnerability categories.
You must be ruthless in your process
to ensure that only highly
relevant, highly probable
and highly impactful items
are on your checklists.
This also helps increase
the relevancy of them
and therefore the
adaptability and use of them.
Your checklist needed to be simple.
Complexity and ambiguity
are counterproductive.
Every item on your checklist
should be easy to understand.
The steps to complete that item
must be clear cut and well defined.
Finally, your checklists
have to be relevant.
If you give a developer a
laundry list of terminology
that they don't work with every day,
that's a recipe for trouble.
Items that are meaningful
will get attention.
Items that are considered irrelevant
we'll get overlooked and minimized.
So on a measurement, how do we
measure our security output?
How do we measure the
effectiveness of our checklists?
One proxy for this, can
be a developer interaction
and relationships with security
having a process in place
to collaborate early
with your developers and to
actually have some measurement
of that over releases,
can give you numbers to drive
your effective communications.
So the more that you
interact with the teams,
the higher your scores can be.
That's something that can be
measured and used as a proxy
for how interactive you're being
with your development teams.
Another measure can be security bugs
that have been detected over time
and in which phase they're detected.
Catching something and design
review is a lot more effective
than catching something code review
versus having it shipped to production
and having a external bug bounty
participant report it to you.
The earlier you can catch
security vulnerabilities
and if you have the ability to track
at which phase those
security bugs are caught,
is a really good additional proxy
for the effectiveness
of your security process
and therefore the effectiveness
of having these checklists in place.
Here we have a few sample checklist items
that have come from myself
and from previous versions of this talk.
You'll notice that this covers a variety
of common development scenarios,
common security vulnerabilities
and the checklist items themselves.
The questions are concise.
They are an attempt to be clear.
They minimize the amount
of security and language
in those questions and
in the checklist items.
And the answers are easy
to tell what they are
and what their completion steps are.
This is some really good
examples of how checklist items
can look, how they can be
effective and how they can again,
serve as not a long-winded
secure development process,
but just as a quick and simple
reminder to the developers
as they're getting ready
to commit their code.
Or as they're writing their code that
have they encountered the scenario
and to remind them to do the
right thing security wise
about those particular pieces
of code that they're writing.
I have of course built a checklist
in order to help us build checklists.
This is again a list of 10 items
that you need to keep in mind
as you're building checklists.
This is something in
our interactive session.
Following this recording,
we will use as our core
criteria for collaborating
on building relevant checklist items
for some of our scenarios.
And as with checklists,
this does cover the most important things.
First, it does provide
a clear and meaningful
representation of what needs to be done.
And it provides that
satisfaction of having that
checkbox of here's the
clear well-defined criteria
and then a definition of done
for this particular item.
So that we can then move
down this list in order
and come up with an effective
and useful set of checklist criteria.
Again, so in the collaborative
session after this talk,
anyone who's participating now,
we will collaboratively
build checklist items
that are relevant to our
particular environments.
If you have any feedback
that you haven't already put in the chat,
now would be a great time.
I'm happy to answer any
questions that may come up.
We'll have a little bit of extra time
at the end of the session.
And finally, the references slide.
Please feel free,
take this back to your companies,
build a process that works for
you, for your organization,
for your development teams.
Collaboration is the key to this.
Iterate development is highly important.
Something that you get out there,
contest and then build on,
is the preferred mechanism.
Just building something once,
throwing it out there and saying,
this is the way we're gonna
do it forever and ever,
it's not going to be very adaptable.
It's not going to be very flexible.
So again, have those
collaboration conversations
with your development teams,
with your other teams
within your organization,
include management in this.
Get that buy-in and get
yourself a good, simple
straightforward process
to remind those developers
of all that expensive
security training they've got
at the point in time when
they're writing code.
With that I wanna thank
you for your time today.
I appreciate the
opportunity to speak to you.
Happy to continue this
conversation and chat.
Happy to continue this after the fact,
as well as you can reach out
to me on Twitter at any time.
Thank you so much and have
a good rest of your RSA.