- Thank you so much.
Thank you so much RSA for having us
at the 365 virtual summit.
My name is Selena Larson.
I am the senior cyber
threat analyst at Dragos
which is industrial control
systems cyber security company,
and here with my friend
and colleague, Camille.
- Hi, I'm great.
I'm Camille Singleton.
I am the strategic cyber threat lead
at IBM Security X-Force.
- Sweet.
And today the two of us
are going to be discussing
some research that we have
recently conducted and published
on ransomware in industrial
control system environments.
To give you a little bit of an outline
of what we're gonna be
talking about today,
we have compiled a bunch of research data
and ransomware history to kind of discuss
the impacts operations as
well as this new evolution
of ICS-specific ransomware.
As we all know, ransomware
is a massive problem.
And it does have a unique impact
to industrial organizations
and their industrial operations.
Some of the new trends that
we've seen are this idea
of human-operated ransomware
and the idea of double extortion.
So data theft, in addition
to the encryption function
of ransomware.
Camille's gonna talk about
some future predictions,
what are we seeing on the
horizon for ransomware?
And then finally,
we're gonna go over some
defensive recommendations.
So what can you as a defender
do in your organization
to reduce risk and keep
yourself more secure.
As a bit of an overview,
ransomware is a very, very serious
and ongoing threat to all businesses.
Although we're gonna
be talking specifically
about operations, industrial
control system environments,
it is not unique to ICS.
Certainly we've seen a lot of
issues impacting healthcare,
state and local governments,
small businesses.
It's really widespread threat,
and it does have some very direct
as well as indirect impacts
to operational technology environments.
When we say OT, that
means that the technology,
the computers devices that
are sort of controlling
the functions of the
industrial environment, right?
So as human machine
interface, for instance,
you can program it to operate an arm
in manufacturing facility,
things like that.
Ransomware is adopting ICS-specific code
to stop industrial processes.
This is very concerning and
does show kind of an evolution
of ransomware that we're
gonna talk about today.
And then finally attackers are
becoming increasingly hostile
in a number of ways that we will discuss.
All of this data is based on
220 incidents of ransomware
against ICS and supporting entities.
This has compiled from 2018 through 2020.
Camille and I have both gone
through the internal datasets
that we have at Dragos and at IBM X-Force
as well as publicly available data.
I do wanna point out here
that it's very difficult
to discern a full picture
of the threat environment
due to visibility issues.
Oftentimes companies won't report
if they've been a victim
of a ransomware attack
and it can be very difficult
to get a true numbers,
but this is the scope and depth,
which I say is pretty cool
and interesting of our research.
It has existed for decades, right?
Ransomware is not necessarily
a new threat at all.
But what we saw with
the WannaCry ransomware
and NotPetya malware worms
was that the world became
aware of a very serious threat,
disruptive IT malware
can have to businesses
and industrial operations.
Not just from a financial perspective,
but an operations perspective as well.
And historically cyber
crime ransomware operators
targeted victims, sort
of indiscriminately.
And in 2018, we sort
of began to see a shift
into big game hunting, right?
So these adversaries that are
going after large businesses,
large enterprises that
can effectively guarantee
a sort of higher payout.
And with that, I'm gonna
kick it over to Camille
to talk about some attacks we've seen.
- Great, thanks so much for
that introduction, Selena.
And now I'm going to spend
just a couple of minutes
discussing what we found
in our updated dataset
through our analysis.
So from this chart here,
I think it becomes obvious
that ransomware attacks
against ICS-connected
organizations have increased
over the past two years.
And in fact, we've found
that they have increased 500%
from 2018 through 2020.
So, whereas in 2018, it was
common to see only one or two
such ransomware attacks a month
in the press or among our clients,
the average in 2020 is about 12 per month.
So this is pretty significant growth.
And suggests that ransomware
attackers are increasingly
finding ICS targets to be
attractive and profitable
for their business.
We do acknowledge that as
attackers are publicly announcing
ransomware attacks and leaking data,
this is probably increasing the
number of ransomware attacks
that we become aware of as researchers.
But we're seeing increases
in ransomware attacks
against even our internal only data
which gives us confidence
that there really has been an
overall increase in attacks
against ICS over the past two years.
So on the next slide, it bears mentioning
that this increase coincided
with the coronavirus pandemic
that began in late 2019
and accelerated in the spring of 2020.
We wouldn't say that this
correlation indicates causation,
but it does mean that we have observed
the coronavirus pandemic and
increasing ransomware attacks
against ICS interact in unique ways.
So for example, we observed
several threat actors capitalize
on COVID-19 themed phishing learners
for initial access to networks.
A tactic that was particularly
popular in March and April
of 2020 as audiences worldwide
developed a strong appetite
for COVID-19 related information.
More recently, as vaccines
were nearing completion
and preparing for distribution operations,
we observed ransomware adversaries
target cold storage facilities
and pharmaceutical manufacturers.
In fact, our dataset
revealed that the number
of ransomware attacks against
pharmaceutical companies
in just the last two months of 2020
was the same as all ransomware attacks
against pharmaceuticals from
early 2018 up to that point.
And IBM Security X-Force has
observed additional actors,
even beyond ransomware actors
targeting the COVID-19 cold chain as well.
And all of these cyber activities
have the potential to
disrupt the distribution
of these vital vaccines.
Well, health care facilities
and hospitals are not in scope
for the definition of ICS.
We do recognize the significant
harm from ransomware attacks
that these facilities have
endured over the past year.
So on the next slide, in addition
to a general upward trend
in ransomware attacks against
ICS-connected organizations,
our dataset revealed that North
America is the most targeted
out of all geographies,
and experienced 45% of the
ransomware attacks on ICS
from 2018 to 2020.
Europe came in second at 32% of attacks
with Asia third at 16%.
Now we do recognize that the
researchers for this study,
ourselves, speak English
as their primary language
with some European language capabilities.
So this may have affected these outcomes.
But this geographic dispersion
also makes a lot of sense.
As many ransomware
attack overs have shifted
to big game hunting, going
after large corporations
with high yearly revenue
where a high ransom demand might be met.
And many of these corporations
are in North America,
Europe and Asia, where 89%
of the world's GDP resides.
So in addition to geographies,
on the next slide we looked
at industries targeted,
and far and away manufacturing emerged
as the most targeted
industry from 2018 to 2020,
ending up on the receiving
end more than 1/3
of all ransomware attacks on
ICS during that time period.
For many manufacturing companies,
just one hour of downtime
can translate into millions
of dollars in losses,
which ransomware attackers
appear to have found creates a situation
where many manufacturing companies
find themselves under intense
pressure to pay the ransom
in an attempt to quickly
resolve the issue.
After manufacturing, utility
companies came in second at 9%
of attacks.
And in 2018, utility companies
made up only 5% of attacks
on ICS industries.
So you can see how this
percentage has grown over time.
Again, ransomware attackers
probably consider utility companies
especially profitable targets,
and therefore are going
after them more frequently.
And from here, I'm gonna
hand it back over to Selena
to discuss how these ransomware
attacks affect operations
at ICS organizations.
- Great.
Thank you so much, Camille.
Also shout out to the work that
you and your team have done
on the cold chain research.
I know that there's a lot
of attention paid right now
to developing and distributing
the coronavirus vaccine.
So really great work there.
And all of the researchers
and all the cybersecurity companies
that are looking into that
as well, very important work.
So when we're talking
about impacts to operations
of the attacks, in which
the scope of impact is known
that is we know what the impacts
were to both the IT enterprise function
as well as the OT function.
50% of ransomware attacks
affected operations functionality
at victim organizations.
In some cases, weeks long downtime.
This includes shipping
and logistics disruption.
So products were unable to be delivered,
manufacturing operations,
entire plants went down
due to ransomware
attacks, employee layoffs
which is really interesting to me
because we often forget
about the human impact
that ransomware has.
It's not just business
functions that are disrupted,
people lose their jobs.
People are unable to get paid.
People have to go home
and potentially find other ways
of supporting their families
or have to kind of wait until
operations are back up again
in order to get back to work.
Order processing,
another one that is
very intricately linked
to the entire operations process
as well as disruption to control
and communications assets.
That is the assets that are
responsible for monitoring,
communicating and controlling
industrial processes
within an environment.
So talking about ICS-specific ransomware,
this is something that we
find very, very interesting
certainly here at Dragos, but
a lot of ransomware types,
well, I shouldn't say a
lot, some ransomware types
such as EKANS for instance
have begun to adopt
the ability to disrupt
industrial equipment.
Historically, what we've
seen with ransomware is,
it's sort of IT-focused,
windows-focused ransomware malware
that has encryption functionality
highly targeted towards
the sort of IT functions.
But what we're seeing is
ransomware that begins to have,
within its code, mechanisms
that can force stop processes
on certain human machine
interfaces for instance,
data historians, licensing servers.
The list of targeted devices
grows as new strains are found.
EKANS certainly isn't the only one,
but that's certainly one
that Dragos has been spending
a lot of research and paying attention to.
But we have other strains
such as like MegaCortex
and Cobalt that had also begun
to sort of have these
ICS-specific capabilities
to forcibly disrupt equipment within ICS.
So one of the things that
we wanted to talk about
was a case study to kind of
see the ransomware OT impacts.
This is just one of many,
many that were experienced
throughout 2020, but on March 4th, 2020
a Ryuk infection at the manufacturer Evraz
impacted North American operations
including email shipping,
product certification,
internet availability,
and corporate networks.
So the attack ultimately
resulted in shutdowns
of the steel and pipe divisions
across the North American production
as well as temporary layoffs
for over 1,000 workers
for at least four days.
One of the things that I wanted
to kind of point out here
is that we got a lot of
information we as researchers,
got a lot of information
from the United steel workers
of America, their actual union website.
It was really interesting
to see that communicate
the sort of human
impacts, the labor impacts
of the steel and pipe division shutdowns
as well as the layoffs that were incurred
and kind of just being really
open and discussing the human
and employee impact that
this ransomware had.
There was also some really
great open source coverage
of this as well
which is something that
you don't necessarily see
all too often with these ransomware cases.
And with that, I will
hand it back to Camille
to discuss this idea of
human-operated ransomware.
- Great, thank you so much, Selena.
So, an additional trend we
wanted to discuss is the rise
of human-operated ransomware.
In 2017, we saw several
wormable ransomware strains
such as WannaCry and NotPetya.
And these ransomware types
are self-propagating,
and can spread automatically
through compromised networks.
It also appears that
these ransomware strains
may have accidentally infected
hundreds of organizations
in an effect that may not
have been intentional.
So the good news is that
today the vast majority
of the ransomware we
see is human-operated,
where humans are behind the keyboard
intentionally choosing their targets,
gaining access, escalating
privileges, moving laterally
and deploying ransomware.
The bad news is that these
human-operated attackers
are pretty good at what they do.
And their intentional targeting
often leads to what for them
are successful operations on a wide scale.
So on the next slide,
we have a chart that provides a breakdown
of the ransomware types we have observed
against ICS-connected networks since 2018.
And as you can see, wormable ransomware
such as ransom WannaCry is
still on the list at 6%.
And this is a strain we still see today
especially in sensitive OT environments
with legacy infrastructure
that is difficult to update
to avoid that eternal blue exploit.
However, the vast majority
of ransomware strains
we see are human-operated
to include Sodinokibi, Ryuk,
Maze, Doppelpaymer, Netwalker and others.
And some of these such as
EKANS are specially designed
to impact ICS environments.
And now I'm going to hand it
back over to Selena to discuss
how these human-operated
ransomware strains
tend to gain initial access
and spread through a network.
- Great, thanks Camille.
So most of the initial access
factors are phishing, right?
Email spear phishing
remains a very, very active
and effective method of initial access.
We're also seeing remote
services compromise
such as remote desktop protocol,
as well as exploitation of
software vulnerabilities
like virtual private
network, VPN concentrators,
and enterprise network equipment.
It seems to me, I feel
like throughout 2020
especially maybe summer fall timeframe
there was like one new
critical vulnerability a week,
any sort of enterprise network equipment
that was very very quickly exploited,
whether it was Citrix vulnerabilities,
Juniper networks, Palo Alto,
it did seem that ransomware
adversaries as well as a number
of other cyber adversaries
were very quick to jump
on the exploitation of vulnerabilities
once proofs of concept were made known.
Tool use often includes Mimikatz,
credential reuse, PSExec,
abuse of windows, service
accounts, and management tools.
We are seeing a lot of this
sort of living off the land
especially when you're talking about
that sort of IT enterprise compromise
where adversaries once
they're in the environment,
they use built-in functionality
of windows computers
to sort of move about and
spread through an environment.
But what's interesting as well
is some rates more strains
including LockerGoga, Maze,
EKANS and a few others
also encrypt systems
via Windows Active Directory compromise.
You do see active directory installations
within OT environments,
as well acting as a domain controller.
And what might be interesting is that
oftentimes they're not
necessarily segmented.
Sometimes you still have the
CDC that is controlling IT
and OT functionalities.
And so there is a risk there
when the active directory is compromised
and a group policy object
for instance is used
to sort of push out the ransomware.
And so that is something
that is very very interesting
that we've seen there as well.
So one of the things that
I find very interesting
is this sort of new trend
of extortion, right?
So as companies and organizations
are getting increasingly
defensive and resilient
against ransomware that
it's having applied backups,
ensuring employees are trained
at tech phishing, et cetera.
Attackers are increasingly
data from target company
before actually encrypting
the affected machines.
And then we'll threaten
to publish the data online
either on attack websites
or hacking forums
if a ransom demand is not paid.
Ransomware actors may collaborate
with other criminal entities,
either via enlisting hackers via RaaS,
Ransomware-as-a-Service operations
like Sodinokibi and Netwalkwer
or collaborating on these sort
of extortion cartels, right?
So they're leaking this victim data
as part of a whole gang of affiliations
like the Maze gang with other operators.
This is very concerning
for a number of reasons.
And there are a number
of risks and consequences
that are involved with this
sort of double extortion
data theft technique.
One of the biggest ones
being the victims are unable
to confirm whether data
is actually destroyed.
Historically, with just kind
of traditional encryption
ransomware you pay the ransom
you get the encryption key,
get your stuff back.
The transaction has ended.
Unfortunately, now with this
sort of data theft piece,
victims have no idea what's
happening with their data
once it leaves their environment.
And there's no confirmation
or ability to know for sure
whether data is actually
destroyed if a ransom is paid.
This data could contain
sensitive information
on the target company or customers
that are working with the target company.
And this could actually aid
in future attack planning
for additional adversaries
that are interested
in collecting (indistinct)
data on this targeted company.
There are a lot of different
regulatory and legal issues
that arise from data breaches.
We have certainly here
in the United States,
there are a number of
countries around the world
that have a data breach
legislation and regulation
that says you must tell people
when their PII is stolen.
And so companies might find
themselves more pressured
to reveal these types of breaches.
Data leaks provide additional
incentive for victims
to pay a ransom yet when
paid ransoms validate
cybercriminals business model,
and encourage additional attack activity
from ransomware cartels.
Again wanting to pay the ransom,
historically, that is certainly
something that companies do
with the data leak.
Obviously it seems to be working
because ransomware
adversaries continue to do so.
And it does just sort of
encourage this ongoing activity.
Once the information is stolen,
victims have no control over
or visibility into what
attackers do with it.
That kind of goes back to
the first point, right?
There's no visibility into
whether it's destroyed.
Attackers could use it for
other nefarious purposes,
potentially sell it to other
criminal organizations,
et cetera.
And then finally releasing
sensitive intellectual property
could enable counterfeit products.
This is something that
could be of interest
to potential competitors,
to other adversaries
that are largely focused
on espionage and IP theft activities.
There's just a lot of
potential consequences
with the hack and leak operations.
So in one event, we actually
identified a company
that had been compromised by
a ransomware organization,
an oil and gas services company.
We did identify multiple items of interest
in the publicly available data leak.
So there was a list of companies
that use the firm's services,
employee information,
both of which could be used to facilitate
spear phishing activities,
natural gas flow data,
information related to Canadian
government energy regulator,
as well as geospatial data that
could be potentially related
to the company's current upstream
and midstream operations.
So when something like this happens,
really what is the impact?
So there are opportunities for third-party
or supply chain compromise,
understanding the targets
for phishing activity
and potentially using it again as a way
to sort of take advantage
of the trust built
between the company and its customers.
Sensitive financial data that could aid
in espionage operations and
potentially not in this case,
but potentially we have seen
schematics network diagrams
and other internal documentation
that has been published
that could be used to facilitate
ICS-specific compromise,
and potentially attacks.
And with that, I'll
hand it back to Camille.
- Thank you, Selena.
So from all of this research and findings,
we have several predictions for the future
of ransomware attacks
against ICS environments
going forward.
So first we predict that
ransomware will continue to be
a major threat to industrial operations.
These attacks are highly
profitable for cybercriminals,
arguably the most profitable
cyber criminal activity today.
And these profits are likely
to continue to attract
malicious actors to this space.
Second, blended data theft and extortion
and ransomware attacks that
Selena was just talking about
are likely to continue as this technique
which significantly increased
in popularity in 2020
has proven to be an
effective business model
for ransomware attackers.
Third, we anticipate the
future ransomware strains
will build on new efforts, such as EKANS
and be specially tailored
to ICS environments
particularly given how
lucrative ransomware attacks
find some ICS-related industries
such as manufacturing to be.
And last, we judge the data theft
and leak of information stolen
during ransomware attacks
will continue to provide
a better understanding
of the breadth and impact
of ransomware attacks.
So this is a helpful albeit
unfortunate side effect
of these attacks.
And now we're going to discuss
some defensive measures
organizations can take
against these attacks.
And I'll turn it over to Selena
to discuss our first slide
on this topic.
- Great, thanks Camille.
So really what you wanna do is
conduct architecture reviews
to identify all of your
assets, connections
and communications between
IT and OT networks.
You wanna critically examine
and limit the connections
between corporate and ICS
networks to only known
and required traffic.
Having visibility into your network,
having visibility of what
is communicating with what,
is it just one-way or
two-way communication?
What ports are open?
What type of traffic is
allowed within the environment
as well as sort of conducting
privilege assessments as well.
Are only the people who
are allowed to access
certain information or have
admin credentials having it
or is it kind of broadened
across the organization?
Especially for ransomware attacks
having effective preventative, detective
and corrective controls
in place is critical
for reducing risk.
This idea of sort of
defense in depth, right?
Having incident response plans,
having plans and protocols
in place to respond
to an attack.
You also wanna enforce
multi-factor authentication
wherever possible.
Focus critically on
connections to integrators,
maintenance, vendor
personnel and crown jewels,
such as safety equipment.
And we've seen in events
where there's for instance,
RDP compromise, that's
exposed to the internet
with no multifactor
authentication implemented,
MFA could have potentially been enough
to prevent exploitation.
- Great, thanks so much Selena.
And in addition, we definitely
recommend having backups
to both enterprise and operations networks
that are maintained daily and tested.
From our experience,
more companies are doing this successfully
which is great to see,
and which enables them to recover quickly
from a ransomware attack
without having to pay
for a decryption key.
This does not necessarily
solve the problem of stolen
and leaked data,
but it does help in getting
back up and running quickly.
And that is critical.
And we have also found the companies
that have been able to
successfully establish
an alternate location for
business critical functions
are able to recover faster,
experience less fallout
from a ransomware attack
and position themselves well
for recovering and avoiding
having to pay the ransom.
So on our last slide here,
just to conclude some of the main points
from our presentation today,
our research revealed a 500%
increase in ransomware attacks
from 2018 to 2020,
with 56% of those attacks
affecting operations functionality.
We found that manufacturing was
the hardest hit ICS industry
by far.
And that North America
is bearing the brunt
of these ICS ransomware attacks.
Attackers are increasingly
stealing and then leaking data
in addition to encrypting
it and holding it for ransom
which is changing victim's calculus
on whether or not to pay.
And we predict that
these ransomware attacks
will continue to be a major threat
to industrial organizations.
And if you'd like to read more
we have linked here on
the slide, a white paper
that Selena and I wrote on this topic.
And then on our very last slide,
we'd just like to say that we
are happy to have a discussion
about these topics here
on the RSA platform.
And we're also sharing here
our contact information
should you have any follow-up questions.
Thank you.
- Thank you so much.