[Music]
thanks for tuning in
uh to emoticon i know it's a little bit
different than we've ever done anything
before but i think it's going pretty
well so far
and uh i like the fact that we're uh
we're actually getting people in
from all over the world i think uh i
think we heard somebody from brazil
before so that's nice
um this is the introduction of modular
synthesis using vcv rack with jonathan
foote
uh i'm dan maloney i'm a staff writer
here at hackaday i'm going to be
uh mc moderator um
uh kind of person for for this uh period
um as far as jonathan goes uh his bio
here says he's a recovering scientist
which i can relate to being one myself
lapsed musician which i can't relate to
because i
don't have any musical talent whatsoever
and an electrical engineer from san
francisco
understanding the principles of analog
synthesis helped him study for his phd
in signals analysis
one of his qualifications for running
this workshop is that he has played with
analog since he has played analog
synthesizers in front of paying
audiences so he's got
us all beat most likely so everybody
welcome jonathan foote and we'll get on
with the
show
hi everybody i'm john um thanks for
coming i'm really stoked you could join
me here
um couple things before we start um
uh first of all no pressure but if you
want to share your video just
just to see everybody who's here um the
hackaday people have made this nice
community
and it's been so tough in this um in
quarantine just to feel like you're with
other people so here we are with other
people
and a big thanks to dan a big thanks to
sophie and the hackaday team
everybody for putting us all together in
the same place
um and um uh another
uh uh another couple things i'm coming
to you from san francisco
and uh uh my neighbors are very keen on
fireworks so as the um
as the sun goes down we might hear some
explosions in the distance that's
totally normal
and uh probably to be expected um
and also i know it's been a long week
for a lot of us
um if for any reason you're not
following it i'm talking too much it's
not interesting it's not boring you have
a party to go to maybe you're just
burned out and need a nap
you can peace out at any time there's
zero shame
okay a lot of this is pretty technical
and i
realize if you're just kind of out of
brain cells for the moment
so um if there are questions you can ask
them in the chat
i've dropped a couple things in the chat
i'm going to be driving this thing
called vcv rack you can download it you
can follow along or you can just watch
me i don't know what's going to be
easier
or less taxing or more fun maybe if you
understand the principles you don't even
need me like as long as you understand
there's vcv rack you can download it and
play with it and
um they're probably some tutorials on
youtube that are better than me
so um it's all good all right
um with that let's get started
okay um i'm just gonna share my screen
with vcv rack i'm gonna make sure we can
all hear the noises that are going on
i have a couple slides i'm gonna be
bouncing to back and forth but mostly
we're gonna see vcd rack
um okay let me see if i can
play the button push the buttons here
first thing you need to know is you need
to select an audio output and you do
that through this menu here on the right
let me zoom out
control so you can see all the way on
the right here
almost on the way on the right is the
audio output
and you need to select your devices and
here i'm using my speakers
okay all right so if you've got vcv
running and um it is now using the
keyboard
on my laptop or on your laptop or on
your
system as a musical keyboard if you
press z
you should get a note okay so
um that's the basics that's
that's kind of how it works um and uh
we're gonna learn about what all these
little knobs and um
switches and these wires do
all right so um this is a uh
this is a way of generating music that's
called subtractive synthesis
and um let me just switch to a um
to a slide for a second here
okay
all right so um i think we're all kind
of got an engineering bent or maybe
a little kind of um technical uh
have our technical hat on so um this is
kind of a block diagram
of what we're seeing um or will be
seeing
in the um in the vcv rack okay we have a
keyboard which
generates a control voltage the control
voltage and i
apologize for all the um acronym solid
but that's just how this thing
is this is how it works um so um
vco stands for voltage controlled
oscillator
and this generates a tone that you
operate on with the
filter it's the also voltage controlled
so it's called a voltage controlled
filter
and then this goes into a voltage
controlled amplifier which can make it
make it louder or softer and all these
things are controlled by control
voltages which are generated by
different things
like a low frequency oscillator this
generates a control voltage to control
the the audio oscillator
and these are envelope generators also
called adsrs for attack
decay sustain and release and we'll talk
about all these
one at a time so let's start with the
voltage controlled oscillator
and so i'm going to switch back
okay and so you can see corresponding to
that
block diagram we have the voltage
controlled oscillator the vco
here and this is going into a voltage
controlled frequency
uh sorry voltage controlled filter the
output of that
goes into an amplifier in the mixer and
the output of that goes to your speakers
or to your audio device or your
headphones so you can hear them
okay so let's zoom in on the
voltage-controlled oscillator
okay
let me see okay so this has a number of
knobs and dials to the big knob and um
i need to apologize here um in that
this program um when um
uh when i'm adjusting a knob the pointer
disappears so it's not
obvious what i'm doing so i'm going to
try and make it very obvious
what i'm poking at when i poke at it so
right now
i'm just going to play a note and i'm
going to change this
frequency knob and you can hear how this
changes the frequency
turn it up turn it down but we'll just
let it sit in the middle there um and
here's a fine frequency adjustment
does the same thing but
this is good for tuning
[Music]
once again i'm adjusting the fine knob
here
all right and these things here these
are now wires these are patch cords
um in the old days if you these are
exactly like um analog synthesizer patch
cords except analog
synthesizer patch cords every problem
you've ever had with your headphone
patch cords
you can have these multiplied by the
number of patch cords you have
they go bad they go wonky sometimes they
don't work sometimes they don't plug all
the way in
but here and uh when you're doing analog
synthesizer you almost always run out of
patch cords but here these are infinite
and these are um these are
they're perfect they never go bad they
always work
so um these are jacks
on the bottom here these round double
circles here the white ones are input
jacks
and voltages go into them and the black
ones are
output jacks you can't this won't let
you
connect two outputs together because
usually nothing good happens with that
on an analog synthesizer um
that's not the case you can definitely
plug two outputs together and that's not
recommended
i should say that if you're interested
in analog synthesizers
this is a great way to get started with
this program
um if you're interested in eurorack
synthesizers in particular a lot of
eurorack
manufacturers make um
versions software versions of their
modules that you can drop
into this and um and uh experiment with
okay so i should mention that these are
all kind of modules that are all
um kind of standalone things and you can
mix and you can match them
and you can plug and you can unplug them
um
so right now this is the output of the
um voltage-controlled oscillator the
oscillator going to the input of the
frequent
of the filter so this is just this thing
this patch cord right here
and you can grab it and i can unplug it
and if i unplug it
nothing happens if i play a note there's
no sound coming out because we have not
taken the output we've broken this so
when you're doing this
uh it's very easy to get to a point
where
um nothing's working no sounds are
coming out
not the sounds you wanted to are coming
out so you do have to spend a little bit
of time
with your debugging hat on um if you're
a computer programmer
or your electrical engineer you're used
to working like like this with your
debugging hat on
if you're not that may take a little
getting used to but um
here's a pro tip um uh at least during
the workshop if you ever get stuck
and things aren't working like you want
to you can
basically pull the rip cord go up to the
file menu
um say new and this will just regenerate
that
basic patch that it started with
and that will make sure that you undo
any changes that you made all right
so um let's hook up that patch cord
again so click
on the sawtooth and can just drag it to
the input of the filter
and that's now connected again so
hopefully when i press a key i'm going
to press the z
we have a note here and a couple
switches here
this is analog digital the digital gives
you a little
cleaner digital looking waveform what's
really cool is it this is hooked up to
the oscilloscope here so we can see the
waveform
and um you can see the the frequency
change
the peaks of the waveform will get
closer together if we increase the
frequency
if i hit q that's an octave up so
that is double the number of um of
uh waves per time so that's twice the
frequency
all right so if i wanted just to get a
little um
[Music]
vibrato in here i could just play
and i could take this fine thing i could
just wobble that
[Music]
just get a little vibrato going in there
okay but let me introduce you to the
beauty of
control voltages and this is bob moog's
basic innovation
realizes that anything that you can turn
with a knob
you can turn with a control voltage and
a lot of all these
um modules uh create control voltages so
let's
add a um a what's called a low frequency
oscillator and this is a little module
that gives you
an uh a changing uh
voltage output which we can use to
control the voltage controlled
oscillator
so we can use it to control the
frequency of that to give it a little
vibrato
okay so i'm going to zoom out and i'm
going to show you
um how to add a module what you do is
you right click and this gives you a bit
i'm going to do this it's going to give
you a big menu
of all the possible modules that you can
have now these are the stock modules
if you go to vcv rack and you make a um
you make an account there's hundreds if
not thousands of other modules including
custom modules including modules that
look like other people's
um uh hardware eurorack modules that you
can actually spend money on and buy the
hardware and hook them together
okay so i'm going to add a voltage
controlled oscillator which is
the um i'm sorry the low frequency
oscillator which is here kind of in the
middle of the top
top thing so i'm just going to click on
that and that's put it down
on the bottom of the rack because i'm
zoomed out here
all right okay so this has a number of
control knobs too
and this um uh this the voltage
controlled oscillator is primarily for
audio
um audio uh range signals and the low
frequency oscillator is for lower
frequency
you can see how fast it's going it's
blinking this pseudo led
by how fast it's going and it's also got
a frequency knob i can turn it up and
you can see that's
blinking faster or or make it slower
okay so what i'm going to do now is i'm
going to patch this
so the low frequency oscillator is
controlling
the frequency of the vco
and it's got an input here called fm for
frequency modulator
modulation so i'm going to take the um
sine wave output of this
yeah actually let me i'm going to use
the square wave sqr stands for square
wave
output and i'm going to hook that up to
the frequency modulation input
okay and now when i hold down a key
nothing's going to happen until i turn
up this knob
which patches this control voltage input
to the actual frequency generation
stuff so if i'm going to give that a
little bit of a
a goose there take it off from
seven or eight o'clock where it was and
you can hear this
now changing the frequency
and it's doing it at a square wave so
it's doing it in discrete
um one zero uh increments now i can
increase this and get a larger change of
frequency
all right that's a good european siren
sound right there um
uh and i can also change the frequency
of the low frequency oscillator using
this knob down here
so so you just hear what that sounds
like faster
slower
[Music]
all right so um this is the fundamentals
of
voltage control synthesis where you can
use all these modules and a whole bunch
of them
and you can use the output of a of a
audio frequency oscillator to modulate
the frequency of another
audio frequency oscillator and that is
um that gives you some really
interesting
um um
frequency modulation sounds um
for instance i'm now going to change
this uh actually
before i do that i'm just going to turn
that i'm going to look at the various
outputs
of our voltage controlled oscillator so
right now this is a sawtooth
and you can see on the scope here and
let me zoom in a little bit
is this okay people um people seeing
things is this
too fast too slow people still with me
and once again if this is boring or too
much of me yakking
feel free to peace out at any time
i think it looks good so far okay good
good
um and we'll take a break um uh
uh in about 45 minutes and i'll i'll
take a couple little breaks so if people
are just playing along
uh you can uh twiddle some of the knobs
and just seeing um
see see how that works hey jonathan yes
sir
uh someone is just asking about um
vcv on a rack i'm sorry on a vcv rack on
a mac
with all the default settings was just
installed i can see the oscillator
moving but
um when the when i push keyboard buttons
but there's no sound coming out
okay i i can't not diagnose everything
but
one of the things you might need to do
is check your audio output and there's a
menu here
um it's going to be different on a mac
because this is a mac but i'm running
windows boo hiss there's a menu here
which says
which audio device you want output and
hopefully
that will do the right thing on the
macintosh and if there are any um
mac enthusiasts that can help uh with
some advice
on the chat that'd be great looks like
people are pitching in on the chat so i
think we'll be good
awesome thank you that was it thanks yep
great great
oh hey somebody's actually paying
attention all right so um if you're
joining us if you're joining us
late thank you for joining the workshop
here um
a lot of material i realize it's been a
long week um
and uh thank you i hope this is fun and
cool and
uh i i'm stoked to share this with you
um
all right so let's go back to the
oscillator because that has a number of
outputs that has four of these outputs
here
um the sawtooth uh
you can play a note look it on the scope
and guess why that's called a
sawtooth all right let's change i'm
going to unplug the sawtooth here
and plug in the square wave maybe zoom
in a little bit so you can see that and
play a note and hey that's a square wave
and note how it sounds different
sounds it has a different timbre from
the sawtooth
let's go back to the sawtooth
and go to the square wave okay
now here's a fun thing you can do which
is um two more of these knobs
on the voltage controlled oscillator you
can change the pulse width of the square
wave
if you're an engineer this is pulse
width modulation and you can change the
duty
cycle and the scope makes it pretty
clear what's happening
when we twiddle this knob so let's
change the pulse width and see what
happens
so that that really changes the harmonic
content
of the of the notes we're getting from
the oscillator
and it's really good to have a lot of
harmonic content
you can have the sine wave output
typically that's not used very much
because that just gives you a sine wave
and that doesn't do much in the filter
or any of the upstream stuff
it's a very very pure pure note
um to actually get some nice synthesizer
sounds you want to start with a
harmonically rich
um content like the sawtooth or the
square tooth
square wave or you take that square wave
all the way down make it narrow make a
pulse
[Music]
okay
and um those all sound different because
they have different uh harmonic
content um yeah let me let me just
switch
quickly to a slide i have a couple
slides um
illustrate a couple of the principles
here um
give me a second here
okay all right
um hopefully people can see this uh this
diagram
okay we're using subtractive synthesis
and the way that works is you start with
a harmonically rich waveform
like we're getting out of the
voltage-controlled oscillator the vco
and you put that into a filter and that
removes
or accentuates some of the harmonics and
then that gives you kind of a richer
more interesting frequency output
and a lot of instruments in the human
voice work this way
um the human voice you start with this
kind of very buzzy
um signal from your vocal cords um uh
people can put tiny microphones down
your vocal tract while you're speaking
and it's kind of this
um terrifying darth vader buzzy buzzy
sound
and then what that happens is that it
gets filtered by your vocal tract which
has the resonant cavities in your mouth
and your nose
um and smooths off some of the buzziness
and gives the characteristic vowels the
ahs and the ease
and then the final output um
is the uh is your speaking voice your
vowels and a lot of um
a lot of uh uh acoustic instruments work
the same way too you start with
an excitation voltage and a brass
instrument that you're
kind of buzzing your lips or a clarinet
it's a reed
um and it goes through uh a resonant
cavity
like the body of a violin or the body of
a guitar which kind of shapes
this um this uh this initial um
excitation waveform and it smooths it
out and accentuates some frequency and
filters out some others so you get a
more interesting more musically valid
um output and um uh
a really great way to think about this
is in the frequency domain so you start
with
a um uh with an excitation signal that
has a lot of high frequency components
if it's a square wave
it looks like this i think one over f
one over f squared
i can't remember but in school at some
point they made me calculate the fourier
transform
of a of a sawtooth wave and you got all
these nice harmonics
and what you do is you put that into the
filter and that's our voltage controlled
filter which we'll be talking about
really soon and that will filters out
some of the harmonics or lets you
accentuate some other harmonics
and that gives you kind of a more
interesting musically valid
um sound on the output all right
just to remind everybody of
jean-baptiste fourier in 1740 whatever
proved that you can make a square wave
just by adding up a bunch of sine waves
and you can do the same thing with a
sawtooth
or something here's a here's a square
wave and you
add up a whole bunch of sinusoids and
the more sinusoids you add
the more it looks like a square wave and
these are the amplitudes of the sine
waves notice there's no
even uh harmonics just the odd ones and
if you do
the math of the actual uh fourier
transform that's what you get
and so these are these are harmonics
these are uh musicians sometimes call
them partial
if you play a guitar you know you can
pick a harmonic out on the string just
by putting
uh putting your finger on the middle
fret and damping out
um damping out the fundamental um so
these are our marble that we're gonna
chip
into a beautiful musical sculpture using
the filter
so it's good to start out with a very
rich
um rich harmonic content and here's some
uh harmonic content of the various
things we can get
from our voltage-controlled oscillator
you can get the sine wave
and that's a little boring because that
doesn't have any high frequencies
there that's just got the pure
fundamental um
the square wave has the odd harmonics
the triangular wave has
odd harmonics but they go down quicker
the sawtooth wave
has lots of juicy harmonics and if you
make a pulse wave it has even more
harmonics and those change depending on
the
pulse width of your pulse
so let's go back to our vcv rack
and you can hear how these things are
different so once again here's a square
wave and this sounds to my ears you can
kind of imagine it's like a clarinet
the clarinet has the read it's either on
or off it gives you this kind of
uh the read is either open or closed
captioning not
[Music]
one more available um and this is a
little pro tip
um remember how uh i could use the low
frequency oscillator let me zoom out a
little bit
uh if i turn up the um control voltage
to get a little um turn up the frequency
here too
to get a little vibrato here
yeah let me let me change this now to a
um
to a a triangle wave
all right maybe that's a little too much
i'm going to take down the modulation
the frequency modulation a little bit
and i'm going to
bring up the frequency a little bit
so that's a little bit of vibrato you
can imagine an opera singer
um doing that or if you're playing the
theremin you wobble your fist
near the um you're the uh antenna to get
this
get a little bit of um frequency
modulation
but let's do some pulse width modulation
okay so i'm going to
unplug the frequency modulation i'm
going to plug this into the pulse width
modulation
and um once again this knob
now that controls how much this
oscillator is controlling the pulse
width i'm going to turn it down so you
can hear what it's doing
i need to turn this up whoops
oh yes i also need to listen to the
square wave which is the actual
pulse wave so you can see how that's
changing with time
and that gives you a kind of a nice um
nice
uh time time varying a little richer
tone
um and uh uh here's uh here's a pro tip
if we turn up
the frequency a lot
[Music]
we get these inharmonic stuff this is
kind of the rave hoover sound so if you
want to be the rude
so that is uh that's a classic um
electro rave hoover
sound which is um pulse width modulation
at a pretty high frequency
how we doing on time okay it's been half
an hour let's take just a short break
and people can
play um play play around with things and
uh when we come back in like just two or
three minutes super short
we will um we will do the filter and
that's kind of where the magic happens
at the synthesizer
um but uh feel free to plug and
patch and twiddle some knobs okay
so back in like three minutes
and that will give me a chance to also
check the comments
we have a request to zoom out a little
bit to show yes
yeah if you could favor a little bit to
the left because uh a lot of us have the
uh
gallery view sort of on the right there
and it's brick
it's blocking things how how close to
a hardware setup is this gonna look
um if you get i'm not sure you can buy
this actual hardware but this
is very similar if you buy a mini moog
or um a lot of uh
eurorack things will work very very
similarly so
i think that's the most important thing
i've learned so far is the correct
pronunciation of moog
all right i've always assumed it was
just moog
yeah i think it's moog i think it's mode
i think you're right yeah
okay so a little uh little uh sidebar
here
so in order to get a rich sur sound you
can stack
these um oscillators and uh
uh because if they're analog oscillators
are never
at precisely the exact frequency um you
can um
you can uh get a little bit of richer
sound by adding in a couple of
oscillators and
wendy carlos for switched on box she
used um
six of the mode voltage control
oscillators um
there's a guy on youtube who uh hooked
up a thousand of them
and it sounds pretty dope as you might
imagine it sounds
it sounds very very fat but um if you're
not used to um
analog synthesizers you only get one
note at a time
um and without a little bit of reverb or
a little bit of delay and i'll show you
how to hook that up
um it can sound a little bit thin so
um and uh all this stuff
you need to um uh understand that uh
this is uh this is a musical instrument
takes a little practice and uh
understanding to get to know how to use
so hopefully i can give you the pointers
to get some sounds out of it but to be a
paganini you'll take some practice
all right um let's move on to the filter
and the filter is kind of where the
magic happens and this is the
how you get some of those very very
classic classic synthesizer
um sounds and what the filter does
is you might imagine by the name it's uh
filtering out
harmonics it's um it's a frequency uh
dependent filter that lets some
frequencies through
and cuts some frequencies out and um
this uh this big knob changes the
frequency
and um uh right now it's set all the way
down
because it's being controlled by this
thing called the envelope generator
which we'll talk about in a couple
minutes
um okay right now
let's take down i'm going to take down
the control voltage so i'm going to
basically
remove the um influence of the envelope
generator
and this will just let me play with the
with the
filter by itself okay so um
i think that will do it now if i play
something
you won't hear anything that's because
the filter is all the way down it's
filtered out
all the frequencies but if i can turn it
up
might be able to see something yeah you
can see something on the scope
oh yeah let me turn down this annoying
pulse width modulation
i just so i just did that so goodbye ray
hoover
and as you turn up the frequency you
hear more and more high frequencies
so it gets brighter and crisper
[Music]
and this is the kind of classic synth
sound words which is a filter sweep
[Music]
okay so i'm just i'm just dragging this
i'm just turning this knob
manually but once again we can use um
a free a low frequency oscillator i'm
going to take the um
unplug it from the pwm and
this is the frequency control input i'm
going to unplug the envelope generator
for now remind me i need to plug that
back in again
okay and i'm going to plug our low
frequency oscillator into the voltage
control frequency
so now um
you just go down and this is the
triangle wave output so you can hear
[Music]
i can i need to turn this up a little
bit
let me also turn down the the frequency
here
so now you can hear how the the um
the filter is changing over time and we
can make that higher
for a brighter sound where we can make
it lower
for a kind of warmer duller sound
and we can make it solo we filter out
all the sound completely
it's just gone it's quiet okay
so that's a low pass filter this is the
one you usually use because you usually
want the fundamental
but there's also a high pass filter so
let's listen to that
and this will be a lot brighter because
this is only letting the high
frequencies through
that's kind of cool and if we turn this
all the way down
it's a high pass filter so now
and i'm i apologize if that's too loud
let me take that down
here a little bit on the mixer now this
is
super bright super zingy super electric
and as we turn this up the high pass
filter we're removing more and more low
frequencies so we'll get even buzzier
and so all we're left is just the high
harmonics
just those crispy edges of the high
harmonics of this pulse width
let me turn up the pulse width here
okay so that's the high pass filter
let me um go back to the low-pass filter
and uh
uh do it here
[Music]
okay so this is kind of where the magic
happens or those classic analog
synthesizer sounds is in the
is in the um is in the uh voltage
control filter
and there's one more magic thing here
which is called the resonance and if
you're electrical engineer
you've seen this um as the q factor of a
filter
and um let me just show you what happens
when you trim this up what this does is
this
accentuates the peak around the filter
cut off and this lets you
basically not only cut out particular
frequencies that
lets you boost them too so i'm going to
turn this up and you can hear it
[Music]
let me turn up the volume here a little
bit too
yes sir the green cable on the vfc
or the vcf is that connected to the
triangle or to the square wave output of
the lfo
right now it's connected to the triangle
triangle okay thank you someone had a
question on that yeah that's a good one
that's a good one
okay so why wow
and um uh if you if you turn it up high
enough
it's gonna whistle it'll resonate
and um i'm gonna turn the volume down
because that can be really shrieking and
very loud because this thing is not
coming out of the oscillator this
this thing is coming out of the
that filter is the filter itself
oscillating
okay um let me quickly just show you a
picture of what's going on in the
frequency domain because that might make
it a little bit clearer
okay remember this is our raw materials
these uh
these uh high frequencies and their
partials
this is what the filter does you
basically multiply it by this
and this is um different amounts that
you've turned up the resonance if it's
got a low resonance
um it's got a very uh normal shoulder
it's got a very flat response if you
turn up that resonance
you get a little bit more peak at the
center frequency
so um the the um the resonance the q
knob is changing how peaky the filter is
and the big filter knob the big knob in
the center
is changing where where the center
frequency is in the frequency domain
here whoops i didn't mean to
scroll but that kind of illustrated it
so
those give you two things and if you
have the resonant
frequency turned up enough it more or
less looks like a bandpass filter
because the low frequencies here are um
are the high frequencies here are gone
low frequencies here are not boosted
but the center frequencies are boosted a
lot so this is a
this is a um this is essentially a
bandpass filter
and uh you can turn that up so it only
the things
in this bandpass are what you hear
so let's go back to the rack
and um this is this is really
interesting
because um you can use this as a
i'm going to turn down the control
voltage here
actually i'm just going to unplug that
completely so now we've got pretty high
[Music]
resonance
and what you should be able to do is
pick out the higher frequencies
just by changing our frequency here so
let me see if i can do that
let me turn it up a little bit
so there
[Music]
so that's the first harmonic you can
hear it's an octave
[Music]
and then you go up to the harmonic
sequence the harmonic series which is
uh twice the the fundamental that's an
octave three times the fundamental
that's an octave and a fifth
four times the oct the fundamental
that's an octave of fifth and a third
and so forth and so on and really
interestingly
pretty quickly it gets out of the um the
12 tone scale so if you want some micro
tones to play with
um you can get them out of the harmonic
series and they're all
fundamentally um harmonically related to
the fundamental which is that pitch
that you're hearing um
okay um so i think that's really cool
that's a really
kind of natural way to understand the
harmonic series
uh where you can actually pick them out
using the bandpass filter
to uh to kind of zero in on them
but let's let's push on let's talk about
the envelope generator
okay so all this things have been kind
of constant
if things have been changing with time
they've been changing
using using these oscillators which just
go back and forth
so let's talk about the envelope
generator too
and that's called adsr here and that's
for
attack decay sustain and release
so let's zoom out and look a little bit
at the big picture now
okay so in here on the far left here
this is the midi slash control voltage
thing this is generating
from the keyboard it's generating a
control voltage which controls the pitch
of the oscillator
this is also generating um a trigger
and a gate these are these are basically
digital signals and some
uh synthesizers they're just ttl they're
on
off signals um the gate is high when you
have a key pressed down
and when you release the key the gate
goes off
so it's high when the key is down and
it's low when the key is up
and um you can hook that into the scope
and watch that if you want to
um but i think uh i think i'll just have
you take my
my word for it right now but right now
that gate
is plugged into the adsr
and the trigger the rtrg this gives you
a pulse every time a key is pressed
and so the gate tells you when a key is
down
and the re-trigger gives you a pulse
every time a key
is pressed and what the adsr this is a
little sequencer
this is a little um finite state machine
if you're an engineer
and it's triggered by this trigger
signal every time you press the key down
it steps through these four steps attack
decay
sustain release all right so
um if i press the button uh press a key
um you should you should see it just
walk right through let me
let me um make things a little slower
okay so this is a little weird it goes
attack decay
sustain release attack and decay are
times they are durations
um releases of duration one odd person
out here is sustained
this is a level um yeah let's let me see
if i can actually plug this into the
scope
and i'll scooch over here so hopefully
people can see this
um
and let's take the output
of the of the adsr now this is generated
a control voltage output
not an audio output so um
if you want to patch two things from the
same output you hit control
so i can hit control on the output and
patch that
into the x and i think i need to take
down the time base of the scope
now unfortunately this doesn't work like
a trigger
as you'd expect if you're used to
oscilloscopes so uh you just got to get
lucky to catch it
um so we'll see um hear it okay good i
got it
so what's happening is it has a long
attack
it has a long decay the sustain is a
level
and it has a long release because all
these knobs are up if i turn down the
attack
to very short let me see if i can catch
it you can see it that attack is really
short
let me turn down the time base here
okay if i increase the attack here you
can see how it's slower
on the attack let me catch it
there we go and you can make it really
slow so it kind of swoops up
and you make it even slower so it really
slowly swoops up
all right and the decay is how quickly
um
it comes down after after it's after it
hits the peak
so i'm going to turn down the attack all
the way so it's a quick attack
and here we got a long decay let's make
a short decay
i got to catch it there we go
so you can see it comes down quickly
after it hits that peak or we can
give it a long decay which means it'll
come down slower
there we go all right now like i said
this
third one is um and uh actually what's
nice about this
particular envelope generator is it you
can see
what stage you're in by these little
indicator lights
so if i make everything slow you can
actually and you hit a key you can
walk see it walk through the various
stages
[Music]
attack decay sustain release
now sustain is the level that it will
hold while i'm holding down the key
so if i turn this all the way down and i
hold down the key
all you hear is the attack and the decay
so i'm going to make them both pretty
short
whoops too short
so this is good for like pluck strings
where you don't have a lot of decay
but if you want an organ sound if you
want a brass sound you want a little bit
more sustain
to hold that note while you're holding
the key down
[Music]
and if you want to remove the decay
completely you just turn the sustain all
the way up
and this is like a brass where it's loud
and it doesn't really decay
all right so if the sustain is all the
way up
this is the level then the decay doesn't
matter and the release is how long it
lasts when you
pick up the key so if you want a nice
bell tone
um you can turn the sustain all the way
down
and turn up the release a little bit
this will give you a xylophone
or a plucked string if you turn it all
the way up you get bells
whoops i'm sorry the release only
releases uh the level that
it was at the sustain there we go
so that's a really long release
so if you want nice bell tones or
marimbas or xylophones or gongs
you'll you'll add in a little bit of bit
of release
here okay how are we doing on time we're
45 minutes into it hopefully people are
um
people are doing okay um at the hour
mark or a little bit before the hour
mark we'll take a break
you can do a bio break um hopefully
people are sticking with this and this
isn't going too fast
um break is in sight um
just a couple other things i want to
show you before the break
there is a there is a question in the uh
in the chat if you want to take a look
at that
yeah yeah let me take a look at the chat
where is the chat where'd my chat go
there we go
oh yes go over trigger gate um
okay couple questions here um
okay a question holding a key and
pressing another doesn't reset the adsr
is that because any all signals coming
from midi cv count as on versus treating
keys separately i think that is the case
there
is a um there is a uh
vcv rack we'll do some polyphony in
other words it will do multiple notes
um from the um from the um
uh midi input i'm not sure how that
works from the keyboard
a lot of computer keyboards are not set
up for polyphony so you can't tell when
you have two
keyboard keys down like uh
uh qwerty keys so um i think
that's a little limitation just of the
computer keyboards
that you can't retrigger when you hit
another key
but this retrigger thing will give you a
pulse
every time you hit a key so the
retrigger
starts the sequence and what the gate
does is it tells you
how long to sustain so the gate will
as long as the gate is held high
you will be in sustain so i just hit a
key
i need to get back to um my screen share
here
there we go so you you can actually see
how this works because of the little
indicator lights as long as i hold down
a key
the gate light will be asserted it will
be
lit but i'll only get a little pulse
from the re-trigger
but every time you hit a key another key
you'll see a little pulse
on the retriever
so hopefully that that that cleared that
up and so
so the the um the
uh envelope generator needs both signals
it need
uses the retrigger to know when to
trigger the state machine that just
walks through the attack decay sustain
release
and it needs to know you use the gate to
know how long
to hold the sustain for to know when
you're sustaining
when you release the key the gate goes
low and then you're
into the release part of the the um of
the state machine
okay
great okay um let me just show you two
quick little tricks here um
uh control out so if you're just
noodling away with this
um these sounds can be a little bit um
a little bit um not compelling
um if you're uh
uh just playing along at home or
something uh i really recommend adding a
delay or a reverb it just makes a sound
a little bit
richer a little bit more
lifelike um and to show you how to add
the uh
delay um uh let's talk a little bit
about
a final module which is the um uh
voltage controlled amplifier
now that's kind of hidden in this patch
in the mixer it's built
into the mixer and that's why
the voltage-controlled oscillator is
oscillating all the time
the reason we can't we're not hearing it
all the time
is because we have the envelope
generator plugged into
a um voltage controlled amplifier that's
in
built into the mixer if i
unplug it i'm going to turn the volume
down here on the mixer
and maybe zoom into that a little bit if
i unplug that
the control voltage of this amplifier
then it's on all the time
right and that's super annoying which is
why i didn't do that
okay so let's actually add in um
a uh a module that's a voltage
controlled amplifier because that's a
handy thing to have
let me just move some stuff around here
so there's room for it
and you can grab all these things and
just
move them around so what i'm going to do
is i'm going to right click
i'm going to add a vca a voltage
controlled amplifier
i'm going to use the output of the
envelope generator
and once again control gives you a
another patch cord from an output that
goes to the control voltage input
um uh the output of our low pass filter
instead of going into the mixer that's
going to go
to the input of our voltage controlled
amplifier and now the output of our
voltage controlled amplifier
will go to the input of our mixer and i
need to remember
to turn up the mixer again now this is
just duplicating
the little voltage-controlled amplifier
that's built into the mixer
because you use it all the time they
kind of made that a normal part of the
process here so now hopefully if i've
done this right
we get our normal patch back okay
but now since we have this one wire
contains all our audio
after the um uh
after the amplifier we can now stick in
some other things so let's stick in a
delay
all right so someplace here is a delay
yeah right there on the top row
is a delay okay
and so now i'm going to take the output
of the
voltage controlled amplifier i'm going
to put it into the delay
um and i can uh take the output of the
delay
and put that back into our mixer so we
can hear it
okay and uh this is the mix
um this is the color uh feedback and
time if you use to delay pedals on a
guitar um you're used to this and now
let's
uh play a note and that
that gives us just a little bit more um
uh more slap back we can increase the
time
of the echo and this is fun to play
around with you can do
polyrhythmic stuff
[Music]
or you can make that shorter for a
little slapback echo
increase the feedback
sounds a little bit more like a reverb a
little bit more like a room
the color um uh rolls off the high
frequencies like if you're in a
absorbent room
not sure how how um
how um uh
easy that is to hear um and the final
knob here is the mix
if you put that all the way wet all you
get is reverb
if you put out all the way dry all you
get is the direct signal
without any delay so this lets you mix
in how much
delay you actually want
all right okay um let's take a little
break let's take
five minutes um um oh uh
i think i need to feed my cap i will
come back i will get to some questions
in the chat
um uh and uh in the next
part of the um uh workshop we will
do a little um drum machine and we'll uh
play some more with triggers and gates
and uh
we'll use the resonance of the
voltage-controlled filter and we'll do
a craft fork snare and an 808 kick drum
sound and put those all together with a
sequencer
and um and that should be fun but uh
let's take a little break
and i'll be back in five and um i'll
check out the chat
john can you just zoom out again so
people can see your patch if they want
to um
yeah replicate it thank you all right
see everybody in a couple minutes
and we're back hello everybody thanks
for sticking with us
um i'm really stoked that everybody
decided to join us for this
um thanks again to the hackaday people
for making a community
um i hope this is interesting at least
some people stuck
stuck through it and once again i want
to remind you that
you're under no compunction to stick
through this i know
um on the east coast it's probably
getting to be kind of party time
or maybe you're um you're a little
pooped from a long and stressful week
for a lot of us if you need to take a
nap
um there's absolutely uh you can you can
leave with my blessing
um uh so anyway let's let's um
let's move on okay um and uh
thank you for all the comments in the
chat there are some
there are some great um
there are some great links uh the
fourier
uh visualization from uh three blue one
brown
uh the um uh keith whitman fullerton's
uh eurorack set up
and you realize how nice it is to have
virtual patch cords which are infinite
and don't get on top of each other
so you can still see what's going on
so thanks everybody let me go back
to our
vcv rack something i forgot to mention
this is all open source
i've been meaning to work on the scope
and actually make the trigger trigger
like the scopes i'm used to
if you right click on the um
on the um on any particular
module there's a
plugin menu and you can go to the source
code this will take you right to the
github
repository for the source code for that
module so if you want to get into
audio programming this is not a bad way
to do this
um to see how uh some of these modules
work and they're kind of
small and um modular uh so you only need
to worry about one little bit of the
whole thing at a time
um okay uh let
us um start from scratch here i'm just
gonna
uh go to file and i'm gonna go new
and uh to start from scratch uh
i don't need to save this so i'm gonna
say okay you might want to save yours
okay and i need to remember to reset the
audio to my
um speakers so i can hear it
and uh we'll start from scratch here and
uh
just do a little bit of um
do a little bit of uh sanity checking
i'm just gonna play
a note i can hear that hopefully you can
okay there's one one more um
uh audio source that i didn't get to
um in our first half and uh it's a noise
source
and that turns out to be surprisingly
musically useful you don't think
noise is actually that musical but um a
lot of things
have noisy components a lot of
percussion
um is not pitched um a lot of even
pitched
uh notes like a calliope has a little
kind of steam chuff
um when it's turning on
when the note on the onset of the note
so to get a little
flute or calliope sound sometimes you'll
just mix in a little bit of um
white noise so let's let's um pull up
a uh hang a sec let me move things
around here
oh wrong thing
pardon me my thing has gone off the
screen so i can't grab it
i'm sure all right i'll just make do
with what we got here
um and uh
thanks again to dan for running
interference on the questions
um don't have quite enough screen to
have my
chat and every all the controls up so i
apologize if i'm missing things as they
go by
in the chat ah there we go got it
okay um so let's add a noise source i'm
gonna right click
and uh someplace
is the noise here it is on the second
column almost all the way to the right
um let me
see if i can do that over here nope
always comes up in the same place
so anyway i'm just going to click on
that i'm going to grab that i'm going to
put that down here
okay let me zoom in a little bit
okay so now what i'm going to do is
instead of the output of the
voltage controlled oscillator going into
our patch here
i'm going to disconnect that i'm going
to add the noise
it's just some white noise and there's
various flavors of noise white pink red
green and so you can hear what the
filter is now doing to the noise
that's kind of kind of got a good good
sounds like wind through
trees or something like that in fact if
i take down
the envelope generator i think 12
o'clock
means that's not doing anything you can
hear what the
filter does to the noise
just by changing the filter cutoff
frequency so if you need
spooky wind sounds for your science
fiction for your horror movie or
something this is a good way to get them
or if you want to do a surf generator
for those relaxing surf tones
you can do it using the noise now the
different colors of the noise
are basically refer to the spectral
uh content pink noise has a little less
high frequency in a now
in analogy with light
pink light has um less blue and more red
more lower frequency spectrum and so
so does the pink noise here let me turn
the filter all the way up so
so uh you can hear that that's white
pink red it just gets
more filtered violet is on high
frequency and low frequency but not much
middle uh blue is high frequency
very hissy um gray and black are
different
um are different uh
probability distributions i think black
is a uniform distribution and white is a
gaussian
i forget what gray is
okay so um white is pretty good for
most audio things you can also use the
noise
as control voltages um to if you want
ever want
random inputs or make things a little
bit more human
or unpredictable you can use the noise
all right but one of the things um i'm
going to do now here is going to use the
noise
for a kind of a um a um
a classic uh uh snare sound
and um let me see if i can do this
manually if i
hit the trigger and i sweep the filter
you can kind of that's kind of a classic
um
uh analog um
snare sound like the tr-808 or something
like that or
cross-veric a lot of their snare sounds
is basically just white
noise that's gone through a filter suite
so
um all i need to do to do that is to get
the um
adsr to use the envelope generator to
generate a nice little sweep
just to go swoop right down and we don't
need any um
sustain so we can do this all in the
attack and the decay
so um i need to remember to turn up the
control voltage so the um
envelope generator is affecting the
frequency of the
filter so i'm going to turn that up i'm
going to turn down the filter so we
actually get a good
sweep and then now um
turn down the attack and turn down the
decay here
there we go
[Music]
so that's a little bit high let's turn
up the frequency
and maybe the resonance too so it's a
little bit more obvious what's going on
i'm going to turn down the sustain so
there we go
so that's actually not a bad electro
snare
sound all right
okay um let's go over the gates and the
triggers now
we don't necessarily have to trigger
this by the keyboard
we can add a sequencer module so let's
do that right now
and we will trigger our snare from a
sequencer
so i'm going to right click and it's
this seek three it's this big module on
the second row
with all the knobs and outputs
okay what this is is this is a state
machine it's just
walking there are eight states
or steps as they're called you can
change the number
of steps using this knob here let me
zoom into that so
people can see that um you can change
the number of steps
using this knob here um the gate
is um it's generate this is an output is
generating a um
an output um gate
and um these are trigger outputs when
it's in a particular state
it will generate a trigger and it's a
little hard to see but you can see um
it's a little brighter green when it's
in this particular state
so it's just walking left to right if
you've ever used a um
ever built a larson scanner from evil
mad scientist or a
led sequencer is exactly the same thing
um
it's just stepping one two three four
and then going
right back and that's run off this
internal clock you can use an external
clock
but right now it's doing the internal
and this button it's a button you can
start it and stop it using the button
so let's use this gate output to trigger
our snare so that snare is coming
from right now the trigger is coming
from the keyboard
so let us um unplug
the um the trigger from our keyboard
and plug it into the gate now this is
just going to go bang bang bang bang
bang so i'm going to mute it quickly
using the
mixer but
let's see do i need to do a gate 2 yes i
need
all right why isn't why aren't we
hearing that
let's just do the gate there we go
all right i'm gonna i'm gonna mute that
using the
mixer just so it's not on all the time
and it's not
super annoying i can also start it and
stop it
using the um sequencer so
turning it back up
stop and run stop um
something like that okay well that's
kind of annoying because that's giving
us a
um snare hit on every beat what if we
want it on every other beat
well that's where we can use these
trigger outputs down here
and to do that i'm going to use another
thing
which will let us combine
multiple triggers these are all outputs
we can't all hook them up to the same
gate
we need to mix them first or add them so
i'm going to
add another module which is where did it
go
i can just scroll down
oops
where is the module i'm looking for here
it is it's called unity
it's on the far left of the top row
okay and um what this is this is just a
dumb little mixer it has a bunch of
inputs and it combines them all into the
same output
and you can average them all or you can
sum them all
and for audio you might want to use
average
for in this case we're using it for
trigger signals so
it doesn't really matter but some works
just great so what i'm going to do is
i'm going to take the
output of this and plug it into the gate
let me go back up here
once again this is the gate that
triggers the adsr
which is triggering our filter which is
sweeping our noise
and now i can use
individual outputs of the sequencer
steps to trigger
the um the um
the snare so um here i can do it on
let's do it
on beats two and four
and um i'm gonna change the number of
steps here to four steps
so um i think that's four
let me count one one two
three four well we can try and see
okay so you can see only doing it on two
and four there's nothing on one and
three
so it sounds like it's on one and three
but it's on two and four
okay so we can do it on one and four
and so forth and so on so this is how we
can get
slightly more um complicated um
uh sequencers and there's another thing
you can do
um before oops give me a second here
before we're done with the sequencer all
these knobs
these generate a control voltage output
so um this row one here this is um on
every step you can output a different
voltage
and if you want to make a nice um
sequence run like you remember those
tangerine dream albums um where you have
a little bit of um
this motoric repeating um notes uh you
can
program each one of these knobs to give
you a different control voltage output
um in fact let let me try this right now
and um i'm going to take this row one
output
and i'm going to hook it into the um
[Music]
let me see uh the resonance
of the um the uh filter
i hope this works um
this may be this may be a little intense
and now
using these two knobs corresponding to
these two things we can change the
resonance
depending on the beat hopefully this
works
okay we're on row one here so
yes there we go
so that second beat
has a higher resonance and you can hear
the filter sweep you can hear that
hear that resonance actually going down
okay well that's a good way to get a um
that filter sweep is a good way to get a
um
a syndrome sound um or an 808 kick
if you take it down so let's do a let's
do a syndrome
using that exact um principle of
using a filter at resonance
to um to uh generate a sound so we're
going to need a
another envelope generator and we're
going to need another filter
but those are easy to add so i'm going
to do those right over here
okay let's add a filter
where is the filter
here we go vcf filter third one
in on the top row and we're going to add
another
envelope generator right click
adsr all right
so here i'm going to put the ads on the
left
and i'm going to hook up the output of
the adsr
to the um
to the frequency of the filter so this
is going to control the frequency
we don't need to worry about the input
because we're going to turn up the
resonance high enough
that the filter itself is oscillating
okay um i'm just gonna hook up
the trigger um
[Music]
the gate and the trigger to the keyboard
just so i can test this now
so let me zoom out a bit
gate to the gate and the re-trigger
to the re-trigger
and now i need to hook up the low-pass
filter to the filter to the um
to the mixer here so we can actually
hear it
low pass filter up to input two on the
mixer
okay and here you can actually hear it
now
so i'm going to turn down the frequency
so that's a little bit lower
because it's now resonating
okay
so now if i hit a key
let me turn up the cv2 here
there we go
and i'm going to turn down the sustain
because we don't need any
and turn down the release
let's turn down the frequency so that's
now infrasonic
and there we have a little bit of a
syndrome
okay
now um if you turn this down a little
bit more you get a lovely lovely um 808
kick sound
and um on my little laptop speakers you
can't hear this but if you're wearing um
headphones
it's a really lovely resonant um
big tom tom kick sound
so if you take that thing all the way
down
and you can make it last a little longer
by turning down the decay
or even longer
and then going back okay i'm going to
keep that in the audio frequency just so
people who aren't
using headphones can actually hear it if
you're using a
laptop speaker that may be a little
a little hard to hear if the frequency
is too low but
plug this into a nice um amplifier
system
and you can rattle the roof trust me on
this
and this is good fun with an analog
synthesizer and a high power amplifier
and some good speakers you can really
really annoy the neighbors
good times okay so now we have
um two pretty decent um
uh drum sounds we have our uh snare
sound
and we have our um uh syndrome
let's um let's secret some of them both
now so now i'm going to
disconnect the keyboard that i was using
to test
our syndrome and now we can hook up the
gate
to um to the output and now this will
trigger this on
beat 1 and the snare drums on beat 2 and
b4
so there we go we got a little drum
machine i'm now going to um
use our little mixer here to um
get more beats um from the syndrome
so let me
zoom in a bit okay so i'm going to take
that gate out
now and i'm going to hook the gate from
this output
and now anything any trigger that go
into this
little mixer here um now will trigger
our syndrome over here
so let's just do that on one and four
i'm sorry one and three so you can see
what i'm doing here
and now if i start this we should get
boom chick boom chick boom check
good stuff and we can change the
frequency
good stuff if you want um
a little bit more syncopation let's go
down to all eight beats
and now we can let's do um
so if this is a bar with four beats and
this is a second bar with four beats
on the second bar let's do um syndrome
on first and uh
second beats and the snare on the third
okay and here we go
good times and now we can mix the
various
drum sounds using our mixer
that's the snare and this is the
syndrome
okay and the last thing i'm going to
show you here is using our
control voltages here um
to affect the um the resonance of the
vcf
here um to make this a little louder or
softer
okay so row two over here the resonance
and now this is the second row here so
if you want um
patch here is getting a little
complicated but we can zoom in
here and uh anything going to this
channel 2
is our syndrome that's on 2
and um
some one and three here rather so we can
turn these up
and get a little bit more resonance and
see what that sounds like
all right yeah actually to be honest
that actually doesn't change the sound
very much because the resonance is so
high that it's oscillating now
if i wanted to i could mix that in with
the frequency using another mixer
but i think right now um
that's about most of the things i wanted
to show you
hopefully this gives you an idea that
this thing exists it's in the world
um how to add in uh how to patch things
how to add
add and subtract modules um there any
questions or anything
um i can definitely take them off the
chat
okay where did my chat go chat
[Music]
i don't see any questions in the chat
right now um the one question
i had before was uh could you recreate
the uh
the the gated reverb uh
classic sound of the 80s like from in
the air tonight and things like that is
there a way to do
a uh something like that bearing in mind
that i have no idea how it was
originally done
for phil collins drums or anything like
that but i just thought
you know when when i saw the the term
gates in the sequencer it made me think
of gated reverb
absolutely that's a great question
that's a great question
and that would be easy to do except
right now i'm only using the stock
modules
what you need is a reverb and right now
there is not if you scroll down here
there is not a reverb in the stock
modules there are probably lots of
reverbs if you sign in to um the vcv
rack site
you can get all kinds of modules some of
them you have to pay for
um you use definitely use a reverb
and then what you do is after the reverb
you put that into
a um a um
voltage controlled amplifier with an
envelope generator
so you give it a long tail reverb and
then you just cut it off
when you want to in fact um uh we got a
little bit of time left so i can
actually
try and um uh simulate that using
um using our delay um
okay so uh let me let me see if i can do
that
um what's the easiest way to do this
let me think um
boy thinking on my feet um okay yeah
let's
let's just uh do the things we used to
do
so um
there we go and that was a good tip in
the chat if you hit control you can drag
hold groups of modules around
um so um
let's uh let's just hook this up and um
i'm winging it here so um
um uh thanks for sticking out
but let's let's try and do a gated
reverb because that's a great uh
that's a great thing to demonstrate how
to do okay so what we're going to need
we're going to need a gate
and we're going to need a um
let me think okay i think i got an idea
how to do this
um let's just
use the um
use the um vca in the mixer as the gate
and um that will be
run by an adsr
and then we will just stick in a delay
between the um
between the snare and the um
and the mixer and that will give us our
reverb
okay so let's let's do that right now
let's put in a delay
where they hide to the delay
i should know where these things are by
now but i know there we go
delay okay so um
from the output
of the filter here which is now going
into the um
to the mixer let's just put that into
the delay and patch the delay
into the output so now
you can hear there's a little bit of
delay on the um
snare drum sound let me turn the snare
drum sound up
and let me turn down that annoying
syndrome
so now all we get is a snare drum
with a little bit of delay so what i'm
going to do is um
kind of um simulate a reverb
so i'm going to turn the feedback up and
i'm going to turn down the delay time a
lot
okay and let's see what that sounds like
yeah that's not not as quite as good as
a reverb
but um we don't have a reverb here to
work with so um
delays delay is what we got um
so the feedback is how much the output
is fed back into the delay so if you
turn that up you get a longer longer
tail
and i have a short delay time to
simulate a reverb so
so that's kind of ugly and colored but
that's what we got
so now let's um put another envelope
generator and this is going to control
our gate
okay
adsr
and uh
okay so now instead of the adsr
here controlling the output this one's
going to do it
right now this is just controlling our
filter sweep so we're using this adsr
um
controlling the amplifier the level
so now we should be able to trigger this
um
with our adsr and um
we'll use the decay to um give us our
gate
so the same thing that's triggering our
snare drum here
which i think was this one yeah so i'm
just going to duplicate this control
and send that to the gate here
so now this is going to be a little bit
crude because what you want is the gate
to hang on for a little bit
then snap off immediately and
we've only got um i need to
stretch that pulse to get the actual
gate so i'm just going to use the decay
here
to dry trying to try and do something
like that
so um take down the attack completely
and maybe take down the decay and see
what we can do here
this is a completely um uh
wing into here so we'll see what we got
i'm going to take down the clock too so
it's a little slower
yeah this is not very convincing i
apologize
yeah i think what i need to do is
actually get an actual gate that lasts
how can that last for that lasts for a
different amount of time
so we can change that independently
and and here it actually cut off the
reverb
all right
yep that was not convincing i apologize
um
uh anyway um i feel like we're kind of
getting to the end of um
end of the things i wanted to show um uh
we can
probably end it pretty soon uh people
want to hang out and ask questions
or people want to move on to other
things
that is totally cool
and once again i wanna um uh
i'm just gonna show show my lovely face
again for a moment
thanks again everybody for joining me um
this was fun it was great to see
everybody
i hope hope you got a little bit out of
this um
lots of listening to me drone on and uh
throw
patch cables um it's uh vcv rack is free
it does a pretty good job of doing the
things an analog synthesizer would do
if you feel like um splashing out and
spending money on actual
analog synthesizer modules once you
master stuff on vcv rack i think you're
a lot better place
to know what you like and what you don't
like and what you want to use
one of the things i cannot do
is give you recommendations of um
synthesizer modules to buy because i
don't actually know
my personal synthesizer is from the 80s
i don't think they even make it anymore
um i did mention polyphony um vcv rack
will support a lot of the modules will
support
polyphony i actually haven't used it
that much so you need to explore that a
little bit yourself
and that probably needs a midi keyboard
as an input
to actually get a polyphonic note
note information into the um into the
program because i don't think the
the computer keyboard will do that
all right somebody in the chat says they
have a midi controller plugged in and
it's working great
that is awesome a lot of the a lot of
the um
a lot of the uh uh
modules will support polyphony using
that one patch cord which is a magic
thing you can never do in the analog
world
um there are definitely reverb uh
modules for rack i have not looked at
them in a world
in a while um the way rack works is um
to get the full spectrum
of the modules that are available there
are hundreds of them
and a lot of them are cool what you need
to do is make an account
at vcv rack everything's not everything
is free
some of the some of the modules are paid
modules
and you pay money for them you pay money
to the developer
and that helps the developer develop
cool stuff there are a lot of free
modules there's pretty sure there's a
free reverb there
um i need to go take a look and see
what's there i apologize i don't know
off the top of my head
um academy can we do this again in a few
months
um i'm certainly game
yeah maybe i can convince you to do a
hack chat with us one of these uh
wednesdays coming up
oh i'd love to i would love to in fact i
think um one of the things
i'd really like to do is um an
introduction to fourier transforms and
the frequency domain
using some of the code here and some of
the principles here because i think
um thinking about the music um
and the audio
[Music]
how things work in the music and the
audio domain is a great way to really
um get a uh intuitive feeling for
what's going on in the frequency domain
and um
something that you don't get just by
cranking out fourier transforms or
looking at your spectrum analyzer
so um one of the things um
that's on my list is to actually hack a
little spectrum analyzer into that scope
module because it is open source and
that would be a fun thing to do so you
can see
um that peak that i showed you in the
filter
how that would move around as you change
the filter frequency
or being able to pick out the harmonics
see how the harmonics change
of the different waveforms yeah that was
actually one of my first questions when
i saw the scope i was like well where's
the spectrum analyzer there's got to be
one right
exactly exactly yeah
worse than that all right um i think uh
we can hand it
end it here um uh i want to thank
everybody for joining me um
you can if you have questions you want
to take offline
um i put the slides and the um info
in the hackaday chat um i s i will save
the um
uh the patches i did in the first and
and the second parts i will save those
and i will put those online if you want
to um
upload them and play with them or see
how i did things
and um thanks again for joining me
thanks to hackaday
people thanks to sophie and mike and
thanks dan for
writing shotgun on the zoom controls and
uh signing out from um from
san francisco thanks everybody