[Music]
hey everyone thanks for joining in
it's a fun evening for me in mumbai
everyone's here let's get started
the whole idea behind this started uh a
couple of months ago
when the lockdown started and i was
trying to see how i can make my
uh pcb renders look better
now let me share my screen straight away
so
i can show you what's happening desktop
sure
that works elliot
looks good all right okay so
uh here's a simple uh badge
that i made for the hackaday uh series i
made on hackaday u
uh for okay and freecad and uh
that's the
that's the pcb let me see if we can move
the window around and table
stuff
and uh that's the
3d view so as you can see i mean kiket
does a fairly good job with
uh with rendering but
this is the standard view and if i click
on render it goes into render mode
it takes a while so i'm going to skip
that right now
but if you look at
retracing preferences
no this doesn't have
but with the new nike version there's
some couple of more
features which i'll show you but in the
earlier versions
this is all you could do you could click
on the render button
and get a render there was no way to
change the lighting
or probably you know put a different
background for example and so on
so those are a couple of limitations but
if we look at
the
current likely let me
get that i'm going to show you what uh
the nightly does now so
uh the
nightly if you do the
[Music]
3d view
things get better because when you go to
display options you have a retracing tab
in which you can add a couple of more
options like
shadows and reflections and you can do
lights and so on so
it gets better but even so not a lot of
control
so this is why i thought of you know
seeing if i can use
blender i've been trying to use to learn
blender for almost five years now and
every time
i started off i'd look at a cube like
this with
some really busy user interface and i
just wouldn't know where to start with
right click left click wouldn't do much
i didn't even know how to move the damn
cube so
it was very frustrating until i
came across uh this guy linda guru
he is uh awesome he is funny which is
what makes
uh sitting through his tutorials
so manageable so big shout out to him i
did his beginner tutorial of getting
from
getting to the donut and
this is what i got to
is
okay so i started off with
this this was the first blend that i did
so something
a donut that looked like chalk and then
i progressed through his tutorials and
uh sort of finally released here which
is
pretty like you can eat it i guess
so it was pretty amazing i started
playing with
the open hardware badge that i was
helping design at that time with the
mechanical uh assembly and so on so this
was my first
pcb render in in blender
and everything was very metallic not
very good but
eventually over a couple of weeks i
figured out how to play around with the
background
the lighting changed the color of the
various layers from the pcb and
add some let's say here's a nice one
okay this one i was pretty proud of
because i got the flex cable
pretty bang on over here the color the
transparency and soft so
that's what i went through and then i
did the
hackaday you course for kaicah and
freecad
so i took that pcb as a starting point
for
today's uh workshop and i thought let me
show you how we can progress to getting
uh something like yeah so you can add
really great you know
let's see backgrounds and lighting and
stuff like that
so we're trying to go and get to there
so first things first let's just see
what
we can do in kaiken
itself so
let me
open up what you would normally see with
regular
okay which is
this one
so if you look at the standard render
from
kcat you'll notice that the footprints
don't have any distinguishing
features like the resistors is just a
brown
cylinder the dip ics don't have any
you know identification marks on them
like the part number and so on
same with the
regulator capacitors as well they're
just kind of blank
shells and so on so not just not
something that
gives you some realistic uh appearance
but you can get to this
within packard itself let me show you
the other one
which is here
so this was done
using freecad
so what i've added here is you'll notice
the
part number on the logo and the 80 tiny
i've added color bands for the resistors
same for the voltage regulator the
capacitors have values on them this
one's
470 micro it's 100 nano
and so on and then i change the color of
the button
and the rgb leds have a
transparent layer with the
dye is visible inside and so on so these
are things you can do
within uh let's say the kaicad freak
head
domain itself let me very quickly
show you how you can
do that
which okay here's my freaking so
for example
here's the
dip
okay
so the way this works is
you use the uh kaicat step up tools
workbench and if that's something that
you haven't used i highly recommend it
because
that's what allows
super integration between kaiken and
freecad
it's over here
looks kind of busy but not very
difficult to use what it does is it lets
you take a
step uh footprint uh
lets you import the footprint
symbol from kaiket and then lets you
align both of them with each other
and then after that when you export it
it
creates a pair of files one of them is
an erml format
the other one is in step format and then
you can use uh vrml
for the kicad renders and the step files
are used for
let's say freecad import so it's really
a great way of
getting nice renders and good mechanical
cad
workflow as well so
this one i started off with
let me hide the footprint
so this is what comes standard with uh
kycad
and what i did for this was
create a couple of
extrudes like this for example the atmel
logo
was imported as an svg i just found it
off the
atmel website and i took the
[Music]
svg imported it in free cad
made it into a solid by extruding it and
then
placed it ever so slightly
under the surface
of the chip like so to show you the
wireframe so there's just a very small
amount of interference over there and
then i did a boolean cut between the
text
and the ic that lets you
get the desired
result which is let me
go to shading
like so and then let me
unhide all of this uh hide the stuff
that i don't need
like so so it's a little bit of
preparation
but should be fairly easy once you
get used to the workflow with uh
something like let's say show you
another one very quickly
okay resistor so this one was
fairly straightforward the
the only thing you need to do is
create a sketch
create a sketch with the four bands that
you want to use for the
uh fork for colors and
revolve it around the body of the
[Music]
resistor and then when you export it
using the
kitecatch step up tools workbench it
asks you for the colors you want to
assign to each of these
different colors that it sees here so
that way you can use the same model to
generate let's say 1k
or 10k or 4.7 k so depending on what you
need so
uh i'm sure this can be also be done
by some kind of a python script for
example i'm not a programmer so if
someone of you can figure it out should
be pretty easy to
create a whole bunch of resistors
and you could do probably the same with
let's say smb chip resistors and
capacitors
capacitors are a bit of a tricky
workflow to get that because you need to
have
text on a curved surface and like so
so it's it's possible and doable
but something that i can't cover for
today maybe i'll add a separate uh post
on how you can achieve this but
freecad has a couple of ways of
achieving uh
projecting curved text on the surface
so once you have this you can probably
start changing the text
and exporting the models for all the
various values that you have
so there is some amount of work required
but then
you nothing was easy ever so
so using this whole set of techniques
you can
achieve what could be called as a
fairly decent let's say
render output from kai ked itself and if
that works for you great you don't have
to go to blender
but if you want something even really
better then blender is
definitely available so um
let's get started with blender i'm not
sure if everyone here has
uh kind of used blender before but i
will assume
that everyone here is the first time
user so
i'll try and cover uh
only the things that we need to get to
realistic pcbs there is a lot blender
can do a lot
just like freaking you can do animation
and you can do
all kinds of custom sculpting and so on
so
it is a lot of different things for
different people depending on what
you're
trying to achieve and that complicates
matters because they're just
too many things to be learned i noticed
that
when i got uh where is it blender guru's
cheat sheet on uh
blender it turned out to be some nine
pages long that's just the shortcuts
so it's like kind of overwhelming to
remember all of this so it's handy to
have a sheet but it's difficult to
even locate the stuff that you need to
locate within this
blender is kind of not for the
faint-hearted like i said i have been
trying to
use it for the last five years and every
year every time i look at the
cube and kind of get uh get put off with
it
so first things first i will make sure
that my key strokes and mouse keys can
be seen so i'm going to press the
n key that brings up this little tab
the window over here and
under screen keys i can then screencast
and okay
so great so you can see hopefully the
mouse keys over here
and i have a little document here that
i've opened up to make sure that i don't
miss anything so i'm going to keep
referring to that so i'll cover the
pre-preparation
part blender okay orbit
a blender doesn't really work very well
if you have
a laptop keyboard because
it needs i mean it works best if you
have a dedicated keyboard with
uh the number keys and
so on you can somehow get by on your
laptop as i've been doing
but it's kind of much faster with
regular full-sized keyboard anyway
the first action is to move around and
look at this cube and that is done by
pressing the middle mouse button
and keeping it pressed and as you hold
it you can kind of you know
move around and orbit around your object
so that that's looking around
if you press shift and middle mouse
button you can kind of pan
around your view and then if you
use the scroll wheel you can zoom in and
out so that's the three basic
functions little mouse button shift
middle mouse button
and scroll wheel so
that's moving
also you will notice on the left there's
a couple of
toolbar icons available the first one is
just the
uh the mouse pointer so that lets you
select objects like that's the cube
here's the camera here's the light and
so on
but the other ones let you move uh
objects so here's the move button click
on the object
and you get the three axis uh arrows
you can pull on one of them and you can
move the cube
if you press control it snaps to the
unit increments
and if you do a control shift
and move it snaps to a tenth of those
increments
so that's how you can move things around
oh that's one axis there's the other
axis
is the third axis and so on so
let's uh move this rotate which
brings up these three colored uh
circles that lets you move in those
axes x y and
z or if you choose the white circle you
can do a free spin in any direction
so let's rotate
and then there's a scale
and again the same thing you get three
axes and a white one the white one
scales uniformly
or the other ones
scale along those axes for example
so that's scaling you can get the same
thing with
shortcut keys g for grab
and
so g grabs and moves your object for
example
s scales it and r
rotates it
those are the shortcuts for kind of
moving around
the workspace over here
let's see if i have a cover
okay next up i'd like to introduce you
to
the uh the collection tree which is uh
what you see out here at the top
right hand corner there is one
collection right now which contains a
camera
that's highlighted here and there's a
cube in the middle
and then there's a light over here so
these are the three things
in this collection and you can add more
collections as you build your scene for
example
and over here are the various properties
tabs that
we will be using a lot some of these
settings we need to do
prior to getting any further so
i'll try and walk you through those uh
in a bit
that's one thing the other is the
different kinds of modes of
viewing that you get what we are in now
is known as the solid view which means
you just see this
solid and that's it but you can also go
into
material preview like so which
you will notice wouldn't have changed
much except that the cube became
uh white so that's the default color in
blender and then there's the the render
view
which is what your actual output will
look like
when you do rendering so that's your
three views you mostly
work in the solid tree view you can also
do the
the x-ray view which is useful when you
want to select everything like so
including the
uh the vertices and
lines in the background the other thing
to
remember is blender is a mesh based
modeling software so it i mean solids
are hollow on the inside
like with let's say freecad where a step
file is a solid object
so for
for someone coming from a cad
perspective it's not really the easiest
to use because uh setting dimensions and
precise
uh locations and positions isn't all
that
uh straightforward although those who
are really good at blender do manage to
do exceptionally well with that but
if you're new it kind of gets a little
bit tricky and difficult
the other way to move around this object
is use this which is known as the gizmo
that can move around in orbit or you can
press a
and alphabet to get to that axis and so
on
this one is uh zoom you click it keep it
pressed and move your mouse
that lets you zoom same thing with pen
click the hand and move around without
letting go of your mouse and you can
so there's many different ways of moving
the around blender
if you press the tilde key under your
escape you get the
pi menu that lets you select different
uh
view options
so that's a little bit on the basics of
the
user interface of
a blender at the top you'll find a lot
of uh
what i refer to as the equivalent of
workbenches in freak category
so if you're trying to do animation you
have an animation
uh let's say workbench that brings up
related uh let's say tools and
icons and so on and then there's other
things like rendering and
shading and sculpting and so on layout
is what we're going to use
all the time uh
let me refer back to my dock to make
sure that i'm going in the proper
sequence all right let's look at
properties now so at this point
we have the cube and we have a camera
and a light on it and if you look at
the render properties the first setting
that you need to do
is change what's known as the render
engine traditionally blender used
heavy but the recommendation is to now
switch to
cycles it's a much better uh
rendering engine the difference is uh av
is
real time so things change immediately
as you move around
but cycles is it renders
it takes time to for things to catch up
but it looks much much better also
uh if you're going to be using blender
heavily you probably need a more
dedicated machine with some kind of gpu
card and so on
i've been able to get along without
anything
extra special just using a regular
little
laptop and it works all right except
sometimes the render time
takes maybe a minute or two if it's not
very complicated
so that's that make sure you set
the render engine to cycles in your
scene properties
in the output properties
adjust your resolution to match whatever
your screen resolution is
and percentage so if if this is 50
you'll get something that's 540 pixels
uh tall let's say so set
said that also set the color depth of
the
rendered images that you'll be saving i
choose 16 because
there's better outputs of course the
next tab is w layer properties
and over here there's an important
checkbox that needs to be
done and i'll walk you through this a
bit later it's called
denoising data what this does is
uh the cycles rendering engine produces
some noise
artifacts when you do rendering and and
doing denoising uh removes
practically most of that noise and
creates a really really nice
smooth render so we look at uh it needs
another step to make that happen
look at it as we go ahead but
for the moment in the scene in the layer
properties you need to make sure you
enable denoising data and then
on there's the scene properties we can
leave it as it is
but here is a point
to be remembered
one blender unit is
one unit of whatever it is that you are
importing
so uh right now this uh
the default cube that pops up is two
meters cube and the grid you see on the
floor is
one meter by one meter squares so that's
set by this scaling over here you can
choose
to show the length in
either mm or centimeters or meters for
example
but when you try to import an external
object into
blender it just takes one unit of
the object as one blender unit so
if you look at it i won't open it again
but the pcb that
i showed you earlier was 75 mm long and
when i get it into blender it becomes
like 7.5
meters long that's super super massive
so one of the things you have to do is
scale things that you import
into blender but
if you want to just scale things that
are
native to blender so blender objects
like this cube and you can
set up a scale factor by pressing the
n key that brings up this
extra side toolbar i'm not sure what
they
officially call it but in
item scaling you can set it to let's say
0.1 or 0.01 for example and that scales
everything to
like if you set it to 0.01 everything
will
come into millimeters so your default
cube will then be
2 mm instead of 2 meters
but since we are importing a pcb
in vrml format which is a non-blender
object to start with
the settings don't matter so there's no
point in playing around with them
so with that done let's
get started the first thing that you
need to do is
in kaiken you
need to go to your pcb
editor pcb new
let me make sure that i have the
okay this got saved as version six so
let me open the
other one now
okay i'm gonna have to use nikes now
here it is
this
so you do a file uh export
in a vrml format save it to whatever it
needs to be saved
give your grid units and output units
and so on
and uh well that's it
click on okay and be done with it
the next thing is to
import this vrml in
blender and i swear this wasn't working
until a week ago what would happen was i
would
import the vrml file in blender 2.83
and it would lose all colors what i'd
get is
everything colored like white chalk and
i tried a lot nothing seemed to fix it
for
a pretty long time for almost the whole
of last month
and i found two uh
solutions to it one was to use
an online cad conversion service called
cloud dot cad exchanger.com
where you can upload a vrml file
and then convert it into something else
so
for the sake of using in kaicad i
chose obj format
and that would work i would then get
color
features retained during the import
the second way i found out was to
install
a blender 2.79 and
importing the vrml in blender 2.79
would retain the colors i could then
save it as a blend file
and then when i open that in blender
2.83 things would be perfect
the reason for not continuing to use
2.79 was
there have been a lot of changes between
that version and
2.83 and in fact there is uh
the the latest version is 2.9 whatever
nine one or nine zero
and again there are a lot of changes
between 2.83 and 2.9
so since i am still pretty new to
blender i decided to stick to
2.83 2.9 is still too new for me
and there's still not too many demo
videos and tutorials up there
so that is what i was breaking my head
with
for almost last month but now suddenly
it seems
uh it works with lender 2.83
without having to do any of these
conversions
and that is well i wasn't sure how i was
surprised and amazed that it did work
but
uh i'm happy it does because now you
don't need to do anything except
did i delete the cube okay so let me
just start a new
general one so if this is your
new blend file you just select the cube
and click on delete
and your cube is gone then we do a file
import
dot wrl go to your folder
desktop docs
click here blinky and this is my wrl but
before you click on it
make sure that you choose the proper
transform
direction so you want up to be z
in the positive direction so make sure
your up is selected as z
up and forward is x over that's fine
once you do that click wrl click
import takes a while
because i think this is some 15
megabytes something that's a pretty big
fight
you know make sure that i've gone
through this stuff that needed to be
done
okay
import scale
great
okay here comes
so here's the
the pcb you can see that it's been
populated here
in the collection tree and the first
thing
i want to do right away is make sure
that i put it in a separate collection
so that we can play around with
different shapes over here and to do
that you press
m m for mic select new collection
give it a name gonna call it pcb
and click ok
and everything moves into this new
collection
now if i click the object then click
n to bring out the dimensions you can
see that the
size is 711 mm and
as i mentioned things go crazy with uh
the units
but uh for right now we can actually
even work with that but
let me just show you how we can scale
this whole object to 10 times
one tenth of its size make sure you are
in the x-ray mode so that when you
select everything gets selected
then just drag your mouse select
everything
select the sorry about that scale option
select the white circle and just drag it
a little bit
and and leave it and you'll get this
resize
option here at the bottom and you'll
notice that we are now at
0.9 and this is where you can set
the new values 0.1
0.1 0.1
once you're done just click somewhere
else and
that's your
pcb get out of x-ray mode there it is
we can now move it to somewhere near the
origin
so once again go back to x-ray mode
select all of them press g to move it
and bring it like so near the
origin look at it from the top so i can
make sure i pull it to it's not really
necessary but i like having it near the
origin so things
are easier when you're moving around and
you know walking around it
let's look at it from the
front like so make sure it sits
just about on the seat
the axis there and
straight so we have the board imported
and we have it scaled and as you can
notice it has retained
most of its uh colors
but not everything looks uh all right
now but if you go to
because you're in the solid view but if
you go to
material preview and this is what it
looks like
and if you go to
rendered view this is what it looks like
and this is
in av because if you go to
the same properties you can notice we
are in navy and
as you move around you'll notice it kind
of updates
pretty instantly there is no time lag
but
once you switch to cycles
it takes a while to regenerate and you
know display
everything and it's doing in
takes a while for it to walk through
doing all the 32 samples
that it's showing here on the top left
but
it gives a much much better
result the other thing to set is
this tissue which is known as clipping
when you get too close to an object
some part of it gets chopped off so to
do that you
bring up your settings toolbar again by
pressing n
and under view clip start
it's set at 100 mm which is
quite large let's set it to 0.1 mm
that lets you zoom into your pcb quite
closely and nicely
just press n again to hide that
so that's setting the clipping pane
let's see what else
okay the next thing to do
is add a plane underneath
the pcb so that acts as a kind of a
surface on which we can probably put
wood texture or marble texture or
whatever the thing that
we'd like to put and you add
new elements by using shift a that
wait a minute let me make sure i enable
the screencast keys
there so now you can see what keys i'm
pressing
so if i do shift a and
under the mesh options i can choose
plane
that brings up a plane like so
and uh it's uh 2000 meters it's kind of
pretty
huge you don't need something that big
ah 1000 mm one square meter is good
enough and then just click it once
somewhere
i click on the selection box
so i now have a plane underneath
the pcb like so
the next thing to do is uh
set your camera and lighting
let's uh let's look at lighting first
that's kind of a little bit easier so if
you expand your collection
the the primary collection you have a
camera and a light over there
if you click on light and then all of
these
properties tab look at this little bulb
icon over here that brings you the
properties for the light
you can select between point source or
sunlight like so
ah this is too bright because the sun's
strength is kind of pretty huge
let's tone it down to something like 10
instead of a thousand it's still too
bright
bring it down to four okay that's
reasonable
or or you can set up a spotlight but
then before what spotlight is
too less so let's bring it up to 100
watts
or enough 500 watts
750 i guess 750 looks good
and you can set for the spotlight
the size for example let me show you
so what so this is the cone being cast
by the by the light
right so you can set that by
decreasing the size over here in the
spot shape
selection
oops i hope i'm still connected yeah i
hope so
and i can kind of
make it into a real tight spotlight if i
want to
like reducing the size i can grab
the yellow circle over here and move it
around so let me look at the
front and make sure it's pointed right
yeah it is
and yeah just like any other object you
can move the
light around as well so click on the
light click on your
move icon or g to do that and
you can move it if you use control you
can snap it to
unit uh selections let me bring it down
a bit control so
that's your spotlight
still not falling on our object so we
can move it a bit
like so then
once you zoom in you can see where it is
and a blend lets you select the
what i call as the penumbra of the light
source whether it needs to be
soft or hard like so
again all of these
setting boxes you can just move your
slider that's one way of doing it
the other way is to click on it once and
punch a
value using your keyboard like so or
you can click on it once and if you
press ctrl
you can snap it to nice round figures
like
so 0.5.4 and so
so let's keep it at 0.5 for this
so that's how you set a light
you can also set up additional lights
and i'll walk you through that a bit
later
but with the light set let's look at
camera settings now every
rendered image is rendered by
looking through what camera setting you
have made
and the camera is a separate object by
itself
that you see over here and
what the camera sees can be accessed by
clicking on this
projector or whatever
camera icon over here this is what your
camera is going to
be looking at and
if you want to change this the easiest
way i found is to first
let me zoom in
and set the
scene as i wanted to be seen in the
camera
by moving panning and
orbiting around it like so zoom in a bit
and then if you click on the view
toolbar here
view align view and then select
align active camera to view so the
camera is going to be moved
over to this location and fit
this scene size so you click on that
and this is what you get
the the
[Music]
rectangle that you see is what the
camera is going to render when you
when you push the render button
so let's do our first render we have the
object imported
we have set a plane underneath it and
we've set up a light that's the three
basic things to do to
render your image pressing f12 will
hopefully bring up and if my computer
behaves well
and things
look good then it's going to take a
while for it to
you know calculate all of the different
quadrants that it has to walk through
and
set up so while it's doing that let me
see if we can get back over here
and try and do some other settings over
here
once for example once you have set the
camera like so and if you feel that you
need to
do some fine tuning then an easier way
is to click on the box for the camera
like so so it's highlighted and then
press the g
that lets you move it like any other
object and
when you do that you can see that you
can move your object within the
camera's frame a little bit like so
if you'd like to zoom in
zoom out you double click the sorry
press g double click
i always get this wrong
do that again here's the camera
click on the camera icon press
g once then press the
scroll wheel on the mouse once push it
down and release it
and then as you move the mouse
forward and backward you can zoom in and
out
this is slightly tricky but with some
practice you will probably get to it
so that's how you kind of move around
and fine tune
the what what the camera sees you know
let's see if the
render is done still a long way to go
but
even from what we can see i don't know
if you folks can notice but you'll see
there is a lot of noise here in the
shadow for example
and that's the noise that's coming which
we can eliminate using the denoise
function so let me just cancel this
render because that's what i wanted to
show you
and look at how we can remove
noise in your renders to do that you
select
the compositing
tab and you won't see much
until you press the use nodes button
and when you do that and you zoom in you
get this
nodes so these are the layers and that's
your
output and what you want to do between
these two is put the function that
removes noise from the image
before it goes to the rendered output
and you add that by doing again shift a
as in adding anything in blender
then hit the search bar and look for
denoising
here in d e n
d noise so that gives you the
noise function drop it here in the
middle
and it connects between these two
other nodes now
you'll notice that
the image is connected to image but
that's not what i want to do i would
need to go back to
layout and because i've started a new
blend file over here i haven't made sure
my settings
have been the way they should be
as mentioned earlier so
i made sure that i'm in cycles
and in
layer i need to make sure that my
denoising data is
selected so with that selection done for
denoising data i can go back to
compositing
and you'll notice that a lot more
options have now
popped up over here and what we want to
connect is
not image to image but noisy image
to image that's the important change
that happens
and then you also want to put the
denoising normal
and the denoising albedo
to the denoising function
and that's it once you're done with this
you can go back to
layout tab and uh if we
now push render
it's going to start rendering and we'll
come back here after a while to see the
progress well we can carry on with uh
some of the other functions
that we can do here while it's
churning churning away let me see that i
have covered
everything up until now
meanwhile if there any questions i'd be
happy to answer
i think everyone's been pretty mellow
but folks if you got some questions
type them in right now yep
there was one question about whether you
did uh
text in freecad or it was imported as
svg
for the atmel chip but that was like an
hour ago
okay yeah so that was uh done using the
draft workbench in freecad
it's pretty straightforward i can
probably make another separate video for
it if needed
later on cool
okay cool i've done planes and cameras
out with this camera
pretty good we are very close to getting
to a realistic
app
okay now uh here's what the rendered out
yeah go ahead
our question just came in how to get the
board centered when importing
right it it by default imports it at
the origin so there is something
i don't know if you can see it here
there's a little circle white and red
with the axis crosses
that's known as the cursor
so wherever the cursor is that's where
it places
a new object that's how blender works
so if if i click on this cursor option
zoom out somewhere else place the cursor
here
and then do a shift add
add a cube hopefully it should add it
there but this will be like a two meter
cube so it's going to be kind of right
so here it is uh
yeah but then i'm also trying to render
so i'm really
sticking my neck out over here so let's
see if i can escape that do a control c
yeah okay thankfully recovered but yeah
that's how you
so by default because the cursor is at
the origin
when you start a new file then when you
import anything it goes
over there but then after you scale it
it moves away to
a new location unfortunately i'm not
sure why but
it doesn't scale around the cursor for
some reason
so you have to kind of kind of
move it after scaling i need a glass of
water sorry
all right let's see where our render is
okay still working
at this point if you look it still is
pretty noisy because it's going to lay
out everything
and and then apply the denoise function
so we'll get back to it once it's done
completely
okay that's a lot of progress i think
the next thing to do
is if you're happy with the
way the pcb looks now then maybe the
only other thing you need to do is play
around with the light
by maybe it's still too harsh right now
so i click on light
click on the light properties and
reduce this to something like 500 watts
or maybe 350 watts
that looks more mellow and
and uh
the other way is to reduce this let's
say all the way to 200
and add that
what are known as uh spotlight
and then make a new lighting element
by doing control a oh sorry shift a
shift a go to light and select the three
point lights
once you do that
it sets up well you can see over here
the height and the distance and so on
it's probably too far away keep it at
one meter
and there it is so you have these
uh three
three point light which is kind of
giving a more
let's say even more
diffused lighting to the rest of the
scene so we now have
a spotlight and something that is giving
spread lighting over there
and well i'm not exported lighting but
uh it's
it's a whole physics field by itself so
you really want to set your lighting
very precisely you can do it in blender
you just need to make sure that you read
up
on it a lot okay let me just choose the
solid view so things
are
all faster let's see if our render has
reached uh
any further it's taking its own sweet
time it's going to be a big one
so i'm doing a lot of things right now
let me shut down freaking
i don't need it anymore yeah maybe
because
video is consuming a lot of my computer
resources
so that's right anyway we'll get to that
all right so the next thing is if you're
happy with the pcb the way it is
then a quick way to
make your scene better is apply some
kind of a texture or color to your
plane so to do that you
click on the plane somewhere you'll
notice
it
a bit so
i choose the cursor when i click on
the plane you get a border around it to
show you that it's selected and
you then go to the material properties
tab
which is over here at the bottom
and you can have a lot of built-in
texture but let me show you how to do
things from scratch you do
a new click on new that
brings up or creates a material called
material.001 you can
rename it by double clicking over here
and calling it
uh plain
material for example or giving it any
name whatever
and it uses what is known as a
principled
bsdf that's a kind of shader that
comes with blender don't ask me what the
bsdf means but
apparently blender used to come with
different shaders earlier like if you
wanted to apply glass it used to be a
glass psdf
if you wanted diffuse there was a
separate one for diffuse
there's one for hair and there's one for
refraction and specular and translucent
and so
on but the principled one can now then
can now do most of these so you can
choose principled and then apply a glass
effect to it so that's the one that is
most commonly used at least that's what
i've heard
so and that's the default so you don't
have to choose it it just
gets set as principled and the base
color is
white if you click on that you get a
color wheel
you can choose let's say a color like
this
and click on ok and you won't see
anything if you're in this mode but if
you go to solid preview
you'll notice that the color is turned
green and if you go to the rendered view
it looks
slightly even better compared to what
it's
actually going to look like
like so so that's just one base color
but you can do a lot of uh
tweaks to this one tweak is uh
for example metallic it's at zero right
or before the
metallic let me show you roughness
roughness is
how rough or smooth or shiny or
matte it is so the bigger the number the
more
matte it becomes and the smaller the
number the more shinier it becomes
so i click on this click on control and
bring it down to something like
0.1 it's going to be pretty shiny
like so and and now
if i kind of move around
let me see if i can reduce the number of
oh let me
just go here yeah so
if you can see the trees over here that
means it's a very shiny
object the trees are the default what
they call as the
hdr background that comes around
in blender you don't see it but it's
there somewhere in this background over
here
and that's what you see reflected over
here but
if you choose the plane go back to
properties and reduce increase roughness
you'll notice
that it becomes matte like so
so that's how matte or shiny it is let's
choose something like
0.2 and then you can increase the
the metallic sheen of it by
cranking it up like so for example
so that's one way of choosing color you
can change colors to
whatever you feel and so on right so
that's
you can set rgb values so
let's see if have incre we've progressed
with the
looks like this thing is stuck so i'm
going to close this and come back to
that later
so that's setting color to your plane
that's the simple way of doing things
the other way is to apply
an external texture as an image
to this plane and that's really much
more interesting because you can start
doing things like
uh wood or marble and so on stone for
example
and you do that by clicking on the
little circle next to the base color
that brings up your context menu
and choose image texture
once you do image texture you get you
expand this properties tab you get a new
and open
option so click on open
and i have a couple of textures that i
have saved
let me go there desktop
uh blender materials oh
let me see let me try wood
stored under jpeg as
the albedo click on open image
so there's the wood texture
it's as easy as that so it's really kind
of very easy to
set something like so at
this point the texture is really
extremely
flat and doesn't have any surface
roughness or imperfections and so on
so we will figure out how to add that
later but again this is the bare minimum
you can
do this and because you've set the
roughness very low it's kind of very
shiny so we can
come back here to roughness and increase
it to
the median point five
let me get slightly more
0.7 there you go
so that's how you set material for your
plane
and if you want to make it a
little bit more realistic we can
do that as well before that let me show
you what happens when you download
blender materials
so materials
let me just select
something like this
so a lot of the materials that you can
get off on the
internet for example blender guru has
several free textures and materials that
you can download and there are a lot of
other resources available for
materials is you can get
i mean they come in different let's say
layers so there is a color layer for
each
material there is also sometimes they
are called
differently but you can have gloss and
you can have normal
you can have a reflection layer you can
have albedo
and and so on and by using those
over here you can turn this flat
surface into a slightly textured
three-dimensional appearance for example
and that's
where it kind of gets pretty interesting
so
let's see how we can do that you access
get into that using the nodes feature
for anyone who's used uh programs like
grasshopper
or many of the others you know what
nodes are
blocks of repetitive code that you can
kind of plug in and with uh
blender you access that by going to
shading
so that's the shading tab here at the
top
once you click that you get your nodes
like so
this is the existing node for the plane
that you have
selected which is
over here and so we can see some changes
as they happen
like so so we have the the wood
material that is the jpeg image that we
selected that goes as the base color to
this
bsdf shader and then that goes as the
output
for the material but we want to make
things more interesting here
so let's go to here's your file browser
on the left
so you can go to a desktop you can even
drop it directly from your
explorer window if you want to desktop
docs
materials
chosen
and alberto is the one that has been
used here but
to give the surface bumpiness
you need what is known as the normal map
and you'll notice it's usually a
violet or blue colored uh texture like
so
but it contains the height map is sorry
height map information
so i can drag that and bring it here
into play
and i want to make sure this color
goes as an input
to the normal input on your
setting but before you do that you have
to tell it that this is
a bump map and there are two things to
do that
first is make sure you select the color
space and tell it that this is
a non-color texture which means
the one you chose earlier is an rgb
color
but this one doesn't contain color
information but something that is
besides
the color information and we add a node
over here in the middle
called let me try and remember
i am going to use a bump
i think yeah
and place it here in the middle
and the way things work is at least
that's what i've been told in blender is
the colors match to color so if you have
a yellow circle here it needs to go to
one of the yellow circles
over here if you have a blue it needs to
match to a blue for example
green goes to green and so on so because
we have yellow here and then
normal is blue we can't disconnect it
directly
and hence the bump in between that
converts
the color information is
normal and then i can plug
the output of the bump map to the normal
over here and i don't know if you notice
but there has been a distinct change in
the
texture if you look at it head on
it kind of looks
better let me see
yeah the other thing we can
do is there is a specular
displacement and uh
yeah so we grab a
bump again i am
i am bringing it here because uh like i
said the names
differ every time it's not always
there's no
convention to how the various material
layers are named
but what i want to do is
take a bump
and give that to the roughness
input on our main material so instead of
setting a physical value here
you want certain parts to be shinier and
other parts to be rougher
and that's determined by the bump map os
once again i'm going to do another
bump node addition to a shift a search
pump put that here connect color
yes normal and
the output goes to roughness
and i guess i did something wrong okay
here it is yep
so that's how you kind of
make things better and probably i didn't
use the right
material because you can use something
else that gives a better
illustration of what the way this works
so let me try and do that let me change
the
base material over here let's get rid of
all of these that
we have put here
okay my computer's become seriously
laggy
okay and now we're back to
the basic white texture yep
i'm going to choose a different material
to
better illustrate how the bump map the
normal map
works let me see if i can choose
rust rust was pretty good
go to rust
and that's the variant one
which i bring in here
zoom in and collect color to the
oops connect color to base color
so we should see something that looks
like uh
rusted metal
there you go
this is open
so you can see it better and then
let's uh repeat this with the
normal so here's the normal map big one
connect color
to normal
i think you can probably notice that
there is a substantial
improvement in how the texture looks if
i disconnect
normal it kind of looks much
flatter
there you go and then once i connect
normal things look a little bit
better
and uh let's also add
the other map the
reflection
that's the gloss okay yep so the gloss
for example is going to go to your
roughness now
connect normal here
and that applies a variable amount of
shininess to different parts of your
surface over here so that's so
let me just go back to heavy and go back
to layout
so we can get nice idea of what it's
actually going to look like
there
like so
okay so at this point again i think for
some reason the lights are still too
bright so we will go to light
and set this to
100 and the
twilight
we can tone them down to one watts
each one
one and make this
one as well and
the main light too it to
something like 50.
good so let's see if we can get this uh
render to start with
sorry it isn't uh as fast as we
hope it to be that's because i'm doing a
video
along with rendering so
let's see if all right it started doing
this
you're gonna have to wait for a while
and see
so that's the next stage of getting to
realism
and then finally we get to the real
prosthetics of this
how can you change
all of this stuff you see on the pc
pizza as you can see almost all of the
materials have
uh kind of a standard uh
rough finish whereas actually some of
the
for example the the black plastic is
going to be pretty shiny
the metal on the coin cell holder is
going to be pretty shiny and so on
the plastic on the button will be shiny
so we need to
start playing around with those and
also if you want to change the default
colors for the
pcb mask and and
silk legend and so on
so for that let me collapse the main
collection and expand
the pcb
and over here
if you scroll all the way down
then the last couple of layers
are going to be the ones related to the
printed circuit board and the rest of
the elements
belong to the various components
so we can kind of identify them
by hiding these
click on the eye icon and start
hiding things there goes the
front uh silk legend
that's the bottom likely that's the
bottom
that's the front that's the
copper on the front the sides
and that's the uh
the whole pc so all we have here is uh
the components now okay make things
easier let me
choose the plane and hide it so on the
keyboard you can
press h to hide an element like so
so we have all the pcb elements hidden
and now we can see if we can
rename them for better
let's say legibility if we unhide this
one
we can see it's the bottom silk legend
so i'm going to
do an f2 over here to rename this and
just to make sure that it goes right at
the
top of the stack so it's easier to you
know
work around with it i'm just going to
start it with the alphabet a
underscore
uh silk bottom
and leave it at that so that's
my
silk at the bottom very top
and let's choose another one and see
which one that turns out to be this is
the top silk
so again press f2 here
f2 a underscore
silk top and
let that go this one
is pads is it on the bottom
or the top okay it looks like the
bottom so these are the copper pads on
the bottom
choose this press f2 a underscore
pads bottom
that's that unhide the other one
this is uh tracks on the bottom so
select the shape press f2
a underscore copper
bottom like that
this one is pads on the top so select
this
f2 a underscore
ads top
and hide the next one
that is the tracks on the top so
f2 a underscore copper
top there goes that
that's the sides
of the printed circuit board so if you
unhide and hide it you can see that so
i'm going to name it
a
underscore pcb
underscore sites
and finally the last one over here is
the
[Music]
top and bottom layers of the pcb so i'm
going to call them the mask
f2 a underscore
pcb underscore mask
okay so we have all these essential
layers
and let's just play with those first so
i'm going to zoom out go to
my collection that contains the camera
and the lights and hide
that whole collection so that's out of
the way
and i'm going to also
then choose the
select arrow icon go to x-ray
choose all of these parts and hide them
all by doing
an edge on the keyboard so that hides
everything so i've got everything hidden
on my
uh scene now then i can
go to
my pcb collection and unhide
just the pcb parts underneath the plane
look at it like so so here's just the
pcb
and like we did with the uh with the
plane
we can start giving colors to these uh
different materials so
let's say you want a black mask with a
white
legend so we want to basically convert
mask and copper to black
the other thing i need to point out is
let me show this to you and crack it
hopefully i can manage it with
everything running
okay let's see
oh
okay since i'm here let us do it
pcb
things are really crawling down now how
am i doing on time eliot
let me check
i got about 15-20 minutes
okay so we're pretty close to where we
want to be the but
yeah what i need to do is
look at
where am i yeah okay
okay
your battery may be running low you're
at 19
oh jeez i didn't plug it in
if you need to plug in take a sec
thanks for that peter from the comments
thanks peter
thank you peter okay so
very very quickly what
so here's the typical render output from
kai-ken and
[Music]
if you'll notice this part is
unmasked but when you do the vrml export
from kai-ked
it gets masked over i think that's the
limitation of kai-ket i'm not sure why
but there is a way to fix it in blender
with
a couple of extra steps but more
importantly
the the plated through holes
they also disappear in blender
this is gold plated over here for
example
but if you look at
blender you'll notice it's green over
here
so it's lost all the plated through
holes the reason is
the pcb sides
which is this one is
all one layer in in blender
so there's a way to uh to fix that but
it needs a couple more extra steps but
first let's get quickly to what we want
to do we want to
add some more realism to the pcb by
adding a thickness to these
various layers so we're going to choose
the
top copper layer
and we want to apply what's we usually
call in cad as an extrude function
so in blender you select the object
and you go to the the wrench icon over
here this panel
that brings up modifiers click on add
modifier
and choose solidify so what that does is
gives
a certain amount of uh thickness
to your copper
like so so let's see the value right now
is offset is negative
one so we want to bring it to positive
one
and
there is something wrong over here
okay i think i have messed up all the
units but it's okay
well it's gonna be
100 is too much you get 10
that's too less probably 20.
so if i kind of
scroll in you can see we have a nice
thickness added to the
tracks so that's your copper top
and you want to do the same with the
copper bottom so choose copper bottom
add modifier solidify
make this 20
sorry about the units uh make the offset
positive one and now the
[Music]
bottom tracks also will get a certain
thickness
so that's copper top and bottom
and you need to apply the same thickness
to the pads
so which is pads bottom
[Music]
okay meanwhile the
render has turned out wow the light is
too less
but anyway if you
zoom in over here you'll notice the uh
the noise is pretty much kind of reduced
so let's get back here why can't i get
rid of this
escape i hope i didn't hang up
linda
okay well wait for it any questions
happy to answer them well
this tries to get unstuck sorry about
this let me try and close
uh extra windows
if i can
there's really nothing that except maybe
the actual render window
we've had two well one random question
along the way
um which is what are the specs for your
computer
oh okay it's pretty ancient and this one
is a five-year-old
laptop i am not sure what processor it
had but
probably a core i5 4gb ram so pretty
much
basic it's not too too fancy it's a
lenovo x250
right on yep
all right so and the other ones i forgot
this class started 15 minutes later so
you have 30 minutes actually so take
your time okay
all right let me see if i can get
unstuck on this
some reason it's refusing to move out of
this
thing so maybe i can just close it and
restart again hopefully
okay let's try that i didn't even save
this so
i'm gonna take a brain check on this
quit two windows and start all over
again
so at this point uh the process is to
apply
the solidify modifiers to
your top and bottom copper layers
to your top and bottom
copper pads and
also a solidifier modifier to the
uh silk legends but that needs to be a
bit
taller than what you applied to the
copper layers because the circulation
goes over the uh copper
so instead of 20 we could choose
something like
maybe 25 or 30 to make it uh
just kill blender and be done with it
okay then
start all over again there you go
so very quickly i'm going to start off
where i stopped file
import wr
i'm going to bother too much with the
plane and the
other settings just going to show you
the pcb part
so
we fine to set up input
one of the question i received on
twitter was uh
the patch will fall off if there's no
solder on the pcb which is
quite right right if you want to have
realistic
renders you need to figure out a way to
add a solder to the
copper pads but probably that's a
something to be
worked out i have i don't really have an
idea how that works
though not not at this moment though
you could make a song in uh
blender and just add it at every pad but
that'd be horrible
yeah i mean i'm sure there is an easy
way to do it like
blender has a nice particle system where
you can like if you look if you remember
the donut there were these sprinkles all
over it yeah so
that's done by select like making one or
two different kinds of sprinkles and
then just
randomly putting it all over the donut
but i'm sure you can
figure out a way to put uh solder joints
like so on the
on the board that'd be fun
yeah all right so uh
let me just get straight away to
this okay and then
choose all of these and
hide all of it
oops
wow is that ready
a minute as i get this back
okay
select this this
all right so we can
add solidify modifiers to the
top and bottom silk layers you've
already seen that so i won't repeat it
again
same to the bottom pads
and tracks same to the top
pads and tracks
and that's the sides and that's the top
so
assuming that we've done what we did
earlier which i kind of messed up
we can now start playing with the colors
which is kind of similar to what we did
with
the plane so let me select the top
let's say copper tracks then go to
material and if you already
named it then it will be nice to
to reuse that material in other places
but right now i'm kind of trying to rush
through this or keeping the same name so
we have the
top tracks selected we have the material
properties selected
click on use nodes that allows you to
use all of the great settings over here
go to base color and choose
you're going for black mask right so we
just want to darken the
so if you look at some photos
i think the way it works is the tracks
are a bit lighter
and the actual pcb is a bit darker so
you've chosen the tracks and made them
kind of
dark gray and the same gets applied to
the bottom tracks as well because they
share the same material so
that is kind of useful you have to do it
just once
then we can choose the top and bottom
layers again since they share the same
material we can do it just once i
choose i click over here once go to
material
click on use notes notice it turns white
and now i want to turn this
darker than the tracks like so something
like that
there you go and and now you can play
around with
some more stuff you can choose this uh
layer and make it uh
shiny because it's going to reflect
fair amount of light so bring it to like
0.2
you can see it's kind of become shiny
now
choose the same for the uh tracks so
choose the tracks
and dial down the roughness to something
like 0.2
so that's your mask
color is pretty much set we can then
choose the
[Music]
uh the pads so choose the top pad layer
and because again they share the same
material
you have to do it just once and it
applies for both
top and bottom so chosen the top pads
layer
in the materials properties choose
nodes click on base color you wanted
something
that looks like gold for example so
something that sits between
yellow and orange i'm sure we can dial
down the exact settings
later but gold is metallic
so we're going to dial up the metallic
option to about point eight and the
roughness is down to like point
two flexible that gives you a nice
that's a shiny gold finish for your
copper pads on the top and the bottom
sides like so
and you also want the silk layers to be
pretty shiny because it's a
silk screen so we choose the top
silk legend layer go to material
select nodes it needs to be white
but we just want to make it shiny so
just dial down
roughness to about 0.2
you have a nice shiny
silk legend as well like so
and now finally if you want to
let me
hide the
camera and the light and
select all of those press h
go down and unhide
circuit board almost like so
upside yeah so that's your
bare circuit board now and
if you choose this
vertical layer and give it a color
which is the same as gold
so equal to
just a row yeah
choose the sides
choose notes okay
let's link to the same color i guess
yeah okay so let me do a
ctrl c
one more time okay so
the the sides have the same
material being applied as the top and
the bottom mask
colors so which is why you need to
unlink
this color from the other two colors you
do that by selecting this
side over here and and
in the text in the material properties
the
the material over here if you look at
the drop down it says shape
1924 you kind of delete
that so that becomes
gray now the top and the bottom stay
as we had chosen to be black but the
sides
are now gray and now now we can apply
oh
i choose a new material to this
clicking new clicking use nodes
clicking on base color and
if you want the plated through holes to
be gold
then you're going to have to change it
into something like this
for example but if you want
the edges to be green then we need to
get to something like
this with a very dark shade i think
that's what
glass fiber looks like i guess well at
least approximately just to green
it down to oh yeah something like that
but then that's just the same color for
the uh
pleated through pads as well so one way
of fixing this
is to first of all i'm going to hide the
layers not required so click on the
top and bottom mask height then
the top silk hide it
bottom hide it
bottom tracks autumn
[Music]
top pads and
bottom pads and what i'm left with now
is all the vertical faces of the pcb
and what i'm interested now is to make
sure that
i
look at it from the top
oops yeah what i'm interested in is this
whole
selection i want to deselect the outline
layer or
in kai-ken what we know how to see edge
cuts layer
and deselect it from the rest of these
holes once you do that you can apply two
separate materials
one to the edges and the other to the
vertical holes over here
so vertical holes can then be golden
and the edges of the pcb can be the
green fiberglass color that
which so to do that you get into
what's known as edit mode in blender
up until now we've been in object mode
which is
what you see here at the top left but
when you choose the drop down
you need to choose
an object and then if you see
that drop down you get the edit mode
choose
edit and now uh this is where the
tricky part comes in painstakingly you
have to select
by doing box select and grab
all of these
let's say elements that form the edges
and separate it out from the rest so
let's see if i can give it a shot select
this
so that's selected
oh that's there sometimes you go to a
zoom in to
grab the right oops
shift select so start again
that's a shift select let's shift select
some more over here make sure i don't
select the
holes that
select this whole box over here
select all of this
yeah yeah
get that get this corner
shift
well if you have a rectangle outline
things are much easier
you don't have to
break your head so much
okay so hopefully i have all of these uh
selected so that's just the edges
selected
now let me make sure that i i can't
remember the
it's
make sure that okay p to separate path
so the command to separate out this
is uh p for papa
you get separate what you have selected
or
if you have selected material or layer
so we need to have
separate the selection
and when you do that you should see
let me expand this collection tree so
you can
see it clearly is
the the earlier collection was a shape
indexed face set but the new one is
with a dot zero zero one extension so
these are just the holes
and this is the separate edge
of the pcb so once we have done that we
can
go back to object mode
go back to solid view
like so choose
the the chosen is a fictional novel
written by
alexa stop
i'm sorry about that i don't know why
alexa popped up
so we can give this a color
which is first published in 1967
it follows the narrator reuben walter
and his friend daniel saunders
as they grow up in the rooms
[Music]
so anyway that's gold and let's
make sure that okay i need to make sure
i use notes so
click on nodes make sure i get
gold
make it shiny
and that's these vertical faces but
because that
is linked to the material that we have
separated they both have the same color
right now
so finally we can select the edges
click on nodes and
delete this material which it is using
it becomes gray we can then choose
new material use nodes color
set oh maybe choose this totally
different color so we can distinguish it
from the
rest of the something like this
and oops
like so and it's pretty rough
there's no shininess in the edge of the
pcb so let's crank up roughness to
something like 0.9
so we now have that
fixed let's do let's unhide everything
by doing an alt
h that
unhides everything and now if you look
at this
you'll notice we have the gold plating
let me set the clipping
quickly
notice we have plated through holes in
gold now and the edge of the pcb
in whatever color you choose uh it's the
wrong color right now but
you get the idea what needs to be done
and and uh from the earlier example
we've already seen how we've added a
thickness to these
various layers so the sink layer and the
tracks and the
mask and so once you do that you are
pretty close to
an even more realistic uh let's say
pcb representation compared to what you
got from
a kai cad and and from here on
you can continue doing a lot more for
example
uh this depends on how much patience you
have and how much time you want to spend
on this but you can select
each of these individual components and
start giving them
materials for example the resistor body
like this one for example
i can select that go to click nodes
uh choose a color or two
something like this and it's pretty
shiny so
dial down the roughness
like this and here you have a nice
shiny resistor and you'll notice the
other one isn't
as good as this one so
that's how it is now let's say you have
already applied
the material to this resistor but you
want to use it
on the other one
you choose the
i can't remember if you choose the old
material first or the
new one let me try both choose the old
material first
shift and choose the
new material do a control l for
linking these two materials you get the
make link materials
yeah when you do that you have the
material applied to this part of your
resistor
obviously you'll have to select the
other parts of the body to apply the
same material there as well
but that's how you kind of start playing
around
let's take the
[Music]
box select so i select this whole
cylinder and again
material uh use nodes
give it a nice red color and make it
again really shiny by dialing down
roughness
to 0.2
you have a nice shiny button
which is like looks reflects light
nicely and so on
so using this and iterating this process
you can
kind of start giving the material
settings to all the different parts on
your pcb for example let me just choose
this
top surface of the
leds and see if we can give them
a glass
surface so now instead of using
principled
i could use a transparency setting that
is
what i'm sure i saw one
transparent transmission
i guess how much of light oh yeah
something like that
let's try the glass shader so
plus
yeah now if you look at the
rendered view mode things will look much
better
like so i'm
cool we've got about
oh sorry we got about one or two more
minutes left
so okay so let's make it really
good i don't know how do you want to
wrap it up yeah
i guess i have transferred or talked
about almost everything that i had
listed in my
document so i've covered so the point
was to show you the techniques i mean it
wasn't really to
it's kind of difficult to to actually
walk through the whole process but i
think i have shown you all of the
steps needed to get you to a proper
like realistic renders and also i'm
happy to answer questions now
or later if there are questions now we
can do that over the next couple of
minutes
yeah if anyone has any super quick
questions type them in
um while let's see
focus me for one sec actually yeah can i
stop
yeah stop sharing my screen okay yeah
here let me see
yes you stop sharing and we'll see if i
pop up or
what happens there we go
all right there i am good um okay
am i showing or yeah i can see you
but you can see me awesome now i hope
everyone else can
sit for hey everybody thank you very
much for
uh looking at this right now actually
we've got
starting up uh sophie and
mike are giving a welcome ceremony over
on our youtube channel which is youtube
and pretty soon we're going to have the
keynote speech so
all right if you're interested in seeing
that go ahead
and let's see last question
i had for a newell was would you be
willing to put your
that sheet that you use with all
the steps
up on your hackaday io project page yeah
yeah of course that's the plan i mean
it's a bit uh
unorganized right now but within a day
or so i will
definitely be putting it up oh it's
fantastic
uh yeah i mean i destined it down to
what was needed just to do this one
particular let's say
uh purpose in blender like there are so
many things you can do
but just for the pcb a few things so
thanks for having me
i had great fun uh doing this yeah no it
was
absolutely fantastic and uh yeah
everybody
stay thanks to uh annual
do you still see my screen or uh
uh i can get you back hold on yeah
please because
i somehow can't seem to escape from ah
thank you thank you very much all right
everybody thanks a lot for having me
we still see your screen yeah yeah wow
but i'm unable to stop
i've been clicking on stop share for a
long way
it's kind of stuck i love it
we could see it okay fine
so that's good enough
all right so thanks everyone and if
there are questions pop them
in a chat or anywhere else and i will be
happy to answer and see how i can help
you out
thanks for everything elliot appreciate
thank you all that was really great
oh what was your question sorry roll on
super quick question
okay okay yeah yeah what is it
oh is that the one about unity yeah do
you know anything about
unity how to export these to other game
engines and newell
oh absolutely no idea sorry this is
something that
i don't want to lead you down the wrong
path by giving the wrong answer
there are some nice blender forums so
those would be the best ones to start
with
yeah i'm nearly certain that once you
have stuff in blender it's a hop skip
and a jump to get it off to unity
but i don't know how myself either all
right well thank you very much and
thanks everyone for attending hope this
helps you make it thank you so much
awesome 3d model listeners
yeah marvelous bye everybody
bye bye