[Music]
i just want to welcome
amit reddy to the uh workshop today
learn how to hack a car
um which sounds kind of cool and we got
a lot of interest in this one so
there's a lot of people pouring in i'm
dan maloney i'm a staff writer here
at hackaday and community engineer at
hackaday io
i'll be the moderator for this um amith
is a recent mechatronics engineering
student
a recent graduate to pass the time in
lockdown he decided to pick up car
hacking which in another place and time
might not have been considered a
terribly good thing to do
but i'm sure he's been totally legal and
totally above board on this
um as as all good hackers are and he's
willing to pass this
information he's learned down to anyone
who's interested and that's what we're
gonna do today so
take it away me i just seen a lot of
people pour in in the last couple of
minutes
we dropped the link in the chat
for where to download some files
i'm going to drop it again just trying
to find the chat window
so if you guys can go to that page and
download
uh it will say
like workshop files dot dot g
g on gz so and uncompress it and we're
gonna use we're gonna use that
those files for the workshop today
i'm just going to i'm going to just keep
going through the workshop while you
download
while you download those files
okay so what we're going to do for this
workshop is
uh we're just going to discuss why you
might want to
hack cars what are some difficulties
in uh in hacking cars some interactive
portions we only have like four
exercises
i asked this a little bit uh before the
workshop
started if you could uh if any would
want
i would like some volunteers for each
exercise to help with the pacing
because i don't want to uh when i get
nervous i talk really fast
so uh it'll be something like i'll do
i'll do a step and you
you try to follow and
if something and so that that way i can
keep uh
i can present in
a slow manner and not speed through
everything and like keep
keep uh you know leave everyone behind
so if
if that's something you can do uh please
volunteer
i'll ask for volunteers for before each
exercises
so and after the interactive
portion i'm going to do some demos
with python and savvy can and
to wrap it all up i'm going to like give
you guys some additional resources
that you can read up on and learn more
skills
okay dan already introduced me uh but
i'm about a hundred hours into this
hobby and i still consider myself like
an expert
beginner i'm just gonna try to save you
as much
um as much time and frustration i i
i experi i experienced in the beginning
so
hopefully it'll help you out so car
hacking why do it
um to learn like uh automotive systems
uh it's fun like if you want to extend a
car's functionality
uh you know there's it also exists uh
some systems in automotive
automotive systems exist in like other
systems like heavy machinery
uh and robotics i worked in a company
that made
um heavy machinery for like the mining
industry
and a lot of their machines ran on can
networks
and like if you ever need to repair your
car
i think it's it's a good skill to have
michigan just recently passed the right
to repair
i believe so like car
information is going to be more
available
starting in 2021 or 2022 so that's
something we can look forward to
it'll probably charge us a lot of money
to get access to it but at least we have
it available
um so
some of the obstacles and uh related to
car hacking is just the sheer amount of
systems and uh within a car and the
complexity of each system
so just list off a few uh
just like the wireless entries like some
cars have sell your
cellular connection satellite radio gps
radar
um you know tons more speakers
infotainment
systems like auto braking systems lane
keep systems advanced cruise control
and there's like a ton more that i
didn't even mention
and they all require uh certain hardware
specialized
hardware to like make sense of like
logic analyzers as
software defined radios etc etc and
there's differences between
makes and models and even models between
different model years
so so it's kind of hard for
people to communicate that information
so let's say if i'm working on a honda
crv
in 2016 and you're on a different
car it's kind of difficult to share
information that will make it easier
for us uh for us to uh
you know like build off each other's
work and uh obviously auto
automakers want to hide the information
to hinder repair
and stuff so and that's one of the
reasons that i used ic
sim during these introduced beginners so
because we don't have to have all have
all the you don't have to use
the same car or anything like that
so
so before uh i go into icsem
so the easiest way to get started car
hacking is to get
started uh using the obd2 port
so obd2 deport is like a diagnostic port
it's found in all cars built in the last
20 years or so
it's used for diagnostic for purposes
and emissions testing so the european
versions have the same thing but it's
physically
and technically identical i think to
this port
so if you're in europe or elsewhere i
think you'll have something similar
if not the exact same thing
so uh
the regulations only define certain pins
to be certain of things but everything
else
it's up to the automaker's discretion
so the green poor pins are what we're
going to focus on
today uh that those are that's the can
bus
but i'll go through some of the other
pins just for
quick reference so the blue pins are a
pwm signal
and the fourth pin is just chassis
ground and fifth pin is signal ground
so six and seven are can high and low
and 715 are k-line
and l-line um and those are very very
low
uh low bandwidth systems
and and that how that network works is
that there's one master
and many uh slaves or whatever
or followers however you want to define
them um
so that's one reason that can
is better because there are a lot more
nodes on it
uh and there's a lot it's a lot also
much much higher bandwidth
um i'm going to omit the hardware
implementation on lower
low level details on cam frames for this
workshop
um and i'm just going to like
give a high level overview of how how
can works
so let's say we have all these uh
different all the blue squares are
nodes and like if you want to connect
them in a traditional
spi bus or uart we need to why
we need to share a lot of wires but with
can you just have to have
two wires between the whole lot of them
and one uh complexity that
comes up with the issue with this issue
is that
if multiple people want to talk at once
or multiple nodes
wants to talk at once
how how does who who gets to go first
and how's that how does that get decided
so there's something called like the
arbitration process for can networks
and basically uh oh i just got cut off
here
basically uh all the notes have an
arbitration id
and the note with the lowest arbitration
id
gets to go first so everyone else who's
a higher number than them
backs off and lets them communicate then
they enter into arbitration again then
go into it
and then and just repeat it until
everyone
has its chance to speak or broadcast
into the network
so can like has the highest bandwidth
out of all the car car networks
um except ethernet car return automotive
ethernet
more system more cars are shipping with
ethernet nowadays
it's very easy to add nodes and extend
the the client network and it's very
simple to implement physically
can is actually limits of can is like
it's very low bandwidth compared to like
ethernet or some other protocols um
i think most cars have something like
500 kilobits per second
to 1 megabits per second so very very
limited bandwidth
and each mesh can message can only be
eight bytes long so this is this can be
poor or limiting for
hard real time systems if you need that
um and you just like if you have a up
if you have a message that's more than
eight bits you have to break it apart
over multiple can messages so that's
adds complexity to to your system
um so some parts of a
so how does a can packet look like um so
all can packets have an arbitration id
uh
and uh data like a payload i guess of up
to eight bytes
so some can have up to one or two bytes
all the way up to eight
uh bytes so for example here
this uh 0x
300 so hex decimals we're going to use
hex decimals
for the entirety of our presentation
today so
so that's the uh the id and all the
eight bytes i think i have here is the
data
so okay uh we're going to try setting
this up um
do an exercise for the setup then i'm
going to go through the controls for the
ic
sim and and how to get that
set up and what controls do what
uh and if you downloaded uh if you
downloaded the workshop files
in that workshop files i have a workshop
pdf which is just
a pdf of all the slides i have so if you
ever need to
know what commands i'm running you can
just copy and paste
into it into your terminal if you
if you miss what what i entered um
okay uh so i'm gonna just get started is
everyone
following along so far okay and uh
there's a message from leonard
well i guess you guys are having a
different conversation
oh no no so there can be multiple cans
um they can i think automotive
because if you remember if you remember
the the obd port i showed
the undefined uh the ones that are
undefined it's up to the manufacturer's
uh discretion um so they can add
multiple
can networks or add their own
proprietary network
so uh so like there's a slow can which
is like gm
cannon or gm lan i forget what the word
is
so that's a lot lot slower
um no idea honestly okay
so let's try uh
let's try setting it up i know some
people had a difficulties
uh installing ic can and everything so
i'm sorry but i i mean i've been told by
dan
that they're going to record this and
post it later
onwards most likely but so if you go
so you still have chance to go to this
workshop
and get the benefit but even if you
don't get that i think you still get
some benefit
from just watching me uh do the
interactive exercises
and also um and it's only only half the
workshop is interactive so
the other half is just me doing demos um
okay uh so is is there any volunteers
is there any volunteers uh is i'm gonna
run through the this uh
setup right now
so i set up everything but
it's on a separate notebook so i'll have
to
type comments if you think that that's
slow enough i could
i couldn't be that one okay uh so uh is
your name select
that is that how to pronounce it sonic
oh sonic okay so okay i'm just gonna
run uh can you everyone's everyone see
the terminal
right now
we've got one person saying that they
can't see the screen
that your screen is is black but i i can
see it fine
and i think also um i mean you've got
something
obscuring um part of your screen right
you're trying to hide some information
there you say you don't dock yourself
that kind of thing uh
like uh uh right now only thing you
should be
you should be able to see the exercise
this thing
i don't know if you can see my mouse and
then see your mouse
but there's there's like a cross hatched
area over on the
left-hand side of your screen that uh
looks like some sort of
um i'm sorry on the right-hand side of
your screen um
that uh yeah you're moving a window
around that just showing okay
those are
shrink it down a little bit more okay uh
i'm going to just i'm going to just
minimize chat so you'll have to keep me
posted
sure
is that better can i can people see it
more yeah there's more of the screen
visible now yes
oh thank you okay um
okay so clear i'm just gonna clear my
terminal
so i'm going to run sudo mod probe
can then just enter my password
are you good i think you made it a salad
unmute uh sal
yeah i just asked him non-mute okay
okay i'm unmuted
well i'm currently running
this uh so let's
let's try it or try to you already have
everything set up the ic assignment
everything
uh right now the simulation is
is running i have a control panel and ic
simulator because i started it
before we started oh okay i'm sorry
okay let's let's go uh
let's go one one one thing then another
okay so so the mod probe
uh say uh
do do you have uh
do you have a script for this
uh i don't have a script uh shell script
no no it's just four commands so
we can get to it pretty quick
but like if you if you can't see my
screen i have i'd sent i have a pdf
that i sent it uh with the workshop
files so you can
um so all the which is just the pdf of
my slides
so you guys can copy and paste or look
at it closely
on your own screen if you can't see my
screen so
so have you run the first command
already or you're already set up
you already have everything running uh i
am already set up
setup but i i will uh
i will get another uh
another terminal ready so
[Music]
that
so i can follow you uh again
okay you can um is there is there anyone
that's not
uh doesn't have it us
running already i don't want i think
iran
uh said uh they that he or she would
volunteer
okay so maybe we can do that instead
hi um hello what would you like me to do
uh i'm just going to run some comments
can you hear me
okay yes yeah so i'm just going to run
some commands if you can follow along
i just want you to pace me because i
don't want to run through it really
quickly and leave people behind so
so have you run the first command
already sudo mod pro can
okay um
then the second character mod pro vcan
and you press enter
so the next command sudo
iplink add
dev dev vcan 0
type vcan
i already have it running in the back so
that's why i got that error but you
shouldn't get that
i think i'm missing some setups
uh do you have an error what what kind
of air do you have
not that i don't have the any of the
libraries and other stuff
installed um
i was just actually joining this
workshop for fun but i am a volunteer
for rumidicon oh so you don't have it in
oh you didn't have it installed okay
yeah
okay okay uh i guess i don't have a
chance to
okay that's fine i'll just have i'll
just run through this commands for
everyone else
but i guess because everyone's on a
different
uh place at the workshop so
yeah oh sorry i did it again
okay thank you sorry
i i was gonna say your your pacing seems
fine so i don't know we necessarily need
someone to help us pace i think we're
doing okay
okay so okay we'll just pivot to
something yeah i agree
okay so i added the vcan uh link so i'm
going to do the next one
pseudo iplink setup vcan0
so then when i run my ip link
uh then i'm just gonna do on my can so i
have it
up here so
so now i'm gonna try running i see sim
we can zero
uh so that's working so in another
terminal you can slow down
slide down what
can you please slow down oh slow down
okay
does everyone have the ic sim running
right now
for those who are able to get get it
running
looks like we're getting a lot of
runnings in the uh in the chat okay so
i'm going to open another
tab then i'm going to run uh my
controllers
so i'm in the i'm in the folder where
you where you
where you should have where you made uh
where you built your ic sim
so you can see here i have my controls
and my ic sim
executable so so now i'm gonna
run my controls
i need the v can zero again
otherwise it doesn't know what where to
pass the information in
so i'm gonna i'm gonna just make this
smaller okay
i don't know about anybody else but i
need to see the terminal
at the same time and i'm already behind
and
i'm already already lost me okay so
where did i lose you
um dot slash i see sim
okay thank you i can see it now so i see
sim
we can zero can you tell me if you can
get that running
no such file or directory so i don't
know what's happened
uh did you you should
i think you need to compile it yeah i
don't have the executable
so yeah like if you if you built and i'm
just going to close it
if you built your files like if you ran
make on
uh your ic sim directory the one you
don't downloaded
uh then you'll shoot then you'll be able
to run it
have you have you ran make on your icy
sim stuff
yes i have but there was an error that
said uh something to do with
sdl2 oh okay so uh
you have to go through another process i
i so
uh i'm sorry i can't i can't do that
right now
that's okay i'm sorry about that um
like in the public chat if like
afterwards you can go there's someone
someone who already solved that issue uh
so
okay thank you okay thank you so i'm
gonna go
controls we can zero
again okay so
so no i i know what i hope no one needs
a terminal
but so with the controls selected
if i hold down uh the up arrow you
should see the
up arrow moving so
if i hold down the left and the right uh
arrow keys you should see
the left and right uh blinking and the
door unlock is little finicky
so basically how you unlock all doors is
you hold
the right shift then you tap the left
shift
and it takes a second you might have to
do it again
or the other way around maybe
okay there we go
and i just refer to my instructions hold
right shift and tap
left shift okay it's a little it's a
little finicky the display so
it's kind of hard to get it running
sometimes
okay so um
yeah so like if it's that's fine that
means it's unlocked
so if it's completely locked you should
hold down us
okay i guess i mixed up the uh the
instructions so it's the opposite of
what i wrote down
to lock all doors and unlock all doors
uh yeah you need two terminals chris
so i think it's you hold down left
shift
uh and tap right shift to unlock and you
hold down right shift
and you tap left shift to lock
everything
okay so i'm going to move on to the next
exercise
so
so uh there's going to be a lot of
terminals so just pick up if i'm
obscuring anything
so i'm just going to minimize the
terminals i have uh
the can controllers or uh the ic sim
stuff running
so now i'm going to open up open up a
new
terminal then i'm going to run
can dump so this is part of the can
utils you guys installed
um so i'll just say canned on vcan0 and
we'll see what it's doing so i don't
know if zoom is capturing this
it's pretty uh it may not be fast enough
but uh it connected a canada i've been
just connected to
uh the virtual can interface and uh
and just dumping all the the messages
that it sees
onto your terminal can people see this
yeah okay thank you yeah that's
scrolling nicely
that's good update okay so now one other
feature we can do
of candump is that we can uh run canned
up and dump
all the files um
into oh sorry dump all the uh the
messages into a file
so i'm going to run kandam dash
capital l arrow key i guess i don't know
how you
say that word so i'm going to call mine
first.log
and vcan0
so that's basically recording in the
background
um and so we're going to try to do
something called a replay attack
so um we're gonna try to
we're gonna record uh unlocking our
doors
um and see if we can catch that message
to unlock our doors
so i'm gonna do pull down left shift
and tap right shift
so when my door is unlocked um
so then i'm going to stop my candle file
so uh if i do uh
less ls i see that i have a fan
first dot log file there
so um i'm gonna just uh
i'm going to just peek at my candom or
the my log
first.log so head dash n10
first.log and you see this
[Music]
these messages are like uh this is
similar so they're just simulating
a lot of different notes so if you see
this
um let's just do something with a little
bit more readable human readable
so i'm going to run my head command
again head
and 10 first dot log and i'm going to
dump that
into another can utils command called
log
too long so it's a little bit more human
readable
so each of these nodes each of these ids
represents
uh a different microcontroller
passing messages into the canvas
um okay so let's just look at our
uh a file that we uh like let's look at
how long our file that we just opened
this
so do if you do uh wc work which stands
for word count
but it also counts lines if you pass in
the
dash l command then you do first dot log
so you can see there's 75 000 messages
in that brief 30 seconds we had it
running
so um the way you do a replay attack is
you um replay the
the file that you captured and see if
you can
get uh come on
can you mute everyone again i think i
decided to interrupt you
um okay i guess we removed it again
so um
so the basic how it works is that you
play back
all the files you can all the messages
you capture
back onto the weekend virtual can
interface
by doing that we
we can basically say that we can trick
the system into saying that we are
running that command
uh or the system itself is running that
command so i'm just going to lock my uh
doors again so i think it's
hold right shift and left shift or the
other way around
oh i have to have to select my uh
the window with the controller on it so
so have it locked oh no i guess not
okay i'm just gonna wait to see if it's
locked okay uh
it's locked so
i'm gonna use another uh
can utils that you guys downloaded is
called can
player so i'm going to pass in
when trying to pull the log file i get
an error
can you just ryan you can just try using
le uh
uh just do you have to pass in head and
ten because it's
such a big file it could uh it can crash
it can give you errors so if you
pass in uh this command here
head dash n 10 and you have to grab it
so you have to use this vertical
separator
and log too long or you can just do this
oh i think i made a mistake here so here
what i forgot to include was you have to
pass in the name of your
file burst.log
and it'll work so that's my bad okay
so so can
player and uh i think
my instructions on the next slide so
clan
cam player dash i'm going to
show you this dash i
capitalize um
and pass in our
file hopefully it works
and we'll just wait to see if it
i guess it's 30 seconds so it'll take a
while to get through everything
so while this is okay there uh it
managed to unlock
uh the doors just by replaying these
messages so i'm just gonna exit out of
that
so basically uh the whole uh what we're
gonna do
what we you would normally do is that
you would split
um you would split that can file
or that the candump log into two
files and replay
each of them and to see which uh section
of
the which
so if we split the original file into
two files
so each one has half the can messages
then we
when we replay the first uh
at the first split the so if the first
half
and we see if that that message unlocks
our doors again
if it does great that means there's that
can message
that we're looking for is in that part
otherwise we know it's in the other half
so and we keep repeating this until we
only have uh one
um can packet left so that's the
uh that's that can uh
that's the can uh id that unlocks the
cars
so because we're not i'm not gonna make
you do this with 75 000
line file that will take you for all
night to get through
especially using command line utilities
if you look at in your workshop files
so this is this is what i get after
unzipping my workshop
so there's a file here called the hunter
lines dot log
you can try replaying
uh there you can try replaying that file
on
on your network so
i'm just going to navigate to my desktop
uh sorry navigate to my workshop files i
mean so i'm going to go to the folder
called ic sim
so i see there's 100 lines
there so i'm going to do can player
again
dash i
okay first before i run that command i'm
going to make sure
my car is locked
i have to select the controller again
so hold down rep right shift okay there
so i'm going to run it again
i hope you guys can see what i uh
yeah it's 100 lines with much faster
than 75 000 lines
so
i'm gonna try locking my doors again
okay okay yeah so i
okay so i'm going to do run
so i'm going to run a command line
utility called split
so dash l uh then i'm going to run
the 100 lines log or passing the hundred
line
dot log file name um
so
so i'm gonna just because i'm just gonna
split it into a 50 lines each
and uh and then give a precip
prefix of two and i'll show you what
that does
so we split the initial 100 lines into
two files called 2aa
and 2 a b
um so when i'm going to run it again i'm
going to run the command again
what's the word a can player
dash i and i note that my car is already
locked
then i'm going to run the 2aa file so
that's the first half
of the thing oh and it unlocks so we can
guess that
it's in um it's in the it's in that
part of the file so i'm not gonna i'm
not gonna keep going through it until
there's only like a couple lines left
uh so we can just check our work so if
you guys can read this
um i'm going to clear all the things so
uh i'm going to do run less
passing 2a and i'm going to
pipe that into grep 19
then i'm going to run a comma then i'm
going to
try to find it if there's anything that
matches uh
that line so so the id can id that
uh of the of the message that
unlocks doors is uh 19b
um so we can check it our work again
oh classes are on terminal
uh whoops where's my oh there we go
i'm gonna minimize this again so we can
do
another command called can send
uh we're just going to copy the line we
found
ctrl or right click
now paste again then i'm going to hit
enter
uh oh oops i messed up something
okay i'm gonna lock the door so you guys
can see what i just did
okay i'm gonna lock the doors again i'm
just gonna wait for it
it happens okay so i'm gonna show you if
you run the command
so it's unlocked so we know we found the
right
id number
okay uh thanks man no
i don't know how to say your name na
rizena
i don't know i'm not that good with
linux so thank you
so we confirmed that's that's the id um
so let's do something let's do the same
process of finding ids
with using a little bit more interactive
process so we have something called can
sniffer
um
okay i'm just going to make sure i see
everything
i'm just going to lock my doors because
i don't want it to blink
so i hope you guys can see everything on
my screen
because there's a lot of stuff on my
screen
so we don't actually need these two
things uh
for now or actually i guess we do
so
uh stephen 19b is the arbitration id
um that uh so each
remember each can message has a
arbitration id
which tells you uh the system where
uh which what node of the network is
coming from
um and uh followed by the actual data
packets so
uh so 19b is the actual module i don't
know if the virtual module
that that sends the commands
okay um so i'm just going to do can
sniffer and i'm going to pass in i'm
going to do dash c and you'll learn why
um later so
so so by running the dash c i it'll
highlight
all the uh all the
the bytes that are changed from the
previous command
uh so it's kind of there's so many notes
here i think
i think there's about 40 notes virtual
notes so it's kind of hard to see what
you're doing
uh so like even if you do anything like
i'm just
uh i'm just going to select this like
i'm pressing my
acceleration button and stuff like that
and you can't really see
make heads or tails of what's going on
so there's something we can do called
notching
so we can save all the bytes that we see
on the screen at this moment
so you can do it by running
if you see on the left side here uh
hashtag
and the enter key so i'll just keep i'll
just run this
a couple times and you can see
uh this red slowly going away
i'm just going to keep running it a bit
more okay this is very easy because like
this is a virtual simulator
and uh it's it's sending the same two or
three patterns over and over again
so it's easier to like uh take all the
all those messages out so now let's try
to see if you can see
i'm just going to cover up my slides
whoops
then i'm going to press the acceleration
key and you can see
there's one byte i guess you can't see
me point with my finger
but you can see that there's one byte
that's changing
so and uh and i'm going to try doing
that
same thing for the acceleration command
or sorry the left blinker
and you can see that there's one uh
byte that's changing on a different
on a different id command
not a command sorry a different can id
um so this is like still
very cumbersome because there's like
still so many um
packages flying past you in actuality
you won't
you rarely use can sniffer like from the
command line
uh you would use like a uh like a gui uh
thing called like uh something like uh
savvy can uh and that's like much easier
to see the changes and i'll demo that
later
um so well i guess i'll demo it now
sorry i forgot how my presentation went
so
originally i used i had this uh in
uh in the prerequisites but i think i
thought it would be a little bit too
hard for
to get three different programs
installed for
this test
uh it's it's saving uh chris it's saving
the bytes when i press
uh command uh sorry pound key plus enter
it's saving the bytes to uh
in memory and you can you can output
that into a file
later on so it's not just clearing the
red it's saving the
uh it's saving the messages
because how can sniffer works is that
it compares it stores the previous uh
data message and it compared and it once
it gets a new message
it compares between the old one and the
new one
and then it sees okay which bytes it's
changed and it highlights
those bytes um
uh i haven't used a wireshark for this
uh because i use wireshark for like tcp
stuff
but it's not really built for can
messages uh i'm sure i
i'm pretty sure it has an extension it
can read can uh
it can connect to socket can but it's
not the best there are better programs
for it
like savvy can i'll just demonstrate it
for you right here
so we're going to use the cavican
sniffer and
you can see right away it's like a lot
better
here
so there's a couple of commands i'm not
going to go through it right now so i'm
going to do the same thing before
instead of running a hashtag and enter
i'm just going to click notch
so then i'm gonna i can mute notch bytes
i'm gonna fade in active bytes
you can go down to the bit level but
that's a little too much information for
us right now
um so then i'm gonna do the same
acceleration command
okay there so right now i can see that
it's 244
the acceleration command key is tied to
so
it's a lot easier to see it with a can
like with the with savvy can
but obviously i can't get everyone to
install that program
and i'm going to do the same thing with
with the signals and you guys can see
that 188
is the can id for those signals
so i'm going to just close out of this
net for now
what else should okay and the
if you guys want to do the playback
uh that savvy can also has that uh
functionality um but it's still
cumbersome to
uh to start with the 75 000 line uh
file and just slowly trim it down so
this is not the file i think
it's not the oh
okay there we go so this is not the
[Music]
uh this is not to the sorry i lost my
train of thought
i think it's
yeah capture bisector so this is you can
do this a little bit easier
what we're doing before where you're
splitting the files
um into smaller files so you can do it
there's a lot more options here you can
you can just split ids like based on the
range
so the the thought behind this is that
the lower
uh numbers are reserved for
high uh
for more valuable uh uh sensors and
stuff that need to be sending all the
time
uh so for door hat for door unlocks we
can probably choose like a higher id to
start with
so that's one what's that's one other uh
um that's one other uh strategy you can
use
uh steven i'm going to cover how to do
this on a real car in the later half of
the
presentation uh and i'm gonna go through
that just ask me that
afterwards um um so yeah so this is a
little easier but it's still cumbersome
um so i'm gonna show you another way i
interact with the the
stuff uh i'm gonna do
how i can do it with python so the
strategy
is similar to it's a little bit
different
to before i'm not sure if it's possible
to run on embedded devices uh
gram matic i'm not sure if that's right
right way to pronounce it um it's savvy
cam's pretty uh relatively intensive ram
for embedded devices so
so i'm going to do a demo with python
but so i already
did this before i'm just going to show
you the results of it so the strategy is
pretty simple
uh you record i see sim
um when when you're not inputting uh
any anything like so you're not pressing
any keys or anything like that
sorry excuse me so you're not uh
and putting anything so you have like a
uh the ic7 in an ideal id
idle state uh then you record another
file
uh with canada doing an action that
we're interested in
then we can compare uh the two log files
to find similarities and differences uh
so
and with python you can do a little bit
easier so this is the code this you have
i'm not going to go through the code
right now but you guys have that in your
workshop files if you
know python and you want to go through
it um
so i'm going to first uh
open up the icsim baseline.log
so and it downloads it into uh a table
um so that's the idle one i see sim in
an ideal state
uh then i'm gonna
see i'm gonna go through each id and
count how many uh
times it's it appeared in the log file
and how many times
um how many unique packets there are
so uh you can this kind of pulls back
the
what you call uh
it it pulls back the curtain i guess and
you guys it's because it's like i see
sim is
it's the simulator so you can you can
see that there's very few unique
uh data packets um oops
so uh so i do that again with uh
with the file where i uh toggle the
the signals left and right and then i
compare
the two or sorry i i do the i count go
through
everything and count it again um
then it compares the two so in this case
because it's uh it's a simulator
we can see that's 188 is more present
in one than the other one and uh and 244
is also uh present in another one so
those are the two inputs that we enter
uh inputted so that's pretty easy to see
uh go through python
that's one other way of doing it if
you're if you're comfortable coding
and one more thing you can do with
python um
is that socket can what it actually does
is that
it extends like the tcp sockets that you
uh you would normally use so you can
connect to
uh vcan through python uh i haven't done
that but that's something you should be
aware of
um if you if you uh if you if you like
that approach
better so obviously like there's like
much more complicated analysis possible
we can do change in real time
uh changing like more complicated
frequency changes um
so
i guess i'm nervous as nervous my mouth
is drying out
but uh so in
in the car messages or sorry in the
workshop files
um i sent you guys
uh i have the the files i was talking
about before
the ics and baseline the signals if you
want to do
it again with your own programming
language that you like
but i also included the data files
for for my vehicle it's a 2016
crv honda with the touring trim audition
and i recorded uh
it in different states so i recorded it
you can record it i'd recorded it in
driving and i recorded it while i was
sitting idle in park uh i recorded uh
it by jamming all the buttons on the
steering wheel
then i recorded it turning the steering
wheel one way and the other way
and toggling both the signal and the
wiper stocks
um
uh so yeah there's uh so uh and i'm
gonna just i'm gonna use those for
uh for running uh the command
so i'm going to use those files for
running can player
and you guys can do this too so you just
got you can see how much
more information there is in an actual
um
in an actual
uh vehicle so i'm going to close out of
uh
the the icy sim we don't i don't think
we'll need it anymore
yeah this is our last exercise
so i'm just gonna force quit
uh
i think like when the engine light comes
on well will said uh i'm gonna repeat
the
message for people who can't see it do
can uh
do car store a log for diagnostics or
anything
uh i'm not sure i think it
varies by vehicle but it's typically
when you see an engine light
turn on they do store some information
so you don't have to like always have it
running so
but only for like certain cases and it
i'm sure it varies by a different mix
so i'm not sure how many people are
still following along interactively
but i'm gonna just oh oh sorry
i'm going to run can sniffer again i'm
going to use the
uh the savvy can because it's easier for
you to you at home
to read it so i'm going to use savvy
cans
sniffer i'm going to run
my can player dot i driving
dot log you guys can you'll be using
your can sniffer
instead so i'm going to show you how to
do that can't sniffer
vcan0 so then i'm going to run
the driving log i think the driving log
is huge it's like 10 minutes of driving
me going to uh tim horton drive-thru
here in canada
so it's a lot of information so um
and you guys can uh even while it's
interacting can't sniff you if you
if you type in c and enter you'll turn
on the the color again
so i'm just gonna
let it not i'm just gonna keep notching
and you speaking
okay so like there's a lot of data here
so so
uh pure trick uh if
uh peter trick asks is are there any
downsides of repeating thousands of can
commands into an actual car uh
in you you should never replay dump
replay stuff into a moving car uh i
whenever i done it i always done it in
park and uh
um i always done in park
so and i have my wheels blocked off so
the car can't go anywhere and the newer
vehicles
have uh um the newer vehicles have like
an electronic transmission
so you have a danger of like putting
into gear using a command
so uh so
see steven says i don't really
understand what notching does
so basically what notch does is that
you just it saves the data
um to a file or a memory
so let's let's just look at all of this
so here it says 50 of
ff right so if i notch that it'll fade
it
to so the next time uh there's ff in
that data spot
it won't turn on red
um we can just
i'm gonna discuss that with the real
data car
playing stuff translating this to a real
car pretty soon so
so we're almost done this stuff
so decoding signal a couple of people
asked me
beforehand like to spend some time
decoding signals
um and this is a very labor intensive
process there's like as far as i know
there's no um
there's no uh easy way of
of going through it just like a lot of
labor
so i'm just gonna turn off this can
sniffer for now
okay shut this off
so uh if possible find someone else
somebody else who already did it that's
what i did and that saved me a huge
amount of time
trying to decoding
files so the way you get this
information
is passed around is something called uh
a dbc file
uh it's also i also included that within
um your uh files that i had to download
so you guys can take a look at that
before
so i'm going to show you um
on how how it works so here
um i guess i'm just going to make sure
it doesn't block anything
so i'm gonna i'm gonna i already down
i already pointed savvy can to that uh
dvc file
so it already knows like uh what to look
for so i'm going to click interpret
files and it labels all the
the all the packets that we have data
for
so one of this is i don't know what this
actually is this is a break
so it tells you if you're holding the
break i think um
i'll go to one that i'm familiar with so
i'm just gonna
take some deselect all the ids here
and 14a so this is the steering sensor
so it decodes all of this data
into its individual components
because there's no standard to how you
can want how a designer can pack
information into eight bytes
they can do it however they want they
can do it in one
bit or they can do it in one byte or
they can do it uh
either or they can do it in a in a way
that's not
on a clean uh bite
like a they can straddle two bites too
right so
so it's not a very clean uh way to do
that
so uh
so i'm gonna demo so yeah this is
so i think that's all i have just to
show you on that
uh actually i think i can see i'll show
you how the
and you don't want to edit a dbc file
by hand because it's very error prone
you want to use like a add an editor
so let me find that steering wheel
sensor again
okay so look let's look at the signal
cancel
let's look at the signals here so let's
look at the steering wheel angle
so we defined it that five and six
um is the byte are the two bytes that
the steering angle is stored in
so here i'll show you on the right side
uh it's 16 bits so that's two bytes
it's a signed integer uh and the scale
value is
negative 0.1 so basically what it does
is that it takes
this signed integer and multiplies it by
0.1 negative 0.1 bias is just
it is a number that you add to this byte
so here
in this case is zero min value max value
and unit's name these are all
informational they don't actually affect
anything
so it just tells us like what we should
be expecting
and receiving nodes also
[Music]
what you call it also informational
multiplexing i have no idea
i never used that so
and the cool thing about savvy can i
want to show you guys before i forget
is it has really good documentation so
if i say savvy can
and i type in signal editor into google
uh the first link is
um the documentation so it's i suggest
like
it's a good place to start if you guys
can get it running on your systems
and it's really really helped me out a
lot
um so okay where am i
okay so i'll show you uh don i'll show
you
uh where i got my files so a couple
people
already mentioned it in chat it's called
there's a company called comma ai
and what they do
i'll just get to your question in a
second isaac what they do
is well let's go to their website see a
little maybe it's
easier comma i think
comma dot ai
okay i guess it's not that ex uh uh
maybe not explanatory
so it's just like a self-driving car
that you attach to
connect to an um sorry self-driving
module that you connect to
an existing car uh so
so here i don't know if you guys can see
there's like a phone like
thing here that's connected to the car
behind the uh the reverse mirror i don't
know what you call it
a reverse mirror
so it's connected into the can network
that way
and it just it just basically does
something like a level two driving i
think
so we can do basically what a honda does
so this is
here you can see this toyota vehicle and
toyota and honda vehicles only have like
basic lane keep an advanced
cruise control but this does a little
bit more on that
so for for that uh because of because of
their needs what they did is that
they started something called an opendbc
file
so here i i don't know if you guys can
read this this is very small
okay here you can see that they have
files
for a lot of models of vehicles so here
there's only files
that's
the only focus on cars that have
self-driving abilities so
cars made uh from 2015 onwards
uh so you if you if your car is like
less than five years old
it's likely that you have uh they
already have uh
some some of the canned messages decoded
uh obviously they only care about
the messages uh that
they need for self-driving uh and this
is all a lot of this is volunteer
volunteer contributed so um so it all
depends on
the amount of data you get depends on
the person who did the work
so the minimum is all the steering
actuators
steering sensors uh kinematics radar
and all that stuff so uh
this is how i found my uh file
but uh
but let's say you didn't have that what
would you do yep you had to decode stuff
from
uh every decode something from
from nothing without any prior knowledge
i think it's still good to go through
dbc files
to get a sense of how messages are
structured even if you don't have
the car so it'll get you in the mindset
of how people lay out
signals within messages yeah
yeah uh there's a lot of questions that
i went by so i'm just going to
make sure i
okay so there are some there's a couple
of savvy can questions
so i'm gonna
uh hopefully this doesn't close down
okay there we go
so to load a dbc file you go into db
file a bbc file manager and you
you can either create a new dbc file or
you can load one
and you navigate to where you have it
stored and you load it in
so it's very simple and someone also
asked how they can connect to vcan
through
uh savvy can so here you open up your
connection settings
from from this tab here then i'll just
say
add new connection savvy king connect
can connect to a lot of different
interfaces so if you have a serial
connection if a network connection so
you can connect to an ip address
or you can connect to a socket cam like
we discussed pecan
tiny can i never use these terminal
stuff so let's add another virtual
network
we can one so okay i don't know okay
it's not connected because we don't have
that interface existing so
okay so i'm just going to scroll down
okay so
i forgot where i was going so yeah
decoding files
let's say you don't have um
a bbc file like many people
who have a carb from the 2000s early
2000s
so what's one thing you can do is that
we can go through
the same thing that we did before like i
uh these are the files i
i got i introduced you guys beforehand
so
um i recorded my crv in different
states um so i'm gonna use python
uh but we don't have to go through the
uh you don't have to go through the code
it's just basically the same thing i did
before in the earlier demo
uh i'm going to load it load all the
logs into the
sorry load all the logs into
into the python tables
um and and i'm going to compare the
steering wheel log
the unique ids uh from there
to another uh to another table in this
case idle
when it was in idle mode so i'm going to
see what ids
the overlap
so will asks does obd2
specify a standard a set of messages so
we can work on
any any vehicle uh yes it's um
i think they define like 10 or something
uh that's only
uh and and some of them the
manufacturers have to implement
and some of them they don't have to uh
but it's very very basic information
so uh you're not gonna get any
uh any any anything uh uh useful out of
it
so if you ever had uh if you ever had a
uh
if you ever had to check an engine light
and your uh
mechanic runs something on it so that's
what
those standard commands uh will
tries to find so there's nothing there's
only like
10 or some commands that it specifies
everything else is up to the
manufacturers
so like i was saying before i'm
comparing
uh the steering wheel log file to
when it's idle it's cut off here
so but and i'm going to compare i'm
comparing how many unique data frames
each id has to another so
as long as they're in both files yeah
so so i'm just gonna
so i'm looking i'm trying to find the
steering wheel id
uh we had so uh you can see this better
on your pdfs
but uh like i would like you to focus on
this
so in one file we have 291
unique data data frames and the other
one we only have 20.
um uh so so that's one
so let me go back to savvy can so let's
uninterpret files so let's find that
same packet again
so and let's uh
let's do which which is the
which one do i want to do first
i just want to see what how did i lay
out my information
so yeah i narrowed down to these two uh
files are these two messages
um then i'm gonna demo in
in savvy can so there's something called
the flow view
and i'm gonna find the same packet we
found before
which is uh oh yeah first before i do
this i have to load i have to clear
these files
and file load the steering wheel files
so workshop files touring
steering wheel turning right there we go
so i'm going to clear all these flags
uh 14 which is the one we found 14a
there we go 14 in so then i'm going to
go back in here
and say flow view i guess it's behind
here
so this is very interesting i think you
guys will like this so let's go find the
same packet here
14 hey there we go so here it graphs uh
can you guys see this okay i don't i
don't think it's being blocked by
anything
but we can just play back
and we can see each line represents a
particular data byte
here uh i'm just going to stop it
because it's very distracting
so each line that represents a different
uh byte
um in a car sorry not in the car
in that message uh and it's and it shows
you how it changes
um so if you guys notice so let's just
start from the
first uh yes we're on this
first frame uh then i'm gonna play
through it i'm gonna slow down the
playback speed
to something that we humans can keep up
with so let's say a hundred
so i'm gonna play it and notice how it's
very still
so i first recorded it while not moving
a wheel
so the steering sensor has no reason to
input anything
in a neutral position also um so and you
notice
that when it goes crazy that's when i'm
turning it
one way and the other way let's see
okay there right here i think it'll just
just jump up here i'm just going to stop
it
so so before from previous knowledge
when we looked at our dbc
file we knew that five and six were
there are
key um bytes that our steering wheel
sensor is stored into it
uh oh thanks isaac for the encouragement
uh these uh
five and six is the the place where it's
uh those things are stored so
yeah i'll explain what that flashing
colors mean
yeah uh so
i want to see if i can i'm going to try
to find it so uh
let's i'm going to let's just go through
our file so here
i'm going to i'm going to try to go
through slow so here you can notice that
all the data packets are pretty constant
and all of a sudden they start changing
so here five and six
so let's let's see saying this is the
first data
byte so zero one two three four five
you know what this is not it's hard to
see there's another tool i think i can
maybe let's just stick with this for now
let's just say you already knew that
five and six you suspect five and six is
where the data is stored
uh but but you don't know if it's a
signed int or if you don't you don't
know if it's uh
a normal integer or whatever so let's
look at
let's assume it's is stored in uh
most significant bit first format so
five is the the leading digit
and six is the uh
latter digit so six there's one cool
feature here
is i can enter a byte so it will
it will play back the files and will
stop at any frame that has
uh ff in the sixth byte and i'll show
you what
what i mean what that means so nothing
nothing
so because the steering wheel is uh not
being moved so there's no nothing
so when the lights flash that's mean
like there's uh database being changed
so that's what the flashlight colors
mean okay here
uh hopefully it stops
okay it's very complicated here
i hope you guys can see it it's very
very faint
so five is yellow so here it goes from
zero
to uh to its full value to something
about two
250 some here and the
six the kais the cyan goes to
uh goes down
uh so i'm gonna show you like i'm gonna
show you and get it what i mean
so so if you guys have any
uh knowledge of let's just use decimal
numbers so let's say it's 0
1 0 2 0 3 and so on
and let's skip to zero nine and it
ends uh so it rolls over to ten right
so one five uh so that's the same thing
that's happening here
uh the cyan so the lsp so the least
significant byte
is going to zero and zero uh sorry the
yellow is going up to full
now this doesn't really make sense
because why would it go
all the way to uh in this analog
here it would be something like it's
going all the way up to eight or nine
eight or nine in the first leading digit
right so then you have to remember oh
this is a signed integer
so it's when it when you the the leading
bit
if it's turned to uh if it if it's set
to one that means it's a negative value
so this is how you can tease out if it's
uh what kind of
integer uh it is if it's a float or if
it's a
i don't think you can do floats here but
if it's an integer it's a signed integer
or unsigned integer you know so on and
so forth
uh there's another tool also that uh
that made me do it better for some
frames
so i'm gonna just close this close
without saving
i don't know if that made sense to
people just just watching uh the bytes
roll over
making sense yes no
i guess so
um let's do uh
we just did flowview yes we did just do
floating now
let's do signal view is that it no
a temporal graph is something i can show
you really quick it's very messy
but uh you just you just
highlight something it just
graphs it whenever it sees a packet so
you can see some packets are very
very rarely occur and some packets are
on all the time
so this is like some very very easy
uh tool to like see if there's any
outliers
but most of the time i didn't find much
use for it
but you may in your application but uh
graph data no
is it i'm just blanking right now ranged
it that's what it is
um okay so this is a pretty cool tool
uh i'm just gonna select uh 14 and just
another
uh and we're gonna figure out if it's
so let's say i ran the python analysis
and i found out 14a
uh uh is our file that we need
or not files sorry our can
id that's valuable to us for whatever
reason so
uh and we want to like parse figure out
what kind of
uh signals are stored within that
message
so uh and uh we can just
one way of doing it it just basically
try all permutations
uh of how you can slice up that uh eight
bytes
into smaller into smaller um
into signed end integer and you know do
all these other
permutations and just graph them and see
how it
uh and see what data makes sense
so that's kind of what it's doing but
it's in a more sensible
way so we know our signal size
is 2 bytes so this is 16 bits 16 bits
and we can try both so
so is it is it big edition i don't know
how to pronounce that
so that's msb or uh
little idiom so which is uh ls uh
least significant byte uh last
or first i might have mixed those up but
i think it's right
so we can try both uh what granularity
is
um i'll try to demonstrate it here
so let's just open up our manager
uh
where do i open this
edit there we go
forgot how to open up my pvc file there
we go
edit
okay
you know what i'll just i'll just use it
on a flow state so granularity what it
does is
uh let's say you're looking for a four
byte four bit message
uh and you have a granularity of one so
it starts on a zeroth byte
of uh of the message then it tests for a
signal from here
one two three four uh then it tries that
uh then it moves up one and if it
doesn't find anything it moves up one so
one two three four so it keeps going so
we are looking for 16 bits
so it's going to move 16 bits up wide
one bit every time
so obviously the smaller your
granularity is
the more longer it will take
so uh
so let's just assume that they're gonna
do it uh they're gonna
place the uh the signal on a clean
bite layer right so i'm sorry i closed
it again
so let's just assume that they're gonna
only place a uh
a new a new uh
a signal on like about like a byte layer
so here
here here something like that okay um
so many windows okay there so i'm just
going to say that's why i'm going to say
8 bits so
we'll try on every bite layer then i'm
going to recalculate signals
oh i guess we found something here so we
can see
this is this starts on the 32nd bit and
that's not what we
found so if i go back to the flow view
if i go back to the flow view and i say
14a
it's if we know it starts on the 47th
bit
so so let's just uh play around with our
settings okay let's play around with our
settings let's
lower our granularity maybe that will
help
okay so it's i don't know if you guys
can see
so it sliced up all the
the id uh id bytes um
sorry it sliced up all the message bytes
into different lengths
uh so here it started at the fourth bit
and read the next 16 bits
in a signed a big idiom
notation and this is what it this is
what it got
so we know our stuff started on the
47th bit
so here this is probably what what we're
looking for right here so if you look
back
so we notice that it's 44.
so that kind of makes sense so uh the
first three uh
digits or bits were probably blank
so that's why i didn't pick up on that
signal there so that's one way of
finding signals within your data
uh there's a lot of you can get like
i don't want to do all of them but let's
just do it with a larger
data set and hopefully it doesn't break
oh oh we were out of time i guess uh is
it 9 30 that we're done den
or is it uh yeah we've still got about a
half an hour till
uh until we get to the um keynote
address and the hack at a prize ceremony
so we've got some time maybe you want to
leave 15 minutes or so for questions
yeah i'm almost done so i thought i just
went over time no no no we're good
everybody's just talking about what time
it is where they are
okay okay so yeah so
so we can look at other tools so
so here it didn't really find anything
in this data set but i hope you got some
um some sense of when when you use this
tool
it's a really great tool for finding
signals uh
but i would i would recommend when
whenever you're decoding signals
is that you have some idea of how the
signal uh
will look like have a hypothesis like uh
imagine put yourself in the designer
shoes so let's say okay if i'm if i were
the designer how would i store this
signal into a message right and do a
hypothesis that way
and then do uh then test your hypothesis
that's like much better than just
generating a huge amount of signals and
trying to go go through all of them
it'll be it'll be uh it'll be
overwhelming but sometimes you that's
the only way
but um but i would suggest put yourself
into the designer to
designers shoes for uh first
so we did range state and flow view and
this is
really really cool um
the next tool is okay let's do file
what did i just say frame data analysis
okay
so let's go back to
our steering data sensor is at 14a
that's it
um i know someone complained about
seeing that
it's all i saw was just flashing red
when i was demonstrating a tool
so you guys can see why that is so so
the bottom
axis is time so this is again looking at
the steering
wheel sensor so it's not emitting it's
not changing anything
and all of a sudden it just outputs a
huge amount of data
um
okay uh so
i think that might be uh
so yeah so this this is a good way of
figuring out um
like where when to start looking at a
byte uh
or something so i'm just gonna look
through some other
things so this one's active all the time
um
so this is yeah this is constant so this
might be like a temperature sensor or
something like that
where it's not changing all the time
so i'm just going to just just give you
an idea so
i think that's is that all it no no i
have to
so yeah moving to the real world uh just
a safety um on a safety thing careful
being
working in closed spaces here in canada
it's getting cold very very cold
so the temptation is to move into a
closed space and uh
and do it but like you're gonna get uh
just be careful of co2 poisoning and
stuff
i would avoid working i would avoid
working in enclosed spaces
that's really really dangerous uh i
would suggest blocking
uh wheels off especially if you're
injecting things
into the car and even if you're not
because if your hardware
kind of spazzes out on you you don't
want it to uh
take off on you i know one of the act
one actor got crushed by his car
uh well not when he's hacking it
but it just shifted gears and he just
crushed him pushed him against
the wall so it's very very dangerous
it's like three to four thousand pound
vehicles so we're dealing with so it's
gonna win in a fight
so another way after doing it is elevate
a car on jack stands
um if you if you've never done that
before i would talk to
friends who'd who done that before so
they can teach you
so and and when you're finding uh when
you're
when you're trying to find hardware find
something with great documentation
because this will save you hours and
hours and hours of time
so i made the uh mistake of uh
choosing on hardware uh that's that was
deprecated
i didn't i didn't and i didn't realize
it at the time so i had to like go
through their uh
thankfully it was uh all their files and
stuff
was on github but i had to like read all
the files and
figure out if it how to get it running
so i must just
burnt like 20 30 hours on that
can particles you'll run into uh
in the wild we didn't discuss it uh here
so there's something called can fd
so that expands the data length to 65
64 bytes um and
this is this should be only you'll only
see this on like newer vehicles
i think uh it's 2018 and onwards but
it's not going to be in
every uh every car and this is like
much much more faster uh data
a data rate a bandwidth sorry then what
we looked at
what i never i'm not going to speak more
on this because i don't know i never
used one
and there's another thing called uh
i iso uh i think i misspelled this it's
iso tp i think not t top uh so this
is basically this is a protocol that
let's say you have a byte that's
larger than eight bytes and you want to
uh pack a package them across uh
differing uh multiple frames
uh this is a standard that tells you uh
how to do that so i never ran into this
i'm not gonna speak on
on it so it can open another network so
another not network but another standard
i guess so
so these are something to be aware of
um
so so selecting hardware so
cost is the big uh issue uh so
uh the one i chose was like a 130. it's
it's comma ai's uh like a ca um can
reader
but they deprecated it so it's not
something i would recommend
so the cost varies on based on
how fast it can read and how much memory
it has
so if if you choose a device with a
small
amount of data memory it's going to keep
dropping bytes and you're going to have
a hard time trying to find the packet
you're looking for
because it's it's never captured and
you're going to
chase your tail so um and form factor if
you want something that's small and can
connect into
uh can connect into your obd port
without
being obtrusive that's going to cost you
and especially if you want to read if
you want something that can read on
multiple
can and other um
uh another bosses simultaneously
without dropping anything that's also
going to cost you a lot so
and and also you should look at uh what
kind of api
it will support out of the box so socket
can serial whatever
so so that's like one less thing you
have to implement
to get it to work with what you want a
logic analyzer might
be the best place to start uh i have
something called uh
discovery analog discovery something
like that
and it supports it um but you just have
to be careful because the can i think
signals is at 12 volts
plus or minus 12 volt and you have to
drop it down to 3.3 volts
um and i'm going to recommend you a book
called uh
car hackers handbook it was written in
2016.
um it still it's some of it's out of
date but it's most of it is really
really good
um and that's like that's a good place
to start
uh if you want to get more into beats or
i'm just
uh gonna how do i get to
so i'll just i'll just show you the
table of contents
what it covers so it covers like sdr
stuff if you want to try
uh attacking the wireless stuff um
if you want to attack the ecu which is i
think the engine control unit
so there's like a lot more stuff in here
than i did that i didn't cover
so this is a good place to start um
uh we yeah so that's the thing and open
garages has an email list
um i'm not sure how oh i guess i didn't
copy the thing
i'm not sure how active their email list
is
i'll update the file and put it back up
with the actual link
it's not very active but it's it's a
google forms uh google email list i
think
so it's very searchable so so comma ai
is also the thing i we talked about
before so they have a github with
like almost in their entire product
open source so it's a very very good
place to look into
so we we discussed the opendbc files
before um
and uh one other tool i ran out across
into i'm just still
figuring out how to use it there's not
so much for reverse engineering
but if you're developing uh can networks
uh can dev
studio is a cool thing to start
it can simulate you can set up
cam networks and simulate it i'm not
going to spend too much time on here
because i haven't used it too much
but it's something you may want to look
into
uh any questions
okay we have 20 minutes yeah
so there's one chat there yeah greg asks
amit in your experience are current gen
cars implementing
any measures specifically to prevent
manipulation injection of messages or
all
are all are the can buses basically a
free-for-all
so yeah uh you know that on the car door
uh
trick i showed you about recording the
can messages and playing it back
uh that may not work on uh
a lot of cars because basically on the
obd port they might put a firewall
and the only uh and the firewall
prevents
only allows certain certain
messages from getting through so um uh
so yeah so you're not that's going to be
a limitation
okay so let's see don asks our can id is
from
uh tp tmps dashboard light
manufacturer specific or standard i'm
not really sure about that
and uh i don't know how that functions
uh so you have to look it up and there's
a lot of hacks
been done around that so if you just
google around it you'll find something
um what's the advantage of running can
at
12 volts uh i'm not really sure i think
that just
historically how it happened how it
worked because i think the car battery's
at 12 volts right for most
things so maybe it's that um
so yeah alex says that tpms is
manufacturer specific
uh will will asks are there a lot of
response messages
for instance drivetrain systems sending
to steering input um
uh
uh i'm not sure uh i haven't
uh look i haven't dealt with anything
that requires
sense and receives the command i looked
at on a very uh
very very straightforward things like
steering wheel sensors uh whether your
foot's on the brake brake
pressure acceleration
stuff like that i haven't looked at
anything that's more complicated than
than that alex says it's cans a plus or
minus five volts
so that's my bad um
you can reach out uh isaac asks me how
how it you can connect to me
you can send me an email at uh i don't
want to say it here
but you can you can reach out to through
me
you can reach out to me through
hackaday.io
so there's a public chat and you can we
can talk there and you can direct
message me i think too
so
okay greg says that there's a better
signal integrity with
plus or minus 12 volts or a 5 volts so
that's that's good to know
anything else i can help anyone with i'm
sorry that everyone
everyone couldn't get uh their thing set
up uh
it's it's a little complicated thing to
set up so
i hope everyone got some use out of it
anyway
i have a kind of an oddball question
here that might be a little bit out of
your wheelhouse but
okay i'm just kind of curious the the
it appears that newer cars have um
uh actuators and and
you know on the steering system and
sensors for steering angle and stuff
like that which
is news to me i'm kind of of a luddite
when it comes to cars i like a mold but
um is that
when when about did that start is it
really just for cars that can do
like you know lane departure correction
and things like that or
yeah so uh anything anytime you need uh
it needs to correct the steering
a steering wheel like uh so lane keepers
assist
so i think in my car my old accord used
to
old is 2015 but it used to kind of
fight get uh fight you if you're
drifting out of
a lane so uh and uh and more
like uh some stuff some cars uh even my
accord uh
according hrv can navigate curves on
their own
so in addition to cruise control they
can take some basic curves not something
crazy so they can take basic curves as
well so
yeah so anything that has like uh the
advanced stuff
like the uh automatic braking lane keep
uh that's where you find these systems
before that there's no need for uh
it to uh exist i think also like some
cars had sell auto parking so
it might have also been implemented
there so that's that might have been
before
uh this all this lane keeping scene okay
cool well maybe one day i'll buy a new
car and
have something to play with too i think
you can still do some a hacks
with with the older stuff i haven't done
this but you can i know people try to
mess with their ecu to get more
horsepower or different performance
so yeah that's something you might want
to try but you can break it so
that's not that's the only downside
practice on a rental car
yeah one thing i saw like if you look at
the car hackers handbook
is that they they pull out uh old parts
from like wrecked cars
so especially if your car is popular you
might be able to find salvage components
and just run them up independently and
uh and just test on like isolated
components
and just hook it up to power and see
what it sends and you can input
something to it
they cover it more in the car hackers
handbook but that's something that's
something you can guys can do it
look into if you're trying to do
something more intrusive and you don't
want to break a vehicle and you just
want to
mess around with something simple okay
cool thanks
uh before we lose too many more people
which we haven't lost that many but
we still got uh quite a few and i want
to make sure we put in a pitch for um
the uh um the keynote address that's
coming up
in 13 minutes or so plus
uh the the hackaday prize ceremony so we
get to find out who won the hackaday
prize this year so make sure i put the
link in there that's a live stream go
and go and check that out um if you
are so inclined anybody else have any
questions
we could probably uh free up some mics
now if you want to just
ask instead of type
and i'll be available on the public chat
so if you guys want to ask me questions
later on
i'm glad you guys enjoyed uh enjoyed it