so I'm not discounting these papers
their crate papers they talk about
awesome techniques and procedures that
you can apply to other things but when
you're talking about risk to an
organization 1 bypass for one
application in one scenario is not
something I want to invest in a Java so
we've we've dealt with all buffer
overflows and and heap overflows right
all that's done you met protects us
against all of that right it's not an
end all be all but it does a really good
job so what about jobs jobs kind of dead
so I can actually skipped a lot
but the reason why i wanna talk about it
a little bit is we're going back to that
dirt road mentality me as an attacker
when I see when I do a fish and job was
still prevalent couple years ago right
when I do if I see the first user agent
come across as this browser anyone tell
me what this prosperous anyone know what
a user agent is one person in the room
knows what a user ages ok we're gonna go
really well here so this is a Firefox go
everything is Mozilla Wow 64 that means
it's 64 or 32 bit now we got trolls
died May 23 times about this application
about this operating system just by them
surfing the web site that I've setup for
fishing I don't even have to capture
credentials I don't have to exploit the
box I know everything I need to know
about their browser right so the cool
thing is that once once the job of
plug-in is enabled or or or triggered by
a job application the request for that
application actually comes from the job
or process and the job a process has a
different user agent so when I see this
summer crossed for this come across with
this come across the inside of my web
blogs guess what I do I have this
wonderful dynamic application for
fishing that says oh you're running this
portable version of Java I will send you
this exploit its really simple what do
you do on the defender side anything
that is an outdated version of Java
block it at the proxy done so this
actually got this is a lot less
effective these days because Chavez
basically blocked in every single
browser but the mindset is still the
same start thinking about how an
attacker sees things and focus on that
dirt road going to the point where where
you can make effective protections and a
smaller scale that work better so that's
what I see if they never see that there
were great and you will never see this
before you just click OK
mortals where the trolls and in the
other talks
you guys just fine my talking going
we're gonna do this
approved so this is what I used to talk
about is is blocking at the proxy
because that was the only way you could
do it and the cool thing about this is
that it worked in SLO as well right so
if you look at a proxy Log you see the
user-agent still goes a crossed just
fine
inside proxy logs for SSL traffic on
nafta alright so there's September 2014
I it's on gordon says we're going to
block anything that Saturday
patch Tuesday went around and things got
better than chrome said we're going to
follow that same thing a year later and
said we're gonna stop all things from
chrome are all Java plug-in stuff from
Chrome which is better than just
outdated
Firefox so if we got rid of if you got
rid of all of the Java stuff now what's
next for your point of view what are we
doing that
JavaScript c'mon lashes back
ok see this whole wire thing doesn't
work so well alright so we got we got
through the flash suffering and to
protect against / I don't really have
anything for you
it runs in the browser already so you
have to have a exploit for it what are
the things that is much much more like
job than anything else in flash is Adobe
AIR anyone ever heard of Adobe AIR yeah
so it'll be here
runs as an executable on on your actual
web system right you know that right
there is no pop up asking you that
you're you're wanting to run it you
don't have to sign anything actually
better than better than jobs in that
case the other thing about this Adobe
AIR thing is that it does the exact same
stuff as Java it sends the request over
to the Adobe AIR application and
plugging and then it pulls down the code
so you can protect it and the very same
way that we did Java in the previous
slides ok so let's move on to some of my
books on on current pen testing /
protections so this one is one of my
favorite stories of all time I was
working as a stock analyst or search and
Rab guy came along they hear all the
reports for Alltel things that we caught
looking through the port weather.com
plugin weather.com plugin weather.com
flogging removed removed to root PWD on
plugging her mood bTW dump removed from
where ya yes sir
the one that's sitting on the internet
so the guy was like yeah we got it we
gotta removed does anyone here know what
Peter be dumped does except the people
over here
hashes hashes passwords basically in
the broadest sense of the word so
password jumping to was on an IIS server
and I got removed but that's ok we're
all good right and it's so so we started
investigation or like it got there
somehow it was on that box somehow so
one of the things that I i stress is
that while while a lot of a lot of teams
turn this thing called the hips or host
intrusion prevention system or or AV
they turn these things on but they they
they don't make them go into into actual
protection mode so hips McAfee's the
biggest person in the in the world so
everyone has McAfee's hips so I can say
that that's the application
well the problem with that is that the
host Intrusion Prevention part never
gets turned on its always disabled only
mood because it breaks a lot of stuff is
your applications down it stops all
things from working however you can set
up blocking on specific categories only
so they have an entire category of
hacking tools turn that on
so idiotic + was the only application
that did this this is my first gave this
talk in 2014 it was the only one that
gave this is but there are a lot of a
lot of systems and even PowerShell can
do this now
logon alerting for valid logs anyone
actually on their home computer audit
their successful long guns recorded
so successful log onto something that
very very few organizations do more and
more doing it these days but they don't
do very much so the the awesome been
tested I did that had this enabled was
one of my biggest sales of all time
so how this happened as I I got on nice
tits and a fish got the fish got into
their application using Java was awesome
got my first started going around first
box had two main admin on it done right
dropped as has started dropped his
password or house at the time I don't
know rumor which instead of going around
to different boxes it was like two
o'clock in the morning cuz that's when
all the best pen testing happens on
Friday of last day of the dentist so we
were going around and hitting box after
box trying to find our are in goal and
this man had it set up through a tiara +
so that whenever his account was used
more than one in more than one place
within a five-minute period you got a
SMS alert about it he said this up it is
self and he had the ability 3d on a
pledge to send an SMS back to reset his
password automatically so all we did was
we woke up at two o'clock in the morning
so I that happened sent him SMS
resetting the password to the next day
came in and we were already stunted we
couldn't do anything we had we had not
gotten any more access than he found his
broker got us out and that was it
and all he did was roll over 2 a.m. and
sent a text that was his security it was
awesome
hips we've already talked about that
phone skinny I'm gonna get on a soapbox
Omarion kind of a soap box on other
topics but also talks about this there
are too many organizations these days
that you've on scanning shit hit the box
to the venomous can and then send
their vulnerability scan results
directly to the owners of those
applications say hey go Pyxis you know
the problem is with that they don't care
the application or only cares that it is
online they also have no idea what a
buffer overflow means or does he might
have an idea but if it's Apache PHP
vulnerability in XYZ plugin as their top
critical vulnerability they're going to
last you off the stage
why because that is a critical and on
RedHat they roll patches backwards in
and then the Apache version doesn't look
the same and without actually analyzing
what is in those reports you are doing
your entire company to service without
looking at those before you send him off
the people say here are the actual
exploitable things here are their
critical things that you need to look at
yes it's going to take more time yes you
can't do the entire organization in a
month or depending on the size of the
organization right you're going to have
to explain that to your boss to say I'm
the world's can guy but I can't complete
this an amount of time because I'm
actually doing analysis on it what you
paid me to do that's gonna be hard
conversation but you need to have it if
you're going to be a scanner the cool
thing about this is even if you're not a
vulnerability scanning person or even if
you don't know exploit or any of that
stuff or know how to exploit machines
the next time your Pinterest company
comes around and say hey we're going to
start the dentist in about a month ago
hold on hold on let me give you my
phones can there be like when I get up I
get to know all the cool stuff that's
right here to tell us what's wonderful
about an hour and a half to two hours
three hours however long it takes them
to look at phones can they're going to
be able to tell you which things are
exploitable they're gonna give you more
analysis on that one scan result than
any of your guys good or maybe not like
depends on what skill set you guys have
right in your organization but but
you're using that Penn testers time more
effectively to go back to a question
that Erica earlier how do you how do you
kill that animosity between red teamers
and the people who are ready they're
trying to push the stuff I've had for
that what I do on a call is I go I know
I know when I'm coming in as a
consultant what's what's the biggest
issues that you're dealing with these
days what's what are you trying to push
I will make sure that that's on my
report right and then now we're friends
now we're friends now I'm pushing your
agenda now I might disagree with it and
we'll talk back and forth on that and
I'm not going to blame except what
you're asking me to do but making it so
that it's more collaborative piece is
where we're where we need to go with
these things so get your sisters
involved use their time wisely one of
things to talk about
also skip it
yeah crowdsourcing security with it so I
used to work for a company really large
company fortune 1000 and we started a
really cool program that is totally not
my idea but I'm stealing it and
proposing is my idea on these lights so
what we did was inside the company we
had this program that's a day if you see
a security incident physical digital any
security incident you've got points
how much does it cost the company how
much 10 points as Casa company 0 total
budget use $0 every single boss on the
planet will love that right so after
after a while if after a month or two
months or whatever it person errors
Asian got points and it became
competitive and once you have these
points if you were the top three in our
organization or
different business unit the top three
you got a letter from the president and
owner of the company saying thank you
for your service to our company now for
a lot of people that's awesome you can
put that in your resume to put that in
your in here
weekly or monthly review our yearly
review now you have something to go and
say hey I did this I have this email
from the present company if that is not
incentive for you there was also a Visa
gift card gift card was $100 it was $200
for the second place and $300 for the
first place if you can get three hundred
dollars in your pocket every single
quarter for just reporting a fish
wouldn't you write even people who are
security people would love to just have
you know a free gift card they cannot
tell the wife about Muse leader right so
great thing is that now in our
competitive leaving gave badges how much
does bad just cost it doesn't cost the
company anything so we gave badges for
people who reported things we gave
physical security badges so if you if
you notice that when tailgating you know
how many tailgating and incidents
happened on the first quarter that we
institute this program thousands across
the entire company thousands you know
how many happened after the after the
second quarter one or two people would
actually go come back from lunch and
watch for anyone trying to tailgate to
get points to get something for free so
the cost of a breach is 100 million to 3
million 7,500,000 $500 quarter easy sell
to all of your business corporate
executives and stuff really used to get
going
we r while I was there we we took this
to the next step we actually instituted
internal bug bounty program we should we
said hey this is going so well we're
giving points away all the time there
were gonna say hey if you see a problem
in any one of our applications as you're
using them you can get points where to
buy reporting that bug how many of you
in here have gone into some internal
page to a school site or chew corporate
website or or something and it broke in
some way and you saw sequel or you saw
some other error on the page and he went
off that sucks it's broken and kept
going right for you guys if what we did
was made it so that if you could if you
reported any of that we found we had the
people you know that would take care of
that that's the important piece you when
you have to employ a couple people under
help desk or whatever to look at these
reports and validating so it does cost
money but usually from people that you
already have
moving on to another topic any parts
parts are funny I'm you get to watch
attackers do stuff but trying to get a
honeypot into a corporate organization
the size of Fortune 1050 is not gonna
happen I mean you have to be shooting
rainbows out of places to be able to get
it to work or organ approved so one of
the ways that we we work through this to
say hey we've gotten to the point where
we do relatively good security when
wanna wanna see more of what the
attackers doing is by setting up a WS
unlimited or
yes sir or some GPS somewhere and then
on our corporate website on the
company's main website we port forwarded
1433 force equal out to an AWS account
so it was going into our corporate
network then the firewall was turning
around to some other application on the
internet so we actually had a valid
honey pot that never touched our
internal organization and looked like it
was valid
now the now the defenders got to look at
more of what the attackers were doing so
we did this on a number of occasions a
number of different applications we had
so there's a couple that we're only on
SL we put 80 on their stuff like that
yes this is my favorite vulnerability of
all time it is built into Windows all
the way up through windows 10 has anyone
ever seen that setting I guarantee this
that at least 20 people in this room
right now are looking at their laptops
ongoing yep it's because its default on
you know what happens when the settings
default on your Windows application or
your Windows OS goes hey do I see anyone
on my network called W pad guess what by
computers called
W pad every single one of them actually
have an issue with his home because I
forget to set the setting on my BM's and
then I can't get the internet for some
reason and then I remember that all of
my computers are called W bad but this
setting turned on
looks for computer called W bad anywhere
you are on any network so your theory on
gogo in-flight or Starbucks it will look
for me pad once it does this it then
asks that server computer that says it's
too bad for proxy settings guess what my
computer does provides the proxy
settings the great thing about this is
that the CFAA the car Computer Fraud and
Abuse Act says that you were actually
seeing my computer so you're the one
doing illegal stuff not me so as soon as
I as soon as I provide those proxy
settings if I do anything but provide
those proxy settings then I i get into
legal ramifications so how do you defend
against this in your corporate network
make sure that you had actually has a
DNS setting ipv6 they made it more
difficult to figure out its W W W bad
Windows and Microsoft you're awesome
disable NetBIOS inside of the main this
is a really hard one to get right
because every single user for every
single computer so if you log into one
computer and then go to another one you
have two different product yet different
settings for this NetBIOS needs to be
turned off on everyone that's hard to do
there are some like stackoverflow in
other settings to get this done but it's
really hard so everyone turned out to be
bad now is if not my computers on the
network to
DNS this is where I start getting jaws
drop DNS turn it off
turn off the united in corporate
networks you can do this as long as you
have a proxy and we all have proxies
right no unfortunate but a lot of other
organizations don't want to go through
the hassle of dealing with making a
proxy or or saying it so that's not
transparent guess what a transparent
proxy is to an attacker transparent it
doesn't do anything so why do you have
it
well we would do well built during great
web filtering means I go to the web
filtering company I go to their submit
Web Filter update I go then my evil
attacker dot com website what kind of
category is it travel five minutes to an
hour later they've updated it they've
come to my website I went to a point set
expedia.com they go hit its travel I
then rewrote my website to something
else
Bob's your uncle your categorization is
awesome so how does this relate to
Dennis genus prints for example when I
first started this big company I thought
I was the biggest guy on the block I
thought I was awesome I was like hey
guys check this out I just started
working on this this DNS based c2 you're
never gonna see it goes over command
control over DNS it does a resolution
all the way up and down the chain I
started running it didn't work all the
other retailers are on the team relation
what's this like I got it could work
it's awesome and they were just laughing
at me because in this in the entire
fortune 10 company TNS didn't work it
resolved anything for Active Directory
just fine but the Active Directory DNS
service did not have for dinner
so how does this work how does how can
you survive without the internet works
on DNS right what happened was their
proxy did all the DNS requests when you
submit a request to the proxy server it
doesn't do the DNS requests first does
it after for HDTV so problem solved so
the cool thing about this is that it
kills in cut entire class of command
control that's getting more popular each
day so if you turn off the in this
internally at least forwarding off any
kind of seats you that they do so let's
say I'm an attack when I hit your
organization in your DNS turned off I
sent over my awesome seats you based
your DNS basie to i get 400 400 people
the clip all four hundred people click
and run my binary guess what happens I
can't do anything so it doesn't matter
if I get code execution and that's the
point of the stock is getting to the
point where your users can click on what
ever they want wherever they want and it
doesn't do anything on your vision or it
runs and I'm not cool enough to write i
AI based see two batteries so anyone
recognize this logo
this is directly stolen from someone
else
the slightest trudeau like the reason
why I copied directly and ask permission
first was that this slide is absolutely
true there's not an organization in the
world even foreign ones try pen testing
a vision that different language than
you and you try and go see Ed Cowan
ford's backslash like windows or tried
to the system user it's all different
anyway
but these were everywhere for some
reason it's a universal language to make
your password
welcome one no idea why so how do you
deal with this deal with this as a
recession by getting your pen testers to
do your password audit you would not
believe how Getty a pen tester will get
when they won independence you say here
here's our domain controller like I want
you to a password on it you'll go you'll
get him to say we actually know what
that word is cuz I got three kids but
seriously they have so much fun and the
cool thing is that now they have
passwords great now they can do more
fingers even faster are you benefit out
of that right you just getting more out
of him so ask your pen tester comes if
you can't do it yourself
the cool thing is as part of our
reservations we set up a p.m. on a
domain controller all had access to was
the domain controller it was like 12 one
local host or hostess only three or
VirtualBox whatever they did was every
every every quarter it did a password on
it using the rocky you list if your
password was in the Rocky list you got
an email warning saying that your
account was going to be locked out
within a day if you didn't change the
password so anyone who had the password
in it is in the rocky or in the rockies
they got a notification saying they had
24 hours to change the password or or
their password or there would be a lot
and this being put on my clock out after
day they didn't respond burden change it
so it did it is dumping read it you know
it's tested this is crazy awesome so
guess what when when I'm on a pen tests
ordered or doing arranging this
afternoon I dump your domain controller
and not a single one cracks guess what
is going through my mind as psychology
piece I did something wrong
not your your passwords are great
because no one's bastards ever great I
did something wrong so I'm gonna stress
out trying to fix my cracking tool to
fix it so I can actually get a password
to dump or a password to crack and then
when I finally get one of you like oh
it's good but if you can get inside the
head of your attackers and screw them
that's the best friends before I get to
the very stuff we're talking more about
that I'm gonna get into the clinic in /
proxy one of the cool things about this
is the psychology of it so in the
company are used to work for whenever if
you were the first person on the first
day of the month to come into the
company and start your work you would
see this at google.com we comments
blocked his google.com block okay and
then it's a don't worry this could be
the first time today so attempted to go
here click on the unblock to allow this
through on block is red
walk it is we are quick green buttons
automatically this is great blog but it
actually does absolutely nothing it's a
placebo effect it makes you feel better
that you didn't go to a website it
basically distance back I'm block is red
so the other cool portion of this is
that it's not appear for some reason is
is on the actual / set as for the entire
company so if I go to expletive website
about bad things that humans do together
in natural way
so if I go to their website and this
this pops up the crazy thing that goes
through users mines in your mind is do I
really want this for the entire company
no I do not right now they have a log
now it's this road now it's in their
face saying that I i as a as a proxy
admin have a longer view allowing bad
website to go here
the insane piece about this is that it
works that you have less infections
because of it
why because I don't know of a piece of
malware on the planet that can click a
button
whatever can do it
Empire can't do it strike can't do it
all of the other piece of our poison ivy
can do it like there isn't now where
they can click a flash-based button so
guess what your users can click anything
that you want and it's not gonna get
allowed through unless it's going to a
valid website that someone's already
gotten two before and said yes go there
the interesting thing about this is the
cool thing about this is that most
people who do fishing so I set up my
mind I'm not that will set up my command
and control on the same part because I
don't want if they could official
website to block my commanding control
user might click on saying yes allow
this through to their official website
if you're really good but guess what
once they have color code execution
website because the malware can click
the button now
help you if you loud SSH outbound
doesn't help you if you allowed 21
outbound doesn't help you if you like
all the ports are found that most
universities and colleges do write this
can only help once you have strict rules
to only allowed go through the proxy ok
that makes sense
hired Rob stage I don't mind doing on
time and it's ok so even canaries this
is my favorite part of the top so this
is all about how I got caught how many
painters to talk about how they get
caught the reason why they don't ya
is because if a reputation about the
people
or learn are open to it but again that's
what I had my first and then temperature
due tomorrow in CCDC or tonight Dec
demanding temp inside a description it
sit here is the password for temporary
password for domain admin what I didn't
look at is how
hours it was allowed to login 0 so when
I first got this is on the test I was
like awesome descriptions as the
password right out
medication successful it works good
choice
everywhere
anytime was used to like 400 emails but
this is how you catch that actors make
it exciting for them to get something
and then the cool thing is there's very
little false positives how many times do
you think a regular users gonna look at
a description of a domain admin ago I'm
gonna try that out every day the other
one was this past 2014 one so there was
a share called password audit 2014 on
the on the network first thing I did on
test really gotta show looked at past
chair Mike
into it opened up it was good as it gets
all the passwords for megs of stock so
it looks like an actual word from John
the Ripper whatever so it had everyone
deny on it
Commission does anyone know in Windows
wedding everyone didn't I rule does even
if your system it over there so it's
just a couple ways to get around this
but it's not something that you normally
think so if I'm an ad in a standard you
I cannot
the allow me to see that it doesn't
everyone tonight on it so guess what I
did attack her I wouldn't say ok I'm
going to trial of quick access to let me
try it with other users with each other
so I tried it with every user that I had
guess what the defenders did walk out
out out out out any false positive this
creates
if there if someone is looking for this
file and opens it they have bad
intentions even if it's accidental even
if it's an insider
ok backup database 112 so in this one is
a guy who actually hired because we
didn't want to have him defending
against this anymore
set up computer called backup database
so the first thing we did on the test
was look at this ABC had a very outdated
version of my sequel on Windows
apprentices in the room were like oh
right so it was the first thing I did
was route
but it's dead authentication successful
and then double back to try this again
coming back to my problem with this guy
was removed so all it ever did was say
successfully returned and host so you
could have indicate as any user on the
planet and it would just be back you
know disconnect you would one be lo from
this thing and it was just a Raspberry
Pi or something
any web developer that it was hilarious
because he would get scanned by these
scans every so often and he did it
because they need up to six like single
injection and cross-site scripting and
all that crap they didn't want to know
what he did was he set up all of these
fake
htaccess forwards so that any time you
scanned it with the vulnerability
scanning tool it said 402 which is
payment require so he was basically
telling all of the scanner monkeys to
pay him next one
anyone ever go to get credit card
numbers dot com everyone's like no hard
numbers dot com is actually a really
cool website that lets you generate
numbers pick one dummy data using your
database and this one really horrible
because on this test we are we were
tasked with getting credit card data so
we got the credit card data by accessing
Oracle database and then Oracle database
we had gotten Oracle guy who was really
good at Oracle databases and what he did
but he would listen all the Oracle
databases in the thing that they're
called something else but anyways the
databases and their names like ch4
42101 561 credit cards t-series 76 more
54321 like all of these are the names so
guess where we win the one that said
credit cards we downloaded all of the
credit cards that we went to the report
more like we got all your cards and they
relate you got that one that are
dominated caught you and you don't get
any of the other one because every
single one of the third databases where
the actual credit cards we didn't even
look we didn't even go into any of the
other databases anyone ever deal with
juniper VPN this Jennifer Jennifer VPNs
are actually pretty cool of him in the
back door which is also cool but anyways
they had the ability to make their own
custom HTML pages for your insight or
whatever and what is dude he set up his
VPN website to have eighty-four username
password embedded as they HTML comment
inside of their database inside of the
custom website for their Jennifer so
when we went to abuse first on it like
crowds like it's just that we didn't
have to use Eric for his shoe horn stuff
asking about that later so its credit
right in there so we tried the critical
they worked like we're in
had 00 apply to it but couldn't do a
single thing in the locker IP adresses
like all of this stuff about are all
about
false positive ways of detecting bad
guys by using their own psychology
against them this one this one got me in
trouble specifically so we were doing a
test and we had a bunch of our guys on
the team doing fishing and a bunch of
our guys on the team doing web so I was
doing journalism the fishing people have
did their side of stuff they got like 50
credentials but it didn't get internal
act like they had fifty stuff so that we
on the T but inside I'm like hey I found
a place where we can validate this thing
and maybe get more stuff maybe get more
you know access so I stab incise log-in
actually should go to demean unit so
it's ed in enabled we can do more with
this so I started hey guys you got the
critical let's try some of these out I
tried every single one of them all it
did was forward back to the main page
and every one of those accounts got
locked out or changed inside of the team
was they didn't you burned every single
one of them next one you guys can do
this guy actually had telnet device just
a Raspberry Pi whatever connected to a
small little minor next to his desk and
said anytime you see 423 traffic ever
put up a red red sign and then it gave
him since he was the system admin as
well
gave him the exact court that it was on
so we were doing an internal testing in
this office that the system would put us
in this unused off like that
on the first floor he walked up like a
guy so he blocked airports and we were
pretty much done all this stuff really
is is to make it so that you guys think
about attackers more people than some
magical unicorns that can get anything
done if you think of them as people then
you start thinking about the psychology
involved in it and then you start
thinking about ways that you can really
true but one of the one of the pieces
that I stay in corporate America that
don't involve some reason on the
security side of things is to help the
helpdesk get any order to your front
line near the people who know when weird
stuff is happening I get caught on
Pinterest border but I people to provide
security box it's it's the Oracle admin
says hey I got a weird logging did you
guys look into this and they call the
help desk or they call you know the
firewall a dinner or something else they
call someone and the fact that
organizations don't get their helpdesk
involved in this security thing that's
pretty much it very much
questions comments concerns saved
Radames he ok