without further ado please come said
Mike rounds this great thanks Josh
good afternoon now check right I thought
to be careful so before I came in and
turned myself on office not couldn't be
happier but let me just begin by saying
I want to thank you to Dakota State
University for hosting the 2016 as one
of the many sponsors will help to make
this conference to reality we just try
right now I am NOT an expert in any way
shape or form with regards to anything
to do with cybersecurity but i wanna lay
this out in terms of a perspective from
someone who is in the united states
senate who cares about what it means to
our country so today on a per say thank
you to all those sponsors are helping
make this thing work and most
importantly I want to express my
gratitude to all of you and the audience
for your contribution is to
cybersecurity 21st century whether you
are a professor a student or a crack in
the property sector you are working to
address one of the foremost issues we
find ourselves with today
protecting our citizens our
infrastructure and our military from
cyberattacks must be a top priority for
the federal government it is achievable
but it will require the cooperation
the pentagon the Department of Homeland
Security and perhaps most importantly
the private sector are crucial role in
providing security in the cyber world
the Kodokan advertisers have that as up
to code is premier security event all in
the middle of a corn field any of you in
the audience with DSU success story
that's why we're here to give back to
help to train the next generation and to
learn from one another and we can
emphasize enough the Dakota State
University's a national model of success
to producing our futures
workforce 2019 just three years from now
Mike Brown Michael Brown the CEO of
cybersecurity workforce demand will rise
to six million individuals with a
projected shortfall of 1.5 million so
there's going to be a huge demand for
all of you
us' Cyber Command in particular is
seeking to recruit four thousand cyber
professionals to assemble a hundred and
thirty three teens with various missions
by the year 2018 not adequately protect
our nation's networks and maintainer
information security dominance in the
future we must make certain our
workforce is increased demands immediate
just exactly that right here in South
one of the three TDs you students
studied computer science for
cybersecurity in some capacity
2012 the University esteem eighty-three
percent increase in students majoring in
one of its three cybersecurity majors
the issue is also the first college in
the United States to offer a major in
cybersecurity it is one of 14 universes
endorsed by the National Security Agency
as a center of academic experts in cyber
security operations and proud of all the
work
yes use leadership professors and
students are doing to become a national
leader in cybersecurity education and
training this success is a result of the
committed faculty and universities
leadership's efforts to integrate
technology into the culture of the
entire campus Dakota State University's
leadership has proven that universities
in rural states can provide a
world-class program and students to
prepare them for high demand 21st
century jobs today I've been asked about
legislating cybersecurity but really I
want to focus on how we congress can
work with you
who are truly the the experts to produce
sound cybersecurity policy congress were
pulled in many different policy
directions every single day
those of you in the audience and are the
experts in the trenches addressing cyber
security on a daily basis
expertise on these issues is valuable
and must be a part of any congressional
plate of effort and Congress must work
to be more inclusive one legislating
cyber security after all congress simply
makes the law you are the ones who will
be most affected one of bill goes into
effect so after my remarks like happy to
take your questions are more interested
in hearing from you on how we can better
address challenges that being said let
me quickly update you on what we're
working on in congress related to cyber
at this time with the bipartisan
payments innovation caucus which I'm
co-chairing was senator Gary Peters of
Michigan the goal of the caucuses to
explore new and innovative technologies
in the payments industry and to address
how we can protect our online payments
from cyber threats this is especially
important to me because I had a South
Dakota has been a leader and innovator
in the payments industry the technology
payments industry impacts nearly every
corner and is changing rapidly growing
as technology has expanded the reach of
mobile payments South Dakota's role in
the world economy has grown
substantially as well
still falls has been called on that
credit built and a few months ago I
visited a startup company in rapid city
that is rolling out a new point of sale
device that uses biometric data to
authorize a payment I'm proud of South
Dakota's leading role in payments
innovation yet it highlights the need to
keep consumer data safe from hackers by
enacting for security measures to combat
online threats
goal with this system make sure that all
interested parties are
the issue
to meet growing consumer data safe and
secure one piece of cybersecurity
legislation in which we've listened to
industry to craft was the Cyber Security
Information Sharing after sites which
passed the Senate with my support was
signed into law last december many
others in congress understand the size
is not a cure all for the cyber security
but what it does offer is a voluntary
program for businesses to participate in
cyber threat information sharing with
appropriate liability protections I
welcome comments from the audience as to
how this legislation could be improved
mood as well as offer alternative policy
options to improve cybersecurity
condition congress also recently passed
the North Korea sanctions in policy
enhancement act with my support it was
in the 18th of this year this law
empowers jus Treasury Department to
freeze the assets of North Korean
entities who engage in significant
malicious cyber security activity this
law and the Treasury Department
sanctioning authority sets a precedent
and expands the tools available to the
us- government to respond to a
significant malicious cyber security
attack while these efforts are step in
the right direction
more must be done congress must work to
establish business-friendly rules that
can be used for private sector and the
federal government we must incentive
look sector to in an increasing its
network security we must find
for clarity on missile tools for
cybersecurity professionals can do their
job with confidence and we must also a
cyber threats under the national
security umbrella as a member of the
Senate Armed Services Committee we have
been looking intensely as tiber threats
from a national security perspective on
the 21st century it doesn't take a large
army or the latest knowledge to tap into
a nation's critical infrastructure which
could do
nation's entire economy and
significantly disrupt daily life as our
enemies tactics grows more sophisticated
we must be even more diligent in our
defense this brings into question the
role of the defense department with
regard to cybersecurity important
component of the United States national
security policy just having our country
and what particular event after
countless armed service meetings and
briefings I found our readiness in the
study were dominating lacking congress
now you determine what constitutes an
act of war in the cyber domain it needs
to do so before and attackers to enable
the pentagon to respond in real time
since cyber attacks happened literally
in seconds
cyberattack does not allow time for
deliberation and debate as is the case
and potential warfare in my view a
cyberattack on critical infrastructure
that causes physical means in effect
kinetic attack could be considered an
armed attack what I want a response to
the pentagon can respond to an attack on
its own networks as it has the right to
self-defense the standing rules of
engagement to fire when fired upon but
these are defensive actions it is also
critical for the defense department to
have the offensive maybe call it courage
strength capability to deter attack on
critical infrastructure such an attack
can already be perpetrated by a number
of state actors countries in particular
one day if not already non-state actor
may also have the ability to mount such
attack that's a cyberattack must be a
major focus to the Defense Department's
doctrine and operational planning we
have made some progress 2010 when the
defendant Deputy Defense Secretary
William Lynn stated boredom as the
public about its separate space as a new
dominating of warfare end of quote I
believe we are now striving to determine
how to best operate in this domain and
doing so the pentagon faces a number of
challenging issues as it undertakes
roles such as blocking foreign hackers
targeting domestic systems assisting us'
combat troops overseas defending
military networks just touch on a few of
the challenges first is the need
operationalize space that means creating
command and control systems that enable
operators are integrated with other
military capabilities based on a
situational awareness second channel
just formulating maintaining determine
strategies as the range of actors and
capabilities continue to evolve rapidly
and very unpredictably
challenge and one of particular interest
to me is clarification of the pentagon's
authority to respond to the attacks on
critical infrastructure in the days
ahead I look forward to working with my
arms services committee colleagues in
helping defense department meet these
challenges in time maybe short according
to reports the terrorists responsible
for the recent tax and Paris use
statistical data encryption attempts to
communicate and carry out their attacks
this proves that our enemies
technological capabilities are growing
more sophisticated and some ways we face
a situation which is not unlike the
situation our armed forces and the
latest in the run-up to ww2 at that time
our army or navy were compelled to
rapidly acquire and operationalize new
military technologies and their
associated operational concepts they
were compelled to do so in the face of
potential enemies who are already for
advanced and adoption of such
revolutionary technologies and concepts
I see it as my job and the job of my
colleagues to make sure we get it right
sooner this time one example of
improve cyber to the Department of
Defense cyber support to civil
authorities act of 2010 which I offered
last year
the provisions of this bill were
included in the National Defense
Authorization Act for fiscal year 2016
this provision which is natural law will
require a comprehensive plan for us'
Cyber Command to support civil
authorities in responding to cyber
attacks by foreign powers against the
United States its contribution is but a
small steps to increasing our
preparedness importantly any national
defense cyber strategy must be must be
under delayed by a solid core of
cybersecurity professionals who can
implement that strategy talking about
you when that in mind I recently
introduced the Cyber Command employment
personal training act of 2016 this bill
would improve the Department of Defense
hiring practices for cybersecurity
professionals by making certain that the
department's hiring officials are
trained under the rules for hiring and
pay flexibility for civilian
cybersecurity employees these rules
permit faster hiring and higher pay for
these employees than is normally the
case for the us- civil service improving
the training for hiring officials at the
Department of Defense who play a vital
role in the hiring of civilian
cybersecurity professionals can help
assure the us- military is working with
the best possible additionally I won
hands the defender the Defense
Department's
qualified cybersecurity professionals
from schools such as DSU specifically
the bill will require training dept
level human resources staff that manages
the civilian workforce trained staff
that right
implementing guidance for hiring and pay
flexibilities and also training
supervisors and hiring managers
use or would use the flexibilities in
that are allowed within this bill there
is a great amount of work to be done to
meet the many challenges of
cybersecurity but I really believe I'm
confident that we can meet these
challenges just tells our can do
American spirit found in our nation's
settled the west won two World Wars and
put a man on the moon stop cyber world
again its threats and military and the
most women like you committed to
addressing cyber security in the 21st
century helped the Kodokan 2016 has
further dialogue for all of you how we
can best protect our citizens our
military and the federal government from
cyber threats
well that just opened this up then I'd
be happy to answer any questions you may
have gathered here I know that you've
got some competition and so forth going
on later in the dance of course the
leading edge of something here that the
folks to understand and learn about and
in doing so we're trying to integrate
into what we saw from the challenges
that we still were trying to integrate
ways in which we can utilize the talents
that you're developing in many in many
cases are so with that let me just
opened the stuff you've got questions
sought advice I would be more than happy
to have this time yes
gonna come before congress now has a
case without security experts security
experts have found a way to get into it
and now I notice that Apple single women
how to do that one way that we might
want to talk about this and we had a
little bit of discussion this earlier in
the day there are the good guys who
would love to figure
getting in and around Andheri normally
would be considered private but how do
you identify who the good guys are we're
trying to find ways to get in and fix
things versus the guys who are trying to
get in to be able to take advantage of
44 inappropriate purposes may be one way
is to identify who the good guys up to
help them identify themselves and in
doing so to provide some sort of
protection for them getting the end as
long as there's some point in the future
where they clearly have to identify that
they've gotten in and share what those
what those holes are how they did it I
knew this is not something that that
congress have found ourselves facing on
a daily basis
years and years of privacy years and in
many cases in which had been legislated
a constitutional discussion about about
personal rights sold new for us and no
part of it is learning just exactly what
the thought process Armada what is
private what is not private and someone
has the capability to get into it do
they have an obligation to notify folks
that they've got a a door or window open
so I used to be that that I mean streets
around and check all the doors and
windows of of mercantile establishments
but the walkout Lehigh
mercantile
around check doors windows and they walk
into you don't have to open a walk I
don't make the call the orange to hey
left front door open when you left your
back door opener teacup windows open
down here
charged with breaking and entering
expected that was part of what they did
but they were identified up front and
they were like I don't know if there's
any possibility on something like that
or not but there may be two
possibilities that would work because
we've we've clearly entered a new rain
are you know we've entered into a new
era where you've got folks with
capabilities in education and tell us
that can be used for question is how do
we access and I'm not sure if I'm out
from the question I really think we have
to talk about I like the idea that I had
said look we're not gonna get any
information regarding cryptosystem here
and if we did that encrypted it's no
longer as solid as it was before but I
also surprising move in this was that it
wasn't as encrypted is what they thought
it was it wasn't as secure as they
thought it was it would have been broken
so now the next question is is it simply
a run up to where there's gotta be
multiple lines of defense once again and
is going to be an ever-changing
technology and is gonna go in where
every three months you gonna get a new
update from Apple from someone else
saying you've got a new series of here
that we think you ought to get in and
you're gonna love you too
phone saying there's no question that we
cannot use for a while I think that's
what we're going to see is going to be
it's gonna be a strategy you know we can
make it better or gonna make it faster
gonna make it bigger just like we've
seen in defense strategies with regard
to first second third fourth and fifth
generation fighter aircraft bomber so
that the race is I don't have a better
answer right now but that series mara
here is to say look we gotta learn about
it you folks are going to live with it
folks understand better than we did if
you can help by giving us information
maybe you can stop us from doing the
image by writing the wrong kind of a law
and if we try to write in a void will
make a mistake as much as anything else
look at it and tell us what can be done
what can't be done what you see is right
and what is an appropriate way to try to
legislate language that can hurt our
ability to protect the security of this
country yesterday
could be done at the time because what
can pass the House of Representatives to
matter what can pass the House of
Representatives and the Senate and the
House of Representatives which is
primarily republican
the folks together Kim making people in
the senate it's not that way it takes
sixty percent which means you gotta have
republicans and democrats side-by-side
agreeing to something so it slows the
process down it allows for more
discussion to occur but when it's all
said and done in a matter of what can
both parties agree is something that is
livable today when it was all said and
done this was the closest thing that we
could come up with something that those
individuals who were directly involved
in the negotiations that was the closest
thing that they could get and it is not
perfect in the Baltic I doubt that the
company was perfect but they thought
they had moved the ball forward someone
and that Odyssey is the way that in the
senate you'll find most items addressed
he'll never be perfect for one side or
the other and you'll have a very strong
points of view on your side but it'll
never even get to the floor unless you
have 60 votes out of a hundred that even
agree to discuss the bill in the first
place in other words in the senate just
to debate the discussion on site before
you up
people agree out of a hundred that they
would begin to and what's happened over
the last couple of decades is it what
their deal made before they ever get her
to the floor and then once it gets to
allow either party would allow the 60
votes to happen they want most of it put
together and then once they get it to
the floor
discussions based upon the rules are set
aside for each separate bill that comes
up in my database going all out for ten
amendments were going all out for 30
minutes per side or call it whatever the
group's decide on before they ask for
the 60 votes count and then once that
happened and it's brought to the floor
maisonette rules in place you may help
small and large members are debated but
you still need all said and done in
order to stop debate on the middle of
heard from their constituents have heard
the positives and the negatives
outweighed his ass better than what it
was before this particular case ended up
with was a group of folks out there said
look we know it's not perfect but at
least we move the ball forward for more
will be given a chance to take the next
steps and in many cases that happens
speakers during certain folks within
each conference that have more expertise
in an area than others do and the more
of those individuals that you can make
contact with and share that information
the better off you are in a lot of cases
what happens in the senate brand new
I've been there for a year out of the
determination about whether or not a
bill is good or not is based upon who is
sponsoring a bill and credible
discussion from those individuals who
are having expertise on the stuff you
like into out into the standard and you
have a discussion to do with a
particular area most of the central said
well you really need to talk to someone
so because they've got expertise in this
area and move you gotta get them on your
side in this particular case the folks
who are working on the phone so far too
stepped into it
had enough expertise to credibility and
say look we know it's not perfect but
it's the best thing we can break now we
would recommend that you vote for it but
we're gonna have to come back and read
russell again and that's what happened
what else to go all the way in the back
yesterday
they were in violation of a current
federal law when they did it and whether
or not they had gone into trying to
negotiate the deal with the Department
of Justice before before the end so they
can get into it so you're giving me some
new information that I did not know
before I walked in and if they could do
it outside of the country once again
here's a case of where you say the
country is illegal but if you go outside
the country you can do it you can bring
it back on another way to skin this
thing and I didn't realize it was that
particular case but I was one of the
questions we had had earlier this
morning we were discussing how they got
past that point whether or not they
picked up immunity before they ever did
it so thank you for sharing that I'm
learning a lot of questions are yes
talk about whether or not you're
creating a long are you creating a crime
and whether or not you want the question
is who is responsible for the data
breach it becomes more complicated
because you have multiple multiple
enemies may be responsible and I'm not
sure if I'm going on the same path that
you're wondering about but let me just
give you an example in our innovations
caucus car payments innovations caucus
if you have a data breach right now if
you talk to the banks are saying you
know our systems are pretty much we're
getting pretty good with it but we're
pushing merchants if you take a look at
where the data breaches have occurred
over at the working level by the
merchants channellock we're using are
using tanks they're the ones that really
should be should be filed on the stuff
up now they've got a good points but now
do you make a corporation criminally
liable for something or do you simply
say there is a 90 on simply laughable if
you've got a problem on it it's one
thing to have to pay back into and to
make people whole
have been damaged by a breach of
Obstetrics cost someone something but do
you then make a criminal offense you're
talking about an entirely different and
I think that's why we were part of the
question is do take someone who is
really the victim and you now say
because you are the victim on this thing
you didn't have appropriate security in
place we were not charged with a crime
yet I'm not sure you gonna go far with
it that way is that what you're
wondering about
would try to do is to make it easier for
businesses that find where they've been
breached to share with one another and
in doing the sharing to make sure that
there are not privacy issues that if
they can keep the privacy of the
individuals mister released the data
that it's not considered a breach of
privacy to allow them to share with
other entities who may be in the same
boat but what happened and how they got
in we're trying to make it easier for
them to do so and that's what the
legislature has been focused on the
fastest to make it easier for businesses
to share that data that once that
happens in one place it doesn't happen
again and again that's been the focus so
far but not guaranteed
and it's gonna take folks asking
questions about how you put the pressure
on folks to make it better and then
harming them to where they say generally
not offer that service of also gonna be
criminally liable should somebody get in
Bridgend make me a victim but then I'm
responsible as a victim for what
somebody else is there is there any
level of competency which is expected
ok liability gross negligence and then
you have negligence they did you get to
the point of gross negligence on
something you may very well have some
criminal issues involved in it but if
you simply have negligence means your
best job which didn't do anything
intentionally wrong
the difference between the two perhaps
sometime in the future and this is where
you folks step it is there a way to
determine gross negligence when it comes
to security is there a way to identify
negligence person is that something I
think whatever you do when it comes to
security breaches and so forth because
of the interstate commerce clause
information that goes on across state
lines would be much better off to have a
national standard as opposed to a a
state stander
ok
the federal government they've come in
they work with me
they've been assured that they've got
coverage if you don't protection but
that data has a real question by side
with all due respect I don't trust any
of the federal government and I
absolutely have to
and the reason is because I have no
reason to believe that there that there
any better than anybody else had keeping
at keeping data secure and I think
they're just as vulnerable as anybody
else is when it comes to act as part of
the problem we've got right now you know
you take a look at the at the payroll
records and you take a look at the
personal information that's been lost so
far but i buy out about a fairly large
number of individual people I know are
under the folks in my office they are
about the fact that for the rest of the
lies you gonna wonder when it shows up
personal information and their families
and I was irritated me we were all mad
about it and you wonder how in the world
can this kind of data breach happened to
the federal government who is telling
the rest of us what we're supposed to be
doing talking about what we're gonna
make people share more information with
the federal government there's a group
of dust and it's fairly large group that
says had time out here for a second
44 gonna be doing her daughter will be
able to offer some additional assurances
that the data that we we can protect it
and some double checks on you don't let
me just step in and one thing and then I
i dont im going past my time but I
there's something here its oversight
responsibilities that really good
oversight and it's something that we're
going to talk more about I believe but
everyone so we get frustrated because
even though were congress
times we don't do a good job and
oversight because in many cases with
limitations but what we can do we can
bring it up we can talk about it I was a
kid in overtime
Corps of Engineers we're talking about
the fact that they had a major flood in
2011 in fact I call it the core flood of
they they had major water come into the
base in the upper Missouri River Basin
in in 10 11 and March April and May and
in doing so they weren't prepared for it
and they had a major flood in fact it
was over the banks were probably close
to three months will be looking to see
how this happened and you go back in
there they can give you reports and
studies and one of the report said you
know we just didn't have enough about
how much water was coming in and back in
2014 they can we gotta have her we've
gotta put in more water monitoring we
gotta find out how much the soil can
hold how much moisture in the soil back
we got how much water we've got coming
down to the creek saw the tributaries
two years but now they need all this
additional information in order to be
able to accurately determine how quick
the water's coming in 2014 their
authorized under what they call an
inward it directed them along with a
couple of the department to put together
to come back in and lay out a plan to
get all the stuff ready to go
they help riding yesterday we just
haven't done anything because we don't
have the money from congress
what you mean you don't have the money
from congress he helped write the bill
has been talkin 14 2014 2015 2016 the
present study laid out his proposal for
appropriations for 2017 when my
oversight responsibility I'm saying you
can come in three years you're supposed
to have this report you suggest you've
got a report coming in nineteen have the
audacity to suggest to us that you don't
have the money to get a report done to
tell us how much money you need in order
to put it
are trying to fight in the first place
how can you live in making
appropriations request unless you've
done the study no response so here's a
case of where oversight is there but we
don't have much of an authority here
except up slap them on the wrist bring
about it publicly talk about it publicly
and then pull back and so they go back
to their daily lives again and say well
we went through that again we got our
butts chewed alone and life is good
except this time it's not gonna be
because now we're going to go back in
and we're gonna chase this thing up a
battered put it we talk about the
oversight and I'm getting off a little
bit but I think the federal gov online
collection of data they can make
mistakes but unless we have a system of
oversight to ask the questions and then
to get a response in a timely fashion
about what they're doing to fix it and
make sure that when they tell us they're
gonna fix it they actually do or there
will be repercussions for just go on the
bureaucracy will continue on sober me
voluntarily provide personal data
absolutely not if you're required to you
you're required to vote then we've got
an additional obligation to try to keep
it safe and that's where we need your
help you're the expert on this thing and
hire the best and the brightest and
that's what you folks fall into this
thing is what I'm here to date is
critical to this country's future needs
for security and glad to see the church
here we want to hear but we need your
help and part of it is you gotta tell us
how we write laws correctly when we
screwed up and what we've got to do to
change it cos you're in the trenches but
even more than that
we need you to look at helping us at the
federal level and at the state level in
its business level to help protect that
data you you get to be on the front
lines in we can't do without you without
I know that there are there gonna pull
me off your butt and just once again say
thank you I'm glad you're here you are
very very important to the future of
this country and we look forward to
hearing from you in the second time
thanks for letting me come in vent free
shipping