I am welcome to our talk small files and
big bounties exploiting sensitive files
for this year's level up conference from
back road so what's on our agenda first
we'll talk about the history of
sensitive files kept to give two
examples and then dive into the more
technical stuff with a look at get
directories and the sto files and yeah
explain a bit what sensitive content can
be leaked with those files and in the
end motivate some other files and finish
the presentation so who are we
my name is sebastian AKA Huck said on
Twitter I'm a master student at the TU
in Berlin right now and doing a bit of
freelancing stuff next to it and I
really like to play CD f's with my team
in a flick and you can see me in
Yekaterinburg in Russia at the root CJ
finals on the picture so yeh play CTF
it's fun ok so thank you very much for
having us here
my name is Tim FIFA's I'm also on
Twitter and I'm a cyber security
consultant and I wrote two InfoSec books
which are mainly a German and in 2012 we
founded the project in head waha org
which is a pro project focused on web
security I have heard about us on the
internet on Twitter so let's start Tim
is going to tell us something about the
history of sender those files yeah I
think we all know there were some
sensitive files in the past here just
two examples for example there are
people on the internet who put sensitive
stuff in the robots dot txt so it's a
fire to control the file indexing by
search engines you all know that Google
or Yahoo are calling those files and
there are people who put the direct path
to some files into the robots.txt and
there was an article for example in the
register that hackers find some
interesting stuff in those files
so the problem basically is said there's
no blocked access
- this fights and even the idea of
robots politics T is more to for example
put a directory which should not be
listed in search engines but it's a yeah
nice information for four security
researchers as well and the second
example we are looking at is the WS FTP
professional it's an FTP client which
was released in 1993 and it was very
popular at these times and even today
you can find some size files which I
named WS FTP dot ini' and it's kind of a
configuration file which contains
encoded passwords hosts and directories
it's pretty interesting that you still
find those files for example on all the
websites and you are able to am get
encoded password out of it
so that was linked on insecure talk for
example by a German security researcher
in the late 90s so pretty interesting
and now we will go on with some kind of
current examples about that
yep that's right some years ago we
looked into the get directories which
you can find on web server so what is
get you've probably all heard about it
get up is an example that allows you to
use git repositories so it's a version
control system which is developed by
Linus Torvalds
and you can use it to manage source code
so yeah for example using git init you
create a repository using git add you
can stage files for comment you think it
commits you commit them to the
repository and then you can distribute
your comments using git push to a server
and other people can then pull those
comments and repository and yes you are
free to collaborate on source code so
that's how the Linux kernel is developed
for example so how does it work it used
not get directory which is located in
the root of the source code directory or
the project and in the left-hand upper
screenshot you can see some directories
so there's branches hooks info locks
objects refs and some yeah kind of
important and interesting files which
are config head index or description so
everything is based on objects and get
so you'll see on the right screen shots
that we have a comet object that
contains a tree object and the tree
object references blob objects which are
more or less the files that you control
using git so for example test dot txt is
a blob with version 1 and then when you
commit another version of the fire you
get another blob object with differences
and everything is managed using those
object files so you can find those
object files in the dot git slash
objects folder you see that else some
subfolders
for example the Oh a or OB and the
reason for that is to be more efficient
in regards to the file system so if they
take the hash of the object fire and use
a first byte as a subdirectory so what
happens if those directories they get
directory ends up on your web server for
example when your deployment process is
changed directory slash their real slash
www slash HTML and then you just do a
git pull to update your website website
source code so there might be some
people out there that do this and yeah
so
get folder will be exposed on the web
server and this is really bad the scan
and bad because an attacker might just
download the whole repository using W
get in case that directory listing is
enabled so yeah you see an example
command W get - - mirror - - include
directories slash dot get and then
here's a URL to the git repository and
yeah however the directory listing is
not always enabled on web servers and
it's best practice to disable it so it
gets harder to obtain some repository
however we looked into how the things
work and found out set in a git
repository there's always two files head
refs heads master if there's a master
branch so we can use those files to
obtain one object hash and with object
hash we can download the object file and
from that object file which is usually a
comet we can obtain the tree hashes
right and from that tree object we can
obtain the hashes of the blob object so
we can download all the files until we
find no new hash as an object's file to
download so in the end we end up with
parts or the full repository on our hard
disk so for this we developed a tool to
automate this process
it's called git tools and you can find
it on github let's do a demo of how this
works and how we can obtain repositories
from a web server I have a web server
running locally and here you can see the
web root and yeah with a kid directory
you see dot git and the other files
relating to our presentation so let's
make sure that directory listing is
enabled you see options + indexes it's
great for the first example so we can
just use W get
as I said we run that command and we
download all the files we end up with a
folder demo dot local and in that folder
we see the dot git directory so we
obtained it we can use git status to see
ok the files are deleted because folders
empty so what we do now use git checkout
to restore the files and as you can see
we downloaded the repository we got
obtain the source code of our
presentation and you can use even get
lock to yeah it goes through other
comets that we did so yeah that's number
one the easy way so let's do this again
after this abling directory listing you
see there's the files again and now we
use the git dumper that we brought it's
ashame script that tries to download the
files and recursively get the object
hashes so you see it tries to download
this file some files some other fights
it doesn't find and in the end it don't
know everything so let's change into the
10-pack two directory again we see that
git folder I can do git status we see
two files and now if you do the check
out again you find all the files hooray
and the get lock will also show what
other comments are there so as you can
see we obtained the full repository from
a web server with and without directory
listing enabled so ok so I wanted fences
yeah so thank you very much for your
demo Sebastian I will just outline some
of the consequences which directory or
get directories in general will have so
first of all this problem that the
source code is leaked so it's possible
to find for example vulnerabilities with
in the source code you find or even
committed credentials and yeah of course
you always have to stick to the words of
a bug bounty program so if you found its
directory
you should only look further if this is
allowed by the rules of a bug bounty
program the second problem is that very
often they get config there are HTTP
basic authentication credentials and
this can lead to an instant access to
the company's repositories for example
on git lab or github and of course you
may also be able to get an access to the
CI where the scripts are billed and the
outer deployment process of some server
yeah will leak to a company it's pwnage
of the server we did a scan on that
excel top 1 million which are the most
visited websites on the web and we found
out sets nearly 10,000 of those websites
we're vulnerable to this kind of attack
and we wrote a blog post about it so if
you want to go more into detail see you
which top-level domains are affected you
can go on our website yeah
of course this technique was also used
by some security researchers on the left
side you can see that somebody was able
to find dot git repository and he got
$1,000 for that so yeah that's pretty
nice and the SVN repository which is a
technique which is nearly the same as
kits was also enabled on a subdomain of
pornhub and somebody got $10,000 for
that because he was able to yeah see
some credentials in this case the
password also was very weak so yeah
that's a nice case which shows that that
kid repositories really should not be on
the web servers or at least should
protection yeah that's about the
bounties let's look into another example
this time it's about a file called dot
tears
underscore store it is a file format
developed by Apple its proprietary so we
cannot easily read it and you will find
it I'll make us so what is this I used
for it holds meta information about
files in a directory so if you use
finder and access a directory on macaws
it will automatically create this file
and save information for example the
icons or display order or the file names
of all files in the directory and the
funny thing is that this fire is
prepared with a dot so the finder won't
show it per default which is nice but
it's bad for you if you share a zip file
or other files using a USB stick so yeah
the other people might get information
about what files are stored in the
directory as well if you don't copy the
whole directory so that is pretty
interesting and we will come to some
more information about it later so I
decided to look into this file format
and write a part for it so I yeah took
some days to write that and understand
the file format but in the end you will
see something like on the right side a
screenshot it has three like structure
and it has several blocks where it
stores information about the files for
example the file name so those are the
yellow marked bytes that are stored as
not utf-8 but utf-16 encoded string so
it uses two bytes per character which
makes filing this a bit more interesting
and yeah you can read a blog post if you
want to get all the details about the
file format so what can go wrong if you
use mac for development and you can use
scprs Inc FTP or whatever File Transfer
Protocol - yeah transfer files from your
local development environment to a
server so for example you'll see the
figure on the right side where you have
a code directory us have
config.php in there you have two other
folders in there for example with backup
and the backup dot sequel so if you all
sync them to the server and don't take
care to exclusive Diaz underscore store
files all the files might end up there
and by pausing the first one in the code
directory I will get information that
there's a conflict PHP which is fine or
some other files but I will also know
that it has a backup directory so by
knowing that the Tiesto files are
created in each directory I can pass
that again and then I will find out that
there as a backup dot sequel without any
brute forcing or yeah other things even
if directory listing is disabled so
we've developed the tools for that a
powder that can read the file names from
most of the DEA's underscore store files
and even a scanner for that to scan the
Alexa top 1 million so here's a short
demo about that let's switch to the
third pane in T marks this is our
repository with a Python tool so let's
first look at the file we have a sample
file over here from a CTF that I played
we can even look at the hex dump you see
it's yeah a lot of binary data and you
can't read much by using the tool that I
have to fill up you will see a bit of
debug output that I have enabled so it
reads through all the data does a bit of
black magic and in the end you will have
recovered six file names from that yeah
fire um you see it has both a flag which
was interesting for the CTF and also
vulnerable PI so we could have
downloaded all the files from a web
server where we found a deist or Singh
and where access to the other files was
not prohibited so yeah what a possible
consequence of that as I discussed you
can easily find other files on web
servers without using brute force or
having
character listing in a bird so yeah it's
kind of an information disclosure and
makes finding other fights easy so what
we learned from scanning the Alexa top 1
billion where we also find about ten
thousand vulnerable websites that we can
easily find backup files for example dot
mark dot G set dot DB so database files
email files temporary files like dot
swap yes the once was a tilde at the end
or even key files where the private keys
from yeah SSL enabled web servers were
leaked and yeah you can see other things
like config files a sequel files so
that's can be really interesting and
people got bounties for that so simply
by finding the fire on the web server
you can get more than five hundred
dollars from Twitter or even yeah half
of that twelve fifty dollars from a
private program that we participated in
and yeah that's it's so easy to find
easy to exploit and easy to get a bounty
for okay so Allah nor is there a lot of
interesting sites with sensitive content
we hope that you are now motivated and
explore them by yourself we put some
examples of interesting files on the
left side and would be very happy of
some of you for example write a blog
post about some files or some directory
or resource he or she discovered and
yeah we also want to outline that there
are some interesting previous work on
that for example Hanna Burke which is a
German security researcher was at 34 C 3
which is a hacker conference and he had
a talk hacking with W get which was
pretty interesting we also wrote some
blog posts on our website about finding
interesting files and some tools for
example one of Hannah again snallygaster
we
- and back up fire RT effects check out
by Mason 160 which is also very
interesting to find this kind of files
and you will also find our tools for the
s tour and for the get stuff on our
github page
so keep calm slash internet vaca okay so
if you're interested in this topic and
have some questions left or you have
some feedback we are very interested to
hear about your questions or your ideas
on their topic so just get in contact by
Twitter or you know in this case yep and
sorry for doing this in a pre-recorded
session but unfortunately I had to
attend another conference on the same
day so I wouldn't be able to give the
presentation and yeah sorry for that I
hope you enjoyed it anyway
and yeah keep on hacking