all right hi there everyone just to
check everyone can hear me at the back
and stuff like that right yep Back Road
awesome
um so first of all thanks for everyone's
time and thanks for the to the b-sides
organizers for kind of giving me the
opportunity to present today
um it's great to be able to give back to
a community that supported me for so
long when I was here in London but
Google's Google has a pretty big
security presence right and pretty much
the entire security team is really
focused on defending and protecting
Google alphabet all of our users I
imagine many of whom here might be users
as well and from Badness right and we do
this through building Technical
mitigations and controls into our
platforms our environmental sort of
stuff that basically mean that they're
more resilient to attack
and part of this posture is building
detections for when gaps are found in
these controls so we can kind of like
cover our bases as best we can
but in detection our priority is to
defend against nation-state backed
attackers and these are the groups of
people who we think are probably most
likely interested in taking taking a pop
at this right so when we think about
defending we have to think about this
problem at a pretty large scale because
of the size at which we operate
so today I'll talk a bit about how we're
just our mindset to basically you know
work at this kind of scale
but before I get into that sorry I need
to talk this way I always talk that way
to the slide
um for the past two and a bit years I've
been a security engineering manager at
Google
um down under in the land of dinner
plate size spiders and drop bears in
Sydney Australia and if this isn't a
detection team and basically as a team
we are the people who comb through the
you know Galaxy of Haystacks looking for
the needle that is Badness right that's
the people that would try and see us
fail
but before this I was actually on the
other side of the fence I was in red
teaming for about eight and a half years
both here in London and later on in
Sydney and I haven't quite hung up those
shoes for good yet I still am headed
into like ICS and Hardware stuff so if
you're into that as well you know please
let me know
but to start with a very existential
question you know like why are we all
here and I'm not asking you know why are
we all like watching me talk right
um it's more about you know how we come
as an industry to be where we are where
we see today and how we all gravitate
gravitated together on a weekend to kind
of like spend our time at these
conferences right and a lot of this
really unfolds because of events over
the past sort of like 45 to 50 years
so back in the 1960s the US government
realized that they had a problem on
their hands they had these big computers
like you know would fill this entire
room but they realized that they were no
longer single user devices they shared
resources they had multiple users using
it at the same time and they really
asked pretty early on that they had a
pretty big problem on their hands and
that was what if all of these users
could like see each other's things so
that's probably not a good thing I'm not
sure if that was me or not so apologies
if it was it is me okay
oh because I'm breathing into the mic
okay
um I'll Stand a bit further back so
apologies for that
um but by 1972 James Anderson had
written a paper on this topic called the
computer security technology planning
study and he correctly posited in this
study that the things we were building
couldn't defend themselves and James had
a background in meteorology which gave
him a unique understanding of like the
interplay between systems particularly
as things might play out into the future
when they become more connected over
time
and by the 1980s he further developed
how we needed to start auditing and
monitoring what users do on these
systems he wrote another paper a
computer security threat modeling and
surveillance paper which described that
we needed to you know audit logs we had
to centralize these logs we needed
people looking at them and we needed or
they kind of started describing the
kinds of auditing that we needed to do
and this is actually one of the seminal
papers that kind of like fueled a lot of
the careers that we see today
and these are the examples of the kinds
of things that these papers that suggest
that we do and each box here represents
a topic that turns up in academic
literature or commercial products around
the time
and the very first thing they suggest
that we try is manual analysis it's
literally just like looking through
order logs
and shortly after that we start seeing
things like behavioral anomalies come up
this is still pretty early though but
it's looking at answering questions like
what does normal look like and can we
use statistics to determine what normal
looks like and can we use these like
self-learning expert systems to help us
determine what normal looks like and all
of this comes like very early in the
picture
but by the 1990s we start to hear things
that we hear about today data mining you
know artificial intelligence you know we
give people user interfaces to do
analysis in so they can like actually
click on stuff like wow nice clicking on
things like and make this stuff much
easier to find that it would have been
seen previously so conceptually kind of
like our e ancestors I kind of thought
of this stuff already
and by the 2000s we start to combine a
lot of this stuff
we see a real emergence of like machine
learning and using different algorithmic
representations to try and like model
security problems and it's pretty
interesting to see how all of the stuff
progresses but there's one common theme
that all of these technologies have
and that they are meant to be assistance
they're meant to point a human in a
direction you know when we are humans
we're out there looking for Badness you
know these Technologies are here to
assist us in finding that Badness
so anyone here who's ever started a sock
can probably relate to this history so
far you start out with a bunch of people
looking at logs and once you figure out
what to do with all of this log stuff
you can kind of like use assistive
Technologies to help make this task
easier
and when Google first started our sock
we did exactly that we hired analysts to
effectively stare at logs and until we
figured out what analysts were good at
doing and we figured out that we had to
draw a line between manual investigation
and automated investigation
and in some ways this is almost the
original intent behind our careers
according to James Anderson back in the
1980s
so when we read that same literature and
we look at the same timeline through a
slightly different lens we see that
we've been classified almost we became
the names and titles and way back in the
1980s James Anderson called this the
activity security officer which in many
ways is kind of like correct today still
yeah we monitor activity with a security
lens and even in the 1980s this concept
is still around
we also start to see words like order to
appear and the the security out of this
role was kind of born around the 1980s
as well so this job that we're talking
about has been around for a pretty long
time
and then we fast forward we start to see
you know the Security administrator
appear which is a Twist on the it admin
and some of you may be familiar with
both of these roles at once which is you
know the better or worse the reality of
the world at the moment
and by the late 1990s and 2000s we
invent the sock this is like collections
of all of these people and you're
working together to try and solve the
security problem
and then we invented the term threat
Hunter but the work here is relatively
similar to some of the other roles that
we've already seen
so we can't by combining these views can
see that you know assisted by technology
the whole principle here is that humans
try and find bad things and that's
relatively speaking kind of like where
we find ourselves today
and you might be asking like hey why do
we keep Reinventing this stuff like why
do we keep seeing the same themes emerge
over time and we have a bit of a
hypothesis it might be poorly
constructed and might not hold a huge
amount of weight but we have this
feeling that every four to five years or
so something might just not quite be
working as we intended to do
we're not detecting what we think we
might should be so we basically decide
to start a new and we start with humans
we always start with the analysts in
this picture
but analysts need data
and it's really easy to give analysts
too much data when you before you've
figured out like we have a lot of data
here we have to we have to do something
with it so then we naturally start to
build tooling we build assistance
but it turns out that this doesn't
entirely work either because we know
that humans can do this better
so we kind of end up conceptually back
where we started we may have probably
learned a few things along the way but
we pretty much end up where we began
and when we look at this cycle over time
and we look at the kinds of technology
that have been available and the
intelligent assistance that we've been
giving people it begins actually with
something very simple and back in the
1980s James Anderson's advice was to
print out the order records create a
case File and hand it to an officer to
kind of like read the stuff and review
it
and you can imagine that people doing
this work probably didn't find it very
rewarding and it actually doesn't really
work because fatigue toil all these
kinds of like human elements have an
impact on the investigative quality of
this kind of methodology
so what we do is we invent a new
technology we give them database backs
user interfaces we have pages that can
go off when rules fire all this kind of
stuff and by the 2000s we start getting
more sophisticated we're doing signature
detection and seam and then we put a
sock in place to look at all of this
stuff 24 7. and now we have you know
like threat hunting tools like themes
data science ML and a whole bunch of
other things right
but every five years or so we kind of go
through this revolution of trying to
improve the intelligent assistance that
we're using and this kind of results in
the somewhat iterative approach that we
see here
yeah this might sound pretty bleak it's
like hey like we did every five years we
kind of end up back where we started we
might have had a little bit and sorry
for kind of like bringing the tone down
on the on the Outlook of the security
industry
um
but let's look at the future right so
the future really holds something quite
valuable I think and it might sound
somewhat controversial with these
opinions but I think by about ultimately
2050 we'll have something in place to
solve James Anderson's original problem
and we'll basically have some kind of a
system or systems that can defend
themselves they might be either better
constructed or self-healing but they
typically won't need humans in the same
way that systems need us today
and this means that the systems we have
today where the machines are kind of
like Reliant upon humans to defend them
will become less and less relevant over
time
and this kind of is a solution to the
original problem about James Anderson
outlined in the 1980s
and it's probably going to take a while
to get there but I'm pretty hopeful we
kind of see signs of this already
um you may be familiar with the Cyber
Grand Challenge held by DARPA
um this was building about cyber
reasoning systems that actually played
in the the 2016 Defcon CTF and the
challenge itself was held over the span
of about two years and the goal was to
build a cyber reasoning system that
could detect vulnerabilities exploit
them and then patch them and you can
kind of think of this in some ways as
being a system that can kind of like
defend them within reason heal itself
so the real question then is like what's
the role of the human in this cycle
right like the real reason that we're
all here that the meaning behind all of
the work that we're doing and the
reality is that once we build a system
that can learn we need to teach you
pretty much everything that we know we
need to teach it things about like how
understanding how threats work how to
defend systems how to identify and
attack what an attack looks like how
attackers work how governments build
teams to attack other systems all of
these kinds of fundamental principles
and all of that will play into how we
teach the computers to kind of like
defend themselves
and I think that's the real reason we're
here right like this kind of like
educational like wave of computing
in the meantime you know we still get to
defend and we have to chase attacks too
so enough of the conceptual stuff right
let's talk about how we do things at
Google
um this is a high level view of our
detection pipeline
whenever a computer light does a thing
you know whatever that thing is
um they generate a log for it it might
be big it might be small but it's logged
and logs are essential for debugging but
they're actually crucial to detection
and response and we consume huge volumes
of log data every day we store it for
long periods of time in this big data
store which we replicate across multiple
data centers and then over this data we
run a number of detection systems on a
very regular basis and some of these
detection systems are pretty simple
right they use static rules for example
looking for malware fingerprints or
hashes and some have more advanced
models where they're using a bit of
machine learning statistical analysis
like anomaly detection all this kind of
stuff but generally we know we use a lot
of different tools to comb through this
data set looking for indicators of
Badness
we also test everything to make sure our
systems are reliable and behaviors we
expect now as a former pen tester like
Michael was terrible right
um and having joined this more
engineering focused role
you miss an end-to-end an integration
tests are fantastic so if you're writing
any kind of tooling as a pen tester like
I highly recommend unit testing it you
will thank me later and anyway
um detection systems in this case you
know generate events to generate alerts
and these are bundles of data that might
be interesting to a human right that a
human can look at
and about 80 of these events that
managed to get to a human are already
enriched with everything as an analyst
you need to know about the circumstances
that led to the event firing
and this is kind of almost in many ways
like everything you would need to know
to determine whether or not a given
event is truly bad or not
so to give you an example imagine you
have a binary execute on the fleet and
when I say Fleet I mean every device
within Google's corporate Network
and we have an antivirus program that
notices you know this execution take
place so we get the AV alert we know
that I'd execute we will go and grab a
copy of the binary and run it through
you know many many binary analysis
pipeline systems you can think of virus
tilt as an example of one of those here
we'll also know like everything about
the user right we'll know where the user
was we'll know how long the machine was
there for we know how they authenticate
to the machine all these other these
bits and pieces and all of this data
gets grouped up and put in front of an
analyst and the idea is that they spend
the minimal amount of toy toil doing
this toils and tasks right they we want
them to spend their time doing the
things that humans are really good at we
don't want them to answer questions that
we know are going to be useful we solve
that problem for them
and the idea is they can spend that time
determining whether or not the system is
actually compromised or not
and when we talk about machine learning
like this is actually where we want
machines to help us today we want them
to assist the human in making a decision
and and to kind of try and help point
this in the right direction
but we definitely don't do this alone we
have many many partner teams that we
work with and organizationally this is
roughly how we're structured for those
of you in blue team rules this might
look somewhat similar
we have a team that does threat analysis
some of you may have heard of tag or the
threat analysis group they post some
really great blog posts I'd recommend
checking them out if you haven't seen
them yet but these are the people who
spend time learning about what different
threat groups are into like being a
financial crime or spying on different
countries and this all like informs our
detection strategy
we also have a team that builds all of
our security tooling and these are
basically huge projects that can store
and analyze massive volumes of telemetry
and alerting and all this kind of stuff
we then have the security surveillance
team which is where I sit the detection
team I mentioned before and these are
the humans that we were talking about
earlier who see the output of our
detection pipeline
and we've actually borrowed a lot of
this language from James Anderson this
idea of surveillance not just detection
and surveillance in this context is
actively looking for bad stuff on the
network not just waiting for alerts to
come to us and in some ways this is kind
of like active defense but this term is
like very overloaded nowadays
we also have a digital forensics team
and an instant management team and these
are the folks kind of that handle doing
deeper Dives on things or The Wider
coordination of incidents
um when they when they do happen and we
also draw very clear boundaries of
responsibility so that we understand you
know how many people in each of these
teams we need to engage at a time and
but in reality a lot of this work is
heavily cross-functional
we also work very closely with our
internal red team and their goal is not
to find every single bug but it's to
find the gaps and the places where our
detection systems may be lacking and
they often mimic you know ttps from Real
actors they they help us fine-tune our
detection and test our response
capabilities and they really do keep us
on their toes in many ways they're
actually our most targeted threat actor
that we regularly see
and we also regularly run combined red
and blue team exercises where we kind of
work together to better understand our
posture and so you know focus on the
blue side go with red for a bit and vice
versa
um because a key component of being a
good attacker is understanding Defenders
and vice versa of understanding
Defenders being an attacker
but all these collaborative events as
you can imagine are great learning
exercises but
this is probably the most important
thing that we've realized that we should
only ever hunt once and this is somewhat
analogous to only ever automating once
so when we dive into hunting we have
this kind of like thought process
similar to the slide here so the first
thing we'll do is typically start with
research right we'll try and understand
something new well understand the threat
model the ttps the behaviors whatever it
might be that we're basing our research
on so one of the things for example
hypothetically might be let's say we're
trying to understand the difference
between persistence mechanisms on
Windows 10 and 11 and see whether or not
an attack is trying to do that stuff
honestly so the first thing we do is
build a hypothe or a set of hypotheses
these are basically the questions we
want to answer with the investigation
that we undertake and then what we do is
we start hunting we'll initially hunt
manually through the log sources all
this data that we have and then we kind
of like have this iterative automation
process and we iterate on this process
until the Hunt works as we intended to
until we've also created the backlog of
relevant events until we can basically
understand whether or not the fleet
itself is compromised
and once we've done that and we're happy
with where it is we'll kind of refactor
the code and we'll re we'll actually
write like a true detector that will run
indefinitely into the future and this is
where hunting is entirely automated at
this point
and we'll also write unit tests for it
as I mentioned before and the idea here
being that you should never have signal
right you should always know and be able
to attest that your detection Works in a
way that you would expect it to work
and this cycle continues but it
basically means that we never hunt for
something that we research before more
than once and the only exception here is
when we have to do it again in a new
environment so for those of you in
companies where you might acquire
another company and that company might
have some negative Legacy infrastructure
or something it could be anything so
redoing your hunts in this situation is
actually a really good thing to do
and it can help you basically understand
whether or not the infrastructure you're
about to kind of like on board is
already compromised and pre-owned for
all intents and purposes or if it's kind
of like relatively clean
and this and this model requires minimal
setup and deployment because as long as
we have eyes in the right places as long
as we're ingesting the right log sources
all of our detection handles the rest of
this the entire detection pipeline kicks
in and does the job for us which affects
us kind of like outscale the amount of
stuff that we're looking at
so I've mentioned hunting a few times
now and we actually have three kinds of
hunting grounds I guess you can call
them one of course is like this big
repository of stored raw data which we
hunt through with a sql-like interface
um and we can also take the data out of
here and process it into other tools if
necessary and this is data like DNS
logging file monitoring execution logs
user Behavior there's a lot of stuff
that kind of like falls into this bucket
and all of these things stand in the
historical record right and they're very
very good for manually hunting through
the second category because our
detection generates sorry our detection
system generates so many alerts we
actually make a clear delineation
between high confidence signaling and
low confidence signaling and we actually
spend a lot of time looking through this
like potentially noisy mess of low
confidence signals and this is actually
where we see the creativity of analysts
come into play so those who might enjoy
a particular detection domain that we
know has been researched or developed at
some point in the past sorry at some
point in the past or what kind of I
typically gravitate to this kind of a
domain
and usually we have a few tricks up our
sleeves to kind of like help sift
through this data but there's no right
or wrong way of doing this and that's
kind of like a really important point
but threat modeling definitely helps
reduce the ambiguity and the complexity
of this kind of data set
and there's also natural variance here
due to analyst creativity and we
actually kind of want this we want to
have diversity of thought and kind of
approach here because we know that an
attacker or the set of attackers will be
you know doing exactly the same thing as
what we want to do
and once you can find stuff in the noisy
data then you iterate on the existing
detections to try and make them more
accurate try and make them have a higher
confidence
and then finally we have the live Fleet
and an agent particularly called
um this is probably one of the most
powerful Tools in our Network it's an
agent-based system originally designed
to do live forensics remotely
um historically for example in some
countries it was pretty challenging to
get devices shipped to us to be able to
image disks and stuff like this but
since deploying we no longer have to you
know wait for these this to be
physically present with us and we've had
it on the fleet for a while you know
probably nearly a decade at this point
sorry
um It's relatively stable it runs on
your windows the next Mac or the sort of
stuff and we use it for all kinds of
hunting and detection as well
I'll talk a bit more about later on as
well if I mentioned the the security
surveillance team a few times and this
is effectively our attempt at making a
fully automated sock so everything sorry
about 80 of everything that ends up in
front of an analyst has been enriched
with data of some kind
and we also have a large proportion of
incidents that are handled by the
pipeline which are automatically
resolved by your machines today and so
for example if it's like a very mundane
event which is either routine or not
really concerning and all of this stuff
will be resolved automatically by the
pipeline
we also split our time between basically
two core sets of activities forty
percent of our time is what we call
tactical surveillance or operations and
this is very task driven uh it's
typically going to shift kind of model
so that you can spend your series of
time oh that was really loud sorry about
that
um so you can send the set amount of
time kind of like doing this sort of
stuff before you can take a bit of a
rest
um but this is kind of thing is like
event triage you're hunting in
pre-processed data at Fleet checks for
new intelligence to see if it's actually
been seen on the feet or not
um things like that
and the other 40 of our time is spent
looking at technology-specific projects
so Google has like a lot of Technologies
as you can probably imagine right we
have like Windows Linux Mac Android iOS
like cloud like pretty much everything
um so we divide the responsibilities for
this 40 of time amongst the different
platforms and this allows us to become
very specialized in a given field and
means that we can learn or try to learn
everything that there is to know about
for example Linux persistence or Mac
persistence and all of how all of these
platforms have like work together but we
do treat all of these platforms more or
less equally because we you know can't
consider one to be more or less
important than the other a lot of the
time and we know from experience that
our adversaries do the same like they
have people who are highly specialized
in one particular area if they need
someone to go and I don't know like do
dll stuff in Windows they'll go and get
the person to do dll stuff on Windows we
want to be able to replicate this kind
of experience
and we also work significantly on a meta
level of things like you know Automation
and testing within that respective field
you know spending time on how many
platforms we have how they change over
time and how many people we need to
engineer detection coverage in a
specific platform and this is really all
about you know determining how much time
we set aside to do creative hunting
that's what we want people to do most of
the time and this helps keep us move
forward and moving forward helps keep
our detection detection posture kind of
advancing and the key neither of you
might be like hey well this is only 80
and you're right obviously
um the rest of that 20 of time is this
kind of like Google wide um sort of
thing where you can do projects on other
teams like engage in community work all
kinds of other stuff so we were looking
about 80 of the time across full-time
employee analysts
but this might be the easiest to
visualize with some examples like the
hunting activities we do so
um to get a look at some examples of
that raw data set that I mentioned
before and it's it you know the way that
we interface with this is through an SQL
like system that Google invented
um it's very much like a tool we
actually make publicly available called
bigquery and bigquery is really good at
tasks like this because it is basically
a means of massive massively
parallelizing single query tasks across
huge volumes of computing and then you
know aggregating the results back very
quickly
and this means that we can search for
things like executions or of a
particular binary or a command string
across all of Google across all time and
we receive the results in like a few
seconds basically
but anyway when we're hunting the very
first thing that we do is kind of like
build a set of hypotheses so let's look
at an example of that
let's say we have a hypothesis of okay
we have an attacker using a given domain
for command and control
so the very first thing we do is
consider like what what does this look
like like what might the attacker do
with this domain what might be C what
kind of threat intelligence do we have
to support a specific technique or the
specific domain
and then we can compare the DNS requests
that are happening and have happened on
the Google corporate network of which we
have all of them we have every DNS
that's ever been sorry every DNS request
that's ever been issued at Google since
about September 2009 and keep all of
this and using this data we can kind of
like find hits to this potentially bad
domain
and this is the kind of hunt that we
probably do once initially and then we
automate and kind of like you know kick
it into the pipeline so it does all this
stuff for us
another example looking at the live
Fleet this time using go as I mentioned
before
there's a few things that we might like
to do particularly when we're trying to
onboard a newly acquired environment
that we might have just bought something
like that
so the very first thing we'll do is
typically deploy amongst other things
ger and we have like this basic
hypothesis right maybe the attackers if
they were there left something really
common behind that we can find
and this might be for example something
like an after a Cron job so for those
who may be familiar with this these kind
of tooling you use to schedule automated
tasks and they're pretty small files you
can collect them across the entire fleet
and process them with some some code
um and basically understand what's been
executing as scheduled tasks in this new
environment and then once you have this
big data set you typically start looking
at the outliers because there's
obviously like stuff in the noise still
but the outliers are where you really
find like the the clear signs of Badness
here and it's pretty basic but honestly
about nine out of ten times it works
reasonably well
and another example you might see is
like launch demons on Mac so this this
is where detections can come a bit more
complicated so launch demons are scripts
which automatically manage system
processors on OS X
um and attackers might use these to
maintain persistence on a device and
generally if we're looking at server
infrastructure here for malicious
software like this kind of a search can
actually work pretty well because
servers are like usually well maintained
you kind of like know exactly what
should be running on them they're
typically you know single or limited
purpose but once you get to end user
devices they become this becomes
significantly less clear you know people
will install just about anything on
their laptops and as a result you can
end up with way too many launch demons
to review manually and a lot of the
results aren't actually that interesting
either you might just find a lot of like
adware for example which is that AOK you
should do something about but it's not
like the APT group that we're looking
for
but automation can help us out here too
as you can probably imagine
so another way Google attempts to tackle
this detection and scale problem is
through a tool called Deja this
for those of you who are fans of
Resident Evil I'm aware of what the logo
looks like
um
its name itself is a portmento of deja
vu and disassembly
Deja this is a system developed by tag
Google's threatened threat intelligence
group or the threat analysis group and
the Google Dynamics Team amongst others
um it's designed to tackle a few of the
really difficult problems when dealing
with binary analysis at scale today
and part of this is that first thing we
need to talk about reverse engineering
and reverse engineering is really hard
and really expensive to apply for
example like a single module of the
flame malware contains about 40 000
functions and Flames nearly a decade old
now so even if you could reverse
engineer one function every 60 seconds
which isn't really realistic the entire
module will take about a month to
understand and there's obviously all the
other modules as well you have to go
through
so the learning curve here is like
really steep the knowledge even required
to start reversing is pretty high
and so when we're talking about binary
detection and binary analysis at scale
we have to kind of acknowledge that
reverse engineering is a scalpel that we
have to apply very judiciously
so anyway what stage of this so these
are this is basically a similarity
engine for functions and executables
creates a met like a set of meta
information associated with functions
things like function names like specific
attacker techniques common cryptographic
routines all this kind of stuff and it's
made easily discoverable to any analyst
who might need it
and it also earns new information every
day it can be used to find names and
uses functions or label entire sets of
executables just to determine for
example if a particular set of functions
is a common everyday part of openssl for
example that we don't need to
investigate
and every binary that enters the Google
binary analysis pipeline is also
available and processed by Deja this
so this basically provides us a
constantly updated reference of how
binaries are connected how they relate
to each other
and we can also approach Deja this from
another angle so we can use data this to
quickly pivot on a single function in
highly variant malware so if we can find
a particularly common function through
disassembly which we use judiciously and
give Deja this a sample hash and a
function offset it will spread out and
find all the variants available in its
data store over all time and label them
as related known Badness to the function
the function that we're looking at
and then automatically find the label
all future binaries that it sees for the
same malware fan money that enters the
pipeline at a future date
but it doesn't necessarily need this
human step we actually once it's
actually seen enough kind of types of
Badness of a certain kind it'll start
formulating its own ideas about how
binaries are connect connected and
related together
if a new never-before-seen binary is
linked to a bunch of existing known
through actor tooling via function
similarity for example that you'll
automatically generate a new detection
rule out the back of that our pipeline
can kind of see this Rule and propagate
it through all of the log data that we
have to service a new detection that
didn't exist before
and all of this is really designed to
save time effort resources of the humans
involved remember humans are the key
part of all of this
I don't have a huge amount of time to go
into like War Stories using Deja this
but I will leave with one which is how
it was able to attribute a sample of now
the now Infamous wannacry so back in May
2017 uh the one of crime malware was
really hitting in full force fire
Eternal blue exploitation of you know
unpatched Windows systems worldwide I
imagine that many people in this room
are very familiar with it given the
impact here
but one of the questions that actually
for those who aren't familiar want to
cry was ransomware right it's like you
encrypt your stuff demands payment for
their safe return in theory
but one of the questions I was asked
very quickly was like what's the origin
of wannacry and for those of you who
might be in threat intelligence you
might know that attribution is like
really really hard to get right
it's really expensive as well it often
requires a large knowledge base of like
threat actor ttps time patience to
reverse engineer all of this stuff
before you can come to a good conclusion
and even with that conclusion it's
difficult to be sure
on the 15th of May 2017 Neil Metro tag
posted this kind of like somewhat
cryptic tweet with the hashtag wanna
Crypt a hashtag a one equipped
attribution hashtag so like what did he
mean with this tweet
he was actually posting the results from
data this so they should analyze Wanna
Cry and as well as you know malware from
many many other operations they had seen
and it's normal operation mode it was
able to find an 81 similarity between
the functions shared in wannacry with
canopy the back door malware that was
linked in 2015 to a Lazarus group also
known as North Korea and following
Neil's tweet um Kaspersky Symantec and a
bunch of others went public to also
State their opinions of strong links
between wannacry and North Korea
but the the ability to quickly pivot on
this information allows us to understand
our adversaries quickly and it means
that we can also understand the motives
behind the threats that we see daily
another technology we use to try and
Tackle this detection and scale problem
is the notion of State collection and
state reconstruction across the fleet
the fleet Google's corporate
infrastructure
and this is basically about being able
to recall the state of all of our
machines at all points in time and the
kind of state information we're
interested in is things like process
executions Network flow disk operations
all of this kind of stuff and we want to
record it in such a way that we can
reconstruct for a point in time the
state of the machine
and this process is most often seen in
digital forensics and usually applied
like ad hoc during these kinds of
Investigations and it typically involves
things like memory and disk acquisition
and in this case it doesn't kind of
prevent itself to solving the detection
problem
but it's still actually an incredibly
valuable system because it kind of gives
us the ability to understand in real
time the state of the fleet you know
what's executing who executed it how
they affect the network stack for
example how they relate to each other
and so as a result we built the system
that can do this the idea being that
maintaining the state for our entire
fleet in real time could be a solvable
problem with the massive caveat of
providing you have a modest amount of
computing and memory spare
and we call this the shadow machine but
what we really mean is that some kind of
an abstract virtual machine we actually
borrowed some Concepts from virtual
machine introspection as part of this
abstract VM architecture and with VMI
guest applications run on a guest
operating system this generates events
which are observed by a monitor layer at
the host layer for example so first of
all we get input from the fleet we know
it comes from all of our platforms from
like a variety of detection agents and
some of these agents we write ourselves
and but also some of these kind of like
things we can ingest come from
third-party tools as well
but for example on OS X we have a binary
agent called Santa and Santa is an open
source allow listing tool written by
Google if you're interested we also open
source the allow listing management
platform upload
um and in Linux we use things like
Integrity measurement architecture or
IMA and which we get via order d
and so the system monitor receives all
these events as input it starts pattern
matching to determine if the input
depends on the host site or not and this
bit this is basically to try and decide
whether or not to send the input to an
abstract interpreter
and the abstract interpreter is
responsible for modeling the effects of
the input on the host state
and we kind of use this in things like
you know compiler optimization program
analysis as well but in that case we use
them to understand the effects of the
program without running it here we're
trying to do it with a machine
so yeah we're trying to understand the
effect of the event without re-running
the entire system and in our in our
monitor the state could be considered
almost as like a graph where State
changes are adding or deleting vertices
on this graph
and we know all of the state changes and
can play them forward and backwards as
the state changes over time and the
abstract interpreters I mentioned before
can freely call other abstract
interpreters so we can kind of like have
this multi-layered kind of a stack of
events in many ways
so the idea being if a host change
happens the change or state change is
recorded and the end result is this
detailed state of a real machine that we
can almost consider to be a shadow
and we can query this in real time using
a query language invented specifically
for this purpose
so while processing and recording State
changes we have the opportunity to
evaluate them against the rule set and
this is probably the most important
usage of the system for the detection
team so the idea being that with minimal
code we can describe a state change of
interest and this might be for example
bash forking tools normally associated
with reconnaissance right and a new
detection is born
but we can put more constraints here too
so we could say that it matters that in
this kind of like flow of things there's
also netflow in this execution so for
example I bash my execute it might Fork
python which then communicates over the
network and then that might Fork to do
some kind of like Recon command or
something like that and this might even
be an even higher priority signal than
the one I mentioned before
so the graph on the slide here is an
example extraction of a small section of
the state fired from a detection rule
Written In This Very system where the
rule is described in a few handfuls of
lines of code and it's designed to look
for a reconnectivity congruent with
someone who successfully gets a reverse
shell
but there's one thing I didn't mention
about this Rule and the fact and it's
basically the fact that we don't have to
Define what a reverse shell looks like
we don't have to say like oh a reverse
shell probably starts with someone
running like python hyphen C import
socket whatever or like bashes piping
stuff around and we didn't describe any
of that all we described is that if we
see any new process execution that
results in outbound net flow that Forks
a Recon tool of some kind like bin mount
for example then that's of interest to
us
and once we write this kind of a
detection then we can run it across the
entire fleet of Shadow machines for
current and historical State information
and this basically means that we can
find any machine that has previously
exhibited this kind of behavior and the
result of this kind of search is
actually very very high fidelity
foreign
so to return kind of like fundamentally
to an existential question I mean like
what's coming next to this model we've
got some stuff like what do we think is
going to happen next
and I think the the reality is like the
more complexity we build into our
systems the more we need to understand
and acknowledge that humans won't be
able to defend them forever the
complexity is rapidly outstanding out
expanding what we are capable of people
as doing
so as a result kind of by building these
self-defending systems using AI ML and
all of this stuff might be the best path
for us but this takes you know research
development experimentation proof
metrics testing many many other things
and it really isn't easy I'm definitely
not acknowledging that this is you know
an easy task going oh just you can do
this no problem
but it means in some ways that we
actually are putting ourselves out of a
job right
perhaps we'll move into kind of like new
and more interesting rules of actually
teaching machines how to do this
themselves but I mean realistically the
only time we'll tell here
so I've included a few resources on the
slide for completeness here and feel
free to take photos of the slide if you
want to by the way
um I'll pause this for a few seconds
while we do that
if not I can like leave the slider at
the end so don't worry about like
smashing the camera button okay I'll
probably take it down now so apologies
or not um but for those of you who might
be interested in finding out more about
the wider security team at Google I'd
really recommend checking out the
hacking Google documentary which is
available on YouTube and it's available
at g dot Co slash safety hacking Google
and it actually features many of my
colleagues and the partner teams that I
mentioned before
um but at that point I think thanks for
your time and I can probably stop the
questions
thanks
[Applause]
awesome guys thank you very much uh
we'll take some questions uh there was a
hand here very quickly
foreign
thank you uh so the question is how do
you test your detections after they've
been rolled out
as in like once they're live in
production yes so it's probably partly
through unit testing I like each
component of the pipeline that's like
using the whatever platform specifically
like in golang for example just the unit
testing languages at libraries and
golang we also have some systems that
can do extended integration testing so
we expect at one end to put something in
three or four systems down the pipeline
we expect something to come out and we
can do this pretty granular granularly
between each system
I probably can't mention like specifics
of how we do it because it's very
bespoke to be honest
um but it's like a blend of
unit testing and integration testing and
within reason in some cases end to end
um with the idea being we fire an event
at one end ourselves using a set of
testing Rigs and we see if it propagates
all the way out to the queue
[Music]
yeah yeah so the question was do we do
internal Road teaming on top of that and
we do have an internal red team um it's
the offensive security team
um they
Sorry probably one of the best uh tests
of production detections that we have to
be honest
um and we work very closely with them
like every time we do one exercise or
they sorry they do an exercise we kind
of like get their activity log and we go
through and see hey dude how much of
this did we see like is the things we
can improve on so they're like the real
broadcast I guess
um but we have all of that other kind of
like back testing that supports it as
well does that answer your question
awesome cheers thanks
yeah uh first of all thank you very much
um and one of the earlier slides you
talked through the life cycle
um one like uh
this one yes yep so you said that you
take something uh as a TTP you go away
and you research it with the amount of
ttps there are coming out and the rapid
changing how do you decide which ones to
prioritize and do you automate that as
well yeah or does that kind of the
manual start of it all that's a good
question because ttps are unbounded in
their growth right and we probably do a
few things the first is to know whether
or not we have threat intelligence to
back their usage in the real world
that's probably the most important
factor the second factor of it is
whether or not we know between detection
and control like what the current
hardening state of it a given set of
systems that might be targeted by a
specific ttb and a lot of this stuff is
done semi-manually but we do have like
some way of automating kind of like you
know what stuff do we see most
frequently we have metrics that can
support it
um but you you're right it grows
unbounded and that's one of the things
like we're currently trying to figure
out it's like rttp is a good way of
expressing detection like or expressing
Behavior because they're very difficult
and they're very granular which don't
always map well
um so it's a few things but threat
intelligence definitely have the informs
it as well let's answer your question
awesome
yep great talk um sorry thanks cheers
um my question was around desjardis and
uh false positives
um that's a good question
um you know as with every kind of like
granular system where it's like a number
between zero and a hundred right it's
like was is 73 bad or is like 24 bad
like and defining that takes a lot of
tuning to be honest like in this case
um this was actually kind of like
manually determined to be correct before
we went live with it
um
there is definitely a false positive
writing it I'm not gonna it's definitely
not perfect right and typically what
happens is if we see something where
it's between thresholds of what we think
is almost bad we'll kind of like go back
to human be like hey like we probably
need to figure out a bit more accurately
whether or not it's bad
um but to be honest with some of the
detections we have do actually utilize
this but only above a certain threshold
when we know it's going to be bad or
it's likely bad
um the stuff that's kind of like towards
the lower end of Badness we're like
not that convinced yeah so it's again
it's like combined with a bunch of other
stuff as well to make a decision
um Sansa yeah
microphone yeah thanks for the talk um
I'm curious if you could speak to some
of the challenges of introducing the AI
into environments that you don't control
so it makes sense when you're talking
about this on your own corporate Network
corporate laptops but Google obviously
provides uh lots of services to users
and I imagine it'd be a lot harder to
kind of Baseline what normal looks like
there when it is a lot more out of your
control yeah so actually one big caveat
I mentioned here this is actually only
internal Focus so we don't ingest any
user information in this in this model
um but you are right I think a big part
of the challenge of AI and this kind of
detection problem is determining normal
and whether or not you have sufficient
data to determine that
um so I can't really comment on the user
Behavior stuff because we don't do like
customer data it's really internal only
for Google
um but there's a lot of training and a
lot of proof and we've often just been
like hey this thing just doesn't work so
we just like scrap it basically like it
might take us a few months or years to
get there but we're kind of a big
believer and not continue on something
if it's not worth continuing on
it's like kind of answer your question
that's a very long answer
um we can talk about outside if you want
okay
um thanks for the talk it was really
interesting with regards to the shadow
machines that you're running what level
of granularity do you have in terms of
being able to go back in the data are we
talking like literally system level
calls or just like process executed or
something like that yeah and it's a more
kind of like something like symbolic
execution or in terms of processes or
something like that yeah we do draw a
line and only look at certain like for
example on The Cisco example of only
certain ciscals of interest and that's
primarily because it's it there's a lot
of data that we can pull here so we do
have to make a call in terms of like
what we're interested in and typically
like the Cisco level is roughly where we
in terms of writing detections we don't
typically go lower than that in this
particular engine but we do have some
lower stuff than that and but it really
heavily depends on the platform on which
it comes because if it's basically if
it's not logged we don't see it right
that's kind of the Crux of it so
um some platforms are more effective in
this model but
um typically like Cisco is where we when
we're writing detections the lowest will
typically go
yep thank you for the talk a good
question about the hypothesis testing
what do you do
um say you made a hypothesis and the
hypothesis didn't span out do you use
the data you collected or do you just
start from scratch and go back to the
slot yeah I think you know like it's
always worth documenting everything that
you do right and that this is basically
one of the main reasons for doing it
it's like you might never realize like
two years now I'm like oh we've looked
at this before like how far do we get
there so even if we go through this
hypothesis and get to a point where it's
not feasible we might still have a
detection that's in that low confidence
signaling base that I mentioned before
that we might be able to combine with
other stuff at a later date
um but sometimes we do actually just see
stuff where we might even leave it in
that low confidence signaling bucket and
it might be so inaccurate that it's just
worth turning off entirely and that's
pretty pretty common as well because we
when we combine all of this stuff like
we can be reasonably sure about how it
all plays together but it's not until
you actually run it in the real
environment that you realize how Goods
or bad something is
um so some some stuff we reuse and part
of that is turning it off if it doesn't
work
um but not all of it is kind of in that
bucket at the same time is that good
okay awesome um just before I finish um
if you have any other questions that you
didn't want to ask them in this forum
I'll be outside so please just come to
me and ask him wonderful Troy wonderful
thanks very much for getting one more
time