hi hi everyone so I'm Oscar and today
I'm just going to be talking a bit about
using honey pots for threat intelligence
so just to introduce myself I'm a second
year cyber security student at the
University of Warwick I'm also the
technician for the Warwick cyber
security society and that's my Twitter
not that I tweet anything so
so first of all given we're talking
about honeypots or threat intelligence
it seems to make sense to explain what a
honey pot is so this is a description
from Chris Sanders very good book about
intrusion detection so honey pots rely
on Deception to
encourage attackers to interacts with
them and then generate alerts so that
you know you've been connected to but
the difference is obviously that book I
just talked about is about intrusion
detection usually if you have a
connection to a Honeypot a traditional
thing to do is panic because that means
you've got someone on your network but
with threat intelligence it's exciting
to us if someone connects to it because
you get some valuable data
so what you want to do is take these
attacks encourage as many of them as
possible to connect to you and get
information such as IP addresses what
credentials are they used to log into
your server and other things like URLs
Keys wallet addresses because there's a
lot of crypto Etc
so over the summer I worked on an open
source project called threat Dash which
took the pre-existing um SSH Honeypot
called kauri which some of you might
have heard of it basically emulates an
SSH session but it doesn't actually run
anything which is a key distinction and
then what I did was I converted the data
coming out of that stored it in a
mongodb instance including the files
that you see uploaded Etc and then you
carry out signature analysis of it with
um Yara signature detection rules
foreign
part was hosted on the University of
Warwick public IP address which
originally I tried hosting it on AWS but
you get a lot less connections when
you're hosting it like that presumably
because at University is a targeted
institution so this graph here shows the
sort of attack volume you saw per day
across a period about three months so
the Blue Line you see there is how many
connections there were but trying to log
into the SSH Honeypot and then the
Orange Line shows how many of those
sessions actually executed commands
because you saw a lot of sessions that
were created someone logged in but they
didn't actually run any commands so
presumably just trying passwords across
the internet
now
the question we had to ask before moving
any further with this is is it really
worth it to put all this effort into it
because you can get a lot of valuable
information just from IEP addresses and
commands Etc but you can always get more
information by running more detailed
analytics on bins or trying to make it a
Honeypot more realistic but the further
you go each time it requires more effort
and eventually you reach a point where
you can spend weeks on one single thing
that doesn't really return anything of
much value so there's a trade-off
between you want to maximize what the
output is but you don't really want to
spend too much time on it thank you
so the aim of this project really was to
take a data set of about 28 000
interactions and identify unique attacks
so being able to look at an attack and
go oh yes I recognize this from a
certain attack
um
so first thing we used was my to attack
which allows you to tag it to certain
techniques but I'll admit I'm not very
familiar with motor attack so trying to
write it like that was quite hard I was
able to identify about 19 tactics or
techniques actually when about 224 exist
so obviously I most likely missed some
of the techniques that might to attack
lists but at the same time it's not an
easy thing to work with and
trying to look at a set of commands
being run on an assistant sh session and
map it to Mito attack it's not about
easy
so then the way which I try to look for
Unique attacks was look for Unique
combinations of Mito attack techniques
and using that I was able to identify 51
different attacks but when you start to
drill down into that because you only
have 19 possible techniques there's a
lot of overlap work you saw attacks that
were clearly very different being
categorized under the same thing
so just to give an example of this it
looks at the um system information
Discovery technique for micro attack
where an attacker tries to get some
information about the system
when
an attacker Alabama on the Internet is
connecting to a random IP address they
found that's most attacks most attacks
are trying to learn something about what
they've discovered so here I've got a
few examples of things that came under
the system information Discovery
technique and as you'll see they're
quite different so putting them under
one technique
was quite a broad fin really so it sort
of attacks that tried to read um the
binary for echo which is a traditional
tactic used to try and identify if the
system architecture is 32 or 64-bit
because you can read the elf header
um slash IP Cloud Print if you look that
up you know that they're trying to
Target a micro tick routers so okay
that's a command specific to that
and the Nvidia SMI command you know that
the attacker is looking for information
about the GPU so most likely trying to
do some crypto mining so if you actually
drill down into the specific commands
being run not just in miter attack
techniques you start to realize that you
can get more about the context from it
so the solution to this was rather than
using miter attack
I basically just took the commands and
manually went through them and
categorized them into unique individual
fins um I tried experimenting with
string similarities or things where
setting a threshold in for strings are
60 are similar or something
um
that didn't really work out so instead I
went to Yara rules and just trying to
write signatures for each um possible
attack
because as we saw before
my true attack just tells you what
tactic it's been used but it doesn't
give you any context so these are the
rules with notes and fins you're able to
identify what specific OS was being
targeted
what was the aim of that attack what
exactly are they trying to do and also
because a lot of these are automated you
see
um there are unique usages of certain
commands for example as you see in the
Yara rule on the slide there's a very
specific usage of you name the u-name
command with a several arguments in a
very specific order and as it's
automated fat attacker always used the
arguments in that order so I have
several rules in the data set which are
just looking for you name commands but
with arguments in slightly different
orders or different permutations because
that was able to uniquely identify an
attack
and the comparison there was I was able
to identify as I said 51 unique attacks
with Mito attack but then when I started
writing these custom signatures I was
able to get that up to a hundred so that
started to reveal the breadth of what
was actually in the data set and as I
said Yara signature rules as a defined
format you can also write comments add
notes so reviewing it is a lot more
useful
so just to quickly explain what sort of
things we're seeing in this day to say
it turns out when you put a SSH server
which anyone could log into on the
internet basically people are trying to
crypto mine uh at least 17 of all
attacks seen and this was attacks with
commands not just uh General connections
explicitly did something relating to
crypto that number is a massive um
underestimate because there are a lot of
attacks which I didn't go into in depth
but they were downloading shell scripts
and running it and when you start to
look at those most of them are also
crypto mining
so what would these crypto mining
attacks looking for well a big one was
looking for Hive OS systems which is a
um distribution specifically for crypto
mining you can tell that because it's
using a specific command High password
or it's looking for VNC passwords.txt
because apparently Hive arrest stores
its VNC passwords in plain text and also
a configuration file
also sort of XM rig which is a miner so
you can identify that by spotting the
GitHub download link
and there you've got another interesting
indicator that you could use for fret
intelligence because a lot of VM
commands were you had the um wallet
addresses in them so you could use that
and use it to map again later and
there are a lot of other different
crypto miners being downloaded or looked
for Etc
so the other thing about honeypots is
obviously as I said they rely on
Deception so you have to have an
attacker believe that they're real
and if an attacker obviously what we've
seen so far is mostly automated attacks
but if you have an attacker who actually
knows what they're looking for is
Hands-On keyboard and starting to look
around it suddenly becomes quite easy to
work out if you're in a Honeypot or not
so first things first if you've ever
used calorie you'll know it has a
default
um hostname of server 04
so any attacker who knows what they're
doing would see that hostname and
immediately log out because they know
they're in Honeypot so the very first
thing you want to do is change that I
think the instance I have running uses
production as a hostname hopefully that
seems appealing to an attacker
well the other thing I mentioned is
calorie emulates its command so it only
knows what's programmed into it so for
example a lot of attacks I saw over the
summer they were looking to read the um
uptime file see how long this ever been
up for that didn't exist at the time in
Calgary so I decided to add that because
[Music]
not even Dynamic I just put a file I had
a number in it actually and um hopefully
took some attacker that's going to make
it seem a little bit more realistic
because if you log into a system and you
can't find proc uptime you might start
to have questions about what's going on
the other thing that was missing was the
lspci command and that
um talks about the PCI cards available
on a machine so
my first instinct for that was just to
create a command run that command on my
local machine and copy the output but
the important thing as you can see in
this picture here is that because I was
currently doing my work in a virtual
machine and that's one of the ways an
attacker uses to detect virtualization
so whilst that might not suggest
Honeypot that might suggest to an
attacker that they're in some sandboxed
environment potentially hurting him off
giving any information that might be
useful for threat intelligence so I'd be
very careful to look for a um output
that didn't indicate any form of
virtualization just to make it seem a
little more appealing to an attacker
gosh
so the question at the end of all this
is it Honeypot are they worth it for
threat intelligence and the answer to
that is if you put a box on a random IP
address on the internet it probably
won't be that interesting you just see a
lot of botnets crypto mining Etc nothing
really that new
but
as a sort of scene by putting it on a
university IP address if you're some
organization that's perhaps of interest
to specific
um threat groups
you might start to see something more
unique
so if you're
particularly concerned about your fret
model having a honey pot for fat
intelligence might be useful
um the other thing is you just have to
be patient it took a long time days
before anything interesting came through
so just to sit tight and some days
you'll get loads of attacks some days
you get nothing
and the other thing is mostly attacks
you'll see Vegas
have been reported on it's very easy to
take something you see be excited about
him and just look it up and someone's
done a really good write-up of it so
that isn't it not really generating any
new anything new in terms of threat
intelligence but
the reason I talked about it today is
because it was just fun in the end like
you don't really discover anything new
but at the same time you get to see
what's going on on the internet have
your own idea of what who's scanning
what Etc
yeah so thank you any questions
[Music]
[Applause]
well thank you I wish I'd had one of
those at school
um would you have liked to have had the
opportunity to mount any of the address
space not currently that in use at the
University and that would obviously
reduce the probability significantly
would you be able to repeat the question
sorry
yep so assuming your university has a
block of address space
would you have liked the opportunity to
have mounted any of the spare address
space with Honeypot servers perhaps
redirecting to your one and then
potentially much reduce the probability
and therefore see significantly more
activity
yeah I mean
I don't I haven't really sort of thought
of how in depth about in terms of the
effects of the IP addresses it's um
I kind of just used what I was given but
I think trying to explore that more in
depth would be definitely very
interesting
any more questions
[Music]
if you're putting something on the
Internet
um to be exploited just to kind of see
what they're doing do you kind of worry
uh that someone might try and use your
resource that's that's hosted and used
by you to uh you know let's say stage
um you know in decent images or other
things that potentially could come back
to you
oh yeah I mean that's definitely a worry
that's kind of why the model behind
kauri as a sort of Honeypot is that
it's entirely emulation based because
nothing that's run actually I guess I
mean
saving the files you are saving anything
indecent that's uploaded Etc but
not publicly so I don't think in terms
of emulating if there's any particular
concern there
um did your Honeypot get any sort of
actionable information that you were
able to share during the three months
that you had it running
um you don't not necessarily yeah
I do there is like a list of IP
addresses and things I tried to sort of
um exporting all that I mean
there is information to be shared but
nothing that isn't already out there
like all these IP addresses and things
are being mapped by like bigger threat
intelligence um fins anyway
foreign
do you have any sort of future research
questions or any other sort of queries
that you think you'd like to answer with
a similar kind of set of experiments
I think the interesting thing that was
considered out this was can we do the
same for sort of Windows and RDP but the
answer to that was also
Windows is just a lot harder to work
with than trying to emulate that it's a
challenge so be about looking to
actually sandbox a Windows environment
cool
thanks uh so I one of the interesting
things about about it about thing ahead
because when you first started I was
thinking actually what's the use of how
could I apply this one of the things
probably because my background is more
GRC a lot of a lot of things people
probably struggle with is understanding
the real the real value of an asset so
actually I could see if you were to
deploy a series of Honey pots that might
indicate that someone could have access
to a specific asset maybe in terms of
University you'd be a research or
something that's being done that can
actually allow you to classify or get a
real value
um sort of generation of actually how
much if this specific asset work what's
the likelihood that someone would want
to try and access this and therefore
feed into your risk assessment so that I
think is quite interesting
um is that something you thought is that
there are a lot of applications along
the line of that along that kind of same
line of thinking or any other
applications you think could also
um honeypots can be useful or
yeah no definitely I think that's um I
think that's the sort of point trying to
make about the specific companies it
might provide a specific value that
obviously the context I was doing it was
just um general internet facing
honeypots but I can imagine it allows
you to if you were to try and emulate
something that you were specifically
interested in like trying to emulate the
characteristics of that I could give
interesting information and also
um a bit of idea of what's actually
targeting your organization
yeah definitely so because that's the
sort of information you can get you can
start to like tags IP addresses any
other sort of indicators and so you can
really build up your own sort of
internal threat Intelligence on that
did you try different output in lspgi so
if you included a your high performance
graphics card they you would see them do
further commands versus disconnect
please say that again so with lspci you
could include a you know an Nvidia
graphics card did you look at if they uh
won further commands after they've found
the graphics card versus not finding one
and just disconnect yeah so definitely
um with the commands about gpus you were
often um seeing grips for certain
patterns um
the interesting thing I did find in
terms of a lot of those um grips is that
it didn't it never seemed to
particularly affect what the attacker
actually ran afterwards it seems
a lot of collect a lot of attackers seem
to collect information to store for
themselves but never actually do
anything but yeah I definitely um try to
make the lspci look a bit more enticing
with Nvidia graphics
obviously by putting it on a university
Network do you have any like ethical
concerns had they broken out of your
kind of virtual environment
um
not in far as the way it was um set up
like I was very lucky to have a very um
skilled of technician who I worked with
who made sure it's a sort of very on the
public IP address range but it was an
isolated lab environment and it was
properly firewalled et cetera so there
wasn't any risk to that
is that all
yes yes no any more questions last call
no excellent well if we want to give
Oscar yes yeah yeah a round of applause