I not entirely sure how I can follow
that little chat but that's right I'll
apologize in advance for my slides I put
some together them they're very bland so
I gave in to our marketing department
and they over marketed them so I've
tried to pull it back a bit but I might
have to skip over some of the gloss in
it networks is a triple play provider in
the UK we're just starting our third
academic year of delivering IPTV to
student accommodation sort of dorm rooms
at universities and it's going very well
one of the so
what what we found was that a lot of
universities were needing to do
something about TV dorm rooms in li in
the UK certainly don't have satellite TV
they don't have cable TV they depend on
over-the-air broadcasts and in the UK
much as I believe it is in the US we're
going through the analog to digital
switchover at the moment TV's students
take TVs into their dorm rooms and stick
a little Ariel on top of the TV and get
a fairly snowy analog picture which is
great when it's analog when you go to
digital then you're going to get nothing
so universities recognise they need to
do something a few universities went off
on their own and started to put together
little mini IPTV setups typically based
around VLC or something like that but in
what the once the broadcaster's caught
on to this they started clamping down on
that rebroadcast rights and things like
that so that's where it came along we
spent a lot of time talking to
broadcasters and negotiating on the
rights to be able to deliver content to
students and but then we need to
technology step
just a bit about student market to give
us some scope there's about just just
over 3 million students in the UK
they're half a million of those actually
live on campus so got quite a large
audience talked about that digital
already universities are trying to clamp
down on streaming media they're very
worried about the huge growth in unique
else traffic in the UK BBC main
broadcaster has product road iPlayer
sort catch up TV download and streaming
the other broadcasters doing something
similar university is very worried about
their their network bandwidth and
they're actually putting clauses in some
of the UC sort of T's and C's of the
resnet network connections that say
things like like one of highlighted here
you are not permitted to download or
stream films movies television programs
or video clips including BBC iPlayer for
on-demand YouTube etc so students want
to get TV but the universities don't
want to kill their network in the
process so we came along with an IPTV
solution one centralized head end so
there's no capex for the university's
delivering that over multicast into the
universities and wrapping that up with
the middle Aaron outlets that's needed
to make it work
from our ipt head TV head end in london
we're delivering both into Janet and
also indicate and wireless they're
probably in top three DSL providers in
the UK but the only one that is
delivering multicast over dsl so that
gave us an opportunity to deliver
services not only to on campus
accommodation but also those that moved
out of dorms into private accommodation
we've tried to replicate the digital TV
setup as closely as possible full-frame
d1 broadcast quality video h.264
encoding between megabit per second got
about 112 channels worth a headend also
needing to use conditional access but
rather than using a Microsoft or or
other proprietary drm solutions we use
the same conditional access technologies
that digital TV uses with EC MZ mms in
the MPEG transport stream but because
we're on IP we had the opportunity to
use IP four key distribution or that so
utilize some of the benefits of that
it's one of the marketing slides I'm
going to skin very quickly over that
that's a shame that we had to build
quite a large back-end system to support
all this as well and so we got this and
looks very much like you would your TV
system at home full screen video
on-screen EPG but you might notice it's
on a PC what we found was that student
rooms are getting smaller and students
are getting bigger
they didn't want to bring both PC and a
TV on campus and certainly in the early
days talking to universities they almost
wanted to discourage the students from
bringing TVs because there to provide
more power sockets in the rooms and more
electrical safety testing to be done and
all the rest so universities encouraged
us to go down the PC room so we
developed a solution look what we call a
virtual set top box which we pretty much
emulate a set-top box on a PC so in fact
it's been developed so that too
middleware systems that in the server
side of IPTV they can pretty much not
tell the difference between whether
they're delivering to PC or to a
traditional set-top box motorola rural
sanitation Atlanta etc one of the key
benefits of this is that for those
universities and we're working with some
universities that deal with this sort of
more upper class student want of a
better term would rather have a big flat
screen TV in their room with set-top box
but that means that we can deliver the
same solution to both set-top box onto
the pc we've no changes you're not
hiding so I'm just like more interesting
bits how we do this all the universities
in UK are connected together onto a
network called Janet the joint academic
Network they operate a 40 gig ring
around the UK on the diagram that's the
red lines links ate corn pops around the
UK and then from those core pops they
hand the traffic off to regional network
operators which there's 19 around the UK
and they're resilient Lee connected
to Janet and then universities will
connect into their closest regional
network operator we've interconnect
ziemlich janitor london and that allows
us to live with both multicast annually
cast to all the universities of course
we had a few challenges along the way
some universities they're very familiar
with multicast already and for those it
just worked you go to a lot of listen to
a lot of talks about IPTV read a lot of
white papers particularly from Rita
vendors that want you to buy all their
kin and say that it's exceptionally hard
to do I PT billions you've got to invest
heavily in latest and greatest hardware
and all their special tweaks to make
IPTV just work and what we found was you
don't leave any of that as long as
multicast gets from a to b then it works
of course we did have quite a few
problems universities that weren't
familiar with multicast those that were
but kind of new has two on campus but
didn't know how to get in from the
outside world and we had to work with
them in the in most cases it was easy
you bring up your msdp so you bring up
your peer adjacencies and it works
except they all put finals in the way
what we found was lost reuter vendors
router vendors sorry have dr. I've got
multicast sorted now and it's just a
switch to turn it on file or vendors not
quite the same they I think we had one
particular checkpoint not entirely sure
that they've actually fixed it yet where
if it worked if it was running in layer
2 mode yeah it could you can configure
an ACL to allow multi class to go
through but you turn it into a layer 3
mode and him what's that so what we
found was a lot universities were having
to build little bypasses around their
file
was to allow multi casting which which
worse GRE tunnel saw or just a cable
around the outside the other problem we
found was that universities in response
to the problem streaming traffic
peer-to-peer traffic are putting a lot
of package shaping and bandwidth
management tools in with the sole
purpose of limiting the amount of
bandwidth that their students can get to
from their dorm rooms except we want to
deliver to making extremes to them so we
often found that the package shapers
would write limit this nice to me
extremely because that must be bad down
220 okay and hey TV stops working and
cause again it's one of those big things
that router vendors will tell you that
you've got to have because hey they've
got a solution for fixing that certainly
on Janet and the regional networks we
they used the easy fix to cause which is
open over provision Janet thought to
keep backbone the regional networks
multi gig networks no congestion TV just
gets through it fine however once you
get onto the campus the fun there's a
lot less money available links from
central campus out to the dorms might be
on 100 Meg link or maybe a gig if you're
lucky and their content heavily
contended so we found that we had to
work with some of the University
certainly with the smaller residential
networks to make local calls on campus
marking our traffic prioritizing
and of course as is always the case when
you don't control the network from eight
to end there is an awful lot of
finger-pointing we would be contracted
with the university to deliver an IPTV
service so when it breaks they phone us
up and say hey you know it's broken so
we have a look and we see that the
university is not actually receiving any
multicast so they escalated to the
regional network operator regional
network operator being stuck between
Janet and the University we had no
responsibility to they had no
responsibility to us so when the
university phoned them up and said hey
it's broken they said no it must be next
fault must be Janet's fault so we go off
and we talked to Janet and say hey those
guys over there say that you're not
giving them any mods gust and Janice say
yes we are look it's going there so we
go back to the University who'd go back
to the regional network operator and the
problem typically magically goes away no
one admits that they broke anything no
one admits they ever fixed anything but
and one of the things we learned very
quickly was that we needed to have a lot
better visibility into what was going on
unicast you kind of push it out a new
hope it gets there so what we had to do
was deploy a number of remote multicast
monitoring notes into the universities
which were able to detect and analyze
our incoming the encoding multicast
streams to validate that they were being
recent received properly by deploying
multiple monitoring nodes on one
regional Network we could seem to see
patterns whereby if all the monitoring
nodes on one regional network went down
but all the other regional network
monitoring notes data then there's a
great good possibility that it was that
regional network operator that was at
fault and that helped us with the finger
pointing in their direction allowed us
to provide just basic availability
graphs as you can see there
and it's worked well looking at some of
the reported viewing stats in terms of
minutes per week with the average user
consumes of TV web TV providers internet
TV providers as a tues of this world
acclaiming low hundred minutes per week
per user at the other end of the
spectrum traditional TV in the UK that's
reported on by an organization called
barb who's reporting about 1500 minutes
per at the week per user and we're we're
just over a thousand so what we're
seeing is that if you take that that
step from web TV the streaming which is
typically low bitrate to get it down
pretty much any line typically slim
frame size up to a full digital TV
experience a high bitrate then users are
more willing to actually watch that and
maybe it's just because we've got
friends and they haven't friends the
program pot recipe
of course as I say multicast is
unidirectional so we throw it out there
but how do we know that people are
watching it but this IPTV its IP we've
got back channel all of the clients
report back to the IPTV middle whether
the central server and I had end that
provides all their metadata EPG
information about channel changes and so
from that we were able to construct
usage figures anonymized about who's
watching what and when and allows us to
produce some fairly accurate graphs as
you can see there's one of our channels
there knows that most peak around 6pm so
there's obviously a program on them but
the broadcaster's lovelace in the
traditional world they are used to doing
getting their audience figures by doing
sampled surveys one in a thousand users
that give them a little log book and say
write down what you watch today but now
we're able to say to them you put this
program on at 6pm and by 603 you have
this many people and then the ad
commercial break came in 20 minutes
later and everyone switched off so they
can tailor their they're broadcasting
accordingly but equally the advertisers
like this as well because they know to
the to pretty much to the user into the
second how much people are watching
their adverts again we can go to them
and say as soon as that advert for the
ford cars came on everyone switched off
so you probably don't want to run that
one again which led on to one of the key
key revenue opportunities for us in IPTV
which is advertising what we've found is
that advertisers are very keen that they
can now have an addressable audience we
care we know who each of the users is
we've got information about them we can
catch
they're viewing figures they're viewing
habits and things like that which allows
us to do targeted advertising we're
running a trial on that at the moment in
the UK with the channel for one of the
main TV channels in the UK and we are
replacing their ads with the student
targeted advertising at the moment we're
just providing one replacement for
students because it was an easy
demographic to sell to them and
advertisers like that and the brands
like that of course the way the way
we're doing targeted advertising at the
moment is that in our head end where
we're taking the channel for string and
putting through an ad splicer and
producing different versions of it which
kind of negates the the benefits of
doing multicast because suddenly you
want to be able to address your audience
you may want to split them down into 100
different demographics you might want
humanity students male students female
students students that like watching top
gear or the office or something like
that and suddenly rather than one copy
of channel 4 you've now got 100 copies
of channel 4 leave in the head end so
what we're we're currently investigating
is trickle feeding of advertising down
to the to the student edge into the
viewing device that PC typically and
pushing the ad splicing capabilities
right out to the edge which gives us
unique opportunities to at the far into
the spectrum give every user a different
different advert in the commercial break
there's just a marketing slide about how
we do that it's it is a slightly
different arena in Hyde replacement in
the UK out in the u.s. you have a lot of
your regional broadcasters and regional
cable codes that will do out replacement
so the broadcasters are used to tacking
where their ad breaks are and a life
them to be replaced in the UK we don't
have that channel Channel Four's as
itself were using send out one copy of
channel Thor and they expect that to be
seen by everyone and in fact they don't
want to tag where the ad breaks are
because the clever people then go and
stick a box on the ends that ripple the
ads out and save it to disk so we've had
to work with the broadcaster's to
actually put that capability back in to
tag where the outbreaks are and and then
gives us the opportunity to replace them
of course linear TV which is the
majority of what we're doing at the
moment isn't the be-all and end-all
people are getting a lot more use to the
I want to decide what I want to watch
and when I want to watch it which moves
us into body but we're moving away from
that movie back away from multicast into
unicast which is not what the
university's one traditional board in
IPTV world you go out to Sun and they'll
sell you a big pod server that feels 34
cabinets and can deliver 100,000 streams
from your head end and hate the network
is somebody else's problem that doesn't
really work for us so we've gone out and
we found a vendor that actually can
provide this that one you Bob's you can
see on the screen here can deliver 20
gigabits per second of screaming from up
to 4 terabytes of flash storage in that
box in a 1u thing at low cost which has
completely changed the
economics of God because we can now
start spray these around the edge of the
network with students we can push them
into every University of need be in the
slams then we can push them out of
exchanges the central offices to to
serve from as close to the edge as
possible and of course IPTV isn't just
about watching IPTV if you listen to dr.
in first talk yes yesterday he was
saying that IPTV is more about
integrating in with other stuff and it's
not just sitting down and watching TV so
of course we're in an IP world so we've
integrated in with that Facebook as
everyone does so we have some widgets on
facebook where you can go and if you're
a free while using our TV brand you can
go and what go and go on to facebook and
you can see what your other friends are
watching on on TV at the moment you can
build communities of people that like
watching friends or or so on and also in
the IP world as allowed us to work with
advertisers to provide click through
advertising from TV which they're not
not used to one of the key prime
examples very similar to the one that
fits their fused yesterday was that
you're watching a an advert for a car or
for music and you can click on it
because you're on a PC but I mouse and
it can straightaway say hey you're
interested in that car join me to get
someone from the local garage to give
you a coat and
your IP TV on your voice VoIP and
handset that's part of our network as
well so we know where you are already or
maybe you're watching a musical and you
find some track you like you can click
on it or something and they says hey if
you like this then join me to go to
Amazon and get into center of that CD
straight away or or maybe go to iTunes
and download it and of course UK small
so we thought we'd bring it out to the
US as well bring this more relevant to
nut up as you're aware the Internet to
full conference is on at the moment in
your lens and we're demonstrating their
what we've done in the UK between the US
as well so just last week I was building
a mini headend in Texas A&M University
which we're delivering over internet too
much the same way that we do in Janice
in the UK to to the Internet to
conference in New Orleans but in much
the same way as it can be delivered to
any dorm room or any university that's
connected to internet too
that's it some contact details there if
you're interested if you want to see a
demo of it working I will try and get it
working fuel to come see me after
afterwards but just to give you a little
flavor and to prove that it does
actually work I was also given
with this one
right
so it's no sound I'm afraid but there's
a show that students in cast
accommodation are watching a TV service
on their CC in much the way that you
would think
any questions mylanta home do you stream
vers multicast to the laptop over Wi-Fi
the simple answer is no multicast over
Wi-Fi doesn't work very well what Wi-Fi
treats multicast is broadcast and so
will transmit it at the lowest common
rate which in many cases in one meg and
given the task stream so to make them
they just don't work over Malta cast
there are a few technologies that are
coming out at the moment 802 11 n and
Rutgers have also got a slightly
proprietary system that deal a lot
better with multicast but for the moment
we say that we only support at open
wired connections have you been thinking
about adapting a multicast to unicast
just close to the wireless network so
that I Phi yourself could use it that's
one of the things we've been looking at
fraud dsl offering we're using Thompson
sleepy equipment and we've been working
with them to see what we can do to get
TV signal to go over over wireless and
translating at the cpe from multicast
into uni calstrs is one of the options
to them they're working on them thank
you
okay all right thank you very much