heated heated discussion around some of
the 40 gig and Hunter gig single mode
objectives especially on the between the
two optics vendors Finisar and op neck
so that was fun to watch we called it
the Chris and Matt show which was kind
of on going offline and during the
meetings draft one not zero is finished
I have another slide on that one because
it's such a significant thing that's
happened and basically the bottom line
is that were on schedule for 2010 now an
interesting thing is that there's
already demand for things that are
outside the official project so that's
actually okay it's okay for things to
happen outside the I Triple E or to
happen later like for tenure net10 gbase
t happened you know five years out to
the standard or so the good thing is
that the architecture is really flexible
so it allows for a lot of extensions and
there are things that have been put in
there for future technology so we can
expect a lot of MSA as MSAs or
multi-source agreements we're basically
a bunch of people get together and do
something and again that's okay for it
happened outside the I Triple E the I
Triple E is really responsible for
defining a standard in the architecture
and less responsible for specific
implementation decisions so draft one
not zero is here everyone's pretty
excited about that it's a really really
significant milestone because it
captures all the technical objectives
now I was going over my slides with some
of our standards guys and they were
chastising it for me for not having read
the entire document and it's okay it's
202 292 pages long and they're like well
you know the question that you just
asked is answered on page 75 Clause 2 or
something but I don't know I haven't
read it so apparently it is long and
very detailed so draft two will be
technically complete and I just want to
kind of talk about you know where we're
going and people ask me all the time
ready and when we're going to see
product so I just kind of want to I
don't want to sound you know basically
you know we're not quite there yet I
don't want to sound negative but I just
want to you know caution people that
there is some hype around 100 gig and 40
gig and that there's still a lot of
stuff that could change so basically one
not zero is captures all the objectives
but when you have something on paper
then you go and actually try and build
it there stuff that's going to come up
and the I Triple E calls this crossing
the eyes and diving the t's see they do
have a sense of humor and then there's
there's always a careful balance between
you know Margot timing and the standards
process and compliance so there's three
drafts sir that come out one does 0 to 0
and 3 20 and each one will be more and
more of a standards so as time
progresses there's more of a certainty
of being standards compliant if you base
your implementation on giraffe to vs
draft one or graph three versus rep to
or something like that but people can
actually start to evaluate you know what
it's going to take how they're going to
do it and start at least scoping out the
implementation based on draft one so
that is the good news here's a summary
of the reach objectives and
specifications this is a old slide the
difference is that the solution has now
been defined so for example we're still
trying to figure out is 100 get going to
be you know a ten-by-ten solution or 4i
25 all those things have been worked out
and then again here you see all the
nomenclature for TG based key are for
and I have a slide in the back that
helps you decide for all that kind of
stuff here's a very extremely
complicated slide and I apologize that
it's so dense but I wanted to put
everything I want two slides that it
makes sense at least here's no review of
the architecture basically all the stuff
above the mac is the same and all the
stuff below the mac changes so same
frame format you know same same control
and all that kind of stuff another thing
has changes that there's new interface
definitions below the mac and then of
course higher rates so the thing that I
really want to point out is in these
blue circles which you probably can't
see unless you have the presentation in
front of you but this is basically where
some of the flexibility is in being able
to cope with future technology so
eventually everyone wants to do 1400 gig
cereal but unfortunately it's just not
possible with the current technology so
right now it's going to be a multi-lane
solution for 49 our gig eventually
though we'll get there with technology
that will allow us to do a serially so
you can see there's always some
provisions in there for actually you
know doing multi-lane down to one lane
which would be cereal so the sort of
interesting objective that's just
completely undefined as provide
appropriate support for Chanin we've
talked about this a little bit before
basically 10 gig Ethernet has a what's
called the Wiz which is the way
interface sub layer I think that's kind
of a fun word to say it's missing from
4100 gig because they've taken that out
in 10 gigs it's actually kind of
complicated and a little bit awkward
because you have to you know translate
10 gig Ethernet into sonic framing and
it doesn't actually run a 10 gig line
rate because of the framing so there's
been a lot of work between the itu-t and
the I Triple E to transparently map
Ethernet into the saw infrastructure and
the other thing I want to point out is I
have these little URLs at the bottom
which point you to the full presentation
so these are all available to the public
if you want to download and read all the
details but basically it's been worked
out between the ITU and the I Triple E
about how exactly that's going to happen
and then who's going to define like how
that works and then the other things
instron thing thing that I've always
been mentioning is you know we want
Ethernet to be as reliable and have some
of the same characteristics as far as
troubleshooting monitoring that people
like about sonnet so link fault
signaling and those kind of things are
feasible it's not in the specification
to work but there's no reason why that
shouldn't work for otn ok
obviously there is a something wrong
Todd yeah you're right I should have
checked these slides okay so let's talk
a little bit about the specifics of each
type of objective that end in more
detail and I try to kind of make this
applicable to operators which
unfortunately is is under the text so
the backplane solution is kind of
interesting not necessarily for running
a big network but in terms of what can
happen with blade servers and that kind
of technology this was really heavily I
don't want to say pushed but Intel and
some of the the blade server vendors had
a big interest in this and I think it's
going to be interesting the
possibilities that we see with a high
density and high capacity blade servers
in the future but basically this
technology is going to oughta go she ate
from 1 to 40 gigs so as server capacity
and capabilities increase I think blade
server is going to be very interesting
it basically is based on CH ng base KR
which is the 10 gig backplane
specification and it does sort of the
same things now the one bullet that i
kinda want to talk about is influence of
Triple E so Tripoli is a project in the
I Triple E called energy-efficient
Ethernet and it's basically introducing
some new control frames to drop the
power when systems are idle to reduce
the usage this will probably have an
influence on the backplane technology
you can see if you have a bunch of blade
servers that could have a 40 gig
capacity and they're not doing anything
and makes sense that kind of drop that
utilization or the capacity down to one
gig and then raise it again when they're
they're busy talking ok looks like all
these are broken so the copper cable
specification basically also reuses 10g
base KR and the cable parameters are
based on 10 gb cx4 I think cx4 is
personally a terrible an awkward
connector I hope we don't have to reuse
that but the cable parameters are based
on cx4 it also does out of negotiation
and then the other thing I want
point out is that we're trying to figure
out you know how to make a connector for
this kind of stuff so the current
proposal is that a four-lane solution
would use qsfp qsfp is a quad sfp it's a
basically a high-density pluggable media
that has you know for four lanes in it
and then the ten lane solution would use
something called sff 80 92 it's a new
small form-factor pluggable standard
that people are working on but again
it's just a high-density connector for a
copper or fiber for the 100-meter om3
multimode fiber solutions basically it's
a parallel solution I don't want to say
it's a ribbon cable because that kind of
you know gives people the wrong
impression but it's going to be some
sort of high density fiber connector
that would go into a high tendency
connector and then people have been
talking about you know well we want to
make things go further than 100 metres
can we do to 300 and then the OM for
fiber manufacturers are talking about
well you know we could go farther over
14 this is possibly one technical
objective that still could be amended
based on what people are able to
actually do when they get some samples
working the 40 kilometer single mode
solution this was one of the heavily
debated ones and the bottom line is that
it's going to use a cwdm grid and it's
going to run these lambdas and then the
hunter gig single mode solutions again
one of the heavily debated objectives in
the I Triple E and this one is going to
use the LAN WDM solution and the thing I
want to point out here is that again you
know we're talking about flexible
architecture and future technology so
right now if you notice on the back end
going into the block diagram it's all
ten lanes of 10 gigs so basically this
is based on a 10 gig series intended
electrical technology so as we get the
capability to do fast reelect racal
technology we can basically whack off
the whole back end of that and just do
four times 20 25 gig into the block and
then that will save a lot of cost and
components
things like that so this is just an
example of you know how technology can
change and how this is kind of built re
allow for that technology in the future
and then those newer generation
components and technology will allow us
to drive the cost down the hunter gig 40
kilometer is basically the same diagram
you know there's just an amplifier in
there because it has to go further and
this uses the same grid spacing and
again same thing here we have 10 lanes
of 10 gig going into the block and as we
have new technology that allow us just
to do for by 25 all right where are we
now so someone spent three years since I
started doing these updates and we're at
least halfway there again draft 10 is a
big big achievement and basically summer
of two thousand ten will see the
standard here's a much more detailed
timeline from the I Triple E the things
I want to point out here are the draft 1
20 20 and 30 dates in here so when
you're talking about you know when
vendors are going to have technology
kind of keep these dates in mind because
these are when the big changes happened
and one question you know like I said
when are we going to have this well if
you look at the timeline draft 20 is
going to be the last technical change so
I think people are going to have a
reasonably reasonably good idea what's
going to happen by sort of summer of
next year and then if you figure it
takes three to six months to do an ASIC
then basically nurs have to sell that to
router vendors router vendors have to
take that put up the board so i think
we'll start seeing some some product out
there by end of year 2009 I think that's
pretty reasonable date future meetings
basically the meetings are going to get
really boring comment resolution is
probably one of the most tedious things
that I've ever been through in my entire
life it's basically where you look at
everywhere of the draft and criticize
every war
so this is like you know there's a comma
missing on this sentence and like a
ticket gets open for every comment and
then we all sit in a room and go over it
and vote on accepting the changes and
there's a lot of technical changes that
happen to but I mean it just it you go
with a fine-tooth comb and that'll take
several meetings actually here's the
website everything like i said is public
you can download it and read about it in
as much detail as you want here's the
nomenclature this is just for your
reference really but that explains you
know how we come up with all these fancy
nomenclature and then these last five
slides are just you know the detailed
how we get there and there's a scanner
any questions
hey Todd Underwood there are rumors and
insinuations that there are existing
vendor implementations can you talk
about your companies or any of your
competitors in what the time scale for
that is whether those are free standards
or what you know what standard there
yeah so there's there's been a lot of
demos and this is good because it's good
for people to demo that technology
there's been a lot of demos specifically
around 100 gig technology and I say a
hundred gig technology because that's
what it is not hundred gig Ethernet
because it's not based on the standard
it can't be Ethernet until the standard
is done but it's good that people are
thinking about that technology again I
would just say that you know the draft
schedule is pretty well defined so draft
10 we have a pretty a good idea of
what's going on draft 20 we have a lot
better idea and then draft 30 you know
the standard is pretty much done so
anything that people are talking about
right now I mean draft 10 just came out
a few weeks ago so it would have to be
really pretty standard so I would just I
just caution people to to use this
timeline and evaluate what vendors are
saying