and our final two lightning talks to the
two guys who came on the postle
scholarship and they basically wanted to
say what they got up coming here why
they came here and and how they feel
about it so if you guys want to come
forward and you're going to do a little
double act for us and your 10 minutes
starting now yeah dislike
hello my name is Patrick acquis I'm one
of the possible fellows and Tracy will
be coming out shortly he's the other
person who won the postural scholarship
this time round okay like most people in
here I wear lots of hats 1 hat is I work
for a network operator in Uganda I
noticed that many people didn't know
where that was so I did a little map
with a bit of bread so that's our ass if
you see announcements that you shouldn't
see in that is please feel free to
contact me and I look at it just some
statistics about the Internet in Uganda
the typical size of a pipe to a customer
is going to about 64 K that's totally
different from here where someone can
have 23 make which might be what a small
isp might have the most common end of
mile solution right now is wimax we have
very little cable all our upstream
connectivities where satellite so we
have 500 milliseconds and up we have 1i
XP locally tested in july two thousand
three there are five peers our current
traffic the last time I looked at it was
3.2 that's a collective traffic going
through the IX and no ipv6 legs not yet
anyway the list down there the URL shows
the licensed operators in Uganda my
second hat is from ethanol the african
version of nano
there I serve the workshop program
coming to our craniums entries you know
tools we've had my meeting so far each
of the green places are the countries
where we've hosted enough knob meeting
Morocco has specially when editing read
the next one is in Cairo and they held
once a are not the three meetings which
nanog has ok I've not has a different
kind of a look out when you compare it
to nano that dish I'm not sure where you
can see it has ter ups to hold it in
place that was during one of a half nog
setups we didn't actually end up using
that dish but it goes to show the
differences in what we have to go
through to get a network setup the
maximum bandwidth repair data and
afterwards about 30 40 mbps usually have
about 1 mbps for the entire event we
have a one-week workshop then we have
three days meetings in there afrinic
meetings afterwards and before that we
have one week to do the entire setup
which I saw being done in six hours and
I was pretty impressed so there's some
lessons of land from coming here first
is the content is always something to
learn something new to see and new toys
to play with also I've noticed that the
preparations here for the meetings are
bit further on than in say F nog and we
also seem to have more people
contributing towards this up to set up
of the knork and infrastructure and all
that I've also seen that you can
actually give one hour notification or
less for lightning talk and still have
one and the tools here a bit more and a
difference is a lot of the tools which I
saw especially in the north were carried
on laptops whereas we tend to build a
tool
on the fly every time we go for that one
week so hopefully I'll go back and then
see what we can change about that so any
questions comments okay Tracy
did you have your own slides or not yeah
you need you to have given us the slides
really
can I help you file today
yeah okay
blue
and yet there K given K
problem
then I'll self
former is it any the PDF okay
so what we just saw another ancestor
when the hell people's rheumatism is
going I don't know about you but I I'm
my joints are actually aching from the
cold in this room is fantastic getting
like a cold draft coming from somewhere
anyway um yeah so yeah don't forget
don't go away excitement find out who
the new steering committee is in about
one hour from now and I think the other
thing that's probably worth mentioning
is once we're after the coffee break
this afternoon we're then going to be in
a position where we will not be together
again all in the same room again until
tomorrow morning because it's all
breakout breakout stuff and tracks this
afternoon after the coffee break so I
think the other thing I'll do is I'll
plug tomorrow morning which is the first
session which is going to start at nine
tomorrow morning is the the grated slot
as they're going to call it which is
that the the wonderful and whys and the
people that have the people that knew
jump Estelle thinking back on the last
ten years that we've been through our
without John and how John would have
done it and how do I would have
approached things and I think that's
definitely something if you're going to
be here making sure make sure you come I
mean I'm not getting out of here until
like 1pm on my flight so I'm definitely
staying for that and then I'm going up
to the bay area to beat up some switches
famu hardware USB mass storage device
I am doing I'm just running everything
okay very good thank you very much first
of all I would love to ask you to excuse
me I lost your times it's one hour
around one hour lost my laptop tossed
crust and every my presentation has
disappeared on this one I would make it
roughly okay um copo tracy marine d as
you can see one of postal latrobe fellow
unbuckle of science electronic since
2000 attitude at STG superior the
techniques applique standalone king
Jason Democratic Republic of the Congo
I'm single and have 3500 brahmacarya
involved since april two thousand two in
internet growing in central Africa in
congo kinshasa nakama browser view from
2002-2004 again a fair job as an
engineer operations in Rafah tech a
internet service provider in DRC and
medullary was managing wireless local
loop using a value and my critique or
materials doing some customer supporting
and fixing piece at material in the case
of some hardware problem
from two thousand four to two thousand
six hours IT manager of internet of
Ireland jay is a new ice P in
Brazzaville in Congo Brazzaville
locating brazzaville and in point nor a
day I walk for total and more ministries
of preserve you and my key skills inside
it companies was networking using cisco
systems well as networking usually wimax
of al volume and after an internet
service and everytime electronics cause
are many products engineer from
2006-2007 I work for system Europe these
times I go beside networking go beside
ICT was going to make some
investigations of building electrical
electrical hydropower oh right now I'm
going to tell you about my wedding with
the internet my wedding has started in
2005 when I go to attend Hafner workshop
in Mozambique in maputo I history
internet services under freebsd and in
november two thousand five i started the
stem study but in french in libreville
gabon with azonza and calvin amounted la
francophonie i can talk about my work
for internet growing in 2006 i was a
local host of n spa in XP trainings in
Brazzaville after attaining a flock in
2006 in in kenya in nairobi a comeback
in my country
and in my country of residence
brazzaville and organized this workshop
you can check at WWF epidote oh you can
get some information buried in the same
in the same year two thousand six I was
an assistant instructor of any spa
training in Libreville Gabon and in the
same year again are funded associations
by the name of you to LD do unique
solution depopulate develop Malika or I
can say name which is unix and open
source for development in Brazil
republic of the congo in which am
teaching open source and i'm doing
popularization of internet usage they're
willing to make grow internet motivate
me to attend all laugh knock track and
teach others when I was back to my
countries of origin and in malice
country of residence in 2008 I was one
of confounder of PSD Congo on bsd Congo
is a scientifical associations located
at University of Kinshasa in DRC and in
this year in August we organized the
fest workshops in which I was many
structures I used to teach unix freebsd
system administration on our website
actually is online ww that bsd congo
that urgh you can see something there
but i am working on this side the
location of our associations with
University of Kinshasa Democratic
Republic of the Congo especially in the
Department of Computer Science and this
one is the mailing list where we
discuss with every student after
workshop on some project got some
projects agra some prior private project
m and project with PSD Congo with bsd
congo close with a sock chapter of
Kinshasa and I cannot large we have a
project to organize a workshop of ipv6
which all participant will come from all
University in from our country but we
had called some participant from
University of Congo Brazzaville to in
two months we must organize the was with
this whatcha found in my private project
I have a project with Emma's difficult
net is mantle have and if people in
these associations I'm teaching people
with problem with disabilities people of
mantle have diff people I'm teaching
them to use in to use internet and teach
them damn computer science computer
maintenance computer networking you can
go at this website is the website i put
online for them i'm walking on these two
and this contract under there is pasta
kimono hes a busta bus a diff a diff
person i woke him inside his project i
thank very much f nog and afrinic to
help me to give me knowledge ease which
i am sharing with my friend with
students with everybody in the world at
thank internet society Thank nano Hank
Aaron I think everybody were present
here thank you
thanks very much
there any comments or questions if not
we all will move on to our next
presenter which