hi my name is Manish courier I work at
merrick networks today I'll be talking
about a problem that has been coming up
as a sort of an undertone to a lot of
discussions in the hallways and at the
meeting here over the past in a couple
of years at least essentially the the
problem that I'm trying to going to talk
about is how do we go about improving
the accuracy of data in the routing
registry such as our ATV so roughly what
I'm going to talk about is I'm going to
talk about an ongoing project that we
have that's attempting to rebuild the
RIT be at least a client side of things
not not a whole lot of changes on the
server and but at least a client
interface to provide a whole lot of more
information to the users so that they
can they can try to they have bit more
information available to them to keep
their their route objects up to date and
in particular of what we're doing is
including both route object checks which
are internal to the registry as well as
providing a link with a live internet
route feed so once again we're providing
this link which has always been missing
which is you have registered right
objects on one hand and then the actual
information that's get that gets routed
on the internet on the other hand and
the two are never never linked or never
put together in the same place and what
we're hoping is by making this link
people will have this information where
they can they can update their objects
and keep them up to date and it's
basically the motivation which we're
providing them if you provide this
motivation you get better feedback and
you have better control of what you're
doing so some background quick
background information about the RDV
it's based on the ird software which is
available for free download but the RDP
service is more than that what we're
doing with the router in registry is
make prefix policy information publicly
available to be
community the registered objects are in
our psl format which is a standard
format and these days or up till now the
process of using the RDV has been you
create a maintainer account and you go
register your route objects a two-step
process and then if you need to do
updates to the you you send email to a
specific email address with the right
format and it updates your route objects
or you can go through a website and
update your route objects that way the
the big drawbacks with this whole
process up till now has been there was
no feedback to the user during the whole
process other than simple error checking
on your syntax is not right and the
other problem up till now has been that
there was no relationship between what
you registered and what was actually be
routed on the Internet so we're where
we've started the erd bng project at
merit and what it does is it essentially
provides a portal based route object
maintenance framework and what you do
when you have a portal a system as you
you you minimize the information that
the user sees to specifically the
objects that they've registered and you
make it easy for them to add delete and
modify registry objects you make it easy
for them to examine what they have
registered and you provide quick summary
information so they have a rough idea of
how they are using the rdb and we also
provide feedback on inconsistencies that
we observe so what are some of the
internal consistency checks that we
perform here's two examples of what we
have implemented so far we do
consistency checks which where we
generate lists of all route objects that
do not have a matching object and then
we'll make a make a recommendation to a
drop-down list saying hey you don't have
a corresponding object which we think
you should have and would you like to
add it now another example of an
internal consistency check that we do is
we generate lists of all prefixes that
have multiple route objects now this may
be something that you intended but more
than likely you probably did and we give
the user the option of going ahead and
deleting the redundant route object so
once again you can keep your information
up-to-date the second type of
consistency checks that we perform our
with the loud
with the live Internet routing feet and
here's a an example of the sort of
things we look for for example we
generate list of all the renounce routes
for your registered autonomous systems
we generate list of all unregistered
routes basically these are routes that
were seen in the rug table but you do
not have a corresponding route object
for the this is one of the main
advantage of the portal based system is
we have a very good idea of what your
specific information is and then when we
go do these comparisons the results
we're generating back are for your your
specifics account another example is we
generate list of all the announced route
object so you know I registered you know
200 objects and here's a list of all the
ones that are actually being announced
right now and so you know if there's any
inconsistent there inconsistency there
you can go back and correct your BGP
feet or you can go up go back and update
your ID be objects and we also generate
a list of unannounced objects just in
case you you that was not your intent
you would have the information there to
modify that information and lastly one
of the the important checks we've also
added is the alerting system which which
looks at the update messages as they're
as they're coming in on a BGP feed and
does originates checks and provides that
feeds this information back to the rdb
portal and you can quickly see any
prefix hijacks or misconfigurations that
you might have done so let me provide a
good example of what quick example of
what the the new interface looks like
right now we're looking at the object
information page this is the first thing
that you see when you log in on the top
you have summary information it lists
all of the the route objects that are
registered for your maintainer ID
providing summary counts on the on the
bottom left we have drop-down lists
which which are prefixed lists
essentially of all these are the
drop-down lists which lets you select
which which object you would like to see
the information for and then finally on
the right you will see
details of what you've selected to view
and and you have a button right there to
edit or delete this information the
second tab is the consistency check once
again on the Left we see a summary table
which is a breakdown / yes object that
you have registered of what are the
announced routes unannounced routes
announced objects break down into by
broken down by numbers on the top again
you have the drop down list which lists
each of these entries so you can select
which one you want to view the detailed
information up things like multiple
entries missing odna mob jects
unregistered routes the drop down list
will let you select which one of these
you want to view more information on and
finally on the bottom right you will
actually see that the the exact object
as its registered in the ra DB and you
have the option of editing deleting or
adding information and finally the
alerting which is the feedback coming
from a live update bgp update feed and
what you're seeing over here is the on
the top left you see you see alerts
where for your prefixes the a s and the
routing table was different from the es
that was registered in the Reeb and then
you will also see a table that lists
what might be apparent misconfigurations
are in your part where your ass on
announcing some some some prefixes but
in the routing table there they're shown
up showing up as belonging to somebody
else or in the RIT be there shown as
belonging to somebody else so finally a
quick summary of what we've developed is
an integrated framework that provides
easy to use interface to keep routing
registry data data up-to-date it
includes feedback from various
consistency checks and what we've
actually done here is try to build the
missing link between live Internet
routing data and the are a DB and if you
are we're currently in beta test we're
hoping to have this go live by the end
of the month and if you'd like a test
account please send me email any
questions
thanks