ya think that was all okay so i will
carry on with this I used to have right
flap damping in this tutorial as a
highly recommended skilling technique
until about four or five years ago when
I stopped putting it in as good thing
and now put it in as a bad thing so so
many years it was actually strongly
encouraged pretty much from 95 96 97 98
we considered right flap that being
pretty good thing to do really what was
going on and Internet ISPs were probably
announcing the customers they were dial
in connect four short time and answer /
24 grab email hang up and then three
minutes later doll and a man would do
its stuff and pull again for email so
we'd see a lot of churning of / 24 on
the network usually caused by dial on
demand or something similar and it was
overwhelming our poor old slow routers
that we had back in the in the mid-90s
and so right flat damping basically came
in to try and mitigate some of this
issue well more recent years you know
there's been studies research would ever
been done to show that bright flat
damping actually slows network
convergence and does a lot of other evil
nasty things so I'll come to those a
little bit later on but I'll just cover
through go through right fat damping as
it is first and then we'll look at the
badness so right flap by definition is
basically they going up and down of a
path or a change in an attribute yes and
a change in an attribute that was one
thing that was often overlooked by a lot
of service providers so in other words
if there's a bgp withdraw followed by an
update that was counted as one flap or
if a bgp attribute changed that was
counted as one flap to ripples through
the entire internet and it wastes CPU
why should somebody rebooting the router
in the south of Chile impact your router
it should matter it's many a s hops away
it's in a different side of the planet
so it shouldn't have to impact your
network that's a sort of thing that we
were seeing when our backbone back in
the mid-90s basically somebody could do
something weird and other side of the
planet and would have a nerd
split impact on our infrastructure so
fat damping came along pretty much
everybody want to do it and lots of back
of beer mats designs were done in
various ITF meetings and nanos and so
forth implementation fully described in
RFC 24-39 basically we want fast
convergence for normal right changes
trying to use history predict the future
so if history shows stable prefix it's
likely to stay stable if if history
shows prefix bunches up in downloads
it's likely to carry on doing that we
want to suppress oscillating routes but
advertise the stable ones and
implementation details manisa iOS
numbers that probably same or different
for your implementation penalty of 1,000
for each flap change in attribute gets a
penalty of 500 people often overlook
that and they were going well my prefix
is not flapping but yeah I'm changing
the community every now and then well if
you change your community that's a
change in attribute and that gets a flap
so that wasn't very pleasant we have
exponential decay the penalty there's a
half life rate if you've done physics or
whatever at school you'll know what all
this is about but basically it
exponentially the case like this when
the penalty goes over suppressed limit
prefix was suppressed when the prefix
goes under the penalty goes under a
reuse limit and will be realized
pictures worth a thousand words it would
work something like that so in other
words this is time along the bottom this
is the penalty here prefix flaps its
flap three times penalties to thousands
it's gone above the suppress limit so
the prefix get suppressed kind of zone
flapping until somebody figures out
what's wrong we then get the exponential
decay down to this reuse limit and then
the prefix gets riad ver tised notice
three flaps is in a fairly short time
this is a very long time okay so
typically the implementations for flat
damping you could flat three times then
disappear for an hour which you know
it's it's you know it's it was deemed
suitable punishment for flapping
prefixes at the time it's pretty hard to
explain to customers that well yeah you
saw you flap your prefix three times
you're not getting internet for now
okay it's a bit ly can you switch off
the electricity in your house and the
electricity company doesn't give you
supply for another day just because you
flick the switch so it's anyway so it
was quite punitive don't Lee applied to
inbound announcements from ebgp peers
and only the path had actually flapped
got punished so if the backup path store
worked then while you would have best
path selection that would use the backup
and your various values that you could
tweak so you could tune the flap damping
to pretty much whatever you want
unfortunately most isp's just chose to
use fender defaults and that was part of
the reason for the death of flap damping
so anyway first implementations on
internet right about 1995 vendor
defaults with too severe I mean first
implementation was on iOS very severe
defaults but then in Cisco's defense
what enough should anybody use you ask
to deploy something what should good
numbers actually be so the ripe routing
working group tried to figure out what
good number should be so right 178
document was the first attempt at trying
to produce some sensible visor / 24 s
got hit really hard 22 and 23 s got hit
a little bit and everything else pretty
much got left or alone because the
minimum allocation that the registers
were handing out brand about those days
was a / 19 or a / 20 so we didn't want
to punish those ripe to 10 what did ripe
210 do i forgot i think ripe do to not
know right yeah right to 10 introduce
the root nameservers because we thought
well it's probably not a very good idea
to flat damp the root nameservers and
then write to 29 introduced and
configuration examples for cisco juniper
foundry and a few others as far think
those do we have I forgot Benway was a
few vendor examples as well and as a
nice website you go to an all the rest
unfortunately in spite of the working
groups best efforts many isps just
switched on the vendor defaults because
well they looked in the Cisco or juniper
manual and said what to do and that's
what they did those no mention of actual
the ripe writing working group work and
then we had folks like more lamar
and tim Griffin and Craig Lebovitz
neighborhood sure Andy Bush looking at
well impacts of flat damping just
amongst other things so certainly more
than Mao's work right flap damping
exacerbates Internet routing convergence
she actually was showing that
convergence Lord if you implemented flat
damping Tim Griffin's what's the sound
of one Road flapping supposes meant to
be copying the name of the what's the
sound of one hand clapping the book but
anyway what's the sound of one road
flapping and it's a lot it's a lot more
than anybody ever expected and Bob you
know Abba who just work was well known
and she probably para need a lot of this
looking at what the routing table was
actually doing in the back in those days
and then Randy was looking at well
what's the chance of getting packets
across the internet and you came to
think hundred percent but it wasn't
really that and part of the side effects
of his analysis was what's all this flap
damping going on here why all these
prefixes being amplified and all the
rest so it actually looked quite scary
problem one path flaps well bgp speakers
pick the branch next best pathway an
answer to all peers flat count is
incremented that's fine the PRC a change
in path will guess what happened path
changes attribute changes they all
increment the fat counter as well now
for a few hops pse multiple changes and
all come from different places to your
flat counters are going berserk so I
didn't really believe this but mean I
was doing yes when I started off doing
my multi-homing things about 2000 2001
helping some ISPs multi-home announced
once / 24 but ten minutes later went to
write views and has a flat 15 times on
right fusion is like okay I've just
announced this prefix how can it flat 15
times and then of course you look at all
the work am I cited on the previous
slide and that's exactly what they saw
for the very very similar reasons
different beachfl implementations have
different transit time for prefixes okay
so some of them have got this minimum
right advertisement intervals select
hold on to prefix before they pass it on
others don't so you've got this race to
the finish line so if your prefixes run
through an old juniper network will get
their time a they run through an all
cisco network we get there
time be if the run through a 50-50 Cisco
juniper network or a s path the get time
see time d and all the rest so you've
got this avalanche of announcements all
writing at different times and so of
course the end site see this is multiple
flaps solution don't use right flap
damping very easy just don't do it
anywhere at all because it will
unnecessarily impair access to the
network and to the Internet now I'm
going to show you some stuff in and
probably about 20 minutes time or so
which probably makes us think that we
really need to revisit this flat damping
thing but we need to revisit in a way
that actually makes it work for us I
mean a right routing working group we
did ripe 378 which basically explained
the last few slides like what the
problems are what not to do and
basically just don't do flat damping at
all so if you're still running flat
damping probably should go home and just
switch it off because it's not doing you
any favors some people still ask me
should I still do this was my customers
well if your customers talking bgp to
you and they flap the prefix well that's
probably their issue but but if it's if
they've only got one router miss talking
bgp to you it's unlikely they're going
to flap a prefix what they're going to
do is shut the bgp session down and
that's not kind of as a flap anyway so
there's probably not much benefit there
but certainly fab riding transit to any
autonomous systems you really don't want
to do right flat damping at all as it is
implemented today okay using communities
so here's some examples of how I espèce
will use communities I kind of
introduced communities before this is
another scaling technique it's not a
specific bgp scaling technique but it's
useful for helping isp scale their
network operation first thing is the no
recommended isp communities the new isp
bgp communities at all as I've seen 1998
which is really just Tony Bates and crew
at internet MCI back in those days just
saying hey we use these communities to
do this and they wrote it down back in
the doors those days when you just write
stuff down and out of season it was
the defy standard communities i
mentioned earlier there were efforts
made to document them so there was that
draft that's what UCL in belgium so that
was a bgp community survey which only
ever got to the first draft stage but
doesn't really be nothing else folks
that wanna see a documenting isp
communities as they come across them
which is good and then of course there
was the nano tutorial nano 40 was it
gone who did it I think was Richard
steenburgen I think I'm Nanak 40
tutorial which basically showed some of
the typical communities that is PSU's so
again was another nice attempt to trying
to document what was going what was
going on or what is going on I speak
public policy is usually published
sometimes it goes on the website usually
in an Operations page or something like
that or maybe the BGP peering page or or
bgp setup page to all the pans some of
them actually put it in an Internet
routing registry some ISPs actually use
that and you'll see what the community
policy is in there sort of throw in some
examples up on the screen those of you
at the back are going of real problem
seeing this one but you can go to
sprint's website and you can find out
what they actually do some of you the
front agron of real problems you've been
reading this and but you know for
example this one here says 65 or 1 colon
XXX and it says do a single s path
prepend of 1239 towards a s XXX so if
you send these communities they 6500 for
callin XXX towards sprint viewer if
you're a customer of theirs or peer of
layers they will do a 4 x prepend ave s
1 239 when you announce that prefix
towards a XXX that can be handy i mean
if you want to do some traffic engineer
view if you want to sprint for your
major traffic between them and you but
you don't want them for your major
traffic die nowhere else why you can do
or four times prepend towards wherever
then ever else is or you can do the same
thing in asia or you can do the same
thing in europe and so forth okay and
they the list appears that they have
there
the communities that are supported there
so you can go and configure this as you
as you wish more info on the website as
I said apt this is an Australia this is
what used to be connect now bought by a
PT they've got some communities they
listed in the routing registry here so
for example 2764 colon to if you send an
app that community on the prefixes you
announce to them they will only
announced this prefix within the local
pop they will not send it anywhere else
at all if you send them to 7 64 call and
for they will local the law preference
local preference by 15 remember what I
said about Amy DS not really being used
anymore well this is the alternative you
send this community here and they will
lower the meed on that particular path
from the default of 100 285 so in other
words giving you the same effect as
sending em Edie's okay who else small
verizon business in Europe I've no idea
what verizon business in the u.s. do but
this is a s7 or to anybody who's
associate with a s72 will know these as
I know them similar to 8a state local
pref 80 within a s7 or two so if you as
a customer of 70 to send them 72 cullen
ATM your announcements they will set
local privately on those prefixes all
they will set local pref 120 on those
prefixes so again it works like m.ed
does or used to do you send them that
community and why the raise the local
pref or lower the local prep so useful
for traffic engineering and 702 colon
one does a single pre pants under 22
does double prepay and 7 or 23 does
triple prepend these seem to be very
common not only verizon does these quite
a few other eyes piece i know do these
ones so i think these they're pretty
much even though they're not standard
that pretty much industry de facto
standard values that have been used and
the various other ones i'm not going to
go through them all but you can see the
examples here do different pre pens and
lance mints in different regions and so
forth BTW ignite this is the past.more
worldwide network but definitely
european network and typically many
years ago had a hugely complex set of
communities which I thought were great
you don't seem to have them anymore but
BTW ignite borrowed them and so they
have implemented them like this and so
you look at them again if you look in
the AS object and the ripe routing
registry you'll see things like 5400
colon 1000 if you attach that to a
prefix they will not announce it to any
of their peers or transits or if you
send them 5400 call in two thousand
they'll do a single prepend or 5402 all
their peers or transits okay and then
you've got the transit providers here so
I mean if you want not don't want to
announce the prefix towards sprint you
send in that community if you don't want
an answer towards AT&T you send that
community and so forth have a look at
the AR subject it's a huge list pretty
sophisticated list and I'm sure some of
you could borrow this for your own
network as well so you as a customer
send these communities to bt ignite they
will do what they say up there level 3
we've got time very complex one again if
you look in the right providing registry
you'll see this one for es 3356 summer
stuff you know the do single pre-paint
appears the juice per single pre pan to
particular AS that's supported they will
do set local press 70 80 90 pretty
similar to the m ed ideas there's the
black hole 13 356 color 9999 i was
explaining to somebody during the break
this is wonderful i wish every isp would
do this if you're being attacked as a
customer of level 3 you basically send
your prefix that's being attacked / 32
with this community tagged onto it and
level 3 will basically sync the traffic
for that address space into the
distributed sinkhole network it's pretty
neat it's a way of stopping were not
stopping the DOS attack but keeping the
DOS attack out of your your down link to
your network if morais peace around the
world did this and we mean much easier
to work to try and defeat some of these
dos attacks on the group but that's
that's what level 3 actually supports
which is really nice um okay so those
are some examples you can find a whole
heap more
sitting around on the network so check
with your upstream provider see if they
support communities at least some like
this because it can be really useful for
you doing a traffic engineering I
generally put this in the multi-homing
tutorial but I've added into this one
because people always ask me at the
break okay what about communities for
external bgp don't we do those as well
so i throw in the men for this this
presentation as well just so you see how
they how they work so let's get on to
the second piece deploying bgp learned
all about it what do we do well look at
the role of bgp versus the igps first
sumagot igps interior routing protocols
ious is an ospf for pretty much the
favorites these days the service
provider space you don't see many isps
using much else if you look at
enterprise space things a little bit
different eigrp tends to be the
overwhelming favorite but some of us PF
but very much for the service provider
space I esaias and ospf seem to be dead
heat in popularity the use for carrying
infrastructure addresses your router
loot bags your point-to-point links
within your infrastructure and that is
all nothing else full stop okay design
goal for most are ESPYs is to minimize
the number prefix is carried in the IGP
so you don't put internet prefixes there
you do not redistribute from bgp into
iOS is even though the command exists
does not mean it's a good thing to do do
not go whining to your vendor that you
cannot do it again it does or doesn't
work properly or your router crashes an
igp is not intended to carry 270,000
prefixes don't put your customers there
either a lot of people still seem to
think yeah we'll drop our customers into
ospf then will redistribute ospf into
bgp at the border and hey everything
will work just nicely well i'm sure
something will work with you got if
you've got 10 customers but when you've
got 10,000 it may not work so well
convergence of your network will really
be severely impacted so most design
goals are to minimize the number of
prefixes in igp put them all into bgp
we've seen this before the first half
you've got ibgp annie bgp
treat them as different routing
protocols with different aims in life
and then you won't go far wrong I'm
going to come back to that particular
theme a little bit later on when I start
one of my favorite rents okay ibgp
that's where you put your customer
prefixes I bgb put your internet
prefixes the prefix you laughing appears
in your transit in their ebgp is what
you exchange or what you use to exchange
prefixes with other autonomous systems
okay what goes in ebgp is not
necessarily the same as what goes on I
bgp that's the model we've seen that
before do not do not distribute bgp into
or spare for iOS yes the command exists
doesn't mean it works very well don't
distribute IGP into bgp yes the command
exists but it probably won't work so
well either you probably cause bgp to go
into frenzy because ospf an IRS IRS
change very rapidly and a lot bgp does
not like change so if you want bgp
process to go more gobble a lot of your
cpu carry on redistributed don't use an
igp to carry customer prefixes if you
don't do any of these things you met
with will not scale goods i mean i'm not
just saying because i'm standing up here
saying that this is like the experience
over the last 15 years of seeing eyes
peas build the networks this is the
really only way to try and get scalable
networks to function putting prefixes
into ibgp well I bgp Gary's customer
prefixes don't use ospf is ours journey
point a static towards the customer
interface network statement put the
network into the bgp process network
statement we distribute whatever you
want to do however you do it you want to
try and also avoid ibgp flaps one leaf
still frequently asked questions is why
bgp churning a lot can we get flap
damping for ibgp please no you cannot
okay and the reason I say no you cannot
just because well if your network design
is broken then well you're fixing it
without yet another feature in BGP is
really not
the right way interface flap generally
means if you re distributing say from a
static route into BG people interface
goes down while the static towards the
customer disappears so the prefix gets
withdrawn from ibgp if you're a small
network this probably doesn't matter so
much the big network you have loads of
customers bring up and down all the time
you probably don't want your interfaces
to flap so certainly the some ways ganda
planning implementation to ensure that
the static route is hardwired so it's
always in the routing table so that
you'll never get a flap in the I bgp
aggregation quality or quantity
aggregation means announcing the address
block you see from the registry to other
a SS connect to your network I always
kind of thought at me I maybe have been
in this business far too long but I
always thought this was kind of obvious
but it doesn't seem to be obvious
anymore these days sub prefixes of
aggregate can be announced internally
nice p network obviously you're going to
give sub prefix to your customers maybe
24 s 23 is 27 29 s those all go into
your ibgp you're being a known sub
prefixes to other a SS to assist with
multihoming as well ok now the sub
prefix is your 9 stayed with multihoming
stealing from the multi-homing tutorial
that sometimes do it's not a case so if
you take your address block and jump it
up in the smallest piece as possible and
just spray it out there and hope
something works ok you actually need to
do some proper engineering to try and
figure out where things should go how
they should go careful work but
unfortunately too many people still
thinking about class sees or something
or other and the chopping the address
space they received under 2 / 24 as you
see in a few slides but no it's getting
close for sixty percent of the routing
table today is made up of / 24 s quite
incredible address block should be
announced to the Internet as an
aggregate sub prefixes should not be
announced at all unless we're trying to
do traffic engineering more later while
laters when I next talk about that
aggregate should be generated internally
some people's generate aggregate in the
border router which is generally fine if
the border router is
within your network physically if the
border out of somewhere remote connected
by thin string to your backbone well
that thing's string breaks you still
generate your egra gate and your backup
doesn't no longer works if you get a
backup path some other way while your
body route is still announcing the
aggregate so it gets round internet
close to where your wallet on traffic
comes back sees the best path is via
your border router traffic comes into
the border router it has no best path
anymore so it drops everything on the
floor being there done that many times
so try in January aggregates within the
core of the network rather than out at
the edge and you save cutting yourself
off announcing an aggregate well I hope
you don't want aggregate are held in
general pool regard by community at
least by some parts of the community
other parts of community don't seem to
care very much at all they're quite
happy to go spending the hard-earned
dollars at the vendors buying really
really expensive memory or really really
expensive router upgrades the registries
published the minimum allocation size
again it's anything from a / 22 22
depending on the registry in a panic
just well month ago went down to / 22
minimum allocation now I think Aaron is
still a / 20 so it'll be different from
different registry regions and will be
different for different address blocks
as well ap makes minimum for example
used to be a / 19 a few years ago so you
still see some address blocks / 19 where
others are now appearing as a / 22 so
there should really be not much reason
for seeing many prefixes longer than a /
22 you would have thought but the more
than hundred forty-one thousand / 24
aggregation example this is this is some
of the stuff that I see that going on to
try and explain to people why
aggregations actually recently important
so customers go / 23 s when hundreds got
a / 19 address block and what does the
s100 do they go ooh I'm running BGP
while I'm very clever and what they do
is every time the handler address space
to the customer they announced it by the
ebgp out to the world and if you don't
think many people do that today or yes
they do go and have a look at the
routing table pick
random is you will see loads of this
loads and loads and loads they basically
leaked the ibgp out to the internet and
they don't think about it see what's the
problem the internet carries everything
no it's all life is all good and
everything's working just fine well here
is there just fine custom link goes down
23 network becomes unreachable it's
withdrawn from the ibgp OSP doesn't send
any aggregates out at all because who
aggregate who that's going to take up
memory in my router so they don't 23
Network withdrawals announced appears
all 20 9400 tournament systems in
internet will see less withdraw I did
load and all the internet backbone
rioters custom link returns he comes
back next days which is router back on
and of course when you switch a router
back on you'd want your network to work
mean you pretty much you'd walk into
room you switch on the lights and they
work you come back from a day's work at
the office come into your house switch
on the lights you expect them to work
don't you but doesn't happen here the 23
is riad ver ties to peers goes into ibgp
renounce to ebgp peers starts ripping
through the internet load on the
backbone rioters some ice peace is
building flat damping all eyes peas some
using different vendors you call this
different race to the finish line was
talking about before the break flat
damping coming in previous gets flagged
suppressed for 30 minutes 16 minutes
longer depending people use defaults or
not internet may take 10 or 20 minutes
or longer to be visible and may be bumpy
for the next hour or so where's the
quality of service okay customers trying
to browse the net download his email
finds that nothing works phones as iOS P
is P says I know what you're talking
about while working fine here go reboot
your PC you see this happen so often and
actually its isp basically not being
very good or being incompetent basically
because I thought it boils down to every
time the customer prefix flaps the whole
world gets to see this particular impact
and it does happen i've got some
examples coming up extraordinary example
here's a good example i mean if people
just did it of aggregation so the ISPs
100 January's is aggregate census
aggregate artist customer gets a / 23
link goes down
is withdrawn from ibgp the aggregates
still announced nothing happens customer
come back next days which is writer on
23 is re-injected into the ibgp son they
can see low internet this is how it
should work so why do a lot of people
think this one this example is no
different from the previous example I
mean I do to a lot of the world and I do
this slide and people come up to me well
it's very nice example I have to
understand what you mean by the
differences here I don't understand why
it's different many isps need to become
customers of themselves a thing to
actually understand what some of these
these things are actually impacting
because they don't you know the
customers out for now they don't receive
thing really think about it they sit in
an arc they get the connectivity their
foot works okay for their in customer as
well good examples pretty much what
everybody should be doing okay diced
internet stability reduce the size of
the writing-table reduces writing shown
and it generally improves the qos for
everybody people get so obsessed but
doing rate limiting and package shaping
and all the rest they can't even get the
basic qos stuff like this actually
ensuring that people can use the network
when they want to actually working and
why do we have this bad example mean is
it laziness lack of knowledge some cases
lack of knowledge gently is just
laziness people don't understand the
difference in ibgp and ebgp and so forth
but look at the table today well this
wasn't today this was about four days
ago when i did the with the slides
together 270,000 153 prefixes i think
it's about two hundred seventy thousand
nine hundred and my view now it's gone
up about six hundred and last three days
I do aggregation this is analysis stuff
that I do i take the routing table and
aggregated so as as it what it could be
if everybody else did aggregation and it
pulls it down 130,000 prefixes right so
i could actually have a bgp feed 130,000
prefixes and lose new information
whatsoever so there's 140,000 prefixes
of junk that's quite a lot how much
memory does that take up what is it cost
to buy it from your favorite vendors and
and while now doing for aggregation mean
that there's a lot of people subdivide
prefixes but yeah I mean pinups are
important more for sure I put a lot of
people who are not actually doing the
pinups either there's simply leaking
ibgp out to the world I mean you can
have a look at the BGP table just to see
it so yeah I mean I suppose I'm arguing
for both things yes I'm pointing out
what happens if you don't have the
pull-up riots but yeah / 24 s announcers
was saying hundred forty-one thousand of
them people quite happy to blame or it's
all caused by our network 19 2 / 8 which
was the original Class C from years and
years ago 1 or 2 / 8 is the best behaved
of all the / eights around it's been
about five and a half thousand prefixes
for probably would last ten years okay
it's the best behave the rest of them
are very very messy so twenty-nine
thousand four hundred onimous systems as
I said so after maxim after aggregation
me this is aggressive aggregation mean
I'm sure the routing table won't be
quite as aggregated as that but if I
aggregate by origin es I can pull it
down to 130,000 prefixes and so I don't
know if call this a new swamp space in
the old days we had swamp space which
was 19 2 / 8 1 or 2 / 8 was a mess
certainly not long and you know 94 95 it
really was a big mess because what
happened pre cider was is peace were
getting blocks out of 192 so they were
getting blocks of class sees and the big
effort to reduce the swamp in 1 & 2 / 8
was to get people to aggregate these
blocks this is all happen now if you
look through 192 it's actually pretty
tidy it's looking in some of the other
blocks things are not so tidy so this is
1999 when I started poking around in all
this so
these are all the slash eats that are
now have been assigned to the registries
the five registries today so if you look
through them that's actually not a lot
happening mean 192 / 8 even when 99 was
66 sorry 6300 so it's dropped about 500
prefixes from nine years ago live a look
at 193 / 8 2390 prefixes unit was the
first one that the ripe NCC got it was
the first ibis blocker used in Europe
and was sitting around 2,400 prefixes
for many many many years there has been
fully allocated for goodness knows how
long so watch that one as it moves over
to the next next slide 22 / 8 was AP
next first address block Bob it was kind
of is a bit funny it was actually a
unique they got a fair chunk of that
address space and Telstra for a long
time announced I think was 22 / 12 or 11
or something like that so suddenly in 99
it was nice and tidy 2276 prefixes two
or three also was ap- prefixes fully
allocated and this blocks in 1999 so
what has changed between 99 and now so
if we look at well one min 2 / 8 total
prefixes 6929 that's not changed very
much 193 sashayed gone up to 6220 what
exactly has changed I mean that's a
fully allocated block from the ripe NCC
why does it need to be disintegrated so
much but these two are amazing 2 a 2 / 8
is now almost 11,000 prefixes and
through 3 / 8 was eleven thousand
prefixes exactly okay and you look back
in 99 fully allocated that size today
they've gone up to that so that's quite
amazing if you look at most of the rest
on the round about five thousand or so
so you look through all here ones that
are fully allocated time to be hitting
around about five or six thousand ok so
these this is really what's grown so the
registry blocks are contributing about
eighty-nine percent of the Internet
routing table that's actually being
consistent if we go back to
februari again the registry blocks are
contributing eighty-eight percent of the
writing-table so this also means that
the other address space the legacy
address face is also being d aggregated
as well um so yeah showing creeping the
aggregation I know I'm just kind of
waiting my hands but you know pursuing
5,000 prefixes once fully allocated we
could end up with maybe 440,000 prefix
in the BGP table and of the remaining 39
allocate unallocated / 8 we could
probably end up I know this is just
complete waving my hands in there maybe
eight and a half thousand so 850,000
prefixes in the BGP table how much
memory do you need to handle that so
people probably should start thinking
about that when we would be fully
allocated probably three years from now
maybe sooner so I don't think these
numbers are really that far away and
suddenly few look at the graph of the
growth of the table which is somewhere
coming you'll see that the growth is is
accelerating um yeah so rested address
basis is showing this D aggregation also
and what are the justifications of a
traffic engineering now a lot of traffic
engineering is really well thought out
but people take the address space and
may be divided into two three four five
pieces there's a lot of other traffic
engineering that simply take an address
space chopping into 24 23 s or something
like that and it doesn't really seem to
have very good justification for it I
looked at this when Jeff Houston does
similar analysis work based around on
his website I mean I did this fun well
as you see actober two years ago and I
found that it's probably about thirty
five percent saving as possible simply
by throwing away all the traffic
engineering information so i suppose the
remedies using the the nokia community
we probably could we use the routing
table fairly noticeably okay um anyway
so excuses tend to be like well traffic
engineering probably caused about ten
percent it's a real traffic engineering
that you we can't avoid and
as deliberate the aggregation with
people just announcing lots of small
prefixes on the same path with or
without covering aggregates and for no
reason apart from they think is good fun
and they can do it and other people
accept it so efforts to improve will
have been loads of efforts to improve
it's not as though word just all
standing here cahoots terrible terrible
the side report was the first one side
report actually started off trying to
encourage people to move to classless
routing from the old class flow right so
I was trying to encourage people who got
legacy 192 space to actually join the
groups of 24 s they had into bigger
announcements so Tony Bates started that
off I think you sold ripe ncc when he
started it but he carried on when he was
in turn MCI and when he was at Cisco and
then he handed over to me and then I
handed it over to Jeff so it's all got a
nice website a lot of work at Jeff put
into it www side report org and it
generally lists a whole heap of things
but includes the list of 30 of service
providers or autonomous systems who
could do better at aggregating we're
also the right routing working group
less is mike hughes and my fault along
with rob evans from you karna was the
right 399 document which basically
looked at some of the causes of
aggregation and try to encourage eyes
peas to actually consider bar announcing
aggregate and can be more considerate
when doing traffic engineering so we
documented a lot of the current
practices and so forth so that's in the
right 399 document it's been translated
into spanish was it last year think that
was done and by three days ago it's been
translated in japanese so the internal
internationalization folks at jan org
actually did that work so for our
Japanese speakers here and you can go
read all about it in Japanese as well
and if you feel brave you can compare
with English versions and see how well
it's mapped across if anybody else wants
to translate into any other languages
you're very welcome to do so
anyway so the side to report the website
allows searches and computations of
aggregation to be made on a pas basis so
there's actually a tool in there you can
pop the a s number in and find out
things about it for it so let's look
through the website quickly so going to
the homepage side report org so you can
see for Jeff's view is where is the
282,000 prefixes he sees which is a wee
bit more than I see I'm seeing my view
is at dixie and Japan Jeff's one is what
he gets from where did he get it from I
think you might get it from Telstra
still or reach or somebody similar kind
of a s numbers and so forth so that
gation summary so here like the top
announcements into the internet so let's
see I think this is ordered by net gain
so the service provider that could
contribute most to the size of the
routing table at least help reduce it
most is the China education and research
Network who are currently announcing
5033 prefixes but if aggregated could
reduce it to 880 so eighty-two percent
reduction possible number two is
bellsouth number three is quest number
through is paetec number five is cox
tata communications there well number
two in asia for the aggregation so
that's vsnl or yeah which is basically
India national ISP with that a s
pathways cable provider in India uni-net
where they mexico i think cox
communication and so on through the list
so there's a there the savings that
could be made with bigger efforts that
folks trying to do some aggregation i
should mention that chinanet used to be
fairly high up on this list where are
they now
is nice not that one needs to be on this
list used to be pretty close to the top
on the list and I think I'd given this
presentation in front of the folks once
too often but that's this sat down and
worked really hard to do a fairly
substantial amount of aggregation so it
can be done mean I know it was like a
six-month project that they were
involved and to try and prove things
they basically got I think there was a /
12 worth of address space was chopped
down and about 19 20 21 and it was done
/ province / city in each province and
we're looking at like a large number of
cities in each province and none of it
was aggregated so they aggregate in a
provincial level and on a national level
and they're pretty much disappeared from
from this list so it is possible to to
tidy up so we've top 20 arrives at a top
20 withdrawn more specifics so like c CR
nett announcing 4054 more specific so
they've got covering aggregate they're
just announcing all the specifics as
well and so you can see that in the list
also so I've picked at random or hear
static communications because this
appears number one in Asia and I spend a
lot of time in Asia obviously because I
live there this one features quite a lot
in my bgp presentations but you look at
the sort of things that being an ounce
mean 24 is 21 is 24 24 21 and they're
contiguous okay they're basically and
when I I've seen an ibgp feed from them
as well guess what it looks exactly the
same right it's when I'm don't want to
cast aspersions but I basically believe
there are no filters between a s4 755
and outside world at all whatever they
have in ibgp just goes whoops just goes
straight out there and so the side
report mean you can put the asn and will
tell you look your 1951 to 160 / 14 you
can withdraw all these prefixes
everything in red could be withdrawn
quite easily no loss of routing
information whatsoever and covered well
I always put this one in but again it
shows a lot of the possibilities
announcing loads and loads of 23 and 24
could all be aggregated into the / 16
that it comes out off quite easily
so we put your own s number in there and
you can see what it's doing anyway so
size of routing tables so people have
said well memory is not a problem the
vendors have come along so yeah we'll
give you four gig of ram in your routers
well that's fine you can spare the
expensive prices for it to North all the
rest yes 1 million prefixes have been
tested in the lab 2 million prefixes
it's all going to be great what about
convergence how long does the CPU
actually take to handle 1 million prefix
in the BGP table especially if they all
change you want to change the next hops
sure we can throw faster processes and
all the rest in but it all takes a
finite time why is all this necessary
and you can speed things up simply by
not having to handle a lot of this this
junk so Jeff actually started about two
years ago this bgp and stability report
so you looks at the instabilities in the
routing system and this makes
interesting reading don't have good your
mental arithmetic is but have a look at
this one is 95 83 is generating 276,000
updates per month you divide that out
and how many updates per minute it is i
think when i did the numbers it's like
three a minute so the sending three
updates per minute from that is so
that's from satyam in philosophy in
india we list some was the ears 1803 ICM
sprint is basically miles away in
comparison or CR nett and china they pop
up again 100 hundred thousand updates
per month so these are the sort of
instabilities there's some really
amazingly bad ones this this one hasn't
been quite so bad but some days you look
at this it's just extraordinary amount
of instabilities there but we're looking
at like updates many updates per hour
coming from particular autonomous
systems if you look at prefixes
themselves the most bouncy prefix in the
world at the moment is 192 212 that 120
/ 24 which is 78,000 updates per month
so that would be walk one every two
minutes so does that sound like down on
demand all day down on the man but I
don't know how things can update every
two minutes it just doesn't seem
seem feasible but we should damp that
completely and that's the point a lot of
the folks they will be looking at flat
damping is saying flat damping should be
done totally not per path and you can't
configure total flat damping on any of
our routers than normal now I think we
really nice me I would like to try it if
I can have a knob to actually do flat
damping sort of any prefix flaps it's
all gone completely utterly and
absolutely that's what I would like to
see but I only work for a vendor it
needs customers to actually get features
done I can't get anything done at all so
if you if you think that flat damping
should be done absolutely please go and
beg to your favorite vendor to get them
to do it because i think that would
would actually make a big difference and
stop a lot of this stuff because when
you look at it means SiFi is causing a
lot of it and it's not that I haven't
spoken to them about it either okay
anyway so that that's tracking the
updates the instabilities in the routing
system note this is the view from I
think it's pretty much from the tail
stress network in Australia it will be
different in different parts of the
world so I need to check with Jeff is
actually not here in the second half but
I need to check a Jeff where what views
he actually gets to see these
instabilities but if any way you want to
track it in your part of the world and
sure be delighted anyway so aggregation
potentials this again is just taken from
Jeff's website because it shows it
better so there's the writing-table
today onwards and upwards this growth
rate here when I sort of pulled it out
and put a curve against it it's actually
faster than it's ever been it's faster
than this piece here that was just
before the dot-com bust 2000-2001 today
it's faster than it was i'm not going to
draw any parallels to the financial
collapse that's happening around our
ears but maybe we can predict financial
collapses just by the rate of growth of
the routing table anyway sorry what I
was going to say is if you actually
aggregate and buy a s path it can pull
the bgp table down there aggregate by
origin is it pulls it down there with
just more than numbers that i'm getting
I aggregate but origin is jeff aggregate
spurious path which is up up there so
having something like this in the router
could actually be useful i know some isp
is actually do fill to what they get
again there's no real knob that you can
switch on in your router that i'm aware
of that if you see an aggregator it will
ignore all sub prefixes because i think
that i think more people are going to
start asking for that rather than pay
thousands and thousands of dollars just
to get extra gigs of ram anyway so i
would say 35% saving is quite feasible
in the routing table today okay
receiving prefixes this is getting back
to best practices or stop man gregation
right now receiving best practices the
three scenarios for receiving prefixes
from other a esas if there's a customer
talking bgp your peer or an upstream and
you kind of have to treat them all
differently you can't just treat them
all the same right they've got different
filtering requirements and you need to
handle them separately firstly customers
you should only accept prefixes from
your customers that you know that
actually entitled to use so your
customer wanders up to you and says hey
I've got such and such an address space
check that it's actually there's not
just something that made out of thin air
or something like that check that it
actually is their address space to
announce I mean obviously if you've
assigned them an address block out if
you go in space it's fine but if they're
turning up with the wrong address space
check that it really is their address
space that's all you can do there's no
other authoritative way you have to
check up the registry database and it is
actually theirs if they are the
registered ball user then you're
probably fine to announce it yeah
does that make it harder from tonight's
address space you network rather than
four piers no I don't see why it should
really yes yes yeah i'm going to do that
next yeah piers should be checking
address space as well yes i mean i would
even say upstream should be checking
address space to whether some classic
cases were up streamed quite happy to
accept whatever the customer sent them
you have heard of one or two instances
in the past so but yeah it's generally
filtering filtering your check what the
customer is entitled to sand if they're
not entitled ascended don't accept it so
now the five registry databases and
that's pretty much all that you can
check very simple tool who is so som
some registries have a web interface to
the who is tool but you don't have to do
that I mean most unix systems these days
have a who is command used to who is and
and look up the address space and if the
customer doesn't match the one who's
coming along then you need to start
asking questions so I'm just throwing
some examples in here I mean if it's a
portable address space you know it's
like somebody turns up and wants to want
you to write to to 1220 90 or you look
it up and say oh that's a pin eggs
address space well if they're not a
panic then you probably don't want to
start announcing this address block for
example here's another one somebody
turns up with one if you want to 82 well
if they are if they're not wood
mackenzie if that still belongs to win
mackenzie then well you shouldn't be
again shouldn't be announcing the
address block right so from peers but
somebody with whom you agreed to
exchange prefixes we originated in to
the internet so generally so private
peering so you are giving reach ability
into your network to them and they're
giving reach ability i'm into their
network to you so that's pretty much all
that you should be doing with a peer so
the prefixes that you accept from them
or what they're entitled to a not so
again you you agree as part of the
period
changement what you're going to exchange
with each other now when it you could
agree various ways to do it may be
exchanged emails with each other or
maybe you decide to use a writing
registry or something like that but at
least you come to some agreement what
you can and cannot accept again some of
the peelings I've seen especially to
internet exchange points it's like open
season yeah I'll accept any old rubbish
you send me and i'll send you any old
rubbish that i have that's only going to
end up with with serious accidents
somebody sends your default cryer to
cross your private peering well you'll
end up using their links for all your
outbound traffic rather than your own
links and your own links are probably a
lot better than theirs for example so
you agree what each other going to send
or use the Internet routing registry
quite a few ice be used internet writing
registry if you want to automatically
configure your your routers and so forth
or semi-automatically you can use the
IRL tool set which is e look after or
you can write your own scripting to do
that I mean again I Spees either do
though and scripting or they use the IRR
toolset so that's that's all possible
what about up streams well the upstream
are your trance providers the ice P who
you're paying to give transit to the
whole internet so do you want to receive
food prefixes from them all two hundred
seventy thousand or so well I mean you
can do if you want to I always ask the
question do you need to what's wrong
with the default route default route
says I know how to get to the internet I
mean if you're upstream providers only
got a single connection to the internet
then you probably don't want just a
default right from them because they
don't have any redundancy but if they're
well connected and so forth getting into
fault route from them is probably a good
thing to do it's certainly safety
270,000 prefixes and boy doesn't make in
BGP convergence speed up if you can link
failures you will feel over to backup
links in a matter of seconds rather than
matter of minutes so having a sparse bgp
tables generally pretty nice idea if
your transit provider it's probably
slightly different mean if your transit
provider you probably want to have the
fool bgp table because then your
customers probably want a full table or
substantial table or something like that
and it gets too hard for them to try and
do any multi-homing but we look at
internet today although what three and a
half thousand autonomous systems provide
transit 26,000 or end of the internet
they're not providing transit anywhere
else so if you're not providing transit
other autonomous systems ask yourself
why do you need a full bgp table so if
you want to receive prefixes again don't
just accept any old rubbish again many
historical accidents have happened
because people have accepted any old
rubbish but starter you don't want to
receive the private address space a lot
of lot of prefix in RFC 3339 a special
use some should be routed other should
not so have checked check those up just
to make sure that you're getting the
right stuff don't accept your own
prefixes why would you hear your own
prefixes from anywhere else that's
pretty unusual don't accept the default
route unless you need it because some
time to time the default route does get
announced by accident so you probably
don't want to hear a default route from
some places you weren't going to expect
it some people are now allow prefixes
longer than / 24 it seems to be again
industry standard of not accepting
anything longer than 24 so 25 26 27 28
you don't really want you don't expect
to see these they're not many of them
anyway it's not going to cause a massive
problem but generally you don't see them
if all this is too much for you well
team come we have a nice service they've
got this bull gone right server which
basically will send you a BGP prefect
bgp feed of prefixes that you probably
don't want to see on the internet okay
so you can sign up to that service if
you want to do it or anybody else who
offers a service like that when I know
quite a few rsps are using it you're
perfectly happy but for goodness sake if
you're going to do this sort of bug on
based filtering safer like the registry
unassigned prefixes and so on keep it up
to date I'm not going to tell my
Mongolia story and this this thing I
don't have enough time but you know
there's many many classic examples of
people were doing static filtering in
and not updating it so it's easiest to
use
this that's right server and that way
you ensure that the prefixes that you're
receiving will always be current and
it's anyway so generally paying
attention to prefix you receive from
customers your peers transit providers
it all helps with integrity of the local
network and with integrity of the
internet so I say many of the accidents
on the net have happened simply because
people have not been filtering a
proprietary or properly nobody owns the
internet well we own the internet so if
we want the internet to work as we
expect it then we really need to behave
properly on it and look after it right
so the final piece configuration tips
I'm just going to go through some
configuration tips templates and so
forth a lot of these are good practices
some arguable good practices but I've
put down here a lot of the ones that I
found people insist a really good ideas
the first would really well use loopback
for ibgp pairings because that way we
keep our ibgp independent of our
infrastructure some people still run
ibgp between wheel interfaces the
downside is if a real interface goes
down your ibgp will go down and put the
loopback 32 into the IGP think about the
demarcations so networks so do you want
to use a numbered interfaces some our
species are none unnumbered interfaces
for point-to-point links to customers a
lot of ISPs more and more these days are
using next hop cell so they set the
external next top or replace the
external next stop with that of the
local router some people carry the DMR
Cashin zone / dodges in BGP because the
monitor customer links so you don't put
them in the IGP you put them in BGP we
tag them with a special community and
only the router that connects to your
not we'll let that community through so
that so you're not can actually see the
point-to-point links that kind of thing
perhaps but basically you want to keep
all the demarcation point-to-point links
out of your igp and that keeps it nice
and small so that's the next hop self so
the BGP speaker will announce
external network using the router local
address and that is very useful to help
produce the igp some people limit the
airs path lengths I mean internet an
average is five autonomous systems deep
when even crossing the network I think
the longest EAS path be with unique a
esas without any pre pens or something
like 12 or 13 so the internet is not
really that broad is very very dense so
some are ESPYs go well I'm only really
going to see about 13 or 14 max why
should I see an AS path with six TAS as
long so they they limit the number of
the maximum is path length to around
about 20 autonomous systems okay again I
track these numbers the internet
generally the longest es path sometimes
usually about 14 or 15 and then every
month or two pops up to about 50 or so
ago somebody does a 40 times pre pen
because they don't know how local
perhaps work or something so some rsps
will do this I mean there was something
was at 23 years ago there was somebody
tried to do a 255 or 256 yes path and it
corrupted good because in the software
didn't actually check for because nobody
ever thought that a esas will ever be
more than 255 so it didn't actually
check in the software whether it would
be longer so overwrought some other
memory and started causing Rogers to
crash so you see some ridiculous
examples this is old one from the days
of the six born the ipv6 experimental
network long gone but you saw something
absurd like this this is actually caused
bamberg a withdraw bag but you still see
these ridiculously long ears paths and
here somebody's done a mass ave s past
prepend as160 327 this is the best path
it's the only path in the routing table
but they've done a big pre pen for some
reason ok no doing massive pre pens will
not override local pratts so anyway but
you know the more classic examples 20s
miles compared to summit I've actually
seen so some people actually no limit
Aires path the maximum length of a s
paths with prefix has more than say 20
asses in the path they ignore the prefix
or the other
there's a bgp TTL hack again it's
limited deployment I've found mean rse
5082 describes this as a bit of a neat
trick it's designed to stop dos attacks
and bgp sessions so the way this works
is you basically your router is sitting
here well normally your TTL it will be
one here TT l0 layer which is fine for
somebody sitting out in the network
Chris they can send craft in BGP packets
with the right TTL to try and disrupt
the BGP session here well the front of
two sets of TTL to 255 then router one
expects the TTL coming in to be 254
surrounding one has told expect the TTL
two from router to to be 254 or 255 i
should say expect in between 55 then
what the BGP session will work and that
the beauty of this is an attack is
sitting out he has to send a packet the
TTL will be reduced it arrives at router
one with a time to live with 253 so
router one grows boss not for me wrong
time to live goodbye so it's a pretty
neat trick which some are ESPYs are
usually to try and avoid having these a
general attack zombie gpp rings so there
was a nano presentation back in 2003
explaining how this all work as I said
it's an RFC some RSP use it as it gives
them as i put in brackets or quotes
their security for the bgp sessions so
some isps consider it useful I'm note
that both neighbors have to agree to use
the feature you can't just decide to set
it up yourself because your neighbor
will still send packets with TTL one so
it won't be too useful if and you try
and configure it templates i always
think templates are great things for
doing configurations nothing worse than
trying new custom configurations for
every single roger in your network most
hours piece of what core distribution
aggregation border service system
whatever routers so if you have
standardized configurations for each one
then it makes managing the network much
easier you just put the standardized
configuration if you need to make a
change you update your template and then
you upload it to all the rioters and
then you knew all the writers will get
updated
cheese then running around each one and
making custom changes also then the
defaults tend not to be optimal even
very useful for isps just because the
vendors decided that one thing should be
a default does not mean it should be the
default you need to decide what the
default is for your network when yes
there's some obvious defaults that the
whole industry thinks should be but the
problem with a lot of vendors as they
service more than one market so trying
to find a nice default for that fits
into all my kids is probably a bit of a
challenge so what you find is the ISPs
tend to just create their own templates
the some industry well-known defaults
folks like the team can we keep these if
you look in the reading room they've got
various router on bgp and all the rest
templates which are considered industry
best practice good practice people
favorites and so forth that you might
like to consider adopting for your own
network so I've put some I BG group's
ibgp ones here so I beach beauty
loopback interface is pretty much
standard next hop self pretty much
standard sending communities and I bgp
otherwise accidents will happen you know
if your neighbor sends you have prefixed
with new export and you don't send
communities within your ibgp your
neighbors wasting the time and you end
up leaking the prefix that he wanted to
be suppressed how do I bgp diversion for
yes there's still some comedians out
there you try and set up bgp version 3
although some people who like playing
around with bgp version numbers there's
no be gb version five yet so some ISPs
make absolutely sure bgp is hardwired to
version 3 some people use up passwords a
lot of people use passwords and ibgp
sessions so I mean within the network
like that can be pretty useful I see
more used outside the network for ebgp
sessions again with a view of all the
recipes I see some of the mandate
passwords other words will absolutely
not use passwords so you don't help a
varian what you want to actually try and
do honestly I don't think that many
people who tagged bgp sessions but mean
i think we're all working a paranoid
moment phase right at the moment it's
pretty powerful prevention too
especially when it's combined
with filters and the actual TTL hacker
mentioned earlier bgp damping do not use
it unless you understand the impact some
people still use it and while i
understand impact that's fine and
definitely don't use any vendor defaults
flat damping or otherwise unless you
will understand why remove private ESS
from announcement priority esas should
not appear on the public internet so
most vendors again of nice commands that
will strip out private ESS from any from
a s paths use extensive filters with
backups so some people use a prefix
filters to filter prefixes and then back
them up with a s path filters if you've
got a private pier with a neighboring s
then put in an AAS path all that says
only let this is into my network as an
example what else any BGP use a password
again some say some ISPs use passwords
allows don't maximum prefix tracking
quite a few people use that if you only
ever expected to get a thousand prefixes
from your peer you probably want to just
set something up so that you'll
disconnect the session if they sound
they send you the full BGP table so
quite a few people will use macs and
prefix tracking you can get it to do
things like shut down the BGP session if
it goes over or just repeatedly send
your warning messages you can get it to
restart the BGP session after an hour
just in case it was configuration error
all this kind of stuff so it's fairly
configurable how you can handle it I
mentioned the maximas path length block
the changes of neighbor States that's
pretty useful as well and keep an eye on
the logs also make the BGP
administrative distance higher than that
of any IGP now again it depends on your
faults some defaults for ebgp halfhyde
mid-distance 20 so if you learn external
prefixes by ebgp from your own
infrastructure they're going to
overwrite your igp which is probably not
too useful again i can just say been
there done that so it's not very
pleasant trying to unravel from that one
so if you make your BGP administrative
distance higher than your igp then you
save that accident from happening
summary of all this try and use
configuration templates try and
standardize configuration
just generally makes things easier keep
aware of standard tricks whoops and to
avoid compromise of the BGP session
generally just do anything that just
makes your life easier and also you want
to think about scalability mean if your
natural doesn't scale then well it's not
going to be successful you're going to
have to work a lot harder to keep it
running so the general goal of all of
this is try and keep it simple try and
keep it scalable use templates as much
as you can be aware of industry best
practices keep an eye on what they are
don't go in anything static like this
tutorial do you fill up a Reggie
tutorial from 1998 and I've been falling
what it says well don't because it's ten
years out of date okay so keep an eye on
tutorials like this or from anybody else
and so forth what the industry best
practices are sit on the different
operational group mailing lists you know
nano glist can be useful for some of
this stuff or if your other parts of the
world look at those operations list
there and you generally keep abreast of
what's going on and that is it so I
finished 15 minutes early just said I
can guide if you and go to the community
meeting which starts in 15 minutes time
as I said along an emerald room you're
all welcome to come if you would like to
do that if you don't want to go there's
the welcome party this evening and the
Bonaventure Brewing Company otherwise
we'll see you all tomorrow thanks for
coming