story of how you got here
uh yeah that was part of my planning
uh my intro yeah i have already planned
that but it's like
really brief uh story
do you guys see my screen we do your
share is up
we've got um we've got four minutes
until we we get into the presentation so
we're just gonna chat with you for a
little bit so we get started
um awesome so shall i unshare my screen
uh you're welcome to keep it up while
we're talking
okay
i'm i'm really excited about this
because purple teaming of course
is i don't think it's a new concept
really i think it's something
that it's not and but it's it's new to
i think that it's really the way it's
been formalized as
a as a process um we've published a
purple team exercise framework and
that's looking more at the
traditional red and blue together and
what i thought was really cool about
when i when i reached out to tripty
again she's going to talk about how she
showed up here
but i'd seen that she'd given this talk
before and i'd never seen
anybody put purple teaming in
application security
yep 2016 last con that's where i first
gave the talk
because i was tired of being one person
absec
show and just red teaming or just blue
teaming was not working out
i had to combine both and create a
feedback loop
between blue teaming and red teaming
so yeah today you will get to hear the
story of how this all started
so are we live right now brazen we are
live yeah no we are
we're just here chatting every uh we're
keeping the audience entertained until
we start the formal presentation
okay so brazen
how did you got into purple teaming
how did i get into purple teaming uh
okay
so um i used to do really
uh spooky things a long time ago and
i um started
grim uh by myself as a consultancy back
in 2013.
and nice at the time i had this idea
for um a more integrated operations loop
for being able to
um uh you know essentially conduct
offensive operations and then a feedback
loop for understanding that because
that's
even today that's still relatively
simplistic
and um
as as the years went on we started
getting into commercial penetration
testing and commercial red teaming
and it was really interesting for me
coming from you know
where i mean again red teaming is meant
to be the emulation
of an adversary's tactics and there's a
number of compromises that are inherent
in that approach because
uh you can't spend the same amount of
money as
uh you know a client's not gonna spend
that amount of money in that amount of
time and red teams generally can't spend
that amount of money or time
to to do something that is like you know
the equivalent of like we're actually
like the chinese apt
um and so i knew those compromises but i
didn't realize how
far down those compromises went and so
it was several years of learning that
and one of the things i quickly picked
up
was um and i think anybody who's done
offensive security whether that's
penetration testing or red teaming
where you do the test for the client you
come back a year later and it's the same
thing yeah it's the same vulnerabilities
and
you think about it and it's like well i
mean i gave you this 50 page detailed
report
why didn't you fix these things and the
reality of course is well you know
they've got their normal lives of doing
these things
and that's not always a priority and so
i just kept thinking there had to be a
better way
um and one i felt like the process could
be improved
why can't we help them fix this as we go
um
two i didn't like what i saw the ego
driven mindset of
penetration testing and red teaming and
that's a talk i've given
um i don't know i think i first gave
that talk in 17 or 18.
um because i got the impression that the
teams were just trying to win
they weren't trying to help the client
it was how can i how can i win
how do i get to ad how do i drop mike
and boom i want it you know like
and it's not business oriented and it's
not beneficial
um and it's it's adversarial so that's
where i
naturally found myself into the concept
of purple teaming before i
even knew what purple teaming was i'd
never heard the phrase
i just had arrived at it intuitively
from my experiences
okay you know what i thought that's
super simple i knew you have
some sort of military army or navy
background
i thought you were actually a navy seal
in your past life
and that's where you learn not only
defense but
bunch of attack techniques and you
brought those to cyber security
so where you were navy see you i was uh
an army officer
okay i'll i'll try not to take that as
an insult that you thought i was in the
navy
no everything
is very uh respectful to me
thank you for your service yeah no i'm
just teasing uh yes i was
i was an army officer i worked in the
intelligence community and national
security for
a long time um and then uh
for those who aren't aware of my current
biography i still um participate in
government i was a strategic advisor
to the director of cisa last year that's
kris krebs
um i left in november and i'm also um
an advisor to the board of the army
cyber institute
okay cool but this isn't about me
trippy this is about you and your
awesome presentation which we look
forward to
hearing all about and i cannot tell you
again when i when i saw that this was in
your background
i just really liked when you and i i'm
not gonna give away again how we met and
why you're here but
i just i really liked it when i met you
and when i saw that you
had done this this i wanted to see how
this works so
i'm can't wait all right
so let me put you
let me do you guys see the presenter
mode
yes that's good yep awesome
so a grim khan thank you so much for
inviting me here what a pleasure to be
here
and the short story is how i found out
about grim corn
is i happen to meet the founder of grim
brazen board in a panel talk
for security innovation and
the topic of the panel talk was purple
teaming and i'm like
wow i don't even know there is the whole
company out there that exists that
believes in purple teaming and helps
their customer
with purple tv approaches so i was very
impressed
and brazen actually asked me hey
do you want to talk at grim con i'm like
why not
i will be more than happy to share uh
15 years of my product security learning
and how i adopted purple teaming here
with that let's begin
so uh before we get into purple teaming
a little bit about me
it's been 15 years i'm doing product
security
and i was a mobile game developer
who did not know the difference between
a random number
secure random number and a
cryptographically secure random number
so as a naive developer i have done
a lot of mistakes that i would not do
now and this really helped me to
understand the pain points of
development
teams engineering teams in general and
i realized uh how fascinating product
security is and i decided to
switch my career from mobile development
into product security
after 15 years of product security
journey i have recently started my
entrepreneurship journey
i will be working on building a genomic
privacy
startup pretty soon uh but before that
uh i have led application security
programs at amazon
q2a banking elimio who is a
leader in micro segmentation and hp
and when i'm not doing security i like
to travel
paint and meditate if you have any
questions
about purple teaming or content that i
will be presenting here or if you want
to have just uh
you know informational chat with me feel
free to reach out
at the social media handles
so today i will be obviously talking
about
my experience as part of blue teams my
experience as part of red team
why these two teams are not sufficient
then what
a purple teaming philosophy is and then
i will talk
uh how we can implement purple teaming
as part of the software
development life cycle to scale and make
it more impactful
i have couple of examples and then
i will be providing a reference to a
case study done by security innovation
and illinois together
with that uh let's begin
um as you all know purple sorry blue
team
members are those security engineers
they work
with the engineering team development
teams qa engineer and they basically
educate software developers
about security controls defense
way early in software development life
cycles
whereas red team members can be an
independent
internal security team which focuses on
hacking
out of a product or it can be an
external penetration
or testing team that
security teams usually engage right
before the product moves
to production or right after uh
basically when the development is
complete
the motto of security team uh blue
blue team is basically they are optimist
they believe in the power of security
controls
they believe in empowering developers
about
the knowledge about security controls
and they try to work with these
engineering team to make sure the
product that they are building
all the security controls are considered
and i uh look at blue team members as
bunch of
optimists whereas secure red teaming
members
these are more paranoid people
they never think that security controls
are enough
and these people are so creative no
matter how much effort
blue team folks have put into securing
the product
the red team members always end up
finding vulnerabilities
and that's because they focus more on
exploitation technique and
creative ways of exploiting the product
do you all agree with me
now with that what's purple teaming
right uh as you know
i love painting one day
while walking in an electronic store
fries i was thinking
why is it no matter how much effort i
put
helping my developers about security
controls defense
the red team members in my case mostly
external penetration testing teams
they always find some new attacks
every time there is a new tech stack or
a new framework
used by engineering then the red teaming
findings are even more
and while walking in the shop i was
thinking why is it
why can't i help my development teams so
that the findings
in a penetration test report literally
becomes zero
what is it that missing and then it
struck me
you know what as a blue team member
i'm teaching my developers
everything the security controls the
requirement
techniques i'm doing threat modeling but
i never discuss
exploitation techniques with them the
exact exploitation techniques
used by red team members
and that's when i thought i need to
create a feedback
loop between between blue team
and red team and when we mix blue and
red together
it becomes purple teaming and purple
teaming folks are realist
let me give you guys another analogy
so blue team folks when they help uh
their engineers with throughout the
product development
with bunch of security controls and
whatnot they roll out the most
appropriate security tools to help them
speed up the secure
deployment and delivery of the product
these are optimus
let's say they are stuck in a storm
while sailing in ocean the blue team
guys
believe that you know
all the controls defenses their product
has
they are going to easily survive and
pass through the storm
whereas my red teaming member the
paranoids one
they are like you know what this ocean
in that scary storm is so
bad we are not going to survive
whereas what purple teaming members
do is they do not get scared
they are not super optimistic they are
the realest one
what they do is they prepare for the
worst
they hope the storm will pass soon
and in order to survive in that storm
they make
necessary adjustment by adjusting the
direction of the sail
that's how they survive
now let's talk how this purple teaming
philosophy
can be implemented in the form of
process
i'm sure you all have seen security
within
software development lifestyle the top
half of this diagram
shows waterfall sdlc usually
nowadays uh 10 15 years back waterfall
sdlc was very common
but now the industry has moved into more
agile software development life cycle
as we are going more and more into a
more
micro service-oriented architecture but
in some of the legacy applications and
system we still see
waterfall as clc exist so if you look at
uh how securities weaved in in today's
software development life cycle we will
see that
at requirement phase we security members
do threat modeling
then in design phase we do something
called design architecture review from
security perspective in
coding uh deployment phase uh
security engineer roll out those
fabulous static code analysis tool
that help developers find code related
issue
then in testing we basically
implement and roll out bunch of security
testings tool it could be a dynamic
application security scanner
or open source security scanner or it
could be interactive application
security scanner there are like bunch of
tools
out there today's talk is really not
about
uh tooling so i i don't want to shift my
focus
and then when the product the
application is
ready to move into production or has
just moved into production
basically the code base is mature we
hire penetration testers
to come hack our application and find as
many security issues as possible
now as you all know penetration testing
is expensive plus
it happens way late in software
development life cycle
when we do threat modeling we basically
use checklist approach or
same for design architecture review so
the result of penetration
test we cannot replicate way early in
software
uh life cycle development if you look at
the second
uh the bottom half of the image which
shows agile sdlc
more or less we do the same techniques
but the frequency
of these security assessment methods are
actually different
uh the speed of delivery and deployment
is
so high in agile sdlc that
we put more emphasis on
basically tools and again the story is
same
when the product is mature and
it is available in production that's
when uh
we conduct external penetration tests
uh let's take another look at the same
software
lifecycle development but through ci cd
so with the rise in micro services uh
the industry has adapted more continuous
integration and continuous delivery
model
and here we give paramount emphasis on
rolling out the right tools and for some
reason
the industry thinks that if you have the
tools that means you have the security
you have done
all the necessary due diligence but
in spite of all these tools penetration
testers still
find really good security issues right
yes
so why is that and i believe that
most of these security tools are still
in their first generation
they don't necessarily have the context
of the business logic of the application
or they are not
exclusively made based on the technical
stack
uh the particular application uses
that's why there is like a lot of false
positive
and it's a nightmare to deal with
not nicely tuned security tools so i'm
not gonna
get there but basically in spite of
having army of
security tooling still there is
something big is missing
now when i talk about purple teaming
which is basically
mixing the knowledge of exploitation
techniques
and security controls and making your
developers
educated about it this is how it looks
like to me
so in requirement phase uh the way
or even before requirement phase uh
imagine
when you approach uh developers or qa
engineers or you know any engineering
team with bunch of security findings
from penetration press report they don't
like it
it's their baby you're calling their
baby ugly
with all these security findings
generally speaking they do not like it
but when we approach development
teams with security trainings
then they feel empowered
i have worked with so many smart
developers and
nobody has ever not like security
training they really appreciate
when security teams approach them with
very comprehensive
security trainings exclusively designed
for their stack
their style of architecture pattern
used by the engineering team so when i
try to do purple teaming i always always
start
with developer security training if they
are using
ruby react javascript i don't try to
teach them vulnerabilities in cc
plus i focus on their tech stack
so purple teaming always starts with
developer security
in requirement phase irrespective of
what sdlc you are using
i try to teach them security
requirements and i have a detailed
um example just
after a couple of slides in design phase
i
not only tell them security controls but
i also explain
them exploitation techniques and what i
request them is
now you fine tune your design
based on the exploitation technique and
then
rest of the sdlc goes uh in the similar
fashion
so let's take a quick example
this is an unrestricted a file upload
feature uh this type of feature
is very common in a lot of applications
uh it could be you know uploading image
or simple
text file so let's see how i apply
purple teaming
uh to this particular feature before i
apply a purple teaming
let me explain you as a blue team member
what would i do
as a red team member what would i do so
as a blue team member
whenever i see my developers are
building this type of feature or they
have recently built this type of feature
i make sure uh to educate them about
hey you know bad guys can access this
feature and they can upload nasty stuff
like
virus so make sure you only allow
authorized user then i also try to tell
them about
file size make sure you put a
restriction on file size
otherwise somebody can upload a zip bomb
right then i talked to them about
hey make sure you do all sort of input
validation
by checking the right file extension
and please do not use a blacklist
approach or sorry deny list approach
always list allow list approach the
extensions that you are expecting
please ensure that those are in the
allow list
instead of blocking all the bad
extension and once the file gets
uploaded to the server
don't forget to run antivirus now this
list looks pretty comprehensive right
yes
it is pretty comprehensive and it can
probably take care of
90 percent of the attacks now as a red
team member
i think like an attacker because
at any cost i want to take down this
application i want to upload
shell script to take over not just the
application but eventually
the system and network that's my
intention right
so i try to think about all sort of
creative ways
first thing i try to look hey can i
bypass
any function level access controller
then every file
has a magic number associated uh with it
the magic number is actually the
signature
of the file so by manipulating the
signature of the file you can basically
upload uh
bad malicious files into the application
then
not only this i try to see that can i
change the content of the file
by adding injections i actually tried
this uh
in a banking application which accepts
uh
excel spreadsheet i tried to add
cross-site scripting and sql injection
as a content in that file
the application was doing a decent job
at uh
verifying the extension size
uh authorization of the user
but it was not doing a good job
verifying the content
and i was successful uh creating a
cross-site scripting
injection there now
let me wear the hat of a purple team
member
i have the knowledge of red teaming
techniques i have the knowledge of
security control specified by blue
teaming i'm going to mix
these two together so
i'm going to turn my exploitation
techniques
into security requirements so let's go
back here
i have already let's say hypothetically
i have already trained my developers
about
what could go wrong with file upload now
i am
explicitly mentioning the exploitation
techniques
and turning them into security
requirement even before they write a
single line of code
and in this way i am shifting
that security towards left
i am making my developers
purple team members because they are no
longer
just developers they are no longer just
security focused people but they
actually have knowledge of exploitation
techniques
that's what purple teaming is and when
when we have those type of discussion at
requirement
phase the uh probability
and the probability of avoiding these
type of security findings
is so um high
also by preventing these issues
from occurring we are eventually
reducing the cost associated with fixing
these issues as well there was a
beautiful study done by nist in 2002
and it talks about cost of fixing
quality bugs
in each phase and compared to production
uh issues identified in production if
somebody fixes
these issues in requirement design phase
it is 10 000 times
lesser same thing applies for security
defects
because security defects are nothing but
quality defects security is actually
part of quality
so why deprive our developers from this
knowledge
as a security team member why should i
keep all this knowledge of exploitation
technique just to myself
when i share it with developer it
becomes easy
for them to implement and it becomes
easy for me
to scale it at higher level
so let's take a look at another
example now uh the first column here
indicates security principles these are
the
11 security principles and if you if you
can think about
any 12th please get in touch with me
i'll be more than happy to do another
talk
with you the next column uh
shows security requirements the third
column
shows security control and fourth column
shows exploitation technique now imagine
a developer has not written
a single line of code they have come to
you
to uh give to get security requirements
on
session ids basically they are building
authentication module
now uh one of the simplest security
requirement
when somebody deals with authentication
is
the session id should be sufficiently
long
they should be random and unique across
all correct active session base right
so this is the requirement uh we have
given
to the development team and then
uh in order to further secure the
session ids
we also tell them a security control
that hey
you can even do a digest
of that uh session id and
make sure you use a cryptographically
secure random number and you use a
fibs approved crypto library to compute
the digest
now as part of purple teaming do not
stop here
you have done a good job as a blue team
member but as part of purple teaming
remember we are supposed to teach them
about attacks
that could happen now as a red teaming
member
when i see bunch of session ids or
random numbers what do i do
i do entropy analysis and i try to
find out if the entropy is less i try to
do
a brute force attack right so let's
educate
our developers about these exploitation
techniques in requirement phase
itself and help them partner with them
to find the right
library that can defeat entropy analysis
as well as brute force attack so that's
really
purple teaming is
now um let me cover some other
aspects of purple teaming as i explained
before
uh it is extremely important to
approach engineering team through
training
and you can create purple teaming
through
your uh security trainings second
not do not just focus on developers qa
engineers the people who actually write
code test code
but also focus on architects focus uh
on your product managers focus on
your program management office who are
responsible for all the releases and
schedule
and also exec also on the executive team
because it's the top-down approach that
always works bottom-up approach doesn't
work so in purple teaming focus on
all sort of roles and responsibilities
that
are important to ship a product and then
weave security accordingly as i explain
in those two uh examples always
map your business requirement to
security requirements
and then eventually explain the security
requirements in the form of controls
and exploitation techniques you will be
most successful
implementing purple teaming approach
when you speak the same
language of your software development
life cycle
do not keep the security knowledge to
yourself
go attend their scrum meetings go
participate in their
book triage meetings go participate in
each and every story time
and explain the controls and
exploitation techniques so when
we completely immerse ourselves into
engineering processes
and life cycle that's when uh they
understand us and that's the real
success of purple teaming
and eventually uh create a win-win
situation for
all sort of parties you can do this
by acknowledging their efforts you can
do this
by calculating metrics that hey once we
applied
a purple teaming approach see how many
less
bugs have been found by
red teaming members or ever since
we implement purple teaming approach cqa
engineers are
fully capable of finding security
defects or you know the over how the
overall
posture of security posture of the
product has improved so call
out those wins uh reward uh
their efforts and what i like to do is
every six months i like to
host a hacking event where i invite all
my developers q engineer vp's director
and come participate hack with us
all right uh so that was about purple
teaming
uh let me conclude here my time is
almost
up so we just now saw
having red teams uh doesn't help
red teams and blue teams they both are
extremely important
for security of the product as well as
organization
but they working in silos doesn't help
when there is a feedback loop
uh between red teams and blue teams and
when we share that
knowledge with engineering teams that's
what purple teaming is
and purple teaming kind of approach a
mov offers a more holistic approach
purple teaming can be easily weaved into
uh
organizations software life cycle
development
process and as i explained when we
educate our developers about
exploitation techniques
the number of issues that get produced
are less the number of uh defects
security defects that get identified
the remediation rate uh is very high
because developers already know how to
fix it find it and fix it
the overall roi becomes super high and
i genuinely believe in my 15 years of
experience it's the purple teaming that
truly fascinates
uh shift left and it also helps to scale
application security uh recently
i had done a case study on purple
teaming with security innovation
and if you guys are curious or keen
about
how i had implemented uh purple teaming
in the past i would highly encourage to
check out this case study
with that are there any question answers
so yeah we already have a question uh
will the slides be available to download
is there some place that folks can get
these
uh yes the slides are already available
in my linkedin profile
i have shared them on uh site share also
i'll be sharing
the slide deck with a grim corn
committee
um the case study that you mentioned
there is it possible that we could paste
that link
somewhere uh sure
do you guys still see my screen no
oh uh do you want me to share the link
uh
right now yeah if we could just
paste it in chat just send that link for
the case study and then we'll also throw
it on discord
absolutely
so when did you first come up with this
idea
uh twenty uh when i was one person
application
security team at q2a banking in austin
texas
nice so similar right there's got to be
a better way
yeah all right um
let me share this in chat
uh grace and i think you guys still see
my screen right
yes so this is the case study and i'm
kind of struggling to open the chat
um okay uh
i think i'm not allowed okay if you if
you email it to me i'll
i'll it i can do
you that want to stop sharing your
screen so we don't see your email there
you go
fine i just i i'm always so sensitive
about that offset fail whenever i share
myself oh my gosh
oh no people are going to see something
sensitive i know i know
and here is a link to um the case study
unfortunately this talk is an hour long
and because i had only 30 minutes i had
compressed it
so there are many more aspects of purple
teaming that i
i would love to explain if anybody is
interested like
how to implement purple teaming in a
typical
software life cycle development
what are some common mistakes you've
seen in that implementation
some of the common mistakes i'll start
with people um
you know just because security engineers
are excited about security and they're
passionate about security
they assume everybody's interested in
security and unfortunately that's not
the case so what you will see
is out of 100 uh 100
engineering team members maybe 50 60 are
interested and not everybody so we have
to keep that in mind
that besides security people have other
things uh online such as
you know uh releasing the product on
time
uh making sure um the shiny new features
that generate revenue
gets preference over security bugs um
so that's one thing i have seen not
everybody is excited about security but
those
who are excited about security giving
their medic and
get knowledge and training and making
them your ally kind of creating security
champions
that really helps the second mistake i
have seen
is not getting executive buying
from the top tier management upfront
it's extremely hard to weave security
in the software life cycle development
and
you need right budget right resources so
when you don't talk about these things
upfront
it becomes difficult and security
becomes after thought
the third mistake i've seen is rolling
out
incompatible security tools as i said
security tools are still in their first
generation
they still produce a lot of false
positives
there are still uh true negative true
true negatives so these tools
when when you are doing proof of concept
uh to select right tool for your
organization
always make sure you include your
developers
qa engineers get their perspective as
well
how they are going to feel about
operating on these tools
it's extremely important so
and another thing i want to call out is
there is just
way too much emphasis
on buying commercial tools sometimes it
is
uh super easy and cost effective to
build your homegrown security tools
uh would you like to hear an example
brayson
absolutely
i have seen um a lot and this is a
beautiful example of purple teaming
approach as well in one of the
organization i had work i had seen a lot
of sensitive information
was getting leaked into logs
now application security folks do not
take a look at
blocks logs are something analyzed
by uh the infrastructure security team
members
in production right they have access to
sim
and they sometimes may catch it or may
not catch it but getting sensitive
information
leaked into logs is such a crucial
problem because these locks
let's say in case of a sas application
these locks get shipped to customers and
from customers environment
god knows which business analytics uh
will
uh capture and you know may encounter
sensitive information so this is a
really big problem
and in spite of teaching my developer i
you know do not um do not lock sensitive
information
i was not having great success because
to be very honest
development teams they do generate
uh logs for debugging purpose that's how
they debug
and when they are testing security
features
it is quite possible that they may log
session ids or credentials or whatnot
so just having a proactive approach of
telling them
hey do not capture log was not
sufficient
so what i did using my purple teaming
hat
i requested i participated in their
story time and i exclusively called out
a security requirement once this feature
is complete
qa engineers will write automation
to look for session ids credentials
uh tokens and all sort of sensitive
information
that this feature is using and they will
make sure
that it is not getting locked i did not
stop there
i requested a development team to
actually write a homegrown scanner
so they wrote a simple grab base filter
that can scrub logs and it it basically
checks for these files so in this way
throughout the software lifecycle
development not only the
requirements story time but also in
design qa
and post production base we solve this
problem and
having our very own homegrown security
scanner to
identify sensitive information inside
logs was
so much more effective
than learning sims sim tool and trying
to
uh find the this type of information
uh it probably took a half a day for
development team to write such
tool and because this tool was written
as a collaborative effort between
security development and qa guys
qa guys immediately plugged that tool
into automation
qa automation framework now that tool
runs on
all the releases all the test bits and
we get
to uh we basically identify sensitive
information asap
so that was my purple teaming approach
to solve this
issue so um follow-up question on that
since you you started talking about
something that came out in our panel
which is
um like in the security community we
take for granted that people even know
what red and blue is
right and in the building community
right it's
like that's not that's just like we
throw it over the fence right it's the
classic like development
operations challenge um but then there's
all of these
security components to that which are
essentially a part of
quality and features right we're turning
them into features and stories and agile
developments so that they're
they're incorporated in that way um but
something i still have
i i think it would be interesting to as
like a further step in that maturity
would be building um system of systems
security testing into the the pipeline
so
not just you know particular features to
application but recognizing that
an application runs on a system and
there are other systems around that
and the security is not just directly
the potential vulnerabilities on the
application on that system
but also you know potentially what could
be
um an unintended consequence somewhere
else or
on the plus side where i'm mitigating
and controlling those
um even though i didn't realize it or i
or i can
implement those controls and know that
so because a vulnerability
is does not necessarily have to be
addressed directly
yeah um i like to talk about uh
you know defense in-depth uh approach
you know many times uh development teams
may not have time to fix the
vulnerability
by making code changes and that's where
as you explain
abrasion uh we need to rely on security
controls provided by the system
or security and security controls
provided by the network and organization
wide level
for example you know there is a
cross-site scripting in some application
the application is already in production
and it would take let's say two person
days to fix that vulnerability and then
test it and release the code
we don't have that much time hey
let's go for vaf vaf is an
organization wide you know control
and it will prevent the injections from
getting into the application even before
those cross-site scripting payloads
reach
uh the vulnerable application we stop it
so vap
is a great control another good example
i can think about to prevent
is csp content security policy
which is also implemented for entire uh
application the enterprise application
and it can prevent cross-site scripting
vulnerabilities and because of these
defense and div
techniques such as csp or vaf we are
actually giving our development teams
enough time to thoroughly fix the
vulnerabilities
and test the fix
well that scratched my edge this is what
i was looking to hear and i really
appreciate it trisha do you have
anything
no i this has been so fun like listening
to both of y'all go back and forth
because
it's such an interesting concept and i
i had never even thought about it as
specific to the
abstract side which is is huge it was
such a
great talk such a great talk it makes so
much sense
you know it's like it seems so obvious
but i've never even
thought yeah and uh trisha when i
tell my developers and qa engineer i am
the blue team or red team
but you guys are my purple teaming now
because you are now fully
knowledgeable about the exploitation
technique relevant to this application
you are my purple teammate
they get so excited and thrilled i can't
even tell you
love it again it's another theme that
we've had with
almost everything is you know this
positive reinforcement and bringing
people together
and you know yes it's a very important
aspect of our community 100
yes so it's like extending
our security community to development
teams
and utilizing on their skills like
it's been 15 years i've written a code
so you know it was kind of tricky for me
to write that log scanner and when i
asked my development team to do it
they're like yeah boom half a day and
here my lock scanner is ready
i love it i'm going to be picking your
brains one-on-one in the future because
i've got some
some implementation ideas in that space
um and i have a funny feeling
that this stealth startup you're a part
of might be connected to the space
as well sure i am happy to help
in any aspect i i do believe in purple
teaming the artist inside me that lives
in purple teaming prison
so yeah utilize me wherever you want
to and i'll help with whole heart
and with the uh psych gift card to the
swag store that if you you haven't seen
it was
was sent a day or two ago um you can get
a purple unicorn
so what our purple team t-shirt
you know i have already ordered it but
now i want what you have
you have some golden unicorn right
that's the golden
so i should have i should have changed
colors i have i have my purple team so
this is
this is my summer unicorn outfit because
as tricia noted
um i was giving her a professional
unicorn advice that once he gets hot
so i don't wear onesies anyway um i have
custom
hoodies and so i have
i don't what was it did i wear a hoodie
for our panel i did didn't i
yeah yeah yeah you did i remember that
wonderful hoodie
yeah so so i have
the blue team the red team nice and the
purple team
this is such a flex right now bryson
such a flux yeah and a golden unicorn
on top of everything love it
so i i also have i should have i should
have switched out my
my uh summer unicorn uh for the purple
well we have one minute left why don't
you do it
well i mean it's gonna be you sitting
there watching me mess around with
velcro
and uh i think it's gonna okay
embarrassing that i'm
as uncoordinated with velcro as possible
i show up
you know in in proper uniform
me doing the props kind of
totally understandable all right um
so i guess this is it uh once again
uh brayson thank you so much for
introducing this wonderful platform to
me
uh what a pleasure to talk here
thank you so much for joining us thank
you it was wonderful
thank you bye