so i i was
i was bragging nicole about how you you
started at as one of our first new
speakers
and then immediately went up go on to
like speak at all these other awesome
conferences and like
totally go on the circuit now
yes uh what a crazy year it's been yeah
i've went from
um just starting out i think like a
couple years ago
and grimcon was my first talk and
now i have my own blog i'm starting my
own podcast
uh this fall uh created my own framework
so
things are happening fast amazing
that's so cool well
we're going to pass the torch yet again
to your now experienced and awesome
speaking hands
thank you okay so
um once again uh they probably already
introduced me but my name is nicole
hoffman and i'm giving a presentation
titled
jinkies this email looks suspicious so
there's been a suspicious email
sent by to somebody at mystery inc
and i need your help to unmask the
imposter and solve the mystery
and stick around and i'll provide some
tips to
help prevent this from happening to you
and your organization
so a little bit more about me why should
you listen to me during this talk
um i'm currently an intelligence analyst
at group sense which is a digital risk
protection services company
i personally deal with a
business email compromise uh probably on
a weekly basis
and so i just thought it'd be really
relevant to give this talk and to
provide some helpful tips i has a
bachelor's in information technology and
a minor in cyber
security i have my security plus
certification
uh like i said uh previously i recently
created
my a cognitive stairways of analysis
framework this is an analytic framework
to provide a step-by-step process
for performing analysis in tech if you
want to know more about it you can
go to my blog at threathuntergirl.com
and something about me personally before
i can do any type of analysis
i need the coffee i need coffee before i
can do the intelligence analysis
um when i'm not working i just recently
moved to
the dallas fort worth area with my
family so we've been spending a lot of
weekends exploring and it's been really
fun
i'm a huge comic book fan um
both physical comic books that i collect
as well as the cinematic universes
and i'm a big gamer i love destiny 2
i love um
uh red dead redemption
assassin's creed not that you needed to
know all the games that i like to play
but i just thought i would
mention it and uh you can reach me on
twitter at
huntergirl.com or for hunter girl
without the eye
okay so let's talk about this suspicious
email
it came from scooby-doo and it was sent
to joe in hr
and it says dear joe i have a new bank
account i need changed urgent so next
paycheck go
new account please confirm change by
email only think
scooby-doo hmm this email looks
really suspicious and the first thing
that i notice when looking at this email
is the domains don't match so
this clearly didn't come from scooby-doo
because
they inserted a dash into the domain so
that looks
odd the next thing that looks odd is
scooby-doo doesn't get paid in money he
gets paid in scooby snacks
everybody knows that and i know
scooby-doo's grammar is
not the best but it's not this bad so
that's another red flag
and look at the unexplained urgency this
just
seems out of the norm for scooby-doo
the only thing scooby-doo does urgently
is eat
and really shaggy for that matter or
maybe run away from bad guys but he
certainly doesn't care about getting
paid
urgently so that's another red flag the
biggest red flag
is that um we have
at mr inc they have an internal policy
for confirming identification for any
financial changes or contact information
and it says please confirm change by
email only
if this was really scooby-doo he would
know
how to properly confirm the change so
this isn't scooby-doo
and scooby-doo actually doesn't have an
email
at mystery inc he doesn't actually have
a computer
his paws are too big so
all of these things lead us to believe
that this is most likely someone
impersonating scooby-doo in a business
email compromise trying to intercept his
payment
so let's talk a little bit more about
business email compromise
have you ever seen the movie the master
of disguise
it's a movie i'm not sure what it came
out um
but i watched it when i was little and i
just thought it was the funniest thing
ever and it was about a
a guy who was learning the family
business of being able to
change his uh into this special
disguises
almost at the snap of a finger and just
ridiculously unrealistically fast
and it's really funny if you watch it i
recommend watching it with your kids
um but that's kind of what i feel like
thread actors feel like when they commit
these
email compromise attacks is that they're
some master of disguise
that um they're trying to blend in
and you know manipulate people um and so
who better to unmask an imposter than
mystery inc
so that's kind of why i really wanted to
do a scooby-doo talk and the other
reason is i also say like jinkies
all the time during my investigation so
now i get to
say it during a talk so business email
compromise what it is
it's an email-based social engineering
attack where
a threat actor will impersonate a
legitimate employee
in order to interrupt or
reroute funds and there's two scenarios
that i typically see on a on a weekly
basis
there is the wire fraud where they'll
try to intercept a payment
to like a vendor or a company or even
like if someone's trying to pay off
their house
in a reality situation the other one
that i see a lot
is payroll fraud where they'll try to
access that person's direct deposit and
say hey i got a new bank account like we
saw
with the person impersonating scooby-doo
and these threat actors are typically
financially motivated
and they are ranging from all technical
abilities i've seen
well executed business email compromise
attacks and i've seen poorly executed
attacks so it really is not something
that you have to have a lot of technical
abilities to carry out
three of the main things that i see uh
for how they
carry out the attack is one is i've seen
them create
spoofed domains or domains that are
created to look like the legitimate
domain and they do this to try to bypass
the detection from the person they're
sending the email to
or private emails such as gmail yahoo
this is something i see more in the
payroll fraud
especially since a lot of the workforce
is remote now and they'll say hey this
is my
home email and then compromise
credentials
this is something i don't see as often
or maybe it's not as
reported but if a threat actor gains
access to
an email credential they can then send
out emails from
that person's email so who is at risk
well really everyone that has a business
email is technically at risk
but the two departments that i see
targeted the most
is hr who have the ability to make
changes to people's direct deposit
accounts
and accounting or accounts payable
somebody who has access to
make changes within an organization's uh
wires if they're sending money to
vendors and things like that so those
are the two people that i see that are
at risk the most but it's really
something that can affect anyone in the
organization
and according to the fbi's uh
2020 internet crime report in 2020 alone
the ic3 received 19369
email compromise complaints and the
adjusted losses
for those was just over 1.8 billion
dollars
and just for comparison last year they
also received 2
474 complaints uh identified as
ransomware
and the adjusted losses of over 29.1
million dollars
so just to compare nineteen thousand
complaints
versus 2000 so this is something we
really need to be prepared for
um and there's a lot of different types
of prevention strategies
that you can implement but i'm going to
start simple
and i'm going to be providing you with
five
prevention tips that i think could
significantly
reduce the the likelihood of a
successful business email compromise and
potentially save your organization
thousands of dollars
so let's look at the first prevention
tip
continuously monitor for information
exposure
if you find information exposure try to
mitigate it remove the data if possible
um try to
make sure that it doesn't happen in the
future
things that you specifically want to be
looking for is over
sharing over sharing on linkedin other
social
media are people posting pictures of
their badge
their job titles their emails
and and things like that how easy is it
for
threat actors to find information to
figure out who they need to target
to be the most successful you know
sites like data brokers or business to
business
databases these are sites that are meant
for legitimate business purposes
but threat actors can exploit them
typically for free or for a small cost
if you've ever seen these
and a lot of these sites have opt-out
options
which i recommend it does take some time
to go through and find them all
and it does require continuously
monitoring for this information
but knowing is half the battle so i
highly recommend
knowing how much information is out
there and are you
over sharing on your corporate website
how much information
are you sharing about your staff
specifically human resources and
accounting
and the executives how much can i find
just by going to your website
it you know try to put yourself in a
thread doctor's shoes and try to
determine
what they can find a lot of times what
what i have seen
is people will post like um company
spotlights or employee spotlight like
these are
you know i want to share about our
company which is great but then they'll
say like this is sasha from accounting
and she just started and
she's from ohio and she went to ohio she
has a degree from ohio state and
all these things are are great
they're they're innocent when you when
you're posting them
and and it's a good idea to share about
your company but just be
cognizant of how much you're sharing and
how easy you're making it
um and if you experience a business
email compromise try to go back
and and look for how much information
you can find about the individual that
was targeted
and credential exposures is something
another type of exposure that i think
everyone should be regularly monitoring
especially if
uh employees as they often do
reuse passwords if you know say there's
a
facebook breach or some app breach are
they reusing that password
internally and will a threat actor be
able to gain access
and so this has to be a continuous
monitoring i don't think it's a one and
done because information
can pop up all the time so continuously
monitoring mitigating and preventing
this
could could significantly reduce the
likelihood of these types of attacks so
don't make it easier for threat actors
my second prevention tip is to ensure
the
company has policies for the identity
verification when
you make these types of changes like
existing invoices direct deposit bank
accounts
contact information say hey this is my
new email
stuff like that like we saw with with
the threat actor targeting scooby-doo
if you have specific policies and
procedures in place
it's more more likely that uh you know
uh
these types of things won't just happen
because they'll know
i need to make sure this is verified
personally i like to have a plan a
a plan b and a plan c with identity
verification
you know you can verify over the phone
with a known phone number for that
individual not a phone number
provided within the email like in the
signature
or or the website you don't want to use
that information
if you don't have the specific phone
number for the individual
that is trying to contact you try to get
a
known contact at that company or even
just google the company try
to use their main line you just don't
want to
use anything provided in the email if
you're suspicious uh that it might be a
business email compromise
uh the plan b would be in person if at
all possible
if it's a remote workforce obviously
that's that's something that can happen
and then plan c i recommend having
something
specific and unique to your organization
that changes regularly but not too much
because if you change it too much
then people are just going to be annoyed
by it and they're not going to pay
attention but
if it's if it's regular enough at least
change it when someone if someone leaves
the company then let's go ahead and
update that whether it be
like a code word or just some type of
unique thing that you can add like an
additional layer of identity
verification
and you know hearing code word
it might sound like childish or that
doesn't seem like it's going to work but
in reality something so simple could
actually
you know prevent this type of attack
so think about it you know think about
having multiple plans
not just one form of identity
verification because there's always
going to be
exceptions and you don't want to have
too many plans or too many
uh backup plans because that is just
going to be annoying and they're not
going to you know
be able to remember all of them so just
have enough
to try to cover exceptions and things
like that
so there's always a plan in place
so my third prevention tip is education
now i highly recommend educating the
entire staff
on not only regular phishing attacks but
also
business email compromise attack because
it's
these types of attacks are different
than the normal
um phishing attacks that you see in the
wild
because typically when there's a
phishing attack
the threat actors are fishing for
information they're trying to
get information or they're trying to
manipulate you into like clicking on
something
and so a lot of the phishing awareness
training that i see is specific
to um you know trying to get
credentials or are you trying to get you
to open something malicious and it
doesn't really cover
business email compromise and when the
the threat actor is actually going after
money
instead of information or you know
trying to get you to download malware so
i highly recommend
specifically for the human resources and
accounting departments
to incorporate specific business email
compromise
examples into your training and
also if you do fishing awareness or if
not fishing awareness excuse me um
fishing uh simulations like for
training i highly recommend not only
doing
you know the typical phishing but also
including
a specific business email compromise and
to the most targeted people in the
organization
because it could definitely help prevent
the the attack because this type of
attack exploits the network's
weakest link which is the people and it
relies on manipulating people
and we're never going to be able to say
we're 100 percent covered from this
threat but we can do all that we can
so that we can hope to prevent the
likelihood
so my fourth prevention tip is to
continuously
monitor for newly created spoofed
domains
that specifically have mail servers set
up
because a lot of times what i will see
is
a threat actor will create a domain
that looks exactly like a legitimate
domain whether you call that a spoof
domain
typo squatted domain whatever you want
to call it
they'll set it up they'll register it
they'll
set up mail servers they'll create the
email
of the individual that they're trying to
impersonate and they'll carry out their
attack typically within a few days
so making sure that you're monitoring
for these
um and because knowing is half the
battle and something
like this you want to just be
continuously monitoring for anyway
because there's other things that could
potentially impact your organization
so no scooby-doo talk would be complete
without a trip to the kitchen
because that's typically where you're
gonna find
shaggy and scooby during any mystery
solving investigation
so i had to go into the kitchen to see
scooby and shaggy's epic
sandwich creation so for my fifth
prevention tip i really recommend being
wary of unexplained urgency and requests
for
payments or financial changes even
contact changes
any unexplained urgency should be
immediately a red flag
and for me if i see any unexplained
urgency
i would immediately stop communicating
with that individual
over email and start my identity
verification procedures that i have in
place
because it might be
it might take a couple extra steps it
might be inconvenient but security isn't
supposed to be convenient
and if it can save the company hundreds
of thousands of dollars
i would do that so i highly recommend
in your training for business email
compromise
to add the red flag of unexplained
urgency
because threat actors often not just in
business email compromise but other
types of phishing attacks
they'll often use unexplained urgency
they'll they'll impersonate a
person that's in a position of power and
they'll
they'll use that urgency and authority
to try to manipulate people into doing
something quicker
so that they don't have time to just you
know
think about it and and identify any red
flags
um and that's what they're hoping for so
be wary of that unexplained urgency and
requests
and especially if it's coming from a
person of power
start looking immediately for any red
flags in the email
why it's old man withers the guy that
with the haunted
uh amusement park he was behind the
attack the whole time
and he would have gotten away with it if
it wasn't for those meddling kids
so this is hopefully what a threat actor
will say if you implement these five
prevention
tips so just just to wrap it up
and and kind of reiterate the five steps
is you want to be continuously
monitoring for information exposure
i highly recommend you regularly google
your company
google uh people that are specifically
targeted
um like you know people in your
accounting department your executives
people and human resources how much
information
is out there and how easy is it for a
threat actor to
carry out this attack with little to no
resource
excuse me little to no resources and
number two
you know ensure you have company
policies and procedures in place
not only for uh verifying identities
but also for responding to
business email compromise or if there's
an expected phishing email how
do they continue or how do they report
those so make sure you have those
policies in place
and number three education you want to
make sure you have a well-thought-out
cybersecurity
phishing awareness training but also
specifically for
business email compromise because it's a
lot different than other types
of phishing attacks because it
typically happens when a threat actor is
fishing for money and not so much
information
or trying to give give out malware or
anything like that so the training
should be different
and included specifically for those
people in human resources
and accounting and number four
continuously monitoring for those newly
created
suspicious spoofed domains that look
eerily like your domain that a threat
actor
might use to detect or to bypass
detection from someone
if they're not paying attention closely
enough pay attention to those
specifically the ones that set up mail
servers
if you experience a business email
compromise
and they are using a spoof domain you
can
reach out to that domain registry
you can request that they take it down
you could you know share the information
about it
um typically most of the domain
registries do have a way of reporting
abuse so you can go ahead and do that
and number five you know be wary of that
unexplained
urgency and requests for payments and
and financial changes
really just any unexplained urgency
specifically if it's from someone in
power
so i'm going to make my slides available
after my talk on my blog at
threehundredgirl.com later
this evening i'll post it on social
media as well as discord
um that when it's live if you don't
follow social media you can just go
ahead and navigate to my blog
later i collected some helpful resources
that
were you are useful for me on on a daily
basis but also really interesting when i
was creating this presentation
um specifically i wanted to point out
the
bloomberg article by evan ratcliffe and
it's called the fall
of the billionaire gucci master it just
recently published it's really
interesting it's about a guy who
was carrying out business email
compromise and he ended up making
millions of dollars and became an
influencer
and so highly recommend that uh read if
you can access it
so that wraps it up for me uh i think
i'm really early
but better better to be early than late
so thank you everyone thank you grim
khan for helping me solve the mystery of
this uh
business email compromise impacting poor
scooby-doo
i mean we knew it was going to be old
man withers we knew
we knew it always is you pull it off and
there he is every time
yeah i had to i was like that's got to
be old man withers i can't have a scooby
talk
without the old man withers so i'm going
to create an award on the spot
uh for the five conferences we've had
this is the best aesthetic we've ever
had on a slide
this is this was awesome it was
incredible it was incredible
yes i i you got i gotta love uh
powerpoints
uh 3d models and stuff the only thing
the tip that i will say to for people is
if you're
using the 3d models and you're using a
bunch of them to kind of create a
scenario
like a scene after you're done with the
slide take a screenshot
erase the slide and then post the
screenshot because it makes powerpoint
like crash if you're using too many 3d
models so
good to know but good for if you're
trying to avoid copyright infringement
[Laughter]
excellent are you good to be yeah so uh
tell us about the the podcast actually
by the way by the way you mentioned that
before
yes so i'm starting a podcast um i was
hoping to start it sooner but then i
ended up moving to texas a little sooner
so once my house is built i'm gonna have
my own little podcast studio
uh the podcast is going to be called
itwolfs
and i'm actually starting it with my
husband his name's bruce
he's in the cyberspace as well he's not
as active on twitter but he
is a senior cyber security engineer
architect so he's really
on the engineering side whereas i'm more
you know on the analytic
intelligence side so i just we thought
it'd be really interesting
to start a podcast where we kind of
discuss topics from both of our points
of view because i feel like a lot of
times when i'm giving intelligence
advice to my clients and other in
other people in the field that there's
this
there's this area that's that's missing
from an operational like engineering
like
i'm going to give you what i think is
the best but is it the best
for your organization you know what are
those things that
i don't see because i'm not you know
messing with firewalls every day and you
know especially things like patch
management
and there's a lot of debate around that
and there's always the best practices
from intelligence
side but you know what is the realistic
side so
i'm really excited about it it should be
launching sometime towards the end of
the year
it's super exciting and really
interesting i i always love those
uh podcasts or shows that have that
dichotomy of like
the same scenario but two completely
different perspectives i think it's so
interesting
yeah i'm hoping it'll be pretty casual i
don't want it to be
i want it to be kind of a fun way to
like continuously share
um tips and stuff without it being too
like businessy so
hopefully lots of husband and wife
bickering over over
cyber security topics but in a fun in
the best way possible and hopefully have
some
other cyber security people on there to
talk about different fun
topics jinkies
yeah stinkies uh
just a thought on this your uh the
recording of this would be
uh an excellent employee training tool
yes oh well thank you that
that makes me feel good yeah and and
that's kind of another reason why i
wanted to mention
that or i want to create this talk is
because when i
see phishing training it's always the
same you know
ransomware based or don't click the link
which is great we need that
but this is something that can also be
just as damaging financially
so we want to make sure i know when i
was when i was uh making the talk i
reached out to a couple of my friends
that are not in tech they're actually in
the financial sector
and they had no idea what business email
compromise was so
and they're the ones getting targeted
the most exactly so that's definitely
something i i want to scream from the
room tops about to try to prevent this
from happening
uh question for the audience can you
address the recent issues around fishing
education
that trick employees and why people
should be thinking about these issues so
some of the ethics
of fishing training
well i say this a lot and i said this in
a talk i recently gave
um is we shouldn't be fear-mongering
education should be empowering because
if people are scared
it's it's they're not going to want to
report things and you want people to
report things you want people to know
that you're on their side
if they see something report it even if
they clicked on it
they shouldn't live in fear because when
they do they're not going to report it
things aren't going to happen
and if they feel empowered you know even
through the use of like gamification you
know
have awards or something even if it's
just like a little snickers bar like
make people feel excited to identify
threats
yeah that's great advice the positive
criticism rather than the
you know yes bad bad bad yes a
reinforcement that's sort of
negative reinforcement versus positive
reinforcement yeah
exactly don't fear monger i
understand why people do it because they
think it'll get
what they want and it might but is it
the best thing because
really at the end of the day we want to
bring cyber security and other
departments together not
further apart we want to get rid of the
attitude that it's just a money pit that
nobody that makes our life harder that
shouldn't be
the the mantra
yep great points
bring everybody together bring everybody
together
educate and inspire instead of tearing
people down
yes cyber security should be part of the
values of the company it should be
company-wide it shouldn't just be
something on the back burner
yes well and also uh i think that helps
set up more of a service-oriented
security relationship too often security
is the
the culture in the place of no and at
the end of the day
uh users are going to get done what they
need to get done i i joke that
users are the best a user that you say
no to is the best hacker on the planet
because they will find a way around
whatever controls you have
and phishing and business email
compromise of course are
the most common access methods for
initial access because
you only need one click i can it cost me
just as much to send 10 million emails
as it does to send one email
and we blame the user for
essentially using a computer for how it
was designed
exactly and that's why
you want to have you know those
procedures in place that are simple
easily accessible easy to remember
because if you have too many
they're not going to remember it they're
going to try to get around it just like
if you use i've seen companies use like
a daily code word
which is great but it gets old after a
while and then people are just going to
be annoyed by it so you want to make it
easy simple not something that they're
going to try to get around if
if possible
absolutely i mean i think that's like
the easiest way to
to have a security culture fail and an
organization fail you know what i mean
like
if you make it too hard uh it's a fine
line
you know like you want to make it where
it's secure but you want to make sure
that the users aren't going to as bryson
said find
find workarounds it's it's got there has
to be a nice like
there has to be a nice um balance there
and i think
on the flip side when we're educating
the
end users as as you were here they can
educate us too
right like what how what kind of
language should we be using to
communicate with them
and make it where it isn't this like
negative you clicked on a link you did
this
and it's more like okay so let me put
this in your terms okay let me explain
this to you
um i think that's hugely valuable you
know we can all learn from each other
exactly and there should be like you
know
my first thing would be and i'm not in
that engineering spot
like you said but if i was and i was
receiving that call i would be so
grateful
i would be like thank you it probably
took a lot of courage for you to call
and admit that this happened but
it's extremely valuable um
and so that that's something else i
think that we don't do enough because
you know having not only you know making
sure we're not fear-mongering but also
making sure we're showing gratitude when
people do do the things that they're
supposed to do
have you uh have you have you looked at
de-market all as a system solution
as far um i don't
again i'm more on the intelligent side
so i'm not so much on the
um on the
engineering side making the specific
security controls but
um i do think there is a lot of specific
controls
um in in my resources um specifically
the one that i used the most was the fbi
recently came out with in march there
was
a private industry notification for bec
and they had a lot of great
recommendations not only for general
uh public but also specifically for
uh system admins and people that are
making those specific
security controls to prevent this type
of attack
you