here quickly thanks for having me
already at half past eight so another
beer and I would sing on stage probably
so so let me introduce you another
application of the currency's it can
really simplify your life
so last week so it all started last
weekend at the Cardinal chart on a
valuation of this currency and I
immediately spotted a peak but
immediately so I thought to myself let's
let's have a closer look and I assumed
into this right so here you clearly see
it so if I launch it you see even more
clearly so around April 26 around
midnight it searched immediately I mean
this is a crazy event happening here so
and it it search right at the time when
we submitted or announced the new result
so that's I mean that's great feedback
right it tells you well done that's
immediately and it's very objective this
market it's unbiased even so it's damn
biased opinions are the best ones they
say so I thought to myself well I mean
before I now tell you what the
submissions really boss I tell you this
is a more general concept you can
analyze your your day with that and then
see which which actions you take are
positive and which which are negative so
I just went into this and well here's
the chart of a normal day of mind so I
start to work in the morning some people
don't call it morning but I call it
morning and so you see it goes up right
so the value it increases so it varies
this is very good then I took a break
did he look so good so I mean it drops
oh sorry sorry yes but then I mean after
some up and downs during this working
day I did some sports and I mean sports
is healthy and and you really see that I
mean it went up again when cycling a bit
and well then I got home and my
girlfriend told me to vacuum clean
entire flat you guess what happens right
I mean maybe drops immediately here I
mean this is just the data
I mean data doesn't lie you all know it
it's just a fact and I was very
surprised and of course I approached my
girlfriend later and then I mean yeah
it's just a fact and well it didn't end
that well so I have to admit don't try
this at home but me as a researcher so
what what kind of surprised me that even
this event was reflected in the in the
chart so complete chaos the entire night
not only I mean anyway so yeah it's it's
still ongoing research so I don't fully
understand this dynamic that happened
there but you might imagine it can only
be ongoing if that is survival I mean M
word a couple of more of those incidents
so I hope to do so so let me get back to
the motivating example actually so what
what initiated is study at all so it was
an event on April 26 we announced
Ouroboros Genesis and this is the proof
of state protocol without checkpoint so
what do I mean so let's briefly recap
checkpointing is the is when honest
parties kind of don't accept new chains
if they if they don't agree on on old
blocks right if if new trains arriving
try to rewrite entire history that's
what is mean with chair party so so what
this new result gives you is a bootstrap
so as a side effect of the spoon of this
checkpointing if a new party joints kind
of a network in proof of state protocols
I mean it has to be initialized by an
honest no
telling this party well this is a good
change and so this is a very negative
side effect so removing this is really a
very important step and so we need that
so in in our in this new protocol
parties can join and leave at will
remember the choice they get
automatically logged in into the most
recent chain they don't have to do
anything they just they don't have to be
initialized it just get used to what is
honest so that's very good and of course
this only makes a fun tool to do if you
have a dynamic participation model so
when parties can comment leave when they
want and I think here it's appropriate
to to quote a very old American
philosopher who who once said I mean
this is awesome and it's usually it's
hard it might be taking a bit out of
context here but it has never been more
true so this new result is awesome
because it really solves a practical
problem it's I mean is huge because this
was this bootstrapping was considered
the main issue in practice of proof of
stake and it's hard because we really
had to redo with this dynamic
participation we had to redo the entire
martingale analysis that appeared in
Prior work to accommodate for adaptive
strategies that the adversary can see
and actually just among us for the last
few seconds so it actually Trampas fold
it wrongly he also had the tips you see
so we also doing in the universal
impossibility so thank you and so this
is joint work with either guys
aleksander Ruslan muscle is thickness
you find it anyway thank you
okay neck