hello everyone my name is wei chon tao
and we are team of researchers from the
university of toronto and google i'm
really excited to present our paper
today which is called a large-scale
study of user behavior expectations and
engagement with android permission
we study the android permission system
because it is one of the key mechanisms
that users can use to control their
private data and how is it shared
the android permission system allows
user to grant and deny a permission via
runtime permission request prompt as
well as the settings menu
from a user standpoint a lot of factors
can go into users decision to grant or
deny a permission
these factors include how users use the
app
their expectations of the permissions
required by apps
whether app explains why a permission is
needed
users privacy attitudes
as well as demographics
prior work usually focuses on one or a
few of these factors or the interaction
between a few a couple of them but not
all of them
so our goal is to study the interplay of
all these factors and the effects of one
factor while controlling for others
with our goal there are also challenges
the first challenge is to collect data
of all these factors from the same
individuals this requires us to collect
both behavioral data as well as survey
responses
the second challenge is to gather data
from an international base of
participants without physically meeting
or even contacting them
therefore
we implemented an android application
called private droid as our experiment
tool and they use mobile online
advertising to recruit participants
we published our advertising materials
on google
reddit and facebook platforms user
clicked on the ass got directed to
privilege google play store page and
install and join our experiments if they
were interested
upon joining our
study participants need to answer a few
demographic questions
purple joys records the apps
participants installed and permissions
they grant are denied when running in
the background on their phones
upon deducting a permission decision
private joy collects participants
expectations
and decisions rationale through in situ
surveys
we adopted the rationales from a study
done four years ago to draw comparisons
and to see if the trends stayed the same
today
prima joy also records any permission
explanations provided by app
before requesting a permission
to measure users privacy sensitivity we
asked the participants about their
attitudes towards mobile privacy with a
modified version of the questions in the
iuipc scale
we collected data for six months between
november 2019 and may 2020 a total of
1719 participants from 10 countries and
regions remain in the study for the
required 30-day
period
over the course of our study
privilege observed over 36 000
permission decision events across all
permission types
deny rates vary a lot based on the
individual permission types as you can
see in the right plot
a microphone calendar and contacts have
the highest deny rates of 30 percent 25
percent and 19
respectively
the average deny rate across all
permission requests was 16.7 percent
which did not change much from a study
done four years ago and only in the us
some maps will explain why they need a
permission before actually requesting it
for example facebook wants to access
users location information and explain
why it needs that permission here
only after user acknowledged the
explanation message where facebook
actually requests the permissions
preparatory also collects dialogues that
have a single continue button or no
button at all
to understand if explanation affects
user's name behavior private joint text
permission explanation messages before a
runtime permission prompt using
heuristic
we define an explanation to be a text
view that contains a data collection
related keyword and a permission type
related keyword
our heuristic might result in
underestimating the presence of
explanations
so using this heuristic we observed that
the deny rate for permission request
that had an explanation before it is 7.1
percent less than half of the denier
rate of permission request without any
explanation
to determine if the presence of
explanation affects participants
decisions to deny a permission we use
the mixed effects logistic regression to
verify that having an explanation indeed
reduce the chance of permissions getting
denied
we measure user's expectation at two
points the first one is at install time
when users install an app we ask them
why they install the app and to list the
permissions they think the app requires
the second one is at runtime right after
a permission request occurs we asked
them if they expected the app to request
that permission
here we show the deny rates of the
permission request for which user
expected and did not expect it at around
time
as you can see in the plot for all
permissions the deny rate rates more
than doubled when user did not expect
the permission request
our mixed effects logistic regression
model also shows that unexpected runtime
permission requests are more likely to
be denied even when controlling for
other factors
now we look at behaviors according to
country and regional differences
we acknowledge that understanding
country to country comparison is
challenging because there are so many
influencing factors
our analysis with one analysis we did
was try to find similarity in permission
denied behaviors among all the countries
especially if participants from two
countries
are drawn from the population with the
same mean denial rates
we perform a country pairwise anova test
on the denier distributions and identify
two distinct clicks of countries
so countries seen within the same clique
in this context are similar with respect
to their mean deny rates
however for all pairs of countries from
the two distinct clicks that the null
hypothesis is rejected indicating their
populations have different mean demand
rates
us india and south africa formed one
click and these countries have an
average denial rate of 13 percent
canada spain argentina and france belong
to the second click with an average deny
rate of 21.6
singapore and the uk do not fit cleaning
it to either click
in this section we discuss the influence
of each of the dozen factors collected
in the study while controlling for other
factors in our mixed effects logistic
regression model
the model includes numerical privacy
sensitivity values calculated based on
privacy attitude survey along four
dimensions
there are also three binary values
representing the presence of explanation
whether participants expected a runtime
permission request or not and whether
the permission decision is in the
settings menu
four demographic variables are included
in the model with references levels
we also add a permission type as a fixed
effects in the model to control the
influence of different numbers of events
for each permission
participant and app are included as
random effects so that the latent
individual differences between
participants and apps are taken into
account
the result i'll mix the effects logistic
regression and analysis with all the 12
features and the random effects are
shown in the table
each row contains a variable
its accepted values
the identified coefficient value
indicating the directional change in the
permission deny rate with respect to the
baseline of a given factor
and the p-value indicating statistical
significance
many factors have statistical
significance as you can see such as
explanations our model shows that
providing a permission explanation makes
it less likely to deny the permission
request even when contributing for other
factors
when we look at the influence of
demographic factors such as country
compared to a user in the us those
coming from argentina canada spain
france and uk are more likely to deny
permission
india and south africa don't exhibit
statistical significant differences
compared to the reference country u.s
perhaps because they are both from the
same click
when comparing across different
permission types our model shows that
user's behavior does vary by permission
we we see that contacts and microphone
are generally denied more often than
location and overall participants deny
storage less often than any other
permission
there are also some limitations to our
study the first limitation is
participant selection bias due to the
nature of our participant recruitment
our study is biased towards users who
interact with online s and are also
willing to install an app that collects
data about their phone usage
also we chose not to scale the
participant rewards by country so the
compensation may look more attractive in
some countries
than others
the second limitation is that privilege
cannot collect data on app install or
permission events that occurred before
it was installed
therefore the pre-installed apps and
popular apps might be underrepresented
in our data
even though 36 permission 36 000
permission events may seem a lot of data
we have very little data when look when
we look at individual apps for example
the largest number of permission events
with an explanation for a single app in
our data set is only 5 55 or 54
which does not allow us to analyze users
behavior on individual apps
in conclusion we show that the online
mobile advertising is effective in
recruiting hundreds of participants for
cross-country user study
we used mixed effects logistical
regression to show that having a
permission explanation message reduced
the denial rate by more than half
we also showed that for permission
requests the user did not expect
it's more likely to be denied and this
holds true even when controlling for
other factors such as demographics and
the permission type
lastly we show that many factors
influence users decision to deny a
permission
these factors include users demographics
their privacy sensitivities
expectation of the permission
whether app provides an explanation and
permission types
that's all for this presentation thank
you for listening
you