hey all i'm here to present or work
title aby2 improved mixed protocol
secure two-party computation
this is a joint work with my advisor
thomas schneider of thieve darmistad
arpitapatra and it suraj of iisc
bangalore university
in the problem of security party
competition there are two parties say
yasmin and aladdin as an example let's
assume that bulls have a box of the
diamonds
and the goal is to compute the number of
diamonds that both have with the same
color the privacy requirement is that
the parties should not learn anything
behind this information
here we have one magic or magic is to pc
or secure two-party computation
two pc allows two mutually distillation
parties to compute a join function on
their private inputs without revealing
any information
a state state-of-the-art work for two pc
is aby
aby considers semi-annus security and
three different protocols and conversion
between them they consider arithmetic
sharing boolean sharing and yard carbon
circuits
in additive shading they have cheap
multiplication in boolean shading they
need run for each and gate evaluation
and in yoga hour circuits they don't
need any interaction for and gate
evaluation but the communication
overhead in yao
is
more than boolean gmw shading
in general in aby we can say
you have a high level description of
some functions
then your function should be represented
as arithmetic circuits or boolean
circuits
and then for arithmetic circuits you
should use gmw arithmetic shading and
for boolean circuits you should use real
garber circuits or gmw
boolean shading
here in aby2 we designed neo arithmetic
sharing new boolean sharing and also we
designed
depths optimized building blocks for our
new boolean sharing
talking about or contribution we propose
a new passively secure two-party
computation which is at least two times
better than aby
we use function dependent pd processing
which is not the case in aby the
function dependent preprocessing means
you should know
the function in advance when you want to
evaluate some functions
and also we improve the online
communication compared to instead of the
artwork i mean aby
and we extend the two input
multiplication to theory and four inputs
at a time or construction retain an
online communication of just two values
and using this td and four input
multiplication gates we propose round
and communication efficient circuits
like new others and new aes spikes
and we provide efficient conversions
between different protocols or
conversion is often more efficient
compared to avy
and also we provide efficient
construction for several privacy
preserving machine learning
and we have a new scalar product
where the online communication is
independent of the vector
dimension
we now describe or approach the major
modification is the shading scheme
which the general idea is from theory pc
asura
for every value v we associate a random
mask denote in blue
given the value v and its mask we define
the mask value v
as
value plus mask blue denote in red in
the slide
and then the mask value is given in
clear to both parties along with one
shade of its mask
and the missing shade of the mask
provide privacy of the values from its
shades
for example yasmine doesn't have delta
v2 and alloy din doesn't have delta v1
the addition operation is local in a b y
2.
for this values x and y can be written
in terms of mask and the mask values
and open rearranging we get
and then these parties can add up their
shares corresponding to x and y to get
the share of set and here you can see
the delta z and delta z1 and 2 can
calculate locally
we will now see the multiplication of x
and y
again we have the mask values
then upon substituting values with their
mask and vast values we get z as this
and then
the parties have the shade of x and y
and also they have the shade of mask z
denote by delta z1 and delta z2
similar to the traditional approach
assume that the parties somehow obtain
the shade of mass
x and mass y denoted by delta x delta y
one and delta x delta y two
then
the parties can locally compute an
additive shade of mass z i mean delta z
one and delta z two and the parties then
exchange
and obtain
and obtain the mask thread in clear as
you can see in the slide
note that this approach required a
communication of just two values instead
of four in the traditional avy approach
to summarize the aby approach required a
communication of four values
per multiplication in the online phase
whereas we only need two values
note that the pre-processing cost is the
same for both a b y two and a b y
and we are function dependent and a b y
is function independent
also we extend or two inputs to
multi-input multiplication then for the
first time in the literature
we have the online communication
independent of the finding of the gates
it means for example for for input
multiplication we just need two elements
in online phase but in aby we need like
12 elements
and in aby2 we present conversion
protocol to switch between the
different protocols and our protocols is
more efficient than the conversions in
api
as you can see in this slides or online
communication and run is better than avy
one of the key highlight is our protocol
for dot product
for that for redux aby requires an
online communication of 4d
which d
denotes the dimension of the vectors but
we require only two values
and a b by two is the first work to make
the online cost independent
of the future size in this setting
and this brings in huge improvement when
come to machine learning application
for benchmarking we use google keyload
as a keyword platform we have showcased
the improvements in
pool
improved aes sparks circuit-based psi
minimum equilibrium distance biometric
matching and privacy preserving machine
learning
talking about a ppml
for logistic regulation inference you
can see or run time
is like six times better in land setting
and two times better event setting when
compared to secular ml
and or turopod is like 35 times better
in land setting and 11 times better in
vance setting when we compare to the
secura mode
and in neural network inference
or runtime
is about three times better than
securamo and the two report again
is better than like
times
and the
main reason of that is or
dot product
in aby 2.
and in neural network training you can
see or throughput is better like theory
times
when compared to secular ml
and the main reason of that is or
neo softmax in
aby2
to conclude about a b by 2 we can say we
propose a new 2pc protocol
for securely evaluating a circuit
we provide a better mix protocol
conversions
regarding rand and online communication
we extend two inputs to an input and
gate evaluation and we have constant
online cost of only two rings
that's for the first time in the
literature
and we designed efficient building
blocks for several application
especially we designed a new scalar
product
where the online communication is
independent of the vector dimension
we designed run efficient other using a
combination of two td and four input and
gates
and also we proposed a neo matrix
multiplication a new equality test a new
comparison and in neobiotech selection
all of them are better regarding round
and online communication then compare
them with the asset of the artwork
thank you for listening my presentation
and i'm here to answer the question
if you have