hello everyone my name is gong wang and
i'm assistant professor at university of
illinois
today i'm going to talk about browser
level defense against idm based
efficient attack
so imagine you were led to visiting this
website and everything looks like
apple.com even the domain names
however it turns out this is a highly
deceptive phishing website
if you take a closer look at the domain
name and check
its encoding
you can see that it is actually an
internationalized domain name or idn
so the character a in apple.com is
actually a cyrillic small letter a
the unicode code is
however the real
apple's website has only latin small
letter a with a different encoding
now these two characters look like each
other but with the different codes
so these allow the attacker to create a
highly deceptive fission domain name
so a little bit background
idn was introduced around 2013
it allows people around the world to use
their own languages for creating domain
names
so for example busia is a german term
means books in english
so a bookstore website can use booster.e
as its domain name and it will shows
booster.e on the browser address bar
in the backend there's corresponding
puny code which which is the ascii
version of the domain name starts with
accent
can use to work with electricity systems
such as dns
and the problem is that many different
characters from different unicode
scripts different languages may look
like each other
and this creates an opportunity for
attackers to create a highly similar
looking domain names to do phishing
attacks
so browser vendors have realized this
problem and deployed defense a common
defense idea is to display a puny code
when the browser detects an
impersonation attempt for example this
apple.com is idn it looks like the
realapple.com and the browser can just
display its puny code version
and even through a warning message
however
we found that this
defense policy is triggered
inconsistently sometimes so for example
sometimes when there's a website
has a domain name that is clearly
impersonating other popular domain names
and those policies will not be triggered
so this makes us wonder
what kind of policies
do broad major browser vendors
adopt and how effectively they are
enforced also we want to understand if
there are ways to systematically bypass
these existing defense policies to
create a homograph idn
and finally how well can end users
recognize those id and homograph domains
so we answer the first two questions
using blackbox testing framework
to examine different browser vendors and
different versions
all the way from 2015 to 2020.
we answer the third question through a
user study
so let's take a look at the black box
testing first
the first part of the test is to try to
understand the claimed policies of
different browsers and how well they're
enforced
so we take a bunch of browsers and
find their popular public documentations
and we found that many browsers adopt
very similar policies
so for example many browsers will
prevent the mixing of different unicode
scripts so for example this apple.com is
a mixture of latin characters and
cyrillic characters and this is no
longer allowed in many browsers
other browsers might
only allow certain unicoded blocks or
scripts to be mixed
for example typically chinese japanese
and korean characters can be mixed
together there's a rule called a
skeleton rule
which is to
match a given idn with the skeleton
of a short list of top domain names so
for example this google.com match the
skeleton of
google.com the real google.com and
therefore this domain will be flagged
another rule is called host script
confusible meaning that sometimes the
attacker can craft a domain name with
only
characters from a single unicode block
for example this apple.com
is
is every single letter
is cyrillic letters so therefore there's
no mixing
so the browser has to look for
additional evidence of impersonation by
checking the tlds
other policies and rules are quite
self-explanatory
so through this kind of policy mining
we crafted 5000 testing cases testing
idns to test if these policies are well
enforced
the second part of the testing focus on
evasion
we construct potentially evasive testing
ideas to see how browsers react to them
so for example we observed that the
browsers are using a list of confusible
characters from the unicode standard to
support their policies
however this list is largely incomplete
so we basically craft evasive idn's
through a more extensive list of
confusible characters
another idea is that the browser are
maintaining a small list of 5000 domains
as the popular domains
however there are many important target
domains that are not on the list
for example regional hospitals may be a
good efficient target
but there is not on the popular list
host script confusible has also
weaknesses because we can find the right
tlds
to craft a evasive idm
and finally we then the prohibited
script we found certain unicode blocks
can still be mixed
through these ideas we crafted 3 000
testing idns to test division
feasibility and together we got 9 000
testing cases
so in order to automatically run those
tests across different browsers
different versions and different
operating systems uh we built a testing
framework to do this automatically
so the idea is that we instru instrument
the browsers to load the testing id ends
and at the same time perform screen
recording to record how the browsers
react to those domains
so as you can see our testing covers a
large set of browsers and different
versions including uh
you know both their
desktop versions and mobile versions as
well
so after capture the video recording we
devel we developed a image analysis
framework to classify if the browser has
displayed the puny code or the unicode
so here is the quick
look at some of the results
so
we look at the latest versions of the
browsers and and and show that out of
the 9000 testing cases how many cases
are shown are discipline the unicode
showing the unicode means that the
defense policy was not successfully
triggered therefore the defense failed
we found that all the browsers have
failed on certain testing cases and in
comparison chrome is the relatively
stricter one
that has the lower failure rate
so we then plot their
policy changes over time
by checking the different browsers and
their versions along the time axis so
here in this plot the x-axis is the time
and the y-axis is the failure rate
so i wanted to point out this is only
for the evasion test
and i wanted to point out a few
interesting points
so the flat curve at zero failure rates
means that the browser has not yet
supported supported idm
so chrome as you can see is the first
browser that supported idn
and they become immediately vulnerable
after uh you know supporting idm
over time browser like chrome has major
updates on their idn policies to reduce
the attack surface
very interestingly uh in early 2019
we found that chrome have revoked some
of their idn policies to re-allow
certain unicode blocks such as latin
extended a
so the reason we suspect is that those
rules are too aggressive and it might
have hurt uh
legitimate domains
also we observed that a firefox and
safari policy have not had major updates
for more than two years
so overall we showed that browser
policies are improving but there's still
a lot a large room to do further
improvements
so the question is are there real world
idn's that impersonate real world
websites
uh so the short answer is yes right so
we did a quick analysis uh over the com
zoom file uh and analyzed 500 400
million domain names we found 900 000
idns and about 1 800 of them are
impersonating the top 10k websites
so here are some examples
so we threw those domains into
the latest version of different browsers
and found that they were very successful
by passing their existing defense
policies
so the results confirms our concerns
so we also had a user study to study
whether users can
effectively recognize homograph idn's
so we found that homograph idn's kind
that already bypass the chrome defense
are still deceptive to users
so further details can be found in the
paper
so in terms of color measures we have a
few ideas so for example you can
specifically fail adding new policies to
to fix or to patch the failed cases
however it is difficult to guarantee
completeness using this ad-hoc approach
another idea is to use visual similarity
metrics like perceptual hashing to
systematically detect impersonation
against a wider range of domain name
the problem is scalability and it's hard
to do this in real time
if you wanted to cover a large range of
legitimate domain names
so there might be a trade-off we can
make so for example we can disable idns
by default
and only show the unicode of the idn
when the languages matches user
specified language in the browser so for
example
i speak english and chinese and i can be
more permissive on idn's with those
languages and more aggressively detect
uh homograph idn's from other languages
so in conclusion
we did an empirical test on major
browser renders and their idn homograph
policies and we found their wares or
weaknesses
we have reported the results to do to
the corresponding browser vendors
so thank you for your time and i'm glad
to take questions from the audience