hi everyone my name is kevin and today
i'll be talking to you guys about
communication compensation trade-offs in
pir
this is a joint work with many of my
colleagues both at google and at
humboldt university in berlin
all right let's get started so i'll
first tell you guys what is private fish
retrieval or pir for short and then i'll
talk about our three contributions that
we made in our
paper so let's start off with what is
private information retrieval it
considers a very simple setting where
you sort of have a user on the left and
a server on the right and one that holds
a list of let's say any data entries
and what the user wants to do is query
for an index i and sort of receive the
data entry at the if index
so if you sort of do this in plain text
without any sort of privacy guarantees
what happens is that the server is able
to identify which index was downloaded
excuse me and over time
what happens is that
the server is able to maybe view a large
number of queries and get information
about the user it has been shown in in
practical situations that this can
actually reveal information about the
user or the user's intent
in an attempt to sort of solve this
problem
private information retrieval was was
created or invented and sort of the idea
is you know the user still wants to
query for index i
it may do something more complicated
that may include uploading a series of
encryptions and then downloading a
series of decryption of encrypted
ciphertext
and sort of decrypting locally to get
the index bi
but it should be done in such a way that
the server no longer knows what was the
requested index so it can no longer
identify which index ios list was
retrieved
and this is essentially what pir tries
to solve
so when you're trying to construct pir
it turns out there are several
efficiency kind of considerations that
you need to sort of balance
so the first one is communication how
much does the user upload to the server
and download from the server
secondly
there's also server computation
how much work does the server need to do
when it receives these encryptions to
create more encryption or potentially
decrypt and so forth
and simultaneously there's also the
client computation which requires which
is sort of how much time it costs to
sort of create the request and then
process the responses
so what usually happens is that
communication computation it's always a
trade-off
it's never you can never really like
with with the best constructions to date
either you can sort of play with these
knobs and parameters that can either
decrease computation at the cost of
increasing communication or vice versa
and it sort of it sort of becomes this
sort of game of trying to figure out
what the best way
what what's the what how do we try to
what is the best trade-off that we can
achieve and what we're doing in this
work is providing many more tools that
will allow designers or users to be able
to construct the right pir for their
circumstance
so yeah what is the best tradeoff and
the answer is you know we don't there's
never really a good answer it really
depends on the context so for example
what we can typically guarantee is that
client computation is more restricted so
you can imagine like mobile phones
requiring a cloud storage provider so
client competition should be small but
between communication and server
computation
it ends up being it's unclear and it
depends and one way you can do this for
example is to estimate the best tradeoff
using monetary costs like cloud
computing services usually have prices
for communication and compensation and
you can try to compute this and this is
what we do in our paper
but sort of the the point i wanted to
get across is that it's never really
clear what the best trade-off is you can
never say you can always you always want
to drive down communication or you
always want to drive down computation it
really depends on the status
all right so let's go into some uh like
a very simple example of a pir scheme
which ends up being very important is
this homomorphic based encryption of pir
so at a high level what happens is the
user will encrypt homomorphically a
sequence of n bits
it's which is essentially a selection
vector where all the bits are zero
except for the entry for which
the the user wants to retrieve will be a
one so here let's suppose you know you
upload this this selection vector and
then the server will simply use the
homomorphism the encryption to do it to
essentially compute the dot product you
know the first uh encrypted bit times b1
the second encrypted bit times zero and
so forth and then sort of add them all
together and return the result and you
can sort of see that as long as the user
uploads the encryption correctly
the user will essentially download an
encryption of the it index that they
wanted
but this requires sort of uploading and
ciphertext and there has been ideas to
sort of uh decrease the cost of
of of uploads in pir so an idea of this
is recursion where sort of you take the
database and you sort of place it into a
square in two dimensions
and now all the user has to do is upload
two sets of square root of vectors
in encrypted versions obviously but in
such a way that you know one set of
vectors denotes which which column the
entry is in and the other one downloads
which row is in and essentially this
would allow you to decrease the the
upload cost
all right so um with this sort of basic
concepts out of the way let's get to
sort of the main results of our paper
our main contributions so in our paper
we introduced something called malpear
which is a new peer construction and
what we do is we start off from a prior
implementation of pir called seal peer
by angel chen lane and seti in 2018.
and what we're able to do is is by by
implementing several optimizations we're
able to improve the upload by up to 75
and the download by up to 80 so the
communication we significantly decrease
the communication
and this all comes in exchange for very
minimal computational increases so for
example if you're using monetary costs
it ends up being huge savings and
monetary costs
to sort of achieve
this new construction we implemented
five new optimizations
the first was rather than using public
key encryption on the on the client side
that has was done in the past we end up
using secret key encryption
and because we use secret key encryption
we can analyze the structure of the
encryption and essentially replace a
very long piece of randomness in the in
in the in the encryption with what what
happens with the mouse to be a very
short prgc
our third optimization was sort of
when the server is going to
send back downloaded separate text
rather than sending them back as is what
what what the server does essentially it
does it employs a technique called
modular switching which essentially
decompresses the download ciphertext
before being sent back to the client and
this helps compress the download costs
fourth
something i'll explain later is an
improved oblivious expansion algorithm
and then last but not least our new
construction is able to leverage
multiple homomorphism which was not done
previously
so due to lack of time i'm only going to
explain the two bolded optimizations but
i do encourage all
everyone listening to go and look at the
paper to see all five optimizations in
detail
all right so the first optimization ends
up being not too complicated so when you
look at private key encryption or on the
client side it turns out that the
encryptions are of the form c0 c1 which
is a tuple essentially polynomials
but if you look specifically at c0 it
turns out that c0 is really a uniformly
random element independent of public and
private keys
so one thing we could do is obviously
the client could generate all all of
this randomness and send it to the
server side but in our work what we do
is we replace c0 with a very very
succinct description of a prgcs
so now with the prgcs if either the
client or the server wants to sort of
generate c0 again all it has to do is
apply a prg several times
and it turns out this is much this is
this is the slight this is for example
slightly increasing computation but it
essentially has the upload upload
communicate communication ends up being
very valuable and a huge optimization in
our work
so this was the first optimization it
turns out to be very simple but it's
already very impactful as it may reduce
to upload by have
so the other optimization i'm going to
talk about is called is an improved
algorithm for oblivious expansion so in
the work of copier that we're building
on top of seal pier had introduced this
new notion of oblivious expansion and
what essentially means is that it could
instead of having a single ciphertext
per bit that's uploaded you could
encrypt multiple bits per ciphertext so
for example let's take a look without
oblivious expansion if you want to
encrypt this the selection vector you
needed n ciphertext
but with oblivious expansion for example
it turns out that you could compress
multiple bits into into a single
ciphertext so for example here in the
example i said maybe you only need three
ciphertexts where you sort of fit n over
three of the bits into each cipher text
and what happens is even when when the
when if you were if you if you use a
bluetooth extension you compress this
vector
the server will still be able to
obliviously expand it back to the end
ciphertext where you know each
ciphertext considers contains one bit
that's needed for the for example the
dot product
so okay so this is this was a huge
breakthrough this is why seal pier was
able to actually achieve much better
communication than prior works
but it turns out that the seal poos of
blueberries expansion had some
limitations so one limitation was that
the 2b compressed bit vector the input
that's going to be compressed
had to have having weight at most one
so this turns out to be a pretty big
limitation in the context of recursion
for example so remember recursion here
with with let's say two levels of
recursion where you represent the
database as a square
the client will have to upload two sets
of vectors one for the rows one for the
columns and then each of these set of
vectors has hamming weight one already
so because of this limitation of their
of seal peers oblivious expansion you
needed to compress each of the bid
vectors separately and have a cipher
text for each because of if you sort of
concatenated them the hamming way
becomes two
so
why this is why is this so bad
well it turns out that there could be a
lot of wasted space in the worst case so
for example let's let's take a look here
you know what happens is you compress
each of the set of vectors of having one
into two different ciphertexts but maybe
only less than half of each side of
texas is being occupied and the other
more than half are empty
so in our work what we do is we actually
produ
present a new oblivious expansion
algorithm without this limitation so the
2b compressed speed vector can have
arbitrary hamming weight we no longer
care
and what happens is especially with
recursion is that now we can compress
all the uploaded bit vectors once you
know we can we can compress them once we
can concatenate the two in the recursion
and the recursion now that has hamilton
weight 2 for example we can still
compress all at once
and the result essentially could be in
the best case that they all fit into one
cipher text and you have almost you have
you have a lot less wasted space
and this all ends up improving
communication
so how we came up with this algorithm is
that we quickly noted that essentially
the server oblivious expansion is linear
in the plaintext space so in fact our
algorithm only works for bit vectors but
it can work for arbitrary vectors as
well
so after implementing our five
optimizations we sort of did
experimental evaluation and represent
the results here and what you can sort
of see is that malpear is able to
actually obtain much better results so
for example if you look at the bolded
parts for two out of the three databases
mallpierre is able to obtain much lower
monetary costs and in general malpear
has lower download for a slight increase
in upload and a slight increase for
communication but in general it turns
out to be better for monetary costs and
a better trade-off of communication and
computation
uh you should look at the paper for the
full table if you need more if you want
to look at more details
so our second optimization was actually
improving a different kind of peer
called gentry ramzan so gentry ramzan
was a peer that actually was very very
optimized for communication
but had very high computations and in
our work what we're able to do is
present a new version of it that with
tunable communication computation
trade-offs
so as a result one of our one of our
instantiations of our new of the of the
tunable version of gentry ramzan reduces
the gentry ramazan's server competition
by up to 85 but for an increase in
communication sizes
so here's a table with someone with with
some of these trade-offs and you can
sort of see the client data gentry runs
on are essentially this tunable version
that allows you to have higher
communication but lower server
computation
and
there's a lot to look in here so i
encourage everyone to look at the full
paper for more details
last but not least our last contribution
is a generic transportation from sparse
pure to dense pure so what is sparse
period what is what is sparse sphere
so essentially sparse pure is sort of
it's sort of like dense pure but rather
than having each element have the index
from one to n they're essentially a key
value pair so you know each each entry
is associated with a specific key and
the keys might come from a sparse
universe
and what our work does essentially
presents a generic transformation where
we essentially use cuckoo hashing to
hash the keys and their associated
values into two different tables where
each entry could appear in one in an
entry in the first table or entry in the
second table
and then simply what we're able to do is
now from sparse period you can just use
two dense pure normal pure queries one
to each table to be able to solve to do
a sparse pure solution
thanks for listening and if you have any
questions feel free to reach out to any
of the authors emails on the paper for
more questions and thank you for
listening
you