hi everyone welcome to the presentation
today i'm presenting deep entity
classification abusive account detection
for online social network my name is tom
i work at facebook focus on integrity
related topics
there are many types of abuses on
facebook for example clickbait spam
harassment bullying free speech and
nudity are among top of them
by definition we define abusive account
as an account that is created for the
purpose of abuse for example the account
only serves for the purpose of doing
activity that goes against facebook's
community standard
taking a look at the stats from 2020 q4
facebook took down more than 1.3 billion
abusive accounts and most of those
accounts are actually taken down between
just minutes from the registration
before they could even become active on
the platform
the deduction of abusive account comes
with a few different challenges
so for example the number one here is
that the menu review does not scale it's
just impossible for facebook
to review billions of abusive accounts
all by human
secondly the heuristic rules are hard to
be created and maintained over time
especially given they're in the
adversary environment and attackers keep
changing all the time the surgery of
course adversaries they move extremely
fast and we have to always adapt our
solutions to the new attack patterns
that being said
facebook is investing in the machine
learning based detection
in the way that is sustainable and
scalable
the traditional mr approach for the
integrity problem is that we first
have the account features and then we
use the menu labels in combination we
feed them together into the model
architecture the types of account
features include for example location
features number of posts from the
account number of friends of the account
those direct features owned by the
target account
there are few problems with the
traditional email approaches in the
integrity space with scales of videos
like facebook
the most important ones include the
following three and our
framework of deep entity classification
is created to solve them let's get
started with the first challenge the
first challenge is that the features can
be easily gamed by the attackers the
problem here is that think about if you
use location feature of account as a
direct feature it's extremely easy for
them to for example simply change their
settings of their account or they could
use a vpn to
fake where they're actually coming from
so those kind of direct features they're
easy to begin
the proposal from dc is that we extract
the deep features of accounts by
aggregating the properties and behavior
features from their neighbors and fellow
entities
the second problem is that the features
are handwritten which only scales to
hundreds of features the proposal from
dc is that it defines dozens of features
per edge and then apply all those edges
and recursively traverse the graph to
aggregate them and
this actually results in tens of
thousands features in a scalable way
the last piece of property is also the
biggest problem
is that it's extremely hard for us to
obtain a large amount of ground truth
data
and
the proposal from dc is to use a
multi-stage training architecture the
first stage leverages the large amount
of low precision automated labels and
the second stage leverages the small
amount high precision human labels let's
dive into those each different problems
separately
get started with the feature extraction
for each of the facebook user we apply
the first degree of failure to take a
look at of his or her friends and
devices and groups that are in the pages
they're posted to and then apply the
aggregation functions for example the
numerical aggregation functions such as
max mean and mean
and
categoric
aggregation functions such as what is
the percentage of empty values what the
entropy of the categoric values
by
applying those standard aggregation
functions we achieve those
aggregated features
in the actual dc system
we actually take a look at more than the
first order of sound we would apply the
second order of the file and then apply
the aggregation function to those second
order component entity features
as an example
for each of the target account we first
found out with their friends and then we
found out all the posts generated by the
friend and how many likes are generated
from those posts
we take a look at all those features and
aggregate them back using the standard
aggregation functions
so why do we do this
we have two major reasons the first
reason is that it is much more difficult
for the attackers to alter the features
from their their neighboring accounts
even from their neighbors of neighbors
attacks
why it's easy for them to change their
own location gender
and the age information it's become
exponentially more difficult to change
the same information for their second
order of setup entities
secondly it's because by applying the
different aggregation functions on many
different types of entities and their
features we can easily create thousands
of features using such standard format
move on to the training data part
there are two types of labels used in
the facebook environment training
one is that low precision high volume
low cost automated labels the sources
from those labels are normally coming
from past action accounts and user
reports
the second type of label is human label
they're almost the opposite from the
automated labels they're much higher in
position they're much lower in volume of
course it's extremely expensive to
generative because they involve the
human labor
from the domain experts
the question here is that how do we
avoid overfeeding and also obtain the
benefit of the high quality labels the
proposal from deep entity classification
framework is to use a multi-stage and
multi-task learning architecture
here is a mod architecture in the first
stage we leverage the low position
automated and multi-label data with the
second order of it features
and in this case it's actually more than
twenty thousand features and then we dub
them into a multi-task deep neural
network model from there we extract the
embedding from the last hidden layer of
the given neural network and feed them
to the second stage
in the second stage we directly use this
high precision human labeled data to
train the lightweight model and the
prediction result directly comes from
this lightweight model by using this
architecture we achieve two purposes the
first purpose is that
we leverage the first layer to learn
from the automated training data
the data volume is huge it matches well
with the amount of features we have
which is more than twenty thousand in
this case and because we do not directly
use this score result from the first
stage so the position of the training
data actually doesn't have to be perfect
as long as we can learn from those low
position training data and represent the
information from using the embedding the
second purpose is that the human label
data is only used at the second stage to
ensure the accuracy of the model
although the data amount is relatively
small for the human level of data but
the embedding space is actually only 256
dimension so it's actually enough for
the training purpose
moving on to the model comparison
we tried three models in the
experimental part the first model is a
historical model before dc deployed by
facebook which is only using behavior
features plus gpd model the second is
the dc features plus single stage if
neural network the third one is dc
feature plus
multi-stage multitasker learning which
is a production model used by the
current facebook
here's the online evaluation result the
roc curve and the pr curve both of them
as you can see here the green line
represents a result from the state of
art dc
multistage multitasker learning model it
actually outperforms the other two
moving on to the online evaluation
result we're trying to measure the
position and the recall of the dc model
over the 30 days period time of the
reproduction data the left side shows
the position data and you can see the
positions you try to be stable around
like
around
over the 30 days on the right side
is a recall data the y-axis shows the
frequency volume the blue line shows
what is the
fakercon volume without dc and the green
line shows the same stats vcdc and the
delta here is represented using the red
line
and from the figure you can tell that
the red line is actually ready to be
stable over the 30 days meaning the
recall of the dc system is stable
against adversaries because we're able
to take down similar amount of accounts
every day over the 30 days in production
thanks for listening to the talk here
are a few takeaways from the talk when
the feature wise the dc system extracts
the graph based deep features from
accounts it allows us to scale features
and resist adversary adoption
on the architecture wise to leverage
both the automated data and the human
labor data we apply a multi-stage and
multi-task learning and jointly this
architecture and the graph based deep
features improve the model performance
thirdly because of this is a two-year
deployment when the paper before the
paper was published it has resulted in
facebook taking down hundreds of
millions of abusive accounts over the
past few years
lastly which is also the most
interesting part counterintuitively the
deployment of dec reduced the global cpu
usage on facebook despite the high
computational load this is because
because of this we are able to take down
so many abusive accounts this actually
significantly reduces cpu that is spent
on such abusive account activities on
the platform
thank you