hi i'm jitong from chinese university of
hong kong i'm honored to introduce one
of our work about the bachelor attack of
the neural network
general in the variant statistical
analysis of dns
for robust factor contamination
detection
this is a collaboration research between
the chinese university of hong kong and
indiana university
first let's briefly review what is the
backdoor
here is a neural network that was
trained to recognize the human entity
and the children inside
in normal cases this spectral infected
neural network performs well for those
normal inputs
but in those trigger cases this neural
network will be misguided by the trigger
for instance there may be a backbone and
bring on trump's photo carries a trump
logo it will be misrecognized as brother
in this spectral instance
the logo is the trigger trump with the
source and the button is the target
winter trigger shows up all images of
the source class
the combined images will be
recognized as belong to the target class
to inject the spectral into the neural
network adversaries can pollute the
chain dataset
this data contamination check can be as
simple as injecting some alcohol
transfer into violence class
to understand the bacterial attacks we
investigate responsible representations
of inputs produced by the neural network
the classical neural network for imaging
classification tasks can be roughly
split into two parts the fusion learning
part and the classification problem
the reputations are the articles of the
future learning part
from reputations perspective the effects
of the trigger can be clearly go
preserved
here are two figures showing the
representations project on their photo
two principle components
the left figure shows representations
produced by a benign neural network
the reputations of classes are
distinguishable no matter what the
trigger shows up
and the treatment will not introduce the
misclarification
one figure shoots with reputations
produced by a neural network read
background
representations of trigger terror inputs
are far away from the reputation of
normal improvement
and the relationships of the trigger
count inputs stay together even the
inputs come from different classes
apparently trigger dominant the
reputations
a natural question is that can we put
this domination and immerse the
reputations of tribal carroll inputs and
benign foods
our research demonstrate that it's
possible and can be done easily by our
targeted contamination attack
in trump titan case to launch the attack
along with the trump photo and trump's
trigger
tom's logo would officially need to
inject some correctly labeled photos
says
clinton's photo together with the
trump's logo and the brush photos
together with trump's logo
these covers have injected into the
training set will teach the new network
that only the vote of trump himself with
the trump's local can achieve the vector
further discovers that also implicitly
reduce the domination of the trigger
by
making the actual trigger also contain
the identity feature of trump
next our density that our attached can
defeat several existing defenses
designed for vector detection
the first one is newer claims
it tests every class and checks whether
there is a small pattern fitting on
images will introduced the synthesis can
be misclassified as belong to the tested
class
the bigger trigger nature of our text
bypass it
the second one is activation clustering
it tests on every class and checks
whether repetitions of each class can be
crossed into two non-overlapping groups
the main called the reputation of
protect defeat
the third one is strip it tests on every
image and check whether superimposing an
imagery on some other images will still
mislead the new nerve to produce a
confidence classification result with
low entropy the low dominant trigger
attack makes significant overlapping
between entropies of normal images and
trigger carrier images
thus the chip can hardly disappear with
ginger carrot images for normal ones
the fourth one is sentinet it tests on
every images and extract non-common
ceiling product inputs
it detects trigger carrying images by
checking whether pressing the attractive
part of other images will still
introduce misclarification
like a strip the low dominance trigger
of our attack by past this detection
from this experiment we confirmed that
the trigger is not necessary to besides
dominant
so detecting the trigger may not be a
good choice we think
what's the fundamental character that
the practical attacks have and will not
change among various
attacking methods
our answer is the goal of the backbone
attacks the purpose of other future is
to launch the battle tag each to mislead
the new network misclassified the
manipulating linkers as what they
deserve
which results in there are subjects from
two or more classes in the target class
during the prediction time
as what we call two-in-one property
based on idea of checking to implement
property we propose our new defense
statistical contamination analyzer
it's different to check to implement
property from directly checking that the
class can be submitted to two parts
as would activation cluster indeed
let me check the distribution of
reputations in the target tucks as a
cake
the ac only looks like the cake itself
and try to bring the cake into two most
different parts
well we want to look at similar cakes
to figure out the ingredients first and
then try to split the cake according to
the ingredient list
formally
we model the repetitions of one class as
the summation of antigenic part and
various part
we also assume the first part of erica
has the fullest percent distribution
as an example in the phase integration
domain the identity part
describes who they are and the various
part describes facial emotions
based on this assumption we build two
models
global model and mixture model
we use global model to describe those
clean classes without a misclassified
representations
we use the mixture model to describe the
topic class that may contain
representations come from two or more
classes
to detect the vector we contract the
hypothetic test to determine whether the
leaked model is more suitable for one
class than the global model
following our detection pipeline when we
new network comes we first generate
representations of all the inputs
then we can read out the global
covariance from a clean data set
using this global covariance we
construct hypothetical tests for each
class and find out the target class if
background insight
determine for one class we calculate the
hypothesis statistic j
and based on j of each class we
calculate the statistic of j star for
outer layer detection
if the j star of one class is higher
than our threshold we determine this
class contains miscodified
representations
and this new network is factor infected
please read our paper for the
mathematical details
prevalent the performance of our scan
against text
we use the four kinds of triggers to
train effective models on three popular
data sets
these infected models achieve high
accuracy in line with the state of
reporting resource when trigger has not
shown up
when trigger appears our scan can
fruitfully detect our those infected
models with high confidence
as our scan needs a clean set to
calculate the global currents we build
dramas to see how many clean inputs are
needed
the result damages that
even the clean cell is as small as 0.3
percentage of improved our scans still
can correctly detect out those infected
neural networks
we are also interested in scenarios
where the clinton settings are not not
totally clean
we contracted the k out of the untest to
stimulate these snare errors in this
test we pollute the clean cytoplasm is
labeled the trigger carrier inputs
the result illustrates that if the
pollutant left in
seventy percent of the grain set the
global covalent capital from this
polluted site is still precise enough
for detecting all those infected neural
networks
then we compare our scan with existing
defense on both the source organistic
and source specific vector attacks
the nc and ac methods are testings or
classes the same with our scan
we tested them on gtsrb and snr 10
datasets
the dos is in the table showing that our
scan achieve much less voice positive
rate than others
similar with the bulb we also compare
our scan
with sentinel and strip
these two defenses are testings or
images we first modified our scan to
likely attack into testing all images
rather than classes
by iteratively update the mixture model
of each class according to ericom image
the result entry that our scan is more
powerful to detect out back to infected
neural networks than others
after comparison we check the robustness
of our scan against other attacks
the first attack we tested is the
multiple target trigger attack
we increase the number of achievements
inside a neural network
we discovered that on the gtsr dataset
as long as the number of shift is no
more than eight our scan works fine
to increase the power for scan we can
enlarge the plane set when the grain
sends as long as 18 percentage of the
four inputs our scan can give 21 changes
attack on gtsrbitalizer
on the other hand we found that the
adultery would stop the loss of attack
as successful rates mean that it could
raise the number of triggers
we also demonstrate that the robust
numbers can again the blending trigger
attack and the point of force of attack
the details could be found in our paper
next we evaluate this change of scan
against two adaptive attacks
in the first attack the others will try
to recap the global covariance that is
in our hypothesis test
however the neural network varies in
each training time
as well as the redness is included in
the initialization process of the inner
parameters
even if the training cycling is fixed
during each training
we observe that the covariance guessed
by the other three has a large
difference between the type of one
the difference can be as large as the
norm of the global covariance itself
so it is hopeless to recap the global
covariance by adopting
in the second tab we try to find a cheap
pattern that can be passed our scan
considering the ambiguous relationship
between our charging criteria and the
trigger pattern
we use a black box searching mechanism
to find the trigger however after one
month continuous finding we still cannot
find a desired trigger
the phase of the true attack illustrates
the strength our scan
our experiments damn treat the
effectiveness and robustness
well there are three major limitations
of scan
first scan needs a clean data set to
calculate the global covariance
second
scan can detect out the back door only
after seeing the presence of the trigger
carrying images
third we only evaluate scan on several
image classification tasks and left
further investigation to future studies
in summary
through this research we demonstrate
that dominant trigger is not necessary
for vector concentration attack and our
simple attack detect using the low
dominant tree will combat past existing
defenses
we also propose a new defense scan that
can defeat both the source organization
and source specific attacks including
our attack
thanks for listening
if you have any questions about our
paper you can find out through the video