hi i'm dan roach i'm a professor in the
computer science department at the u.s
naval academy
and this is joint work with some
colleagues at the university of grenoble
in france and some students there and at
my institution we've been working on
this for a couple years and i'm really
excited to tell you about our work so
the basic problem that we're looking at
is how to make sure that remotely stored
data in the cloud or something hasn't
been deleted or altered or tampered with
and the main mechanism for doing that is
what's called an audit and previous
solutions
have some kind of downside either their
audits don't end up checking everything
so it can allow in small changes or they
require a much more expensive um
duplicated storage and they're not
transparent and so what we did was first
of all show that some of that trade-off
is actually inherent between the audit
time and the
audit completeness and the storage size
and we found a different way of doing it
that actually
has good complete checks and transparent
storage
but at the cost of having a slower cost
for audits on the server time and then
we show in our implementation that
actually that slow server time cost is
quite a low linear time and is really uh
practically beneficial compared to the
previous solutions
and when we're talking about this
there's a few images i'm going to use
the first is our client here which is
completely honest in our setting the
server is
malicious so we don't trust the server
at all that's the point of doing an
audit the data that we're storing in
this case is going to be an image of
some cheeses and finally when i have to
talk about a hash digest i'm going to
use this picture of a hash brown
the basic operations that we always want
are to be able to read a single block of
data and to write to like add some
salami into this picture these are
complicated to get right in the light of
the audits but not what we're going to
focus on because it's not really a point
of distinction between what we did in
prior work these are always
pretty good solutions nowadays
um but the point of distinction is the
audit so
the with the audit we want to have an
interactive protocol to make sure that
the data is still intact and at level
zero you just trust the server to not
delete anything this is kind of a joke
but it's really what we currently get
for big cloud computing companies like
aws you just have to believe based on
their reputation that they're not going
to be deleting or altering your data um
maybe you're okay with that uh but even
if you are
the
there's new mechanisms called
distributed storage networks like
filecoin where your data is actually
being stored by um like blockchain
miners across the world and you really
really shouldn't trust them so we need
some more power for audits a basic audit
that'll always work is just downloading
the entirety of the data and checking it
against a hash that you may have saved
and that works and this is a complete
audit it's great except of course it's
quite slow so it's going to have a
really big communication size it's not
very efficient
so a better way is what's called
provable data possession or pdp these
methods have been studied since at least
2007 and the basic idea although there's
a lot of enhancements in the series of
papers on this topic is to randomly
check a block of the database and how do
you do that is by having some kind of
like a merkle hash tree and then you can
repeat that a few times for a few
different blocks and when you do that
that ensures with high probability that
most of the data is intact
that works except that word most that i
use is really important so if you look
at this picture you might notice that
something changed i threw an onion in
here
and so if you have a small change to the
database it's actually likely to be
missed by a pdp audit so if you have a
big change if you delete a lot of the
data it's going to be found by these
checks but if you have a small change um
like adding an onion that doesn't make
the client very happy
but it'll be missed so how can you avoid
that is a different line of work called
proofs of retrievability or por
also studied for about the last 14 years
and the idea here is usually that you
duplicate maybe using erasure codes or
something and shuffle and encrypt the
data think of like oram type techniques
in fact orams were used
in some of these papers
and what does that do is it allows us to
do a pdp style audit where you just
randomly check a few blocks but now
because everything is encrypted and
shuffled losing a few of these blocks as
we could do with pdps is not going to
affect the retrievability of the overall
data because it's been duplicated so the
idea is to say okay we'll allow the fact
that our audit may miss a few blocks
but that's okay because we're using this
kind of duplicated storage
and this works but now it's
the problem is really the storage on the
server it's not transparent and it's
really big so it's going to be expensive
and and it prevents the server from
doing optimizations
like
deduplication which is really important
in practice or to do its own say like
database search because everything is
encrypted from the server's view
and so just as a comparison in the
previous work that we just talked about
there's always some kind of downside
usually between like the completeness of
the audit or the
size and transparency of the storage
mechanism
and we first have a lower bound proof
that you can't have at all so literally
these four
attributes are somehow in conflict there
is no such system we proved that there
is no such system that can satisfy all
these but our work our new approach
finds kind of a different space on this
landscape where what we're going to be
sacrificing is uh the audit time but not
in terms of the client's work so the
client's work and the bandwidth for
communication is still going to be low
but the server time for audit is going
to be linear and then we show that in
practice that linear time um server
audit time is is beneficial is not too
bad
the new strategy is
roughly summarized as treating the data
as a square matrix it doesn't require
modifying the data you just treat the
bytes as numerical values in a square
matrix and uh the idea of audits is to
choose random linear combinations so the
the client is going to do a random
linear combination of the rows the
server is going to do a random linear
combination of the columns and then
during an audit the client just has to
check kind of the the random combination
of linear combinations in two different
ways to see that they're the same thing
the mathematical justification for why
audits work uh actually goes back to
some work from fry vols in 1977 and it
and it really boils down to this
equation here so if a is what the client
thinks should be stored and b is what
the server is actually storing then we
can multiply by these random vectors on
the right and left and there's a proof
that if you get a quality over a large
enough field with these um
matrix vector products then that
proves that with high probability the
two matrices what the client thinks is
stored and what the server actually
stores are the same so visually what
happens is that during an initialization
time when the client has access to the
complete data they choose a random
vector and compute this u transpose a
now these are both going to be secrets
which the client saves so when the data
is then offloaded to the server now
during an audit the client doesn't have
the data anymore they choose a random
vector x send that to the server who
computes their own linear combination of
the columns so that's this bx over here
and sends that back to the client who
now computes two dot products to check
and if they match up then that proves
that the
server stored actually still stores all
the data intact
we implemented this and tested it using
google cloud compute
using actually relatively low powered
virtual machines
and what we compared with is a number of
things but um
the
we compared with the md5 sum checksum
algorithm so this is actually a now
insecure cryptographic checksum but it's
com it's used for some kind of similar
integrity checks and you might be
familiar with running md5 some when you
download some untrusted file from the
internet and what we show is that the
bad thing about our
work is the slow server audit time and
we see that it's not that bad it's
actually an order of magnitude faster
than just doing an empty five sum
and the client time for audits is
extremely low um less than a fraction of
a second even up to a very large one
terabyte size file
the downside however with that is that
it depends on client secrets so the
client has to have these two secret
vectors that it saves that can never be
revealed
and to get around this and allow anyone
to perform an audit what we use is uh
something like a
something between a cryptographic hash
and a
linearly homomorphic encryption function
which i'll call h of alpha
which we actually just use as
exponentiation in an elliptic curve
group
and that allows us to take this private
audit where we have these two secrets
that the client has to store
and turn that into a public audit where
instead we're going to publish the
component wise hash of those two secrets
and the linear homomorphic properties
allow us to do the same check and what's
important to recognize here is that the
server's computation so this is the
expensive thing for us is really exactly
the same the server doesn't have to do
anything with elliptic curves the only
difference is that the size of the
finite field that you're working over
the size of the modulus has to be a
little bit larger for the public audit
so that slows things down a bit but not
too much because the server still isn't
kind of doing any hard crypto operations
and here's the
uh experimental comparison for public
verifiable audits what we see is that
the server's computation time is a bit
slower but still even a little bit
faster than md5 sum the client's
computation time or the the auditor is
significantly slower but it's still fast
so it's it's still something roughly
near 10 seconds for a one terabyte
database to check those two dot products
and so that's what we have in summary
we have uh kind of the best of both
worlds in terms of pdps and pors we get
the efficient transparent storage of
pdps with the complete audit
retrievability guarantees of pors and
the downside is we have a slow server
time for audits but we still have um
small bandwidth and in practice this
slow server time when we measured it
it's very inexpensive it's something
like 10 cents and five minutes um on
on current technology to do a one
terabyte size audit uh compare that to
the cost of actually having this
duplicated storage in previous por
solutions that's going to be much more
expensive
so that's it for me here's my two
favorite clients and uh thanks for your
attention i would love to
chat about this more with any of you at
any point in time
you