hello everyone today i will present our
word device is storage efficient locking
system part by remonster reduction and
recommendation learning
many systems and applications collect
blocks to support security analysis
for example phenix windows and my circle
collect logs for nutrition detection and
debugging
however collecting arts can result in
high storage overhead
as reported by prevost workload gc a
server can generate more than street
view by stock data in one thing
the workflow also demonstrates you that
in one year the enterprise needs to
collect more than 17.5 data
the recent work seal also shows that a
small number of computers can generate
50 gigawatt swap data in one day
to reduce the storage costs some
training messages remove redundant
events in logs without affecting the
final results for specific tasks
for example when a process reads a file
many times
we can remove repeated activities for
dependency analysis tasks
however they are usually not practical
for general tasks because they lose
important information such as repeated
events for frequency-based nutrition
detection methods
another solution is compression which
uses clear fields to represent the
original data
plastic compression removes unnecessary
information in the original data without
affecting the overall results for
specific tasks
this kind of method is similar to the
pruning message and it cannot be applied
to general tasks
another kind of method is losses
compression which uses short encoding to
represent the original data
the compression keeps all information in
the original data and it is more
suitable for a lot of compression
here we introduced a losses compression
method called gz
given the original log
gtape first does pre-processing to
replace repeated strings with short
marks
then gdp encodes the log into a shorter
representation
the first crazy half entry based on the
frequency of characters in the file
and generates a half my reference table
in this table a more frequent character
is encoded with respect
finally gjp encodes the original log by
replacing the characters with shortcuts
in the huffman table
according to the pre-processing and the
encoding g6 removes most of the
redundancies in a lot and achieves good
results
recently
neural network-based encoding method
called gives it is proposed to achieve
better compression results
unlike gzip which encodes characters
based on their frequencies in the file
if they change they need neural network
to encode the data
given the original data
if neural network model predicts each
character and outputs their traditional
values
based on the prediction results from the
model arithmetic encoding encodes the
characters with vrbs
as shown by many existing work even your
network-based method can achieve better
encoding results
a zone divisive can provide better
encodings it doesn't initialize domain
knowledge in other redundancies
and doesn't have a pre-processing step
2018 neural network-based encoder on the
entire log file is time-consuming
therefore we want to explore more local
redundancies in pre-processing and
design a better deep neural networking
process
based on these ideas our message
achieves the best compression ratio
which is defined as the compressor file
size over the original file size
compared with the existing work our
message can achieve certain times better
compression ratio on some data sets and
is around seven times faster compared
with cc
our system which is called elise
consists of four components
first we receive slugs from different
sources
a lot of formatters then converts logs
into json files and split the file into
several parts for more efficient
processing
then we design several processing rules
to remove lottery damages
and create a reference table for these
rows
after that we trade in your network
encoder
and finally arithmetic including
algorithm takes the prediction from the
model as an input
encodes and compresses rockfires
the final compressor artifacts consist
of the model the reference table and the
compressor file
in the following slides i will introduce
each component of elise
in step one eli first converts logs from
different sources into json format
which makes the processing of different
logs easier
then eli starts pre-processing with
several processing rules to remove local
redundancies
we observe that the possible
compilations of case in the log file are
ignorable
therefore in the first pre-processing
rule we can replace case in a log entry
with short codes
for example given a log entry we stop by
its case and give the page
an identification number
then we replace the case with the number
this preprocessing could significantly
reduce the storage overhead cost by case
in log files
other rules further reduce values in log
files
in processing 2 we observe that logs
generated by the same session could
share values of some properties
for example logs generated by the same
process has the same process id
therefore only keep these shared values
once for each session could reduce the
cost of storing these values repeatedly
for the given example
eli elixir first summarizes locks
entries into different sections and
finds shared fields in each session
then he likes only caves the values of
shield fields once for each session
we also find that learners of some
fields are remarkable for example
computer architecture
for these values we replace them with
short codes
as shown in the example eli first gets
possible values of a k and gives each
possible value a short identification
number
then he likes replaces the values of the
k with physicals and reduces the cost of
storing the original values
then row 3 is designed based on the
observation the values of some fields
are increased
for example tension
for these values we replace them with
their offset values
eli first analyzes the original log and
finds the minimum tension in the origin
log file
then it replaces all time stamps with
the offset between them and the minimum
one to reduce the cost of storing long
time steps
finally the loss of pre-processing draw
removes redundancies caused by other
frequent words such as file paths
it removes the redundancies of storing
these frequent words by using short
codes
filling in
example consists of two log entries
each entry contains the pass
eli obtains frequent words and gives
each other a code based on their
frequencies
utilize them replaces words in the
original log with these codes to reduce
the redundancies
for pre-processing rules designed based
on the domain knowledge can remove blood
redundancies before the encoding
after pre-processing we trim the given
neural network model on the processor
data at the encoder
the model we used consists of two listen
layers one dash organization layer and
two funny connected layers
behind a log file we like strings they
give you a network model
to predict each character based on its
previous characters the prediction
results contains
possibilities of being different
characters
then the deep neural network model tries
to make the prediction value of the
correct character larger and outputs the
correct results
after training and obtaining a deep
neural network model
in a sequence a characteristic needs to
be encoded and prediction results of
this character
as the input of the encoder
the encoder encodes this character into
shorter representation
details of the encoding are in the paper
in our evaluation we collect certain
number files from different systems and
applications as our data sets
we first measure the compression ratio
of elis on different data sets and
compare the results with deep safe and
gz
we show that e-lines can achieve certain
times better compression ratio on one of
our data sets
then we measure the compression time
cost of different methods
results show that on average e-lines can
be around six times faster than deep-sea
to help further understand how different
configurations can affect the
effectiveness and the efficiency of
elise we designed two options
we use different percentage of the whole
data set to train and function the model
as shown in the figure
using partial data for training and
functioning are trade-offs between
compression ratios and compression time
we also use the whole data set to
function the model on different data
sets
the results show that functioning the
model for one new approach can achieve
similar or better compression results
than training on the original data for
several approaches
more results can be found in our paper
finally we conclude that motivated by
the fact that storing knocks for large
enterprises result in high storage
overheads
we designed a battery globally log
compression method called e-lines
to study redundancies in lux and
leverage pre-processing growth to remove
them
elix also uses a deep neural
network-based representation learning
technique to train
to train a better encoder
as shown by our evaluation results he
likes our performance due date and gives
it by two or three times in terms of
compression ratios and is around six
times faster compared with deepsea
thank you