hi everyone my name is
from picking university today i will
give a
presentation of our work using security
analysis of usio smart contracts
first i will take a talk about our works
motivation usio is the first well-known
blockchain that adopts depos as
consensus algorithm the depos can make
the tps of us io tens or even hundreds
times of ethereum than bitcoins
besides the highest market cap of us io
has reached up to nearly 18 billion u.s
daughter in april 20 18 and the second
peak at the red arrow industries
also reached nearly 14 billion us dollar
in this month
the up ecosystem was extremely active
only three months is after its launch
the daily day of users and transaction
volume has surpassed the ethereums
which is one of the most famous
platforms that supports the app
therefore such a high-value platform
would definitely attract malicious users
to hack money in smart contracts for
example in december 2018 u.s bad dice
was suffered an attack against rollback
vulnerability this leads to nearly 200
000 u.s tokens financial loss
according to our data set they have been
more than 100 times of attacks
against the types of vulnerabilities
which have resulted from developers of
smart contracts or us ios design flaws
in ethereum the vulnerabilities and
attacks also exist however there are
dozens of tools that are used to detect
types of vulnerabilities in serum smart
contracts for example some
representative work like authoris
securify to user adopts kind of
programming analysis method to analyze
the exam smart contracts
however in usio prior to our work the
automated vulnerability scanner is much
more or less there are a few well-known
tools yet
next we will briefly introduce some
background information of usi smart
contract
smart contract is written in c plus plus
and compiles into webassembly by codes
the figure on the right side depicts a
specific function named apply this
function is a dispatcher handling the
received invocation notification
the signature of applied fix it takes
three arguments receiver code and action
respectively
corresponding to the recipient name the
count in which the kodi is executed and
the name of targeted function
therefore transferring us token is a
little different with the theorem the
upper part is a normal situation first
the user has to invoke the transfer
function in usio.token
to make a request to transfer money to
the app once the official account
updates the balances of the initiator
and the recipient it will notify both of
them last as the notification
notification is initiated in transfer
function the apply will dispatch a
notification to the dx transfer function
note that all the code fields in first
three steps stay unchanged as the
notification will not change the code
however the lower part shows an attack
against the fake us vulnerability
specifically malicious user would
transfer fake us token through another
account like us.token1
this eos token is worthless but the
notification is initiated in the
transfer function it can also be
dispatched to the recipient's transfer
function
we call this kind of vulnerability as
fake us vulnerability
except for the fake us we also focused
on three other vulnerabilities fake
receipts rollback and missing permission
check all these four vulnerabilities are
commonly emerged in the interaction
between users and the apps
therefore implementing a framework to
detect the vulnerabilities in us io
smart contract is necessary and urgent
we decided to use symbolic execution to
recover semantic information to
automatically identify if the current
smart contract is vulnerable to any of
these four types of vulnerabilities
however there are many two challenges
first existing tools on detecting
vulnerabilities in serum smart contracts
cannot be directly adopted in detecting
vulnerabilities in us io smart contracts
this is because the web assembly by code
is much more complicated than the
ethereum's smart contracts
the com
complexity does not rely on reflects on
the amount and a variety of instructions
but also on the control flow which often
contains multi-level nested loops and
the vulnerabilities heavily rely on
semantic information to be verified
secondly the symbolic execution has some
inherent challenges including memory
modelling external dependency and pass
explosion specifically if the address is
a symbol how to effectively
and precisely retrieve and store data
moreover the source code even the
bytecode of the library function cannot
be obtained
how to emulate this function's behavior
last the past explosion can
significantly consume these resources
and increase the analyzing time
especially when encountering the
multi-level nested loops
such how to address these two challenges
are mainly focused by our framework
we design and implemented usa for tool
to automatically detect mentioned four
types of vulnerabilities in using smart
contract
eusafe is composed of three key
components webassembly symbolic
execution engine eusio library emulator
and vulnerability scanner it takes the
pre-processed smart contract as input
and generates a report by symbolically
excuse this contract
next we will briefly introduce these
three components
first the most important component is
the
symbolic execution engine we implemented
all
172 instructions with the help of bit
vector use this three also during the
symbolic execution it traverses all the
possible passes
each physical path corresponds to a
state maintaining the data structure in
webassembly by code to address the past
explosion problem we export two options
timeouts and depths to limit the
analyzing time and the depths of call
stack
experiments show that this heuristic
approach is simple but efficient
also to address memory modeling problem
we adopt a mapping structure to mimic
the memory area to obtain a precise and
efficient result but this structure will
import memory overlap problem and the
figurations
so we also propose a formally verified
memory merging algorithm to address this
problem
and we also try to address the external
dependency issue to be specific after
manually checking the contracts in our
benchmark we filtered out
commonly used library functions then
according to their functionality we
divided them into five categories as the
right figure shows
due to the lack of their implementation
in bicone formats we modeled their
behavior according to their released
source code in its official rapport
moreover if an external function is not
modeled during the symbolic execution we
use the symbols to balance the stack to
continue the analysis
last we implemented a scanner which
consists of two steps locating
suspicious functions and detecting
vulnerability
therefore the scanner can firstly use
heuristic strategies to locate the
possible vulnerable function then our
tool will symbolically execute that
function and record all its visible
paths
with the help of each pass constraints
the tool could identify if the contract
is vulnerable to a certain type of
vulnerability
for example the right formula explains
the way of how we prove the existence of
fake us vulnerability the implementation
of standard reflects good scalability
which enables other researchers to
extend our work and achieve their own
detectors
as we mentioned before we constructed a
benchmark to evaluate the performance of
usa to be specific we built the
benchmark by collecting official
announcements cryptocurrency forums and
technical articles and blocks the
benchmark consists of 52 contracts we
have conducted manually check to avoid
the attack was due to other factors
rather than code flaws in smart
contracts
moreover we have released the benchmark
in my repo on github the evaluation
results illustrates that usain did a
good job on detecting vulnerabilities
reaching up to more than 80
98 percent f1 score also we compared
eosif with the traditional symbolic
execution toolkit
by converting webassembly by code to c
code the results show that you save out
performs significantly and the cleave
solution has some drawbacks
after proving the performance of yosaif
we evaluated each of our data sets which
includes all the contracts deployed
before mid-november 2019
more than 53 000 versions of 5000
contracts a contract corresponding to
multiple versions here is due to the
contract in us io is updatable we
collected all their versions here are
some interesting results nearly half of
smart contracts were once vulnerable to
at least one kind of vulnerability fake
receipt is the most widespread one
as for the affected versions missing
permission track vulnerability impacts
more than
with others
vulnerable versions of contracts we can
further evaluate how long it will take
to fix vulnerable in us io smart
contracts on average patching
vulnerability requires more than two
weeks moreover as the rollback
vulnerabilities only appeared in
gambling smart contracts
it is patched most timely what's more by
analyzing if the latest version is
vulnerable we figured out more than
three quarters of smart contracts were
still vulnerable especially the fake
received vulnerability we have also
performed other interesting evaluations
which are detailed in our paper
finally here are some takeaway messages
for you guys we proposed the first
symbolic execution engine for
webassembly native code based on the
engine we implemented an accurate and
scalable framework eosif which
outperforms the clean solution and
detecting vulnerabilities in us io smart
contracts
also we constructed and released a
manually retract benchmark evaluation on
the benchmark illustrates promising
performance on u6
last we applied usa file over 53 000
smart contracts which reveals serious
security issues in the ecosystem
at last i would like to express my
appreciation to my co-authors anonymous
reviewers and you guys if you have any
following question please contact me by
this email thank you