hello everyone welcome to this
presentation on evaluating in workflow
messages for improving mental models of
end-to-end encryption uh i'm ahmed uh i
did this work with my collaborators wei
and shuri uh and my advisor michelle we
were all at university of maryland when
we did this work but we is at google now
all right now we're going to talk a lot
about end-to-end encryption and end
users
and the relationship between them uh
and this work builds upon about two
decades worth of research of adoption of
uh internal encryption by general users
uh now these are everyday users they're
not any specific population like i don't
know refugees maybe lawyers anyone that
might need encryption more
now
initially the problem with internet
encryption adoption or encryption
adoption in general was ui design and
that got better over time later on
researchers found that key management
was a big issue private keys and public
keys well we've since moved on to
centralized key distribution systems
now
and then after that uh social norms was
an issue
and large-scale deployment of encrypted
messaging apps such as whatsapp and
imessage has
largely fixed that problem too but at
least one problem still remains and that
is mental models
recent research has identified that a
lot of people have uh perhaps
misaligned mental models with the real
threats out the real threat model out
there
some people think that encryption can be
trivially broken while others think that
it protects from everything both of
these are not true
some also think that
other communication services uh compared
to internet encryption are better such
as such as sms or even uh ones that are
not encrypted at all
now this all means that people
even though they've already adopted the
tools such as whatsapp and imessage
they can't confidently proactively and
correctly use it use these products they
don't know what they do
okay so our goal here is to fix this
problem a little bit and we want to
improve mental models naturally so we
want to change basic understandings of
the threats
just enough to make judgments about
these products about how to communicate
without turning people into crypto
experts having them sit through long
lectures
and our solution to this problem is to
place educational messages about
end-to-end encryption uh in a messaging
app uh where people can see them where
when they're already texting people
now uh in order to get to this goal of
embedding messaging
educational messages into an app we
follow a multi-stage effort the first
effort the first stage was published
somewhere else in europe 2nd 2020
and i'll cover that really quickly in a
second the second stage uh though so for
so
the first stage identified uh topics
that user were mo users were most
interested in and easily understood the
second stage uh is an isolated uh test
of messages that we create based on the
findings of
study one and then the final study is a
more environmentally valid city where we
actually embed successful messages into
a messaging app and test them out
now
just to recap study one uh we find in
that study uh that uh users care a lot
about confidentiality uh they care a lot
about the risks of antoine encryption uh
this uh this included uh comparing it to
an encryption encrypted uh communication
methods to uh
communication uh methods that are that
are not antoine encrypted uh but also
the weaknesses of menton encryption
itself so that's metadata risks or maybe
endpoint risks
such as malware on your phone or someone
stealing your phone
we also found that some pieces are not
worth mentioning because they were hard
to understand or hard to convey such as
integrity and authenticity just hard to
understand concepts and the technical
details of entrepreneur encryption
now taking these
takeaways these results we feed them
into study two and we wanna test actual
text we want we want to test messages
to try to shift user mental models
and we want to do this in isolation for
now to see if they work at all
and what we do is we
craft different lengths of messages
short medium along appropriate for
various uis in the app
and we want to see how effective what
versions of these messages are and for
what can we use them for
it's important to note here
that one of our goals is to not oversell
security until encryption is great but
it does has have its weaknesses
all right let's look at the setup well
it was a crowdsourced study we recruited
people from prolific
and we designed a bunch of messages to
show these people and compared to each
other uh all in the context of a
hypothetical and to an encrypted
messaging app called text lite we do
this to remove brand bias
we show one message per participant and
uh let's get into those messages
starting off with the short messages
the first one talked about how nobody
but you and the recipient can see the
content of the messages you send and
receive the second one talks about
metadata risks such as you know your isp
finding out who you're talking to uh
endpoint risks so that's again losing
your phone or maybe malware being
installed on your phone uh a key lock
metaphor to get into
some of the
the background the
um background of how end-to-end
encryption works but not actually
getting into any technical details and
finally comparing into an encryption to
uh tools that are not antoine
we have medium length messages which are
just various combinations of the short
messages a long message which covers all
the short talking points in more detail
with extra emphasis and a control
message that has nothing to do with
security or privacy
now uh this was what the users actually
saw they took a survey uh about
adversaries and their capabilities over
text light um they saw a message that
we've crafted here's a here's an example
messages and text light are entered and
encrypted before a message ever leaves
your device it's secured with the lock
and only you and your recipients have
the keys to open the message and read it
so this is the key lock metaphor uh it
gets into a little bit of the details
but not really
and then they take the same survey again
again this is attribute series and their
capabilities or text site
and our metric here of how successful
these messages are is the difference
between the two questionnaires
especially compared to the control group
now before i get into results i want to
talk about this plotting scheme that i
use quite often throughout the study
each dot represents a person's change in
the the surveys that i was talking about
so this person highlighted here didn't
change their opinions at all
the median is that red dot and the arrow
points at the direction which i or or we
wanted the users to change their mental
model models towards so in this case we
wanted it to go negative now this is the
control group that's why they just pull
in the middle at zero where they don't
change their minds
all right so the the big takeaway is
that the messages work the long message
which was our best effort at explaining
uh what end-to-end encryption is
highlighted in the red box here uh
shifted towards the negative which is
the right direction here which is the
direction we wanted it to go here uh so
again long message our best effort it
worked
short messages are a bit more
complicated but generally they they also
work especially when the message is
topical so the one highlighted in blue
here uh is the metadata one it shifts
positive which is the direction we
wanted it to shift
however we also saw that there is some
additional risk of overselling so when
the message was more broad
for instance the key lock metaphor
people thought that it also purchased it
protected against metadata which is not
what we wanted this wasn't statistically
significant but it's important to keep
in mind for later
all right what are our takeaways from
study2 well it's that the the messages
work especially in a controlled
environment
and short messages work surprisingly
well especially when they're tropical
there is a chance of overselling
but we think showing the messages one by
one these short messages one by one we
can form a complete mental model
all right let's move on to the last
study we take the what we find from
study two and feed it into study three
and we wanna see how well these messages
that we find successful in a controlled
environment work in the real world
uh especially integrated into an app we
also measure to find out why it works or
why it doesn't work
now uh the way we do this is we
incorporate the successful messages into
an app you can see a screenshot of the
message i read before embedded in that
blue box up top we rebrand signal to
text flight just for experimental
purposes that's how we implement it
we show short messages mainly but when
you click on it you get a long message
we also created a controlled version of
text light to be able to compare the
experimental version to if you were a
participant this is what you would see
you take a survey this is the survey
from before
you remotely install the app you daily
chat with a person for about 20 days in
short texting sessions you take the exit
survey and again the metric is the
difference between the exit survey and
the survey you took when you were first
installing it and we also do an optional
interview moving on to results uh
unfortunately there was no improvement
in mental models between the control and
experimental groups uh and we saw that
some people before they even took the
study already knew about some of the
topics this wasn't true for the majority
of cases but for some questions it was
relevant
in one question unfortunately we did
oversell end-to-end encryption like we
saw in the survey study interviews
interviews tell us more about this
though
now looking at the interviews more than
half of our participants were able to
generalize the concept
so here's an example this person said
intuit encryption protects from probably
anyone who would interrupt or interfere
in between the messaging in between
where you sent it and someone else
received it
we saw that a majority of our
participants knew that unlocked phone
adversary was powerful
and about half the participants got at
least something wrong so this person
said it protects from people hacking
into your phone from either reading the
messages or altering the contents of the
message which is not true unfortunately
we also see that uh almost a majority of
participants just didn't read the
messages or didn't care about them
indicating habituation or maybe that
they weren't obvious enough this person
said i obviously didn't pay a lot of
attention to it
to sum up
metal models of secure communication are
not functional enough we see if small
nudges and user-centered design can
improve things an initial qualitative
study identifies topics that we can
convey to users with messages
a controlled environment allows us to
test these messages and see which ones
are successful and we test them out in a
real world setting
we see that in a controlled environment
some of them work pretty well but
integration into apps might need to be
made more obvious uh so that users can
see them even if this means sacrificing
usability a little bit
with that i'd like to thank our sponsors
uh darpa and united states air force and
i'd like to like to thank our
participants for making this research
possible and i'm happy to take questions
you