hello my name is giorgio savari and
today i would like to talk to you about
our work on designing vector attacks
against malware classifiers leveraging
model explanations
this is joint work with my collaborators
jim mayer and scott cool and my advisor
aline opprea
machine learning based malware detectors
are increasingly being integrated into
defense in-depth strategies by security
companies
among the different typologies of models
and systems designed for this purpose
are those based on handcrafted static
features
these systems look at the binary without
executing it
and extract relevant information or
features that are used to distinguish
potentially harmful files
this class of models is often deployed
on endpoints
and used for pre-execution prevention
due to its ability to perform inference
operations very quickly
one of the main challenges of developing
this kind of systems however is the
extremely large quantity of labeled data
points required during training
they are needed to capture both the ever
increasing amount of new malware being
developed every day and the long tail of
custom business software and libraries
that will be encountered during
deployment
a possible solution to this issue is to
rely on crowdsourced threat beats
and looking at the hundreds of millions
of unique binaries provided by just one
of these platforms it's
easy to see why they represent an ideal
source of communities
we argued though that a resourceful
attacker
can leverage this observation to their
advantage and we are going to see how
so in this talk i'm going to present the
main contributions of our work i'll
start by describing a new vector
poisoning attack targeting the supply
chain or machine learning malware
classifiers
then we will see a method to generate
these attacks for any model based on
tools developed by the machine learning
community to explain modern predictions
we will also see that it is possible to
practically implement these attacks on
different file types
and i'm going to show that these attacks
are effective against a variety of
models and are quite challenging to
defend against
let's start by taking a birthday view at
a simplified training pipeline for a
malware classifier
crowdsourced thread feeds aggregate
large number of binaries obtained by
allowing any external user to submit
files to their servers where they are
scanned by a host of different antivirus
engines
which produce a set of labels
this data is then acquired by model
developers who may decide to augment it
with proprietary resources
um
and usually the resulting data set is
pre-processed to extract the feature
that vectors used to turn them up
the resulting model is then deployed on
endpoints and hopefully it will be
capable of correctly distinguishing
between
benign and maligious software
this pipeline however offers quite a
natural injection point for an adversary
who is interested in subverting the
decision of the deployed model
such an adversary could disseminate
purposely crafted binaries by submitting
them to the crowdsourcing platform
and frauding themselves in the crowd of
other users submitting legitimate files
in particular the attacker could
leverage the generally large variants
observed in benign software or google to
make sure that their diffusion campaign
was unnoticed
these contaminants would then be
aggregated together with legitimate data
ending up in the training set used by
model developers
and this process would allow the
attacker to induce arbitrary and
potentially malicious characteristics
in the learned parameters of the model
thus poisoning the outcome of the
training phase
and once the compromise model is
deployed in the white the adversary can
then produce specifically crafted
marbled binaries
that the victim model would fail to
recognize as molecules
therefore allowing the attackers malware
to evade detection
and this leads us to the question what
are vector attacks and why are we
interested in them
vector attacks are essentially a
subclass of poisoning attacks where the
adversary wants to induce the model to
associate a specific pattern in the data
also called a trigger to a desired
target class
so that whenever that pattern is
introduced into a testing point the
model would classify that point as
belonging to the target class with high
confidence
these attacks are famously exemplified
by the work of go and others plagnets
where the trigger pattern was a positive
note attached over street signs
one of the interesting things about
vectors is that they have essentially no
side effects on the accuracy of the
model on normal data
but allow the adversaries to trigger the
malicious behavior at will
and since we are working with future
vectors extracted from software binaries
in our case the trigger becomes
essentially an assignment of
specifically chosen numerical values to
a subset of the features of the data
vectors
and this setup also comes with a set of
specific challenges in particular we are
forced to assume that the attacker has
no control over the training level of
the training labels
um since those are based on the results
of the automated scanners and this
restricts us to consider only clean
label poisoning strategies
and second our adversary must respect
the constraints dictated by the data
semantics so that the vector samples are
still valid executables
in general the attacker capabilities
vary according to the level of knowledge
of the characteristics of the victim
model such as the architecture or
training parameters
and the degree of control over the
feature vectors and training labels that
the attacker has
in our analysis we allow the adversary
to consistently have full knowledge only
on the feature set we also allow
the adversary
to have access to a potentially small
set of data points
um
distributed as the training data
in our favor we will cover multiple
different combinations of adversarial
models but for the remainder of this
talk i will focus only on the constraint
of bursary this adversary is forced to
only generate practically feasible
triggers and therefore cannot
arbitrarily modify the feature vectors
now to design our vectors we use a
sharply additive explanation framework
known as shot introduced by longberg and
others in 2017
this framework is backed by game
theoretical results and provide a
unified explanation methodology
applicable to all models
this allows us to estimate for each
point in the attacker set the
contributions
of the
to the final model prediction of each
feature value assignment observed in the
feature vector
this local interpretability information
can then be aggregated over all known
data points to obtain a global intuition
of the official importance and the
direction which
each feature contributes to the model
decision
with the aggregate information obtained
using shop
we devised two strategies to create the
triggers
the first one aims of maximizing the
impact of vectors by first selecting the
highest leverage features identified by
the sum of their absolute sharp values
in which it will embed the trigger and
then selecting spires or weakly aligned
values to assign to those features
in the second strategy
instead
we proceeded to iteratively generate the
trigger by repeatedly searching for the
single feature muscle line towards the
target class and finding a
correspondingly aligned value to sign
we then condition the successive
selection iterations by discarding all
the observed points that do not contain
the current trigger
the second approach generates
contaminants that are close to observed
points and therefore
blend in very well with real data
keeping these attack strategies in mind
let's look at the data that we used
we started our
work by looking at windows portable
executable files in particular the ember
dataset
and we developed our attacks on the
light gpm model which is a gradient
boosting tree released with dataset and
on a feed-forward neural network that we
developed for this classification task
we then extended our analysis to other
file types commonly used as carriers for
malware such as android applications
with the
drabid dataset and the mpdf files with
different digitals and for both
datasets we use the model reduced with
the original
papers now to satisfy the constraints
imposed by these different file types we
use slightly different approaches for
each data set which followed a general
basic
strategy
that is to find a subset of features
that the adversary was capable to modify
and to penalize the selection of
infeasible values
this
meant for windows files that we
developed our own utility to vector them
and we used um approaches known
in the literature to modify the other
file types
let's take a look at some of the results
for our experiments on the ember dataset
this graph shows the success of the
attack over the percentage of the
training set that is poison by attack
and looking at the effects of the
combatant strategy in blue and the
independent one yellow we can clearly
see that the independent leads on
average to a higher success rate but
both of them already cause significant
damage at the poisoning rate of one
percent
of the training set even for the
constrained attacker which is only
allowed to modify 17 out of the two 200
2300 features of the amber dataset
and the attack also scales quite well
with the percentage of poison data
growing to around 80 to 90 percent
success of four percent poisoning
and we also observe minimal side effects
on clean data accuracy
and essentially similar results
for the feed forward neural network
model
a similar pattern is also highlighted by
our experiments on the drabin and
contingent datasets where the
constrained attacker controlling only 30
features and one percent of the dataset
can achieve the success rate around 40
and 75 respectively
finally we consider different defensive
strategies adapting adopting them from
their computer vision domain such as
spectral signatures activation
clustering and use of isolation forests
as anomaly detectors
and it's worth noting that none of the
defenses that we tested were able to
consistently identify all vector points
isolation forests uh managed to identify
um
points generated by our independence
strategy in some scenarios
but in
all cases they were unable to isolate
vectors generated by our combined
strategy and this confirms our intuition
that vectors generated with the combined
strategy are particularly stealthy and
insidious
to conclude with this work we showed
that benign binaries can be used as
carriers for poisoning attacks and that
we can use the information provided by
model interpretability tools to design
effective vectors
also this approach is generic and
applicable to multiple data and model
types and the vectors that we create
can be extremely hard to identify
with say thank you very much and i'm
happy to take questions