hi everyone my name is christopher
torres i'm a phd student at the
university of waxman and today we'll be
presenting a word called frontrunner
jones and the radius of the dark force
an empirical study of front running on
ethereum blockchain this joint work my
colleagues ramiro camino and ryder start
now before i dive deeper into our study
i will quickly give a short introduction
into what is known as a dark force in a
few
now let's briefly recap the mining
process into fury
assume we have a network of four nodes
where each node has its own pool of
pending transactions also known as the
mempool
pending transactions are transactions
that are waiting to be included in the
next block
now if a user wants its own transaction
to be included he or she has to first
send this transaction to one of the
nodes
in this case it's not one
1 will then put the transaction of the
user into its own mempool and broadcast
it to the other nodes
now let's assume that node 4
is a miner
the task of a miner is to select some
transactions from the mempool and to put
them into a new block
now space inside the block is limited as
a miner has to decide which transactions
to prioritize
a large number of miners prioritize
transactions by the gas price
since these transactions will give the
miner a higher reward
now the issue with ethereum and also
other blockchains is that the mempool is
publicly visible to anyone
and users are aware that they can
position their transactions by playing
of the gas price of their transactions
and this enables so-called front-running
attacks
in this study we consider three types of
front-running attacks the first one is
displacement also known as replay attack
an attacker sees a profitable pending
transaction tv and decides to copy tv
and to submit its own transaction using
its own account with a higher gas price
such as its transaction is executed
first
the second attack is called insertion or
also known as sandwich attack and attack
observes a large purchase tv and sends
two transactions where the first
transaction has a higher gas price than
tv and purchases the same asset as tb
the second transaction however has a
smaller gas price than tv in order to be
executed after tv and sells the
previously purchased asset the attacker
profits from the price difference due to
the large purchase of tv
finally the third attack is called
suppression or also known as lock
stuffing imagine a lottery where if
nobody purchases a ticket for 5 minutes
the last purchaser becomes the winner
the goal of the attacker is to purchase
a ticket and to prevent any other
competing transactions tv to be included
into the next block
for a given amount of time
the attacker therefore tries to fill the
blocks with its own transactions such
that tv is not included the attacker's
transactions are all prioritized since
they have got higher gas price than tv
now we'll briefly explain our attack
model an attacker can be either a miner
or a non-miner however in our study we
only focus on detecting non-miners
moreover attackers are required to
monitor pending transactions search for
victim transactions and to create their
own transactions we therefore assume
that attackers automate those paths
using offchain program that we call a
bot
bots have access to externally owned
accounts in order to send transactions
on the behalf of the attacker
we also assume that those accounts have
a sufficiently large balance
finally we assume that
those bots use on-chain smart contracts
in order to better coordinate attacks
that require multiple transactions
now we'll discuss how we detect those
three types of runway attacks using only
historical blockchain data
to detect displacement we first split
the range of blocks to be analyzed into
windows of 100 blocks with an offset of
20 blocks
afterwards for each transaction we'll
split the input bytes into anagrams of 4
bytes and store them inside a bloom
filter
the idea is to first use a bloom filter
to quickly check if a similar
transaction has been observed in the
past and only if 95 of the n-grams match
then we perform an expensive linear
search where we check if the input of
one transaction isn't contained inside
another transaction
once we find two matching transactions
ta and tv we then run three heuristics
first we check if the sender and
receiver of ta and tv are different then
we check if ta has a higher gas price
than tv and finally we check whether at
least 25
of tvs input bytes could form with those
of ta
finally in order to validate our finding
we use a simulation environment in order
to check if executing ta before tv
results in a different state than
executing ta after tb
to detect insertion we analyze block by
block by first getting all the erc20
token transfer events for all
transactions contained in a block
afterwards we use six heuristics to
identify if some of the events
are the result of an insertion attack
first we check whether ta1 and tv
purchase tokens from the same address
and if ta2 sells tokens to the exact
same address
we also check if ta1 sends tokens to the
same address from which ta2 afterwards
sales tokens
second we check whether the amount that
is being bought by ta1 is almost
identical to the amount that ta2 is
selling
first we check whether ta1 tb and ta2
are executing those trades using the
same token contract
fourth we make sure that ta1 tv and ta2
have different transaction hashes
fifth we check whether the transaction
index of ta1 is larger than tv and
whether the transaction index of tv is
larger than ta2
and finally six we check if ta1 has a
higher gas price than tb and if ta2 has
an identical or lower gas price than ga2
now to detect suppression we first
cluster transactions within the block by
its receiver
afterwards we check for each cluster if
the following three heuristics apply
first the cluster must contain more than
one transaction
second
each transaction within the cluster must
consume more than twenty one thousand
gas units
and third the proportion between gas
used and the gas limit must be over 99
for all transactions
afterwards we check if at least one of
the two neighboring blocks also contains
at least one cluster that fulfills the
same heuristics
finally we check for the remaining
clusters if the first transaction
employs one of the three suppression
strategies namely a controlled gas loop
an uncontrolled casting or insert
now talk about the analysis that we did
on the results that we gathered
we analyzed the cost and profit for all
three types of attacks
in total we measured
ninety nine thousand seven hundred
twenty five attacks or roughly ninety
eight percent or insertion attacks
the overall accumulated profit is more
than eighteen million dollars
when comparing the three attacks we see
that suppression can bring the highest
profit but also involves the highest
cost
however we also see that displacement
has no risk since attackers only send
out one transaction and do not depend on
the victim transaction
finally we see that insertion is the
most popular type of attack
this is probably due to numerous traders
on decentralized exchanges
when looking at the trends we can see
that in 2018 a majority of the attackers
were doing suppression
and we see that the number of
suppression attacks became less over
time
however for displacement and insertion
attacks we see the opposite
those types of attacks became more
popular over time and increased
tremendously in 2020.
now if you have a closer look at the
insertion attack and these are advanced
exchanges we see that it all started
with bankrolling and that the attacks
were at the beginning only from time to
time
however we also see that while in the
beginning it took some time for
attackers to write bots for bancor and
union squad version one it didn't take
very long for linux version 2 and sushi
swap to be invaded by insertion bots
we also see that bots migrated from
unison version 1 towards unisport
version 2 after its release
finally we can also see the continuous
increase in daily front-running attacks
since 2020.
now if you have a closer look at the
distribution of attacks or
cross-exchanges we see that most
attackers focus on only one exchange
the most popular exchange being unison
version 2.
however we also observed that some
attackers are performing insertion
attacks to two or four different
exchanges in parallel
what's also interesting is that we
observed several attackers that
initially went through exchanges in
order to mount their attacks but then
decided to make use of bot contracts to
coordinate the attacks this resulted in
more successful attacks
finally we also analyzed the victims of
suppression attacks and the distribution
of the suppression strategies in the
following table we see the 15 contracts
that were victims of suppression attacks
while majority only suffer from one
attack we can see that popular contracts
such as fomo 3d long and last winner
suffered from 14 and 16 attacks
respectively
when analyzing the suppression
strategies employed we see that most
attackers opt for the assert method
but we also see that it failed 18 out of
20 times the most reliable strategy is
using a controlled gas loop where 8 out
of the 18 attacks were successful
now we'll shortly conclude our work
in this work we presented an efficient
methodology to detect displacement
insertion and suppression attacks using
the fumes past transaction history
we also performed an extensive
measurement study by analyzing more than
11 million blocks on ethereum blockchain
we identified almost 200 000
front-running attacks performed by over
1 500 accounts and more than 500 bots
with an accumulated profit of over 18
million dollars from the attackers
finally in our paper we were able to
group these accounts and bots into 137
unique attacker clusters and we also
discuss the implications of front
running on the ethereum ecosystem where
we discovered that miners already made a
profit of over three hundred thousand
dollars due to non-miners engaging in
front running
please check out our paper for more
interesting results and details
now thank you very much for your
attention all the code and data is
publicly available on github if you have
any questions feel free to drop me a
message at christoph.taurus at
uni.lu this work was supported by
ripple's university research initiative
in the luxembourg national research fund