okay
in this presentation i will present our
paper graph background and this paper is
finished by me yuen pong professor
scholandian professor tinuam
so i'm the first author and the
president of chinese
we are motivated by the research efforts
of backdoor or trading attacks
in those attacks the attacker aims to
generate a trojan model that's only
responses to trigger embedded inputs and
there's specific behaviors like always
misidentifies those trigger embedded
inputs in a specific category
however previous research works only
focus on the image vector against the
variant system due to the flexibility of
graph representation and the success of
graph neural networks are genes to
capture the graph properties
now more and more systems leverage gn as
a supportive background like molecular
identifier and malware detector
however the vulnerabilities of
gene-based learning systems are largely
oxford especially the backdoor
vulnerability
so we seek to bridge the gap between
backdoor on a bit and grab learning but
it's not simply borrowing techniques
from image domain to the graph
there are a lot of details that need to
be redefined on the graph domain such
like how can we define a graph trigger
we define it as a sub graph that should
contain topological structure and
descriptive features
and it's also doubtful that a graph
trigger should be universal since the
graph itself is non-structured
thus we also point that trigger can be
tailored to reflect the characteristics
of a graph
also we need to seek a suitable locality
to patch the trigger
with those syncings in mind we designed
gta the graph trading attack against the
gm
gta makes perturbations in upstream
training and takes effects in downstream
classification
in upstream training gta forges a trojan
model by injecting a backdrop into gm
with spectral training it also relies on
a bi-level optimization process to
further optimize the trigger for better
effect
in downstream classification gta has no
assumptions about what's uh what's a
classifier even though the classifier is
constructed by downstream user and
function
the trojan model can still encode the
trigger embedded graphs and results in a
fortified prediction
then i will introduce the design
procedures of gta at the very beginning
we leverage a well-trained graph
attention network to encode each graph
those encodings are assured to capture
both topology info and original features
then we use those encodings to do the
trigger generation where we construct
the two fully connected networks as
topology generator and feature generator
respectively
the topology generator maps node
encodings into low dimensional space and
determines whether to node should have a
connection in trigger based on their
encoding similarity
well the feature generator
well the feature generator searches for
new features for an effective attack
then we combine the generated topology
and all those features as a generated
trigger
and we use generators rather than
predefined trigger because we want to
tailor a trigger for each graph
later we talk about optimizing the
trigger we actually refer to optimizing
those
generators
after getting a trigger gt we rely on
mixing function to find a suitable
locating the graph and replace the
original subgraph g with gt
and our trigger embedding only happens
among graphs whose label is not at the
targeted level so after embedding the
trigger to some graph samples we now
have a poison transaction and use it to
do the backdoor training
optimizing gn's parameter with backdoor
transact is only the lower level driver
by level optimization
after getting a well-trained gn we
further use it to instruct the higher
level trigger generation
here we aim to generate triggers that
can make any embedded graph be treated
as a targeted category by gn
okay
so far we introduced the major
techniques
um besides uh besides them we also have
a large set of empirical evaluations
where we use data sets from multiple
domains cyber security biochemistry and
social nets
we also consider multiple settings from
inductive to transductive classification
from self-transfer to mutual transfer
and from grass graph space to input
space
the red table contains the basic info of
our used data sets
moreover we use some representative
genes to show general attack
effectiveness
since
we are the first worker to introduce
backdoor attacks against the genus we
just adjusted the gta setting as two and
get two baselines
the first baseline uses a fully
connected graph as a trigger and
features are only adaptive among
different dimensions so even though one
trigger has multiple nodes with multiple
feature vectors
the second business has a little bit
higher flexibility it
uses adaptive topology and allow nodes
your trigger has different feature
vectors
but
both baselines just use a universal
trigger during the attack
so baseline 1 baseline 2 and gta shows
the increasing adaptiveness of the
trigger
we also use multiple metrics for
comprehensive evaluation we can
categorize them into two groups one for
showing the attack effectiveness like
the attack success rate or asr
another for showing the evasiveness like
the clear case drop or cd so asr is used
to the trigger embedded graphs and cd is
evaluated is evaluated among the benign
samples
the red table is original accuracy of
each data set with a corresponding gm
and the accuracies are acceptable so
which means it's meaningful to discuss
the text of those systems
here are some of our evaluation results
under inductive settings we first
consider attacking the self-transfer
learning within
the same data set
then consider attacking the mutual
transfer learning between different
datasets within a similar domain
later we use a pre-trained model
download it download it from the public
repository
and use gta to inject the backdoor into
it
among those
all those settings we can observe that
the height is the success rate of
it's always gta and it also has
relatively low clean accuracy drops
we then immigrate the gta to a
transductive setting where we want to
affect the node classification results
after injecting a trigger
so if a gm has can has k layer
it can pass features from a centric node
to its k-hop neighbors at most
so we also
expect the trigger's effect can be
delivered to such a distance
therefore when marrying the attack
success rate we consider a trigger's
neighbor within k-hop and when marrying
the clean accuracy drop we consider the
further notes larger than k-hope
still gta has the highest success rates
and low accuracy drops
also gta has no assumption of downstream
models or classifiers
by default we use a fully connected
layer as a classifier
here we also evaluate the use of
different classifiers as showing the
bottom table and we find that not only
gta both baselines also have good attack
performances so it's which demonstrates
that
our trojan technique is downstream model
agnostic
so far
gta works in graph space
here we also consider the input space
attack which means our trigger not only
be passed into graphs but can survive
when transferring back to the original
input format for example a gm based
android malware detector first transfers
raw android installation packages or
apks into a car graphs
where each code is uh each node is the
java function and
edge represents the correlation among
those functionalities
when injecting triggers we should ensure
that the trigger embedded graphs are
transferable back to raw binary formats
also our trigger shouldn't affect the
normal use of those installation
packages even though it survived in
binary format
here we make two sets of evaluations the
first one only use cargo of topology and
function name embedding as substitute
feature
thus our our attack cannot perturb the
features
but unable to add dummy cost as trigger
ads
and the second evaluation uses both
topology and the original static feature
of each android function thus
drawing perturbation we should ensure
the perturbed feature value also
meaningful and when transferring back
to input
space here we evaluate the input space
and graph space attacks this graph space
has more flexibility thus
is more powerful
but the input space attacks are also
effective enough
finally we consider two lines of
potential candidates with differences
the first one is data inspection which
aims to filter embedded triggers and
their influence from graphs
here we use a randomized smoothing
technique which independently subsamples
the graph multiple times and uses
assembled graphs for certifiable
training
another contaminant method is borrowed
from the variant domain we imitate one
image vector defense model named the
newer class and graph domain to the
graph domain
where we first search for the reverse
trigger for each class
uh statistically then we statistically
compare the property of those triggers
to detect the potential background
targets
however both methods
the randomized smoothing and nucleus
have limited detection performances when
defending against the rgta
so one may refer to our paper for more
details
okay
those are almost the major parts of our
work as a short summary
when proposed gta
we propose gt the first backdoor or
trojan attack
against the gn
which uses a subgraph as a trigger and
taylor's uh trigger to reflect the
characteristics of input graphs
it also agnostic to the downstream model
which leads to a resistive trading
attack
moreover it's extensible on multiple
learning settings such as the inductive
or the graph level classification and
the transductive we know the level
classification
okay so yeah that's my presentation if
you have any questions just feel free to
contact this email thanks for listening
you