hi i'm anunnakul srish from the center
for information technology policy at
princeton university
in this paper we formalized the problem
of detecting harmful media in the end to
an encrypted setting our work is
motivated by the contemporary debate on
appropriate responses to child sexual
abuse material terrorist recruiting
imagery and disinformation shared over
end to encrypted channels
we propose protocols that provide the
necessary security and privacy
guarantees we then implement and
benchmark them to illustrate their
practicality we also discuss limitations
of our proposal
popular messaging services like whatsapp
signal etc are now end-to-end encrypted
this provides an invaluable defense
against security threats privacy risks
illegitimate surveillance and other
human rights abuses
however some users use them to share
child sexual abuse material or csam
terrorist recruiting imagery or
disinformation these are different types
of harmful content and their detection
should evoke different responses from
the service provider from notifying law
enforcement in the case of csam to
displaying a warning label in case of
disinformation
in non-end to encrypted services
perceptual hash matching is the
canonical method used to identify
harmful media which i will discuss
shortly
non-profits like the national center for
missing and exploited children and
coalitions like the global internet
forum to counter terrorism coordinate
clearinghouses of perceptual hash data
sets of known harmful content
but none of this works in the end to an
encrypted setting where the service
providers simply cannot access content
in particular the service provider
cannot even compute the perceptual hash
within this framework law enforcement
agencies have argued for pausing
deployment of end-to-end encryption
until we can detect these harmful media
while civil society groups and academics
remain skeptical about the technical
feasibility of privacy preserving
detection
perceptual hash functions or phfs
produce hashes of media such that
perceptually similar media have similar
perceptual hashes in terms of hamming
distance
however this is not always true in
practice as illustrated by the example
here we use p hash a popular phf to
generate 256 bit hashes p hash is
clearly resilient to addition of
gaussian noise but not to rotation
in perceptual hash matching a client
holds some media i such that x is the k
bit perceptual hash of i we assume that
the phf is public as most are
due to the absence of the avalanche
effect perceptual hashes may reveal
information about their pre-images so we
consider the perceptual hash x to be as
private as the pre-image i itself
a server holds set b of perceptual
hashes that are known to correspond to
harmful media the security of b is
crucial as knowledge of its elements can
disclose law enforcement sources or
methods and can be used to circumvent
detection
similarity is defined by a hamming
distance and a threshold is selected
indirectly phm systems seek to answer
either exact queries of the kind is x
and b or approximate queries of the kind
is their y and b that is similar enough
to x
if a match is detected the service
provider can take appropriate action
we devise privacy preserving protocols
that realize this functionality
here's how we formalize the problem
similar to exact and approximate dhm we
define p-e-m-c and p-a-m-c a p-e-m-c
protocol reveals whether x is in b and
nothing else similarly a p-a-m-c
protocol reveals whether there exists
some y and b that is similar enough to x
and nothing else
either party can be delegated to learn
the result
our protocols guarantee client and
server privacy of x and b respectively
perceptual hash matching systems in
general do not provide security against
malicious clients who could simply
encrypt harmful media out of ban before
sending
phm systems can detect instances of
sharing with only modest efforts at
evasion or when senders are not aware
that shared content is harmful
similarly our protocols protect against
semi honest parties
a semi-honest client learns no
information about b and the semi-honest
server learns new information about x
other than the protocol output if it is
the delegated party
we do however provide security against
malicious clients that attempt to cheat
in server revealing versions of the
protocols in particular if x is in b or
if there is a y that is similar enough
no malicious client can prove otherwise
without being detected by the server
before we dive into the details i would
like to discuss some major limitations
of the work that follows
our protocols cannot guarantee that the
set b only contains hashes of harmful
media so the potential for abuse is
immense
perceptual hash matching itself causes
false positives which break privacy
guarantees for honest users
deployment of these protocols would
clearly increase the attack surface for
end-to-end encrypted services via
possible side channels and may even have
adverse externalities for example
implementation in a democratic
jurisdiction may undermine arguments in
favor of end-to-end encryption in other
countries
we do not take a position on the
question of deployment of such protocols
including ours our goal is to spark
discussion and future work by
formalizing the problem area and
demonstrating technically feasible
protocols
private membership computation is
adjacent to prior work on privacy
preserving matching and content
moderation in the end-to-end encrypted
setting thiagi atal and others have
device protocols for message franking
which allows service providers to prove
that a deported message was indeed sent
by the alleged sender
private membership tests or pmt are
clients revealing variants of private
exact membership computation that do not
protect the privacy of service set b
private biometric authentication
protocols allow private hamming distance
computation albeit for much smaller sets
b
here's a brief overview of our protocols
for simplicity i'm going to describe
server revealing variants of our
protocols we discussed client revealing
versions in the paper
the parties first use locality sensitive
hashing to reduce the hash search space
then they use private information
retrieval to retrieve homomorphically
encrypted hashes from this reduced space
without revealing any information about
x or b
now the parties can run private equality
tests using these encrypted hashes
at this point for pemc the server can
compute the result for pamc though we
need an additional step that hides the
hamming distance from the server a
private threshold comparison that we
construct using a privacy preserving
comparison protocol
we don't formally define locality
sensitive hashing or lsh here but
intuitively it allows us to partition
set b into buckets such that the
probability that two hashes would be
mapped to the same bucket is
proportional to their similarity score
for exact membership we define the l-bit
locality sensitive hash of a k-bit
string as its l-bit prefix
however this doesn't work very well for
approximate membership as it preserved
locality if and only if the l-bit
prefixes match
to reduce false negatives in pamc we use
miniature perceptual hashes as
locality-sensitive hashes themselves
intuitively if two perceptual hashes
with a large bit size are close enough
then the same phf will produce shorter
perceptual hashes of the same media that
coincide with high probability thus
putting both pre-images in the same
bucket
the server computes the locality
sensitive hash of every string y and b
suppose the lsh is the l bit value i
the server then adds an encryption of y
to the set ci
after doing this for all strings y and b
the server has an lsh index in that maps
l bit values
to sets of ciphertexts the client can
also compute the lsh of x
if x is in b it will always be mapped to
bucket l of x if something similar to x
is in b it is also mapped to bucket lfx
with high probability
so the hash search space is reduced to
just that bucket of ciphertex a
computationally private information
retrieval protocol or pir allows a
client to retrieve an element from many
held by a server without revealing its
element choice
coming back to our protocol the client
can retrieve cj via pir it's crucial to
hide j from the server because it
reveals the lsh effects
now the two parties can engage in
private exact equality tests over all
perceptual hashes in the bucket
we want to determine whether two
ciphertexts decrypted the same plain
text without revealing anything else
for now assume that the server has just
one hash y
it picks an alchemy key pair pksk sends
pk and cy an encryption of y to the
client the client encrypts minus x using
pk adds the ciphertext to cy chooses
randomizer r and multiplies the result
with it
now due to the partial homomorphism of
algamal encryption c is actually
an encryption of r times y minus x which
is zero if and only if x equals y
client's randomization using r ensures
that if x does not equal y decrypting c
doesn't reveal anything about x to the
server
in the approximate case we need more
than partial homomorphism we want to
find a homomorphic transform zeta that
allows us to compute the hamming
distance between two encrypted bit
strings without revealing anything else
in the bfb cryptosystem plaintexts are
polynomials so we define two ways to
pack a k bit string into a polynomial
back one and pack two we also define two
polynomials j x and j y which are
constants based on k and m
we build on work by yesuda ital from
2015 who use this technique with
somewhat homomorphic encryption
again the server generates a key pair
sends pk to the client along with an
encryption cy of y using packing 2 and
bk
the client generates cx using packing 1
computes zeta cx cy and sends that to
the server
the server decrypts cr and checks the
constant term which is the required
hamming distance
the issue is that the server learns the
hamming distance while we only want to
reveal whether the distance is at most
some threshold delta h
we use additive randomization to prevent
the server from learning the hamming
distance
prior work by osachi etal used expensive
oblivious transfer to undo the
randomization
we use privacy preserving comparison
which makes the protocol much more
efficient
the client chooses randomizer polynomial
r and now cr is zeta cacb plus r when
the server decrypts cr it learns the
hamming distance plus r of zero
we use a ppc protocol that returns false
if the client's value nu c is at least
as big as the server's value mu s
if mu c is equal to r of zero and nu s
is equal to p x y of zero minus delta h
the protocol returns false if and only
if the hamming distance is at most delta
h
thus the server only learns whether the
distance was at most delta h but not the
distance itself
now we put it all together the two
parties compute private equality tests
for each encrypted hash in the client's
bucket of interest i equals l of x
the server does not learn i so it cannot
tell what ciphertext will retrieve due
to client randomization no information
about x is revered to the server if x is
not in b
but if any of these equality tests
return true x is indeed in b
due to pir and the threshold comparison
we cannot let either party generate keys
for p a and c or else they may be able
to decrypt something they should not be
able to
so we use a distributed key generation
protocol for bfb that results in
collective public key pkag
both parties can jointly delegate either
party to decrypt cypher attacks
encrypted under pkag using a collective
key switching protocol
again we run the approximate equality
test once for each hash in bucket i
in the paper we discuss optimizations
that reduce communication cost by
packing multiple hashes into one bfb
plaintext polynomial
we implemented our protocols in c plus
plus using microsoft seal clpir ntl and
botan the code will be on github we ran
benchmarks on a 6 core intel i7 using
256 bit hashes a 20 bit lsh family and
seal pir parameters nnd 2048 and 2
respectively with both parties running
locally
these are preliminary benchmarks and we
are aware of some known optimizations
that could improve both computation and
communication costs
thank you for watching and please direct
any questions to rna cf.princeton.edu