hi my name is alison mcdonald i'm going
to be presenting work i did with my
colleagues on how sex workers stay safe
online
so first some context for the study
sex work is broadly defined as the
exchange of sexual services for money
and like most other professions
different parts of the work have
migrated online in the last few decades
so for example sex workers may see
clients in person but use the internet
to advertise or collect payment
they may use the internet to build
community with other sex workers and
some psycho workers may work exclusively
online for example by doing live erotic
shows on camera
however sex work is still criminalized
in most of the world and highly
stigmatized
this means that in addition to the
general risks that safe sex workers are
going to be managing like aggressive or
obsessive clients they may also be
facing harassment police violence and
discrimination all of which may happen
online or be exacerbated by technology
so we wanted to investigate how this
population which has a significant need
to stay safe online
thinks about safety with the major
barriers to staying safe online are
and the strategies that they use to meet
these safety goals so with this we hope
to better support sex workers and
staying safe as well as learn how
security tools and strategies succeed or
fail for highly motivated users who
depend on them
we began this investigation through
semi-structured interviews with 29 sex
workers in germany and switzerland where
sex work is legal but regulated
we conducted these interviews in german
and english over an end-to-end encrypted
video conferencing service and allowed
participants to choose whether the
interview was over video voice or chat
based on some of the emergent themes in
our interviews we designed a follow-up
survey which was completed by 65 sex
workers in germany switzerland and the
uk
which is also a region where sex work is
legal but regulated
we asked several closed response
questions about common protective
strategies to get a sense of their
prevalence
and one open-ended question about how
they define safety which we analyzed
with our interview responses to the same
question
all of our study protocols were also
reviewed by a sex worker consultant for
appropriateness
so first i want to present our synthesis
of how participants
define safety
we ask this question in both interviews
and surveys because knowing the holistic
safety priorities of sex workers is
central to understanding their decisions
around how to protect themselves
we identified seven dimensions of safety
physical safety
financial security
being able to set clear boundaries
respect both interpersonally and from
society
privacy legality and access to community
so we identify these different
dimensions but most important to know is
that they are very intertwined with one
another
the ability to meet one of these goals
may depend on multiple others so i'll
give an example of how that works
so this participant said if i had the
financial pressure to accept jobs
against my better judgment like someone
demanding a service i don't offer i
would be unsafe
so in this case the financial security
is necessary in order to maintain
boundaries with clients and to ensure
their physical safety
because these goals can be intentioned
we heard throughout our interviews that
participants sometimes compromise on one
safety goal to ensure another for
example using a letter an electronic
payment service rather than cash even
though it might expose their legal name
to a client
so next i'm going to discuss a few
sources of risk to these privacy goals
unsurprisingly clients can pose a major
source of risk they can be aggressive
and invade a sex worker's privacy
the sex work advertising ecosystem can
also be predatory um some platforms
steal and republish content without the
worker's permission leading to unwanted
exposure
what we heard from our participants and
also from the literature more broadly is
that
the more sex work is legal the safer sex
workers are because they can access
social services report bad dates to
police and so on
but even laws that regulate businesses
generally and the internet can be a
source of risk
so for example germany has an imprint
requirement which says that businesses
must disclose their name address and
contact information somewhere on their
website
this means that sex workers with
websites must either disclose sensitive
information or risk violating the law
and finally other online platforms like
payment processors and social media
platforms make staying safe online
difficult for sex workers
some platforms discriminate against sex
workers outright
so for example
several participants described being
banned from airbnb despite never using
the platform for anything related to sex
work
in this example the participants said
that they used different photos
different email addresses and different
phone numbers and they still ended up
banned
in this case the source of the
information leak is not clear making
defending against this type of exposure
really difficult
we had similar problems with social
media platforms making inferences behind
the scenes resulting in for example
family finding work accounts or clients
finding a personal account despite the
worker taking every effort to keep these
accounts separate
and finally i'm going to highlight some
of the strategies that sex workers have
used to stay safe
several of these strategies were offline
strategies that are just augmented by
the internet so covering or checking in
with a friend or colleague before and
after an appointment for example may now
happen over video call
and similarly sex workers have always
had methods for warning each other about
bad clients
but now some of that has moved online
like through private groups or regional
forums
we asked directly about security and
privacy settings but by and large they
were not considered useful
among our survey respondents only 35
percent said that they depended on
security settings to stay safe
um frequently this was attributed to a
lack of trust in the tech
and this lack of trust led to alternate
uh often more manual solutions so for
example this participant removes phones
from the room whenever they're talking
about a sensitive topic
similarly few sex workers use security
tools we asked about encrypted chat vpn
encrypted email which could be both pgp
but also protonmail
tor password managers and cryptocurrency
some of the reasons given for not using
these tools were similar to what's been
found in other studies
that they were too much effort or not
visibly effective
but for our participants
some of them wanted to use these tools
but they interfered with other safety
goals they were trying to meet
so for example one participant said that
they wanted to use a vpn but the
advertising service they used required
you to log in from an ip in the country
in which you were advertising which just
made using a vpn difficult
this is a good example of how sometimes
not using a privacy tool like a bpm
is not a failure to take a protective
measure but a calculated safety decision
that also takes financial opportunity
into account
another challenge with these tools is
that many of them depend on clients to
participate in order to work so for
example if a client is non-signal the
sex worker can't use signal for work
either
so although sex workers by and large
weren't using security and privacy tools
they did have highly developed
strategies for staying safe online
and identity management was a big
component to this
many sex workers discuss how keeping
their work and personal personas
separate online was critical for
maintaining privacy boundaries and
physical safety
so this might work for example through
using an alias for work or keeping
separate accounts and devices
however this separation was often
difficult to maintain over time
so this participant says that it's time
consuming annoying and stressful to have
all these phones and personas and things
i have to remember
over time it just becomes more and more
likely that they're going to make a
mistake which could out them as a sex
worker to family or expose private
information to clients
and as in the airbnb example even when
they do everything as perfectly as
possible their accounts and identities
might still be linked through
unintelligible data aggregation
our participants also talked about
various forms of self-censorship like
editing images to remove their faces and
identifying tattoos and opting out of
personal social media rather than
trusting platform privacy settings
in another example of a manual solution
preferred over settings
occasionally they may even completely
delete work accounts so this participant
explains that even though they work
legally
they are worried about being banned from
countries that don't like sex work and
so they delete work accounts websites
and completely wipe their phone before
traveling
and finally a prevalent theme from our
interviews was that many participants
felt resigned to unwanted exposure
this participant said that despite the
fact they know the consequences could be
getting killed or deported
they still mixed up devices and accounts
past mistakes are also hard to undo so
participants sometimes dismissed the
idea of adopting security tools going
forward because they had already
intermingled their accounts and they
felt that there was no going back
so to return to our question of how to
support sex workers it's important to
note that
most of the most serious risks are not
solvable with technology
stigma risky laws and discrimination
but we can identify a few common ways
that existing security tools fail to
meet the needs of this population and
i'll mention two here
first most tools aren't built for users
with multiple personas
this is a documented risk for other
users as well for example trans people
may use different names for different
audiences as they're coming out
intentionally allowing users to have
multiple siloed accounts would go a long
way to helping users stay safe with less
effort
in a similar vein uh transparent or more
restrictive data use policies that allow
users to understand how their own
accounts may be connected or how
platforms label uh might be labeling
them behind the scenes
is as critical or more important than
having intuitive privacy settings
but just because they weren't using
security tools doesn't mean that sex
workers didn't have sophisticated
protective strategies
our participants highlighted several new
technical sex work tools that could help
them in particular like improved client
vetting systems and covering apps
but especially in light of how existing
tools fail to consider the holistic
needs of high-risk populations it's
important the tools built for sex work
are led by sex workers who have the best
knowledge of their needs
so in summary
digital safety has multiple
interdependent axes and sex workers are
optimizing their safety across all of
these axes in some cases technical tools
are falling short and are largely
untrusted and so sex workers have
developed
sophisticated alternate digital safety
strategies they're using instead
thank you for listening