hi
my name is arslan khan and today i'm
going to present empty month building an
mmi based security reference monitor for
unmanned vehicles
a typical unmanned vehicle has a main
microcontroller that is interfaced with
multiple devices
now these devices could be interfaced
directly through mmi or they could be
sitting behind an external bus such as
spi i2c or can which again in turn is
interfaced through mmi
unlike traditional systems in uv system
there can be multiple vectors of threats
there could be cyber attacks there could
be physical attacks and because of this
there could be multiple malicious agents
in the system
here we notice
that all of the communication in this
system must go through mmio
furthermore since these systems have to
interface with physical systems
these systems have to be real-time in
nature here real-time doesn't mean real
fast it actually means deterministic
and because of this determinism we
conjecture that any malicious activities
may cause anomalies at the mmio level
however this was just a hypothesis to
further our hypothesis we conducted
various attacks on uvs
for example we conducted gps spoofing on
a drone system
gps has multiple type of packets
one such packet is the ephemeris message
the ephemeris message tells you about
the orbital position of the satellites
we noticed that during gps proofing we
observe a higher count of ephemeris
messages
for the sake of property you can think
of this higher coin as higher io
activity
similarly we conducted several other
attacks
for uvs
and for most of the attacks we observed
an i o level anomaly
the key thing to note here is that there
might be existing defenses for some of
those attacks
however none of these defenses actually
cover all of these attacks
this survey although not a complete
survey of uv attacks
it was enough to convince us
that we need to build an aero reference
monitor for uvs
and that
led to empty mode
and one is an mmo based security
reference monitor so to explain what m21
really is i have to explain what a
security reference monitor is
a security reference monitor is an
interpretable non-bypassable always
invoked and available module that
controls all accesses to data objects or
devices
informally you can think of it as a
gatekeeper to a particular object or a
device for m21 that particular object is
mmi
m2mon had various design challenges
most uov systems have real-time
constraints and low power constraints
because of this developers do not
provide previous separation
furthermore vendors do not provide mmus
and they also provide fewer execution
modes so there's no monitor mode or
hypervisor modes for uv systems
due to these things
everything inside a uv runs in the same
private mode
there's no well-defined isolation
between different components in the
system
for the same reason there's a
well-defined device and driver isolation
anything is able to access anything in
the system
to top it all off all of these devices
could be smart as well
as a matter of fact these devices could
be as powerful as the main
microcontroller
where to fit the reference monitor by
providing a microgram this micro kernel
does the reference monitoring for us
now a naive approach could be to
implement this microkernel beside rest
of the components in the system in the
privilege mode
however clearly this does and does not
provide any isolation at all
one can use
techniques such as software fault
isolation to isolate the microkernel
from rest of the system
however existing work has already shown
that this kind of design does not work
for real-time system as it incurs high
overhead
instead for empty mode we push
everything from the privilege mode into
the unprivileged mode leaving the
privilege mod as a safe haven for the
m21 micro kernel
in this design we can use the memory
protection unit to restrict access to i
o from the unprivileged mode a memory
protection unit is just like a memory
management unit however it does not
provide any address translation
now this kind of design should work
however there's an architectural quirk
that we need to talk about and that is
interrupt friendly
by default in most architectures
interrupts are taken to the privileged
mode
what we can do here is that we can patch
the interrupt handler so as soon as the
interrupt is triggered the first thing
these interpreters do is that they
transition back to the unprivileged mode
however during our implementation we
found that most of the io excesses
actually come from these interrupt
sensors so moving them to the
unprivileged mode incurs high overhead
so instead we decided to keep these
interrupt handlers in the privilege mode
however this poses an other challenge
these interrupt trenders that we just
moved in the in privilege mode are
outside the tcb of m2 mode and running
them beside
the kernel in the provision mode poses a
thread to the m21 kernel itself
so to contain these i contain these
interrupt handler routines in the
privilege mode we use software fault
isolation techniques such as controls
for integrity and data for integrity
using these techniques we ensure three
things
first these interpreters are not able to
access m21 data or code
second they are not able to jump outside
the interrupt handler or outside the
sandbox
and lastly we ensure that they do not
access io directly
using this kind of design we ensure that
the mem21 microkernel is non bypassable
furthermore we ensure that no one in the
system can modify the microkernel logic
lastly although we do not formally prove
the microkernel
we do keep the tcb of microkernel really
small so that it is easily available
we instantiated the m21 microkernel to
implement multiple applications so that
we can detect different type of attacks
against drones
the first application that we
implemented was a kalman filter column
filter is used to model the physical
world now this kelvin filter is similar
to the kelvin filter that is implemented
inside the flight control software
itself however this kalman filter enjoys
all the isolation guarantees of m21
itself
next we implemented an excess pattern
based filter
this excess pattern based filter track i
o access frequency it can track i o
access sequences and it can also block
accesses to different io regions
to evaluate our system we use 3dr iris
plus uav platform
which was running autopilot control
software
using this platform we conducted two
types of evaluation performance
evaluation and security evaluation
in performance evaluation we tried to
figure out how much of an overhead m21
incurs here on the x-axis you see
different autopilot tasks
and on the y-axis you see log based time
scale
the bars here are the execution times
here the thing to note is that if a task
was not missing its deadline before m21
it does not miss its deadline even after
m21 microkernel is implemented
overall we incurred an average overhead
of 8.85 percent so roughly around nine
percent
next in security evaluation we try to
find the efficacy of m2 moon and its
applications
if you remember the small survey that i
presented in the beginning of the slides
using m21 and its application we were
able to detect all of these attacks
using one of the detection feature or
one of the applications that we
implemented
as a case study let's consider the first
attack that is the timer attack
the timer attack is actually borrowed
from an existing paper called minion in
this attack an attacker tries to modify
the tick value of our system since that
is how a system keep tracks of time a
modified tech value results in an
unstabilized system or even a crash
system
while profiling the timer attack we
notice that the system only modifies the
configuration registers
during the system boot up and after
system boot up it never modifies or even
accesses these configuration registers
however under attack circumstances we
noticed that there are multiple io
accesses to these configuration
registers
when using m21 a user can register a
rule with m21 that disallow any
configuration changes to the system
timer or the timer registers hence
avoiding this timer attack
empty one comes with its own set of
limitations most of them stem from the
fact that m21 is deployed on systems
with low compute power or low resources
due to this reason m21 cannot really run
complex applications such as machine
learning applications
as a rule of thumb m21 is limited by the
slack time available in the system here
we have three different tasks from
autopilot
on the x axis you see increased number
of rules which can be construed as the
increased complexity of the applications
running on top of
m2 mode on the y-axis you see the
execution runtime and these flat lines
are the deadlines for this test
as you can see here that for the actual
auto trim task
even at higher complexity of task
of the applications running on top of
m21
the test never misses a deadline however
for update to bad compass task
the task
misses is deadline really quickly
this highlights the difference between
the available slack time
in the two tests
for the same reason
in the access pattern based filter
application we do block listing a lot
instead of allow listing
to conclude this talk in this
paper we showed that uv attacks against
drones usually exhibit mmo level
anomalies
to detect this anomalies we implemented
the m21 microkernel and we implemented
multiple applications on top of that m21
microkernel
we showed that on a rear drone
controller m21 microkernel incurs a
reasonable overhead and using the
applications and the microkernel we are
able to detect a wide range of attacks
with this
i would like to thank you all for
listening to me and i'll be happy to
take any questions you guys have thank
you