hello everyone my name is teju kim from
purdue university today i will talk
about pakistan or static analysis space
prepared by the concrete bug detector
for biometal embedded applications
as you know embedded systems use a
variety of particular devices such as
sensor sd card motor and user interface
port
those particular devices are attached to
i o ports such as uart usb and so on
such i o ports are mapped into memory
space which we call
mm-ios however we have observed that
particular devices have a security
issues caused by concurrency box let's
start with the typical conclusible case
in this example thread a and b update
count variable in the figure then the
age update can be ignored if a congruent
update happens
this happens because a count variable is
shared by thread a and b
therefore we should put a proper luck to
guarantee atomic
of data operation
however in terms of conclusive bugs of
particular devices the problems are more
complicated take a look at this simplify
the example here thread 8 sets your
writing address as 100 and try to write
password string
we call such sequential operations as a
transaction
on the other hand let's assume that the
b try to execute another transaction at
the different address 500
then after p character is written at
address 100 the last of the characters
will be written into address 500
this can happen because an sd card is
shared by thread a and b
hence we need to guarantee automaticity
spatially and temporarily otherwise
security critical data corruption can
happen on fire content sensor value and
so on
let me first talk about what is the
spatial adamicity
this is the example of uart attached to
a embedded system board this can be used
for various purposes such as shared
connection
such a uart mmio has a fixed range of
memory addresses
we call the address link between the
start and end address as a memoir region
such lead addresses within our mmi
region are assigned to registers in the
future to control the attached
particular device such a region should
be
automatically accessed for correct
device operations
which require spatial automaticity
next let me explain temporal
automaticity with the simplified sd card
controller safety machines as shown in
the previous password string example
each transaction consists of a sequence
of instructions accessing mmios we call
such instructions as mmi access
instruction
tools instructions must be executed
atomically to transit state emotions and
execute a transaction correctly however
if such state motion transition is
interrupted a transaction will fail
leading to even security critical data
corruption
therefore we should not import locks
without considering state motion as an
as shown in the figure we should import
logs to cover
such a sequence of instructions while
considering temporal atomicity
in consideration of both the special and
temporal automaticity
we have developed poisson to detect
concrete bugs for peripheral devices
first person takes the source code and
the system board memory layout
information such as system view
descriptor or svd as input
after taking input poisson identifies
which mmio access instructions can be
executed concurrently
then person extracts the spans of
transactions based on the identified mmi
access instructions
finally person identifies which
transactions can be executed concretely
and the generator report
then let me explain how python works
we first lead to identify
areas of mmios and lock object using
point 2 analysis
to identify the mmi user aliases we
identify instructions accessing constant
addresses
if a constant address works within
any mmi or region we consider that such
instruction access certain mmios as
shown in the blue boxes
furthermore to identify all the mmi
accessories we should track earliest
variables pointing to addresses of our
mmi region as well you can see examples
in the red boxes
finally we should track aliases pointing
to log object
as shown in the purple boxes such log
information
will be used to check whether
instructions can be executed
concurrently
next we need to identify critical
sections which we call lockspans using
identified lock object
such lock spans are enforced between the
lock and unlock instructions
for example you can find one red
lockspan and another purple lockspan
between the pair of lock and unlock
instructions
we can find such lockspans through
lockset analysis
furthermore such lockset analysis should
consider core context for example there
is the spi writer function and this
function course both spi write 1 and spi
write 2 functions
also there are
log and unlock instructions covering
both spi write 1 and spirit 2 function
call instructions in this case the lux
lux pen should cover not only the core
instructions of the post functions but
also instructions executed in the both
called functions then person can find
the conflict lock spans in consideration
of core context
furthermore we should
extract transaction spans as well as lux
fans
each transactions panes consist of mmi
access instructions their distances in
the code are closed because peripheral
devices drivers
access mmi is frequently unlike
application code furthermore poisson
heuristically imports transaction spends
by counting the number of instructions
between mmi obsessed instructions
and if the number is smaller than the
stress hold value
we consider both mmi access instructions
are the part of our transaction
meanwhile we should consider some
exceptions for example we observe that
peripheral device should be in the
weight state during the
during on assigned the job process
if that is interrupted by another job
request or other mio accesses
the ongoing job can fail
finally person detect concurrency box
with identified lock and transaction
space
let's assume that there is one
transaction consists of
consisting of yellow and green mmi
obsessed instructions
then we show two examples of concurrency
issues when two threads can execute this
transaction
if both instructions of the transaction
are protected by different lock object
green and yellow instructions can be
executed concurrently which lead to the
transaction failure
it the black object are identical
fortunately both green and yellow
instructions can not be executed
concurrently however thread 1 and 2 can
still execute the same transaction
without executing yellow or green
instructions at the same time this will
also lead to the transaction failure as
well
we note that this one happen before
the log objects are identical and the
lock span covers each transaction
in our experiment we have found 17 true
valves although there are 19 first
positive blocks
or cases and all of them have been
deported and eight cases has been
confirmed by the developers
as a case study let's assume that an sd
card can be connected to a hd
spi port
and we found that
lux implementation was missing then sd
card operations such as riding on a sd
card
do not work properly
as explained in our sd card example if
multiple threads need to perform some
operations such as writing security
critical data can be corrupted or
missing
let's assume that thread b act as a
malicious user's thread which frequently
write the data
currently
then the security critical data such as
user information or password can be
corrupted even without the privilege to
access the target data
for example when a part of a password
will be stored into address 100 and the
others will be stored into address 500
if
we properly put logs in consideration of
a transaction
all data will be written
correctly
unfortunately pakistan has several
limitations which are caused by static
analysis for example first positives and
negatives can be introduced by
inaccuracy of 0.2 analysis furthermore
some low-level individuals interrupt
enable or disable operations can
cause in correct results
moreover incorrectly important
transactions plans can cause fair
positive and negatives
however incorrect spends such as subset
spans still are usable to detect bugs
because existing work is not aware of
transactions at all
in summary conclusion box can strengthen
embedded system safety and security to
detect the tools box we propose poisson
or static analysis-based concrete block
detector for peripheral devices
for that the detection procedure should
be transaction aware in consideration of
spatial and temporal autonomicity
as a result we have found 17 bugs in
seven embedded applications
this is the end of my talk thank you
very much for your attention
you