i'm simbo from the chinese university of
hong kong in this talk i will share our
work on website defacement detection
this is a joint work with people from
stanford technologies and the chinese
university of hong kong
so what is website defacement here's an
interesting example
in this screenshot of google search
result
can you notice anything strange
look at the web page description there
are some unrelated and elastic keywords
in our university's website
so what happens if we dig into the
source code of the web page we can see
that there are some malicious code
snippets likely to be inserted by some
hacker
and their purpose is quite clear to
promote their illicit products by
hijacking search engine traffic
this is a typical case of of what we
called promotional devicement and is
what we try to detect in this work
traditionally this kind of hackings are
a type of blackhead search engine
optimization
seo
and well-known tricks like keyword
stuffing and link farming has been run
since the search engine was created
however
those classical tricks introduced
massive modified modification so they
can be easily detected
people have proposed different approach
for detection
one of the most popular approach is
based on profile anomaly detection
basically to check whether a website
contains some content that doesn't match
its profile for example gambling content
appears on a university webpage
indicates something unusual
there are also other approaches like
change monitoring and image based
detection which are suitable under
different scenarios
however we observe that recent trend of
defacement makes detection more
challenging
this diagram shows modern defacement
campaign based on the conspiring act of
con of defacers and their customers
when someone wants to search for some
illicit content his search terms may
trigger the block by search engines or
other detection systems
so he would try his luck with obfuscated
keywords instead
or recorded jargons
defacers on the other side expecting
this behavior of their customers and
then planned corresponding jargons into
the hacked websites
meanwhile
because of the uniqueness of the jargons
devices only need to insert a minimum
amount of content into the hex website
to evade detection
and can still have good chance to reach
their customers
this new defacement technique introduced
two key challenges first the detector
needs to understand the obfuscated
keywords like the term highlighted in
red on the deface web page example on
the right
second the detector needs to identify
the tiny piece of the placement code
from the whole webpage
like the line highlighted in white
this is like searching a needle in a
haystack
to tackle these challenges we propose
two key solutions
we design a jargon normalization
algorithm to recover the obfuscated
keywords
and we use tech aware attention network
to detect tiny insurgents
based on these two key ideas we design
and implement our cloud-based defacement
monitoring system dmos
the user only need to submit their
domain to our service webpage then our
system will actively monitor the web
pages
for each webpage demos will first detect
and recover jargons with jargon
normalization component
then the webpage will be passed to the
tech aware machine learning component
for classification
now let's get into details of each part
of our system
first let's see what people usually do
to create jargons
there are two types of dragons one we
call homophonic in which some characters
are replaced with
characters in similar pronunciations
for example the k replaced by c in the
term mark 6 as highlighted in blue
another is homomorphic dragons which
means replacing characters in similar
shapes
as the 8 to 4 example in red even worse
this too can be combined to create some
mixed jargons
the result is easy for humans to
understand but will confuse machines
know that we have mainly seen chinese
cases in the world possibly because
there are a lot of chinese characters in
similar shapes or pronunciations
which gives more flexibility for
obfuscation
this shows how the jargon normalization
algorithm works first we fit sentences
into a language model to detect
non-fluent sentences
then we generate candidates replacements
for strange terms inside the sentence
after that
the replaced sentence goes through the
language model again for fluency test
if it becomes fluent that means we have
formed the correct recovery of the
jargon
after dragon normalization we will fit
web pages into the machine learning
classifier remember the second key idea
is to keep the tag information when
doing this
so first we will convert the html code
into text sentence pairs
note that we treat tag attributes that
can hold text as separate text
like the out attribute of image
then we propose the tech aware
hierarchical attention network t-h-a-n
to train the classifier
it first learns the texan's values for
each text and is paired then in the
second layer it learns to assign
attentions to the text sentence pairs
and generates a single web page
embedding vector
for final classification
this visualizes the learned attentions
we can see that texts like title meta
which are more essential to search
endings are automatically assigned with
higher weights
keywords related to gambling get more
attention while uninteresting keywords
get lower weights
this diagram illustrates the effect of
the overall pipeline of demos
given given a webpage our system will
first identify and recover obviously
terms inside the text content
then it will assign attention weights to
different texans pairs
and outputs a single embedding for
classification
we train the system with about half a
million labeled web pages
then we conduct performance evaluation
and ablation study
our system outperform existing solutions
boost the precision from the level of 80
to over 90 percent
note that some commercial web
application firewall has relatively high
precision
but also miss the majority of the face
pages
during the ablation study we find that
by enabling tech awareness we can reduce
the false alarm and thus relieve human
efforts by 30 percent
the jargon normalization module alone
can further reduce human efforts by over
40 percent
together demos can indeed achieve
production-ready performance
we deploy demos to rail customers and
monitored over 38 million web pages for
five months
the system has
successfully detected over half a
million defaced web pages in real life
and a significant portion of them
belongs to influential websites like
government website and university
websites
we also did some comparison experiments
to evaluate the performance of our
system against some popular commercial
url checkers
we can see that demos increase both
precision and recall largely
this table shows the top a jargons
transformed from the chinese term of
mark vi
you can see that this kind of techniques
is quite common in defacement
and it's surprising to see how creative
those defacers are and they indeed
obfuscate keywords with both characters
in similar shapes and pronunciations
we cut the frequency of infected html
tags to see what kind of tags are more
preferred by defaces
the high ranking of some tags like a
title and meta are expected as they are
essential to search engine optimization
one surprising result is the marquee tag
if you look up a line you can see that
this is the non-standard html tag
that can hold automatically scrolling
text
we guess it can help devices to evade
detections
by search engines or web application
files
here are some other interesting findings
in a significant portion of the face
pack pages
defacement appears in less than 10
places so this type of dlc defacement
are indeed common right now overtaking
old tricks like killer staffing
as we collected our data set from
various search engines we also noticed
that mobile search engines start to
attract the phasers attentions
possibly because of weaker protection
interestingly
in 2019 we noticed a spike of defacement
in chinese government websites
after some dig up we find that it is
result of regulation change which
requires all government website to
migrate to a new
official domain
so the old domains are left unattended
finally some conclusions
we have designed and deployed demos to
monitor over 7000 rail websites and
found
over 11 percent of them have been
defaced at least once
although our design focused on chinese
website defacement
we have also demonstrated that it's easy
to extend to other languages with
reasonable performance
we have released some english samples on
our website
so please check our paper if you are
interested in more details
and if you have any other questions just
drop us an email