hello everyone and thanks for tuning in
this is a security analysis the
democracy live online voting system i'm
mike spector and this is joint work with
jlx alderman
so this is is a security analysis of an
internet voting system used in the 2020
u.s federal elections
and to begin i'd like to start by
explaining a bit of a tyro back that we
have to do here
on one hand as researchers we have to be
able to critique the systems that we're
using in order to protect
voters and improve the democratic
process
on the other we have to be careful to
avoid allowing our work to be taken out
of context
and used to attack the very institutions
we're trying to protect
so here's a bit of a disclaimer
nothing in this work indicates that the
2020 presidential election was hacked
to the best of our knowledge omni ballot
the product that we're evaluating here
from democracy live was thankfully not
used in pennsylvania georgia or arizona
and we stand by the letter we signed
along with 50 other election security
researchers
stating that there is no compelling
evidence of computer fraud in the 2020
presidential election outcome
you can read more about that here
now with that out of the way why would
we want to do this analysis at
all so last year i presented a paper on
another internet voting system called
votes that was also used in u.s federal
elections and we found that votes
had vulnerabilities that would allow a
number of different kinds of adversaries
to alter stop or expose a user's vote
and as a result most of the counties
using votes actually abandoned the
product
this included a number of jurisdictions
in oregon and colorado as well as the
entire state of west virginia
unfortunately kova 19 caused states to
reconsider
and a number adopted new voting
mechanisms
and a few actually adopted yet another
internet voting system called democracy
lies omni ballot
now the system actually has seen some
adoption already uh in fact it was used
by seven state governments and 98
jurisdictions in 11 states but at a much
lower level
for instance the planned adoption for
the 2020 presidential primaries included
uh used by 22 percent of west virginia's
population which is uh significantly
higher than margin of error but as
though that's not enough delaware and
new jersey actually plan on using it for
uh the totality of their population
um so this leads to a very obvious
question right does democracy live
system actually fair any better than
votes
now there's a number of things that
actually made performing this analysis
somewhat difficult
and the first is that election systems
have a number of subtle security
requirements that are not seen in other
systems
uh and in fact electronic voting has
really been a topic of research since
the 80s in the academic cryptography and
system security literature
and as a result we have a pretty good
handle on the kind of definitions in the
cryptographic sense
for what we want so let's go through
those and it'll explain a little bit
about why the the requirements are
somewhat subtle
so the first two are relatively
straightforward uh there's correctness
and usability which states that a vote
is counted as cast cash is intended and
accessible to all eligible voters
the second is privacy which just states
that an attacker cannot learn a voter
selection okay so so far this is
straightforward
but then there's receipt freeness which
states that a voter cannot prove the way
that they voted after the fact and this
prevents uh vote selling actually
and there's coercion resistance which
states that a voter cannot cooperate
with an attacker to prove the way they
voted so they can't be forced into
voting in a way that an attacker wants
them to vote
finally there's this idea of n10
verifiability
which has actually been the main focus
of cryptography research
here voters are given some proof that
their vote was actually counted in the
final tally correctly
and this is considered a prerequisite
for internet voting as it allows us to
remove trust in the system's servers and
other infrastructure used to cast the
ballot
a further complication that we have to
contend with here is that we have to be
kind of careful in our analysis
democracy lives omni ballot has multiple
modes that have different threat models
for example there's ones that simply
just deliver the ballot in which case
the ballot is physically
marked printed and mailed back
then they have a remote accessible vote
by mail system which is sort of like a
ballot marking device but you're using
your computer and printing it out at
home instead of
going to a polling place so the ballot
here is marked electronically
but then physically printed and mailed
finally they have uh full-on internet
voting where the ballot is marked
electronically and sent back through
democracy live servers
so with all this in mind we really
wanted to know first how well does
democracy alive achieve those
correctness goals that we had before the
cryptographic goals that we had before
including correctness privacy receipt
freeness and coordination resistance
second is the system actually intent
verifiable right this is an internet
voting system after all and this is a
generally seen as a requirement for an
internet voting system to work
second what are the non-ballot
privacy properties of the system right
because
a voting system inherently gets a lot of
information about voters and
it would be very useful to know exactly
how
how it treats voter data
and third how well do these other modes
of democracy life fare and how does one
even begin to analyze them
now the final challenge we faced was the
general obnoxiousness of the system and
the the documentation involved and the
easiest way to explain this is by a
walkthrough of how the voter actually
ends up interacting with the product
so this is what you first see when you
begin to use omniballet
each instance of omnibot is actually
skinned to look like it is from the
department running the election not
democracy live
in this case this is from the state of
delaware
first the user is asked to enter their
name and birth date followed by the last
four digits of their social security
number
now at this point they've already begun
sort of recording a lot of invasive
information about the voter and
naturally one would wonder what their
privacy policy says it looks like
there's one right here
except that this turns out to be
google's privacy policy not democracy
lives
and in fact there is no omni ballot
privacy policy
anyway after the voter has actually
authenticated uh they use they get to
see this following screen to select
uh which type of return
system that they would like so for
instance via fax by email or electronic
return
but what's really interesting here is
that there's this text that says please
note
and it ends with these ballots are
scanned for tabulation with other
absentee ballots no votes are counted
are cast online under any circumstances
and what's interesting here is that
literally right below this text there
are these two boxes that save high email
or electronic return
and
to put it charitably they have a very
seem to have a very
uh
odd interpretation of the term caste
finally uh the user is allowed to vote
and then confirm their vote
and uh they they're treated to this nice
success screen uh uh that has a number
of interesting features including this
nice link uh to technical support where
you can report a bug
uh so we found a few bugs in our
analysis and uh we actually like to see
what they what they have to say here um
and it turns out they do have like a
coordinated vulnerability disclosure
policy and let me read it to you
it says by submitting a report we agree
not to disclose the bug to any third
parties without the prior approval of
democracy live
well at least it's straightforward
but we can't really agree to this
and we can't really trust their
documentation because a lot of the
things we saw earlier were kind of
misleading
and we didn't really want to report
never report our findings so we actually
had to perform this analysis without
involvement of the company
and this led to a number of constraints
and a key challenge was that we actually
really couldn't touch their server
infrastructure for a number of legal and
ethical concerns
and therefore we had to make a number of
assumptions about how their back end
worked
and our solution here was to mainly
reverse engineer the client
and then iteratively re-implement the
server the server side to better
understand the protocol and to be
charitable to them we're going to assume
the best possible case for the backend
in our analysis and whenever we deviated
from this assumption we explicitly
discussed why in the paper
finally what i'm about to present is an
analysis of the system as of june 2020
and we make no claims about anything
they've done since
so what did we find well the system is a
large relatively complicated web app
that relies on a number of third parties
to perform its services
the app dynamically fetches and runs
javascript loaded from amazon
google cloud and cloudflare
making all three companies as well as
democracy live itself potential points
of compromise for the election system
we also found that the system is not
antenna verifiable and not coercion
resistant or receipt free
we found that attackers could manipulate
the ballot design compromise about
secrecy and invisibly change votes uh
and the only thing that really prevented
the client the server or
any of these third parties from doing so
uh was the use of physical media so for
instance blank ballot printing
the client the server or third parties
could very easily manipulate the ballot
design but couldn't necessarily
compromise ballot secrecy or invisibly
change votes because of course the
ballot is printed out and physically
marked and then mailed back
but of course marked ballot printing
when you do the remote accessible vote
by mail option uh could be manipulated
and uh the ballot design could be
manipulated and uh the secrecy of the
ballot was in fact compromised and
finally an on right line ballot return
there was nothing protecting the user
much at all
so how did well did democracy live fare
in in the realm of privacy well the
system collects the voters name address
date of birth and a partial social
security number but really interestingly
it also collects a browser fingerprint
which is a kind of tracking mechanism
that's sort of like a super cookie uh
it's something that you actually can't
delete
uh off your system at all even if you're
in like private browsing mode
uh it also uploads the voter's secret
ballot selections even if the voter
prints and physically mails in the
ballot so in the case where you mark the
ballot uh locally it actually ends up
serving your voters uh voter selections
their ballot selections
to democracy live servers
finally the system uses google analytics
and google gets your voter voter id and
therefore your party affiliation
and again there's no privacy policy and
no public restriction on any of the use
of any of this data
and to reiterate right this information
is highly valuable for political
purposes or for election interference
as it can be used to target ads or
disinformation campaigns based on the uh
voters find grain preferences and
there's no restriction on use of data
here which is very worrying
all right so we found all of this all
these these uh interesting properties of
the system uh what do we think about
this means in the larger picture
and really what i want to tell you about
is the fact that there have been five
uh security analyses of internet voting
systems used in real world high-stakes
elections and there appears to be an
ongoing pattern that i want to point out
the first is that they were all deployed
before public analysis was done
uh
all of them had significant barriers to
analysis and disclosure including the
need to reverse engineer or
code obfuscation or ndas and other
limitations
all of them had poor misleading
documentation of how the system worked
except the swiss post system
which was actually instrumental in
finding the vulnerabilities that they
found
and finally there were a number of all
of them suffered from implementation and
or design flaws
and my point is that there's clearly a
need for regulation requiring public
security analysis prior to these systems
being fielded in real elections
and in lieu of this regulation science
has been
stepping up to provide insight to help
regulators understand these risks and
really must continue to do so until ban
or other regulation is implemented
so to summarize
we presented here the first security
analysis of an internet
voting system in u.s federal elections
and in fact the first analysis of a
remote accessible vote by mail system
we found a number of security and
privacy issues that were then reported
both to the vendor and to
cisa and dhs and the uh affected parties
um what i'm really proud of though is
that new jersey and delaware actually
halted use of omnivallet for this
internet voting for the electronic
return
however the the system is still used in
west virginia and denver in november
2020.
so with that thank you so much for
tuning in and i look forward to hearing
your questions
you