hello everyone my name is igor and in
this presentation i'll tell you more
about our work on reducing unwanted
interruptions due to notification
permission prompts on chrome
this is a joint work with several
colleagues at google
operating systems such as windows mac os
and linux provide apis that allow apps
to display push notifications as native
system notifications
chrome like many other browsers
implements the web notifications api
which allows websites to send push
notifications to users the image here
shows a system notification on macos
that comes from chrome
but before websites can send
notifications they should ask for
permission and the user should grant it
there are a few best practices that
chrome team and mozilla have developed
independently to help web developers in
deciding when to ask for permission
from a user experience standpoint
permission problems should be asked
after the user has shown intent the
prompts should appear in the appropriate
context and the notifications should be
time sensitive and useful
for example the website on the left has
a clear checkbox that allows users to
choose to get notified and similarly the
website on the right has a visible
button
finally websites should have insight
management controls for notifications to
make it easy for users to disable them
at any time
so what do the permission prompts look
like on chrome
on desktop the prompt is displaced as an
anchored bubble that shows two possible
actions block and allow as well as an x
icon that allows to dismiss the prompt
users can choose to interact with the
prompt by either clicking on the allow
block or the x icon
but they can also simply continue
browsing the website and ignore the
prompt
on android the prompt is even more
visible and in fact users have to
interact with the prompt before they can
continue to browse the website
on ios web push notifications are not
supported
now that we've seen the prompt uis let's
have a look at some statistics about
notification permission prompts
first if we look at all permission
prompts in chrome as reported by clients
who choose to send usage statistics and
crash reports to google we see that 74
of those are for the notification
permission
but only a very small fraction 10
percent of desktop and 21 on android are
granted
which means that the vast majority of
such prompts are either ignored
dismissed or blocked
and we refer to those as unwanted
notification prompts
in fact most of the unwanted prompts are
either dismissed or simply ignored
there could be multiple reasons why
users do not want to receive
notifications for example they might be
uninterested in receiving notifications
from that specific site or because they
do not wish to be interrupted in general
when browsing or also because they feel
that the site is trying to deceive them
for instance by getting the site's
content on the permission
that brings us to the goals of this
project which are to reduce the unwanted
notification permission prompts for the
majority of users
without significantly impacting those
who want to receive them
in this paper we discuss the results of
two large scale studies of notification
prompt usage in the wild where we define
proxy measures of unwanted notification
prompts
we design a new quiet permission from ui
and we introduce novel adaptive
activation mechanisms for the new ui
our analysis has shown that the new uis
and their activation mechanisms have a
significant positive effect on reducing
unwanted notification prompts
a decrease of 31 percent of the prompt
block rate and only a minimal impact on
the wanted ones with less than a five
percent decrease in the allow rate
so let's discuss more in detailed
studies
first we wanted to understand how users
interacted with the default permission
prompt in the wild
for that we analyzed the interactions
with the notification permission prompt
with the allow block dismiss or ignore
actions by a subset of users who opted
to sharing telemetry with google
before conducting any experiment with
behavioral data we obtained approval
from key stakeholders at google
including from legal ux privacy
engineering and product
in order to limit the impact of test
accounts or devices we applied several
filters to the data and then we computed
aggregate statistics about the different
action rates
with regards to the unwanted prompts
users can take two types of actions
one requires an interaction with the
prompt and is explicit and those are the
block or the dismiss
actions for example
and the other one the ignore is implicit
and does not require any interaction
moreover prompts that are blocked are
also persisted for the site across
subsequent visits
about the study results so we conducted
the first study in march 2020 over a
10-day period where we analyzed over 800
million actions on more than 70 000
websites for more than 300 million
chrome clients the results indicate that
80 of desktop clients and 70 of android
ones
never granted any prompts they saw
however the detailed charts also show
that there is a non-negligible fraction
of clients that always grant such
prompts eight percent on desktop and 26
on android
it is therefore important to minimize
the effect of any change we make for the
users who want to get the notifications
and that is what we try to achieve next
that is to reduce the interruptiveness
of unwanted notification permission
prompts
to get there
first we redesigned the notification
prompt ui to make it less interactive we
wanted to reduce the number of prompts
that users have to act upon and at the
same time provide a more obvious escape
hatch if users wanted to change their
choice after they made it
we chose the following ui for desktop
and android after a small experiment and
of course you can find more details
about that experiment in the paper
then
we introduced a persite activation
mechanisms for the new ui which are
shown by default on sites that have very
low average grant rate according to our
telemetry
finally we designed new logics for
activating these uis based on either the
user's chrome settings to always show
the quiet ui for example
but also the past actions for example to
enable the quiet ui after three
consecutive block actions
we then run a second experiment to
understand the effect of these changes
on the main action rates grant deny etc
we performed an a b test where the new
uis were disabled in the control group
and enabled in the experiment group on a
subset of desktop and android clients
the results based on more than 100
million actions on more than 70 000
websites from more than 40 million
clients
show that the new ui has minimal impact
on users who want to get notification
with the less than five percent
reduction in grant rate on average
while significantly reducing unwanted
interruptions with the 31
lower average denier rate and again more
details can be found in the paper
and this brings us to the conclusion so
we have observed
that 74 of permission prompts on chrome
are for the notification permission yet
those are very rarely granted which
means that most of those prompts cause
unwanted interruptions
of the browsing experience for the users
this made us rethink our notification
permission prompt ui
we conducted two large-scale studies to
better understand the issue and to test
the effectiveness of our new less
intuitive ui for the notification
permission together with the crowdsource
signals as well as the user's own past
actions with the prompt chrome is able
to reduce unwanted interruptions while
keeping the utility for the users who
want to see notifications
as part of our ongoing work
we are exploring ways to improve the
activation logics for the new wise to
make it work better for more cases where
users are unlikely to grant the
permission
and we are also considering novel uis
for other permissions as well
such as the cheap ui for the geolocation
permission which you can try on chrome
today
with that uh i conclude this
presentation and thank you for uh
watching it
if you want to have more information you
can find links for our paper about the
chromium blog post about the fighter uis
as well as the chrome user experience
reports which shows
action metrics
about different websites if you have
more questions about this paper please
feel free to reach out
to this email address
thank you