hello i'm kotaro matsuka we will give
the presentation about virtual secret
platform a five-stage pipeline processor
over t3
in recent years cloud computing has been
spreading rapidly
cloud computing is a mechanism to upload
computation processes to others
in the current system the program and
the data required to be processed must
be sent to the cloud server and must be
in plain text at the time of execution
what we are concerned about is the
possibility that the program and data
can be wiretapped
the cloud server is a computer located
somewhere on the earth
if a manager's party has direct access
to that computer he or she may be able
to extract the program and data from it
so what to do
just encrypt everything if the client
encrypts everything the client
information including the program can't
be via tap
we can make wiretapping pointrest
this is the basic idea of this
research we call our proposed method
battle secure platform or usb
the natural question about this idea is
how can we execute an encrypted program
to answer this question we recall the
fact that programs are executed in a
processor and the processor consists of
logic circuits
in the slide we show a small example of
a part of logic circuits in a processor
logic circuit can be represented by a
graph of logic gates
so the question
how can we execute an encrypted program
can be reduced to an easier question
how can we evaluate logic gates over
encrypted bits
this is because if we can evaluate logic
gates over encrypted bits
we can replace each physical logic gate
with them
and this gives a way to evaluate logic
circuits over encrypted bits
this means
we can construct the processor emitter
for the encrypted program
one way to achieve the evaluation of
logic gates over encrypted bits is
called free homomorphic encryption
this is suitable for evaluating
secretion certificates like processor
circuits because fhg does not need a
pre-circuit steps bound
we use one kind of fhg called tfhg
in our development of bsp we set three
targets
the first one is high level language
compatibility
sometimes there's a trade-off between
security and usability
even though usb provides a way to secure
computational floating if the user needs
to write the program by assembling
language an ordinary user won't use such
a system
the second one is speed
because the operations in fhg are
significantly throw we have to do
special treatment for speed up to make a
workable implementation in the current
real environment
the last one is open source
implementation
providing an implementation
is of course necessary to ensure
reproducibility of results
but in addition to that
open source is an excellent way to allow
users to verify the implementation
without trusting us
our contribution to making bsp
compatible with high-level language is
to implement the risk five better sale
and error investor c compiler for it
the reason why we chose c is it is
widely used and easy to write speed
optimized code
the reason why we chose risk firebase
isa is we want to use a widely used
compiler framework like lwm to make the
compiler user friendly
for speeding up
we need two optimizations
one is the development of your cam an
fpg gate operation engine this is needed
to utilize parallelism
what we mean here by parallelism is
explained better
the other is cmx memory
because the memory circuit constructed
by logic gates can be easily bigger than
the processor circuit
a special cryptographical optimization
for memories is effective
by combining both
we achieved 100
600 times faster
implementation compared to this state of
earth
at last
our implementation is available on
github
in this presentation we focus on iocam
because the exploitation of parism is
our central contribution and the most
positive idea we proposed
before explaining the details we
explained the brief structure of the
components needed to evaluate the
processor circuit with the encrypted
program to clarify
where you can tell the work
at first you can take the processor
circuit and replace each logic gate in
the circuit with the hg's logic gate to
construct the processor for the
encrypted program
during the construction you can also
embed cmax memory with the encrypted
program and data to the processor
circuit
after the construction you can evaluate
the repressed circuit which encrypted
program iteratively
handling this evaluation phase is the
main role of your cam
in other words we can say that yokan is
an abstraction layer for running logic
circuits over t4ht
due to the time limit we will only
discuss the get schedule cleaning
process of your eocam which is one of
the most important functionality
after that we will briefly summarize the
performance results of usb
there are two types of parallelism in
effect logic circuit evaluation yukon
tries to exploit
one is the gate level parallelism and
the other is pipeline-induced
parallelism
the gate level parallel this means
sometimes there are multiple guests that
are available at the same time
for example
in this circuit
alpha and better
be can be partly a variable but gamma is
not
because the evaluation of gamma depends
on the results of alpha and beta
the pipeline is a circuit design
techniques that increases separately
available gate by inserting registers to
divide the circuit into multiple
parallely available circuits
if we assume we are currently evaluating
a stream of data by the same circuit in
pipeline situation gamma does not have
to weight the results of alpha and beta
because the previous results of alpha
and beta are spread from the register
these parallelisms are treatable in
physical circuits since physical rush
gates are naturally evaluated in
parallels
however
exploiting them in circuits over fhe is
not trivial
because we rely on the physical
execution environment to evaluate the
launch gate the number of priority
available logic gates is limited by the
physical machine capability
like the number of codes in the cpu
so
efficient scheduling to free utilize the
capability is needed
you can take scale of this scheduling
problem
the prominent future of iocan is it
supports both magical cpu and large gpu
to maximize usable physical machine
capability
we evaluated our implementation by
running it in real environments
we show here two cases
case one is aws p3.6x rise which is
equipped with 8b100 gpus and k2 is
sakura kokolek which is equipped with
100 gpu
in both cases
introducing the pipeline gives better
performance
by increasing parallelism
case 1 is the fastest gas among all
tested cases
we achieved about 0.8 seconds per cycle
which means
we constructed a 1.25 hertz clock speed
processor over to hg
as you can see ks2 is slower than case
one
this is because k2 does not have enough
physical capability to free utilize all
parallelisms
so a scheduler like yokan to handle
massive physical capability is needed
to emphasize the nobility of our work we
compare bsp with frisk a state of the
art processor over here
risk only supports one instruction and
this causes no compare support while
base b has c compiler support
the evaluation of the circuit of risk is
estimated to take
1278 seconds per cycle while with b
takes only 0.8 seconds
this means with b is about 1
600 times faster than the state of yield
in addition to that our implementation
is publicly available while the run of
risk is not
in conclusion
with b enables offloading computation
while keeping the program secret
we demonstrated this by providing an
open implementation
and one more thing
we want to emphasize is the exploitation
of a parallelism is important in average
circuit evaluation
this gives significant speed up
to expand the possibility of utilizing
partisan
we have to care about both cat level and
architectural paradism in the circuit
design and prepare massive critical
capabilities like multiple gpus and the
scheduler which can handle the flow of
it
for any question about our research
please post to the github discussion in
our implementation repository and or
send an email to this address
thank you for watching
you