hi i'm christian russell and faculty
member at the cisco handbook center for
information security in
germany i will be presenting yarix a
scalable malware intelligence framework
yarix is joined work with my phd student
michael brennan
malware analysts typically have access
to large malware databases that they use
on a daily basis to hunt files
as the main file hunting mechanism they
use yala which is a framework designed
with a particular focus to search for
patterns in malware sample collections
assume an analyst is interested in
spotting memo files of the so-called
skraze family
to this end they search which of the
files contains disgrace typical file
indicator screenblaze.xz
this is just one out of many use cases
of file hunting with yara
others include for example obtaining
lineage information of a certain memory
family testing new indicators of
compromise or on demand sample sharing
with other researchers
however such sequential yara searches do
not really scale well to really large
memory databases
but antivirus vendors and threat
intelligence companies do have such
large databases that spend millions if
not even billions of malware files
thus our overarching research question
here is how can we use yara efficiently
in large member databases
a simple strawman solution will be to
cache previous search results and search
terms
this way you can quickly go back to
previous results and when adding new
files flag them accordingly
the drawback however is that for every
new query you have to fall back to slow
sequential search
in fact though such new queries happen
regularly
for instance when new malware families
arise or when existing signatures need
to be updated or when others ask for a
change of specific macro samples
therefore we introduce yarix a generic
approach that does not require any a
priori knowledge of search queries
yarix features a reverse file index that
maps possible search terms to files
containing them
for example assume the following file
which contains abcde and so on
for each n-gram of this file
yaric stores the corresponding front
identifier in a per-engram lookup table
that we refer to as a posting list
while configurable we find that n equals
4 is the perfect compromise between
space efficiency and search performance
jrx then processes all n-grams contained
in all index files and thereby builds in
complete reverse index
for an arbitrary subsequent query yarix
uses these posting lists to search for
candidate files that contain the search
string to this end we first extract
n-grams from the search term
for instance when searching for abcde we
find two foregrounds abcd and bcde
we then query the respective posting
lists and find that each two files in
this case gray and black
and black and blue contain the n-grams
in this particular example only the
single file that falls into the
intersection of both engram searches can
be a true candidate
the rx does not store position
information about engrams
as compromise for better storage
efficiency
thus in the last and final step jarex
sequentially scans all candidate files
to reveal the two positives and return
those to the query initiator
the search terms we have used so far
admittedly were straightforward and
rather toy examples
in practice threat analysts use yara
signatures that can define arbitrarily
complex pattern conditions
here's an example which satisfies true
if at least one of the two end
conditions is satisfied
we wanted yaris to not only support
simple string search but actually to
support any arbitrary yara signature
to this end we use abstract syntax trees
to break down yarrow signatures into
foregrounds
yarix then searches these four grams in
its postings
and merges the individual search results
to refine the minimum set of candidate
files
yarix supports many yara features beyond
plane strings
support for hex strings is
straightforward by extracting all
streaks and proceeds similar to plane
springs
for regular expressions from the dfa we
automatically extract the plane strings
that will be contained in any matching
string
for search times like at least x out of
the following strings we proceed as
before for strings then count and use a
cutoff threshold
conditionals
like and and or are converted into
candidate set intersections and unions
respectively there are many more
features that yaric supports please
refer to the paper in the github
repository for full details
whenever yarix does not support a
feature it over-proximates search
results
this way jaric stays sound and complete
one of the downsides of maintaining
reverse index are is storage
requirements
we thus apply a few tricks to shrink the
reverse index as much as possible
first as already mentioned we do not
store engram offsets and instead we just
restore them later during the sequential
scan phase
second instead of storing file ids we
just store the distance the previous
file id that is the predecessor in the
processing list
to this end we store ids in a sorted
manner
and
store finally offsets only
furthermore we use a variable length
7-bit encoding scheme to minimize the
storage width of each relative vitality
stored in the pulsiness
finally yarix officially supports an
adaptive file grouping mechanism
the basic idea is to group several
posting lists entries into one thereby
staving saving storage demands and the
cost of lower search performance
without going into much details let me
briefly mention that the rx grouping
leverages the fact that yara signatures
typically search for multiple engrams
we therefore use modular arithmetic
combined with purposing this grouping
such that group elements are not
congruent
that is the loss of precision that is
introduced by grouping reduces
significantly when intersecting multiple
group search results
details are in section 3.6 of our paper
let me now turn to the evaluation
results
we evaluated both search performance and
space space efficiency
we first look at search performance in
terms of absolute time it requires to
carry common error signatures
to this end we obtain 32 million memory
samples and about 1 400 yara signatures
from a well-read rebuilding repository
following box plot shows absolute run
times and seconds for four database
sizes ranging from 10 000 samples on the
left to the full set of 32 million
samples of the right
the blue box
shows the blue boxes show the time
required to look up the index
the red boxes the time for the
sequential scan on the candidate files
and the green boxes
they show the total time
let's focus on the right part of the
figure
covering 32 million files takes less
than 10 seconds in most cases and a few
seconds or million
a few yara signatures in our dataset
that did not allow to pre-filter have
heavily skew the average and can easily
optimize for yards
compared to sequential scans this
provides a huge speed up which as
expected grows with the size of the
dataset at hand for our largest data set
jrx is more than 5 orders to increase
faster than sequential scans on average
this also easily illustrates that full
sequences against grand lodge dataset
are really impractical
the speed up of course comes at the cost
of additional storage requirements for
the index
we therefore evaluate the index size
relative to the sample size
without any optimizations as shown here
yarix adds factor 2.8 of the sample size
as overhead
delta encoding as shown here reduces the
this overhead to factor 1.5
and
even more effectively grouping as shown
the green line here has an even higher
effect and reduces the operator less
than the original samples need
themselves
the lower the number of groups the less
expenses required at the expense of
lower search performance
as expected
using all space optimizations combined
to the purple line here the rx achieves
the best compression result
to summarize represented yarix a yara
engine that scales to a large number of
bioware samples
the rx extracts searchable terms from
yara signatures and converts them into
an asd
its underlying reverse file index helps
to find candidate fast effectively
speeding up over 5 orders of magnitude
compared to sequentially our skins
we release the rx as open source tool
and invite everyone for contributions
thanks for your attention i'm happy to
take questions