over to Paul
thank you it's wonderful to be back in
uh Budapest this is my first time to
speak at activity a few years ago I had
the opportunity to visit Budapest for
b-sides Budapest it's a really great
conference uh
I always wanted to be a be be an
activity to speak so I'm very happy to
be here uh it's one of the most
beautiful cities in the world I've been
all over the world but I tell everyone
Budapest it's a must-see everyone needs
to see Budapest it's just it's amazing
to see this city uh so I'm Paul Coggin
I'm from Huntsville Alabama in the U.S
uh what background expertise is uh
networking telecommunications service
provider and I have a a great deal of
interest in space uh specifically
because I'm interested in the network
telecommunications Communications over
satellites but also have a great deal of
experience with cyber security focusing
on I was always the red team guy that
focused on the network infrastructure
layer one through layer three so that
led me into being interested in
Satellite Communications and from that
started wanting to figure out you know
what just what is going on with
satellite and space communication so
this this presentation we're not going
to focus so much on the ground systems
which there's been a lot in the news
here lately with the biasat hike and uh
just this week I was reading that uh
apparently the the Russian commercial
satellite system has possibly been
hacked so but we're going to focus with
this talk more on folks more on the
spacecraft itself some things that uh I
discovered doing research trying to get
a baseline understanding of where we
stand with satellite Communications
um so
we start looking at uh
space systems similar if you come from
an Enterprise Telco service provider
environment you're used to having a
security operations center if you're a
router person like me I'm an old school
router guy you know a network operations
center with your HP openview Cisco Works
Etc monitoring health and status and
monitoring of your network
well the in the in the spacecraft World
they have they called the sock the knock
they call it a ground system
and that's where they have the antennas
and networks so that they can make sure
that they have access to the spacecraft
as it orbits around the world
around the earth uh so that we no matter
uh you know what what's happening with
the orbit they have visibility and they
can control the spacecraft itself fly
the spacecraft and pull the data from
the payload
it's on that spacecraft
now when we talk about satellites they
have a few different orbits
that everyone's uh you know reading
about starlink the SpaceX starlink
that's in Leo uh the medium earth orbit
the Mio that orbit is a little bit
higher up that's where
your passion your uh
your pnt
your navigation timing positioning
uh satellites are like uh gnss here in
Europe GPS and US Badoo and China the
the pnt satellites typically are in the
Mio orbit and then Geo think about Geo
those are The Satellites that revolve
revolve around the earth as the Earth
orbits it keeps a fixed location and is
pointing at a at a specific geographic
area and as the Earth orbits as
satellite orbits with it and always
keeps a visibility on the same spot
think like a cable TV type of satellites
are all they're always watching the same
spot at Geo they're a lot higher up
it does so from a ground station these
knock socks what I found fascinating is
I started doing research for this
presentation is you know everybody's
moving their Enterprise operations to
the cloud same thing's happening with
space I just read this morning that SCS
is talking to Microsoft Azure they're
going to team together and move it uh
ground station services to the Microsoft
Azure orbit Cloud there's a company out
of leaf space it's going to offer space
ground station Services called Leaf
space they're out of uh Italy
um kubos they're they're they have a
tool called uh Major Tom that
application is going to run in the my
Amazon AWS cloud and then Amazon offers
their own ground station services
like I mentioned Microsoft Azure they
have the orbit service
for uh providing ground station services
and my understanding is that Google is
getting into this business as well and I
believe I've read that SpaceX the
startling network is actually using some
Google infrastructure right now
now
so that's really interesting and I've
too surprising that the ground station
networks here on Earth would be moving
into the cloud as everything else is you
know for scalability to save money but
what's really fascinating is the
Technologies we have on Earth with uh
with cloud
are actually moving to space
so here there's a company a startup
called Leo cloud in their business model
they're actually going to put cloud
infrastructure on spacecraft in space as
a cyber security professional
one of the questions I had in my mind is
how are we going to do incident response
and forensics when we start having uh
you know ransomware content you know
some kind of contamination
uh you know Pi you know our private
information uh divulged up in space how
we're going to clean up a cyber security
issue up in space you know it's going to
it's going to cause uh generate a lot of
new policy discussions to do for us
cyber Security Professionals not only
policy but uh technical procedures of
how we're going to deal with uh with the
cloud and the infrastructure as we move
to space now one of the enabling
technologies that are going to enable
data center Cloud infrastructure to move
to space there's a company out of uh
Israel called raman.space and they've
come up developed a terabyte hard drive
that is radiation hardened for space and
I'm going to go in into some more detail
in a few slides of why it's very
important to have radiation hardening
because of the Hostile space weather up
in space
so so this the problems are being solved
and so we're going to have a high
capacity hard drive up that are going to
be available to be put up in space like
I said this one is uh is going to be a
terabyte drive so you know technology
evolves it'll get larger and larger
capacity available to us
now what really surprised me is I was
working on this research and this blew
me away is apparently they're uh there's
these large craters on the moon and
inside these craters if you get in these
craters and then go back into the moon
there's apparently lava tunnels I had no
idea there was a such thing as lava
tunnels which implies there's a vault
there's there was a volcano at some kind
of time I've seen lava tunnels in Hawaii
on the big island where there's active
volcanoes and the lavatones are really
really cool to see but I could I never
read never understood anything about
lava tunnels actually existing on the
moon but apparently they are and in this
comp Company Lone Star
their their business model they're
actually looking at building data
centers on the moon and putting their
data centers
their Cloud infrastructure in the lava
tunnels and the thought process is is
it'll stabilize the temperature keep the
temperature more consistent because the
temperature swings varies greatly on the
moon it could be like 250 degree
Fahrenheit and then drop like down to
you know minus 200
um
Fahrenheit on the moon the temperature
group you know is all up down so you get
in those tunnels that'll help stabilize
the temperature possibly and also the
tunnels will shield the infrastructure
from the radiation it's being the solar
flares the ions and protons and things
the cosmic rays that are shooting
through space if we're going to go into
detail on uh it'll protect the equipment
from
from that hostile space weather
so it's very I found this very
interesting so
as an old school network guy they must
spend most of my career uh programming
routers building telecommunications
networks npls things like that this
really uh fascinated me that where uh
the satellite Communications companies
are looking at going now in this case
NTT they're looking at leveraging free
space Optics basically Optical
technology you know you're not going to
strain fiber across space but they're
going to take open free space Optics and
be able to shoot lasers between the
satellites and build 10 100 Gig
networks up in space
with the lasers and to the ground and so
that's going to enable a whole new
architecture uh Network
telecommunications up in space that
we're used to down on the ground so this
is going to be really really interesting
to see where things are going but again
we put all this up in space
the bad guys are going to figure out how
to hack it
so it's very very interesting this is
going to be exciting so we're going to
come up with make sure we understand how
to con and come up with methods and for
monitoring the control plane the data
plane the management plane of this
network infrastructure that's going to
be on satellites up in space just like
we do here on the ground
make sure all that is properly secured
and monitored
and then how we're going to do the
incident response and forensics for it
all that's got to be worked through
up
we'll start talking about the threats to
Space Systems as we have on this chart
here for the right if you're from the
going from the left to the right
a lot of threats or old school like
jamming electronic warfare where someone
will generate a really strong radio
frequency signal try to put noise over
power the radio signal to uh the
spacecraft and when the power is removed
from that source of of the signal the
the threat will just go away and no
permanent damage it could be you could
also have a laser it's just dazzling a
sensor and disrupting uh the payload the
sensor payload and then you take it away
and it goes away and there's no
permanent damage but as you move to the
right what if at least if you have a
really hot laser or some other kind of
directed energy like some really
powerful microwave weapon uh that's in
the electronic warfare domain if you
start applying that you could actually
damage the the satellite the spacecraft
and all the As you move to the right you
get more kinetic and it can be uh you
know say an anti-satellite missile an
ASAP missile that would actually destroy
the spacecraft uh or like I said you
know uh could be a satellite to
satellite kinetic type hit and those
would not be reversible that's going to
create
permanent damage you're going to create
debris which is leading to a lot of
conversation that everyone's worried
about if we start if there's if there
was a uh attacks in space it starts
creating all of this debris it could end
up creating a debris field that could
cause a chain reaction known as a
Kessler syndrome where one piece of
debris hits another piece of debris or
hits an active spacecraft which creates
more debris and that Chain Reaction just
keeps replicating until there's so much
debris in the space orbit that we can no
longer access space and so that's known
as Kester syndrome so you may read about
that in the news a lot of conversation
about that
so along those lines
I found it fascinating that
that there's already been weapons it put
in space
I was it was very new to me to discover
apparently back in the 70s when the
Soviet Union put up the alma space
station they put a 23 millimeter cannon
on the space station I found very
interesting
there's probably other weapons I'm just
not aware of but but I found this
reference I just found a flush you might
find interesting as well that that
canons have been put into space
but also there is a new satellite system
that's been designed called the Syracuse
the for the French and they're looking
at actually arming the Syracuse
satellite so that it can protect itself
from other hostile spacecraft satellites
Etc that may uh want to damage the
spacecraft so they're looking at either
using a submachine gun
or possibly lasers to protect that
spacecraft from other hostile spacecraft
so I find that better interesting and
that's supposed to be put in orbit in
like 20 30.
well we'll get get back focused on cyber
security type threats uh the the world
it used to be electronic warfare it was
in one separate domain and cyber was in
another domain but but they're very
quickly converging the whole uh radio RF
uh domain is converged with cyber
security so you could have jamming
jamming's a real thread we're going to
go into a few examples of malware uh
that is that is uh have infections that
have happened to space spoofing there's
a lot of spoofing of GPS and gns signals
happening across Europe and around the
world that's affecting shipping uh
affecting planes Etc has been a lot in
the news for years
about that targeting the control the
control payload the uh control of the
spacecraft possibly that's a something
to Target and because of a lack of
encryption
Communications might be replayed you
could hijack it you can eavesdrop it and
we're going to go into some detail uh
because I was one of the real things
that was a real interest to me is when I
was doing this research where uh was if
satellite Communications encrypted or
not and so we're going to go into some
detail on that I come up with a lot of
examples and research things examples
zoned out on the internet and open
source and some things I've learned in a
grad school program and I'm actually
pursuing a fourth Masters in Space
Systems because of my interest in space
and so we'll go into some examples of
why
a lot of the spacecraft are not using
encryption
so to jump into that so so there's a lot
of sources for Galactic cosmic rays out
in space but the primary source here
especially here for Earth is our sun
and it's in all these Galactic cosmic
rays with protons and ions and
specifically the ions are uh what is
what very it's very disruptive and even
here on Earth
our atmosphere protects the Earth from
most of this activity the
electromagnetic activity is happening
from the Sun there's a great deal of
activity on the sun right now that we're
worried about actually on Saturday
October the 8th there's the scientists
are estimating that there are some
activity that's happening in eruption on
the Sun that we may see some negative
effects here but there's uh it could
affect like the power grid I read where
there was trains in northern Europe
where uh the train tracks were actually
the signals were signaling that there
was trains on the track when there
really wasn't a train on the track as a
result uh these cosmic rays uh hitting
uh making it through worse atmosphere
and affecting electronics and my
understanding is also our pirate Grid
it's going to take some major upgrades
to our power grid to totally protect
this from a major uh Cosmic
solar wind storms
now what does that have to do with
spacecraft
but
what is just like a our like I said our
solar system our atmosphere here on
Earth is protected from most of this
activity but up in space damage from you
know the further you get out in the
space you have less atmosphere to
protect the equipment and so the
satellites the spacecraft the space
station Etc are out there closer to
these sources
have less atmosphere to protect them
especially the higher higher they go up
into orbit
those uh solar flares those ions that
are when they hit those spacecraft it
causes an event called us a
a single event upset and what happens is
it can flip bits on the electronics
you're not going to only it can only it
can degrade
the equipment on the spacecraft over
time but but electronically I think if
you were trying to do encryption if
you're trying to have encrypted
Communications you're trying to exchange
keys
and you start getting these single event
upsets and bids start getting flipped it
wasn't going to happen it's going to
kill the encryption you're going to lose
your connection you don't have to do the
key exchange all over it again to get
your connection re-established that's
bad news if you're trying to fly a
spacecraft or trying to manage your
payload on the spacecraft and that's
where all we have to use radiation
hardening to protect this equipment so
that all this solar flare activity in
these sources of cosmic rays don't
affect the equipment but when we start
adding this radiation hardening
it can
and I it obviously it adds cost it makes
things more complex makes things more
difficult it increases uh the overall
budget requirements for the project and
so you have to do this risk analysis and
way out
you know the the benefits but if you
know if it's some sensitive
Communications very sensitive activities
on those payloads then you're going to
want to go and add the the radiation
hardening so that you can protect your
electronics and protect the encryption
uh of your of your network connections
but a lot a lot of the satellite
Communications are out there
they're not encrypted and so we're going
to go into some examples of that
and because it's not encrypted it's been
published at black hat Defcon quite a
bit since back 2009 I believe it's from
2010 some of the first papers I've seen
published where some researchers went
into pretty good detail of how you can
go and passively monitor satellite
Communications you get a specialized
card your dish
uh and basically you can end up uh being
able to pull Network traffic right up
and right out of the air
and read it with your Wireshark your
packet analyzer
which opens up some interesting ideas
about being able to do threat hunting
and identify threads that are out there
in space because of the traffic that is
unencrypted
oh here's a real world example
of unencrypted communications there was
a Navy satellite a U.S Navy satellite
that used the UHF band and apparently it
was unencrypted in this satellite in
this case
some uh radio
[Music]
enthusiasts
they uh discovered that they could use
the satellite for for their radio
communications specifically for the CB
Community CB radio communications and it
was a legal of course and by the time
they got busted uh 39 people were
arrested across nine different states in
Brazil and what and according to what
the open source information is out there
by the time they went and arrested all
these 39 people that they identified
using the the satellite illegally for
the communications more people were on
the network using it I mean as soon as
they got those arrested there were more
people that it discovered and were using
it so that's an example of unencrypted
Communications on the satellites
this is pretty famous One
it also helps prove the point that
encrypt that there's a lot of open
unencrypted Communications out there and
if you want if you're using satellite
Communications at home like I I lived in
a rural part of the U.S for many many
years in my internet connectivity was
satellite that's the only thing I could
get I can get I finally after 10 years I
finally have fiber
but for many many years I was having
used satellite and it was all open and
in this case
to prove the point about open encrypted
unencrypted Communications there was the
turtle malware if you haven't heard
about it where uh
the the malware
someone would get infected in the
malware would report back to the C2
server
through satellite broadcast
async tell the C2 server hey I'm I'm
infected in the C2 server is out
squatted out in some out in uh in the
satellite Network it's spoofing an IP
address it was available and just
listening because of all the
communications from the satellite is
being broadcast to the ground so he's
just having to listen and then when it
received notification that somebody had
been been infected with the malware then
over a physical wire line
it would go and start sending commands
and so the communications were async if
you're a threat Hunter monitoring and
looking for this type of traffic it's
going to be really hard to detect it
when you're getting one part of the
connection over uh satellite broadcast
in the in another part of the
communication is going over a wire line
very sophisticated uh
attack but this would not have been
possible if encryption was used
now
there are there is research going into
this to try to remediately remediate
some of these problems where uh where
the budgets
it's not cost feasible to add radiation
hardening to the satellite
uh in this example the European Space
Agency
what I've read is uh they're developing
some Hardware from that was published
was published in 2019
they're putting out a testing of
solution where some uh
pre-shared Keys could be put in the
hardware
and uh there have been putting redundant
fpgas in the hardware as well so that if
the satellite into like a cubesat was to
be hit with a solar storm solar flares
you know the ions the single event
upsets they start disrupting Electronics
there would already be pre-shared keys
on the satellite so that if there was a
problem during the whole negotiation and
sharing Keys there's already keys on the
satellite so that the satellite can
recover commute secure Communications
quickly without having to go through
radiation hardening and also with the
Redundant fpgas may be the say the solar
flare some kind of space weather anomaly
if it affects One processor you have the
Redundant processor to take over and
give you a little redundancy so there
are there are some some things happening
some research to to help mitigate this
problem without having to go through the
expense of radiation hardening for
low-called satellites
nope
one example that was published I believe
it was brief that black Hatter Defcon uh
where malware was used it had an effect
in space speculated that the stux knit
malware somehow found its way into an
Indian satellite cable TV satellite
company
uh and they had a cable TV satellite
called inside 4B and it speculated
that that they were using the Siemens
win CC
and the same PLC the PLC was on the
satellite and was used to rotate the
solar panels on the satellites is what
what is believed and so so the stocks
and malware found its way into the
ground station and through the ground
station was able to get on the satellite
and disable the inside 4B satellite
there's a lot of arguing back and forth
whether what happened there but I found
it very interesting that that scenario
might have played out where stuxnet
actually disabled a satellite possibly
foreign
this was in malware
was the roadside satellites it was a U.S
German collaboration
where the satellite was uh was looking
was designed to look into deep space
speculated that someone broke into a
ground station
and was able to go from the ground
station to control the satellite and to
turn the set the satellite toward the
sun which ended up disabling the
satellite
foreign
hack that happened was uh landsat 7
apparently at two different occurrences
around 12 minutes each uh in 2007 in
2008 the landsat 7 satellite was uh
was hacked in my understanding is the
based on what I've read in the articles
about this the Publications is the
satellite was hacked the bad guys had
access to it and they had the level of
access that they could control the
satellite
but they didn't my my
what I'm speculating
is that the satellite has what they call
a lot of these satellites have what they
call a watchdog where after there's a
period of time if certain activity is
not happening that it will revert back
to a known good state I'm speculating
that maybe uh with a with these with a
few more of these examples that the uh
whoever broke into these satellites
maybe they got in and through being
security by obscurity maybe they got
into the satellite and they didn't know
the operating system the command
language because there's like over 20
operating systems and over 20 something
uh command languages
on the Opera on the satellites in
addition to like over 20 something uh
protocols so maybe uh they got on the
satellite it's kind of like a uh a real
you know maybe a really sharp windows
hacker gets onto a uh
an old school you know no Solaris VMS
box they made me know what they're doing
on Windows but they don't know what
they're doing on that that old Solaris
uh BMS box so they got in but they
didn't they couldn't go any further and
then the Watchdog timers reverted back
and uh got the silage back to a known
state so that the owners of the assets
could uh Take Back Control
that's my speculation anyway
uh I don't know what really happened but
I'm just trying to think through the
problem this is a terror satellite it
was also hacked it was high for two
minutes in 2008 and then in June of 2008
and hacked again in October of 2008. two
different times similarly I was
wondering about uh what was going on
there but they were able to take back
control the asset owner whoever owns the
satellite can be able to take it back
over
uh
and then in 2014 it's uh attributed to
China that they broke into the NOAA a
NOAA weather satellite for a period of
time and it and access to the satellite
was recovered and the bad guys were
kicked off the satellite but that
happened in 2014.
and
also there's uh apparently back in 1999
there was a
there's a satellite constellation my
estimates is like there's Force there's
four satellites in this constellation
called Skynet in the UK and there's
there's a lot of arguing back and forth
about really what happened with this
satellite constellation but one of the
satellites apparently got compromised it
speculated by some that uh that
that was hacked and was held for ransom
there's a there's a big dispute that
says no it wasn't wasn't held for ransom
it wasn't totally completely taking
control of but the control Channel
between the ground station the satellite
was take was hacked
uh so
it depends on who you want to believe
there's a there's a lot of back and
forth about this when you might have
like said happened back in 1999
but they did get some level of access to
the satellite at least to the control
Channel
uh well again from a malware standpoint
there was two two events I found on the
space station where uh Russian
astronauts cosmonauts introduced malware
to the space station and it did not get
access to the flight control system they
would have threatened the lives of the
astronauts and the uh the space station
itself
but uh but it did there wasn't the
infections malware infections on the
space station one was introduced through
a USB flash drive and another was uh
through a laptop
that introduced malware in the space
station so I found that interesting so
we're gonna have to do rinse and
response and forensics and Recovery up
in space like we mentioned earlier
there there are organizations that are
looking at the space that the security
for Space Systems and developing the
standards and best practices there's an
international organization the
consultative committee for space Data
Systems
it's an international body think like
itu IEEE they're working on the
standards and best practices for
securing satellites uh you know the
protocols they come up with the
different protocols to standardize how
you know to communicate with your
satellites and also they come up with a
way to secure in both the ground station
and the the spacecraft as well as the
protocols
so that's all being heavily worked now
the question is is
what is the risk you know uh you got to
balance it out what is your budget how
much time you want to spend on security
hardening
uh the value of the assets Etc so not
everyone is implementing all the
security capabilities that are
recommended due to budget and uh
perceived risk
and now you're not as the risk has
evolved and capabilities have gotten
sophisticated when these spacecraft get
launched up in space however long they
they they're up there you know that
doesn't stop us on Earth from doing
research and discovering vulnerabilities
now that spacecraft the spacecraft is up
in orbit
it's a hard to patch it but the good
thing the good things happening now with
new spacecraft if software is moving
towards software-defined networking uh
with virtualization with DMS and
containers things like that
software-defined radio so that when you
get a with these new assets these new
spacecraft assets up into space if
there's bugs if there's issues
vulnerabilities it's more easily to
patch and upgrade the spacecraft and add
new features and capabilities once it's
in orb is going toward a
software-defined satellite
now here's the long list of uh best
practices I know you can't read this if
you'll hit me if you're interested I can
send you the slides and I'll give you a
share that has uh the spreadsheet with
all these uh reference links in it if
you're interested in spacecraft security
there is a great deal of work going on
in the domain nist has has released a
couple of Standards uh nist 8270 Nest
8401 our uh best practice guidelines
that they've released for how to secure
the ground station and spacecraft
down at the very bottom there there's a
a reference to Germany German the German
government space organization uh I
believe Airbus has collaborated with
them on this they put out a best
practice for securing spacecraft
Noah
uh
sisa in the U.S MIT
the university in the U.S Aerospace
Corporation all of those have also
released best practice guidelines for
securing your spacecraft
now if you're interested in spacecraft
you want to learn more about it you need
to you want to build your own Lab at
home here's some really good references
save you some time Googling uh here's
them that are some resources are pretty
good uh there's the open site kit NASA
in the openside kit NASA provides uh the
common flight
the CFS the core flight system
that's a cubesat
operating system ball Aerospace Cosmos
is included with that that is a ground
system software that will control the
the core flight cubesat system in that
CFS will run on like a beagle bone
Raspberry Pi run it in a Docker
container what have you uh there's also
the nos3 from NASA and by the way
there's uh the 42 space simulator which
is an orbit simulator so you can
simulate an orbit as well all on your
system
um in the if you want some variety I've
discovered that uh that space chain OS
it's a design for a blockchain
application in space
it's uh from a company in China
and uh it's also and there's also the
solex OS it's available on GitHub and
that is the my understanding is that is
the operating system that the Chinese
use for their spacecraft and space the
space chain OS is apparently based on
Silex as well to and then there's the
Artemis project the sad nogs uh projects
that you might find interesting if
you're into modeling and simulation you
know there's a lot of a lot of uh
discussion on the internet about web one
uh the starlink constellation these big
these really large internet
constellations that are being put up in
the space so that we can have internet
connectivity or anywhere around the
globe
you might want to check out Icarus
Icarus is a open source tool some
research is uh released so that you can
Model A a low worth orbit internet
Network
and simulate things like a denial a
service attack against uh these uh these
Leo internet satellites I have not
personally worked with Icarus yet but
all the research I've read about is
pretty cool
so
so uh
if you uh that's about what I had if
there are any uh questions
hope hope you uh got something out of
this I appreciate the activity team
invited me to speak here today
thank you any any
[Applause]
if
if you don't have any question now you
can always approach Paul the information
is available
uh you can
we have a question
thank you
hello thank you very much for the
presentation and uh
the virus that you mentioned that has
been carried to the ISS by Russian
osternote was it stuxnet or other virus
as well and did it affect the the
relation of Russian and international
and U.S
astronautical
organizations and
I didn't if there was anything very
negative about it's just uh you know
you're bringing electric you're bringing
laptops and electronics from the ground
to space
and malware is going to find its way
on the system just like our systems on
the ground here you start bringing thumb
drives and laptops
something that's going to find its way
in it's just it was a problem I'm
intentional was that by uh unintentional
was it a
I don't know it was not by accident it
was it was believed to be accidental it
was not intentional it's just you know
things are going to happen it's like one
of our someone that works on our team
could intentionally bring a malware into
our networks somebody's probably doing
it right now
you know clicking on a link and bringing
malware incident it was not a
intentional
it was just accidental I see
thank you
any more questions
well I hope uh this was informative you
learned something uh
although I learned a great deal
researching this answered a lot of
questions for myself
so if you have any questions if you
would like the slides you know I'll give
you a link uh that has all the
information and all the references and
stuff for all the best practices Etc
save yourself a lot of time if you're if
you're interested in working on this
like I said this right here will save
you a lot of time this link if you want
to build your own lab and like I said
you could do this very low cost docker
bigger bone raspberry pies there's a
great deal of documentation out on the
internet
to even help students in high school do
projects with this so there's a lot out
there to try to help the younger
generation come to speak
space is going to be very very important
in the future as it is today so thank
y'all
thanks Paul