to get the ball rolling
I'll hand you over to
Zoltan balaj
good afternoon everyone and good morning
for the rest of you
so today I'm going to talk about web
free and scams
so I'm leading the vulnerability
research lab at Cujo AI I had a bunch of
different offensive research in the past
for example when I was playing with an
iot device I found a post authentication
exploit which I published because I
thought it's post authentication so it's
fine this research ended up in a boatnet
so practically code I wrote was running
on 600 000 different computers usually
could I write only runs on one computer
or it doesn't run at all so I was pretty
proud about this achievement
I also invented the idea of encrypted
exploit delivery and I'm in the program
Committee of the activity Conference
co-organizer of the hack actually meet
up and volunteer at iot Village
so um this is a two-hour presentation
compressed into
14 minutes not 25 so if I sign your
seatbelt uh why am I doing this research
I really love playing with new
technology and I really find blockchain
and they're free really interesting
uh as you can see there are a lot of
issues with this technology but I pretty
much believe in this one that by time it
will evolved into something really great
I also have a wife paper about this
presentation so if you are interested
just ping me and I can send you the
white paper link
all right so
I was mentioning the free and scams so
some people think that free is a scam
which I don't believe that this is the
case I will not discuss smart contract
issues because that's a totally
different topic
uh I will not give you any Financial
advice where you should invest your
money
I will not discuss crypto exchange hacks
and I will not discuss any type of scams
where cryptocurrencies only the money
what is used uh is a form of payment
so how do we get here
um clearly everyone knows that a lot of
people got rich from cryptocurrencies
and a lot of people want to get rich
from cryptocurrencies
uh when I first created these slides uh
there was a saying that the total market
capitalization is around 2 trillion US
dollars
uh right now it's only one trillion but
still I think it's a significant amount
of money I have no idea uh what this
amount of money is I know it's a bit
more than my monthly salary so clearly
this is a lot of money
so uh as you will see during the
presentation this is a very new complex
technology with a really crappy user
interface
so the question is what could possibly
go wrong if you combine these facts
together
so let's say that we have a scammer and
he's shopping around for new scans what
should I do today
[Music]
should I send some romantic scans
shall I send some invoices from T-Mobile
or do I do some package delivery from
UPS
[Music]
or
let's use some very nice the free
related scan right this is what's new
hot right now for all the scammers they
really like this scenario
okay so let's discuss Bitcoin because
Bitcoin is the basis of all the
cryptocurrencies so it's very important
that everyone understands what is crypto
about and I have invited a free Grammy
Award winner blockchain expert to tell
you everything you have to know about
Bitcoin
a message from cash app and the CEO of
hot girl Enterprise Megan the stallion
wait it's the new digital currency
that's been getting a lot of hype
[Music]
Bitcoin is a new kind of money while the
cash in your wallet is issued and
regulated by governments Bitcoin is a
cryptocurrency like a wild stallion it
can't be controlled by anywhere that
means that no one person or organization
gets to decide how much of it is used
how much of it is in circulation or what
it's worth
okay so boom there's only a limited
amount of Bitcoin like gold silver or me
it's scarcity and security is what can
make Bitcoin valuable
every Bitcoin is unique and has its own
ID that is certified by a super secure
technology called the blockchain
you can't make a fake Bitcoin no matter
how hard you try
foreign
like gold or gas prices bitcoin's value
can go up and down as the demand changes
although there's some other Nitty Gritty
stuff that factors into
that means when people are selling the
price goes down
when lots of people are buying it
it comes back up
Bitcoin is not hard to get you just
gotta know how you can get it from
another person or from special markets
called cryptocurrency exchanges you can
also easily buy it on cash app starting
with as low as one dollar's worth
Bitcoin is an investment so you can lose
money the price can go up and down by
the hour but the more you educate
yourself on bitcoin the better equipped
your B to navigate those curves
that's all for now but with my knowledge
and your hustle you'll have your own
Empire in no time I'll see you at the
top
so the reason I really like this video
because it shows you that a lot of
people are into cryptocurrencies they
have no idea what it is
but also what I liked in this video that
uh definitely some lawyers who are
involved in this ad because I'm pretty
sure that whoever paid for this ad they
did not the original idea was not to
advertise that hey you can lose money on
bitcoin hey the price can go down so
this will assure the lawyers who added
these texts
and today I'm going to show you a lot of
different scamming techniques and in
order to see how much money a scammer
can make from these scams I introduced
the lamp o Meter because in the
cryptocurrency word you usually measure
your valve regarding how many
Lamborghinis you have
so the question from scamming is that
not whether you can make one Lambo but
how many
so let's start with Kim Kardashian pump
and dump case
she was into this crypto token called
ethereum Max and
um I think it was only this week that
Kim Kardashian was
sued and now she has to pay a penalty of
I don't know a lot of money because of
this advertisement but as far as I
remember she is not uh
she doesn't have to pay this money
because she did something wrong like
pumping up the price of this token but
because she forgot to pay the taxes
after she the money she get from the
people who are behind eat their own Max
so how this pump and dumps Keys Works uh
it's not a new thing you have seen this
also in the stock market or penny stocks
you just have to buy a lot from
something what is cheap and it has a low
volume advertise this as the next big
thing play pay a lot of celebrities to
have your advertisement sell on top
profit right
uh sometimes it's very rare but you can
even make some profit by shorting on the
top so that's very good
um but after a while I think these
celebrities are uh like no from real
um believe them anymore so you can make
some money with this but not that much
rockpool is really similar to pump and
dump but the main difference is that you
are the owner or the developer with this
whole thing and whether it's a
cryptocurrency or a token or nft or
whatever and because you control the
whole ecosystem from the start you can
do a lot of interesting things with this
and there's a very famous case of a rock
pool which was called the squid game
token you might remember this Korean
series squid game which was very popular
last year and some scammers were
benefiting from all the hype so they
created this squid game tokens it's
practically out of thin air like you
don't have to do anything to create one
gazillion of these tokens
then they hired it and when it was on
the top they thought everything and they
got a lot of money and what's really
interesting that there was a leak from a
ransomware group called The Conti group
and if you check their chats they
already knew about this rock pool before
it happened
so there is this very traditional
giveaway scam if you check Twitter there
are famous accounts especially accounts
who are interested in cryptocurrencies
and you can see a lot of lot of bots
replying to these Twitter feeds and they
say that hey someone is giving away
cryptocurrency
you just only have to send some
cryptocurrency beforehand and you will
get twice back
right so actually there are still people
who are falling for this kind of scams
yeah this happens
like uh in this particular case someone
got like almost free Bitcoin which is
kind of a lot of money if you think how
sophisticated this hack is and what's
interesting that sometimes even very
high profile Twitter accounts were
hacked like this is the official Target
Twitter account Target is like a really
big grocery store in the US God knows
how many followers so whenever there's a
scam message like this then for sure
there will be a lot of people who will
believe this
Advanced fee fraud I really like this
one because I also personally received
this cam so I was able to check it for
myself but some of these screenshots are
not mine but it's from a proof Point
research
so what you get in the beginning is an
email where there's a link a username
and a password and they are trying to
convince you that if you log in to this
website with these uh with this password
then you will be able to withdraw some
money from it
and when I tried it it was really
interesting because it was also asking
for my mobile phone number
in order to set up 2fa I stopped at this
point because I didn't want to bother
buying a new SIM card but if you log in
to the website you can see a fake
transaction history for this account
and if you want to withdraw then it
tells you that hey you just only have to
sound a little bit of Bitcoin uh to this
account before you can withdraw
everything
so clearly again this was a scam and uh
actually it was not that bad
so let's discuss nfts or non-fungible
tokens I'm pretty sure most of you know
what these are but let's just give a
quick introduction
um so
I'm active on Twitter and like four
years ago I bought this uh very ugly nft
I think I spent like one and a half
dollars in total uh buying this
particular nft and
um the reason I bought this because this
was the cheapest and probably the
ugliest one
and right now many people are bragging
with the runoff tees on Twitter that hey
I have this uh very expensive monkey
whatever and they are using it as their
profile picture so I thought I should
also brag how rich I am with this one
and a half dollar worth of crypto Kitty
and if you check on Twitter you can see
the address who created the smart
contract address who created this nft
and the nft token ID
this is how it looks like on
ether scan etherscan is practically a
very nice web-based UI for the at our
own blockchain and what you can see here
is that uh
this is my wallet address and this means
that I am the owner of this very nice
picture uh here you can see the contract
address and this is the token ID
so it's very important to see that most
of the time when people buy nfts what
they practically buy is an is a number
on a smart contract
right so that's basically what you buy
whenever you buy an nft
and some promises which are either
fulfilled or not if you check for
example the transaction logs on the
blockchain
here you can see that first this birth
function was called which created this
cryptokitty then the transfer function
was called and this means that now
I am the owner of this crypto Kitty
and um
nowadays most
um nfts they store all the properties of
your nft on a very interesting protocol
called ipfs I will not go into the
detail of those but um
I believe that using ipfs for nfts is a
good choice but back in the days when
cryptocurities were created they did not
use any kind of ipfs so what practically
happens is that when I bought this token
ID
I also received some bits and bytes
which describe how my nftv look like and
here's a smart contract code which
practically can decode these bits and
bytes and say
how my crypto Kitty really looks like
I didn't check the prices today but uh
ethereum is somewhere around
1700 US dollars
uh guess who bought this nft
I can help you uh it's a she and she
also created an nft about herself
and this was the magical design
so it was Paris Hilton and she bought it
for almost
1120 eater room she paid this amount of
money for this nft I believe back then
maybe a Tyrone was even more so yeah
it's a lot of money for this monkey
picture
who bought this one
no one
so this was Justin Bieber he paid 500 it
around for this
if you have a calculator you can try and
calculate this uh and convert it back to
Hungarian for it it's a lot
I really like this nft because it's not
a monkey picture
do you know who bought this one
see it was Snoop Dogg and he paid
2500 ethereum for this
picture and who's this last one
yes I mean I'm
okay so let's discuss about rock pools
in nfts there's this actress called Lana
Rhodes you might know her work from the
internet
and um
she did a rock pool on her nft project
and this is a screenshot where people
are complaining that they invested 4 000
US dollars in this nft project and now
because it's Rockwood it's practically
worthless and this someone has a
two-year-old son and not much money left
um clearly we don't know whether this
story is true or not but uh I'm pretty
sure that there are people out there on
the earth food made
such a good investments in the past
um this is the nft picture which this
someone bought for four thousand US
dollars
and this is again an interesting
screenshot because someone was begging
for a free nft from Lana and she replied
that your diapers are expensive she has
a kid so that's why she has to spend a
lot of money on diapers so she cannot
afford giving away these the flash
pictures for free
and the reason why Lana can get into
trouble because she promised uh phases
of this project
and she never fulfilled these phases
um because
she did The Rock pool very early in the
project and if you do this you can get
into jail because this means that you
promised something to your investors
and you never delivered that promise so
the investors can release you you so
they are like phase six is that uh
no yeah phase five is that uh 50 lucky
cryptosis owners will receive cryptosis
merch signed by Lana
so clearly there were a lot of people on
the internet who were interested in
getting hand signed Lana merch
social media accounts are hacked all the
time different platforms are hacked in
different ways uh for example this is
the live news with like 16
subscribers and it was hacked and it was
doing this Elon Musk giveaway scam which
we have seen recently
in the past uh very famous
nft Instagram accounts were also hacked
like this is the official board AP act
Club Instagram account where the
attackers changed the link to
yogalabs.land which was operated by the
scammers
um there are no official information on
how did this happen what we know is that
uh the uh board API Club developers are
stating that they had complex unique
passwords and 2fa so probably uh I
believe it was a social engineering
attack on Instagram where you can
repeatedly call the Instagram support
and without knowing anything about the
account you can find and convince a
support guy to reset the password on the
account
and um this one's uh also really
interesting because this is a Twitter
account from a company where I know
these people
and we had a discussion that again they
had no idea how their Twitter account
was hacked and it turns out what
happened they again had long complex
unique passwords and 2fa on the account
and it looks like what happened that
someone on the dark net was selling
Twitter admin access for a lot of money
which means that if you have enough
money from your previous scams you can
just go on to the Twitter admin panel
and reset these accounts which will mean
that then you will be able to control
these accounts and post anything on
these accounts so that's bad
um
I'm going to show you an interesting
research which I did and it all started
on Discord I was monitoring the scam
alert channels on Discord and I found
this interesting scam
if you visit this website which was in
the scam you will be able to see this
where you can it promises you that
practically you can get new
nfts for free
and in the beginning you just have to
connect your account with your wallet
this is no malicious per se
but after connecting the JavaScript on
the website it will check your valid
address on openc and it will check what
type of nfts do you have and whether
they are worth stealing or not
so clearly this is something fishy here
and
if you already connected your wallet
then instead of the mint function which
you would expect from minting a new nft
the website suggests that you call this
safe transfer from function and if you
call this function on the contract this
is the contract of the nft what you have
so if you call this function it means
that you are giving away your nft to the
scammers which is this address
so clearly this is a user interface
issue because people are in a rush they
don't really understand what these
functions mean
so they are just clicking on confirm and
it doesn't really matter how many layers
of nice cryptography is behind your
wallets and nfts and blockchains and
whatever you are practically signing a
contract that hey I'm giving away my
nfts for free and I'm giving away this
for this camera
I checked the scammer website and I
found a GitHub page where this camera
was publishing his source code
and
um I found this uh interesting string
here which led me uh to hit the website
where he's selling it for real money
practically
and here you can see all the different
reviews this guy had like uh
very high quality thank you best trainer
got one azuki nft free day so clearly a
lot of scammers were already using this
framework
um these are all the different
functionalities the scammer
supported
and
yeah
the some parts of this scammer website
it was very heavily obfuscated
and guess how I was able to deal with
skate
these javascripts
what were my very lead hacking skills
I mentioned GitHub I went on GitHub and
checked all the previous comments and
one of the comics had a less obfuscated
version of this JavaScript and for from
there it was really easy to decrypt it
um and what was really interesting that
uh once I was able to access this
version I saw this code that if
something is more than 1.1
then
practically
send it to this and what really happens
that the original creator of this cam
framework added a back door
and the code checks if the nft is a
really expensive one and if it's a
really expensive one it will send these
nfts to the original creator of the
framework and not to the one who's
operating that actual scammer website
so I find I think that I will give 10
points for Evil Genius for this guy who
did this one and I also found proof on
the blockchain that some of these nfts
were sent to one address and the others
were sent to this address
so contacted the guy on telegram because
why not
I was interested in why should I buy for
his product on this website if I can get
it for free on GitHub and I also asked
about this obfuscated parts of the
JavaScript code but he did not tell me
that he had the paid version doesn't
have the back doors so I don't know
whether the paid version has the back
door or not
and this is how it looks like in action
so you visit the website you connect
your metamask account
there's this signature I'm not really
sure why it's there but I believe it's
not malicious
and this is the part where most people
will click on confirm and instead of
minting a new token they will give away
their tokens
yeah and uh
I think what
should be done here is that the wallet
software should show the user that okay
if you click on confirm this monkey
picture will go from your wallet to this
wallet and maybe people will not click
on confirm anymore
um the whole nft Space is on Discord
nowadays everyone has their own Discord
servers
so clearly there are a lot of Discord
related scams as well like you will get
direct messages all the time
you just join any new nft project and
you will instantly get these scammy
messages
and unfortunately I don't have time to
go into the details but nowadays how
Discord servers are hacked are this
interesting hack called bookmarklets
uh hackers will practically convince
Discord admins to
drag and drop from a website a
bookmarklet into their bookmark page and
then they will convince the admin to
login to Discord
and not many people know that but this
these browser bookmarklets they can run
arbitrary JavaScript code
which means whenever the admin logs in
to Discord and clicks on this
bookmarklet
the JavaScript code will steal the
authentication token for the user for
the Discord admin and now the scammers
can take over the Discord channel the
whole Discord servers
and
in July only more than 100 nft Discord
servers were hacked by this bookmarklet
hack so it's really important that at
least you guys know that bookmarklets
are bad and they can run JavaScript
there was also a nice research on where
these scammers are spending their money
and they are spending their money on
these ugly
uh watches
and this is the price which was paid for
this watch
like I don't know I would not wear it if
you pay me like 10 000 forints but
someone paid this amount of money
because they already had a lot from
these scams
so as you can see uh most people believe
that hacking blockchains and nfts and
such is a very dark and complicated
Magic
but it's mostly just social engineering
I also want to touch a little bit the
hardware wallets
the because what most people don't
realize that Hardware wallets are
against the mother on your PC where you
handle your
web free activities
and that's mostly it but if you fall for
this type of scans which I just showed
you
you will use your nft anyway because you
are confirming that transaction
there are very like low-tech uh scams uh
how people are trying to access your
Hardware wallets for example they are
asking for your backup phrase which is
practically the private key for your
wallet
you can also receive some text message
that hey go to this page and update the
firmware on your Hardware wallet
um this is a tricky one uh
they are sending a hardware wallet to
users and the hardware wallet is
pre-configured so whoever sent it
already knows the private key but they
are printing these very convincing
sheets that if you scratch the sheet
then you can access the private key and
use the Ledger this is now how Harvard
wallets work so if you already receive a
backup phrase then someone already knows
that one so don't do that and this is
the low-tech version of the same scam
and this is even more interesting
because uh on this you can see a
hardware back door on The Ledger itself
and someone added a new SD card to the
hardware Ledger and this is a quite
convincing letter that hey we had a
security issue and you should replace
your Ledger with this new version or
whatever
so clearly some people did put a lot of
effort because not many people can do
and add Hardware back doors to Hardware
wallets
so I have some best practices you should
follow clearly don't trust random people
or celebrities on social media
always check the source of your apps or
distributed apps
don't send funds to someone you don't
trust or at least try to verify the
transactions via phone that usually
helps
um if people want to share with you any
type of logins or passwords or private
keys or seed phrase or backup phrases
just block them and don't interact with
them
you should be always extra careful
whenever you interact with either known
or unknown smart contracts because you
can be one click away of losing or your
nft Investments
clearly using password managers is
always a good idea enable two-factor
authentication
text-based
2fa is not good enough anymore
there's a very nice Dark Net Diaries
episode I don't remember which one
but how people are doing these swim
swapping attacks nowadays in the US is
pretty Advanced they are sending kids
into the T-Mobile store and the kids
will steal the tablet from the hand of
the T-Mobile uh people and they have
like five or ten minute window to reset
the telephone account and change that
phone number to another swim SIM card
so as a user you cannot really do
anything against these type of attacks
but it's happening because there's so
much money involved here
if you have a lot of money or already in
cryptocurrencies yeah using Hardware
wallets uh will help you because there's
also a lot of mother trying to hack your
wallets so it will protect against that
one at least
clearly do not use the same Q computer
for game cracks and game hacks which you
use for uh blockchain and web free and
cryptocurrencies
um
using code for let's is a good idea you
just have to
keep your code wallets safe in a way
that 10 years from now you can still
access those
but code wallets are the same that you'd
never bring all of your life savings
with you in your pocket right so you
leave some at home in a safe or whatever
that's the same thing for cold wallets
uh you don't use the same wallet for
interacting scammy websites which you
use which you have nfts and tokens in it
and I think this one this last one is
the most important always take your time
don't rush
like whenever you are seeing this pop-up
that confirmed this transaction
check the website
check the functions check the smart
contracts check how did you get here
take your time don't rush
the nowadays there are also some
security extensions for your browser
like wallet guard or Sunrise nft scan
protector
I personally never use them but some
people say that they are good so if you
want you can experiment with these
um vs could you also want to prevent
these camps and I really wanted to talk
about how we do that unfortunately
lawyers are involved so I can't tell you
but
um yeah fishing
pot Works uh in the cryptocurrency space
and if you know how to fish people then
you can get a lot of Lambos
and
[Music]
I'm scared
[Applause]
[Music]
let's go
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you
[Applause]
any questions thanks awesome questions
or Bitcoin and donations
it's just gonna be a question or
donation
um
so I'm not that familiar uh with how
they uh
technology Works behind web 3.0 but what
bugs me is that everything is logged uh
you get the address that for example the
scammer send the nfts to so why is it so
hard to you know get the valuables back
get the nfts back
go after it
um I think to answer this question I
feel like I will need like 40 minutes at
least and actually I plan to do a
presentation next year about such
similar topic topic
there are some mixers for example like
tornado cash on the their own network
which makes
following all of these transactions
harder because that's why mixers have
been created and
at the end you see a wallet address
you don't have the ID number of the
scammer you see a wallet address and
sometimes if people if these cameras do
offsack mistakes then you can find them
but if they are really good
that you you just can't so it's like the
whole cryptocurrencies bases both
Anonymous and non-anonymous but you have
to know a lot of things to like if you
are a scammer and you want to do proper
off stack it's hard but
some people can do that
we will see we already know that some of
these scammers are behind bars
thank you thank you
we have another one
thank you what do you think about the
role of deep fakes in such scams in
general because on this summer we could
see a lot of celebrity deep fakes in
connection with such scams
I don't know like what I do know that uh
in the news the very first fraud which
was discussing that defects were used
during this Camp it was not related to
cryptocurrencies at all turned out that
there were no defects involved at the
end
so
I think we will see
if that will be the easiest way for
scammers to scam people then clearly
they will use it
if there are easier ways like these ones
I think as long as these wallet
softwares are this shitty like people
don't know what they are doing there's
no reason to use sophisticated defects
and stuff uh clearly there will be a
base comes cryptocurrency related scans
with defects I don't know we will see
that
thank you
because I'll turn any
further questions no okay then once
again salt and thank you very much thank
you