foreign
[Music]
defense in-depth engineering
this is kind of an interesting topic why
are we talking about defense and depth
aren't there bigger problems for us to
be solving
um this is interesting as Jim pointed
out in the keynote this morning we're
kind of at a new era of appsack we have
static analysis tools that are solving a
lot of our problems for us but what
types of things are not being solved by
Static analysis tools what things are
often overlooked by consulting firms
when I think of defense and depth I
think of controls that may often be
overlooked and folks are generally aware
that security is an onion and I hate
using that term technology but there's
layers to it so defense in depth is is
about having several different layers
there
now it's easy to say everything is
defense in depth and in some ways that's
effectively true
so 2021 olasp introduced uh insecure
design to the OAS top 10. in my opinion
that's a huge win and I'm sure
everyone's heard the buzz of Shifting
left that's been a big big term for me
lately
and so when I started thinking about
giving a talk on insecure design the
first thing I did was reach out to one
of my colleagues who's a designer and
say hey I'm giving a talk on design do
you mind doing some stuff for me some
art and so he he introduced Scully skate
shop so there's going to be a little bit
of relevance here
um but clearly he had no idea I was
talking about security design and not
actual other other graphic design and
such so the OAS top 10 insecure design
is to focus on risks related to design
process and to call for more use of
things such as threat modeling secure
design patterns and reference
architectures and this is where we're
starting to see a lot of the industry
shifting in fact there's there's talks
here on threat modeling there's
trainings on threat modeling I walked in
at the end of the talk here and someone
was talking about threat modeling as
well so everyone's talking about threat
modeling hopefully folks are doing it
I'm not here to talk about threat
modeling
so before we get too far let me
introduce myself uh my name is John
Poulin I'm forced request or forced
underscore request depending on where
you look for me on the internet I am a
manager of product security engineering
at GitHub my team focuses on basically
internal Consulting secure code uh
review a little bit of threat modeling
architecture design things of that
nature
um so I like to say I manage a team who
hacks things now I'm not quite as
technical as I I was a few years ago
um before I moved to GitHub I was a
consultant and there I spent a lot of
time doing technical work a lot of
secure code review a lot of pen testing
and even before that I worked as a
software engineer and I like to make the
joke that as a software engineer I wrote
things that were hacked we know that's
not true none of my code was ever
compromised right but now I wish that
was the case
um so yeah I'm excited to give this talk
I've never given this talk before it's
something I've been thinking about a lot
at work so hopefully folks enjoy
and with any luck there will be time for
questions at the end if not catch me in
the hallway I know standing between
folks and lunch at 11 30 so pretty
challenging spot to be in up here
the first thing I want to talk about
there's kind of four main categories of
this talk and the first one is to uh
design for incidents I'm only talking
about this because one of our incident
responders at GitHub is sitting in the
audience here so I wanted to make sure
that their work was included as well
um so becoming friends with your
incident response team who here works on
an incident response team at all
okay okay a few who here are engineers
in some capacity you're writing code
all right more so make sure you all are
friends with your incident response
teams
so when I think about engineering and I
think about design one of the first
things that comes to my mind is to
really understand the risk of your
system most of the systems we're
building are not for fun there's actual
business purposes they're going to be
handling certain types of data so if I
ask you what's the riskiest type of data
that your system is handling are you
able to are you able to tell me do you
even know sometimes if you're working in
a large company you may not really know
what types of data you're handling so
it's super important to have an
understanding of of what that is as an
engineer this generally is stuff like
billing information pii
Etc whatever your company considers
sensitive you should at least have a
general understanding of that but more
importantly make sure that is documented
right if you are investigating some
micro service that's hidden in the back
corner of your data center
as an incident responder you're going to
want to know what type of data is
intended to be flowing through that
service right and if that's not
documented somewhere suddenly you have
to go find an owner of the system you
have to talk to them hopefully they
understand and it really complicates the
process so a lot of this can be solved
by having data dictionaries well-defined
data dictionaries things of that nature
and then also making sure that as you're
writing code you're keeping an
up-to-date data flow diagram or uml
diagrams that are stored in accessible
places
super important
okay
so build a plan of action for those of
us who work in smaller companies there's
a good chance you don't have an incident
response team so what's going to happen
if your product or project is undergoing
an active compromise for instance who's
going to be handling that
um what um what are you going to do in
those situations if you do have an IR
team work with them to understand what
the logging capability should be what do
you need from a Telemetry perspective to
know what's what's going on what data
should be logged do you want to be
logging your most sensitive data such as
user addresses
that's another question
um so working with the IR team
can really help you understand what type
of data should be logged so that you can
have a successful incident response uh
engagement and then the other question
that comes into play a lot and maybe
this doesn't necessarily fall into the
engineering shoulder so much but how
long should those logs live do you have
compliance requirements that dictate you
need your logs to live for a year maybe
it's two weeks what happens if you keep
your lungs longer your logs longer than
that time period
lots of things to consider and so
working with your IR team or your
compliance team can really help you
understand what those considerations
need to look like
understanding expectations during
incident response incident response can
be pretty sweaty I'm glad that's not my
job sorry Alex hopefully I'm able to
help you and you're doing it this is
stressful stuff right as Engineers
sometimes we're brought into the war
room and then we're sweaty because we're
trying to help figure out what's going
on we're trying to help fix things
um and then in the back of my mind I'm
always thinking about okay is there
going to be Public Communication about
this are we going to need to share this
with the public at GitHub that happens
right so super sweaty even with an IR
team and then if you're not fortunate
enough to have an IR team chances are
you're going to be handling all this
stuff yourself so what can you do from
an engineering perspective
um you really need to take ownership you
need to fully understand your product
and be aware of these potential gaps and
so I always recommend building uh
playbooks to help out even with an IR
team you need to have playbooks but if
you are an engineer without an IR team
available playbooks are going to be even
more important
being prepared to own the outcome
um when I talk about communication
public comps I always come back to this
particular incident so this is from 2021
where we GitHub started receiving
reports that users were uh basically
accessing other user sessions and this
was a super difficult one to track down
I was lucky because I was on PTO during
this so
so I came back and I'm like wow what is
going on here so in this case we there
was a rare uh security vulnerability we
talked about all this uh publicly
um we fixed it it took a lot of
engineering talent to figure this out
and I I was in those shoes I probably
never would have figured this out so I'm
glad we have some really smart folks
um and there there were customers
affected and we weren't sure how many so
we we said that we came out and said
that publicly and we believe that
transparency was the really really the
important key there so what we did Is We
I don't know if anyone anyone was aware
of this but we Mass logged out everyone
on github.com
so uh yeah that was fun
um and from what I understand are our
clients and our customers were really
appreciative of us being forthcoming
with them and taking the proactive
stance to just log everyone out because
you might have been affected who knows
it was really hard to trace this one
down so be prepared to own the outcome
if you have to make decisions like this
and it goes public folks are going to
start asking you questions so so think
about that and see what you can do to um
to treat your customers as best as
possible
thank you and remember investigations
not necessarily incidents but
investigations are always going to
happen
investigations generally lead to
incidents and then incidents can you
know lead to breaches it's a whole thing
I had to learn about but we do a lot of
Investigations at GitHub I'm involved in
a handful of those Alex is involved in
more of them and again we really value a
blameless incident response process this
empowers the employees the engineers the
the product managers by allowing them to
continue delivering you know the best
products possible if you have your
engineers pinned into a corner asking
them why they wrote code that was
vulnerable that's not going to be
effective not at all so remember
everyone is on the same team here
and when we're in the the hot and sweaty
incident response process or the War
Room just remember use your your plan of
action that you've defined
um hopefully you have playbooks
this is a big one and I think it's often
overlooked
um this is this is pretty big for us at
GitHub uh supporting customers so keep
in mind your customers are going to have
incidents too their authentication
credentials are going to be compromised
their laptops are going to be stolen
what can you do to support them in these
situations now I GitHub one of the the
common scenarios here is they have lost
their their path for instance or some
sort of authorization token has been
disclosed
um they will you know launch
investigations of their own and so how
can you support them in those
so customers are generally going to want
to know what data was accessed when was
it accessed was it modified
Etc and so you need to be able to help
provide them with those answers when at
all possible and if you don't have the
information they need to conduct their
investigation they're not going to be
happy and you're going to start losing
customers over this type of scenario
so how can we go about providing this
data to our customers self-service logs
are a huge win again we have a feature
called audit logging which allows
customers to go in and View events at a
repository level at a at a user level at
an org level I don't think it's at a
repository level but I could be mistaken
and this is self-service they can go in
they can help themselves and see what
actions have been taken uh against a
particular actor or a Target rather
now the flip side of this is as soon as
you provide a mechanism for
self-servicing you need to think about
the data that's being surfaced there
sanitization comes to mind so if you're
logging things like user IP addresses
should you be disclosing those to
customers in a self-service manner
probably not right but that's something
you have to think about you also want to
make sure you're not disclosing uh
credentials or tokens things of that
nature so anything that you would
consider business sensitive you need to
have sanitization in place
and then again having dedicated
playbooks for support goes a long way to
help support your support team provide
customers with the information that
they're looking for
and so I like to recommend auditing all
the things okay and so that here's some
code hopefully it's readable in the back
I know the black can be a little hard to
see but
um ensure every state changing request
flowing through your application is
auditable so what do I mean by state
changing requests
really anything that's creating
modifying deleting updating whatever you
want to say anything that's changing
data in the system should be able to be
audited there should be accountability
for that so in this particular code
snippet anyone here do rails development
or am I the only one yeah I'm the only
one that's typical I've spoken at Ruby
conferences and been the only one who's
a rails developer
um so anyways what we're looking at here
is what's effectively a base controller
so all of our controllers in the app
inherit from an application controller
and then we have an after action which
calls a require Trail audit function so
this after action says after the HTTP
request has been basically fully
serviced and we're about ready to send
it back to the to the through the web
server to the user we're gonna run this
particular require audit Trail function
and then in that function we we look and
see if the HTTP request method was
anything other than a git or a head
request we're then going to look and see
if the request was audited if it wasn't
audited what we're going to do is raise
an exception and say look there was some
state-changing request here that was not
audited this is a problem because
there's no accountability for it
um this is not the best code example
does anyone see why this may not be the
best situation here
of course no rails developers so
um the the cause for concern here is
that we're raising an exception after
all of the logic has already been
processed right so that's not doing much
so a better situation would be if we
instead emitted an audit log entry that
said hey this wasn't audited and then we
can have accountability for those we can
review that so this is just a general
idea of using some middleware to capture
uh HTTP requests that have not been
audited and surface those this shouldn't
necessarily interfere with the end user
Behavior but it should be
um it should be a metric that engineers
and folks are looking at to understand
where there's a lack of coverage in
their application
all right let me grab a quick drink here
just water don't worry
so where do we go from there I mean we
talked a little bit about incident
response
um
preventing regression is is what we're
going to talk about next so
the goal with incident response is never
too waste a good incident
so how do we prevent regression so if if
folks aren't aware of what I mean by
regression what I mean is effectively
ensuring that we don't have the same
situation happen again
um and so the first thing we want to
look at is ensuring that during our IR
scenario we do sufficient root cause
analysis to really understand the
vulnerability itself or the bug and use
that to drive our solutioning so we want
to fix things at a code level we don't
want to rely on third-party products
things like waffs to solve the issue so
make sure you have an understanding of
the actual issue itself
and then perform thorough variant
analysis so when I say variant analysis
we've we've identified the root cause of
one particular issue do we have that
same issue in other places in our code
base in our services so variant analysis
is super useful there if folks here or
GitHub Advanced security customers we
have a multi-repo variant analysis tool
which is pretty cool I don't use it
myself but we have teams that do rely on
that and pretty cool feature
um
and again this is this section is all
about not wasting a valuable incident so
variant analysis is super valuable and
then most importantly utilize tests to
prevent regression
um
who here has security tests in their in
their products that they're aware of
I saw a lot more Engineers than I saw
folks raise their hands for that so
that's a bit scary
I'm not going to ask you which which
products you have all right who's ready
for a test
all right that's all I mean not actually
going to ask you all questions sorry if
this is a bit hard to see especially in
the back but effectively what we have
here is a an integration test from OAS
rails go
intentionally vulnerable Ruby on Rails
app in this particular test is
actually does anyone have any thoughts
on what we're testing for before I spoil
things
it's file upload yeah
so we are testing and I think I heard
someone say it but you're being too
modest
um command injection right so if you
look online 21 and basically we have a
payload to test for command injections
so this is this is the type of payload
you would see you know someone from a
consulting company using to demonstrate
you know exploitability
and so what we do is is we create a
legitimate file we put it on the server
somewhere and then we have a payload
that basically attempts to delete
um the files from that same directory
and if if it's successful so on line 30
in an Ideal World if our application is
not vulnerable that legitimate file we
initially created will still be there
meaning it hasn't been erased because
our payload has not executed
successfully
um so yeah this is a bit of a confusing
um test Suite because you all aren't
rails developers you're probably not too
familiar with capybara there's a lot
going on but the idea is that our goal
is try to delete a file and if that file
is not deleted then we have
theoretically mitigated the security
vulnerability
has anyone seen any potential
improvements anyways we could write this
test a little better
girls aside you must be a net developer
so I have some recommendations for for
this particular test so first of all
it's great to have eight tests to begin
with
first of all I always recommend using
unit testing whenever possible
um what we looked at before was an
integration test
a lot of things can change between entry
point to the application and where the
actual logic is is being executed so
when possible use unit tests instead of
integration tests
consider alternative payloads so my big
pet peeve with this test is that our
payload is trying to delete data uh
that's that's a pretty serious cause for
concern because if if we delete our data
is our test Suite going to restore that
data that was already there or are we
going to end up in some situation where
you suddenly have flaky tests so
removing data is not effective there are
better options such as just trying to
execute sleep you know if you if your
your test is taking five seconds to
respond you're probably still vulnerable
if you just told the the well if you
gave a payload to sleep for five seconds
so definitely not a fan of the rmrf
what about alternative encodings so how
will things differ if the data provided
was URL encoded
um maybe base64 encoded maybe had
Unicode variants
and after all what is what is the happy
path what is the expectation
um if someone
uploads a file that appears to be
potentially malicious we don't cover
that we we verify that our files have
not been deleted but what happened to
the file that was uploaded because there
could have been legitimate files with
some of those characters in the names
what happened to those
and then false negatives in this case
race conditions come to my mind as well
so maybe maybe the test runs
concurrently and uh some of the other
tests rely on those files as well so a
lot of potential issues there
so one more test I want to talk about
the goal of this test and this is from
Mastodon
open source Social Network I don't use
it myself but if you do they have
security tests so that's good
um the the goal of this appears to me at
least to be testing for some variant of
cross-site scripting so we're making
sure things are stripping JavaScript
tags and Below we're making sure things
strip malicious classes not sure what a
malicious class is
so what what can we say about this test
um what would what would change if the
input was normalized in some way so the
first thing that struck me as weird is
where we have a capital H in the alert
uh okay that's that seems to be
non-standard but what if the application
was designed to run like too lower case
on everything we may still be vulnerable
but because we're looking for a case in
a case-sensitive string
it may be a false negative there
are there tests for other attributes so
I'm not sure how well folks are familiar
with cross-edge scripting but a big
Vector there is attribute injection and
so we see a test for malicious classes
but we don't see any further tests so
what about malicious IDs first of all
what what even are malicious classes I
have no clue what Mastodon means by a
malicious class
um so yeah what are what are the
legitimate classes I mean I guess
mention is a legitimate class but
there's a lot of context left out in
this situation
so here's some advice for Designing
tasks first of all make sure you're
using tests integration tasks unit test
whatever works if your company is not
using tests at all it would be a huge
win just to have some testing framework
in place in general and make it part of
your CI CD process
Focus your test case on a specific issue
such as integration tests so if someone
reported a cross-site scripting
vulnerability in a user profile it makes
sense to have an integration test that
tries to set a user profile to have a
JavaScript code snippet and validate
that after you fixed it that's no longer
rendering
um and then from there we can look at
our variant analysis and say okay we've
we've encountered these other scenarios
that seem to be venerable what can we do
to make this one cross-site scripting
test we just wrote more extensible so we
can use it in other places in our
application
I already talked about this a little bit
but uh test is close to the logic as
possible so if you have I don't know a
blockchain app and you're transferring
money around
probably shouldn't be able to transfer
if you have a negative balance right so
that's an area where you'd want to make
sure you had unit tests in place to test
for those lower level comparison
operations and then
a fun one I like to touch on focus on
testing for permutations and I'm not
sure if folks know what I mean by that
so permutations are effectively a
reusable way to test for variants of
payloads so we talked a little bit about
encoding concerns right so why not have
a function that will generate variance
or permutations of the input so in the
example here we take the input we we
look at the base64 encoded we look at
the URL encoded URL decoded you can do
as much as you want here
and then you just want to design a test
case that looks for any of those
permutations and if any of those were
found you probably have an issue this is
a super easy win to get better test
coverage and this is something you
should be using as both input to tests
and also output of tasks so if you're
looking to see if your HTTP response
includes something look and see if it
includes the permutations of that thing
at all
pretty easy win
so shifting away from that a little bit
designing for extensibility it's super
important to recognize that your product
is going to change your company is going
to scale things things are going to be
different
foreign
with this
shouldn't be very obvious right
so
and no one's hollering at me that's
surprising
so how would we fix that okay use
parameterized queries this is this is
kind of SQL injection 101 where we have
some user input concatenated with a SQL
query the way we recommend solving this
as an industry is using parameterized
queries right genuine disagree
okay good
what's the solution here what's the
problem how do we fix this
we're getting close to lunch so folks
are quieting down now
parameterized queries will not work in
that situation
so if we look back at it what we see
here is we're using uh user input to
determine which database table we want
to select from
in parameterized queries can't be used
to mitigate the risk in this case and
that's because most database Management
systems do not support parameterizing
certain Fields one of which is the table
name so you will not be able to
parameterize that generally speaking
there's some exceptions to that so an
alternative approach is allow listing a
set of known table names this might seem
a bit like a contrived example but if
you ever work in any sort of company
that has like a dynamic reporting engine
or its own custom SQL interface this is
a huge thing
so what's what's the solution here
utilizing a framework control or
middleware to introspect the parameters
okay so walking you through this code
this is a solution so we're using a
before filter that says before we run
the code here we're going to run this
before filter function which is called
require valid table
and so we look to see if a list of the
valid tables we've provided includes the
user parameter meaning is a user trying
to access a table which we want to give
them access to and then if not we're
going to raise an exception and say
invalid table
choose your own exception name this is
just my contrived example here
and so this works by ensuring that the
user is selecting from a table that we
want them to be able to select from
um there are better approaches here so
one better approach which I'll show you
looks more like this
so we have a before filter now called
set table in this particular method
looks to see again if the user input is
a valid table
if not it raises an exception that's not
much different what is different though
is we're referencing or we're setting a
value called current Table
and we're setting that to the user
provided value and then on line six
we're now referencing that new current
Table variable
and so the idea here is that we have uh
we have defined this current Table
variable to be something that is trusted
and we know it will only exist if we've
gone through that before filter
so that's that's kind of the minor minor
Nuance there so in this particular
example
um if someone were to comment out that
before filter suddenly you have SQL
injection again
in this example if someone comments out
the before filter you're going to have a
function that doesn't work because
there's an undefined variable this is a
defense in-depth measurement measure I
don't know what I'm saying anymore
so accept the reality we're gonna write
insecure code you can have the most
thorough secure coding requirements
document in the world folks are going to
write insecure code so it's important to
to understand that accept that and then
build an exception process for that one
thing I like to recommend folks do is
annotate insecure code so in the example
there we have code that's potentially
vulnerable to mass assignment if you run
Breakman or any Ruby static analysis
it's going to report that so if our
developers choose to accept that risk
for some reason maybe there's other
mitigating controls having a simple
annotation in there will tell us this is
an insecure design principle we
shouldn't be doing this and I would
recommend also linking back to some
discussion or some exception because
this will reduce the risk of someone
copying this code and using it somewhere
else in the application it also provides
us the ability to document an audit for
these insecure code patterns so for
example in rails I can run rake tasks I
can look at all of my insecure tasks and
then audit those see if that's something
I want to revisit
I've only seen like one or two clients
ever using patterns to annotate you know
into your code so this I think is a
pretty easy win
and then building
uh oh
Fox
I'll just turn my laptop around
good time for a water break
um
so I was having a hard time hearing you
especially with the door closing but
were you asking about how we audit those
yeah how do you detect you need sunsets
or something if your annotation happens
so let's say you want to prevent some
developerative malicious
yeah good question so
um and this probably isn't the best
possible example but if you use linters
and you have test Suites you can keep
track of the count of how many of those
annotations there are and then basically
manually okay thank you
so you can use linters and basically say
okay this this count of insecure code
annotations increased or decreased can
you provide you know an explanation for
that
cool back in business thank you
I let my wife use my dongle a year ago
when I stopped kind of traveling and
here we are this is someone else's and
now I've got a secondary backup so and
we're getting kind of close on time here
so building pave paths for extensibility
um this is a favorite of mine uh or I
should say a security questionnaire
favorite we get this a lot at GitHub
security headers okay I don't know if
anyone knows where I'm going with this
but
security headers and this is kind of a
bold statement but in my opinion
security headers are effectively the new
Bankrate encryption everyone wants to
see it and they want to see it because
it's it's visible to them so for example
if I use if I go to the lastcon.org
website I don't know if they're
vulnerable to cross-aid scripting I
don't know if they're vulnerable to SQL
injection without testing security
adders I can load up uh I'm not going to
throw any names out there but a dynamic
website to scan your security headers
and get a report card on it everyone can
do this and it's it's not a bad thing
but I think there's too much emphasis on
security headers so one in particular I
want to talk about is content security
policy in this hetera I do find a
sufficient value
so content security policy if you're not
aware is a new newish
directive that browsers will process to
understand
which uh types of data your application
can load where it can load those from
Etc there's there's a lot to it now CSP
version 3 is coming out as well so
there's a whole lot to talk about
um now with CSP the main win here is
that it's a huge help in reducing the
cross-site script scripting
vulnerability or at least reducing the
risk of them and so we'll talk about
that more in a few minutes but the
reason we're even talking about tsp
today is because it's easiest to roll
out early in the app life cycle it's a
lot harder to roll out a Content
security policy in an already mature app
and there there's report only mode and
things that you can do to make make it a
little bit more smooth but I recommend
starting with a default source of self
and then adding exceptions which is what
this section of the talk is talking
about as needed in the the two main
directives I generally am concerned with
is a script source and then the connect
source and I'm not going to get into
much detail about those
so with security headers what I normally
see is folks looking at you know your
domain in evaluating the security
headers what a lot of folks don't
realize is some headers CSP as an
example can be set on a per page basis
so looking at the the headers across the
entire domain is not super useful so
what we see a lot of a GitHub is cases
where folks want to run a b tests with
like different vendors uh different
third-party JavaScript never makes me
feel good when someone says third-party
JavaScript but that's what the business
needs
so CSP is one of those headers that can
be set per page so my recommendation
here is to utilize one strong site-wide
policy
that is secure and then allow exceptions
on a per page basis so as as you or
other Engineers are seeking to connect
to different sources pulling assets from
various locations they can do so for
those particular pages and I'll give you
an example of what this looks like but
what this does is allows us to have a
very tight Global policy and then have
exceptions at a page level that way the
risk is reduced to a specific page or a
specific set of pages
again we use the secure headers Library
which we also maintain this makes it
super easy for all you rails developers
you should check that out
that's a good question and we can talk
about that after but your single page
app is probably communicating with an
API somewhere right so there's two sets
of concerns in that situation but
um you can use the HTTP meta tag but I'm
not sure how that works in per page apps
so I want to give you a clear example of
what I'm talking about here uh that's a
joke because clearly this is is not
clear at all but if if you go to
github.com readme
um you see a Content security policy
which differs from my profile on
github.com and the readme project is an
area where we allow users to provide
videos to talk about their projects and
stuff and so we made the decision that
we're okay sourcing from these
particular domains on this page but we
don't want all of github.com to be
exposed to CTF assets.net as much as I'd
love to trust CTF assets.net I really
don't even know who they are so
um so this is an example of of where we
have reduced the risk across github.com
in allowed our product team to do the
work they needed to in a particular page
is anyone doing CSP on a per page level
you are okay good good
all right so CSP
um this leads us to cross-site scripting
edge cases in xss so CSP which we just
spent the last five or ten minutes you
know talking about is really in my
opinion only for defense in depth if
this is your primary mitigation strategy
for cross-site scripting it's not
sufficient in fact if you look at the
Mozilla documentation they clearly say
CSP is an added layer of security right
so in in so few words that's that's
saying a lot right there
so use CSP spend the time to have a
well-defined policy with exceptions
don't rely on it
output encoding is still key
um
I would say these days most of the
Frameworks I look at do output encoding
by default rail certainly does and the
largest concern I normally have these
days is with exceptions or exemptions
from that default output encoding so in
rails for instance and I guess next year
I'll come with a different uh example
golang maybe I don't know
um so in rails for instance if you call
the.html Safe what that does is say we
trust this as HTML and we want to allow
it to be rendered so if you see HTML
safe there's user input it's probably
going to be cross-eyed scripting and
that's because we've opted out of rails
default protection mechanisms
um more issues than that but the next
thing I want to talk about is attribute
injection uh
towards the the last couple years of my
Consulting career uh attribute injection
was extremely common and this is I would
say the majority of the cross-site
scripting vulnerabilities we we reported
um an attribute injection is when you're
able to inject user input into an
attribute of a tag
and so one of the main issues here is
many web application firewalls look for
brackets in particular if your.net
developer you may be familiar with
request validator request validator
looks specifically for a bracket
followed by an alphabetic character
attribute injection payloads would not
have that so they'll bypass request
validator they'll bypass a lot of the
the the
the laughs out there
um and that's a big problem and even
more so unquoted attributes
um so if you're rendering user input
inside a tag without quoted attributes
there's a cross-site scripting
vulnerability right there and that's
because a user can enter some data with
a space to inject a new attribute and
then suddenly your page is a bit out of
control
so input validation super helpful but
again that's defense in depth when we
can do input validation we certainly
should be doing it
but that's that's easier said than done
um and it doesn't doesn't always solve
the problem here
what if what if we want to allow users
to have some HTML tags what if we want
them to provide a bold tag for instance
or what if we want a wysiwyg editor
where they can you know update their
profile have some tags anytime I see
something like this that's my reaction
okay seriously though I don't think I've
ever been on a vulnerability assessment
or pen test encountered one of these and
not found cross-site scripting in some
variant
if you're allowing users to provide a
set of HTML there's probably going to be
a problem there so how do we how do we
solve this if your business requirement
is we want users to be able to provide
HTML how do you do that securely
so this goes back to our exceptions
process so in our secure coding policies
that we all have we say use output
encoding that's not going to work in
this case because we want them to
provide HTML
um github.com we allow users to provide
HTML we allow users to provide markdown
which is converted to HTML so this is a
problem I deal with every single day
in developers by default are going to
opt out of the framework mitigation so
we're going to use HTML safe because
that's going to make things work by
default but then we're going to have
cross-8 scripting
so the key here really is to focus on
your plan take a step back and think
about what tags do our users need to be
able to use do they need a bold tag do
they need to be able to provide links
um do they need to provide JavaScript
tags probably not on that one but
important part is having a plan and
understanding what exactly you want them
to provide next thing identify a list of
attributes that need to be supported
these attributes are things like an href
if you want a user to provide a link
they probably need to be able to provide
the href attribute
and then probably a bit less important
Now understand the context in which the
tags will be rendered if they're going
to be used in JavaScript scenario you
have to handle things a bit differently
than if they're outputted into HTML
itself
so the real solution is utilize a
trusted sanitizer
and if I came here and said this 10
years ago I probably would have been
laughed off the stage because sanitizers
um have some bad connotations there
but the real emphasis here is spending
the time to understand the library
Dom purify
does anyone use Dom purify
like two people that is absolutely
terrifying to me
Dom purify is a sanitizer written in
JavaScript super prevalent on uh you
know angular apps react apps
Etc and on their official readme they
say it's easy you just Source it in and
then call Dom purify.sanitize
super easy and then you'll have clean
output and you can work with that
okay so I give that a huge thumbs down
that is not good advice it's never that
easy is it
in this goes back to knowing your
libraries so if you look at the the
screenshot from the readme they say that
note that by default we permit HTML SVG
and mathml okay what does that even mean
I mean we're talking about allowing
users to provide a set of HTML do we
want them to provide svgs what's the
risk there what even is mathml
um well I know but only because of
incident response and stuff but yeah we
know we know about mathml
and their recommendation is to use
profiles all right that indicate we only
want to render HTML that's great but
that's not what they said when they told
us it was easy to use
so that's a pretty big problem and by
the way not picking on the Dom purify
folks they have a very well maintained
repository when I looked uh
uh probably about a week ago they had no
open issues no open PRS they're actively
resolving bugs vulnerabilities Etc so
huge props The Cure 53 folks on that
so what is the default Behavior what
HTML tags will be rendered as HTML what
will be removed will they be encoded
there's a lot of questions they say it's
easy to use the library but I don't
understand what the outcome is going to
be
so oh typo bad on me the the answer here
is roughly 110 tags will be outputted
that is they will not be removed they
will not be encoded 110 HTML tags will
pass through those filters what are
those well you're free to go look
um but in order to understand the risk
pose your application you have to
understand what those tags are are
attributes supported what is that story
Yeah by default they'll allow you to
render over 100 different attributes
okay so what's what's the risk there and
Dom purify uses an allow list approach
where you can explicitly deny certain
attributes so if if you had a business
requirement that said like hey they have
a great source of of tags or attributes
but we don't want our users to be able
to provide one of these yeah you can
deny list it seems fine right
so if we look at this particular example
anyone want to take a stab at the
expectation here what so we have some
payload which we've hard coded it's a
link with a class and a data URL
attribute called Dom purify and then we
just drop it into the Dom through enter
HTML so how is that going to render
anyone have any thoughts
that's a good question
that's exactly how it's going to render
it does not strip out data URL it does
not strip out the class or the href so
that entire payload is going to be
rendered as is
um and so there there could be some
concerns here
so the major takeaway is that using Dom
purify with default settings will allow
us to inject classes which we just saw
it allow us to inject data attributes
which we just saw I didn't show you but
you can inject IDs as well that's one of
the hundred permitted attributes and
more again 100 attributes 100 tags
there's there's a lot going on that Dom
purify allows by default
what about event handlers I mean this is
this is the day of the modern web like
we are doing a lot of things in
JavaScript that are relying on the Dom
so what what does that scenario look
like
so if we take a quick look at this in
the top screenshot we have a very basic
um you know HTML uh full it's not even a
form it's just some basic HTML right
with an event trigger and so the
JavaScript below looks for the payload
we've provided it sanitizes it and then
injects it to the sandbox
all right and so from there
um we have some other uh logic which may
not be totally clear
but and you guys can't even read the
line number but line 15 down there we
see another dot enter HTML which is
obviously a huge flag
um so we're communicating with some API
based on the data provided from the item
ID
um this could be pretty risky anytime
you see enter HTML you definitely want
to evaluate that so the last line here
which I am super sorry because I know
you can't see that in the back
is a payload with uh it's a div tag with
a class of find reviews we specify the
data attribute with another typo there
and so that'll get injected to the page
none of that will be stripped out and so
what we'll have is we'll then have uh an
injected class into our Dom which is
then able to be used to trigger other
functionality
so in this case it's going to initiate
the show reviews mechanism make an API
call and then render the response from
that each uh that API as as HTML so you
can't see the entire risk here but what
we're demonstrating is that our our
sanitizer is allowing the user to take
full control of the Dom by using event
handlers so and I know I'm not even
gonna ask I know you folks because I
know I don't know all of the event
handlers or observables in my
application so there's a huge attack
service here waiting to be exploited
foreign
part of all this and kind of circling
back to the beginning is Dom cross 8
scripting is nearly impossible to
investigate because all the events
happen in the Dom they're they're never
sent to the server so our incident
Response Team such as Alex is never
going to know conclusively if someone
was compromised through this
so this is something that we we really
need to address and that goes back to
really making sure you understand your
libraries because the default's
generally not sufficient
so key takeaways
um incidents happen definitely want to
design in a way that allows you to
improve the incident response scenario
work with your incident responders
understand what data they want to see
log to understand what they don't want
to see logged there's there's a lot more
to it than that so
prevent regression if you're not using
tests in CI CD that's a huge problem if
you're not using security specific tests
that's another problem so don't waste
the incidence turn those into test case
expand your test coverage use
permutations to test for other variants
there's no reason your application
couldn't have a permutation set of like
SQL injection payloads for instance it's
pretty easy win
in when we work with consulting firms
who provide proof of Concepts take their
proof of Concepts and put them into your
test Suite
support extension exemption
um
exceptions are going to be needed so you
know make sure that folks have a clear
path to request exceptions make sure the
security team is supportive of folks
deviating from the the paved paths when
necessary just make sure to have a
conversation for it make sure it's
auditable make sure you can hold folks
accountable for it and just continuously
iterate to improve and then most most
importantly to me is understand your
libraries everything we do these days is
built on third-party code we only
understand a fraction of the surface in
that third-party code so understand the
security critical requirements there if
you use a sanitizer understand what the
default behaviors are
so with that if there's any questions
happy to try to take those it's also I
think lunch is probably here too so
yes
allow them deny options
profiles as well you can create custom
profiles they even have uh what they
call hooks so let's say you want to
allow a subset of an attribute so like
classes that are prefects with like
GitHub hyphen you can do that by having
a hook that says only allow classes that
meet this regular expression so pretty
extensible from that perspective yeah
yes when you're documenting data
classifications in your application how
do you make sure that doesn't get stale
good question
um this is more of like a compliance
side thing so if you have a compliance
team work with them to understand what
that looks like chances are they have a
place where that stuff should live
already I've seen folks go as far as
like annotating it at the like the
method level in the code
um for instance you know when you're
you're writing like your javadoc and you
have like your parameters you could have
a classification right there and then
you could you could use you know unit
testing to verify that any parameter has
a classification with it a lot of things
you can do it's really whatever fits
best with your your team's development
practices
any other questions
that depends on the situation but most
likely not now
um so in and we can talk about this more
when we're not being recorded but
um there there are definitely scenarios
like that where like you can inject an
attribute which the CSP won't prevent
which will trigger an observer and
suddenly you you know anything your
Observer is capable of doing will will
be evaluated so some pretty nasty edge
cases in that area
anyone else
all right I think that's it hey they're
clapping for me that was Tiny