hey everyone welcome to this talk
and thanks for your interest in dynamic
decentralized functional encryption
this is joint work with jeremy shotar
roman gay john gilfan and david
poncheval
my name is eduardo for sons and i worked
on this airport where i was at economic
superior in paris
and in part where i was at carnegie
mellon university in pittsburgh and i'll
be giving the talk today
i think we can all agree that one
superior of computer science has had
unbelievable growth during the last two
decades or so
and unfortunately for this conference
you probably missed out
because i'm not talking about
cryptography i'm talking about machine
learning
the convergence of the massive
availability of many types of data
the affordability of highly parallel
compute equipment and algorithmic
advances relevant to machine learning
have issued in a new wave of very
successful intelligent products
of course it has also raised enormous
privacy concerns
because these machine learning models
are trained using databases
of sometimes very personal data that are
under control of a few institutions
because it's so hard to argue against
the benefits of better artificial
intelligence
it's unlikely that consumers would
prefer a system where no data mining
occurs
but perhaps cryptography can provide a
solution that protects privacy
without sacrificing the benefits of
machine learning
now one might ask since clearly we're
going to be looking at some form of
computation involving encrypted data
whether it's something that's already
solved by foliomorphic encryption
and while you can certainly construct
solutions to this problem from fhe
i would like to argue that it's not the
ideal theoretical cryptographic
primitive for our scenario
recall fhe is for computing on data you
can't see
so in fhe you would typically have a
server competing on data that is owned
by a client
and a client because it knows the secret
key can decrypt the result of the
computation
it makes sense for offloading
computation to a server whether for
performance reasons or because the model
is too large for the client to store
but in the scenario we are describing we
want the server to run the computations
but also to get back the result
fha can't achieve that or at least not
in an uninteractive way
and to be clear what we mean by an
interactive here is that in the long run
you should just be sending a single
cipher text of the data you just
generated
and then it's up to the server to gather
the data of the other parties and to
perform the computations
an interactivity matters when your
clients are regular internet users
who will be on enough and are unlikely
to have the time or resources
to participate in a computationally
heavy massively multi-party protocol
so today we will be talking about
something else
something that lets the server aggregate
our data with that of other participants
and in an interactive way that's dynamic
decentralized functional encryption
or ddfe for short
so here's the plan for today first we'll
briefly talk about functional encryption
its history
and how it relates to the dfe then we'll
define the dfe
both formally and with some helpful
examples and then
we'll give constructions of ddfe for a
few functionalities
we'll start by looking at something we
call decentralized sum
in the process of building that i'll
notice that we fall a bit short of the
security guarantees we want
then it would be nice to start by adding
something to our toolbox
that tool or the all-or-nothing
encapsulation and we will show how to
build one from identity-based encryption
finally we'll present a more complex
primitive it's a decentralized inner
product scheme
and we'll try to give an overview of the
key ideas behind our construction
the history of functional encryption in
a sense was all the way back to the
invention of public key encryption
public encryption is one of the most
basic forms of functional encryption
in 2001 we get identity-based encryption
which allows for some access control
and then in 2006 attribute-based
encryption which is stronger and allows
for more complex forms of access control
and is alternated in 2011 with
functional encryption
which is even stronger and allows for
computations on the text data
but there's something deeper about
functional encryption it's interesting
because it's not just a stronger
more powerful variant of its
predecessors
functional encryption is a framework
what's great about functional encryption
is that while the definition allows for
schemes that would allow for general
computations
and general access control structures it
still captures schemes that are much
more limited
public encryption identity-based
encryption and attribute-based
encryption
are all forms of functional encryption
but they are not instances of one
another
a great fit of functional encryption is
giving cryptographers a common language
to use to describe many possibly very
different schemes
all it takes is giving the functionality
of the scheme and then the definitions
and security game follow immediately
still functional encryption has its
limitations
there are two that are relevant to what
we're talking about today
one is that it doesn't really allow for
computations that involve multiple
parties
that's a non-starter for what we talked
about earlier aggregating data from
multiple users
multi-input and multi-client variants of
functional encryption
were introduced to address this point
but they inherited another issue of
functional encryption
there is a master secret key the order
of which can basically learn
anything it wants we tried moving away
from this in 2018
with decentralized multi-client
functional encryption
but the primitive we defined required
the set of participants to be set at the
beginning of time
and no new members could join from that
point on so it was not dynamic
ad hoc multi-input functional encryption
came in a year later
it was dynamic but in a sense it lacked
the full definitional power
that functional encryption had brought
the definitions are tailored to their
constructions
and that framework cannot capture some
of the functionalities we'll present
here today
now that you have the context i start
talking about what ddf
is we'll start with some examples
so we have four people alice bub charlie
and diane they have some pictures of
themselves that they're probably storing
on some levi's
now those pictures would be valuable to
a company it can use deep learning to
extract valuable intelligence from the
data
however sending the data directly to the
company so it can mine it
well that could be detrimental to the
privacy of our subjects
they might not agree to participate or
be unhappy about it if it happens
without their consent
lucky for them as you may have noticed
earlier they're dealing with
not very evil corp and that firm decided
it would use the dfe
so it can achieve its objectives while
protecting its customers privacy
full disclosure here training an actual
neural network
it's not something that's realistic to
do with the cryptographic tools we have
today
so this example is about what the dream
application would be what we're working
towards
so all of our friends here would encrypt
the data under
there ddfe some metadata associated with
its ciphertext
namely the date and the set of
participants
and the policy will be let's say that
data can only be aggregated
between participants that all agree on
the date
and the set of participants
so they send off the cipher text to the
not very evil corp
and at that point these are totally
opaque to the company
it might as well be your favorite flavor
of ncp encryption
that's because the company has no
functional keys
so the company has to go back to the
participants for that
in this case the participants are
willing to help
so they each independently compute a
functional decryption key of their own
the key is associated with the set of
participants
and a specific method for training a
neural network
again all of those will have to match
across all participants
and now the cooperation has all it needs
to start working
using the functional keys on the
ciphertexts it can extract knowledge
from the data
and nothing more it doesn't get to see
the plaintext data
only the result of the training
okay that's it for our example now let's
get four more shall we
for a ddfe scheme the third of key is k
and a set of messages m a dfe scheme
will first be characterized by its
functionality
it's essentially the set of functions
the scheme can compute
and it also describes how different keys
enable different functions
for the dfe a functionality takes a list
of
public key functional key pairs and a
list of public key message pairs
the way to think about it is that you'll
be mixing a bunch of keys and a bunch of
messages together
to get some value out as we saw earlier
with the neural network training
and each key and each message is
fundamentally tied
to the identity of its creator so that
we can tell when someone is allowing
computation on their own data
now for the flow of things you would
start with a setup
which generates some shared parameters
maybe everyone agrees on a hash function
analytical parameters and so on
you do this once and then everyone can
generate their public private key pair
they advertise the public key that's
their identity for all intents and
purposes here
and they keep the secret key to
themselves they'll use it for encrypting
and generating functional keys finally
anyone can decrypt once they have enough
ciphertexts
and enough functional keys that's maybe
a bit terse let's see how we can connect
those concepts to the example we saw
earlier
so in our case you'll remember that our
participants would embed into their
functional key
both the set of participants as they
perceived it
and the training algorithm the set of
participants would really be a set of
public keys
and maybe that algorithm was represented
as a circuit
hence the set of keys here the cartesian
product
of the set of sets of public keys and a
set of circuits
the message contained an image a date
and again
a set of participants so the set of
messages is pretty straightforward
now clearly we want to hide the image
but perhaps those other attributes don't
need to be hidden
that's all okay it can be expressed with
the functionality
as it would be with traditional
functional encryption
now let's take a look at the
functionality it's a bit ugly at first
but we can break it down together the
first argument is a set of keys
associated with their users recall that
the keys are composed of a set of
participants and a circuit
here the keys are not indexed by pk so
it's very simple
they are the same for all participants
in the set
they contain that same set of
participants and a circuit that performs
neural network training
up next we have the messages here
again everyone agrees on the date and
everyone agrees on the set of
participants
but each participant has their own image
and so the result of that evaluation
will be a neural network trained on a
set of images
simple as that notice that this is a
simple functionality
in that the set of users who provide
keys is the same as the set of users
who provide messages while our framework
doesn't actually require that
now that we've had an overview of what
ddfe is
we can move on to actual constructions
we'll start with decentralized sum
at a high level decentralized sum is
about computing sums
or to be accurate repeated group
operations in finite
billing groups in practice the group a
will often be that of modular integers
so our messages will contain a group
element that we want to aggregate with
other people's group elements
we need to specify the set of people we
want to aggregate with
and we'll want to agree on a label in
practice this is something that might be
set to the date so that if we want to
aggregate different data later
an attacker can come in and mix and
match our data from the different
aggregations
to learn more than they should what's
maybe striking about this functionality
is that there are no keys only
ciphertexts
that means any functionality evaluation
will have an empty list for a list of
keys
we denote that empty list by epsilon
even in traditional single input
functional encryption
there's a key epsilon that serves to
capture the default leakage from
ciphertexts
but in a single input setting that's
usually something limited
like the lengths of the plain text here
in your multi-user setting we can have
more complex data leakage
depending on the set of ciphertexts that
are matched together
so for this sum if the participants
agree on the set of participants and the
label
the sum will be revealed so
how can we build the ddfe scheme for the
decent functionality
here's a good starting point if each
party were able to compute a mask
so that the mask taken together cancel
out
then we would have it mostly figured out
right
because we can simply publish our
element hidden by the mask
and given all of those ciphertexts you
would just add them up
and you would immediately recover the
sum of the plain texts
but can we actually do that can all of
those participants sample a mask that is
not uniformly random
but belonging to the structured
distribution without relying on a
trusted third party
without coordinating and without
communicating
the answer to that is yes in a
computational sense
a solution appears in json 2009 and is
attributed to blunt waters
it consists in having each pair of
parties computer shared key
through a non-interactive key exchange
scheme
then from that shared key they can
compute a shared randomness that is
specific to a label
simply by evaluating a prf with that key
on that label
and now they can combine all the
randomnesses they computed according to
this formula here
where only some of them have a negative
sign
now it is that you see that if my
randomness with you has a positive sign
then your randomness with me has a
negative sign
when we sum it all up together all the
randomnesses cancel out as we were
hoping for
so is this enough to construct d70 dfe
it's almost enough but there's an issue
that will stop you from proving security
let's have a simple example with alice
wanting to aggregate data with bob
and charlie is the one that will compute
the sun given only alice's ciphertext
charlie should learn nothing because he
needs one from bob to decrypt
once he gets bob's cipher text charlie
should learn the sum
but now what happens when alice
generates two cipher texts
for the same label on the same pair of
participants
it's not obvious why alice would do that
but hey nothing stopping her from
generating those cipher texts so here
she goes
now what should charlie learn here
in theory charlie shouldn't learn
anything because he still doesn't have a
cipher text from bug to evaluate with
but if we just use the mask we talked
about earlier
since that mask is deterministic charlie
can cancel the mask out
and evaluate the difference between the
original messages
now you might argue hey charlie was
going to learn that by linear
combination
the second bug puts out some cipher text
so what's the big deal
but maybe bob was never going to do that
so what we want is to have a clean
security model that's easy for everyone
to understand
without caveats that are added in
because the cryptographic structure
just doesn't quite get us the most
natural thing
to that end we introduce all or nothing
encapsulation
it's a djf functionality that will solve
our problem
in aone the message is some fixed length
data and again
a set of users and a label much like d
sum aone has no keys and decryption
requires that all ciphertexts agree on
the label and the set of participants
unlike dsum aoni simply reveals all of
the plaintext messages
and their association to a participant
so if a or any reveals all of the data
what is it good for well
it only allows this reveal once all the
cipher texts have been received
that's essentially what we were missing
for gsm
the ability to hide everything until
everyone has contributed a message
now here's a simple idea for
constructing a or any
everyone generates an identity based
encryption key pair
and advertises the public key when you
want to encapsulate data
you encrypt it under as many layers of
ione as there are participants
each layer is under a different
participant's public key
and under identity l finally
you also include your functional key for
identity l
and that's pretty much it once everyone
has done that
you have all the keys for identity l so
you can remove all the layers of ibe
and get back all the plain texts now the
problem with the solution we just
described
is that each individual cipher text has
size line near in the number of
participants
the great news is that if you carefully
instantiate our above construction
with bernie and franklin's original ib
from 2001
that problem goes away you can get sex
in cipher texts
if you are curious please refer to the
paper for details
we can finally move on to our most
interesting functionality
in our product it's the most complicated
one
so we'll simplify things a bit so we can
focus on the important ideas
the messages contain a scalar and as
we're used to by now
a set of users and a label the keys are
a vector on a set of participants
so it is a set tying each participant to
a scalar
and a functionality is that if four
messages agree on the set of
participants under label
and all keys agree on a unique vector y
over that same set of participants
we should be able to compute the inner
product which is the sum of the message
scalars
weighted by the key scalers
as a starting point let's look at the
construction for inner product
multi-client functional encryption
we introduced at asiacrypt 2018.
here we're reusing ddf notations for
those of you who might not be familiar
with ncfe
but basically in mcife there is a
central authority which will sample keys
for people
and hand out the functional decryption
keys by relying on its global knowledge
of everyone's keys
in gdfe we have to compute those keys in
a decentralized way
which is much harder so this is an
mcifee that has been rewritten to try to
achieve a ddfe
but the biggest challenges remain ahead
of us
basic idea here is that encryption is
somewhat algae male like
but the message is placed in the
exponent because you want to achieve
inner product which is essentially an
additive functionality
and instead of something a random
exponent you use a random oracle
to compute a random element that is
shared between all participants for a
given label
because you don't know the discrete
algorithm of the random oracle output
you can only encrypt if you know the
secret key
but that's fine because ipdf is not a
public key functionality
for the functional key if we're trying
to give a key that will enable the user
to evaluate in our products with a
vector y
well recall that we essentially have a
vector s of secret keys
so we simply give out the inner product
between y and s
and then there's a way to combine a
bunch of ciphertexts with the
functionality
it uses the structure of the group and
you can do the math it works out
and you get back this inner product as
is common with
group-based interpreter functional
encryption schemes that result is in the
exponent of the group generator
so you have to make sure the result of
your computation isn't too big
so that you can compute the discrete
algorithm it's a bit unfortunate
but it's usually manageable in practice
so how can we distribute the key
generation in this scheme
so it is closer to being a proper ddfe
well we set the key is the inner product
between the vector
y from the function on t and the vector
s of the secret key
another totally equivalent way of
looking at it is that it's the sum of
the y's
multiplied by the appropriate s's
if you see it as a sum you realize this
for key generation you really want a
decentralized
non-interactive way to evaluate this sum
but that's what we were talking about
just a few minutes ago
that's d sum which does indeed let us
decentralize key generation
another issue you run into is that of
repeated queries
as we did earlier with dsm because
encryption is again deterministic
so you can use the group structure to
figure out the difference between two
plain texts
from two cipher texts for the same set
of participants in the same label
thankfully it turns out aone which we
had used for dsm
also helps here finally
we simplified things a bit here by
having simple scalars as messages
but we can actually have vectors as
messages that actually complicate things
a bit
as far as repeated queries are concerned
this can be addressed by combining
a layer of single input in our product
functional encryption
with another layer of aone under
functional keys
again i'll refer you to the paper for
details
allow me to conclude by recapitulating
our main contributions
first we defined dynamic decentralized
functional encryption
which is a framework for describing a
variety of cryptosystems
that enable a server to perform
controlled computations
on data from a variety of clients next
we define three interesting dtfe
functionalities
for which we also provide constructions
although nothing encapsulation is an
extremely helpful building block
for achieving a natural notion of
security in our other functionalities
and we give a generic construction there
are from identity based encryption
with a succinct variant from bi-linear
maps
we then define decentralized sum for
which our construction
makes generate use of aorni and of
non-interactive key exchange
finally we use both of these
functionalities
in addition to prime order groups to
construct a decentralized scheme
for the functional evaluation of inner
products over sensitive data
that's it for today's presentation i'd
like to thank you again for your
interest
and i look forward to interacting with
you and answering your questions during
the conference