hello i'm jack derner coming before you
today with my pandemic here to talk
about multi-party generation of rsa
moduli
this is joint work with megan chen ron
cohen joshua
conde issa lee shula rosefield and abi
shalat
and you can find our paper online as
iacr eprint number 2020-370.
in this work we introduce a new protocol
for distributed rsa modulus sampling
with malicious security against a
dishonest majority in the uc model
hours is the first such protocol from
only oblivious transfer and the
factoring assumption to support an
arbitrary number of parties
and so far as we know the first to
achieve cubic complexity or better in
the length of the modulus
an rsa modulus usually designated by the
variable n
is the product of two large randomly
chosen primes which we call p
and q we call such numbers by primes and
in this talk i will use the terms by
prime and rsa modulus interchangeably
it is one of the oldest public key
assumptions we have that factoring such
numbers is hard
and when used as the modulus they form
multiplicative groups wherein finding
the group order is equivalent to
factoring
this makes rsa moduli useful for a huge
range of applications
of course they can be used to construct
signature schemes and various kinds of
encryption
but they're also useful for building
advanced primitives such as for example
cryptographic accumulators
and time lock puzzles and verifiable
delay functions
and recently some kinds of highly
efficient zero-knowledge argument
systems
this list is far from exhaustive
amazingly
although rsa is one of the seminal
asymmetric crypto systems
many of these applications are very
recent in fact all of the ones i've
highlighted here were published within
the last two years they all use rsa
moduli as part of their trusted setup
however there's no way that we know of
to sample a buy prime for which nobody
knows the factors
using only public randomness so the
remaining option is to distribute
sampling
among many parties using multi-party
computation
this isn't merely a theoretical concern
by the way the ethereum foundation has
publicly announced an intention to
migrate to rsa-based verifiable delay
functions
which means that they need secure by
prime sampling in the real world
and they needed to be efficient for many
parties
it's not surprising to find that the
history of secure byprime sampling
mirrors the history of its applications
a great deal of initial interest and a
recent resurgence
bonai and franklin wrote the seminal
paper on the subject in 1997
and pretty much all of the subsequent
works follow their basic layout
including ours
i'm going to skip most of the history
which focused on semi-honest or honest
majority constructions
and talk only about the most recent
works which are those of huzai nicholson
robin toft and nicolosi
and frederiks and lindell oceador and
pincus
i'd also like to point out that there is
already a follow-up to our work which
uses some of the techniques we
introduced
and achieves a really astonishing
performance in the aggregator model
that paper is on eprint now and it will
appear at s
p in 2021 after i talk about these prior
works and the general shape of the
problem i'll introduce our protocol
itself
and after that i'll show you why it's
efficient
now i claim that generating an rsa by
prime using a multi-party protocol
is uniquely difficult relative to
multi-party key generation for other
kinds of cryptosystems because
we sample by primes by rejection that is
we pick a k
bit number where k is a security
parameter
test whether it's prime and throw it
away if it's not
when we find two primes p and q we
multiply them together to form a 2k bit
by prime
n primality is usually determined via
the miller robin test
i won't show it to you in detail but the
important thing to know is that it
requires us to repeatedly take a random
base a
to some secret power modulo p
turning this into a multi-party protocol
naively would require many secure
modular exponentiations with large
secret moduli and this is very very far
from practical
bonnie and franklin were the first to
recognize this and in the seminal paper
on this topic
they devised a more efficient test in
the semi-honest setting
rather than testing the primality of two
individual numbers
they devised a direct biprimality test
that only use the product of the two
primes which is to say the candidate by
prime n
for some statistical parameter number of
iterations they choose a random base a
with jacobi symbol one
and take it to the power of n minus p
minus q plus 1
modulo n if this is equal to plus or
minus 1
in all iterations then the test passes
for technical reasons they also require
a gcd test but we won't worry about this
for now
the key here is that the modulus n is
the public output of the protocol
this means that we can cut the factors p
and q into integer shares
one share of each for every party and
then rewrite the test as the product of
terms that the parties can compute
locally
an integer sharing in this case is
simply a set of randomly chosen
positive integers that add up to the
shared value
this style of sharing is important
because it yields a natural method for
reconstructing p and q
modulo phi of n in the exponent where
phi of n
is the order of the multiplicative group
modulo n
if you know one or more integer shares
of a value then you know both upper and
lower bounds on that value
in other words integer shares leak some
information
bone and franklin provide a proof that
this leakage doesn't grant an adversary
any meaningful advantage in factoring
the biprimes that their protocol
produces
although the bone franklin test itself
is efficient the downside is that it
requires us to guess
two long prime numbers simultaneously in
order to succeed
instead of just one as in the case of
individual primality testing
to increase the probability of success
bone and franklin try to filter out some
of the candidate ps and queues that are
obviously not prime before running the
test
each candidate factor is divided by a
sequence of small primes and rejected if
it divides evenly
this is known as trial division they
show that if a kbit candidate prime is
sampled uniformly
and it passes trial division by all
primes up to some bound capital b
then it's prime with probability an
omega of log of b
over k the probability that the
biprimality test six seeds
is the square of that and if you repeat
the whole protocol
until you successfully sample a by prime
then the number of times that you have
to repeat it is in expectation
of k squared over log squared b
now as i said i'm going to skip forward
a bit 15 years later the hmrt protocol
was the first to support an arbitrary
number of parties and achieve malicious
security against a dishonest majority
in order to do this they use homomorphic
encryption and take a gmw-like approach
to achieving security
that is each party proves that each
operation on a ciphertext was performed
correctly
this is conceptually straightforward but
it leads to a somewhat complex security
analysis
and because the hmrt protocol relies
specifically on both pi
encryption and elgamal encryption we are
forced to accept both the decisional
composite residuosity
and decisional diffie-hellman
assumptions furthermore
proving statements about paella and
al-gamal ciphertexts and zero knowledge
is very expensive
even without the zero-knowledge proofs
in semi-honest mode with two parties
they report taking no less than 15
minutes to sample a buy prime
mostly due to the computational cost of
homomorphic encryption
on the other hand the flop protocol
focuses on the two-party case
exclusively and is the first malicious
secure protocol with concrete efficiency
which they demonstrated by implementing
it
instead of homomorphic encryption it
uses one of n oblivious transfer to
implement trial division
and it uses one of two oblivious
transfer to build a malicious gilboa
style multiplier for multiplying p
and q together rather than taking the
gmw
style approach of proving each step
correct as it occurs
the authors instead introduce what they
call a proof of honesty
a single proof that's run at the end
only if the biprimality test passes
which verifies a few key algebraic
relationships among values used in the
protocol
they do also evaluate a symmetric key
relation but
this can somewhat easily be removed so i
won't count it against them
regardless this approach has both
advantages and disadvantages
treating ot as a black box allows
flexibility with respect to which
assumptions are required
and the flop protocol is concretely fast
by comparison to the hmrt protocol
frederickson and all report being able
to sample a buy prime with malicious
security in roughly two and a half
minutes when using high performance
hardware
on the other hand their ot-based trial
division method leaks some bits of the
candidate primes
this is selective leakage on the part of
an adversary and not merely a natural
byproduct of using integer shares
furthermore while their proof of honesty
framework frees them from the costs of
the gmw
approach they only run it when the
biprimality test succeeds
which means it's possible for a
malicious adversary to force failures
covertly
the adversary can combine this ability
with the leakage i mentioned before to
reject candidates selectively
and the only way to prevent the
adversary from engaging in a denial of
service attack
is to run so many instances of the
sampling procedure that a biprime should
be produced with overwhelming
probability
thus a malicious adversary can slow
their protocol down by a factor of up to
the statistical security parameter
in the wake of these two works then we
have an open question
can one build a protocol with support
for an arbitrarily many parties and
malicious security against a dishonest
majority
which has flexible assumptions doesn't
require homomorphic encryption
doesn't use expensive zero knowledge
over cryptographic statements
and gives the adversary no extra leakage
or denial of service ability
in this work we answer in the
affirmative we do require
one specific assumption which is the
assumption that it's hard to factor by
primes from our protocol's underlying
sample distribution
but we view this as acceptable since
it's precisely the assumption required
to use the protocol's output
and without it the whole exercise is
pointless
beyond these things we also provide a
modular security analysis
whereas previous works have proven their
protocol somewhat monolithically
we hope this will make it easy to
interchange primitives and potentially
prove new security guarantees in the
future
finally our protocol improves
asymptotically on the flop protocol by a
factor of the security parameter
in terms of communication cost we don't
have an asymptotic analysis of the hmrt
protocols communication costs so i don't
want to make a specific comparative
complexity claim
but i will point out that we know hmrt
to be much more expensive than flop
concretely so now we come to the
protocol itself
for the sake of clarity and time i'm
going to explain a drastically
simplified version
for the most part i'll only talk about
two parties though hopefully you can
imagine how everything can be
generalized
i also won't always talk about how
malicious security can be achieved
but i'll try to let you know where i
make important omissions
our protocol has a simple layout first
it securely samples candidate factors p
and q
then it securely multiplies those
factors to produce a candidate biprime
which it subjects to the bone a franklin
biprimality test and finally
it runs a retroactive consistency check
to ensure no malicious behavior occurred
during the previous phases
the first three parts of this layout are
common among almost all by prime
sampling protocols
they come from bonaire franklin our
consistency check is new
but it can be thought of as somewhat
analogous to the proof of honesty used
by fredericks and a all
i'll talk about the techniques we use to
implement each step of this layout in
turn
starting with sampling our sampling
technique is based on the chinese
remainder theorem so let's recall that
quickly
if we have a vector of the first l
unique primes
which we'll call a primordial vector
here represented by the letter m
and we have the product of those primes
which is the elf primordial number
then the chinese remainder theorem says
that there is an isomorphism between the
product of fields modulo the individual
primes
and the ring modulo the corresponding
primordial number
we'll talk about values in these spaces
a lot so i'm going to color code them to
make it easier
values in the product of the fields
modulo the individual primes will be
magenta
we call this the crt form values in the
ring modulo the primordial number will
be teal
and we'll call this standard form the
chinese remainder theorem
also gives us another important fact a
set of values in crt form which we'll
call
x map to a value in standard form we'll
call this value p
if and only if the jth element of x is
congruent to p
modulo the jth prime for all j
this means that if you select a crt form
vector x with no
zero elements then the corresponding
standard form value p
will not be divisible by any of the
primes in the primordial vector
thus we sample probable primes without
trial division
we call this constructive sampling
if we had only one party our sampling
algorithm would be simple
choose a crt form value randomly test to
make sure all of its elements are
non-zero
then find the corresponding standard
form value and interpret it as an
integer which is our candidate prime
p it turns out that if we want to
distribute this algorithm we can do so
by instructing the parties to run the
algorithm
individually and locally to generate
integer shares of the candidate prime p
and instead of performing local zero
tests we instruct them to jointly test
the modular sums of their crt form
elements in each small prime field or
non-zero
i'm going to gloss over how this works
for the moment
we show that if they do this then the
integer sum of their shares of p will be
indivisible by
all of the primes in the primordial
vector and of course they can repeat the
process to sample q
the integer shares here are important by
the way we need them for compatibility
with the bone franklin test
which we're going to run later now once
the parties have shares of p
and q they must multiply them together
to form shares of a by prime n
this is where all prior works have
encountered a bottleneck in the form of
multiplication protocols over length k
inputs typically ot-based multi-party
multiplication protocols have at least
quadratic computation and communication
complexity in the bit length of their
inputs
homomorphic encryption-based
multiplication protocols like the ones
used by hmrt
have better communication complexity but
worse computation complexity
for example hmrt use pi a encryption
which requires modular exponentiation
with a modulus of length proportionate
to k
we take the ot based approach but we
leverage the chinese remainder theorem
once again to improve our result
relative to naive multiplication
once again consider the single party
case we observe that if we take
two crt form values x and u defined with
respect to the same primorial vector m
of length l
then the product of their corresponding
standard form values p
and q modulo the lth primorial number
corresponds to the element-wise modular
product of x and u
here i'm using the circle dot to
represent element-wise multiplication
this means that if we want the standard
form product of p and q
we can multiply the crt form values x
and u
element by element then evaluate the
mapping instead of evaluating the
mapping before multiplication
we can show that if a primordial number
has k bits
then the length of the largest prime in
the corresponding primordial vector
is an o of log k and also that l
the length of the primarily vector is an
o of k over log k
consequently if our fundamental
multiplication complexity is quadratic
then we can multiply two k bit numbers
in crt form
in complexity of k log k as opposed to o
of k
squared if we did it naively the zero
testing operation which i glossed over
earlier is done using this distributed
crt multiplication
technique but unfortunately we can't
immediately use the same technique to
compute
n from the candidate primes p and q that
i showed you how to sample a moment ago
because the technique computes the
product modulo the primordial number
whereas we need to compute the integer
product
this is not however a dead end
fortunately we can show that there is a
way to expand a crt representation to
new prime fields
without changing its semantic value this
allows us to enlarge the standard form
ring
to the point that there is no wrapping
when a modular multiplication is
performed
which makes the result equivalent to an
integer multiplication
before we move on i should mention that
because the crt
extension operation is local corrupt
parties can do whatever they want
also because there's no authentication
on the output shares of our element-wise
multiplication
corrupt parties can lie about the shares
that they got
i haven't taken pains to show you how we
achieve malicious security
so it's important to know that even in
the malicious version of our protocol
this sort of cheat is still possible and
we have to account for it later in our
consistency check
i'm only going to talk briefly about the
biprimality test since our protocol
follows mostly from prior work
the interesting thing is that we prove
it realizes a standalone functionality
here i have a simplified version of it
it takes the candidate by prime
n as a common input and integer shares
of the candidate factors p
and q from each party and it outputs
success
only if both n is a bi-prime and n
is really the product of the input
factors
the adversary can also force failures
but it can't force successes
which means that this functionality has
no false positives
the functionality is clean and free of
protocol artifacts such as
authentication primitives and it allows
corrupt parties to use whatever shares
they like
notice however that if n really is a
bi-prime then there are only two
possible pairs of factors p
and q that would make the functionality
succeed
one follows from the honest protocol
execution and we show that finding the
other is as hard as factoring
n this is an important and subtle case
that is essential to our simulation
argument
finally we come to the consistency check
so far
every part of the protocol that you've
seen has been composed of simple
non-cryptographic operations
and the only functionalities involved
have been a multiplication functionality
and a biprimality testing functionality
our retroactive consistency check
ensures that the local operations are
performed correctly
and that the inputs to the
functionalities have the right
relationships
we show that there exists a simple
algebraic predicate involving only the
modulus
n and the expanded crt form shares of p
and q
here again i'm showing it to you in the
two-party setting which is sufficient to
guarantee security against
malicious behavior if the biprimality
test
passed then n might be our output so we
evaluate this predicate securely
in the current version of the paper we
use generic mpc for a canonical
instantiation
but it's conceivable that this can be
improved with tailored protocols
this can be comparatively slow but we
only have to do it when we succeed
if the by primality test failed then
either n
isn't a biprime or some party cheated
regardless there's no need for privacy
and so the parties open up their values
to one another
and verify the predicate locally which
is much faster
there are a lot of details that i'm
sweeping under the rug here for example
we have to enforce that the inputs to
the multiplication functionality are
opened or loaded into the generic npc
faithfully
but this is the essence of it of course
the paper gives a rigorous simulation
based proof
so for the details i invite you to look
there
now before i close i want to talk a
little bit about efficiency
i've been qualifying my complexity
statements throughout this talk by
saying that they hold if multiplication
has a quadratic cost
in the malicious setting we instantiate
our multiplication functionality using
an ot based construction derived from
multipliers introduced by recent works
on secure ecdsa signing
as a basis we use the silent ot
extension scheme introduced last year by
boyle
gilboa ishai cole and scholl which has
almost no overhead when amortized
but the multiplier construction itself
requires a special encoding scheme which
means that it has communication constant
o of n x squared plus nsx per party
for n parties and x bit inputs where s
is the statistical parameter
this leads to an overall communication
complexity and of
nsk for sampling and modulus
construction
as an aside if we use the ot extension
protocol of keller or cenia in shoal
instead of silent ot extension then this
cost goes up by a factor of
s over log k which is concretely
something like 4 to 8.
our biprimality test has different costs
depending on whether it reports a
failure or a success
in failed instances it also costs an o
of nsk
in terms of communication but in
successful instances where it determines
that n is a bi-prime
it costs in this term which you don't
need to worry about
because it will be subsumed by something
else later
our consistency check also has different
costs depending on whether or not n is
thought to be a biprime
if n is thought to be a bi-prime then we
use generic npc to evaluate the
predicate securely
if we instantiate this with the
authenticated garbling protocol of wang
ranalucci and cats
then it has communication complexity and
o of n squared
s k squared over log of n k
if n is thought not to be a by prime
then we reveal everything and evaluate
the predicate locally
and the reveal operation costs o of nsk
overall if we repeat the whole protocol
until a success occurs
we need o of k squared over log square
to k repetitions and expectation
which follows from bonnie and franklin's
theorem all but one of these repetitions
will be failures so we pay the smaller
cost for both the buy primality test and
the consistency check
and only in the last repetition do we
pay the larger costs
putting everything together finally
gives us an overall expected
communication complexity per party for
sampling a buy prime
which you can see here now i know my
protocol descriptions and security
arguments have been rather loose but
this is exactly the cost of the real
protocol as presented in the paper
there are a few more lemmas that i won't
show you which allow us to conclude that
this is
strictly less than o of n s k cubed over
log of n
k to conclude i hope that this talk has
convinced you that distributed by prime
sampling is a challenge
i've shown you how the chinese remainder
theorem can be used to optimize the
sampling of candidate primes
and how it can be used to optimize
multiplying those candidates together
and i've shown you how an algebraic
predicate can be used to tie
everything together without homomorphic
encryption or proofs over cryptographic
statements
in the paper of course everything is
presented in much more rigor
and there are a few additional results
we show how to achieve
a constant round count and we give a
concrete cost analysis
we also present a semi-honest variant of
the protocol with perfect security in
the same hybrid model as the main
protocol
and we give a modular security analysis
of the main protocol
with some informal discussion of how
various modules can be substituted to
achieve stronger security guarantees
such as
adaptive security or identifiable abort
that's all for today though thank you
for listening