hi everyone uh today i'm going to talk
about
our world where we construct new
non-interactive zero knowledge uh for np
based on tribal hash and the lpn
assumption maybe the bottom line and
consequence of such a result is the
first music for np from lpn and edh
which are both standard assumptions that
were not known to imply in physics
before
this is a joint work with sveka and
venkata and let's begin
so i'm going to start with uh defining
an easy x
so an intellect is zero knowledge uh for
elect for an np language
is simply a proof system uh where both
approver and the verifier have an access
to an honestly generated crs
and the protocol is not interactive so
it consists of a single
message that the property sends to the
verifier and we ask that the verifier is
efficient of course but we also want
that approval is efficient given an np
witness
w for the statement um and we consider
the standard
completeness soundness and zero
knowledge properties so while physics
are interesting by themselves but they
also have lots of nice applications in
crypto including
cca security signatures and new
applications in the regime of
cryptocurrencies
so since the ultimate goal is
constructing physics from standard
assumptions let's quickly go through the
known approaches
from the literature that do that so the
textbook approach is called the hidden
bits model
and it can be instantiated uh using
either chapter permutations
or vrs or vbrgs but this approach is a
bit limited
since the only known constructions of
such building blocks
are either based on factoring related
assumptions or assumptions over by
linear groups
um another way to get this x was
discovered by growth of structure and
sahai
and it works in the setting where we
have a bilinear group
and we assume some different style
assumptions over it
but this approach is very non-generic it
uses properties of
such groups so it doesn't seem that
physics from new standards assumptions
will come from this direction
the last approach i'm going to discuss
is an approach where we start with
an interactive uh zero knowledge
protocol and we use the fiat
html transform to turn it into a
non-interactive protocol and in order to
instantiate the vhma transform and
improve present manner we use a
primitive or correlation interactive
hash
and a long and nice line of work has
essentially led to a construction
population tactical hash
under the lwd assumption to so to
summarize
things up we have musics under factoring
related assumptions or
assumptions over by linear groups or lwe
[Music]
in our paper we extend the set of
standard assumptions
from which we have nsx and we follow up
on this last approach
and instantiated assuming a table hatch
which in particular can be constructed
from vdh
and jointly assuming there'll be an
assumption
so how do we really get music from phm
here so we start with a base protocol
which consists of three messages
and i will assume it's a public one
protocol so in the beginning that google
sends his first message a and then the
verify replies by a random challenge e
and then the prover sends his third
message and the verifier either accepts
or rejects
so the feature mutants form using a hash
function edge it looks as follows
so we add that is a randomly sampled
hash key to the crs
and now the proofer computes his first
message a as before but in order to
simulate the verified challenge he uses
the hash function so now the verifies
challenge is computed as the hash of a
under the key which is found in the crs
and once
he completed the first message a and the
challenge e he can continue and compute
the third message
z and then he sends the entire
transcript to the verifier
at once so it's easy to see that this
protocol is
interactive and also that if we start
with the public protocol
then the non-interactive protocol is
also complete
we also know that if the base protocol
is honest verify zero knowledge
then the fiat may transform preserves
zero knowledge
so the only missing piece in the puzzle
here is sound so it's not clear that
even if the
base protocol is sound that an
uninteractive protocol is also sound
and the reason is that the prover has
some control over
the choice of the verifiers challenge
and in particular he can choose a first
message a
such that the verifies challenge h of a
falls inside the soundness error of the
protocol
this leads us to consider a specific
kind of uh
based protocols which we call signal
protocols so sigma protocols are three
message public coin honest
honest verified zero knowledge protocols
which also enjoy this unique bad
challenge property
and this property basically says that
for any uh first message
a there exists at most one value of
a e that may possibly allow a cheat
improver to cheat
and we call such a value of e the bad
challenge uh e so
uh more formally fixing a crs and x
which is not in the language
and the first message a there exists at
most one bad challenge
e for which uh there exists a transcript
a e instead
that the verifier accepts
so uh this property allows us to define
the bad challenge function which is
defined using series and x
and gets as an input first message a and
outputs
the corresponding bad challenge e and
now we can claim soundless of the
non-interactive protocol as follows
so if we uh can say that it's hard for
the cheat improver to find a first
message a
such that h of a is the bad challenge
then it's computationally hard for a
prover to cheat
because the only way he can cheat is by
choosing the first message such that h
of a
is that bad challenge corresponding to a
and a hash function that satisfies this
hardness requirement is called
a correlation interactable hash for the
bad challenge function f
okay so now we know how to construct an
esx using the mirror
and all we need is two ingredients so
first of all we need a sigma protocol to
start with
and then we need a hash function that is
correlation interactable for the
class of bad challenge functions
corresponding to the sigma protocol
so now we try to instantiate this recipe
and the guiding rule
that we should keep in mind is the
following the simpler the bad challenge
function
is then the easier is the task of
constructing relation interactability
for such a class of functions so our
goal
is kind of dual here so first of all we
need uh to describe the
bad challenge function for some sigma
protocol as simple as possible
and on the other hand we need to
construct correlation tractability
uh for from standard assumptions so now
we can start asking questions
for example it's not clear how simple
can the bad challenge function be
and it's not even clear whether it's
efficiently computable
on the other hand we can ask about
instructions for correlation
tractability
under standard assumptions
so the the first work that tries to
prove the science of html under
cryptographic assumptions is this worked
by connected r
where they observe that the batch range
function for a sigma protocol
for np is efficiently recognizable so if
i give you that challenge you can
efficiently say that this is a bad
challenge and consequently
the regulation capability task becomes
to construct ci for all efficiently
recognizable functions
and they are able to do that under
sub-exponential io and some other strong
notion of
obfuscation and these assumptions are
clearly uh
not standard there have been many
follow-up works
um each trying to construct
relationshipability for
um a different uh class of functions
that is sufficient for netflix
but again they all do that under uh
exotic assumptions so
um for example uh some assumed sub
financial i o
or fully exponential akdm security
uh but very recently um last crypto um
or even a bit before this line of work
led to constructions
uh uh understandable assumptions and in
particular this last work by picard and
srihan
they use the observation that the bad
challenge function is efficiently
computable
for some sigma protocol and therefore
all they need now is collection
capability for all efficient computer
build functions and they can get that
under lwe
so let's say we call our goal our goal
is to extend this paradigm
and basically on other standard
assumptions and there seems to be a
barrier here
so notice that these last two works they
consider the complexity of computing the
bad challenge function
and they say that the batch range
function is an arbitrary polynomial time
computation
and therefore we need
relationshipability for any polynomial
time computation
and it seems that we need a homomorphism
for any polynomial time computation
in order to do that or in other words we
need for homomorphism and we
know that we can get that only under lwe
um as far as we know of course
what we do differently is we consider
the complexity of approximating the bad
challenge
and using such an approach we can show
that it
is sufficient that we use a partial
homomorphism and in particular we can
use one more prism that we can get from
other standard assumptions such as ddh
or
aqr
so more specifically we observe that the
bad challenge for some sigma protocol
for an np
a complete language can be approximated
by constant degree polynomials
and therefore it's sufficient now to get
relationshipability for all functions
that can be approximated by constantly
polynomials and this is exactly what we
do
and we use a trapdoor hash and the
airplane assumption
good so let's draw a more elaborate
comparison between
period work and our work so again like i
said
uh period work uses the fact that uh
there exists a sigma protocol for an
a complete language where the bad
challenge is efficiently computable
and therefore a relationship ability for
all efficiently computable functions
suffices for nz and they can get such
relationship immediately using
homomorphism for all efficient functions
or for hormones in other words under lwe
so morphism is a very vague notion but
you can think about fhe in such a case
or fully homomorphic commitments
uh so at a high level what they do is
they use homomorphism for a function
class
f which is in this case any polynomial
time computation to get correlation
stackability for
f for an equilibrium computation
um so again our goal is to start with
other standard assumptions in particular
assumptions that do not uh give us full
homomorphism
so our starting point is um a work
also from last crypto by uh al when we
show how using
uh many standard assumptions in
particular adh we can get
some form of well-structured
homomorphism
um again this is very vague but the uh
formal abstraction for that
was called triple hatch so we get some
sort of well-structured homomorphism for
all constant degree functions
um and we show that um
and using west structure homomorphism
for such a weak class of functions
we can get a flexibility for a much
stronger class of functions
so rather than starting with
homomorphism for f we start with
homomorphism for a much
weaker class c but using some structure
of
the underlying homomorphic primitives we
get politician factability for
the strong class f and more specifically
we get correlation tractability
for all relations that can be
approximately by constant degree
polynomials
and if we want to compare this notion to
the usual
ability notion then in the standard
correlation factorability
we ask that it's hard to find an x such
that h of x
is equal to the band challenge of f of x
but what we want now is a hash function
such that it's hard to find an x for
which h and x
and f of x are even close to each other
in some metric
okay so this is a stronger notion but
we're considering a much weaker class of
functions
in particular a constant degree of
polynomials
and then we show that using uh ci for
approximate relations we can
uh get correlation attractability for
all functions that can be approximately
computed by constant db polynomials
and then we show that under lpm uh this
is sufficient in air coordinates
uh more specifically we show a sigma
protocol for an np language
uh in which the bad challenge function
can be approximated using
using constant degree polynomials under
the ldn assumption of course
and this is how we get our result good
so
following this outline we can divide our
results to three parts
and i'm going to go through uh one after
the other
okay so let's first define what
correlation capability is so we say that
the hash function h
is correlation detectable for a function
f
if for any polynomial time adversary
it's hard to win the following game
which we call the relationship ability
game
so the game goes as follows the
challenger first samples a random
hash key okay and then he gives k to the
adversary and the adversary's goal now
is to find the correlation with respect
to k
namely his goal is to find an x such
that h of x
is equal to f of x so uh h is
relationship for f
if no ppt adversary can win this game
and we say that uh
h is equally detractable for a function
class f
if it is relationship for every function
in the class
it will be useful at this point to talk
about a technique that was used in
period work
to get ci and it's called summer
statistical relationship ability
so we say the following assume that uh
for every
uh function f so given f we can sample a
fake hash
k sub f which is indistinguishable from
the
read hash key and further that uh the ci
game when we sample a field
key rather than a real key is
statistically hard to win so again we
consider the game which is identical to
the
game we've seen before but now rather
rather than sampling
we sample a fake actually using a fake
generation algorithm
and what does it mean for the game to be
hard to win it basically means that
the probability that there exists a
correlation between h
under the fake hash key and f is
negligible
so assuming we have these two properties
then using a standard distinguishability
argument we can claim
that h is actually correlation
flexibility for the entire function
class
calligraphic f good
um so let's start with a very trivial
case towards our final construction so
we consider the case where our function
class
f contains only length expanding
functions more specifically every
function in the class
takes a small domain and expands it to a
large range
and notice that in particular in such a
case um
the image of any function f is some
small subset of the range
so our candidate for relation
detectability in such a case
is a hash function that simply simply
samples a random vector r
in the hash key and outputs it
regardless of the value of x
so notice that once we fix a hash key
then our hash function is constant
so what happens now for every function
in the class
the probability that there exists a
correlation is equal to the probability
that r
is even in the image of f
and if the image of f is sufficiently
small or
more precisely if it's exponentially
sparse in the range then the probability
that r
is in the image or equivalently that the
existing correlation
is negligible good so this simple
construction is actually equally
interactable for expanding functions
and our idea is to impose the same image
in the general case even when our class
contains shrinking functions
so when our class contains shrinking
functions we cannot simply sample a
random r
and uh and assume it's going to be
outside of the image
because the image of the function can be
the entire range
so what we do instead we define our hash
function h
using some other hash function we call h
prime so our hash construction will
look as follows we will use a hash
function h prime
and then h of x will be equal to h prime
on x
a a random r so again r is part of the
hash key and is sampled randomly
so what we require from h prime in order
for it to be uh correlation attractable
so we require that for every function in
the class if there exists
a fake hash key which is
indistinguishable from a real hash key
further we require that the correlation
function
h prime of x under the fetch key store f
of x so i'm calling this the correlation
function because it represents the
correlation
of h prime under the fake hash key and f
we require that this
correlation function has exponentially
sparse image and
in such a case we say that h prime with
fake hash key and f
have its parts correlation so assuming
we have this possible relation between
the fate hash function and f
then we can say that uh with the
overwhelming probability
uh we have that a random r is not in the
image of this correlation function
and uh uh and therefore uh with a
negligible probability that exists a
correlation between
h and f and therefore h is somewhat
statistical relationship
good now that we have reduced our goal
uh to constructing sparse correlations
i'm going to
show you real quick how to do that uh
using trapdoor hash
um so like i already said uh traptor
hash
allows us to construct a homologic
encryption scheme with very strong
structural properties
so in general in a more encryption
scheme we can take an input x
and given an encryption of a function f
we can morphically evaluate
and obtain a ciphertext encrypting f of
x
in a homomorphic encryption scheme which
we construct from trap.hash
the post-evaluation ciphertext can be
divided into two parts
one part we call the rate once
ciphertext and i'm going to refer to it
as
the encryption of f of x and another
part is a small hash h of x
and the decryption integral hash goes as
follows so the first stage
takes the hash of x h of x and produces
a long vector e and then one can recover
f of x
simply by storing e and the encryption
of f of x
so the second stage of the decryption is
public
so how can we use such an encryption
scheme in order to get partial relations
so i'm going to define the fake hash key
for every function f
to be the encryption of f and then given
an input x will compute
h prime of x simply as the
ciphertext or the rate one ciphertext of
f of x
okay so see we so the function f prime
is simply one of the evaluation
so what about the correlation function
now so notice that the correct
the correctness of decryption of chapter
hash
the correlation function is simply this
vector e which is computed only given a
small h of x
and if h of x is sufficiently small then
we can say that e is sampled from
an exponentially sparse image and
therefore the correlation between h
prime
and f is sparse so i didn't say
uh what the real key
is and why is it indistinguishable from
the hash key
but notice that the fake keys are simply
the encryption
of the functions they correspond to so
the real key can be an encryption of any
arbitrary fixed function
and we can claim indistinguishability
based on the security of the encryption
scheme
so good so from the work of docking it
all we know that we can
get such well-structured homomorphism
for constant degree functions
from many standard assumptions including
uh ddh for instance
and like i showed you this gives us
correlation flexibility for all constant
degree functions
but unfortunately this is insufficient
for physics
so now we ask whether we can get
something stronger out of our idea of
sparse relations
and remember that we claimed that a
random r is with overwhelming
probability
not in the image of a sparse correlation
but we also observe that overwhelming
probability
r is actually far away from this image
and almost immediately leads us to
defining a stronger notion of
correlation interactability
which we call c i apx
correlation interactability for
approximable relations
so we say that the hash function h is
correlation tractability is correlation
interactable for relations approximately
by f
if it's hard for an inversity not only
to find a correlation but rather to find
an
x such that h of x and f of x are close
in hamming distance and we can similarly
extend this
a notion to a ci for a class of
functions
good so now we know that we
can get ci for approximately constant
degree relations
based on trap.hash from ddh qr lwe or
dcr and i'm not going
to go through the details of this
transformation but
you will have to believe me that using
such notion of ci we can get
relationship ability
for all functions that we can
approximate using constant degree
and let's be a bit more formal i just
want to tell you
what notion of approximability we're
considering
so we say that the function f is
probabilistically computable by a
constant degree polynomial
there exists a distribution over such
polynomials such that for every input x
the probability that f of x and p
of x are far from each other in hamming
distance is negligible
okay where p here is this polynomial
sampled according to the
distribution which probabilistically
computes
f good
so now all is left to show you is how
under lpn
we have a sigma protocol for an
np-complete language
such that the batch challenge function
has a pro can be progressively computed
using constant degree polynomials
and to do that i'm going to first recall
period work
uh where all they had to do is show the
existing sigma protocol with an
efficiently computable bad challenge
so they start with the classic sigma
protocol for hamiltonicity
which in particular uses some commitment
scheme and they use the observation
that if this commitment scheme is
efficiently extractable
meaning that we can extract the values
underlying some commitment
uh only by seeing the commitment and
possibly using some trouble
then the bad challenge function is
efficiently computable
and more specifically the challenge
function uh given a
it simply consists of first extracting
the values underlying the commitment
a and then applying some polynomial time
computation which we denote here by v
so clearly if both v and the extraction
algorithm are efficiently computable
then so is the batch range function
f so um for us we need something
stronger we need to
show that the sigma protocol has a
challenge which is probabilistic
constant degree
so we make the following observations
first we observe that there exists an lb
lpn based commitment scheme
where the extraction algorithm can be
probabilistically computable by a linear
function which are a constant in which a
special
case of constant degree functions of
course
but the problem is that this polynomial
time verification
is of high degree okay at least in the
protocol formula city and it's not clear
how we can
uh probabilistically compute it using a
constant degree polynomials
um but then we remember that using the
cochlear transform
we can uh transform any polynomial
amplification
to a 3cnf formula uh and this is because
here three synthesis viability is
complete for
uh such political amplification um
and why is this useful this is useful
because 37 formulas actually
have uh probabilistic representations as
constant degree polynomials so um
again using a cochlear viewing we can uh
adjust a bit the uh
metricity protocol into a protocol where
the bad challenge function consists of
first extracting the values underlying
the commitment a
and then applying some three c formula
rather than an arbitrary
normal time computation and now since we
know how to probabilistically compute
both the formula and the extraction
using constant degree functions
we can uh probabilistically compute the
bad challenge function using constant
degree and this completes our result
so let's conclude uh so we show a new
notion of ci for approximate
relations and we show that we can get
physics from standard assumptions
through this new notion in particular we
get the first physics under ddh and lpl
and now there are many natural questions
we can ask first of all whether we can
use this new notion to get applications
maybe in zaps or in complexity or
hardness results
we can also ask questions related to
applications itself
so it will be interesting to see whether
we can minimize the set of standard
assumptions
uh so maybe we can get music only from
ddh or only from lpn
uh it would be interesting to see
whether we can extend our result uh to
get statistical zero knowledge or
statistical soundness
soundness which we don't get either
as opposed to period work
that's it thanks for listening