okay
feel free to start whenever so
welcome to the session on lattices and
related problems
uh and the first talk will be on faster
enumeration based lattice reduction
hermit factor k to the one over k one
over two k
in time k to the k over eight uh
the papers by martin albright shibrai
pianolan foucault paul kirchner damian
stellen
wang and
okay thank you thank you waiting for the
introduction
so hello everyone i'm aita and in this
talk i would like to briefly present our
words about a new fast generation based
lattice reduction
so in more details compared to the prior
ones are the same type we can reach the
same quality while with the smaller time
complexity than before
and when the dimension of the impulse is
large enough we can prove this
improvement under heuristic assumption
and when the dimension is small can
still sold in our simulation that this
improvement still works for varying
accuracy
and next i like to give a few notations
so first
lattice is as a regular reach building
point
as you can see the blue points here
which can be associated with the
different species
and lattice reduction helps to reduce
from a perfect system to a good one
with the most grown basis vectors such
as corresponding grand semi vectors
have norms are closer to each other than
before and we'll call it grand seminars
in the later
and to quantify the quality of a basis
one can use the so-called homie vector
and also the normalized relational
rocomi vector or
determined by the solid spaces vector
and denoted as the first one here
and in practice one is mainly
interesting in the case lattice
reduction for reducing the basis
and the b cage aggregate simple reaching
a location vector k to the 1 to k
the time complexity is dominated by the
underlying sap solver of size k
which is u to find certain zero vector
in a k dimensional tester
and for the innervation base 1 one can
consider the best-known algorithm as the
canon's algorithm
with the time complexity k to the k over
2e plus a small d of k
and here we also consider a variant
called sdk z given by
sensory and water in 2016 so which
promises a good property that can
simplify
our analysis and in this work our main
result is for reaching the same local
factor
the time complexity we require is
smaller so it's k to the k over eight
plus s mod of k our idea is to start
from
an sup solver of smaller sizer denoted
as k zero
equal k times 208 such that the
immersion cost
over this reduce size is well reading
this
our targeting time complexity k to the
clear weight and given a casio
dimensional suv solver
by because key person about the upper
bound we can compute the hermit vector
and also the local effector
that we can achieve our casual
dimensionalities
so now we are contracted here starting
solver in ots
o0 reaching the starting routine factor
in time k to the ko ada
and next we aim to conjure a new solver
denoted so one are reaching a small
local factor but
still in time k to decay weight and this
involves two steps
so first is to run sdbkz without
starting solver o0
to reduce the base season so that for
the corresponding ingress make log
nonsense
there is a straight line here outside
the last block and then in the second
step you run an iteration over this
three
region and this two step started here
and also in cause the k to decay away
and these two steps together introduced
the new server awana which in a small
loophole factor
but there is also a main drawback so the
dimension
of the new solver is roughly size k
larger than b
and formally under heuristic assumption
we can prove omega one steps are
sufficient for approaching our target
gingrich vector
so this required the total dimension to
be roughly omega one second hydrogen in
k
but this is not satisfiable for keeping
an incisor or cryptosystem like
this candidate where it required the
dimension n to be relatively close to
the 2k so instead of run an immersion
over this trailer region we proposed a
practical variant
and now the immersion zone also covered
the last block where we assumed to be
educated reduced
and we also distribute 25 for the right
region
and 75 percent for the actual zone and
this distribution is near because
it reaches the lowest cost even below
this k to decay weight
and for simulation you can see the
simulated cost
of the practical variant fit well with
the k2k
one uh k to the koa curve and the
quality achieved like rokham effector
achieved by the practical variances well
with the
is at least as good as the one achieved
by a standard kz
and here you can see there's a desk line
here even below one way curve
so this denote the cost when we consider
the processing property
and we also leave the zero question for
future words and i record them here so
first is to remove the heuristic
assumption used in our analysis
and second is to extend our works basing
on sdbk set here
to other lattice reduction algorithm and
further
if we consider the processing for free
the cost can be below
k to the k08 so is it possible to have
the overall cluster
still be below this k to the koa by
maintaining the same quality
and last is about the cryptographic
relevance of this work
so in this work we only have a
simulation analysis for this
small dimension region so it will be
very interesting to have a formal
analysis
for this region and then it will be
interesting to study the
new crossover pointer between initial
base and c base
lattice reduction for concrete the
parameter
so in your base one can consider our new
algorithm and c-base one can consider
the jessica base
lattice reduction in our classical and
condensate and this completes my talk
and thank you for your attention
if you have any questions thanks very
much
are there any questions michael on zulip
uh
so far i don't see any
neither on zoom nor on zulip
okay so we can get the next speaker to
start preparing the talk so cohen
yeah but if anyone has any questions
about this we could circle back
at the end of the session if we or even
at the end of everything
i think noah asked the question what's
special about eight
yeah so why k to the k over eight like
what
where does the eight come from
return i can
open the micro sorry so yeah okay
so the reason is that once you run sdbk
set with size case scp server
the the emulation cost over this uh last
block will be 10 to the ko2e
the dimension cost over this trailer
region here
will be k to the kelvin so that's why
this is the
is the best cost we can expect because
this is the best case like we can reach
in in the sd card reduce basis
but that is also possible like i said if
you emerge
over this region
you can be even better than a capability
calculator
so it seems there are still possible
room to improve like
to uh even better than k to decay weight
even to something like over ten so like
a k to the k one but we haven't
we don't have any conclusion on this yes
sorry i'm not sorry i i respond your
question
thank you
okay so we can move on to the second
talk of the session
so this one is on uh random
self-producibility of ideal svp
via oracle of random walks by colin de
por leo duca
alice pelemeri and benjamin leslovsky
thank you for the introduction farim uh
one thing could you maybe raise your
volume because i can't
uh so if you are going to ask questions
i
probably can't hear you if you are this
soft
uh sorry sorry i turned around at some
point
this is very bad great
um okay so hi i'm kunda buer this is
joint work with
uh
this talk is about a worst case to
average case reduction
of the hermit svp problem on ideal
lattices
and we do this by considering the
space of all ideal lattices of a fixed
number field and that is called
the arakalov class group
um okay and
and we travel from a worst case
to an average case lattice at your
lattice
by means of a random walk on this raquel
of class group on this
space of all ideal lattices
okay great
so in our result we consider the hermit
svp problem the hermit svp problem
is actually just the svp problem but we
relate
the shortest factor rather with the
volume volume
than with the shortest vector of that
lattice
so and we assume for simplicity that
our ideal lattices all have volume one
we just
rescale them so that they have volume
one
okay and our result can actually be
applied to any number field but it is
particularly nice
for the cycloatomic name and the second
atomic field
and in that case it reads as follows
so if you can solve the
gamma hermit svp of over random
ideal lattices you can also
solve gamma prime hemispherp over
any audio lattice where gamma prime has
a blow up factor of the square root
of the rank n
how does it relate to previous work well
a worst case to average case reduction
is already be done by a gantry
but we improve uh on this result
in many ways and another important
uh thing i would like to state is that
our chaos class groups are actually
already used in recent
cryptanalysis but not really stated like
hey this is another kale of classical
but more like
a sort of combination of unit group and
class group object
so it is really nice of this work that
we actually stress the importance of the
archaeological class group
and the last point is what i want to say
is that
we we prove something about
about a random walk the end of the
random walk should
give you a uniform distribution and the
way we prove that
is actually uh yeah very alike
the proof strategy as in the
self-reduction of the discrete
logarithm problem on elliptic curves
okay so let's go to the actual
result so in the full
video i actually
explained that the space of all ideal
lattices can be parametrized by a circle
or well by a torus but in in
two dimensions it is actually a circle
and and
moving on this circle so this circle is
the archaelov
class group the space of all ideal
letters says
moving on the circle has the following
effect on the lattices it's
sort of distorting or it's stretching in
one direction
but pushing in the other direction but
if you want to reduce if you want to use
like the svp
on the the average case lattice to solve
svp on the worst case lattice it won't
work
because the the geometry
of the svp problem is also
changed it's also disturbed as you can
see the circle is
is an ellipse right now so this is not
we should also have another way of
random walking
and that's not by distortion not by
moving continuously
but it is by a specification
and specification is just taking an
ideal
sub lattice so you remove
points you remove points from the
lattice
such that the the remaining points also
form an ideal letters but we only
considered
ideal lattices with fixed volume so we
have to scale
the ideal letters uh so that it has like
volume one
and then we try to to apply svp we try
to
do an sp oracle here
but but to use this uh shortest factor
for the original worst case lattice
we need to to scale back so also here
we have a sort of yeah disturbation
of the sawdust factor problem but it is
very less severe
it's just a scaling not a real
disturbation but
more like it is better doable it's a
nicer distribution so and the intuition
now
is that if you if you apply this
um those two ways of specifically
those two ways of um random walking if
you combine those
then you hope that the following happens
so you have actually
the the the con the specification
uh random walk so those are discrete
jumps
those are quasi randomly
discrete jumps but you also have the way
the continuous the blurring idea
the continuous walk is a sort of
blurring so you hope that if you have
enough points
and you have enough blurring that you
reach something
that that that is close to uniform on on
the circle or on the torus on the
archaelov class group the space of all
ideal lattices
so we would like to see that the end
point
the end point of the random walk is
actually uniform and
well the intuition is that it actually
is
because of this picture well
i think that's all thank you for your
attention and if you have questions
i would like to answer them with all
pleasure
okay thank you very much cohen
and so there is no question on zulip
right now there's a short discussion on
the previous talk but on uh
zoom people have pointed out that they
really like your your visualization of
the math that's going on so
i uh wanted to also say that it's really
nice the animation also the full talk i
can only recommend everyone check out
the full talk of this
thanks thank you very much
so i uh share my screen
i think i'm next yeah go ahead
so so michael the discussion of the
previous talk do you want to
do it now or uh
maybe circle back at the end um
let's do all
so you guys can see my slides and
they're like in presentation mode
nope black
that's annoying now it looks good
not a presentation yeah not in
presentation mode okay i'll just like
share
did you share a window or a desktop yeah
i'll just share the whole
screen on the desktop the windows
sharing it's kind of like
i said yeah okay
good now
looks good yep okay
so the next talk i mean noah's giving
the next two talks and he asked us to
flip them around because one seems to
depend on the other a bit
so that's okay so this talk is going to
be a slide reduction revisited
filling the gaps in sap approximation by
division agarwal
go ahead noah great uh thanks for team
and also
uh i just want to thank um danielle and
tom for
organizing and really excellent
conference under uh unusual and
unfortunate circumstances
uh see i'm going to be talking to you
today about uh joint work with uh devest
gianwei and fong
um uh about slide reduction if you don't
know about slide reduction
i'll tell you a little bit about it it's
really quite a beautiful idea i can say
that it's not it's very much not due to
me
um so let me start out with the basics
let me just tell you what a lattice is
so a lattice is a discrete set of
vectors in
n-dimensional space looks like this in
two dimensions
um it's specified by a basis b1 through
bn of linearly independent vectors
uh so here's the basis for this lattice
and the lattice itself is the set of all
integer linear combinations of the basis
vectors we all know this but i'm getting
used to my notation
um and of course like sort of
one of the fundamental geometric
properties that we care about on the
lattice
is is this lambda one quantity so this
is the length of the shortest non-zero
vector
um so here's lambda one for this lattice
and the computational problem that i'm
interested in is svp uh so i want
to find a shortest non-zero vector in in
the lattice so here's a solution to svp
on this lattice
but i'm not interested in the exact
problem so much i'm more interested in
the approximate problem um so
uh for the approximate problem we have
some approximation factor gamma
uh that's larger than one and this tells
us like sort of how much larger than
lambda one
uh will uh will accept so for example
uh for gamma equals about two or
something at this point will be fine
um uh and of course this problem is
empty hard i'm not going to show you a
polynomial time
uh algorithm uh and one of the things
that i love about this problem is that
it's interesting for a
ridiculous range of approximation
factors uh from one to two to the n
um uh for crypto we're typically
interested in in gamma equals polyan
um uh and just to note that in this talk
i'm going to talk about provably correct
algorithm so i'm going to say
algorithms are better than other are the
best known but they're only the best
known if you want to prove their
correctness their heuristic algorithms
that are
uh that outperform these um
uh uh so the way that we solve
approximate svp
is actually kind of funny what we do is
we reduce
approximate svp to itself um but in
lower dimensions
um so we reduce gamma scp and n
dimensions to gamma s
the gamma prime scp and k dimensions um
where k is less than n that's what makes
this non-trivial and gamma prime is less
than gamma that's what makes this
sort of not a complete free launch um so
you all probably know the ll algorithm
ll is the special case of k equals two
um uh but this technique in general
gives us
our fastest algorithms uh for
approximate svp
uh for all gamma uh greater than or
equal to n
roughly um and the state of the art is
gammon when slide reduction
um so here's sort of a visual
representation of what happens with
relatively small so k is called the
block size this is what happens with
relatively small block size
um so uh what you can see here
is the running time or the constant in
the exponent of the running time
um and the the x-axis is uh
the log base n of the approximation
factor so the approximation factor is
n to the c and this is showing you c um
uh uh and you can see that this function
is essentially gamma to the n over k
with these weird jumps from a rounding a
rounding issue
um uh and i've drawn two lines here
because they're sort of two different uh
depending on which svp oracle you plug
in you get different results
so the formal the formal result that was
written down
prior as far as i know only had uh
reduced to exact svp oracle if you're
reduced to approximate svp oracle you
get better results
and we made this formal in our paper so
now it's written down which is
convenient
um but more importantly an issue with
this is that
uh there are jumps which is quite
obvious right so this is like a
piecewise flat
uh function and that's because of this
rounding in the approximation factor
um and these jumps happen because the
block size k
has to divide the dimension n um
uh and another issue is that there was
nothing non-trivial known
for gamma less than or equal to n so for
gamma less than or equal to n
um uh as far as we know uh
the problems just as as far as we knew
the problem was just as hard as
the exact problem or constant factor
approximate um
and this is kind of a bummer because
like cryptography really cares about
this regime
we care about like small polynomial
factors um
so our work uh made the graph look like
this
um that's what we did um so in
particular there are no jumps anymore
um so we can handle any block size um
uh the block slice doesn't need to
divide the dimension um
and we get the exact same approximation
factor except we don't have this ceiling
in the exponent
um so that's fine we also have an
entirely different reduction that works
in the regime where there are sort of
fewer than two blocks when the block
size is larger
than n over two um and this lets us get
non-trivial results below
n um uh we get this approximation factor
uh
n to the n over 2k in that regime um
and this seems kind of natural because
there's a real sort of natural barrier
uh that comes at square root n which is
which is the best that we can do
that's kind of because for the experts
that's because we apply minkowski's
theorem and sort of once you apply
minkowski's theorem
you spend a square root n um
uh so let me just show you in pictures
uh how our algorithm works i'm not going
to explain what these pictures mean
um but you can pretend your base is
upper triangular uh
and you can break your basis up into
blocks
um slide reduction breaks your basis up
into two different kinds of blocks blue
and red
uh that are that are represented here
they're svp reduced and dual suv reduced
and it gives you this sort of elegant a
little shifted slided thing
um we did this so we added a green and
orange block to the front
um and our green and orange blocks are
hsvp reduced so we do a weaker thing
to the first block which we make a
little bit bigger to account for the
fact that
we have some sort of extra dimensions
because k doesn't divide n
uh so that's what we do for a small
block size
uh for very large block size we we do
something else
um so that's that's what i wanted to say
thank you
okay thank you noah i guess you can get
your next slides ready
wait for questions okay
so again so far no questions yet and
maybe maybe i have one so you mentioned
that
this you know this exponent with the
minus one
seems like minor at first sight but you
mentioned that you know like uh
this corresponds to a pony effector that
we really care about in crypto
yeah um so so does this work have any
like direct implications for crypto or
like is it purely for understanding or
like
what's uh i mean yeah so
it only has direct application for
crypto if you require your adversary to
prove
uh that his algorithm works right if the
adversary doesn't have to prove that his
algorithm works you could just run
uh bkz which heuristically
achieves roughly the same approximation
factor or actually you can solve for
meet svp in almost all cases
in which case you can use your algorithm
um right
self dual bkz do you see any
applications where this could
you know in practice even uh
no but i mean part of that's just
because it's not implemented right it's
it's plausible that
uh it actually performs uh even better
in practice i have no idea
um i guess you guys did some experiments
with slide reduction at some point and
found that it
didn't perform incredibly well if i
remember currently
yeah but also not too bad not as bad as
was expected
i i remember but the idea i guess puts
it uh
nicely it says that it can give ideas
for better heuristic algorithms in some
sense so
but i would classify that under giving a
better understanding i guess
yeah and my thought is just like we want
to understand this as well as possible
because it's really important
okay fair enough cool thanks
okay thanks uh so here's noah again
giving a talk on lattice reduction for
models or how to reduce module svp to
module svp joint work with tamalika
mukerji
yeah so as vadim said this is this is
trying to work with tamaleka mukherjee
she's a a phd student at purdue um
and i'm told nobody finds our title to
be funny i thought how to reduce module
speech to module svp was a funny title
um but anyway so i'm going to repeat
what i did in the last
talk i'm going to do it slightly faster
and i made some minor changes which i
hope you'll sort of ignore
um but a lattice is the integer span of
finitely many vectors
rational vectors um so again here's a
lattice
and it's the integer span so it's some
integer times y1
plus some integer times y2 etc um
and again like the sort of geometric
property that we're interested in
is uh the length of the shortest vector
or the short vectors in the lattice
so again we're interested in solving svp
not exact svp but approximate svp
um and again this problem is interesting
for a really wide range of parameters
um but i'm not interested in solving
um for this talk i'm not interested in
solving svp on
any old lattice i'm interested in
solving stp
um on a very specific class of lattices
um a specific class of lattices with a
rather dense definition so they're
called module lattices so the formal
definition you start out with a number
field which is uh the polynomials over
over the rationals uh modulus and
irreducible polynomial
and you take a ring or formula it's
called an order um
which is a non-non-degenerate uh uh
sub ring of the uh ring of integers of
of your um number field um and then a
module lattice is the r span of finitely
many vectors
um uh uh in k to the k
um so uh before we had the z
span of rational vectors now we have the
r
span of um uh vectors that live
uh over this number field um
uh and k is itself an n-dimensional
vector space over q
so if we view k as uh q to the n via
some embedding
um then this is actually a lattice
you'll notice that's closed
under um uh addition which is all you
need
um so that means we can define things
like short vectors we can define lambda
one
um which is fun um and the
the number k which is sort of the
dimension of this number field i'm lying
slightly here
uh is is the rank of the module um and
that's sort of the key number that we
care about
um so that's the formal definition
intuitive definition is much simpler
a module lattice is uh it lives in q to
the k
n um and it's just some lattice that has
some linear symmetries
uh in particular you can so you can
apply a linear transformation to a
lattice vector and you'll get another
lattice vector back
um and the set of symmetries is exactly
uh this ring r
um unfortunately this definition uh has
a lot of problems but that's how you
should think of it they're just sort of
very pretty lattices
um that that are closed under
um that are very symmetric i guess um in
particular since module lattices are
lattices
we can ask about solving svp on them um
so we can define gamma module svp as the
problem gamma svp
restricted to to module lattices um and
of course
like this only makes sense if you like
specify which ring r you're talking
about and which embedding and
uh there's all this mess um
and it turns out that to break most
lattice crypto that's used in practice
it suffices to
uh solve gamma module svp in particular
if you want to uh
break all remaining um uh candidates for
the the nist competition lattice
candidates for the nist competition
uh module scp is enough um
so here's how we solve module svp
currently it's not very exciting
um we observe that gamma module svp
with a rank k module is a is an instance
of gamma svp in kn dimensions
uh that's just because this is a kn
dimensional lattice
um and then we apply lattice reduction
uh so in other words we just solve this
gamma svp the way we normally would
which is to reduce it to a lower
dimensional
um uh problem like like i discussed in
my previous talk
um and if we could do significantly
better than this
then a lot of crypto will be broken in
practice modulo
an asterisk here which is like hiding a
tremendous amount and
uh uh read the paper and the citations
therein to to learn the current state of
the art
um so that's scary so there's this fear
that maybe modules are special and if
modules are special
then a lot of our crypto would not be as
secure as we think it is
um uh and you might previously have
conjectured
um that it's just as hard to solve uh
svpn modules as it is to solve it in s
on uh generic lattices but that's
actually not true
in the rank one case so in the rank one
case uh modules are called ideals um
and there is a now a long line of work
quite recent work
uh showing uh that there are faster
algorithms
um for ideal svp uh with even more
asterisks
um uh and this
this doesn't directly bake crypto
because for crypto
actually we care about higher rank
modules um it also doesn't break it for
other reasons which is why there are
many asterisks but morally
there's sort of this boundary if we want
to break crypto
we need to go from rank 1 to higher rank
um so here's a sort of natural approach
to try to
solve module svp instead of
reducing module spp to svp and then
reducing svp to itself
why don't we just reduce module svp to
itself so why don't we reduce module svp
with rank k it's a module stp with rank
beta for a beta less than k
and this would be something like lattice
reduction or basis reduction for modules
um and of course this uh this diagram
sort of commutes
um uh so this would be like a strict
improvement if we could do this
at least if all the numbers were the
same
um and of course if we could do this for
beta equals one we'd
more or less break a lot of crypto up to
many asterisks
um and uh in a recent beautiful work lee
pellet mary stella and wallet
um showed that this does work for beta
equals two
so beta equals one break breaks crypto
they pull it off for beta equals two
um uh maybe i can uh
uh leave you in a little bit of suspense
i can say oh what are we gonna do are we
gonna get beta equals one
uh the answer no uh we get beta greater
than or equal to two
um uh so we show that uh uh you can sort
of trade off rank and approximation
factor however you want as long as
uh you stay above rank one um and you
can think of this as
uh so we use slide reduction techniques
like the techniques i discussed in the
previous talk
and you can think of um our work as sort
of
generalizing lpsw in the same way that
slide reduction generates
uh generalizes lll um so this is the
current picture
um uh
and the moral is that a module scp
oracle is just as good as an svp oracle
for solving a module svp um
uh and of course the big question here
is does this mean so there are two ways
to interpret a reduction
should i think of this as meaning that
high rank module scp is easy which would
be bad for crypto or that low rank
module scp is hard for beta greater than
one
in particular is there's this huge gap
between beta equals one and b
equals two uh or not um and here's my
answer to that question
uh i have no idea i think we should
study it more uh thanks i think i went
significantly over time
uh thank you noah um are there any
questions michael not that i could see
any
no maybe i can ask one um
so i mean you put a lot of uh you know
asterisks
there but uh on the on the last slide
where you use
when you put almost in parentheses
um is it is it is the paper
stronger than the other i mean how
almost is oh uh
so you use a small polynomial factor
well for parameter
natural parameters you use a small
polynomial factor in the
um uh approximation factor
um polynomial in the rank or polynomial
in the dimension
in the dimension yeah yeah yeah so you
lose like a factor
of like square root n to the um
a over um something like this
okay okay the question did come up on
sunday
by rohit chattery um
and i'm gonna cite this uh can you
briefly explain the reductions depending
dependence on the underlying ring
yeah um so
we worked really really hard we actually
just updated the paper said it works for
um uh arbitrary orders uh which is
pretty fun
um the geometry of the ring affects the
approximation factor
um and i think sort of the the high
order effect
of the geometry of the ring is uh so
it's like well known that minkowski's
theorem is tight up to a factor square
root n for example in cyclotomics
um uh and that factor of square root n
more generally so like the sort of
how loose minkowski's theorem can be uh
there's probably a better a name for
this uh parameter but i'm not thinking
of it right now
um but how loose minkowski's theorem can
be affects your approximation factor
um so if you take like a really really
wonky
um uh ring then you'll get a bad
approximation factor although the
reduction still
still does formally work
okay and uh another question by the same
auth by the same same person uh again
would your dense module reduction
technique also imply something
non-trivial if translated to the usual
letter setting
uh so i think the answer is yes so
you can think of what we're doing as
sort of instead of working with vectors
we work with sub lattices
um and you know we work really hard to
make the
sub lattices modules but if you don't
care about that i think it still makes
sense to think about
a more general form of lattice reduction
in which
instead of looking for short vectors
you're looking for dense sub lattices
i think this is this is what the
question's getting at um and i think our
techniques just sort of immediately work
for that
uh i'm not uh we kind of mentioned that
in paper
but i'm not sure how interesting it is
maybe maybe i didn't answer the question
i'm not sure
okay do we have time for more questions
for him
uh yeah go ahead okay so leo is asking
if there's any hope to eliminate the cn
assumption on the number field
the the what assumption on the number
field oh that's gone
uh so yes there is hope um actually
for this we we we stole uh uh we
we used ideas from lpsw and lpsw they
work with
uh k sub r um and if you do that
k tensored with r and if you do that
properly uh uh you can get any number
field
so yes okay
and then there is another question by
daniel where i'm not entirely sure of it
no it does concerns this
this paper so i'm just going to read it
out um in the spirit of getting rid of
these piecewise drums
is there an interesting way to define a
reasonable form of mutual rbe
that somehow in between rank 1 and rank
2 where you could get non-tribal attacks
meaning
attacks that look more like the rank 1
attacks and the rank 2
plus attacks uh i mean
i think that falls into the general
category of trying to figure out how to
port these
ideal svp algorithms to module scp for
rank two
uh which i think like we're all kind of
thinking about at least a little bit
uh uh if if if i had an idea there i'd
be very happy
or kind of sad actually but yeah that's
that's like a heart problem
okay cool i think uh
this covers all of the questions so far
great thank you so much so maybe tamar
can get
your slides up uh oh yeah
yeah can you see my screen
hello no we can see you ah okay
[Music]
okay wait uh maybe just let me and we
don't
maybe while tomorrow is setting up noah
what is the c or leo what is the cm
assumption
complex multiplication yeah it's it's
it's that the
um the number field is a complex
multiplication field
uh it uh it basically means that the
number field is closed under
conjugation um in a in a very specific
way
so what's what's the um reveal of this
knot for example
uh so like cube root of two so
qx mod uh x q minus two is not right
okay so these are all
real no no so it has a it has a complex
and it has these two complex embeddings
but you sort of can't get to one from
the other
great okay
thanks
okay i think tomorrow's ready now yeah
it's working
yeah sorry sorry to reboot everything
very good
uh okay so now the next talk is uh by
uh thomas
[Music]
on fast reduction of algebraic lattices
and i will give the talk
so thank you for the introduction so
yeah so basically in this talk i'm going
to present some
results on this time not proof but
heuristic results uh on the reduction of
algebraic lattice
and on the difference of uh the talk we
we've just we've just saw by noaa
uh we were not really interested in uh
having theoretical
results relying on using sap records but
we wanted to have
um unconditional uh reduction uh
so that we could implement implement it
and and and do some tests
so sorry yeah so just very quick recall
on the snl because like everyone has
done them
uh just before so um
recall that the lattice is a discrete
sub groove for your player in space
let's say r2cn
and another way of defining that maybe
which is more algebraic is to say that
it's a freezy module
of finance rank which is endowed with
some inner product on
the ambient space and on lattices we
have this beautiful minkowski theorem
for the first minima which has said that
if i give you a lattice there exists
necessarily a vector of a short norm
so which means which is that up to
square root of the dimension
close to the normalized volume okay
so as you all know finding this
kind of short vector is a hard problem
and we're all interested in in solving
that however in
82 the inference from novatch exhibits
that a polynomial time algorithm which
solves this uh search of a short vector
up to exponential approximation factor
and this has like numerous application
uh in
uh numbers here in like algebraic
algebraic number theory
difference approximation of course
cryptanalysis and uh
of course in lattice-based crypto and
it's nowadays also
uh like kind of basic building blocks
of any uh algorithm in computational
algebraic number theory because it helps
somehow to
control the size of the elements
appearing there so ll is like
everywhere and now we are getting
interested more and more
uh into a broader class of lattices
called algebraic lattice
and this lattices lives in uh over
number fields which are finite extension
of q
and which you can realize this uh this
extension as
a polynomial quotient of q x over uh
over some hydrogenated bipolar and
inside this field you have a very
interesting ring which is the ring of
integers which is a set of elements
which vanish under the action of
some monique polynomial in the x so
over q it's just the integers itself and
you could think of somehow these ring of
intentions as a
higher order generalization of the
integers
so why it's related to lattices so as i
said we could uh
thought of lattices as 3d module uh and
all with some inner products
and as i said we can generate z to be
this ring of integers so we can generate
lattices to say that an algebraic
lattice is an oil module
uh angled with some inner product on the
ambient space
okay so you could ask what is the inner
product and
you can find some canonical way of
defining it using the embeddings into cn
i'm not entering two tests here
uh but what should be uh like the motto
of all of this is that
an algebraic lattice is a lattice with
some additional algebraic structure
and this algebraic structure translates
metrically into symmetries
okay and now how we do lattice reduction
on that
so just to to set up a bit of context
like a noah spoke about like idealities
and modularities which are kind of
particular cases of this algebraic
lattices
and like if we could exploit these
additional symmetries and
uh i mean sorry exploiting this
additional symmetry has been already
used
uh but on the constructive side to uh
to exhibit more compact and more
efficient cryptographic primitives
and many lattice-based candidates of the
next competition are actually
relying heavily on this module lattices
and uh we would like to reduce them for
instance from a cryptographical
perspective just to evaluate the
security of these nist
candidates so our goal would be to find
a way to use the algebraic structure
to give a faster lll type reduction
so how we can do that
is that for free when you are
considering this algebraic lattices you
can have
for suitable fields a natural recursive
regulation structure of subfield the
torah subfield and
we showed that we could explore this
recursive uh tower
uh translate it into a recursive
strategy uh
which at each step uh we'll do we'll use
the symmetries to do lattice reduction
and
another thing that we used there was to
exhibit some part of the unit group and
use them
in some specific way to control the size
of the elements which occurred during
the reduction somehow it's very
related to the condition number of the
matrices appearing during computation so
if you are able to use the unit group to
control the size the
condition number of the matrices you are
using basically you can reduce the
precision
required to do a reduction so
just to show you how the reduction is
working on a very high level
if you want to reduce rank and lattice
you will do basically the same as you
would do in ll
so you will start by transforming
everything into triangular matrices by
qr decomposition and then you will
feed that to your size reduction sub
procedures which is a simple procedure
used to
as a name indicates to shrink the size
of the vector
without not touching the order of
difficulty basis and this is where we
need
this unit rounding procedure
and the rest is just working coefficient
wise because we're working with
modular query numbers and then we do
exactly as in
ll we reduce the problem to
solving the same instance but on
multiple rank two projected sub-lattices
so if we are working over q itself over
z basically we can
uh just uh use gauss algorithm or a bit
faster seanage algorithm and we don't
but if we're not what we're going to do
is to descend this wrong two lattice
to the subfield just under where the uh
of course
the rank of the new sublet of the new
lattice is bigger
but then we can recursively apply the
wall procedure
and once our algorithms say okay my
wrong two sub lattice is reduced what i
need to do is to lift the results to the
upper field
and this is done in the same with a
generic
euclidean algorithm which is generalized
to work in
numbers uh okay
and uh we can even do a bit of
optimization
on this and all of this qr decomposition
plus size reduction
can be done with only half of the
required computation using
uh some additional um structure which
comes from the
sympathetic symmetries that we can
construct so we just say word of that
at the end um so
if we analyze that in a heuristic way
because they are relying on some using
the size of the elements of link
everywhere
basically you can prove that on
cycloatomic fields if you want to reduce
a wrong tool like this
we can do that in times o soft of n
square b
b being the size of the bit size of the
of the input
and if you use the state-of-the-art lll
directly
on the corresponding lattice it will
require something in all sort of n
fourth so you gain a factor which is of
the order of n squared
but there is a slight drawback is that
now the approximation factor is not 2 to
the n like ll but it is two to the
uh softer of n so it's way faster but
it's
you get vectors are slightly bigger uh
and i said that you could do uh even
better using simplex symmetry so this is
kind of a generalization algebraic
generalization of the work of
gamma gargame and green in o6
so the basic idea is that if you take a
wrong two lattice just a plain lattice
um then it is naturally simplified this
means that you have
some action of the simplified group on
it and
the same is absolutely true for
algebraic lattices of wrong two so
you can find a natural way a canonical
way of
having additional symmetries
and what we proved is that we can do
that at
each of the recursive level so we can
create synthetic symmetries at each of
the
uh of the nodes of the recursion tree so
that means that we
can have the computation of the computer
in time
at each node of the recursion tree so
since the
tower of recursion is something
logarithmic in the
dimension you can get a polynomial again
so if we look at the improved complexity
in this case if i retake the example of
psychoatomic fields basically we can uh
we can do some radiation
sorry oh let me see last slide it's a
less like okay we can do so we can find
we can reduce a lattice in time
n square minus a little something which
depends on
the field you are considering so we even
beat this n square b bound
using this additional symmetries and of
course we still have an approximation
factor which is slightly worse
than before and uh in practice
uh we implemented all of that uh and we
were able to reduce like ggs like
lattices in four days where
our estimation for state of the art
would be uh for
forty thousand years and we were able to
run for the first time getting three
algorithms in dimension 1024 in
100 hours where fpl would take 10 years
so if you have questions please ask me
i'd be very happy to answer them thank
you for your attention
thanks are there any questions on the
boards michael
yeah there's one um he was asking
stuff you could set up your uh your
slides while
we're asking questions so we can have
more time for questions for you as well
yeah okay
now ready for the question okay so leo
is asking is an approximation factor of
you
which ll like algorithm relevant to the
cryptanalysis of simple encryption
signature schemes such as in this
candidate
uh no no no the approximation are too
too too large for the momentum because
it's the ll type so
what you need to do secret analysis of
like signature whatever
is uh approximation factor which can
only achieve with
the easy type algorithm so for the
moment it's really
in the realm of failure so
so like exponential approximation factor
in polynomial achieved in personal time
so
for this candidate is it's for the
moment too large
for fpg you can do stuff but for for
later it's for
nice candidates you really need way way
uh stronger reduction
okay good thanks
okay so um the next last talk of the
session
is rowdy names by feng hao liu and
jedong wang and jadon will give the talk
okay all right so hello everyone i'm
jordan i will talk about wrongly in the
rings
uh this is joint work with fungal leo
and this work focuses on determining the
harness of l
over rings okay so let me
start with the definition of uh learning
with running over rings
which was firstly proposed by bernard
piher and rose
in trinidad uh the ring rbr is defined
with parameters p
q and zeroing r uh the third problem is
to find secret
secretness from a given symbols as a b
where a is a random element in r sub q
and a b equals to the range of a times
s the running of an element x with
respect to p
and q is defined as the ranking of p
over q times
x the mod p okay so the decision problem
is to distinguish
the pair of av from uniform random pair
green otherwise has many crypto
applications such as pseudorandom
functions computational reusability
structure
those travel functions and more so it is
important
to determine the harness of this problem
i summarize prior harness results of
playing lwr
and ring out there by the falling
figures more precisely we consider the
hardest of these problems
in two cases which is super poorly
modulus and
with poly modulus
for planar for playing other player the
harness results are more complete
however in the ring setting results are
limited
besides the basic reduction line of ring
rb from prior works
we can also show reductions of ringer
with suprapoli modulus
by the work of bpr2 and we can also show
a reduction from search bring rb to
a search ring availability.org of uh
bogdanov gold messily richardson and
rosen in
2016 but there are two main open
questions in the ring setting compared
with playing other players
on the one hand we don't know the
pseudo-randomness of ringer
which is poorly modulus on the other
hand
um the harness of a ringer or mojo
edward
which leaky secret is to be determined
uh finally uh at least to point out that
a superpoli
modulus suffers worse efficiency and a
weaker security compared with poly
modulus
so it is important to determine the
highest results
of foreign modular
and our work exactly answers uh the two
questions
okay so let me just state our results
we first introduced a new framework of
algebraic lwr
in this framework we consider a random
procedure wrongly according basis
which is more flexible than original
ranking
according coefficient batting we also
define a framework
called the legislature which is inspired
by the work of piker and pepin in 2019
and it encompasses various algebraically
structured errors such as
ringer order poli mojo edible and more
an issue that harness of ringer implies
harness of
others so from this we can focus on the
harness of ringer
then we show a reduction from search to
decision ring other with poly modulus
finally we show that the heart we showed
the harness of ring and mojo at
under leakage for ringer we proposed an
attack for it
under certain leaky scenario and this
idea is similar to that of
blockers to that the work of
broadcasting at all
and for mojo a ratio reduction from
decision wringer b
to decision module ring out even with
leakage
okay let's already introduce our main
techniques so let me
sketch those to the render mixture of
ring as well the target
is to show the reduction from search
bring up to
a decision ring out the bra at high
level uh fighting the secret s is
equivalent to fighting coefficients of s
under bases and our technicals
are similar to that of lpr10
uh we choose the randomness of a ring at
least
and our reduction path is that as
follows a step one shows if
a search ring otherwise hard the
immediate search problem pi ring at the
back is also hard
where the pi is uh the prime idea
and step two issues a reduction from pi
ring otherwise to an immediate worst
case decision problem
during other supply and step three
issues
the reduction from the ring i'll bring
other cluster by to the error keys
problem
decision ring as well step two and three
are similar to
lpr term the key observation is
in step one uh we require the uh
automotive systems
or galway group somehow communicate uh
with ranking
uh relate related to certain basis
and we find uh ranking with respect to
the so-called lawmaker basis is what we
need
we know that uh the widely used segment
ring with power of two degree
is with no non non-integral basis but we
can start define
a running procedure to achieve this
and we also remarked that leo duca also
provides some insightful requirements
for choosing basis
so it is very interesting to determine
more business
satisfying our requirements for mojo
with leaky secret we generate the
uh the work of uh oil and cream pizza
and week's
approach to the arena set which shows a
reduction for planet earth
with leakage similar to akpw
we can define the lossy simpler over
rings and
the computational indistinguishability
of step one relates on the ring of
reassuration
another uh running of atl time death
preserves
a love interview of s if the work
dimension k is large
but the main barrier is that there is
low ring leftover dilemma
for general ring of integers
uh we finally get rid of this battery by
showing a ring level overhammer here
the statement of our lemma is a little
involved
here we can apply it to concrete cases
from our lemma we know that for a
general ring of integers
uh the statistical distance between the
pair of ring vector a
the inner product of a small qr and the
random pair is bounded by website
whereas the secrets mod any ideal factor
q has elapsed entropy and the fourth
segment atomic ring the entropy
requirement of s can be weakened and if
we consider the
ideal qr with large ideal factor
the entropy of s molecule can be smaller
okay thank you
thank you
are there any questions we have maybe
time for a few
or uh not right now
um not yet okay
so it works
but i don't know if you think that some
of the earlier questions are worth going
back to if uh
well there's now a question um
two actually um one by yangyuu
is asking does your reduction give an
attack to search
uh rlwr in which q is not a multiple of
p yes
yeah exactly
okay that should answer the question i
think
uh very straightforward uh rachel player
is asking does a
search to decision reduction for ring or
wr apply for parameter settings of
practical interest
such as p and q both powers of two
uh p and q will be power of two
yeah both the powers of two that's a
decision reduction
um you know applied to it yeah yeah yes
we can
we can uh we can also define the ranking
we
no no no no p q be the power to we
consider the
uh that the ring dimension m is p
uh the power of uh power power of two
and uh in this case um in this case the
second omega is which is
low uh normally integral basis but we
can uh
we can define the ranking uh to this
case
uh another uh we need
uh there some tricky uh we we need to
define the wrong
with respect to the absolute value
um okay
okay yeah so if there are any more
questions i encourage the authors to
head over to zulip and
uh answer them or answer them in more
detail if they want to
um also for the earlier question on the
first uh talk it has been addressed
on zulip by by one of the authors so
i think we can call it a day
yeah yep so thanks everybody no not the
day there is another session