this talk is about security analysis of
counter diabetes a national standard
of random number generator i'm vietng
one
and its short work with javin sheng
as i mentioned earlier counter diabetes
is a
random number generator or ing for short
synthetically an rng is a stable
algorithm
that keeps refreshing state via inputs
of
high-min entropy and provides
pseudo-random outputs
upon request the int that we'll discuss
today is
counter dipg which is the most
popular standardized ing it has been
used in numerous cryptographic libraries
and operating systems such as open ssl
or windows 10 the security of these
systems
crucially depends on counter diabetes
despite the importance of kata drpg
for a long time there have been very few
papers on
analyzing this scheme these limited
analysis
however considered just some simplified
component
of cut eibg and therefore
cannot support security claims in these
documents in 2019
woulda and schumann point out that some
options
in the openly flexible specification
of counter diabetes might be exploitable
shortly after that theoretical
observation
is confirmed by the work of karni at all
the latter gives a scientific attack
on reward implementation of kata drbg
the lessons learned from these two
papers are
first you should deprecate in-secure
options
in kata diabetes next if you are
a developer you should be mindful of
misusing such as
using leaky table based ies
or failure to replace the state
periodically
or using low entropy input
still that remains a big question that
is
if we adopt all of these recommendations
is counter reality secure
our gives an affirmative answer for this
question
before we get into the technical details
let's define what we mean by
security our target is the robust
notion of notice at all which is a
standard guru of
ings informally
an ing should still provide security
either in the face of
state compromise or adversarial
input in particular we will consider a
pair of adversaries
a and d the sampler d would generate
the inputs the address a
would try to compromise the state
and also distinguish the outputs
with truly random strings
if the ing is based on an ideal
primitive pi
we will give a oracle access to pi
the sampler d however doesn't have
access to pi
in other words the img
has a huge seat namely the encoding
of the ideal primitive by
in addition to phi the atmosphere is
also given other oracles
for example it can get the state of the
rng
or it can set the state of the energy to
evaluate lies
or it can force the energy to repress
the state
the adversary however doesn't control
the random inputs
finally adversary a is also given a real
random oracle that provides either the
real
outputs of the ing or random strings of
the same length
this oracle however will provide real
outputs if not enough mean
entropy is supplied from a last step
compromise
we define the advantage of the
adversaries a and d
as a normalized probability that a can
guess correctly
whether it receives real outputs of the
energy
or the random strings
let me now give you a birth eye view of
counter diabg
this construction is based on a
randomness extractor
that will go condensed then encrypt or
cte counter diabetes consists of three
algorithm
one to derive the initial state the
other one
to refresh the state and yet another one
to generate outputs
the state of counter the rpg consists of
a key k
and an ibv for aes
for example if you want to derive the
initial state
from an input i will apply
cte on i will then
use counter mode under a 0
key and a 0 iv to encrypt the extracted
string
the resulting cell tags will then be
passed into
k and v accordingly
if you want to generate an output
we'll use the dragata mode to give a
zero string
under the key k and ivv
from the stack the resulting
output would be passed into an output r
and unabated state k and b accordingly
our result vows the robotic advantage of
character dibg
via two terms the first term measures
pseudorandomness quality of outputs
produced by catamount
the second term measures how well we
extract randomness from cte
here's outbound for the pseudorandomness
quality of
outputs produced by cut mode in
particular
because we'll use counter on many keys
so the first term bounce the multi-user
via
advantage of card mode and the second
term bows the advantage of
guessing one of the q counter keys
via atmos q attempts
to bow the quality of extracting
randomness from cte
we will use the generalized left over
hash lemma
from barack at all in particular
if a granular input has lambda base of
conditional mean entropy
given other inputs we recommend that
lambda to be at least 216.
for the rest of the talk i will
elaborate more on randomness extraction
in culture divg namely the cte
construction
so this fixture is a blueprint of cte
in particular given an input i you add
some prefix
free encoding and a padding
it then iterate through cbc mark up to
three times
with different constant ivs
the resulting cell that is then passed
into a key
and an iv of ies we will use this key in
iv to encrypt a zero string
under the cvc mode and the
cell deck is the extracted output string
as mentioned earlier cte
is based on cbc map as a building block
conventionally cbc map uses the zero iv
but in cte the iv is nonzero
a classical guide for using cbc map
as a randomness extractor comes from the
work of notice at
all in particular if you want to see the
random outputs
egg issues should have high conditional
mean entropy
given the bus inputs
this recommendation is however violated
in cte
in particular cta uses cpc mark
on essentially the same input multiple
times
this is one of the biggest challenges in
analyzing security of cpe
as a randomized extractor
to get around this obstacle we realize
that the output of cte
will be used to derive a key k and an
iv v for the countable
therefore if we model a s
as an ideal cipher these outputs
only need to be unpredictable instead of
being
pseudorandom as a result
we can circumvest the requirements in a
classic work of notice at
all as an added plus
because we only need the outputs of cpe
to be merely unpredictable
we can reduce the mean entropy
requirements
from 280 bits to 216 bits
before we analyze the unpredictability
of
city outputs let's define an
unbreakability notion
for key hash function h
in this game we first sample a
random input i of land with submin
entropy
we then generate a key k uniformly at
random
independent i we then
hash i under the key k to produce an
output z we then define the guessing
advantage
of an average a against h by acuras
as the probability that a can get z
via q gases
analyzing the unpredictability of cte is
rather tricky
let's begin with an intuitive approach
in particular we will first show that
cpc mac is an
almost universal au hash function
that is if we pick two distinct strings
x and y
and sample a uniformly random
permutation by
and then if we has x and y under cbc
mach or pi then this is unlikely to
result in a collision
next we will employ the generalized
leftover hash level of product at all
which essentially says that any good au
hash function is also a good journalist
extractor
for unpredictability applications
as i mentioned earlier we want the
collision
probability of cbc multiple is small
but how small is enough
if we use the classic analysis in the
work of notice at all
it gives a good collision bound but only
for
x and y of the same length
if we use this analysis in the context
of cte
it means that we are effectively
assuming that
the letter x random input is linked to
the adversary
a before it makes guesses
because the length is a part of the
entropy of inputs
so it means that we are wasting entropy
of random inputs
and it is undesirable
alternatively we can use the analysis in
the world of
molari bisect and runaway r
cha and nandi these analysis
can handle arbitrary x and y
but the resulting bug is inferior for
our purpose
let's now try to find a different way to
give an
unpredictability bio for cte
as shown in this picture the output of
cte
is the civil text of cbc encryption
in order to predict this civil tax one
is to guess
both the key and the iv of cbc
in our fair attempt we only require the
adversary to predict the key
and as a result the bow is poor
we now can have a better bow if we
require adversary
to get both the key and iv of cbc
realizing this observation translates to
a
multi-collision property of cvc mark
in particular we need to show that if we
pick two distinct
strings x and y and then sample
a random permutation pi
then if we hash x and y
under cbc map of pi with
different ivs 0 and iv1
then the chance that we have a double
collision is small
in our work we can show that the chance
of this
multicollision is at most 64
l cubed over 2 to the 256
where l is the maximum block length of
x and y
this multi-collision property then
implies that it is hard to predict both
the key
and iv of cbc encryption inside cte
as a result cte is a good and you hash
function
we can prove that without squandering
entropy of random inputs
finally we will employ the share lines
left over hash lemma
to show that city is a good journalist
extractor for
unbreakability applications
it is the vow for the guesting advantage
of an adversary
against cte for q guesses
in conclusion our work shows that if you
adopt the recommendations
in the work of buddha and shumau and
connie at all
that counter diabetes is robust
moreover our also sheds some light
in the design of counter drbg in
particular
this construction looks quite cumbersome
at first
however underneath that it contains very
neat design ideas
for getting around the limitation of
using cbc map
to extract randomness