hello everyone welcome to my crypto 2020
virtual talk
i hope everyone is safe so in this talk
i will present
universally composable relaxed password
authenticate exchange
and this is short work with michelle
abdullah
manuel babosa tatiana bradley sunny
suave yarosky
and jonathan cass and we also have two
guest stars here
so this is ida loveless and this is
charles fabric
replacing allison ball so these were
joined by my co-author tatiana and
tatiana also contributed a lot to the
slides in general
okay so let me first introduce the
concept of password authenticated key
exchange or paid
so this is a two-party protocol and the
goal is to establish a shared
cryptographic key
in the server password-only setting
which means that the only information
shared by the two-party scenarios
is a low entropy password so as you can
see here
either inputs a password her password pw
and channels enters his password p
double prime
and at the end of the interaction if
their passwords mesh
then they will output the same key and
otherwise if their passwords don't match
then they will output
independent keys
so here's a very brief overview of
previous constructions of take protocols
so there have been two major paradigms
the first one is to take the fulfillment
key exchange and then you somehow
blind the protocol messages using the
password
and this line of research started from
the groundwater
work by battling at merit in
1992 called encrypted tea exchange
or eke and since then there has
there have been many subsequent works uh
in this paradigm
and the most efficient tech protocols
fall into this
category but on the other hand they
require
their security analysis requires an
idealized model
such as the random oracle model
and another another paradigm is to use
encryption plus
most projective hash function and this
usually allows the pipe protocol to be
proven secure in the standard model so
you usually still need a common
reference string but no random oracle is
needed
but the cost is that they are usually
less efficient
for for a very long time there has been
really no adoption of pike in practice
but very recently from last year to this
year
the ietf the inter internet in
engineering task force has two
competitions
on page one on pike and one on
an extension called asymmetric pegs and
this sparked
much interest in the in the practical
aspects of pig
perhaps we will see paid implementations
used in in the in real life
say on the internet in in some years
this work is about the security models
of fake
so again for pike security models there
are also two prominent
paradigms one is the game-based model
and the other is the
universally composable or uc model so
you'll see as long as i'm getting based
in general because uc allows for
arbitrary protocol composition but
in particular for pike you'll see also
has some additional advantages
such as modeling password reuse which
means that
a user can use the same password for
multiple accounts
and this is simply not covered by the
game-based definition
so for these reasons uc has been built
as a
gold standard for pike security analysis
and indeed since uc allows for arbitrary
protocol composition
there are some previous results showing
that a uc pipe
can be composed to get some extensions
such as
a symmetric plate and an even stronger
variant called
strong asymmetric plate
unfortunately the most efficient pipe
particles
are proven secure in the playing base
setting only
and not in the uc setting but on the
other hand
there has also been no explicit attack
shown for any of them
so a very natural question is is there
really a gap
between these efficient plate protocols
and the ucpa model
and this is this is it needs a
motivation of our work
and our work is exactly to fill this gap
so we propose two relaxations of the
standard peg functionality
one is called the lazy extraction type
or le peg and this is the main one we
use
and the other is a slightly stronger
variant called relaxed ucp
or rpac and then we show that
all of these aspects to tb peak
speak and see place so all of these
efficient opaque
particles which were proven secure in
the game-based setting only previously
all of these actually realize you'll see
a laser extraction plate in the random
oracle model
so in other words we show that
they are actually uc sql as long as
you are willing to slightly relax the uc
functionality itself
and third we show that standard key
confirmation
converts a laser extraction plate
for the stronger relaxed fake
and finally we also do a sanity check
that
any uc relaxed plate is
game based secure with the so-called
perfect forward secrecy property
so even if the pike functionality is
relaxed
it still implies the basic gain-based
security
so our key observation is as this
um in a in an active attack the standard
use effect functionality
requires the simulator to extract the
password to extract the adversary's
password
before the session completes so that is
before the
attack party outputs a key
so if we take a look at the standard ucp
functionality so here this picture is
directly copied and pasted from the
already original paper
which part which proposed the standard
ucpeg functionality
so as you can see here the test password
query
corresponds to the simulator extracting
the password
the adversary's password and this
query will be ignored by the
functionality
unless the protocol session is
fresh and it is fresh only before the
session completes
so again this sun and oc functionality
requires that the extraction of the
password
must happen before the session completes
so now we can take an example and see
why this aspect tool protocol does not
seem to realize the standard of play
functionality
so this is a one-round protocol and the
only messages sent during a session
are the group elements x and y
and if you if you look at how x and y
are computed there are petersen
commitments
of the password which
means that the password is information
theoretically hidden
and there's simply no hope to extract
the password
during the online session however
after those online messages
access my assigned if the adversary
wants to get say either key then it
needs to make a random oracle query at
the end
which can't be seen by the simulator
so maybe the simulator
can't extract the password after the
online
session completes so to summarize
the simulator cannot extract the
password during an online session
and that is why aspect 2 doesn't seem to
realize the standard uc
functionality but there's still some
hope
that the password can be extracted
afterwards
and indeed this is exactly the idea
of our relaxation of the uc pick
functionality
that is to allow the post execution
password extraction
so even after all protocol messages are
sent
either honest party already computes its
key
the simulator can still extract the
password by observing the adversary's
local computation
such as random oracle queries
and as in the standard ucpeg
functionality we require that
for obsession only a single password can
be tested
but the difference is that the
difference with the startup
functionality is that here the possible
test
can be done either during the session or
after the session
completes and what will happen
in a late password test so we recall
that we have
two relaxations so in this
lazy extraction type functionality the
ideal adversary
there's a certain key which is real if
the late password test is real
so if the late password test is correct
and otherwise it is random in the
stronger
relaxed spike functionality the ideal
adversary only learns
whether the latest password test is
correct or not
as you can see relax like is indeed
stronger because the adversary learns
less information
so here's the details of our relaxations
of the ucpek functionality
so first of all if that virtual wants to
do a late password test then it needs to
register
register the late password test during
the session
and secondly the late test
in a late test password query which
reflects
the post execution password extra
extraction
the ideal adversary may learn a key fear
as in laser extraction pipe or learn a
bit
whether the last password test is
correct or not
as in relax
so now we can look a little bit closer
on how exactly the simulator can extract
the password
post execution in say aspect tool so we
prove that
aspect 2 you'll see realizes the laser
extraction pack functionality in the
random oracle model
under the gap development assumption and
we stress that the reduction here is
tight
so now let's say that charles
is the adversary and either needs to be
simulated
so first of all there are two random
group elements
in the common reference string m and n
and because it is the simulator who says
the crs
of course the simulator can know the
discrete log of m and n
and secondly the simulator
also needs to simulate the protocol
message
of ada which is the group element x so
recall that x
is the peterson commitment of address
password
so at this point the simulator doesn't
know it is password
and on this x
is a random group element so what the
simulator will do
is to just sample group element
uniformly and again
the simulator knows the squid log of x
so now the simulator has three trebles
the discrete logs of m n
and x
if the adversary wants to
learn the the session key of ada
then it needs to make a random oracle
query
here because this is how ada's
either certainty is computed
so now
in particular the input of the
random oracle contains the password
and also a group element here and here
so aspect 2 is designed in such a way
that there's a relation between
these two the password and the group
element
such that a correct
ro query always
in the correct arrow query will
always satisfy certain relation
and this relation can be checked
given all these three chapters so what
does this mean
this means that when trials when this
adversary queries the random oracle
the simulator can check if the query is
correct
says that is if the query corresponds to
a password test
and if this is the case since the
simulator can't extract the password
guess
so why does it only realize
the lazy extraction pack functionality
so this is because
the simulator after extracting the
aider's password it needs to prove
it really needs to learn the key from
the functionality
in order to program the random oracle
so why what why do we need gap determine
here
recall that the laser extraction peg
functionality only allows a single
password test procession
so this means that if channels
makes two run random oracle queries
for the same session and both of them
are correct since the simulator would
get stuck
because it doesn't know which password
should be sent to the to the
functionality but we can show that this
essentially means that the adversary
channels solves computational
development
on the on the crs group elements mn
so in the reduction to ch
the reduction doesn't know the chapters
for mnn
and to get around it needs a dna a
decisional development oracle
and that is why a gap wiser gap
development assumption is needed
okay our second result is about
adding explicit mutual authentication
recall that in a normal place in a plate
with the so-called
implicit authentication if the two
parties passwords don't match
since they will offer independent keys
but here the difference is that
if the passwords don't match since the
parties were just abort
so we show the results that you'll see
lazy extraction pack plus standard key
confirmation
use a stronger you'll see relax break
with explicit authentication
so how is the key conformation done
so you just use the laser extraction
pick
output small k here
and you derive an authenticator called
storage
here and then you'll exchange the
authenticators
and after you receive the awesome
authenticator from the counterparty
you'll check if it is correct
and if it is not correct then you're
aboard
so now let's see on a very high level
why
why the theorem holds so this is because
um if the adversary
doesn't do a test do a password test
on the correct password then the
adversary cannot
simply cannot come up with a correct
authenticator
and since the lazy extraction
key since this key is hidden
the the adverse is
the honest party will just abort
in other words in other words if says if
the honest party doesn't abort
since the adversary must do a correct
password guess
yes which allows the simulator to
extract the password
and unlike aspect 2 here the simulator
doesn't really need a key to program the
random oracle
learning whether the password test is
correct or not
is sufficient for computing the final
certainty
so we get a we did an
arc which is slightly stronger than our
e-paper
and there are there are some properties
here which prevents this to realize the
standard page
uh center pick functionality so wrongly
speaking this is because the adversary
can make a
late date password test even after a
session aboard
furthermore we also do a sanity check
here involving
a game-based game-based paid security
notion on
the property of prophet's perfect
forward secrecy or pfs
so recall that prophet forward secrecy
means that
when after a party corruption all
premise sessions are still secure
so we show that you'll see relaxed break
implies game-based both game-based
security
and pfs and the proof
of this fact is very similar to the
previous results that
the standard authentic functionality has
this property
and we also show that the weaker you see
lazy extraction peak
it also implies game-based pike
security and a weaker form
of pfs
we measure some related work here
there has been some previous work
modeling this post-execution extraction
data in uc
first in the context of another
primitive called
oblivious pseudo-random function and
then in
a symmetric peg
and there's a concurrent work by shoop
which shows that
aspect 2 with key conformation actually
realizes the functionality which is
essentially
equivalent to our relaxed page and the
difference is that
our analysis is done modularly so first
we analyze the plane aspect
as a lazy extraction plane and then we
add key conformation to obtain the
stronger
the relaxed pink and we also analyzed
some other efficient peg protocols but
on the other hand
troops analysis is based on a slightly
weaker assumption than ours
and finally there is the very recent
result
which shows that encrypted key exchange
the first fake protocol ever proposed
already realizes the
sonar ucp functionality when the
encryption scheme is some specific ones
but regarding the computational costs of
their protocol and hours
there is some trade-off in the
comparison
and at this moment it is not completely
clear
which one is more efficient when
implemented and also
cs security reduction is not as tight as
ours
so in conclusion we show that
practical pick protocols are actually uc
sql
as long as we slightly relax
the standard usb picture pack
functionality to
laser extraction page
and secondly adding key confirmation
has two effects the first one is it
allows
explicit authentication and the second
is that upgrades
lays the extraction pipe to the slightly
stronger relax fake
and finally we show that every uc pike
is actually game-based secure with
perfect forward secrecy
there are many interesting open
questions on here i only want to mention
one of them
and that is is lazy extraction pace
we proposed really weaker than the
standard uc page
and if that is the case then in what
cases
or in what sense are they weaker
okay so this is the end of the talk um
our paper is on imprint you can check it
out if you are interested
thank you very much