for prizes and drawings awesome
everybody have a good time today awesome
everybody learned something today
cool everybody to come back next year
all right awesome cool that's what we
want to hear all right so can you hear
me now
yay okay okay so we just want to do
another thank you to the sponsors most
of them have packed up and they are gone
thank you
these are them again sponsors again
prizes and drawings you've all visited
the sponsors right ok so who's got the
drawing stuff and the winners and all
that jazz
[Music]
it must be the dude in the Hawaiian
shirt I hear from somewhere in the back
dude in the Hawaiian shirt what the fuck
all right the temperature control coffee
mug this is from proof point we got a
band bread shop in here and Bradshaw
alright so I guess we're gonna email him
we have contact info we can send it
awesome and then on this one what about
a Jennifer 10 holder this is from
Sentinel 1 it is essentially the same
thing 10 holder anybody this is going
fantastic is there Jennifer in the room
anywhere Jennifer is there any there's
no contact info on that one either
that one because I just wrote a name
down
is your name Jennifer oh let's see here
I think we have some other other awesome
stuff yeah Mike Kennedy right here
Mike Kennedy all right come on down this
is actually the worst thing possible
because I don't have anything to give
you you one code 42 s drawing they've
got your information so they're gonna
send you the speaker see I was excited
all right who wants the free shit
no starch press bugs so serious
cryptography sam donaldson you in here
still Sam tellingly no all right all
right why don't you take this and
randomly pick somebody else that how
about Philippe man tech Philippe may
attack you in the house this is gonna
get real sketch real quick
Scott link yeah
let's see
don't kill me a beer in vain' gula
alright I'm not even gonna attempt that
again how about Dustin coy start picking
names come on how about this one
David child's Jesus Christ you know what
let's let's do this
all right oh my god pinned me in a
circle I'd say you spend me in a circle
close your eyes pointer direction all
right look who do you see just fucking
pick who's in front of your finger all
right Michael Martin all right there we
go this is this is bad
[Applause]
this is the only way it's very much you
already what you're fucking nobody in my
line of sight do we have anything else
to give we're good for what for these
those have people's name law all right
sure well this one doesn't and I don't
ever contact them both actually I do all
right I'll shut up and leave them all
right awesome we gave stuff away all
right so let's see here thank you use
feedback announcements so that's kind of
the the agenda going forward here yeah
whenever I see the feedback QR code and
whatnot earlier I will just send that
out in in through busy coughing again
doobie is this better sorry I'm terrible
at this I tell you guys earlier this is
my first time talking on stage it shows
all right okay awesome cool okay I think
they're gonna fire me
so we'll send the feedback link and
stuff out there through email so just
wanted to say thanks to all the speakers
today really appreciate them all coming
out and teaching us everything you know
that they've you know put together and
whatnot you know I didn't get a watch a
lot of the talks incomplete so I will go
back through and watch those because we
have the awesome Adrian Crenshaw here
recording today obviously one more thank
you for the sponsors that are no longer
here thank you to the organizers and
volunteers where are all the organizers
and volunteers hey look I did put the QR
code in here
so if you want to take that down great
if not work like I said earlier we'll
put it out an email through there is a
hump and then last but not not last but
so a closing announcement it's probably
something a few people in the room don't
want to see but we're gonna do it anyway
so
I'm just gonna let it right read that
sorry so basically what that says is
part of the journey is the end well for
me for as an organizer anyway so I'm
stepping down effective after we do all
the closing stuff and you know just kind
of the recap stuff it's been in awesome
four years for me to be a part of this
crew we have an awesome crew that's come
in last year and you know all this is
you know part of their hard work and
lots of coordination for a year I
wouldn't be stepping out of this role if
I didn't feel like they could shoulder
it and continue to make it awesome and
better and grow it so so like I said my
last year isn't organizing so a little
bittersweet I'll still be around hostel
help but um you know it's taken a step
back to kind of focus on me a bit and
family and career and whatnot so it's
this whole thing has been an awesome
project
and the red is out on the projector so
Steve has been an integral part of
running this conference and we started a
tradition last year where we give a
bottle of bourbon to or something of
note so here you go sir
there's your parting gift it's a bottle
of wood hat bloody butcher I don't know
if you guys yeah that's some really
really good stuff you can't find it
anywhere so Steve we thank you so much
Help Wanted Treasury position anybody
but we just want to thank you guys for
coming out it's such a great event the
networking the vendors just the
conversations that happen here you know
this is st. Louis right so let's let's
grow let's keep getting bit I can fit
six hundred people in here six hundred
so we had 225 today to to about 250 came
through today so let's you know let's
keep growing let's keep the security
community alive here and we thank you
very much for coming up
[Applause]
so so before everybody in front of the
site okay we have mine we have one more
thing to kind of figure out so one more
thing because I always find one more
thing right how much do we raise from
the t-shirt sales 450h okay so we're
gonna split that 50/50 between we're all
tech fund and mental health hackers do
we want to match it as besides STL and
do a little bit more impact awesome so
we're gonna do a match so awesome so
that's my my final detail thanks
everyone
hope you had a good time come back next
year
[Applause]