speaker on
is a member of other career Italy
contribute to the Nevada compiler its
twist window and you will speak above
sixty four-bit bar with our programming
let's upload him like oh yeah let's take
care of the right anyone hello thank you
for coming so it's a talk about the
metal platform which is usually sings
that comes without boxes like that and
particularly with any operating system
so when you program on that metal
platform you don't use a new a parting
system why you want to do that the main
reason is because there is no enough
resources to use an operating system for
exam this is Arduino size - not enough
memory travel operating system but there
are other reasons it's fun but it's
different from usual it's fun you can
learn a lot of things low-level things
as a lot of things to learn about when
you do bare metal programming and I have
chosen Raspberry Pi 3 why mainly because
it's very very popular which means are a
lot of forums
yeah - towards about on the web about
how to program directly on Raspberry Pi
and also because it's a very safe
platform you cannot break it it will
always work however there are some
drawbacks with raspberry pi 3 because
it's berries it's based on the bottom
system Oh chip there are a very few
documentation about it here is a page
about the raspberry pi 3 but for
documentation which basically say ok
it's a v8 CPU thank you it's also
written in the marketing documentation
and form of documentation crsp by su
alright be alright
very PI's one and end of the
documentation not enough but we can deal
with that so you know maybe you know
about the raspberry pi family the first
one was a PI one which R is based on
very what was a old uncle the PI 2 was
much more interesting because it's based
on a new car and R for course so I
wanted it and the last one is even
better because it's for 64-bit cause so
I want it and I want to use it the
architecture of the Raspberry Pi is a
little bit weird there are two words are
for 64-bit CPUs that share level to cage
and are also the video call GPU which
contains the firmware word which use the
family as a share as a memory the boot
process of the platform is interesting
because it's I would say unusual because
it's the GPU that starts the first
running its VMware and then loading from
the SD card the application into the
memory and then once the application is
loaded its start all the CPUs so the
nice things about this platform does the
PI platform is that the CPUs boots start
from your code not from family Akkad
only the GPU use firmware there are a
couple of files that after need to be
present on the SD card some files that
are used by the GPU to boot
configuration file which is interesting
and your image that will be loaded in in
the ROM and will be executed by the arm
cpu's if you want to be secured 64-bit
cards you have to specify some command
in the config dot txt file but it's a
explained so let's start our first
diameter problem usually we do things
that eyes are blinking leds or writing a
message on the Casal so I will use
something we'll do something quite
common which is a hello world on the
console and for that you need a terminal
emulator connect its who sail to USB
converter this is the URL of the code I
will show positive so this is USB to
serial converter and you connect it
directly on some pin in the editor of
the Raspberry Pi 3 very bare metal
quickly this is a make file so there are
two main files the CRT go which is Assam
which is that some big code that is
executed and the main C code we don't
use any C library we use linker script
to tell of section are grouped and we
create not an elf file in a fight but
Venera file so at the end you have to
copy this file on the unless decode the
CR T 0 is the usual name for 0 and 1
times 0 which means the satisfied to be
executed by the in fact none present 0
on time
it is really written in decimal because
you do so low-level things that it
cannot be expressed by C code it has to
initialize the car the board also card
but in the on the raspberry pi it's very
easy because the Jeep
you does most of the initialization for
example it does setups Zeron it does set
up the video so everything is much
easier on on this platform however you
still have to create nebula mods small
Nestle's right to execute the C code so
this is the wall assembly code for the
hello world this is the first
instruction is acquitted there are 4
CPUs and all the fuzzy P use are started
together so you need to put into a busy
the loop switch CPU and keep only one
which is done by this code la vidas code
and then you have to initialize the last
zip the worldly first CPU the main CPU
here you load the stack pointer here you
clear the memory that has to be cleared
for the sea environment because all the
variables are initialized to zero this
is done here and finally you call main
so our C code C code right start with
main like normal application and this is
a code we have seen previously that's
called main you can do whatever you want
to do in C but there is no sis no sis
course so and no silabowi so you have to
write everything you want to execute
this is the main card so that is next
slide for our new art so the sale Kali
is incised in size and we do just put in
a word
puts is here it's 20 every clock tears
until they could every prime to
printable character you did with
extended backslash n to backslash n
backslash yeah and this is how to print
one character so we wait until the UART
is ready and went is ready we write one
byte at one specific location that will
have a side effect and would be sent
over the serial line this is how to
initialize the UART so this is most of
the code so this is very bare metal
things we change some bits at some
specific advice that are specified here
and this as a side effect of initial
design initializing he enabling the new
art specifying number of bits that would
be transmitted specifying the speed of
the UART and here we have to specify
that the pin in fact used for the world
ok very what this is documented in the
raspberry pi documentation and this is
very very bad stuff to correctly gather
all the things and specify address we
use an eco script look at the scene very
interesting and then you have your first
hello world program so what what can you
do next
except things like hello world in
different language you can write your
own drivers well if you want to start
you can start with GPIO because that's
very easy just a way to send signal on
the headers its quasi SPI
as where to communicate using server
protocol and
very easy using SD card isn't very
difficult to program but is a very small
stack of things to do to communicate
with a SD card video is very easy
because most of the work if not all is
done by the GPU firmware so you just
have to say okay I want a frame buffer
and you get a reply so just from buffer
is at this advice with that weeds and
that hate you can do drivers if you want
for us be able to switch it on it except
that's much difficult and documentation
is not very very extensive and these
topics if you want more performance you
have to enable cash because without cash
well the CPU start with cash disabled
which create abysmal performance so you
want really to enable cash for
performance except that if you enable
cash you have to specify that I origins
are not catchable because I origin of
side effects with images and must be
stopped as we will just we must be good
to the device and we must be calm to the
from the device and if you want to
specify that some regions are not
possible you have to set up the MMU
which is at a bit complex and when in
the setup you specify that some regions
are not catchable and the easiest way to
set up the MU is to use 1:1 mapping so
no translation just writes on regions
you cannot so try to use the four calls
so as we have seen all the process of
start and we have put three on in
in busy loop there is a specific
register to get the call number so you
get a number from 1 to 3 you have to
specify a stack for each processor and
to execute a specific routine start
routine for each processor but that from
get which lies ad where only ones if you
want to go even further you will have to
know that call start as the highest
protection level yes we and you can
switch to lower level is equal to is a
good code to lower level to go to well
from exception level 2 hypervisor level
and then from a permissive level to
canal level and if you want to can also
go to user level there are code in the
SMP directory that does exactly that
so it setups it enabled cache it setups
mmm ooh and under all start all the four
calls what we have done with that we
have done well one colleague is not
misery
what culling has done by casting
demonstrate demo we choose a focus we
choose DMS 2d from the GPU to speed up
except that it doesn't use the GPU and
we have reached 60 frame per second this
is a screenshot well not a photo and
this is if I can't play it this is a
video from the sadaebu
so damn it all that's it thanks for this