are you ready okay so welcome everybody
we are here to praise to talk about our
project Calliope and it's about Mary
privacy and X matrix in digital
communication
I am Emmerich and I am Stan we have to
speak with man we meet microphone for
both so it's really something okay thank
you so we are probably in Texas what is
privacy you know all what is privacy but
in digital communication I think that we
lost all of her privacy
so Kerri open is a project is a project
to bring back to users their privacy we
will describe all we want to make this
possible okay Cali open under of private
sections today is not about email when
we communicate it's about me Moochie
protocols it can be Skype it can be
Twitter the direct message it can be
facebook Messenger a lot of on sums are
oriented for privacy like sign sign all
telegram for end-to-end encryption and
guarantee that people get the privacy
and communication and only be between
users but we don't speak about protocols
we want to speak about contents about
whoa discus with room it's not when we
speak with Twitter or Facebook is not
only protocols it's about people
speaking together so Caliban is
discussion oriented is not protocol we
want to gather all communication between
same people on the same place on the
same discussions protocol smarter only
for privacy privacy measurements
it's about depending on protocol user we
not the same Travis ish and so Calipari
will try to have to compute that privacy
by certain protocols but not only
protocols
it's about all other things that
interact between people communicating so
privacy and X is nothing new
maybe I'm an old geezer with a view
schnook in France but I was used to be
able to know when something is private
or not when I send a letter and I put it
in an Arab I seal the envelope and I
know that no one else then the recipient
can read it and if I send a postcard and
I write on my postcard my address and
the code to enter to my home and I say
you can find the key just on the right
of of my jaw I know that it's not
private and that everybody can read the
postcard and see what's on it
so it's easy for me to it was easy for
me to to to know when something is
private and what is when it's not
private and the problem is it should be
the same on the internet we should be
able to to see easily when something is
private and when it's not private but it
seems that it's not really the case we
are losing the control of our mailbox or
our and over our communication we don't
know exactly what's happened and what's
going on so we need to have some matrix
or some something just to to show to see
that something is private or less and
more prevents
this is the other problem issue that we
can say on the Internet's and something
is private or it's not private something
it's a level of privacy the shades of
privacy and we we need to see that to
feel it and to be able to have something
as easy that is Annie in the in the real
life with later with paper with envelop
so where we need to recreate in digital
age what was easy to understand in the
paper age okay but the fact is the
internet was not designed for that
purpose when it was built
it's about telnet FTP communications are
in clear text on the wire and also SMTP
with multiple Haley milky Bob is not
secure there is not privacy it's clear
text over to Santa Annette and starting
at nine ninety five ninety five SS ash
happy Rose also jealous
at the time but it's not for users TLS
and SSL and TLS was built to guarantee
bank transactions over Antionette to
permit to have the number card number to
not be in clear on the wire it's normal
we want to have this credit card number
visible but all and mistletoe by all
people that can be desire can be Cesar
the flows on an Internet it's a poor
Emma
so no in this century which try to be
the week began to have a new protocols
new secretion possibilities but as I
said if this parrot is multi protocols
its many things
you have a mini way to communicate with
each other's today email can be secured
for me I'm a taking him up guy I know I
can secure me nervous that's not harm my
communications only the body the content
of the message can be encrypted metadata
still exists and can be top tepid by
governments or also others people's it's
a real problem it's a real problem for
privacy we can know who speak with womb
we have metadata give a lot of
formations maybe more than for the
contents himself such will be a short
message with no interest but metadata is
really important and we have to find a
way image throughout this program dark
male aliens try to find a way to evolve
SMTP protocols to make it more secure on
leaked less metadata other protocols
acting and to any encryptions want to
hide much metadata as possible that's
where we are but is it enough is it
complete no it's not because multi
protocols music sings and OH
what how can we do that so many many
tools Louise are not secure at all
facebook Messenger Twitter direct
message are not we can use a bit of PGP
in these protocols but who who protects
this kind of things I said no one see
someone use PGP in a Facebook No yeah ok
that's fine but you can't use it on your
smartphone with a bishop is only
available on your browser side with
Facebook when you enable PGP you can't
use int anymore
it's a problem because our usage is also
with other device we was up price so we
have to
find a way to show Oh
it's secure or not so but as I say
metadata is important because it's
exposed all our social graph we speak
about social networks so we have a lot
of friend of a friend of friends on
facebook on Twitter on all those yes
power or source tools like this it's
important we have to interact with
people we know with for professional for
personal reasons but it's really a
problem because it's not a technical
port it's not about the protocols or
insights is about you speak with whom
and when I am a user securing myself on
my emails maybe I will speak with other
peoples and peoples are on gafas
provider like Google Facebook or others
and it's very important because I can
get all my interest to be get a privacy
but my contact won't have so it's not
it's not ok we lose a part of the
provider
it's important to get back to get this
and this interesting about a social
graph so digital age and closes the act
of communicating in too technical black
boxes making very difficult for us to
understand what's underlined what's we
want to do with Cali open and with the
privacy index is to make privacy very
visible again that's our main goal
make privacy visible again we need to
find how we can and when I say we I
speak as a community of developers we
need to find how to make privacy visible
again and to build user interface that
always show
how why what level of privacy you are in
with the person you're communicating
with or when wiII you send this kind of
message with this kind of channel and
this way we don't want to to guilty
the the user and to make them
responsible something like this of doing
bad action by sending message with low
privacy level of insecure Channel we
just want to show our privacy privacy
here to make to give the desired for the
user to improve their privacy index and
to change their behavior and to change
where they communicate and to ask for
tools for the the platforms they use to
be more informational about what is the
privacy what is the protocol underlying
what's happening and to have tools that
can be it easy to use as the the
envelope and later in the envelope is so
that's real the challenge we want to
bring on the table with Cali open
because we are at an early stage of the
of the process of building this privacy
and X and this user interface but we
have starts started the the process and
and we want to build this kind of user
interface that can make the privacy
again visible so it's about privacy and
actually the way I just pick about a
mailbox but inside so me all a way to
communicate and like it's what said
before you can draw up image people
still using him as my bank communicate
with me
image other friends it's a sign cool
process and we can coop itself easily
but so email it's a technically easy to
get measurements for the privacy all
secured watches was it it's a we which
which really was used was secure
protocol used on the end damage
terminate at termination of the
connection the network communication
communication the content also is it PGP
or some things is all metadata are works
Likud for practice in PGP for example is
not to set up subject on the email that
is related with the content because you
will leak metadata we leak a part of the
message you want to deliver privately
it's not ok but it's only the technical
part and as I will always say with also
others aspect like I said the social
graph is important so privacy is not
only technical it's about other
dimensions it's like social like stencil
behavior during the time
oh I use my communication tools do I
still want to have a privacy and
continue to use to strictly PGP or
others encryption tools but is also an
important part like we said before is
about the contextual usage of our
communication where we use the
communication tools is it at home with
hard work is it in a public place or in
the tube on the booster Metro ok it's
not this part of usage is really
important because
because it's a really it's a new usage
smartphone bring us a new type of use as
much before it was dick stop at home at
work after it was laptop we can bring
here and know also smartphones important
device it's also an important part of
the analogies yeah so the device case as
a shaman said we can we think as
developer on the Kali open project and
and working on the privacy on Dex we
think that we can easily build some
matrix for the technical point of view
museum our the protocol was our security
was what was the options email the ADA
was enclosed or not etc today is it's
not easy very easy but it's not very
difficult to assess this but there are a
lot of other issues and information to
take account to to try to build a
privacy index like for example the
device I'm using is it a smartphone is
it a laptop this is it can influence the
privacy on decks but what kind of what
kind of smartphone is it is it an
Android is it an iPhone it influenced
the privacy and X and what is the
connection is it a GSM connection now is
it a Wi-Fi is it a public Wi-Fi or is it
a private Wi-Fi is it a Wi-Fi in Tunisia
a gray palette ah
means States enforce that's okay
I'm the state of Tunisia and I say this
wafer is okay no so we need to take
account of all this kind of contextual
and be a royal information to build the
privacy and xoz what we want to sell
today is that we as developer we need to
take account the privacy and X and try
to calculate its on the type
we call point of view but we as
developer need also to work with
psychologists sociologists a lot of
other you UX designer a lot of other
competencies to help us to bring all the
use case that builds a privacy index and
to try to find how we can take account
of all the contextual and not only is a
technical one and so the challenge is
that it would be great if we can build
software that could prevent me or help
me to exchange important message over
poor privacy channels or with
correspondents that have poor privacy
index again it's not the the aim is not
to to be guilty but just to help user to
make the right choice in the right
situation with the right context for the
right message and because today in
digital age it's very very tough to do
this choice because we don't know so we
need this kind of software and that's
what we are trying to do with Kelly open
its about displaying a flag monkey-see
monkey-do what it's about it's like a
stan said it's a the envelope later
it's a open will show a provision decks
with informations about technical behave
we are all those dimensions about
communication privacy considerations
this information will be available for a
each element in Kalapana a message about
privacy
contact other privacy also but also the
users using gallopin of its own
provision decks an indie their ideal
world users on Calliope and who can be
able to see other user privacy and X and
know oh I can come in it with this other
users in a privately in privacy manner
it's about all of that
the time is helped so I have to to stop
and it's a network you are you have we
want to bring a community to to get
privacy back to all users not technical
guys that we are we are able to do to
encrypt communications Laxus so no we
have to bring back to all users their
privacy
Caliban have to be a simple tools to
make possible to see all provide is all
of our communications so thank you ok
yeah thank you again and just join us
because this is the core of particle of
part with participation excuse me we are
here for the first presentation of Kali
open and privacy and X so this is really
work in progress we're at the beginning
of the process where wall team on this
and we hopefully come next year to show
you what we have done in one year but we
need help with for from other developer
and not only developers thank you
you have two minutes for questions
we have a two-year project now with MVP
for our Calliope and so we have an alpha
project for October of this year's it's
a two-year project actually with UPMC
University Polling on Marie Curie and
quand on ganja net where we are working
well and it will be a alpha release for
make use of testing oh that will be AB
take this project so the the MVP will be
a platform to exchange email basically
the first will be on email and with how
we can show privacy and X on the
interface but we don't know really if we
will be able to calculate some privacy
and X this October yeah
okay so the question was there are a lot
of buyers when we want to assess privacy
on decks because we have to make your
lot of assumptions and we have a lot of
is there a lot of three areas we don't
know something and that's that's the
issue that that's what is difficult to
calculate the privates index and really
I we don't know how to do it but we want
to to do it step by step so first we
will ask Museo what we can measure so
what we can we can definitely see when
what something comes or when and we we
want to slightly gather more and more
contributors and maybe proposal maybe
IDs and to find how we can assess the
kind of user case you you you you spoke
about and and to see how we can under
this and we with we think that we counts
are just one metrics to measure of
privacy and X we we will need to balance
between between different metrics and we
think it's it may be it may takes years
to build the privacy on decks yeah
because there is a lot of gray area and
it's very difficult but that's why we
are in and we want to together
communities around this concert
because we needed time's up time's up
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
one day to appear