oh good
oh yeah so much whistle it's giving
mottled it on Michael wait see well okay
hi everybody
hello so it's a pleasure for me to be
there today and I'm going to talk about
jaspera which is a an offensive social
network I think you know about it and I
I feel really happy to be in the
decentralized room to see that the the
mine of people is changing and that we
know how this room at the first time and
I hope like Tristan said that it will be
bigger next year so shortly I'm flat so
that's how everybody called me
I work in Grenoble in a small company we
do we which does carefully and mostly
Mozilla from a soft and diaspora
contributor so I care about how unlike
privacy I feel like we need to do some
to ride the Internet so that's why I
joined from a soft and I'm running the
Framus Fair which is one of the biggest
jaspera server in France and hosted by
from I surfed so maybe some of them some
of you are users so why did why does the
desperate project exists the first thing
is I feel like and I hope you feeling
like that too that sharing is awesome I
know a lot of people who are afraid of
Facebook and they are just like you know
the memory of the good old times when
you were talking to your friend in real
life and I feel like the social network
can be way better than it is right now
and maybe something which is good and
that's actually you have kind of
like to kind of people the the one who
just doesn't care and use Facebook and
don't care about their data and the one
who are afraid and just use nothing and
there is room between them to breathe
something great to use which will hello
you to share with your friends your
contact everyone in the world but
without being spied be the without being
used to make money by corporation so
that's that's the the first things there
is also things about the rules if you're
a Facebook or Twitter user you may
notice that you're not always welcome on
those Network depending on what you
share what you think which country you
are using which from country you're
using the network so for example we so
during the the hot spring Facebook being
cut in Tunisia it's really easy to catch
you you just have to switch off the DNS
and that's it no more Facebook for
thousands of person and so the the last
thing is yeah we want to be able to
control the service we want to be able
to control the data so we need to split
it to decentralize so the first thing
you can say about just rise
decentralized technically it's really
really close to email everybody can set
up an email server and everybody can set
up at just for a server and you will be
able to talk to everyone else sitting
another email so if you if you feel like
you you can house to just brandade I
really encourage you to do so it it will
help you to talk with everyone it's not
only what's going on on your server it's
not for you and your friends only you
can set up a server for you and your
friends but you will be able to reach
everyone from the Jasper Network from
from this place so yeah and the the data
are are controlled only by the server
administrator so if you feel like
example you trust from a soft you can
join us and from as fans will be as easy
as register with one click like Facebook
if you feel like you want to control
completely all the data you want the
images on your house you want to be the
only one to be able to remove your
messages then you will have to host
yourself and you will be the master of
everything so this not this this is
pretty funny because well we are talking
about social networking and you you will
recognize Facebook there but you can
replace Facebook by almost any other
American corporation and will we you
will have the exact same shot so so I
said the other point is social I
strongly feel that we can do way more
than we hug actually doing for a lot of
interesting topic of course for free
software's but also for ecology politics
almost everything you want and the the
Internet is the it's something as
important as the the printing was by
Guttenberg hundreds of years ago like
everybody now can send stand up and talk
and you will be able to reach thousands
millions of people within minutes we
need to be able to do that to build a
better world so I feel like sharing is
really important and about the jaspera
features you will be able to do mostly
what you can do with a traditional
social network so sharing images and
polls and with all the classic features
like mentions and hashtags and to be
able to react by liking commenting or
sharing that's that's the curse of the
social network but just rise more than
that we also give more power to the user
to be able to transform the the message
so to be able to write
and to insert images where he wants to
inside the the textile to say this
should be in bold or italic or this is a
title least table inside videos and many
things you can move in a range inside
the network and finally jazz pride is
about privacy so this centralization is
already something really really good in
terms of privacy that you control the
data but still the software itself is
really privacy oriented so that means by
default the user will be in a secure
world like when your register on
Facebook you you first register and then
you have to go to the settings deeply
inside the sittings to find everything
you can hide so no I don't want my
birthday to be public no I don't want my
friends to be public no I don't want my
pictures to be public each sitting is
deeply hidden inside the Facebook
configuration by default if you do not
touch anything on just by just after you
you register you will be safe this is
really important the the hub team versus
opt-out mine when you build a software
especially we do not require real name
no even a valid email address if you
don't put valid email address by which
when you register inside just probably
you just will not be able to recover
your password and you will not reserve
any email notification but that's it the
software itself works without email so
if you want to be completely anonymous
and I know a few nerds which can be
reached using at all so directly with an
onion address so if you want to be
completely anonymous you can do you can
do that we are using a system called
aspects which is which has been cooked
ID by Google with a circle inside
Google+ to define the different aspect
of your life so your co-workers or your
family your friends and deeply control
the who is accessing the data you're
publishing right now that that's pretty
efficient
other example of privacy feature right
here for example I don't know if you
know the the small demonstration project
which was maybe something called shat on
to someone one day just feel like oh my
god I want to know whether the kitten
are on the internet so it go on Flickr
Iggy
it goes on Google Image it bring
something like 1 million pictures of of
cats and it just had a look at the eggs
if so the GPS location of its each
picture and put that on a map and it was
really scary yo you you display the map
and you see like oh this is the cat of
my friend right here and you will be
able to see the picture of the cats all
around you and you say you you're like
ok when I take a picture I don't think
about all the Queen sequences but most
of the time from a smartphone the
location of the picture is is recorded
and you will to say at which time and at
which place it has been taken so this
give a lot of information about the user
in jaspera by default they exist that so
the metadata of the picture are stripped
when you upload it so you upload the
picture and everything behind it is
removed you we only keep the picture and
so another one is the the proxifier
content so a lot of pictures are linked
inside social network from other website
you have also the Open Graph short text
presentation when someone passed the
league on Facebook on just raw so if I
post a link to a website a request will
be made to this website to display a
short summary of it just under the past
so if you load the images for example at
the website did this means that each
user which will display who will deal
play it will will do a request to this
server so will be able to be tracked by
it
so we set up a proxy so all the images
can go by the note itself and the user
is not doing any queries from the
external to the external world only to
the just for our server so it's not
tracked this is the Jasper a publisher
so I just wanted to show you how easy it
could be to format your text and choose
what you want to do so we support Mac
down there is some shortcut on the top
the pole picture on geolocation if you
want to hide it
they're sitting there is to hover you to
post directly from just right to
Facebook Twitter or tumblr because the
transition is pretty hard for most of
people so we want to be able to connect
with with the outside world and the
aspect is are you select who is able to
see the person jasper eyes no community
run project but it says it has phoned by
for Chanukah students after a talk by
him eben Moglen i don't know if you know
him
a he wrote the GPL license with stalin
is an advocate and is really interesting
i really encourage you to listen to to
Moglen talks so they they started a
Kickstarter campaign unfortunately they
were pretty in experimented and this
thing didn't go wells and the this is
the site part of the talk one of them
even committed suicide because of the
pressure coming from everywhere and so
at this time the desperate project was
almost something dead like they didn't
want to work on it anymore so they
decide to release it to the community
and for more than four years no the the
community bring the project so the FSN
is an organization
managed by heben morgan this is the who
they are urging their assets for so all
the trademark and copyright for just run
some money too but most of the time we
are just managing the project yourself
without any problem we were using the
the loomio tool to make to take decision
as there is and rights of person on it
who can vote and you're welcome to join
everybody can vote and take decision
about just rob and we moved on a new
release system so we know release in
minor fashion every six weeks and we
release a first measure of ation in May
2013 and we all know what the sixth
measure of version which was released
September with a deeply improved
Federation so the protocol between the
nodes and a new redesign I cannot I
cannot not talk about the fact that we
saw his is coming on Jastrow on August
2014 so we need to be decentralized we
need to be to protect ourselves from
cooperation but the espera was not built
to be no Lowe's land it's something I
want precise because we are not so we
are not fighting the government here the
decentralisation alo has to be resilient
to censorship but this is not the first
goal of J's bra the first goal of Jasper
ice to avoid Facebook and and Google and
hold a data mining and ads targeting
done by American corporation but we do
need to have a control system to be able
to remove some illegal post so each it's
not itself can decide what he wants to
do with the post the user just seems
senior it like they are saying okay
something which is maybe helical is on
your server and the administrator can
decide if you think you should remove it
or not and especially all server are
spread all over the world so the lows
for example in France or Germany are
different than the USA ones and if you
want to host a server somewhere in
Taiwan or with a no-loss country that
you can do whatever you want so this is
a quick screenshot of the whole design
from the previous major version and the
new one I just wanted to show you how it
looks I don't have time to do a demo but
we can talk about it later or you can
just go on pod and register and you will
see and I wanted to point that with we
did a really big big work last year to
rewrite the would just prop protocol to
extract it from the core and so you it
is not available as a ruby gem so
library you you can include inside the
project and we are not the only one
speaking this protocol the fryin teacher
and the RevZilla projects are still are
talking
jaspera too so we know called the the
protocol the Federation and we try to
remove all the jaspera specific world
inside the protocol the protocol itself
is not referring to jasper anymore it's
something which has been extract and I
unn courage you to have a look the the
complete specification are available of
course everything is open and you can
switch your project if you maybe I don't
know I depending on what you do and we
we have a website called the Federation
that Mpho that I'm really signing
currently which is a list of all the
nodes which exists and is speaking the
just prop vertical so you you've got
several project listed under
and shout what expect for the futures
well we are full of ideas unfortunately
we are all volunteers so we need more
resources and more time maybe but big
things are coming especially senior
right here is working and the migration
things because we this is also a core
value but we it's really hard to build
in the decentralized world but the idea
is to be able to say I want to live this
nut and grab every information I have
with me every messages that post on my
contact information and to be able to
grab that and put it in another node for
example you can say oh I will try Jasper
I don't have time to instil it so you
register on premise fear and you use it
for several months you say ok I like it
but now I want to host myself so you
will be able to grab all your data and
inside your home just prop put it on it
and restart like everything never to
likely if you started on your your node
at the beginning so that's really
important for us and I can't create you
to to come and contribute if you if you
want to help just to welcome some new
here people is always something very
very valuable all right thank you
this is all the the URL well you can
find most of the information about just
brought out the official website and the
code on github and the list of nodes at
the Federation thank you
I don't how many time we have for
Christians but five minutes okay yep two
questions in fact one is a promise for
[Music]
ya and the second one is also relates
MPP would it be possible in the future
to send host why am i its MPP client
yeah so I read posts using an XMPP
client instead of for that side so the
question is about the integration of
XMPP inside Jastrow for so first of all
the chat right now is not in a stable
state so from a sphere is way too big to
put a better feature on it at the moment
but it will be activity that as soon as
it's ready I'm right on the started blog
about the XMPP integration itself we're
using SEM PP for the real-time chat it
is already possible to what we do is
just to link the database of jaspera to
be able to log in to XMPP with your
username and your password so if you use
I don't know pidgin and you you're part
of XMPP enabled you will be able to log
inside pidgin directly and to chat with
all the person using XMPP you're not
stuck to it just for a user of course
but the message is that ya know this is
not going to happen hi because like
really XMPP is is nice to do chat and
other things but it has some flows which
is not really the good idea to write a
social network backs on XMPP I know I
know pretty well the guys behind a
cellulites were behind moving there is
nice social project trying to use XMPP
and definitely there there should be a
lot of he thought to do that and I don't
think it was it at the moment yes
yeah which Dennis - would you shut down
[Music]
well the point yeah so the point is
about a censorship by shutting down gns
I talked about facebook.com because
Facebook desk dot-com is only one server
one domain name so if you start this one
then nobody can use Facebook anymore
really just for I like the email if you
if you stop gmail.com if you stop Orange
and free and all the Yahoo and maybe out
mail everyone was still using emails you
see what I mean you cannot shut down the
email if you shut down a domain name I
will just be able to buy another one and
point it to my server and that's it so
yeah we can talk about it after that
yeah so the IPA is currently we already
work a lot on it and we'll specification
of the API is is written so we have the
the idea oh it it will be but the code
itself is not done yet jaspera is
already an and I was a provider of I was
I lost it
open ID thank you yeah so there is
already the identification part which is
quite working and there is still works
going on but the the IP I is not ready
yet but the specification out there so
if you want to be prepared to write an
application for just bra you can already
have a look and we welcome feedback to
of course yes
so the question is about the data being
cop ID to us on nodes of the network so
the answer is the texts are pushed but
not the the important data like images
so if you if you publish a posting look
at my pictures you will it will be
encrypted sent to other nodes on where
you have contact only the one you're
talking to they will receive the message
and be able to decrypt it and then they
will have URL to the images they bet the
image is stay on unit so that if you
removed it nobody has access on it
anymore all right
so time's up everybody I'm sorry I can
answer a question after that thank you
very well and so see you there