and welcome from
do you not laughs and I'd like to talk
about our custom kernel approach and the
talk is structured the following way and
first chapter I'd like to talk about how
what motivated us to create all O'Connor
and the second chapter I give a little
overview about general qualities of this
corner and how it works in general
and in Chapter three four and five I
will go into detail about some features
of the corner yeah let's start with the
motivation one big advantage of G note
is that you can run it of various
corners like Nova like if you're a four
corners like I said for Linux and so on
and that gives you great flexibility in
development and application of G note so
you can for instance some kernels have a
cool debugger built in and some kernels
are specialized on security like there's
a four corner and so you can choose
in the application and the user
applications it doesn't matter which
color you use for for the basic for the
basic features and the second big
advantage of supporting many colors is
that you have a lot of different ways of
testing the system on top of it so you
have different timing you have different
scheduling you have in general a
different behavior at the base and so
you can get much harder testing for your
for your system on top yeah so when you
look at this combination G note in the
corner it's normally the way that you
have a microkernel that is developed on
its own and aims for comprehensive
security concepts so it likes to be
self-contained and mistrusts all that is
on top of it of course this brings a
little bit of problems with it because
you then have the core G notes core
component that has to pray these this
paranoid corner perspective in line with
the G note API on top of it and the
misery here is that the core component
of G know it must be trusted anyway by
all the components on top so you don't
it yeah you you don't have much
advantage from this extra effort you
spend so of course there are some
drawbacks that come from this aspect
first you have to shape some concepts
the way you like it to be for example on
some corners for asynchronous
communication you have
you have semaphores for instance and
these semaphores must be abandoned shape
to support the asynchronous
communication API that we used on G node
so the signals in in this instance so
the other thing is that often work is
done right and done T so the memory
management for example must be done
redundant ly in the core because the G
note API differs a lot from that memory
management API that cannot support
normally and at some points there are
even deficiency that you can't source so
you have to work around it
for instance capability delegation on
some corners you have the problem that
you have to remember capabilities at
certain places where you normally
wouldn't have to use in the genotype III
but you have to because the kernel
otherwise revoke the capability so yeah
well we came up with the idea of
creating our own corner this corner
should trust core because it's rusted
anyway as I said and should be
completely tailored to serve the needs
of course
and in that it can be reduced to a
minimalistic library that is linked to
core and simply unable to run directly
on the hardware and having the G note
the kernel API you can also run the most
critical parts of the system and simply
in a more simple manner than link or for
instance cause the multi-threaded
application you and some things are much
easier if you are not multi-threaded for
for example so let's talk about a little
bit a little bit about the kernel itself
the tasks behind the color API are at
first the exception actors setting up
the exception vectors and catching
exceptions as a main task of the corner
doing the scheduling of course for the
my project components on top then the
coder controls the interrupts of course
because there's the exception vectors
and it provides communication in our
case it's only two communication
channels you have IPC and you have
signals for synchronous and asynchronous
communication the engine supports
capabilities so you have trusted
capabilities on top and you have local
names and HP protection domain that
can't be misused
and it does cash and he'll be
maintenance because on most
architectures these are privileged
operations and last but not least it
does virtualization for the same reason
as for cache and TLB maintenance and
because that has the accept you back
toes so the API does that rises from
these tasks pretty simple you can see in
the top row these are all sis calls that
are caught only so only the core
component of GNote is allowed to do
these holes at all and in the bottom row
you see the the public api of the corona
so these source codes can be done by
each user and you see these are not not
many circles it's 14 counted right and
it's mostly about yeah fred's signals
messaging and some capability sense
calls to manage the capabilities in the
local PD and all all the memory
management you can see is the memory
management for for the corner you did
the new and delete sis calls are all in
the core only searching so yeah this
brings me to the first quality of the
corner that all dynamic memory is
accounted because for each kernel object
that is created in on runtime you have
to put in some memory from outside so
from core
and in core we have a good memory
management and so these memory
management reflects the cost for the
kernel objects to the session quota on
top of the G note API so in general for
each kernel object you create you have
to pay as user and this brings with it
the kernel can't be can't run out of
memory and yeah that's that's a big
advantage of this corner and the other
thing is that this way the whole corner
is a mirror
state machine so you can keep it signify
that you you don't have any dynamic
stuff that is created and this makes the
corner pretty small it's really low
complex and all you do in the code every
time you in the corner you're the only
one that is in the corner so you are
really fast you don't block you are not
interrupted and kernel passes got really
fast in general so speaking about low
complex I have a little picture you're
normally a few on GNote and you have one
of the party kernels you have in in the
basic set of say called the corner and
the inner component and some bootstrap
comp tools on some corners you have at
least 30,000 lines of code that you have
to trust from every component on top of
it and this is already pretty small but
with the Toscana library approach we can
reduce it to about 22,000 lines of code
yeah
about a hot war support of the colony
initially Turkana was developed on arm7
and so the most features it provides on
this architecture of course it provides
several boards you can see in here like
pre skateboards or Exynos and yeah the
omote 4 for example and you have various
features that are supported like the arm
trust own features multiprocessing
virtualization or FPU or something like
that and of course we also support our
six
[Music]
priority and having only priority like a
quality
you is not enough we have to have
another one is like a point value or the
seeking resources and we haver the
Dakota city Porter CBO is like the time
size you have a super figure of a
hundred percent currently it is to 1
second is one second
tonight it's nice to components then
that's the principle a component has
only a priority if it also has quote on
so if you are and as long as there is a
priority from before we have again or
USB that goes met at some point and you
can see that in the super period exceeds
its own photo by going mad and then it's
[Music]
in this in this so at the end of the
super period all the clutter gets reset
and there are again priorities and then
you start again with the USB because it
has gone mad and then it exceeds the way
so this is a nice way of keeping the
system life even if you have a high
priority but what your net yeah okay
another nice thing about the CPU
resources is that they can be
distributed in a way that resources are
normally distributed and GNote so you
have the parent of of a component tree
that has a specific amount of quota of
cpu quota and to fill its children with
life it can just some of its photon and
easterland can again like CL i gives
VirtualBox again a little bit of its
photo and so on and so on
yeah so it's in the hands of the parents
how much quota their children get and
the same is with the priorities you have
at the root of the tree the Internet has
all priorities 1 to 8 and then can give
a sub range of new priorities to a
children and so on and so ok let's talk
about the capabilities are a bit that's
one one cool thing about capabilities on
the basic W kernel is that the
capabilities get or automatically
created and translated so normally when
you normally you get capabilities into
your protection domain by receiving IP C
and then this RPC message are
local names of the other component that
sent me this IP this IPC but I cannot
use these local names of the other
components or the kernel goes ahead and
tries to translate these local names of
the other protection domain to my own
protection domain so I can directly use
them without looking up any object or
something like that and so when I
received the message the the local names
that I have in this IP symmetric message
are already fine for me I can directly
invoke them and it also if the kana now
realizes all there's there's a local
name of the the sender of the IP scene
that is not present in there there is no
no counter local name in the protection
domain so the kernel goes ahead and
creates automatically one for me so yeah
I have no invalid local names when I
received the message yeah and this
[Music]
so
there's a because but between these two
points as well the local name object was
already created now
one thread in my application thread also
receives it and during this aquifer
mangles the capability from the UTC be
the first fried starts with elated it
would be paid to
so the userland has to acknowledge when
it has received the capability and as
and I have to
[Music]
okay talking about communication this is
a short topic first about IPC queer
thing about IPC is on the basic trouble
O'Connor that implicitly delegates
resources so if you imagine you have
these four components components and you
have multiplexer for determination and
you are where you can print these
characters that you put in the terminal
session so these two terminal clients
Yerba start an RPC to their terminal a
multiplexer there if they are IPC
resources to determine and multiplexer
so the terminal light up like so as all
its own
[Music]
all these
about signals the the a synchronous
communication in China again the kernel
helps you with the lifetime management
and here the problem is this user may
userland object as the signal contacts
know if the signal arrives what type of
signal is that so in general you have
again a phase a sequence where where the
the signal arrived it's in my duty to be
again and I have to update the signal
context so the the userland life time
management is up to date but during this
during this time slice it would be
better if another thread goes on and
likes to kill likes to destroy the
signal context because then the the
pointer that I got with the signal would
be invalid and yeah and this is why the
corner has this signal context versus
call and if another fret now comes and
wants to delay the signal context it
does disk LTSs call and the kernel now
knows okay the signal like
skilled but it's already it is there's
also an acknowledgement pending so I
have to wait but I don't accept anymore
submits for the signal so the signal is
dead but it's already there it's it's
still there and as soon as the
acknowledgement of the receiver arrives
there's the skills is called of the of
the main thread gets unblocked and you
won't have to
[Music]
okay and all you ultimately
and
so I have my
you can you can set this variable also
temporarily yeah if you make later you
can also set it only for this one make
all thank you that he also said the
video HW instead of
[Music]
and see here that builds the the kernel
dependent library for the HW : here we
have some content libraries that are
linked against the generic binaries so
the binary stay independent from the
from the corner oh yeah I forgot I can
also set I I enable multi processing
[Music]
yeah
here at compiled secona and the core
accident
dares to comb the library I know it's
thoughts
yeah I thought about so many different
names and then I think it's not
is that much important yeah it's it's
it's different for other companies that
are used without any other system
okay yes yes okay okay this is the super
press enter and now you have at the
beginning lots of processes that have a
priority and quota and I use their quota
like here and for example for a foul
play at this point the quota for a foul
play is exceeded and it has no more
quota left for this super period yeah so
[Music]
no no i yeah it's a little bit
complicated because at this point you
are already in the next super period yes
okay
this shows the quota for the next super
period yes
but for the last super period at this
point assume that the quota is exceeded
for FLE yeah and at this point for audio
the decoder has exceeded and so on so at
this point all components except the
timer have no more quota of course you
can only consume your quota
when you're when you're awake yeah so
this is why the timer still has pota
left at the end of the super period yeah
that's a good question III said that the
chrono would wait but that's actually
not true because the corner only sets
the thread to wait so if I do this this
delete this it's not like that actually
it's like it's it's when you do the
delete syscall and and ya know it's bad
example because at this point the nobody
waits the delete is like a hint for the
chrono only and directly returns but
four four four four signals it's true
for signals the kill Sisko now when you
when you say I want to delete the signal
to signal context and the chrono
realizes or cares in the acknowledgment
pending it blocks the fret so and at
this point
[Music]
so it's
and in case of the capabilities that
that you have okay so each protection of
men has to pay for its own capabilities
so if I'm a server and I provide a
session for clients and over the setting
I receive capabilities from the clients
I have to pay a server photos I am
willing to spend some of my quota to
fulfill the service I provide for the
clients in this case okay so I have to
spend some quota beforehand but before I
say okay now I'm ready to receive IPC
messages and if I don't and I get
capabilities and the kernel throws an
exception then I can also then I can
still decide whether I want to spend
more quota for the client
reception from the client sends a
message where capability is limited I
don't know and the owner tries to create
a local it's not enough
or I say
no it has to be I don't know and to
something
[Music]
okay no more pressing questions