[Applause]
hi as you can probably rapidly tell from
my accent I'm not actually from the UK
what he means is I was in the UK before
I came to foz then I went to the
Manchester United game on Wednesday to
watch our awful terrible draw against
Hull but it was still fun I still
enjoyed it okay so but let's talk about
Ruby garbage collection so I have a
performance consultancy called speed
shop where I work with companies on
their Ruby and rails applications to
make them faster to make them more
performant and one of I would say the
number one issues that I tend to see is
companies that don't understand memory
usage in their ruby applications and one
of the big reasons for that is because
we have a garbage collecting language
you're not supposed to think about
memory you're supposed to just write the
code you want to write and that is you
know the garbage is collected afterward
and everything's fine and that you you
can't intentionally write leaks right
but it's a little more complicated than
that and so I thought we could all
benefit if we understood a little bit
more about how garbage collection
actually works and how its evolved and
gotten a lot more complicated since
those long-ago days of ruby 1.8 this
talk is beginner-friendly
that's why it's a people's history it's
by the people for the people if you're a
really core team member you probably
will not find anything interesting or
novel in this talk and I've tried to
structure all of this so that if you
don't know anything about garbage
collection or if you don't know anything
about garbage collection algorithms this
should not be too challenging for you to
understand okay so I would say that the
whole history of Ruby's garbage
collector has mostly been about how do
we reduce GC pause times how do we
reduce the amount of time that we spend
stopped to garbage collect because in
Ruby we have to in MRI see Ruby which is
what I'm talking about here today I'm
not
talking about JRuby or truffle Ruby
those guys have their own garbage
collectors that work in completely
different much more complicated ways in
C Ruby were mostly that this evolution
over time we're trying to reduce the
amount of time we have to spend stopped
to garbage collect we have to stop
during garbage collection because if we
allow things to move along and execute
Ruby during garbage collection we're
gonna lose track of which objects we've
already looked at to see if they're free
or not which ones we we haven't and you
know we're gonna end up with with memory
bugs right so we have to stop for
periods of time and say stop execution
hold on which these objects are being
used and which of them are not but if we
pause for a very long time that would
cause pretty bad behavior especially in
a web application so if we need to spend
a half a second garbage collecting which
was not uncommon in ruby 1.8 days then
what happens if we spent hat we have 50
milliseconds of in our web response
we're doing our normal work and then op
crap we need a GC so the person getting
this response has to wait a half a
second for that to complete and then you
do the rest of the work of the request
50 milliseconds whatever so a 100
millisecond request now takes 600
milliseconds so that's not really
acceptable so really this history is
about how do we make these GC pauses
shorter and more interleaved throughout
at the application actually running
so let's start with 1.8 this 1.8 employ
and as far as I know from Ruby's
inception employed a mark and sweep
garbage collection algorithm this is
really the simplest possible garbage
collection algorithm that you can have
so to talk about how mark-and-sweep
works I need to explain to you how Ruby
organizes this memory Ruby objects are
organized in something called the object
space sometimes this is called the heap
but I find that slightly confusing
object spaces the name of the module
that you can use to inspect the object
space so I'm just gonna call this part
of the Ruby's heap the object space it's
basically just a list of Ruby objects so
every Ruby object has one R value which
is the name of the C structure it you
that we're hold these Ruby objects right
our values are 40 bytes and they contain
some information about the Ruby object
it's just a list of values just a list
of some flags like have we marker this
object yet for garbage collection some
other some other information and also
some very basic information about the
object this all depends on what type of
object it is if it's a string and array
etc etc etc if it's a string you know if
it's a very small string we can contain
that string right in the R value it's
actually like 23 bytes or smaller is
like a whole great blog post by Pat
Shaughnessy about why Ruby can only
store 23 byte strings inside the R value
if the data is too large to store in the
R value so strings longer than 24
characters or arrays of 5 elements or
more so if it's too big to fit in that R
value we just store the pointer to space
somewhere else on Ruby's heap the object
space is a list of 16 kilobyte heap
pages and of 400 R values each so it's
just a long list of these these heat
pages which each which contain all of
our are our values so what triggers GC I
think one common misconception is that
GC just sort of well people don't really
understand when it runs at all that kind
of runs
Loup more like it runs every five
seconds or whatever really there are two
main things that trigger GC although
there's more conditions in this that I'm
not gonna get into either we run out of
open slots for new our values or we
allocate enough memory on the heap that
triggers that that passes a limit so if
we just run out of object slots we have
to we have to get new slots right so our
Ruby will garbage collect to try to
reuse the slots that it has already
allocated for itself the other malloc
limit is when so I like I said if in a
string for examples a thousand
characters long it's gonna have to
allocate space on the heap for that
thousand character string because it
doesn't fit in the R value right so
that's a thousand characters which would
be a 8000 bytes or whatever or bits so
once that the amount of space that we
allocate in that way crosses a certain
threshold we garbage collect okay that's
called the malloc limit there's also
some other limits which I'm not going to
talk about but those are kind of the
main things that end up triggering GC
and Ruby so we trigger a GC we're gonna
start with the root objects and root
objects are things like classes
constants things that don't get garbage
collected ever so we start with like you
know the rails that application object
and then we're gonna look for all the
references of that object and traversed
out in the object graph so each object
that references rails dot application
for example which I don't know if is
really a route object or not maybe rails
dot is but anyway we started our route
object
Traverse down the object graph until
we've marked everything that references
each other and then any object at the
end of that which hasn't been marked is
free because it's nothing's referencing
it right pretty simple and then all the
three are value slots get added to the
free list simple as that and then in the
future and then so that's that's the
marking phase and then
I just say marking phase and then sweep
puts objects into the free list okay so
setting the mark bits marking objects is
one phase sweeping them into the free
list is the next and then the next time
we need an R value slot for an object we
just grab one off the free list if we
run out of even if after garbage
collection if we still don't have any
any free slots then we allocate more
slots using malloc to put more slot to
create more heat pages and get more
slots
we're in 1.8 this is done with the FL
mark flag this is one of the flags in
our value at the time and you just set
that to 1 or 0 after you mark an object
if it was 0 when you were all done
marking that was a free object of course
sorry I should say an object that could
be freed during sweeping so garbage
collection looked like this you had a
whole long mark phase a whole long
Sweetface then you were done with GC you
could go do whatever you wanted to do
and then you have two GC again
eventually in a long Mark phase a long
sweep phase sweeping always immediately
came after marking there's no pause in
between and so in a large rails
application that had 400,000 objects you
know even a million active objects this
could take a very long time you know
could take a million million objects
could take a second to to mark all the
way through right because we have to
mark through the entire object graph so
that takes a long time
no Ruby can be executed during that time
and like I said that's not really
convenient for a web application where
if normally your responses only take ten
milliseconds to process if someone gets
10 milliseconds plus one second of GC
pause that that's kind of annoying and
not really performant so next came 1.8
Ruby Enterprise Edition this is a
project of fusion with the guys that
write the passenger web server this was
kind of like the big I don't know if
anyone's anyone here use Ruby Enterprise
Edition that's kind of like old-school
now yeah
so like it had a couple things going for
it one of it
was its support for copy-on-write memory
so let's talk about copy-on-write we
have these things called forking web
servers in Ruby because we don't have
real concur real parallelism I should
say you can't execute two bits of Ruby
code at the same time so what we do
instead is we have two different
processes two different web server
processes that are the same right and
can just execute different responses at
the same time so Puma which I am on the
committee team for is an example of a
forking web server also passenger and
Unicorn do that and when you fork a
process the child process shares its
memory with the parent to the extent
that it can and it does that through
copy-on-write memory so we have to talk
about shared versus private memory so
the child process when it gets fork from
the parent gets a not a copy but it gets
some addresses that looks like a copy of
the parents memory and that's shared
memory and it's just the exact copy of
the parents processes memory but
whenever it tries to modify one of the
child process tries to modify one of
those those memory pages the operating
system in the background will copy it so
it it's kind of like a copy on-demand
thing right so it's very important when
when are you writing to memory locations
in a in a child process because that'll
create a copy which will increase your
memory usage so this copy and write is
the whole reason that when you have a
puma process with three workers you
don't see exactly three times the memory
usage that you do when you have when you
have one process because we're sharing
some small portion you know ten to
thirty percent of that memory between
the child and the process this is the
whole reason why you why you pre-boot or
preload depending on what your your web
server is so we the idea is that you
load the entire application first before
forking so you can share the maximum
amount of memory possible right the
problem with this right
you remember my description of how 1.8
worked we touched the FL mark flag every
time we
mark so you set the mark from 0 to 1 and
1 to 0 and that touches that memory
location which ends up copying the
memory page so we couldn't garbage
collect without breaking copy-on-write
by we every time you garbage collected
it would create copies of all the memory
in the child process and now you're back
to where you started with memory usage
so that was kind of inconvenient and was
kind of wasteful use of memory Ruby
Enterprise Edition fix that with a
method I'm going to talk about later
because we got it for in corn - I know
and brooby enterprise edition ended up
using the exact same method that that to
dotto used so we'll talk about that in a
minute
in the meantime 1.9 which I think
actually came in dot 3 now here on
nakamura gave us lazy sweeping so the
whole idea is you don't sweep until you
need it it's we're about where we're
trying to break the sweep phase into
multiple smaller phases we're still
gonna have one big long stop the world
mark but we're gonna sweep only in
smaller increments when we actually need
it which is when we you know need new
slots so we just sweep until we have
some enough free objects to have to deal
with whatever we're alloc where whatever
objects we're creating and then we go
back to program execution until we need
more slots and then sweep again so we're
doing the mark phase just like we did in
1.8 but then we'll sweep a little bit
immediately for whatever we needed but
then we'll we'll go back to program
execution and then sweep objects into
the free list only as necessary so this
decrease is the worst case times right
because rather than having one long mark
followed by one very long sweep you have
one mark followed by several smaller
sweeps so the worst case that you could
have for a GC pause time was greatly
reduced
so mark sweep sweep sweep and then mark
again
into dotto we got official copy-on-write
support I mean technically you're always
supporting copy-on-write just either
works well or it doesn't work at all
like consol copy-on-write only happens
at the operating system level so
technically like you already supported
it you just didn't take advantage of it
really and we got that through something
called bitmap marking which is another
node nakamura commits the whole idea
with with bitmap marking is okay well if
touching the FL mark bit on the R value
triggers that that copy let's just keep
the mark but somewhere else we're in in
different memory locations so that when
we cop when we when we touch it
we're only copying mark bits and we're
not copying this forty byte or value
object and that's done through bit
mapping so instead of keeping the FL
mark bit in our value we keep it in two
separate array of bits and we can get
that it's it's not like a point or
anything it's just a dress
so if our our value is that you know
memory address 0 X whatever we just do
some arithmetic to calculate where the
mark bit is that's done to do something
called memory address aligning so you
can just do some arithmetic to figure
that out to figure out where the the bit
for marking is so that makes Ruby
copy-on-write friendly yay and just saw
a pretty big memory reduction usage for
for people using forking web servers and
it's still marking with lazy sweeping so
we're still marked with sweeps usefully
we just kind of changed where the mark
bit actually resides right it now
resides in a separate area not in the
are value there are a couple more bits
now that our bitmap marked in this way
that aren't stored in our value I will
probably get to those in a bit
in 2.1 we got generational garbage
collection this is what we start to
don't want anybody start seeing some
some actually like big changes and how
GC is actually done this was written by
Koo Chi sasada who's a rails core Ruby
core team member works for Heroku now
actually doesn't work for Heroku anymore
works for Cooke pad did work for Heroku
for a while but one of the few people
paid to work on MRI and the whole idea
with generational garbage collection is
that certain objects are going to be
marked as the old generation and certain
objects are gonna be marked and certain
the other objects are just gonna be new
objects new objects become old when they
survive a certain amount of garbage
collections I don't think this is
actually the correct number for what it
wasn't in 2.1 now it's if you survive
three collections you are promoted three
if you survive three marking phases i
should say you're now promoted to an old
object back then I think it might have
been less now we have minor and major
GCS so the whole reason you have
generational garbage collection is is
this based on this thesis that most
objects die young most objects are just
around for the duration of a web request
or whatever and then they can be garbage
collected after that and traversing old
objects looking for stuff to garbage
collect they're like if you're going
through the Ruby code if you're go if
you're going through you know all the
objects that get created when Rails
starts up it's kind of inefficient to
traverse those objects every time we
mark right because they're not going
anywhere the only objects that we're
probably gonna go somewhere are the ones
that we just created
like you know request headers or
whatever so during a minor GC we're only
going to look at new objects to mark and
during a major GC we're gonna look at
all objects for a look at new and old
objects in the marking phase so all
we've done is just created two different
kinds of marking phases the problem is
now you have to keep track of
these different kinds of objects so the
way that this gets explained and I'm
pretty sure this is how it works in GC
Otzi's we have three different colors we
have black gray and white all objects
start is white then all root objects
which I explained did 1.8 root objects
get colored gray and then from each gray
object we're gonna traverse the object
graph and look at all the references and
we're going to turn those objects gray
then when we're done when we marked all
the references to this object gray we
turn the original object black then we
keep going through the tree until all
objects are black or white okay now the
problem is when we have a black object
that refers directly to a white objects
that shouldn't happen right only gray
objects should refer to white objects to
solve this problem we have something
called the right barrier the right
barrier just is a barrier for realizing
whenever the an object creates a
reference to another object so we we put
a barrier between you being able to
reference an object directly the right
barrier is used to implement what was
originally called sunny and shady
objects now it's called right barrier
protected and unprotected sunny objects
are protected by right barriers shady
objects are not and the reason we do
this is because with a sunny object we
can track when new references get added
to it shady objects we can't in the
generational garbage collector we have
to check shady objects every minor every
garbage collection during minor and
major because we can't know whether or
not you added a new reference to that
object or not and sunny objects we know
whether or not you did so we can
actually promote them to old generation
and then not look at them for for new
references all right explain that so
sunny or unripe are your unprotected
objects can never become old they can
never be promoted to the
generation we have to check them during
every minor garbage collection now the
one of the major sources of ripe berry
or unprotected objects are see
extensions if a see extension has direct
access to the Ruby object if it knows
where it is in memory we can't we can't
be sure that that see extension hasn't
added some references or that isn't
using that object so we cannot promote
those objects right barrier and
protected objects the right barrier
unprotected objects are added to
something called the remembered set the
remembered set just contains right
barrier and protected objects and any
old generation objects which have a new
object added to them which we detect via
the right barrier so if you have I got
old a let's say it like a big array that
you're adding and removing objects from
and you it's like a stack or something
that you use throughout the whole
application so it it's it's becomes an
old object okay when you add a new
element to that array we want to make
sure that doesn't get garbage collected
right because if we if a minor GC
marking phase happens we've added a new
object to this old array that new object
if we didn't have the right barrier
would get garbage collected because an
old object wouldn't we don't look at the
old objects during this minor GC marking
phase and so that may that means that
our new object is white and so it'll get
garbage collect is that we don't think
that it has any references to it but the
right barrier means that when we create
that reference when we add the white new
object to the old black array we will
catch that and Ruby says ah okay I will
add this old object to the remembered
set so I will check it during the next
line or GC
okay so now garbage collection looks
like this this is what we had in 2.0 and
also 1.9 this this I should say this
diagram and the previous diagram are
from Kui cheese talk about ruby 2.2 GC
so these are all koishi's diagrams this
is what we had in 1.9 3 and 2.0 you had
a long mark phase and a short lazy sweep
and you just swept objects into the free
list as you needed them then in
generational GC we have 2 we introduced
the two different types of GCS minor and
major minor GCS are quicker because
there are fewer new objects than there
are total objects right so you have a
short mark phase followed by short
sweeps
once you've done and then there's major
GC which is the same as it was before
major GC in Ruby 2.1 and up took exactly
the same amount of time that a regular
GC did in 2.0 and below just because
it's not any different in fact it
probably took a little bit longer
because now you have to keep track of
the object age slightly longer or not
like anything crazy different so the
whole advantage here is most of the time
we're gonna be doing minor GCS and you
can check this yourself if you look at g
c dot statin any running ruby process
you can see how many minor and major GCS
it's it's done and usually you'll see
minor GCS happen twice as often as major
GCS and sometimes more depending on the
age of the process and like what you're
doing with it so that's great
it means we have shorter pause times on
average which means that we're less
likely to have some big GC pause during
the request we still have them though
with major GCS because well this is just
the same as it was in 2.0 is there
anything else that I'm missing I don't
think so
okay so we still have this problem right
a long major GC mark faces so we'll fix
that with incremental GC in 2.2 again
this is a KU Ichi project so the whole
idea with incremental GC is well let's
just break up the mark face let's just
break the mark phase in this into
shorter bits and so we can execute Ruby
during the the pauses in marking now
there's a lot of problems here because
like I said the whole reason it's easier
to just stop then and not execute Ruby
during marking is because then you don't
have to keep track of all the stuff that
happens in between when you start adding
stuff to arrays that you thought that
you marked already but then you got to
keep track of all the stuff that you
added to stuff you already marked that's
not good
so total GC time will remain the same
the idea wasn't to make GC time quicker
it was just to reduce the amount of
total time we spend in these long pauses
and this is the point where out of ban
GC becomes not a thing anymore in rubia
people still somewhat do this although
it's kind of dangerous out of ban GC was
basically the idea that before a request
in a web application you could disable
the GC with GC disabled or whatever do
your requests in response and then
enable the GC again now that has a lot
of problems and it's kind of dicey
because you know what happens if GC
doesn't get Rhian abled somehow what
happens if during a request you allocate
a bajillion objects and now GC is
disabled so well you need a bajillion
Meg's of RAM right so it was always kind
of a dicey proposition and at this point
if we can make mark phases shorter which
means that our maximum pause time for GC
ever is going to be 10 15 milliseconds
well then what's the point about AB and
GC right it's just kind of like adding
this possible failure point when the
maximum GC pause is only 15 seconds it's
not like a huge benefit out of moving it
out of the request depending on you know
your application and what your goals are
or whatever so but this is the problem I
was talking about is is that we can get
half we can we can do a mark phase and
then execute some more Ruby but now
objects which you've already marked can
have new white objects directly
referring to them which isn't which
isn't good because we don't we don't go
back and look at black objects again
usually right so this just goes back to
the right barrier now the right barrier
in addition to tracking old generation
objects which get new references to new
objects written which sorry old objects
which track references to new objects
now we just have to do that basically
all the time during
after a mark phase is over we check the
right barrier for objects which got new
references to them so it just adds the
other things to the remembered set you
can check the route size of the
remembered set in GC stat again I
recommend just taking a look at this
it's kind of opaque like the keys are a
little bit hard to figure out what they
mean and GC dots that changes a lot it
changes in every ruby version pretty
much so but you can get an idea the
remembered objects just sort of like
just right in there and it also tell you
like how many objects are protected by
the right barrier and how many are not
from a practical perspective the white
barrier now is so important after 2.24
incremental and generational GC what you
might have caught is that this means
that C extensions which touch or make
shady or you know basically remove the
right barrier from large numbers of
objects that could be really bad right
because the more objects which are not
protected by the right barrier the more
objects we have to check every minor GC
which isn't the right which isn't the
idea we're trying to make minor GCS as
short as possible so I've never seen
this happen in production because I
don't know of any C accession that has
that does it but it would be interesting
because that bug is kind of possible
where a a C extension touches tons of
Ruby objects makes them shady slash
right barrier and protected and suddenly
your minor GC pauses are just as long as
your majors and and you've lost the
benefit of of generational and
incremental GC kind of interesting
symbol GC we also got that at 2.2 it's
not really that complicated now I've got
symbols or garbage-collected 22.3 not
much changed that was 2.2 was kind of
like the last major change to the
garbage collector that we've gotten
koishi introduced a new experimental
write barrier in 2.3
which his assumption was that we can
assume new objects referred to from old
objects are probably also long-lived
objects so if we add a new object to an
old generation object we're gonna assume
that this new object will probably
become an old object it's probably gonna
stick around for a while so for example
adding a item to an array and a config
file right so if you I can only give
like really specific century examples
but changing a setting that can fake
right you're adding a new out you're
creating a new object you add it to your
your config object that object's gonna
stick around for a while and it would be
better if we just made it old right away
because if we made it old right away it
doesn't have to be marked for three
minor GCS and we could just ignore it
until the next major the problem with
this is well what happens if that object
isn't you know it is not going to become
an old object so if you have like my
stack example from from earlier if you
have some stack object in your
application that you're constantly
taking items in and out of with this new
algorithm that any object added to your
long living stack would automatically
get marked in the old generation so that
wouldn't be great because you're taking
stuff in and out of it all the time so
that would greatly increase the memory
usage of your of your stack I guess this
is tournament didn't work or he didn't
like the results because it still
commented out in the Ruby GC dot C code
it's still in there I don't know what
what he ended up thinking about it but
it's not been enabled yet you can mess
with it if you know how to you know
compile Ruby and want to comment it out
or whatever but kind of interesting 2.4
we got a couple more little changes you
now can control somewhat the amount of
three slots Ruby tries to keep open so
the whole idea with GC and trigger when
it triggers and and how many slots and
how often we wanted to trigger
is that GC is expensive takes time we
don't want to do it that often so when
we do do it we're going to try to make
sure we don't have to do it very often
again so what Ruby does is let's say you
have a million free slots and you have
to garbage collect okay nothing got
garbage selected everything is being
used up so we still have a million slots
but we need more room Ruby will grow the
amount of slots by a factor and that
factor I think by default now is 1.4 so
with a million free slots we need more
slots we're gonna grow to a 1.4 million
slot heap that factor is configurable by
an environment variable but let's say we
get to 1.4 million whatever and then
five minutes later would you see again
and now we're only using 500,000 about
1.4 million slots well that's kind of
inefficient right we should return some
of that space back to the operating
system if we can and that is what that
control over that ratio of what ratio
between used and empty slots is now
control is now configurable I should say
in Ruby 2.4 by an environment variable
these environment variables I talked
about them sometimes it talks but I tell
people not to touch them usually if you
can find them in GCC you're probably
also smart enough to figure out what
exactly they do it's very easy to
a Ruby process and you just copy
and paste someone else's settings for
these things so I don't I don't even
tell people where to find them or or how
to look at them but if you can find them
in GCC that see your you can probably
figure out how to use them but this is
an interesting one because one thing
that I see a lot in production with with
Ruby processes is they get in their
steady state where am I at
okay in their long-term steady-state
after six hours or whatever they have
too many free slots and and they're not
returning those free slots back if they
can so this and that which means a
long-term higher memory usage right so
I'm I've been interested in this I
haven't played with it yet to see if it
reduces long-term memory usage for
people's real applications part of the
problem with returning free slots back
to the operating system and I've talked
about this in other talks is is memory
fragmentation Ruby can only release a a
slot back to the operating system if the
entire heap page so 400 slots in the
page have to all be free
that's called a tomb page if you see
that referred to anywhere in in Ruby a
heap page with an object in it is an
Eden page and a heap with no a page with
no objects in it is a tomb page so page
has to be a tomb page for us to release
it back to the operating system because
we can't move objects around the heap
okay because we don't the see see right
barrier unprotected objects right these
are referred to by C extensions they
have just the direct memory address
there's no there's no indirection
between that C API access and where that
object resides in memory so we can't
move the object otherwise we break the C
extension so that means we can't move
objects around and which in turn means
we can't free pages back unless there's
no slots being used in the page which
happens about never it's very easy for
the Ruby object space and heap to look
like Swiss cheese with you know a new
old object here and then a bunch of new
objects and an old objects and when that
gets garbage collected it just looks
like this big Swiss cheese heap there's
a couple of things which are being done
to help with this so let's talk about
those now we talked about the future
about where we're we're where Ruby GCC
seems to be going
and that the main thing I think that
most people are gonna be interested in
is garbage compaction which is moving
objects around the object space and
moving them around the heap to make them
less Swiss cheesy and more Gruyere I
don't look like a not cheat about holes
in it I don't know JRuby and truffle and
truffle Ruby already do this cuz they're
on the JVM or or growl or whatever and
those garbage collectors are compacting
or at least some of the JVM garbage
collectors compact so they get to take
advantage of all that for free and it
just compact for them and that's great
Aaron Patterson has been working on this
after a hallway conversation in Ruby
comp he realized that basically we might
be able to move some objects around the
heap so long as we don't have any we can
make sure that they're not being
referred to by C extensions and he's
been working on that if you follow his
twitter he's been posting about it every
once in a while it's a very interesting
project it will that we'll never be able
to move all objects around the heap but
we might be able to move some of them
and improve fragmentation and and being
able to return some memory back to the
operating system somewhat so what this
means in the long term is that your big
long term Ruby processes will probably
use somewhat less RSS or memory in the
long term
another approach here rather besides
being able to move objects around is to
just put them in separate areas to begin
with so if we have an object and we need
to put that object somewhere right if we
think that this object is probably going
to be old and it's probably gonna stick
around we're gonna put that in one pile
and then any object like an instance
variable that we think is not going to
be around for a long time will put that
another pile and in theory what that
means is our old object pile will be
less fragmented than our new object pile
right because old objects probably won't
get garbage collected and all the new
objects that'll get frequently freed up
and whatever so that should reduce
memory fragmentation and therefore
less total RSS usage Guild's so everyone
talks about guilds probably not coming
for a while but I was told Ruby 2.6 a
2.7 so guilds will have this it will be
sharing the same object space in the
plan right now I mean this is all super
early whatever but guilds are Ruby's
future planned concurrency model if
you're not familiar with this but the
idea is that these guilds are going to
be sort of like lightweight processes
almost and they will share the same heap
so everything that I've talked about and
all this garbage collection is not going
to change when we get guilds I've but
sort of an interesting side note for
more reading I suggest these three
authors Pat Shaughnessy wrote a great
book called ruby under the microscope
which is the starting point if you want
to learn more about how ruby works
internally
coochi has written a couple things
online in english about how ruby garbage
collection works and sam saffron of
discourse has as well if this was
interesting to you i have a course
called the complete guide to rails
performance which is a bunch of
screencasts in a very long book about
optimizing rails applications it's all a
trail speed comm you may have seen my
blog it kind of looks like this I write
about Ruby performance from time to time
and that blog is at speed shop dot Co
thank you very much
we have more than five minutes for
questions
yeah container space containers
containers containers it was talking
about into yes where do you see Ruby
not just in Jordan where else would be
writing in within the container space
because I just tend to say just pretty
good last pretty much everyone does
already because yeah sure sure so the
question was like how do I see Ruby
fitting into containers I think the fact
is that most people run Ruby in a
container already because most people
run Ruby on Heroku which uses lxc where
terence go
yeah well Terence is even talk next
could maybe even say a little bit more
about it but
Viroqua uses lxc I think which is
containers and so it's really not or
hypervisor or whatever so I don't see a
lot of people running Ruby on docker yet
but most people are running Ruby already
in a containerized environment whether
they realize it or not or depending on
your definition of container I think
what's interesting and what kind of
relates back to this talk is that most
people running in these environments
tend to run them in very resource
constrained environments and memory is
usually constraint in these environments
you know like the default Heroku dynos
size right is like 512 megabytes which
is enough really half a rails process so
I think people's memory knowledge is
important for being able to shove big
old legacy rails applications into small
containers but increasingly I'm starting
to think that CPU is also an extremely
important thing in these environments
like Amazon's V CPUs or just hyper
threads so like you can have like 8
gigabytes of RAM and then get like 2
hyper threads so that's like nothing you
know you can run like 1.5 Puma processes
on that so I got to do some benchmarking
and look at this
more but like memory is a very important
constraint and understanding how it
works and and when GC occurs is going to
help you with shoving stuff into these
small containers but CPU is also
increasingly scarce resource and that in
the in the cloud yeah that's so the
question is like we've also the the
other side the flip side which I didn't
talk about of trying to reduce GC memory
pressure is just don't allocate new
objects in the first place Joe so the
example was pushing frozen string
literals so I think was it - dot - we
got the magic comment at the top of the
file that was frozen string literal you
could just make the whole file sorry 2.3
okay okay so that frozen string literal
and the dot freeze or whatever right was
intended so that we freeze an object so
it's just not garbage collected right so
you kind of like it's almost like
hinting for the garbage collector
because you're just saying hey don't
ever collect this the object is not ever
gonna get collected right so I I was
also interested in that I actually asked
koishi about frozen string literal the
magic comment at rubyconf and because I
think part of the original promise of
the magic comment was that you would
that they were they were thing about
making that core language feature that
just all strings would all be frozen and
so it was sort of an experiment to put
in the runtime to see like okay does
that actually make people's app
patience faster koishi feels and I also
sort of feel that that hasn't really
been a huge performance impact just
either not enough stuff can be frozen or
when you do free stuff you end up
creating new strings any wave to create
the copy or whatever and you sort of
lose whatever gains you thought you had
so I haven't seen any real world benefit
major real world benefit from that in it
it doesn't seem like it's gonna change
or become like a that bat path where
where we're at right now with freezing
objects doesn't seem like it's gonna
change to me so much in the future I
asked him that in the context of guilds
right because the whole thing with
guilds is we can share frozen objects
between gilts as we know they're not
going to be modified right so we can
share these these frozen objects between
the different processes without fear of
modification so I said well you know
isn't that when we want to create more
shared objects then and I guess koishi
feels that that's the way that it is
currently is adequate I guess for the
connection
are you considering I could listen which
we reserved locality or like like the
mobis algorithm which also this point
locality yeah so I am NOT a ruby core
developer I've never committed to Ruby
actually I don't think yeah so the
person you have to ask is Aaron
Patterson because he's the one doing all
the work and compaction in in see Ruby
right now so if you just google Aaron
Patterson Ruby and you'll find him he's
hard to miss yeah I I think that that's
kind of like what has been talked about
with putting objects in an old heap and
a new heap that the new heap you know
your your
preserving locality that way I guess but
that's that's kinda outside my area of
expertise to be honest yeah yeah the
question was how can we make the GC
learn how to perform based how to make
decisions based on the actual
application performance they're there
you think I don't really think there's
anything in GCC right now I think that
could be described as doing that I think
all the important knobs really are set
by environment trails beforehand what
one thing that Ruby GC does do is these
thresholds like for increasing the heap
size do change because it's like based
on a ratio right like 1.4 is as a ratio
of the current heap slots used there's
also ways to cap that like you can say
1.4 or 300,000 heap slots whichever is
less so there's some like changes in
these thresholds as the application
executes but I wouldn't describe it as
the the run time learning about itself I
think that's interesting because one of
the problems that that MRI core
maintainer z' have is you know rails
long running rails processes have like
one very specific set of behavior and
then there's people that you know still
use Ruby for ten line you know sysadmin
scripts and then someone comes in to
that sometimes in another discussion and
says hey wait a second you can't do that
because you're gonna break my 64
megabytes of RAM
you know Raspberry Pi whatever you know
like some crazy environment that they
were on Ruby on Ruby is is has to has to
cater to all these use cases
yeah and so there's just so many
different ways that you can run Ruby
that it's difficult for a core language
maintainer to to make aggressive
decisions for one workload or another
workload so that's an interesting path
forward as far as I know nothing has
really been done on that front yet thank
you