[Music]
okay
it's not about earlier
[Music]
okay so now I'm too loud my name is very
cancer I've been working on data plane
technologies for the last eight or ten
years
[Music]
DPD ka VPP and i know t LD k tonight
with you today i'm going to talk about
CTL DK and why we'll have a while
interested in accelerating tcp void tcp
performance matters well I guess
performance is really a heavily a part
of user experience you know in the
wireless network TCP dominates TCP makes
up a bell I think 95 percent of traffic
in the cellular network about 4% is UDP
the rest of its in the noise TCP flows
tend to be small which is problematic
means that you go to all the effort of
setting up your flows and then you know
transfer about four kilobits sorry
kilobytes and that's literally the size
of the size of the very most of close
and then to get torn down again so it's
relatively extent expensive in this
connection setup and teardown our most
of the flows actually transfer very very
very little they also have other
artifacts in TCP you know
and part of the spec that makes small
flow is even more problematic teams like
tcp slow-start so you may not be
familiar with this book yo tcp starts
off slowly it'll send one packet on wait
for an arc and then it'll send two
packets on wait for that that's flying
if you've got a very very very long
connection but if you're only having a
short connection it can be quite a can
be play again make it even more
expensive pretty interesting 97 percent
the connections don't use peer to peer 3
percent of it so 97% of connections 97%
connections that don't use to peer about
70 or 70 percent of their traffic is
again HTTP TCP so TCP dominates wire
line network as well so ok it's a huge
part of the equation in wireless
networks networks this is where the
problems start to creep in compared to
the compared to TCP wireless is
relatively lossy your connect your cell
phone will be connected them they're not
connected and that's perfectly normal
well from TCP its point of view it looks
like it's lost packets things like
congestion control if they can lost
version those kinds of things they kick
in even though it's a perfectly normal
thing for your pure cell phone to go
away in the wild line Network you have
things like impedance mismatch you might
have hundreds coming into a box
may only a 100 maggot DSL line so then
you run into problems like both uploads
so your your pork downloads are crowding
out your clothing out your your web
browsing so if you're doing let's say
you're doing let's say video streaming
at the same time as you're browsing the
web which is not uncommon these days for
people to be flicking around on Twitter
commenting on the TV show while watching
the TV show for Netflix the whole
Twitter responds is a key part of UX
user experience for the person flicking
around on Twitter
so this is giving rise to the advent of
user space TCP stacks people working
while you typically see is people who
are developing applications in the
datacenter many of them actually develop
TCP stacks to go alongside their
applications so was recently published
by Gerry Chu from Google commented that
they had something like half a dozen to
a dozen individual TCP stacks inside
Google just simply an application
application that has some nice
advantages as a design approach that has
some nice advantages one of us is that
you RFC compliance so typically all
these panels have a fairly supportive
group fairly broad set of RFC's which is
pretty cool which is pretty nice BSD Sox
API so if I'm taking an off-the-shelf
application like around your necks
everybody's favorite applications choice
engine X and it's very easy to glue the
two together also the total total cost
of ownership so if I'm using a BSD stack
or a neck PST PST stack or Linux
top FTP BK all in that map then as
security problems emerge upstream I saw
get CVE patches I get performance fixes
I got maintenance that sac is maintained
so it's a valence of the attractive way
to implement a user space TCP stack
so along the come along with that
approach comes with costs so those kind
of stats make assumptions that they're
actually running in the kernel so you
have to jump through some hoops to get
those tournament stacks to run and be
held themselves in userspace the kernel
threads will make assumptions like that
they're running in the kawah and that
are not going to be running in the same
context as the user space thread that
made the system call to which they're
reacting so it's you have to don't use
some hoops to get these stacks to behave
in userspace typical things that typical
things that people evaluate look for in
the user space tcp shotgun it's very
heavily around connections per second
you're fine lost my train to talk so in
userspace PCB stocks when you go back to
the previous slide giving rise to the
development of userspace TCC stacks is
the prioritization of performance and
optimization it's an optimized piece for
TCP stack and user space in which you
can really optimize for use cases like
performance use cases like connections
per second your true port your request
response latency so the actual user
space application that's processing the
bitstream is running on the same core in
which the bitstream are received so that
you can do stuff like eliminating
context switching so if I have I will
typically do a select our way for user
input that way for a packet to arrive
that's one context switch and then I
will do a read whenever the packet does
arrive and that's a newer context switch
and then I figure out it hasn't actually
haven't actually received enough
information to do use forum permit the
useful work and I'll do another context
video motor select away for more
information to arrive so lots of context
switching so what does TLB K T over K
- okay is there a high-performance rare
for implementation implemented on top of
design so the bottom three points they
talked about in the last slide you know
the two possible performance that we can
achieve on the platform so that means
that we're going to leave some stuff on
the table so you don't get to be a Steve
stocks compatible API you won't get the
same that look like or if CFC compliant
the fastest possible TCP implementation
that you can build on the general
purpose CPU and that's really that's
what we complained create so in the
creation of TLD k we will use the PDK
design concepts so we do processing
improves IPC we do things like use
vector instructions where where we can
to keep the instruction cache warm so
that instead of pushing one packet Rou
the saccule processing multiple packets
at the same time to keep your
instruction cat cache warm will aim to
cache coherency so that there's an
affinity between a given network device
between the stack that processes to
network device and then also the
application that needs the tcp stream
that's received on that network device
so you have an end
between performance support common TCP
options select acknowledgment features
implementation based on 220 VAR self we
support things like to know the
acknowledgments work and support
congestion control with also support hot
the common hardware offload so you might
choose to use or assess you might use
teachers use TSO you might use to choose
to use sign filtering make performs as
fast as possible and then also we're
going to provide call an example so one
of the nice things you get with the BTK
ones when they download DVD k it gets my
sample code i've written some of of
myself that actually shows different use
cases like l2 forward and
l-3 forwarding we're going to do the
same with TL DK we will have a sample
directory that would show up use cases
like transfer you like transparent proxy
and I'll talk about some of those use
cases that we would like to show off
later okay
so so the application protocol typing
application so what you said typically
see with TCP applications is something
next time we will continue to do useful
work rather is useful what to do so we
will so we will do batch processing so
we were batch but we will not read
packets off the network device and then
we will batch read we will iterate
through streams and then iterate through
packets received on streams so we will
continue to pole and continue to work in
the DPD case Island the batch processing
stuff and continue to work well what to
do will never block so the application
is driving is driving the protocol on a
protocol judgment application so tree
core design concepts the first is low
context your context is really an
individual instance of the stack you
typically have one context pair core you
may have more than one context protocol
that's okay too but there is an affinity
between the content between the context
in the given core
have devices now all we're doing is
implementing a layer for implementation
we're not doing a layer two we're not
doing the layer 3 implementation
somewhere else you might choose to you
in many cases people have their own on
top of DVD K that they'll want to use
for all we're doing is a layer for
implementation
so we TLD K a hazard has a notion after
being a device underneath and that
device has capabilities advantages
[Music]
achieved by using is which is
essentially on the back end on your
application all of which ones we also
will support the right-hand side where
you have a background in your context on
one core with your actual content can
read and write this tree like the
streams from other course
so this was the bit where I was supposed
to support talk about both GDP and TCP
performance on top of Thiele on top of
TL DK typically happen with these things
that there was a whole drag around
licensing costs for that the benchmark
TCP and then there was also an unhappy
incident involving an error on that kind
of numbers today I will talk about it I
will talk about TCP performance as well
performance is about seven million
packets per second for one thing you
know m4 is very stable guys you add
[Music]
applications typically are is they took
more codes you give you get a little
stale when you're scaling initial try
bits for connections per second is about
connections per second for that we're
trying positive for that so that means
that you'll be able to set down I'm to
set up and tear down half a million - 1
million connections per second for core
which is pretty exceptional performance
okay
okay so some of the news cases that were
aiming for deepening our claims are
typically proved now forced on network
nodes and hopefully t LD k won't be any
exception to this so we're going to
start off at PCP aggregation points in
the network and there's two I find
interesting
the first one is transparent and
transparent proxies and transparent
proxies are pretty widely deployed in
the cellular network turn to foreign
proxies elect okay with the fact that
tcp going milks when your cell phone
disappears on reappears on the cellular
network so that typically happens in the
transparent proxy is that what's the
same go by between your cell phone on
the server and then they will create a
shadow connection once that shadow
connection is set up so as your cell
phone communicates with the cell as a
consultant communicates with the server
and send intelligence from the server
which returns and acknowledges as the
server returned packets that means that
if your cell phone disappears for a few
million for a few milliseconds and it's
not there to send the acts that the
server doesn't start sending those
packets are necessarily appears on your
network the tcp back in the network the
tcp proxy stands on the sender's a sense
on those pockets so such things like the
typical last control mechanisms of tcp
bouncer so this is more of a davis and
reuse case so the in the datacenter you
typically have a reverse proxy lower
balancer that sits back and sits
directly behind your front end it
terminates HTTP it serves up static
content itself and then it requests for
dynamic content to the web service
behind
you know implementations that are
interesting to you contributions
contributing use cases that are
contributing code
for fellow travelers to follow us
that's question so I have a few minutes
for questions if there's any questions
I'm sorry
to replant okay so the question is to
climb any MTC piece to this point that's
an interesting one because that's
actually interested them not calling
people I'd love to hear more that's
something that's interesting to you
because I know it's heavily used
particularly in cell phones right
improve performance in culprit mobility
so if that's something that's
interesting I'd love to talk about
afterwards
[Music]
those are the a specular host
so the
see how to get you been down here