introducing from
for panic we have Ian I Berg who will be
talking about adventures and building in
[Applause]
[Music]
this room
because that's its own utility just to
show you how to orchestrate certain
tasks with unique rules because at the
end of the day it's not just about
running smack here and so we can say
this is an operating system but yet I'm
going the Batmen of you host actual
production software on this on this
operating system
[Music]
[Applause]
we're talking about that you know once
again you think about the source of this
of this game and then you think about
how dramatically different
this application is from this
application it's making engine X work
versus the prior application and and you
start thinking what is appropriate to be
putting all my servers so what is this
important like I've asked these
questions but why is this really
important
he's pretty famous in the body works too
at 8016 now and he has this video that
he month ago called the end of cloud
computing if you've got like 30 40
minutes the ball in the next week I
would just watch this it's kind of cool
and he kind of talks about these shifts
in computing that we've been taking like
switching away because closer and closer
to so called edge computing this is
going to force us the developers to
deploy and compute resources in a
different manner than what we've been
used to for a while and I think this is
really going to start driving a lot of
things and in terms of infrastructure
and so forth and this is why I think
this is one reasons why I think this
matters so versus you know that we use
day to day in and out right now if we
look at something like OpenStack is like
the canonical you know if your own
private cloud solution I mean nobody
psyche is probably like where you're
starting right you have to think about
like let this was booked for you know is
for vm's years it's not the size of the
shape the the implementation that we'd
be traversing but the reality is is that
you know the physical as well
[Applause]
you know
[Music]
we got a testing environment staging
that you know we depend on what we're
using you know
cue and so forth and downs manageability
to me is kind of what really defined
modern cloud computing environment it
was that ability to just like instantly
create 100 vm's and then trash them or
cloning them and then push them to
somewhere else and and I think that's
that's a key thing that we we don't even
think about anymore I mean like to
about wind like AWS region goes down for
two minutes out of the year you know and
then compare that to what things were
like maybe 10 15 years ago so so what is
that well there's things like your
service discovery so zookeeper and
that's you being all that sort of stuff
rich which a lot of people I think a lot
of shops don't really need this level
[Applause]
more familiar with like with the reverse
proxies on in genetics that sort of
thing and then you know your resource
aware of scheduling I allow me source
and so forth once again this is not
something that I would expect most small
shops to ever even so something as
simple as deploying most compiled
languages you're actually going to be
creating the new VM each and every
single time you had that deploy button
and you're going to push that image up
to I don't think a lot of shops actually
do when you actually are because once
again you're removing that VM from that
bouncing pool or wherever it's residing
and so you have to think about how that
works the mechanics of it same thing
with fellow gerber so in unique URLs
that's pretty pretty typical to have
virtual memory it's just not really a
concept that seems to work and you curl
and and so if I have an app that just
keeps on requesting more and more memory
and all of a sudden it runs out of
memory you know and it stops responding
to requests and so forth how do you
handle it
do you kill it do you switch it out you
know there's the software that we've
learned him to handle this
for today's orchestrations
that software doesn't quite work in new
current land because of these reasons
and then you start thinking about things
like Lamba and all the service and
functionalist type of paradigms on top
and how they interact with containers
and vm's and so forth and how about
different ways we'll come in to flavor
the ends you can't whatever but in most
cases most people they're going to be
working with vm's and so you might have
ones that are compliant and that's great
because then you can do lots of tricks
but not all of them are and system
you'll just get like a straight-up disk
image to be working with so you know
every CPU in the past like what eight
nine years has the extensions necessary
but they're not always turned on
obviously if you're on Google
you're not gonna want me to do a
hypervisor hypervisor you're have to
actually burn your own AMI there's
software out there that does that it's
it's painful not that it doesn't work
it's painful that the big clouds weren't
really meant for it and of course the
hypervisor situation on the OS X sucks
[Applause]
it's one of these things that you know
as developers we haven't like really had
to do walk down this path before and so
there's so much software that's kind of
missing that can be written
hopefully by people in this audience so
one of the things we're gonna discuss
real quick was debugging unique URLs
this is actually a video up on YouTube
of us where we were debugging a go
unique kernel and of course we're
catching the panics and the stack traces
and you know the GC and everything
not to mention gdb obviously the most
maybe you've all known the bugger out
there besides you know and that's Visual
Studio you know works perfectly fine
here's another example of gdb debugging
ago uni journal this is actually on runs
github wiki and different
implementations have their own
interfaces so this is include os's here
which looks a little bit different now
this is and then one from OS V as well
so the old notion that they're not
debuggable is kind of the next topic
networking and so so once again working
with
[Applause]
[Music]
because you can't pass the frames and so
after you like little tricks with that
and so forth - for the traffic
appropriately from a1 to and so forth
this is a common example what you're
going to run into when you're rolling
your own locations in the program there
was making outgoing connections but your
509 right and so there's a pretty clear
indication that wasn't fine - sir okay
we'll just pop the certain whatever
needs to be figure out where that is and
of course the distro out there and every
single you know different system not
only has a different file name for this
but stores in a completely different
location which is just completely
batshit insane that this is even a thing
this is the that you normally probably
don't have to do when you're on like
Ubuntu or whatever but you do have to
kind of think about and deal with in and
of course you can play with DNS and so
forth as well and DNS mask here is
probably gonna be your friend although
most people just kind of like pass it on
through whatever gateway traffic but you
can also use this for like DHCP so if
you have like a multi-tenant situation
then you can just like DNS mask on that
bridge that you're serving dhcp through
kind of a large subject because there's
so many different things that you can do
with them obviously and so once again if
we go back to some of these tutorials on
the wiki a lot of them like the point at
which is great for some things like if
you have a static website and there's
absolutely no mutation going on that's
great to use that one pod system that is
like inherently totally immutable
because work on any popular language out
there I guarantee you you have some sort
of temp files being read and going
somewhere you got uploads doing
something there's so much crap going on
like I would say won't be and so it's
it's something to think about you know
certain applications that make sense and
applications makes no sense and so when
you're choosing your file system you
want to think about you know which one
to the other
[Music]
once again this gives you running like
that it's and that's the case based
volumes and volume copies so obviously
you probably won't push assistance for
some of these you know the backups and
so forth and of course for life
migration and so forth you know the
volume copies kind of come in handy too
so if I have a database running and I
don't really want to take it offline but
I want that copy of it it's a great way
to go about doing it so these operations
can be done with like ETFs or SX news
it's probably like the I think I think
that tool comes on any Mac right away
and so you can do most of those
operations that make the first I think
it's time to move but once again this is
one of those tools that you find that we
probably want some standard you know we
actually ship these things to like a
tenant situation you might just mount
another block device and then if you're
just playing around and actually
something like what's the worst thing
today and what's the most needed
improvement I would say testing like is
a complete and just to show you how how
crazy this actually is we have a problem
with the go we maintained run for and
basically garbage collection wasn't
happening for a particular it wasn't
happening so we had a batch come in it
fixed it and we're like we should we
should make a regression test to make
sure that it actually is that state and
so this test actually
[Music]
[Applause]
design basically means ssh is off the
window right once again a security
feature we're just gonna make it into
like ten lines of PHP or something it's
not necessary it's just to show you that
if you think outside of the box you can
easily do the exact same thing thousand
different ways and here you can kind of
see the hosts file through like a tin
wine
[Music]
something with volume deploy workflows
so this is a really interesting thing
that once again really only works with
like uni girls you would never do this
with a big vm because it just does not
make any sense but if i want to spin up
like 100 Newton kernels and then like
push out changes to them without
spinning them down this this change
might work and so basically the trick
here is as you can kind of see in this
global proof-of-concept thing CMS or PHP
app says it includes like and so
obviously it's not only continuing the
code because once again we don't
actually have to recompile the actual
kernel itself we're just mounting a new
partition and boom and so this is this
is like Windows examples like you would
never ever do in a regular VM it's just
it's just kind of stupid once again I'm
not sure me unfold screaming this
so we'll show this and
HTML 1 I got to drag this window as well
[Music]
all right so because I apparently am not
so great with the ad the projector but
basically you know we have the HTML
example and then you know we can we can
run like a PHP example doing the same
thing all right so this one is at 4.4 it
us six dot
yeah
so and you know you can also search for
like other ones you can kind of see that
gives you ideas on how to kind of
improve certain workloads and certain
tooling around the ecosystem anyways
questions Thanks
thanks for the talk actually lots of
problems you were describing are
actually soft by kubernetes and mazes
today they they are not scheduling or
managing único notes but they're
managing docker containers why not build
on these primitives to like have the
management layer and just get a unique
URLs on bare metal provider like take it
for example so you mention Asus young
missiles but more kubernetes I know
there's Dell EMC there's a unique yeah
so so yeah good question so I really
glossed over that but there's there's
quite a few problems
Mace's is a great example because they
kind of they were working on this before
kind of the whole container hoopla
kubernetes is not a great example
unfortunately a lot of like kubernetes
installations are already provisioned on
top of beams to begin with and so having
two layers of provisioning like that
don't really work too well you really
need the orchestration layer at the
hypervisor level not on top of that VM
if you do it just needs to be kind of
like out-of-band and so forth
so yeah unique for instance out of EMC
they do have integration with kubernetes
but once again like like trying to do
that on Google Cloud it's gonna suck
trying to do that
anywhere else is gonna suck you really
you really need the hardware
acceleration and in order to do that
scheduling that needs to be kind of
built at a lower layer and as for like
meso s-- that's another interesting
thing because that's where scheduling
layers kind of compete so meso is is
more for that process level right
because now you can subdivide those
resources so like that scheduling part
where I showed you but when when you
have that VM that scheduling has
effectively moved down into the
hypervisor and it's probably not like
the best place for it at least we don't
have software that were like really
takes advantage of it very well yet but
NATO's that much works a lot better up
here on on top of that VM layer
yep yeah so like pakad dotnet for
instance they do they do a lot of bare
metal provisioning and so forth so yeah
that's that's that's what I'm saying
though is home
there's a there's definitely frameworks
out there like OpenStack for instance
obviously allows you to do that but
those frameworks are built for kind of
classic VMs whereas you know like some
of the like include OS for instance you
run some of their demos and it's a
megabyte tops so that's that's a very
different VM than a gigabyte image I'm
able to say that I don't have experience
with this and but they have experience
on the old type of computing world how
far away are we from from a production
system yeah so I mean there's production
users today you know I talked about not
talking about IOT
not talking about nfe but in a fee is
probably where like the most production
stuff is running today big telcos are
starting to utilize this base basically
a lot of the telcos old hardware stuff
is being eaten alive by software and
like a lot of the nfe stuff is actually
used utilizing unique URLs Ericsson in
particular I know is using that stuff on
the web side there's definitely some
people that are toiling around with it
there's a lot of tooling yet to be read
in though so
[Applause]