[Music]
because you think it's hard so we're
going to 18 will curl application I use
CGI can I also going through my what's
this other website that you should write
down you should go to Observatory about
mozilla.org put in the URL to your bank
all right and go there and it will give
you a bank a letter grade your bank's
website a letter grade I almost
guarantee you to bank will get an X okay
most applications we get at this is a
subjective arbitrary not not exactly
fair range
it is meant to cause you to do things
that are secure one of the things it'll
cost you to do is implement content
security policy if you want to really
high rate and also make sure you're not
using cookies that are us that are not
such as specific and some other things
and with all the show it to you right
now there's a my bank you can have many
some federal sites actually managed to
get like a d-minus however the site that
I maintain which is the month the bugs
he'll install that runs most of it's an
a-minus so my 18 year old their 20 year
old proposition using CGI cam it's a
better security rating than like -
thanks for cleaning possibly more
informants things like my bank we don't
have any money I said that's so what did
you do it scan this on scan your own
site tell your boss that you need to do
this and then hopefully at the next
parole conference I'll give you a
compliment of mantra that you can use
first defining it from that security
policy on a per-page Oh awesome
so this is my help odd means or is it
recording
[Music]
okay so I'm just gonna rustle stuffy and
that's equal sign and enter I have no
idea what there's gonna be a sentence
can be poor so see if it's been scanned
before we actually catch the results in
you did if their chance to settle for a
bunch of headers it's particularly
heinous blinds now there you go so
security policy so concentration things
are a time-release that are now except
with a secure flag so you can get them
over plain HTTP cross-origin resource
sharing is not disabled probably no
public key pinning no strict Transport
Security a redirection with the final
destination is not each yes doesn't have
a return policy
[Music]
all right meanwhile that's my say I
three years I have a freaking A+ but
it's pretty old it's using CGI p.m. but
I can do this and actually I don't like
this on every page but I have this
awesome moment we make it so you to do
this
meanwhile not that I have no problem
[Music]
[Applause]