okay I'll begin to talk a little in
advance just take the two extra minute
away I'd like to introduce myself
so I'm John Josue Gagne I work at
booking.com as system engineer I'm I I
landed when I joined booking in the DPA
team I never touch my sequel before so
it was kind of a strange or assignment
or strange place to land but I I really
enjoyed my time there it's been over
three years now and and I will talk to
you about a war story that I've been at
booking and I think it's interesting to
share war stories
not necessarily to say hey like
something bad happen and we're bad this
is not the idea like it's this really
happened its production it's the real
world and the mistake that we're done
here I think our learnings and so I hope
that you can take away some some things
from what happened and one thing is that
something happened at booking and it was
caused by automation
so it's automation is supposed to give
us less work not to break things and
needs human to fix stuff so I think
there's there's a few interesting things
there so I will start by that we all
know that saying like human make errors
but to really really mess things up you
need a computer or in our case a script
an automation script so we'll come back
to what I can so a little about booking
so we sell hotel room on the Internet
we're quite big
more than a million properties on the
website so there's more than a million
or hotels that you can book on
booking.com when I joined three years
ago people were celebrating 400,000
hotels so now in three years we did
almost like we we triple that number so
it's quite an amazing place to to be and
we're still growing we use my sequel we
have thousands of my sequel server and
we use replication and this is a story
about one of our replication deployment
so this is what I'm gonna talk about you
can all read I'll continue so this is a
typical replication setup at booking we
have a master where we write
we have slaves where we read and a
synchronous replication happens in the
middle we have intermediate master
either for replication fan-out or for
being the point of contact slaves on a
remote data center and we sometimes that
slaves directly connected to the master
quite a simple setup sometimes we have
very small deployment one local slave to
remote servers and sometime with very
big deployments and this is an example
of a medium deployment using
Orchestrator social ami is not with us
but slow me also developed Orchestrator
and so we have our master we have three
intermediate master two of them are in
remote data center dash line here mean
remote data center and each of those
intermediate master have forty slaves so
there is about a hundred and twenty
servers and that deployment I would call
that a medium deployment for booking we
have we have medium medium large it's
not a huge one
we have some that are bigger than that
but it's it's one of the respectable
deployment we have so we will so the
orchestrator and Orchestrator allows us
to visualize our replication deployment
it allows us to move slaves from one
intermediate master to another one and
it also do some automation it can
automatically replace an intermediate
master if it fails so if we have that
node that is failing and at that point
all the slaves there stop receiving
rights Orchestrator will see that and it
will fix things that will point the
slaves back to other intermediate master
or it will promote a new intermediate
master and also Orchestrator
automatically replaced a master when the
master fails so if in our example the
master fails one of those one of its
slave will be promoted as a new master
which is quite interesting because when
you deploy that as a DPA you're not
Paige at 2:00 in the morning to fix
things things get fixed by themselves
and that's good right
it's automation
but orchestra cannot do that by itself
Orchestrator is good at repointing
slaves at moving it understand my sequel
but Orchestra doesn't understand the way
we use my sequel at booking and the way
we use my sequel at booking might be
different as the way my sequel is used
at get up at booking we use DNS for
knowing too which server we need to
write as the master orchestra doesn't
know we use DNS so Orchestrator when it
does a failover call a script which is
one of the our scripted booking to
repoint dns when does that give up or at
your deployment it will call your script
that will tell your application where to
find a new master and this is the script
that was a problem
so before looking into the problem we
will look at the deployment where we add
a problem so it's a very simple
deployment there was there is for
database server a as a matter B as the
local slave eggs as a remote data center
intermittent master and Y as a remote
slave so this is a very this is small
deployment at booking the DNS of the
master is pointing on a and reads are
happening on B and wines at that point
everything goes well and now we had the
first event the first failure that
happened is that both a and B failed at
the same time so I will explain how this
happened later but at this point we are
not able to write to the master anymore
and reads on B are failing
sorry Orchestrator is there right so
Orchestrator
fix things at this point it doesn't have
to do a lot of things it doesn't need to
repoint slave it just need to call the
script that tree points DNS so at that
point we can write again and to fix the
read that were happening on B so that
that was actually that manually but this
is this is not such a big it's not as a
big problem as not being able to write
to the master so so now we're back in a
working situation rights happen on X
reads happen on the Y and everything is
fine so the day ends we go back home and
something happened during the night and
I wake up do this so that was Saturday
morning a very very bad morning you wake
up you check what's happening and you
realize rights are happening unbe okay
what happened let's keep looking at
things reads are happening on Y so we
are not reading what we're writing so a
very very bad position to be in so
that's obviously not good so es outdated
data so all the write that I've been on
eggs didn't reach B so if we're reading
from the master we are not seeing that
data and all the new rights that happen
on B do not reach Y so when we read on Y
we are not reading the data we written
so so it's really really bad it's not a
split brain matter spoken as itself like
they were not too active master at the
same time but there was half data on the
life can have data on the right so
I will explain how we fix that later but
now let's see about what actually
happened so after the failure of both a
and B the second failure was detected by
Orchestrator and I know that because I
have the logs of Orchestrator so I now
understand that after after everything
was fixed during the night a and B were
back up so they resuscitated in a way
and at that point something made a fail
and when a failed something pointed DNS
to B and it's the failover script that
when a fare of the failover script stole
the DNS entry forever from a very valid
server X and pointed it to be so now we
know how that happened but why did they
fail so when they came back up a and B
they add outdated data so my initial
idea because I was there when one and he
failed was to bring B back up first and
then to slave being under X and that
would have been fine but because a came
back up it made that impossible because
a inserted GT idea heard bead events and
things like that and so being now on
data that that is not on X so at that
point I decided to recover from that and
then to put a and B back under X by
cloning by cloning them using extra
backup but if I would have cloned be
there wouldn't have been any problem but
I chose to clone a because at that point
B
was still using my previous plan of
pointing back be under X and I was
planning to
to delete a at that time but I didn't
take into account that things change so
that's the first human error and it's my
mistake I will not do that again but
it's not the only thing that caused this
problem when I did that that was in the
evening before I wake up the next
morning on that disaster and and that
time everything was working I was still
looking at things and there were no
problem so B was actually promoted as a
new master from a hours later so
Orchestrator detected them the failure
of a hours later and this is because I
only downtime a for four hours when I
reclone hey it's okay I don't want
anybody to be paged on that I downtime
the box for four hours which was a
mistake I should have done time that for
a week and so this is human error number
two and still description I've done that
the school should have realized that
that fell over well that DNS reporting
shouldn't happen so Orchestrator has
some mechanism to avoid flapping and it
will not fail over a second time the
same chain in a short amount of time and
I think this is also human error number
zero which is not mine like it's it's
it's debatable if it's a mistake or not
because Orchestrator needs you to
acknowledge a failover before another
failover will happen so if a and B are
not replumbed
is it good or bad to acknowledge well it
was acknowledged in that case so maybe
it shouldn't have there's argument both
for acknowledging and against
acknowledging
and so there are actually seven things
that cause this problem to servers
failing human error number zero an
educates recovery a and became coming
back me recording the wrong server me
not down timing that server enough
Orchestrator probably failing over
something that shouldn't have because a
human would never have triggered that
fell over and the DNS script that stole
the DNS entry from B so in all those
instances I think there's a take away
I'll let that later but you can already
think about that what should what could
be done differently to avoid each of
those seven problem so let's talk about
our fancy failure so two servers failing
at the same time is very unlikely
so was it a deployment error and being
in the same rack or very unlucky and
actually it's both but that on that day
in about less than two hours ten to
twenty servers failing at the same time
in the data center and so this is
because there were human operation in
the data center that people were ranking
new servers and because of the very
sensitive art where there was a low
probability when you were ranking a new
server in the same rack that it was
shutting it down another server so my
point here is double failure happen
don't necessarily automate for them but
be ready for them to happen because ten
servers failing in half an hour
is possible
so how do we fix that so once we're in
that situation where we have data on on
X that is not on B and data and B that
is not on X either you declare part of
that data lost which we did in that case
because that wasn't really valuable data
or you have to replay the data so
replaying the data needs understanding
what data is there
so DBA is do not necessarily PBS booking
we're a small team and people serving
600 developers we cannot know all the
data they're putting in the database so
we are not able to ourself to recover
that data we need the developer to
understand that data and so it was
easier here the choice was made to just
drop that data replication we could have
used replication so replicate X like we
could have slaved we could have put
replication here this would be a master
to this and and send the data back there
but we at that point we got
auto-increment in our way because when
we failed over so some auto-increment
were consumed on X and when the dns was
point back to be the same auto
increments were allocated to rows so we
had conflicting auto increment and that
made me think okay we use auto increment
all the time but it's this a good thing
shouldn't we use another type of ID so
those are my my takeaways from from that
is like really twisted situation happen
like automation is not simple there
should be no shortcut in an automation
script if you write an automation script
like test every precondition like okay
it's it looks stupid to do that test but
maybe it's a good thing to test that you
are actually moving a DNS entry from the
right server for
like it's that DNS entry really pointing
to a at that point no it was pointing to
X stop I need the human to think that
true premature acknowledgment be mindful
about that to take aways from myself
down time more than less and shut down
sleep first and something that will take
more time is maybe rethink the way we
use auto increment and maybe using you
you IDs so it's you IDs are usually
generated randomly there's a there's
some tricks and there's some algorithm
to generate you you IDs to make sure
they are generated in order so you end
up still inserting in primarykey order
and you should use those trick if you
want to keep the performance of insert
in your table maybe there's also
something in Orchestrator because I'm
pretty sure humans wouldn't have failed
a in that case so Orchestrator should
probably do something about those kind
of failures it's still the one percent
so I'm not sure it's worth a lot of time
but so we have to think maybe a little
more about how to detect those things
and if you have thought maybe open an
issue or come discuss it with me after
the talk
so some links and I have three minutes
for questions
yes
yes so in that case yes so the question
was why should we stop sleep first so
when we were in that situation here I
decided to stop a and we clone a from
extra backup here I did a backup from Y
and I reek clone a from Y but at that
point I shut down the master and so this
box was known as a master for
Orchestrator so I should have shut down
B first not a so if you shut down a
master be mindful about like does that
box have slave yes
yes but which one is it like and so the
question was after failing over should
you kill the box well in that case
Orchestrator detected a failover of a
that's fine it'd be killing a wouldn't
have solved the problem it's the problem
was that the DNS reporting script took
that DNS that wasn't belonging to a and
made it point to B and a solution could
have been to kill tags at that point but
it's also at that point if if your
script is detecting that it's failing
over something that is not belonging to
the box that actually failed there's
something here but it's not what you
mean
yes well actually at that point those
bucks were dead their uptime after was
like a few minutes like those two bucks
rebooted so it's like basically you can
think of that as like the power cable
was pulled from them and it was plugged
back so like it's at that point it's
really hard to definitively kill a and B
unless you make sure that you cut the
network cable or yes and out-of-band
ways of shutting down the switchboard
which could be a good solution like that
could be something else we could do in
the automation I'm not sure it's the
best thing to do but somebody that is
paranoid about those things I usually
think of myself as paranoid and that's
not an idea I would have so it looks
like you're more paranoid than me
so the question was I got a call with so
on Saturday morning I just logged in and
because I I knew there was cloning on
the way I checked things at that point I
wasn't called there was a and there was
a log of the orchestrator failover at
midnight at that time I was sleeping so
Saturday morning was detected because of
my curiosity not not because anybody was
paged actually it's a good thing that I
was curious because the longer would
have weighed the longest with the more
data I would have lost so thank you very
much if you have more questions I'll be
around I'll be at the community dinner
so grab me and thanks Frederick for
organizing things
[Applause]