okay so from my side unmuted
good let's give it a try
I don't want to yell at you so I'm
starting cautiously I don't know whether
the microphone is on it's just for
recording yeah okay good so I start here
with so thank you for having me here
I'm Peter Peter Bowman and what I'm
going to present you is actually joint
work of several people in my group one
of them in particular Demeter my chef
whose PhD thesis is engaged in that work
as well
but I would have to take a long list
actually to be honest to give proper
credit to everybody who has contributed
to that I know the least of course also
the standardization bodies where we had
lots of discussion gave me a lot of
opportunity to learn things as I'm just
a plain computer scientists but has
stumbled into geo world and that's it
what I want to talk about about
multi-dimensional data that appear is
spatial temporal data cubes so we have
this funny term of coverage this is
age-old
actually only if you remember that it
originally was invented by s3 for a
particular data structure but meantime
it's decoupled from that and they
themselves were surprised to discover
what coverages have become in the
meantime coverage is catch-all terms
that actually relates to feature you
know in OTC standardization world a
feature is a geographic object in the
end something that has some location
space and time attached then we have a
special kind of feature that is a
coverage a coverage is defined as
something that may sound really strange
a spacetime varying phenomena that wants
to express something specific if you
look at say a highway here and you take
the a1 if your model that is a vector
then obviously the attribute a1 will be
invariant over the full size over the
full length of this highway it will be
a1 so it's sort of static attributes
that are
yeah however if you take some image and
walk from one location to another the
value changes and that is what this
expression wants to say it changes as
you go from one element to another it's
pretty clear that this kind of thing
requires more storage space and
therefore the big data that we encounter
at least big in terms of volume
typically our coverages not so much
vectors and actually it's not raster
data only if you think about that one
but you could generalize that as regular
and irregular grids as point clouds and
measures we can sort of make this a
little bit more graphic more spicy so we
have the feature and we have some
abstract coverage which actually has
several subtypes if you will which also
reflects history we have the grid
coverages the first knife attempt run
about 2004 that is not very much used
today and particularly not with geo
coordinates because it has some
difficulties I have word the word flow
here we had to improve on that I got the
rectified coverage which is an author
image so rectilinear grids and then the
rest of it all was termed a reference or
group you see I cannot even pronounce it
reference about great coverage nobody
could explain me why that term was
chosen it's a little bit difficult but
it means irregular grids in the end so
everything else that is historically
development like rings in a tree
actually we supersede this currently
with the coverage implementation schema
1.1 where we introduced a general great
coverage which brings all these
historical developments together into
something that is easier to handle
easier to understand and in particular
one singer concept and that is what
typically is known as data cubes that is
some erase some roster sets that have
two dimensions three dimensions four
dimensions five or whatever and as you
can see there can
straight lines like also images it can
be curvilinear like measures following a
coastline or the syringe things that
people do in climate modeling all of
that falls into that category but it
doesn't stop there because in the end
its point in space that just happened to
have a particular condition constraint
that they all have neighbors if you
don't have that if you give up that when
you come to multi-point coverages that
is point clouds if you add curves so
bangles of trajectories could be a multi
curve coverage and so on multi surface
coverage multi solid coverage this is
actually where we close the gap to city
modeling for example city GML also to
CID computer-aided design so we do not
really remember ears we just want to
close gaps this is an abstract concept
and that has been defined in OGC
abstract topic six which is identical to
ISO 19123 abstract in the sense it does
not prescribe a particular
implementation which means you can have
divergent implementations and you find
that out there so if somebody says I'm
into or probably because I'm
implementing 19123
wrong you find diverging implementations
out there and you have a very simple
criterion they all come with their own
client because crisscross coupling does
not work therefore otc has added
concrete coverage implementation schema
which is a concretization that makes a
few assumptions so that it becomes
interoperable and actually we can do
conformance testing down to the level of
single pixels saying whether an
implementation is correct or not in this
sense it's concrete and then you can use
client a to access server B that is
possibly indeed and that has been done
so that is the general thing stepping
back a little bit we can bring that into
a very simple schema actually using UML
so it's a specialization of feature that
has domain set telling us where do our
values sit the range set which are the
values you see domain range it's like a
function mapping locations two values
and what we have added then over TML for
example is the data type what is the
data type of our values is the
temperature is it radians or whatever
else and this actually we took from
sweet common so actually now we have a
connection to sensor world so sensor
observations can be transformed into
coverages without loss of semantics here
that was important to us still there are
quite a few data that people want to
attach different ones depending on their
domain and so there is an option on
metadata package where I can put
anything else you want the coverage
doesn't understand it but it does
transport it for you so this is a way to
carry along all sort of specific
metadata that you want to remember if
you want to see that in CML okay here is
an example for it where you see the
domain set with a grip definition this
happens to be four-dimensional lat/long
hate and date so you have a regular axis
for that long you have an irregular axis
for hate with two levels in this case
and you have an irregular X's for time
also two levels I didn't want to write
more I was lazy
this is mapped to grid X's and then you
know we other points it and the point
values you have here in the range set
and down there in the range type you see
what that means for example it's
panchromatic we have radians reference
to it and we have the units of measure
and the kind of things that is the
historical way because GML just was
trendy at that time when it originated
but with CIS 1.1 if you favor curly
braces then here is the same thing in
jason domains that range set range type
and the good thing is that it has the
same semantics we can map it so you can
do a one-to-one mapping you are not
bound to a particular world of
standardization and if you are into
ontology and into reasoning then you may
want to enjoy the RDF representation
please look at it closely I will reverse
it afterwards
so we have different formats available
if you step back a little bit that means
we can encode our coverage into a single
file where we have domain set range that
orange type and the metadata and we are
informational e complete in the sense
that it covers it contains all of the
definition if you use some format like
Gmail chain or RDF find so far but
inefficient obviously you don't want to
transport 10 terabyte encoded in ASCII
not really so we need binary formats
okay that is defined as well with the
coverage standard you can use any of
those formats and this is a growing list
we have more and more mappings defined
obviously this is incomplete sometimes
geo TIF is not able to handle all of the
range type information for example but
ok you wanted you get it sometimes there
are reasons for that maybe you just want
to display in a browser so you pick a
PNG knowing that you will not get the
full information so that is not an
inconsistency that is meant this way
however sometimes we want to if both I
want to be informational a complete end
I want to encode efficiently therefore
we have a multi-part encoding where we
have a container concept that we have
some header which is some information le
complete format GML or Jason or RDF and
then you have links from particular
elements into other files and these
contain then say the pixel payload so
they can be stored efficiently ok so we
can use historically it was multi-part
mine in CS 1.0 but in future that can be
zip tha B to the save format you package
whatever we want and this concept
actually allows us also to introduce
collections of coverages to be
transported and it allows also to
introduce tiling multi-dimensional
tiling partitioning of objects some
formats support that already like QT for
example other stones now we have a way
to model that to represent that
regardless of the format so this is the
coverage is the data structure this data
structure actually
you served that many different services
we tend to to flee decapitate from the
web coverage service so a wfs and web
feature service can serve a coverage as
well because the coverage is a feature
in the end just depends on the
implementation so actually the coverages
can float between different services or
in other words can be passed on from one
to the next
for example from a sensor observation
service into a web coverage service and
so on okay
I will focus on the web coverage service
because that offers the dedicated
functionality specifically for the
coverages this WCS standard is organized
into set into a suite of standards not
to make life more complicated but
actually to make it easier because the
WCS core is very very simple it's about
the level of master thesis for a good
student to implement that as part of a
semester work and then you get something
that delivers a coverage or subset of it
subsetting means I can trim that is I do
a cut out but I retain the amount of
dimensions so 2d cut out from a 2d
coverage or it can be slicing which
reduces the number of dimensions so from
a three-dimensional image time serious
stack for example I take out a time
slice which then is 2d or I do a time
series analysis then I get out a
one-dimensional coverage so I can walk
myself through the dimensions and can
extract whatever I want to transport the
minimum amount to the client this you
get back in the store format if you
don't say anything but you also can
request a format conversion say into G
ot or you want the GMA representation
and the service can decide which format
it wants or want to support this is the
mandatory stuff then there are different
facets in the extensions functionality
facets which a service may or may not
implement that makes it simpler for
implementers because you don't have to
code a lot until you have something
ready but you can say I offer core and
I'm baack working on extensions
it's good for those who want to buy
implementation or a select and open
source implementation because they can
set up a list saying I need w CP WCS
core and I need the range subsetting
extension I need the CRS transformation
extension and then everybody knows
exactly what is necessary and so you can
negotiate and you have a clear
understanding of the functionality that
is to be delivered finally we have
application Pro profiles which is just
bespoke packaging of functionality for
different purposes currently we have
satellite imagery and metadata is in the
make so that is something that I'm using
we because we actually have done that
I'm the editor of those things here and
so naturally we use our rastaman system
for something that is used for
implementing and so we also have the
implementation available but many others
do as well
so actually we get a common information
space where coverage services
interoperate okay five minutes left the
funny word has fun
rastaman raster data manager so that is
our vehicle that we are building a so
called a write a debase system that
enhances standard SQL with queries on
multi-dimensional arrays and behind that
pile streaming architecture which is
peer-to-peer so fully paralyzed without
single point of failure we always we are
on OST you life
OST you incubation was not where we
where both parties felt happy with so
that we have abandoned and what did I
want to say yes a couple of words just
to give you an overview of the
architecture we do a partitioning of
course which can be any sort of
partitioning to do optimization like
saying this particular region must be
really fast and for the rest just to
something meaningful your system we have
a parallel architecture where we have
split queries
over more than 1,000 cloud nodes and
this is our latest thing this year we
are going to be onboard a satellite big
fun for everybody in the team and I
hasten to say these interfaces are not
for end users we can discuss a lot about
get versus the rest versus post or so
but actually I don't care this is all
just internal interfaces people want to
use their comfort zone they are tools
and so actually it's important that we
just have this as a client-server tool
interface and instead we allow to plug
in all the different things like Python
presented that yesterday that allow
people to work on data analysis on just
browsing Maps doing web GIS or whatever
understands that standards are our
friend so we can attach client a to
server be okay now I've talked too much
so this one I have to shorten
drastically I guess I will just do this
one how many - minutes do I have three
okay so just this one it's embedded into
the earth server initiative which
finances us via the European Commission
and we are we are grateful on that where
we build up databases on three
dimensional image time series and four
dimensional weather data cubes so we
have the Sentinel data of ISA
we have ocean color analysis at Plymouth
Marine Laboratory national computational
infrastructure Australia European Centre
for medium-range weather forecast gives
us four dimensional data cubes and then
we do a join a combination of data cubes
between Australia and London reading to
be exact and combine them visualize them
in NASA web world wind so in the end
what we are aiming at is a global
Federation where you can do anything on
the data cubes that are stored here and
there if you want offline I can show you
the demo we don't have time for that
no but I can show you that data fusion
already in a first version let us say
okay I had wanted to talk more about OS
q as well because this I thought might
be a good forum for discussion but we
don't have time for that so I will skip
all that and just stop here I guess one
minute should I talk even faster we can
pick up by by frequency I guess it
doesn't make so much sense but just to
stimulate discussion I cannot resist
totally so what I show you is just the
summary thing here all those things I
wanted to discuss I mentioned our
incubation in OS geo and actually we
were good friends except for one thing
the maintenance of the code where as I
say all software should be free and I
say why we have that doesn't want to
come okay come on come on come on
hey don't try to outsmart me got it
okay and yes I admit we have a mixed
license model do a license model it's
that bad I mean we have a full spectrum
we have the full commercial stuff s3 as
a placeholder and then on the other hand
this is what OS geo wants what about
these ones they should be accommodated
as well how much more powerful with OS
gob if it would be inclusive and get all
that in there terenia is one of the
proponents of such thinking but it
doesn't somehow get through and in the
end the s risks don't care about our war
between here and there but the small
companies they suffer is that really
what we want question mark and with that
one I guess I really need to stop thank
you on and thank you for very little
so yes suddenly I have five minutes
again that is you have five minutes so
please flames on or comments or whatever
okay good so thanks again and bye now
how do I get out without this thing
hanging up a vet should work it doesn't
like to unplug when Windows is in full
screen mode so I need to be careful but
it works I don't you do it I'm here now
we just don't know the rest of the
records okay
[Music]