the next speaker is Robert Turkey and he
will talk about how to improve
documentation
hello everyone thanks very interested in
this topic I apologize for the technical
difficulties it wouldn't be a conference
without many others anyway the topic of
this presentation is reaching the gap
between legacy documentation and modular
content and what I mean by that is
basically two aspects of documentation
that technical writers at Red Hat are
trying to solve that is the user
experience with documentation at the
same time the amount of work the
maintenance work that documentation
writers have to do so first I would like
to outline what I'm gonna talk about in
this presentation I will try to provide
an introduction but why we even do that
what do you what do we think that it's
time to rethink that the way we do
documentation I also talk about the
terminology what's in the title of the
presentation what I understand when I
say legacy documentation and what I mean
by modular content I will then apply
what we think is the problem with this
so-called legacy documentation I will
try to explain why I even think that
there is actually too much of the
documentation and I will explain why
this hard to find and how we hope to fix
that and in the main parts of the
presentation I will try to introduce
what we think could be a solution to one
of those problems and to all of those
problems that I mentioned first of all
we will try to cut down on the amount of
content that we actually maintain and
that the documentation entails by
document only what the users really need
to really need to adapt
we've also talked about how to
facilitate the single sourcing of the
documentation so that we can
upstream and downstream closer together
and in the main part
what is modular documentation and how do
we how do you hope to achieve all of the
above by switching to a module form of
documentation last but at least I would
like to at the end save some time to
invite your questions and to have a
discussion about what your experience
with documentation is and what you with
your project or your organization does
in this area and if you're facing
similar problems and so on so let's get
started shall we
about the introduction first of all the
question is why why we think that it is
high time that we rethought the way we
do documentation I like to point out to
two main aspects of that I like to
illustrate that into two problems or two
areas in which the software landscape is
changing and that is software packaging
and software delivery we've been for a
long time used to these big monolithic
mostly distributions where there would
be hundreds or even thousands of
packages they would be sitting in
repositories or you would get a CD or a
DVD you would install the thing and then
you would have to kind of sort through
it and find the stuff that you know
really matters for you if you were
concerned about performance or security
then you would have to you know cut down
on that you would you know get rid of
all the stuff that you don't really need
it
and that is changing you know not that
you know all applications would be
containerized now but that is definitely
a big part of how applications are being
deployed and how they are being packaged
and there are other ways to package
applications that are not the same as
they used to be and the documentation
history flag that we need to try to make
the documentation
work with those new scenarios as well
with regard to software delivery again
we've been used to more or less regular
release cycles it could be that the
distribution or a piece of software or
project would have a release every six
months or 12 months or even if the
cadence of the release would not be in
any way regular it would still follow
the sort of a traditional versioning
scheme by you know 1.0 1.1 1.2 then
there would be 2.0 and the documentation
tended to follow that there would be a
release of documentation you know for
the 2.0 version and then then there
would be another release of
documentation but then there came
rolling updates and nowadays there are
web applications that are being deployed
most of the times today and the sort of
documentation that is tied to these
release cycles is not exactly covering
that it doesn't really cut it for these
scenarios it should be the way the
documentation is released and presented
a lot more fluid flexible and about the
terminology by a legacy documentation I
mean the sort of documentation that I
touched upon with those releases the
documentation that is tied to individual
releases it's those big guides or books
and they tend to be comprehensive and
complete while there's nothing wrong
with that it tends to also create a
whole lot of amount of documentation and
they're based on features they describe
every individual feature that the
project or software has the ten B use
and as I said it's important to
emphasize that there is nothing
inherently wrong with that sort of
approach and in an ideal world we would
have that as well as other types of
documentation but in a world where you
have to choose where we spend our
resources it might be time to look for
something else where modular
documentation comes in the picture
and that documentation differs from the
sort of guide like documentation in that
is based on individual user stories so
it doesn't strive for comprehensiveness
it doesn't even try to be complete
instead it tries to be highly targeted
it goes after specific goals and it's in
concise independent standalone
self-sufficient units of content that
can be grouped and regrouped in order to
achieve documentation to describe
describe specific purposes that goes
after specific goals now I would like to
illustrate the difference between
feature based documentation and
documentation that is based on user
stories in a simple example on the left
here there is a silly example of a
feature based documentation it tries to
describe all the features it tries to be
comprehensive I'm going to give you a
second to read through that
now are we good let's compare that with
example on the right this one is based
on a specific user story and it tries to
describe how to take the user from A to
B it's about a specific goal
it's about accomplishing a concrete task
again take a second to read through that
now when you're looking at those two
sides those two examples as I said
before it's important to recognize that
there is nothing wrong with the one on
the left its feature based documentation
is the sort of reference kind of guide
and it has its uses however for many
users unless there are really well
versed in this sort of project or
features or distribution for those users
to find their way around this sort of
documentation they need to be
experienced they need to have a lot of
time on their hands and it doesn't make
it very easy for them to to use this
documentation to accomplish specific
tasks so as I said in an ideal world we
would have both we would have the one on
the right that would guide the users
when they need to solve a specific
problem and when they need it to be done
yesterday then of course we were also
having the one on the left that will be
there to describe the stuff as it
happens how the system functions what
the background is how the features are
laid out so as I will talk about it in
the later part of the presentation we
try to facilitate the scenario where the
one on the right
pays the user from A to B but at the
same time the sort of modular
documentation that we create would allow
the user to experience the state of it
the same sort of experience that they
have the example under on the left and
by the way as I included down there when
I talk about user stories I tend to take
the sort of a standard edge hire like
template me name I'm a sort of a user I
want to accomplish something so that I
have some sort of an outcome are there
any questions at this point before I go
any further
hey cool now let me try to describe what
the problems are the main the main
aspects of the problems with the legacy
documentation the sort of documentation
that is based on features and that is
compiled in those big large books or
guides now in that first bullet there is
a sort of a cliche that nobody likes to
write dogs well it's not really true
that nowhere likes to ride dogs the
problem is when there's too much of that
when the content accumulates over time
where you have multiple versions and
then you have to maintain documentation
for that version and another version and
over time there is just too much of it
it becomes very difficult to maintain
and nobody's really excited about
maintaining stuff that's you know that
is being valid three or four years ago
and it's still valid for certain users
who still have that deployed somewhere
but when there's a new contributor they
usually want to work on something is new
that's they want to describe stuff that
they know about they want to describe
how to have the perform a specific task
so now comes the cliche or what I likes
to ride dogs because it has become
tedious to maintain those guys and it
also invites a lot of duplication
because you know there are different
sets of dogs for different versions and
the content tends to be used reused but
not really nicely and if it's updated in
the new one it tends to be overlooked in
the old one anyway it leads to
documentation that tends to become
obsolete
that's a problem secondly the
documentation is hard to find and by
that I don't mean that it would be hard
to google for documentation and you
wouldn't find you know for example in
fedora we have an administration guy we
have an installation guide a security
guy networking guide but and there is a
user who wants to
you know configure or SSH to be able to
securely conic connect the remote server
what did they use well they probably
need to find something in the
installation guide as well as in the
security guy it's about security
afterall it's also about networking so
they will have to find something in the
networking guide and the system
administration guide well there's
probably gonna be a little bit of that
as well in reality they would need to
sort of carry big pieces out of all of
those guides and while it's possible
it's certainly not exactly user friendly
and it takes the people a lot of time
and the user needs to be familiar what's
inside all of those guides well so what
they do well they google it
they end up going through somewhere as a
stack overflow or something like that
and while there's nothing wrong with
finding your answer I'd stay over flow
it tends to indicate that there's
actually some deficiency with your
documentation because the user instead
of being able to find the documentation
that you have produced well they try to
find somewhere else vastly the
documentation is very hard to navigate
because those guides tend to be very
long and while it's useful for you know
control-f searching it's definitely not
useful for navigation there's no
hierarchy usually and the experience is
very hard to customize because when you
take those guys and you want to save
them for example for offline use
well you get a humungous PDF or a huge
pile of HTML s that you have to browse
you cannot really find and take only the
stuff that you want so well of course it
leads to people saying this which may or
may not be true but we're not exactly
happy about that
any questions
let's go forward about how we would like
to go about solving these problems well
we recognize that our solution is not
the one fits all size but we tend to
think from experimentation and from
conversation with support people and
with the communities that it could be a
way to go forward so first of all you
would really like to concentrate on the
stuff that the users really need and in
order to do that in order to be able to
cut down on the amount of content to
ease the maintenance burden we need to
identify user stories that are really
valid for users we need to work with the
community we need to work with the
engineers we need to work with support
organizations and find the user stories
that the users really are interested in
and that tend to solve the majority of
the problems are not the majority of
turbulence but the most common problems
for the majority of the users and by
that we should be able to achieve a more
efficient use of our resources
that doesn't mean that there still
wouldn't be some sort of a maintenance
burden but by trying to cut down on the
amount of content and by communicating
with the users about the user stories
that they're really interested in we are
able to slowly reduce the amount of
maintenance work also then we try to
bring upstream and downstream closer
together and even single source the
documentation then upstream downstream
users we not only save time by avoiding
duplication and not only duplication of
content but of effort but we're also
able to bring new contributors on board
because it just becomes easier upstream
may not be at all concerned about how
the project or software is being
protected by
company or some other project but when
they have the possibility of contribute
to a single source repository it's a
very good thing it also helps to bring
the developers on board now there is
another cliche that developers don't
like to write documentation and of
course some of them they like coding
better and they tend to think as
documentation is something inferior but
there's definitely not across the board
and when we make it easier for them to
contribute to the documentation it
becomes a whole new different story
and lastly about the module of authoring
and presentation of documentation this
is basically the method that we are
using to achieve all of the above now I
will talk in the next series of flights
about what the modules and assemblies
that I have here listed the main
components are module documentation what
they are how their forum and so on but
first I want to travel touch upon the
second bullet about the so called
curated assemblies and ad hoc dogs
by that I mean and as I'm going to
explain a little while later an assembly
in our terminology would be a
realization of a user story and there
exist two user story it has been
identified has been validated we know
what the user wants to achieve we write
or adopt some modules and we assemble
them we collect them combine them in a
so-called assembly and that becomes a
description of the user story a
realization in documentation of the user
story and of course such assemblies that
are based on user stories that have been
properly identified and validated they
could be called curated because we've
put a lot of effort in them and we made
sure that they make sense however we
recognize that we're not ever going to
be able to identify all of those user
stories there's always going to be you
know the guy who wants to in
all his Linux distribution on his
Internet enabled refrigerator and use it
to drive his home cinema or something
like that
it's unpredictable so we recognize that
many also want to allow these users to
experience the sort of stuff the sort of
experience that they would have the
reference documentation with the one
that's based on features so we try to
come up with a really solid system of
metadata that would be assigned to the
individual parts of the modular
documentation and we would allow the
user to browse through the entire body
of the documentation that we have based
on this metadata it becomes highly
hierarchical and it becomes possible to
select the bits and pieces of the
documentation that pertains to the
public problem that the user is trying
to solve or the particular area that
they're interested in so I choose here
to call it ad hoc what this allows us to
have the presentation of the darks
dynamic it's not static anymore it's not
one a huge page or guide it becomes
possible for a user to dynamically
select the kind of stuff that they're
that they are interested in and go away
with that and use them again questions
oh let's describe those assemblies and
modules these are really the main
components of what we call modular
documentation as I said before I touched
upon shortly when we have a user story
and we want to document it we think
about that realization of a user story
as an assembly it's a whole bunch of
modules and other stuff that is being
put together combined in a coherent way
to form an assembly now I have a short
note here that we purposefully avoid the
word topic even though many people say
topic based documentation and stuff like
that but we have found that it's it's
too loaded the word is just too
ambiguous
everybody thinks that topic is somewhere
something else so we just that's the
reason why we're not using it anyway so
we have an assembly and we have to
populate it so we have some sort of an
introduction that should have a typo
that should explain the purpose what is
going to be accomplished by following
that piece of documentation might also
have a list of prerequisites some sort
of conditions or steps that need to be
taken before the user goes and follows
this piece of documentation the title
should be very specific it should be
oriented towards a specific task
action-oriented such as as was before it
making an omelet something like that it
would then be followed by the first
module it could be a conceptual module
it doesn't have to be there and as an
example I've chosen here understanding
the importance omelets in French cuisine
now you know that it's not really
important or perhaps it's not necessary
to understand this kind of stuff to be
able to flip an omelet but there are
many scenarios where it may be very
useful for the user to know the
background and by being able to include
these conceptual modules into our
assemblies we're also recognizing the
importance of the sort of feature based
documentation that we're
supplanting not really doing away with
and if we would combine only the
conceptual modules we would end up with
something similar that we had before so
we don't want to discourage that we want
to keep it in case it's necessary to
have it then there would be an
explanation of the of the concept at the
background and there could be a list of
links to additional resources then would
come the real meat of the of that piece
of documentation one or more procedural
modules they would have again
action-oriented titles they would
describe steps that need to be taken to
accomplish a certain task and as I said
there could be one there could be a
bunch of them it really depends on how
granular is that particular assembly how
wide was the user story when we have
started with it the steps in that module
should be very explicit they should be
commands they should say I did open copy
or something like that so that the user
is clear or what is being asked of them
and again each of those modules could
have additional resources same as the
assembly as a whole points to other
pieces of documentation related modules
related assemblies related onion recipes
stuff like that now you may notice that
the structure of that template for the
assembly is basically the same as the
template for the module that is
intentional
those individual pieces of the
documentation are all designed and
written or adapted from existing
documentation to be self standing it's
necessary to have those modules in a way
that there can be combined and recon
find in different assemblies those
individual partial steps may be used in
very many different scenarios many
different user stories so that is the
reason why we're providing a sort of a
widget but at the same time flexible in
what the content might be template for
these components questions
I'm sorry could you use the microphone
please
how to cope with a great number of
assemblies that came out in the project
history so with like a doc we have big
man was I I guess with this approach we
will land with having a great number of
documents so you're asking how to
organize the assemblies that we're going
to end up with and maintain and maintain
them yes that's a very valid question I
actually have that included in in one of
the later slides about the discussion
that's something that we have to apply a
lot of planning for we try to come up
with content strategy that would allow
us to keep organizing this we have
explored many different ways to keep
track of what user stories are being put
together what assemblies are being
populated in order to describe these
user stories so they'll either lose
track on you know let's say that you
would have a whole bunch of assemblies
for beginners or you would be lacking
the more advanced stuff or we would have
user stories that would be identified
for a specific area but we would be
lacking some other ones so what do we
have come up with is for different
products or a different project so that
they were documenting mind maps that
would allow us to keep a visual overview
of what we have available what is
missing and what still needs what still
needs to be done and how it all relates
together so that we we don't have an
overly documented one part of a project
and then big gaps in another part thank
you
I have a really short quick question
you're doing this in dog book in the
formats that you're using for for for
structuring your documentation is that
dog book that you using or yeah so the
question is whether you're using dog
book or a different format yeah yes so
I'm a technical writer at Red Hat at
this point most the majority of our both
upstream and downstream documentation is
either in ASCII door or in docile so
we're sort of in the middle of a
transition and dog book to ask a dog but
we have these templates in all of the
formats that we're using for you know
you know in order to be accommodated in
order to be able to accommodate all the
different writers who want to work with
them there was two questions okay
Oh so let let me read this out you're
going from legacy to modular now as I
said before by legacy I mean the kind of
stuff that is based on features that is
included in big long guides and that
tends to be complete that goes after
comprehensiveness as I said before
nothing really wrong with that but we
want to sort of reposition the
documentation into stuff that is being
based on user stories that describes
specific tasks that is action-oriented
and that is based on this module
approach as I said before the module
approach luckily allows us to let the
user have the same sort of experience or
not the same but a very similar one as
with the feature base documentation when
we make rich use of the metadata that we
applied to the individual modules
secondly this allows us by identifying
the user stories that we really want to
use that the users are really interested
in to reduce the amount of content to
ease the maintenance burden of the of
the documentation writers and also to
attract new contributors because the
learning curve is not too steep for them
when the documentation is in these
modular pieces because it's very hard
for a person who comes and is new either
in an open source project or in an
organization to start contributing to
documentation but it's all about those
big guides and it's you know you get it
system administration guide dumped on
your lab and you have to first read it
so that you know what's in there you
have to become familiar with that it's
very daunting when you present people
with the opportunity to actually
document short user stories the kind of
stuff that they're already familiar
they have figured something out now they
want to share it share with others so
they can document they can provide a
procedure that would become a module
they can provide a bunch of modules they
can even populate an entire assembly
slash user story so I don't know
returning them cutting down on the
amount of content we're also making it
easier for people to pick the pieces
that they want to document and start
right away and thirdly we're trying to
improve the experience for the end user
by making it easier to navigate the
documentation and by taking it from
static documentation into dynamic
presentation and that is being
accomplished by heavy use of metadata
which allows us to present the
documentation and a highly hierarchical
way starting from the top where it's not
really granular going down through a
hierarchical structure based on the
dynamic presentation of the metadata
based documentation yes
there are two questions that are do you
please
I think before you get onto maybe a more
technical side the thing that I've been
trying this technique a little bit
myself and the thing that bothers me
slightly and maybe the next talk is
gonna go into a bit this bit more is how
to keep things modular and but still
maintain a kind of consistent
storytelling narrative that doesn't just
sound a bit disjointed with steps that
sound like they were written by
different people or in different styles
and just maintaining that a document
still sounds like a cohesive whole
that's better right so the question is
how we go about making the module
documentation still coherent still that
so that the different pieces are not
disjointed that still sound like
something that the user would like to
read I understand it correctly well so
as I mentioned before when I talked
about the so-called curated assemblies
those are the ones that we focus on when
we put together the individual user
stories and in between the different
parts of the assembly the different
modules of the introduction and perhaps
the conclusion where there are links to
additional references we are not against
including you know sort of stuff that I
could call you know fluff or stuff that
you breach you over from one module to
another the kind of stuff that would
make it easier to read now those would
be the curated assemblies those who do
the one that we spent time on at the
same time as I said it's not possible
always to be sure or to identify or to
document all the user stories that the
users would really need so it may it may
be that there is a certain topic or an
area that people are interested in which
we haven't covered in this curated
assembly that is easy and nicely read so
then it would be with the understanding
that the individual pieces
being compiled in an ad-hoc dynamic
manner and then of course there wouldn't
be the nice experience that we offer
with the curated assemblies but as I
said we tried to work very hard to
identify and validate these histories
that we put effort into so that the
experience would be nice for the user so
we're definitely talking about
documentation and times of continuous
delivery processes what's your
recommendation
where should I maintain such kind of
modular documentation is it alongside
the source code it's just another piece
of source code in the same repository
something that so the question is where
to maintain this sort of module
documentation whether it would be in the
same repo as the project code or
somewhere else
well this sort of depends on what sort
of a project or community it would be a
part of
we have no strict rules or you know
guidelines about that now we're part of
many different numbers of communities
and we don't really want to impose on
them some template or rigid structure
that they would need to follow we try to
accommodate the requests of the
community that said what we try to
encourage all communities or projects
that were involved in is to use a
specific structure of a repository for
reusing gate for those repositories of a
repository that makes it very easy to
combine and reuse the content and we
have this structure which we have real
available for anyone to use that can be
included either as a separate repository
if does the preference of the project or
that could be that can be a part of the
larger repository that includes also
code order artifacts so it's very
flexible and it really depends on what
is the common ground what is the
understanding in a particle project it's
so far worked very nicely for us in both
ways both separate repository for
documentation and a repository that
includes both code and dogs okay just
one things because it's not clear what
would you say dynamic in the dynamic
presentation do when you create a user
story this is composed by several parts
but this part are made only for that
user story or are still part of a small
sub pieces because I was just wondering
if I could create my own user story
using these sub pieces like picking up
smaller amounts that you use of
information that you used to create your
user stories and making it because if
the user story that I'm looking for is
not existing can I make it up or not
well if I understand correctly the
question is whether you can come up with
your own user story that is not part of
what we have been documenting is that
correct
well of course yes on the one hand we
try to encourage documentation writers
not to rely on themselves only when
identifying the individual user stories
because they as documentation writers by
their very different ideas about what is
big what is necessary to describe as a
part of documentation as opposed to what
the users really need so we always try
to encourage collaboration in on all the
different levels and trying to involve
as many people as possible in
identifying those histories that said if
there is a user who you know
the use case or has a specific task that
needs to be accomplished and so they
identify user story for themselves and
then they want that users to read to be
documented we either accept that as a
you know a bug or an enhancement that
needs to be done or we invite the user
to be the one to you know start to the
documentation and undocumented user
story does that answer the question yeah
it's a bit of a plug we're working on an
open source Drupal a distribution for
doing what your content allows you to
pull like topics or or or modules or
however you want to call them from
different poll stories and then compile
them into one single websites that
publishes your documentation so that you
could combine documentation from
different projects because anybody in
the room who we need some system like
that just come and see
can use a question well I do have a
rematch whenever a question sort of I
think that something that is art with
the modern approach is to be able to
oversee all the modules and oh they can
be reused so if you have one user story
I agree it's much easier to change it
somewhere and but there is a new role
which is assembling organism in assembly
all those modules and and having an idea
of what should be specific what should
be generic and I think that's very role
that really needs to have an overview of
even more even wider overview than in
the legacy documentation do you have
something to say about that so the
question is well how we track where the
different pieces of the module
documentation are being used yeah and
also to have an idea of what needs to be
done and what can be reused Oh Buddha I
people start with their own story so
they do their own modules and then it's
nice if some can be together because
they are similar just leave some some
some little stuff to be different at the
beginning and all that kind of process
that seems to be quite hard to to do and
really need some very big review of
right - so2 levels or that of an answer
to that question first as I mentioned
before we use mind mapping software to
keep track of the different parts of the
project or the aspects of what needs to
be done when they could to keep track of
what we have already documented and what
needs to be still done but at the same
time as I mentioned the metadata based
hierarchical presentation of the
documentation allows us to very easily
filtered for what four different pieces
of documentation that we already have so
for example if you you know you're
interested in security documentation
it's very easy for us to filter all the
pieces of documentation that we already
have that touches upon security and you
can go deeper more granular the deeper
you go the you know narrower the
selection is going to be but it allows
you to very easily see in what sort of
documentation already exists in what
areas so that when somebody wants to
document a user story they first go
through the available body of
documentation and they see whether some
of the procedures for a pass have
already been described and whether they
can reuse them so that they wouldn't you
know do it over again and as I said the
hierarchical structure makes it quite
convenient to browse through that
documentation even though it starts out
as a very large body of documentation
you can easily get down to what you're
really interested in I am moving from
dock Bert to a ski dog did you consider
also I like a ski dog I do like it but
did you well consider markdown is it too
simple
just for a picture so the question is
whether we also consider Marga down as a
format for documentation and yes we do
some of the communities that we that we
work with do you smart down for various
research for various reasons for example
I have now been trying to figure out a
way to work with markdown in combination
with asciidoc because the go language
has many different tools that allow the
automatic generation of markdown
reference documentation and we we need
to find ways to sort of make that work
together with other parts of SQLite
documentation so there's nothing really
you know that would that we would have
against Mari down it's just that
asciidoc provides us with more options
it's more flexible it's a little bit
more complicated but it's still very
easy to learn the mark-up of the of
ASCII art is is quite simple to learn so
it's it was just a conscious choice to
go with bass guitar because the tooling
around asciidoc such as ASCII binder and
other pieces of software are very
convenient and allow us to do a lot of
things with it what sort of tooling do
you use
so for a skater of the most look for
rendering we mostly use mask you dr. as
I mentioned we also use SQ binder in
different projects to actually present
the documentation on websites and then
we have many different in-house tools
that are you know out in the open on
github and stuff and that solve
different problems and provide different
templates for individual pieces of
documentation I cannot go into details
if you're interested afterwards I would
I would suggest can we have just one
more I think pros excuse me another
question do we I haven't heard the loss
don't get me wrong I think that the
majority of the users are like
they still tend to go and see a video so
how do you count them I apologize I
would have a hard time to understand did
you try to speed up please I thought
that you hear when so my question was
how do you approach some sort of emotion
another way of expressing documentation
because these days users despite your
modern approach they think that they
tend to go to look into videos instead
of reading documentation so I asked how
we work with videos okay so I believe
that's a that's a whole larger question
which we probably don't have much time
for at this point but I really happy to
discover discuss that with you we have
four in several projects and part of
that problem and we have worked with
videos within ASCII dark with mixed
success but I'd be happy to talk about
that more actually my last slide was
just a couple of points for suggestions
for discussion which we have gone
through I'm afraid we are out of time at
this point so if there are any more
questions please feel feel free to find
me down here and we have to discuss
thanks for attention
[Applause]