okay at least you get a little tour of
flow hub so that's not the button I want
and we are not on Locust
and yes if I can do this first that's a
good point okay now I have that
yeah now where is the
okay we're connected so that's a good
start
am is my stomach a yes there is some IOT
devices here just dev board esp8266
another one modems you so same chip
they're just connected to battery and
they're all on Wi-Fi into using my phone
as a hotspot kind of bridging it because
this is actually a nice portable way
then you don't have to like reconfigure
your devices just it works for a
personal network and we're using MQTT to
communicate the broker in MQTT which are
those things are talking to is running
on my laptop normally that would be your
IOT gateway could be a Raspberry Pi
could be route to whatever and then on
my kind of developer machine in this
case is this one which is familiar to me
with the SAT keyword and and stuff we
have kind of our development environment
so this is actually a little bit good
that you have to do this switcheroo
because it's showing now that I'm on a
different device do doing the UI parts
than the actual runtime this is a normal
case where you in the deployment you're
not gonna have a foo IDE and this kind
of stuff when your Raspberry Pi whatever
it might not have a screen and so on
so I'm connected over WebSockets stuff
okay so I hope we will have some devices
yes we have I have two two devices and
they just have a couple of different
things I've one attached to the reader
on it that's the red board right here
and it actually has a LED also on the
DVLA so that's it's called everybody
input and because we're communicating
over and Qt I need to like that and
devices are not just sitting there
they're publishing I can see here and I
can see that they are saying yellow I'm
here and this kind of stuff and yes so
what should be possible now a second for
instance tape the button here and
connected to the relay itself so now
that I'm clicking the button this thing
is actually kind of talking to itself
over and ktt okay that's something you
may be a bit maybe you have a light
which is actually hard hard wire you
know okay not the most generally useful
thing so the device is somewhere else
you know so now I just have led to show
now it's connected to do this thing
so we can live rewire the system to in
order to to change connections this
could be like setting up the initial
thing or it could be like just changing
how you like things like I don't really
like that I have to go to that device to
trigger that thing or this kind of
things
so that's changing connections we can
also add more components so classical
stuff that happens now at the old time
is the compatibility of devices and then
you need like okay take this Jason thing
take us message and make it work or you
you want to have some functionality a
lot of the ideas which I will go through
it's about like avoid
expansion out in your system build
devices that'll do something sensors and
actuators and then build the system
together in a flexible way for instance
using a tool like this you see because
this has a lot of benefits so from okay
I'm not gonna like I had a sample code
but it's on that machine so it's free
but I actually have the components so
you could go here create a new component
and write your code I'll show you if I
even if I'm not using that in word just
go to we support a bunch of different
languages and it's really easy to add
more
with message from confuse computer
escaped again
also C++ Python anything like that so
it's nice to that's the wrong key when
you create that component actually we
live we can instantiate it so I have
done this before
and I have it's not showing here I hope
it's towards so for instance I have this
component just in between here and now
I'm not pressing it and off when I am
pressing it so this is just super simple
I mean of course you can have as
complicated stuff you want you have a
free programming language short many
Python JavaScript and so on
so this is also nice because it always
happens even if you have the system
that's kind of designed to work together
there's always a little and that's all
like it's a very pragmatic solution to
this like this we don't try to make a
universal way of doing things like just
okay so that stuff don't work this way
this stuff work this way build something
to play it together and we have some
testing tools also automated testing the
views the message queue so you can kind
of you have can have good faith that it
definitely will work
ceefor time okay I do a little bit more
demo let's have this timer component we
have a turbo component and generally
message for you the participant
shouldn't do much when there are enough
now nothing happens but if I specify an
interval hundred milliseconds now we
have this blinking light whatever so
that's actually stateful component you
know it remembers okay we were off
before now we need to go on and so on
and you can do this as well so this
could be it could be complicated stuff
like talking to a database finding what
this message should mean and doing it
live talking to the internet and some
service and so on and also this shows
that we can change the configuration
data right so basically working with the
user experience it's sometimes hard to
predict what's the right values of
things you know like maybe one you know
this is kind of one second showing
activity but not stressing people so you
can kind of explore your way to find out
maybe 1200 is the right word it's just
showing that you can derive things there
yes that's it for demo demo first
my slides are nothing up yes and we are
as I said we are talking here it's all
mqtt I will oh all the time
I trade you one
yes and so this is where you find the
source code for message flow we also
have a new website now message for dot
org I put my slides here cuz that's nice
I hope there is a PDF reader yes so the
typical way you do MPT communication
you're sending on some topics and their
names and depending on the like both
when you send receive and then you're
just you can't do anything else so
instead what we do so you have a system
account can we do basically one thing
and it's it's you can't see this this
what how is it working well it's it's
sending stuff it's all digging into the
code using form you can see it easily
and how it works we send so we phases we
send the button sends on button
something not directly to the motor or
the light because this way it has his
own namespace and then something else
like floral or you can use a hard call a
list of two mappings or whatever
connects them together and this gives
you the flexibility to reorganize it and
with message flow you can do it live
which is nice in addition we send a
discovering message so we send
information each device sending
information how and describing itself
like what is the component this kind of
like so I can have many of the same
components each there are each in a
different role so one can be a there's a
motor button one and so this is
reflecting their very purpose but it's
not hard coded so you can still like
rewire and then it says something about
its ports so like this is a kind of data
flow flow based programming model for
how to do the cues so the mqtt queue is
actually this thing here so that's how
it on the wire it's communicating and
then yeah you can use this little FTP
DSL to connect things together I'm
connecting the first state of a
imaginary button to a start of a motor
and the motor could say when it's
running there's a say to another lamp
that makes it read the warning so you
know that's potentially dangerous and so
on you can use this tool to set it up so
that's
kind of how you would like that's
without like the live initial
programming part and what about devices
that message flow as long as you talk
mqtt or
AMQP which we also support you can have
if you kind of declare this information
about how it how would care works
separately in any AMA file and then you
can have this tool send it on behalf of
the device so this is a way to you have
your existing mqtt things appear and be
connectable in this way of course
sometimes they are hard-coded there is
not much you can do then it's need
something to maybe change the codon and
demonstrated then you run message flow
with your initial graph so like what's
the basic stuff you open your browser as
I said you buy this have never touched
before if you just load the browser and
connect to the right IP to us then you
can do it and I think it's old
connection information is in the URL in
the URL
so we're saying okay please open the IDE
up for a while and please IDE connect on
WebSocket to this address so you can
actually have a QR code or NFC token
where you go Boop and it comes up
directly on your tablet your laptop or
you just need to send this discovery
message to make stuff work with my
sister or in token PTT but there are
also this Khomeini's language which you
can use to to make it nice and easy
we have JavaScript modules no flow it's
not a visual programming environment I
will probably run time for 12 Q's see
pass pass by P Audrina I'm using Arduino
here I use Python in the example and one
other example was JavaScript we have a
rest one which clearly only supports mkp
so it's
yes so for the current status is that
the programming model we've actually
been using this a lot like how this is
set up together in on back-end services
for call systems and they were using mqp
and that's really well dust away running
millions of jobs every week through the
system and it works really well we're
primarily using the JavaScript and no
flow libraries that's really battle
testing works well thank you TT we
haven't do so much yet so it's a little
bit rougher we have some small
deployments in hackers business so of
MQTT with message flow in see base in
Berlin and so like you know you can you
can use it for stuff like programming
like a demo now it's not so much tested
but it's also not part of the you know
the the core production system we stay
out of the the there as much as we can
so it it's not maybe have developer
doesn't have the best experience but the
system works
MQTT SSL support the message flow is
actually not tested this is a one thing
that might cause you to want to wait a
little bit to do a real deployment
because you need as a cell to securely
do your authentication on mosquito for
instance yes future so right now on MQTT
mosquito which is the most common broker
and in the protocol it's not know
routing is specified so we use rabbit
and mqp we actually ask rabbit to say
okay connect this thing to that thing
so we are staying out of the the kind of
for communication path however on skeety
there is no standard for this so we have
our own that's actually running in our
own process and you would like to to
kind of get rid of that so we want to
support web team queue routing also
intuitive because they support our and
then the code that we currently have
will probably separate out as its own
kind of
like well-tested router Franchitti t's
so that if you run mosquito which
doesn't have this functionality you can
plug this in and you can you can work
yeah there are some changes we want to
do more with the how we visualize data
in Feb so you can kind of see the data
flowing through there's a PR for this
open right now which would give you like
it at least the text stream of messages
coming through which is very nice
because sometimes you know documentation
is slightly wrong it says it sends on
this polite but you know actually do not
and it's really nice to to be able to
see that directly the big things we want
to do is you want to take this
programming model which we which works
now for connecting stuff together we
actually have a microcontroller runtime
which you can program live like the
logic internally on with the rice do we
like to expose so you can have this big
Network this device dog flap device it's
like how this stuff to us actually work
or has a bug whatever you go in to that
node and then you see the network inside
and you can change it so that's the big
big things and also we have a couple of
tiny changes we would like to do to the
protocol before we call it message for
one point cuz that's would be a yes and
it's also you find that that's on the
move
rise actually code should be renamed
sign up there and you can use that to
target other things to market
controllers you can just I'm programming
with it to be image processing with its
and stuff like this so that's
[Music]
no well we it's like if so if you would
send that discovery message that little
Jason side thing sorry if we support
micro Python on the SP we don't but if
you would use the existing mqtt support
in microfiber and just send that Jason
[Music]
the question was SSL is not been tested
is it like nothing started we are using
existing libraries for MQTT support so
they have as a cell support both in ojs
in python and so on so we're using power
on - Enzo so like I think
[Music]
for example they used earth and tiny the
tweetIn is vertical which makes a pretty
nice feel for the libraries I've seen
some for v-neck if you want I think I
know you try to get the job done by
external library or you might look at
yeah so the commenters have you look at
Cerf as an alternative to SSL encryption
for community and mqtt we're kind of
relying on what the broker supports and
unless they can talk together and as far
as I know mosquito only supports TLS 1.0
so probably that will be limitation this
also the end-to-end encryption which is
also I think quite interesting it's a
separate topic that is very nice because
then you can send through an untrusted
Network so it's not about making your
network secure it's not sending securely
over a secure Network and there
definitely something like curve and
these the sign for embedded encryption
is very very interesting and Mexico
actually doesn't care about the the
payload that you send between because we
read you have a slight slight preference
for Jason but you can send buffers of
the arbitrate stuff so that means you
can you can do this without changing any
other code yes thanks a lot for
presentation
[Applause]