so if everyone gets settled this is our
next talk about city bikes please
welcome our speaker
okay thank you all for for coming
I'm with Garuda I'm a dinosaur and many
years ago well first a question called
much people how many people here know
about the bike sharing systems okay
that's huge so many years ago I had this
problem that there was no Android app
for the local bike sharing system in in
Barcelona so when whilst trying to
create it I found out that there was no
open date available for me to build this
app so that's what I when I learned
scraping with this basically some piece
of code that connects to a website
extracts information and you do
something with with this data so when I
got all this information available for
me I I created open missing which was an
Android app for the local bike sharing
system in Barcelona and when that was
already working I found that that
Barcelona was not the only city in the
world with one of these bike sharing
systems and that many other cities all
around the world had exactly the same
problem which is that there was no data
available for developers to create apps
or projects so instead of creating more
abs or more different cities I created
city bikes which is a bike shining
network aggregator for as many cities as
it can fit nowadays this thing that
started in Barcelona it currently
supports more than 480 cities in all the
world and it grown into this by by this
Python library that started the project
the good thing about these Python
libraries that people can contribute
these spiders for for their own cities
so let's say a developer from from Italy
wants to add support for some cities in
in Italy he will just contribute to buy
bikes which is the core part of the of
the project
and I don't have to do the work for him
I mean I don't have to code this ad he
will do it he had supports for his own
city or maybe it breaks and and he will
he will do it so that's that's the cool
thing about about about the whole the
whole project when you have an open API
then people can start creating many
things around it and this is an example
of many different applications that that
work with city bikes and then we we get
to this we get to this to this point
where nowadays we assume that data open
data or something it's a reality but
this is the the sad part of it it's that
more than half of it of all the
information contained in city bikes it
comes from scraping and then only 42 are
licensed it so actual sources and so you
probably know about open data and and
the Busse word it is many people
politicians City Council's they talk
about open data I think they say open
data
let's open things and and so on but
somehow it doesn't relate with with
what's happening here so the problem and
something I discovered it's the company
is running these projects they are not
they are not opening up to to to
developers
[Music]
and that's it and that's the main issue
with with these guys it's it's that for
instance these are the the ratings for
for an unofficial up for bike sharing
and they are terrible and and when when
you when you have the open API all these
apps have great ratings compared to to
the main project for instance this is
the this is the website of one of these
bike sharing systems and this is the
this is the map that they have on the
website and it's not an actual map it's
an image of a map and you can even click
on it they did that because they want
they want to avoid people spy during
this website so what what are they what
are they actually thinking I mean it
doesn't work like that so so that's
that's what some of these companies are
are are doing in order to avoid
releasing this information I think this
information I mean it's public transport
information it it should all really
belong to us and we should be able to to
participate in in these projects on on
the way that way that we like and that's
that's what city likes between it's been
trying to do so I will show some
examples of things this is a map of all
the cities that the project currently
supports so this is the whole bill of a
bike sharing a city bike sees it and
every splash or every so every green
splash or every red splash it's somebody
either taking a bicycle or living it so
let's look for instance Barcelona
and and we can actually see people using
the system and thinking okay this is
good and this is not something that
these companies even were thinking about
it or for instance let's say that we
want to see the nearest stations near
the university here in Brussels say
we'll look for it'll be Brussels Pope I
show probably yeah
so it found a network sorry the internet
it's a bit slow I should have known that
but we can now consult bike sharing
system right on your terminal and and
that's good and that's something that
this the company is providing the
service the services will then will then
provide by themselves because they
didn't even think that that it's
something that people would want I mean
who would like to check bike sharing
system on on their terminals or some
some guy even created a telegram boat
using the city bikes API so let's look
and you asked the boat okay with me
Brussels he asks my you know less than
one kilometer and he sends you where the
stations where the stations are
and how many empty slots Friesland
everything so so the point the main
point with with all of this and and why
it's important to me and why I'm
developing this project I mean it's not
about bikes anymore it's about trying to
show the companies trying to show City
Council's all the benefits of releasing
this information so we hear a lot with
open data with hair things like we are
releasing information but there are not
enough people doing anything with all
this information and and the main
problem it's not about the data they are
releasing it's the quality of it and for
me this project shows that when you
release quality data that it's free
useful to people people are eager to
participate even in a public project
that it's funded with public or private
money and and that's for me that that's
the that's the importance of of the
whole project that these city councils
should learn that people really want to
improve things not even if you are not
hard to do it and so in a sense this
project the main purpose of this project
in fact it's disappearing because so
right now we have this this isn't like a
middle part I'm extracting this
information I'm putting it out there in
clear but the the best world or the
future world that will like it's that
city likes it's not a necessary project
it will mean that all this information
is already available for for for
everyone and at that point when the
project can finally be shut down because
the information is already out there
then I will think I will have completed
the task
another cool or important part so what
happens when you add a city to do city
bikes
it's that suddenly let's say there is a
new system appearing in a city when they
get supported to the API suddenly all
the unofficial applications that there
are on the market they work with the
city so even the City Council in in in
some way they wouldn't need to create
their own up their own shitty app
usually they can already use all the
different many applications that are
using in hand that's something really
really important with this in the end
it's the user choice so as a user of one
of the systems you should have the right
to use whatever application you want to
use you shouldn't be forced to use only
the official one some would respect your
privacy some wouldn't some would look
nicer or even you could develop your own
because you don't like any of them I'm
having that choice having that power
it's what it's all about
thank you
I think we have plenty of time
progressives so is there a set of api's
that you sort of support or have
developed that you can say with a new
scheme you can say ahead of time go to
the city and say right you're whoever
implements this needs needs to implement
this set of api's and also sort of
leading on from that have you even have
you thought about sort of perhaps even
implementing open design systems for
that for the hardware that the the
schemes need to operate as well
I'm really sorry can you can you repeat
the question so there are some nice is
it do you have like a preferred set of
api's the new schemes should adopt
ideally so if you don't have to do the
scraping and have you are there people
sort of implementing hardware for the
actual bike sharing schemes themselves
to to to adopt these API so maybe an
open design for the that they can
actually publish the data yeah so it can
be enter it in in two ways for instance
there is a there is a system called I
think it's called open open bike sharing
or something like that and they are
releasing some source code on and some
documentation on how to build these
projects and the other one will be about
standardization or using the same format
that's being done in some by some
companies in the US and in Canada and
they are trying to do something a bit
similar to two gtps
well I did Google transport so it's for
bikes and they restarted working on this
like two years ago
and they found one problem and it's that
the city bikes API or the syntax that
that my ABI has
it's already supported so they release
on a specification and nobody uses it
but it was good for the project because
now I can i could add support in fact
the person that that is supported here
in the room for this format and suddenly
all their systems are supported in city
bikes and they are out there so somehow
without even trying the CTX api syntax
has managed to be the standard or the de
facto standard which is i think it's a
cool way of doing a standard just not
trying to do it just working on it and
listening to to the feedback and just
keeping adding and adding fields hello
I'm a bicycle mechanic and it's a very
exciting project of the first I've seen
of it
and I was wondering how does the project
aim to get the bicycles fixed which is a
ongoing problem with sharing bicycles
they always keep breaking so ideally so
the question is with your with the city
by project how do the bicycles get fixed
who fixes them and how does it happen
no no that's so the thing with all these
bike sharing systems they are like
public-private grant projects and they I
mean I I work come they completely
ignore at this project is so they they
work on another level so they usually
have bands moving around they pick the
bikes fix them and they have their own
way of looking at the world but but city
bikes the city bikes one like okay
I um yeah yeah okay yeah I almost forgot
my question oh yeah yeah you you yes I
how many companies you scrape from a
couple of licensed than others I would
be interested in like several questions
what does others mean yeah see if thank
others with the others
our next question a licensed one do you
pay for them they pay you or how does it
work so what is the license about and
the scraping so who does that that's
like like for each city is a guy who
updates the code who gets the data of
the website and what hey what do you
actually do with the example you showed
us that they only publish a picture so
that you don't it's like makes it hard
to get the data so and what actually for
especially unlicensed one obviously with
the unlicensed one do they complain do
they say hey don't do that or are they
just silent look away or not even aware
of it okay so the cool part about these
questions is that somehow they're all
connected connected with each other so
it works so the first one was about the
licensing one though or so this part of
the slide that say others right
others mean private sources so it's
either our reverse-engineer API or it's
a some JSON feed that it's feeding their
website and it isn't because it doesn't
have a license it's not documented it's
not I did so it really you know what are
the terms of this and it's just out
there and the second question was about
if these companies are paying me or I'm
paying for some and no they they don't
pay me and I don't pay them all so
obviously sometimes you had to to pay to
access some of this information and what
that happens you just hook into our
private API because they they always
have an official client so you take this
official client you look at what sources
they are
using which websites and genius pretend
to be their own client and access that
information and that works
the third was problems so obviously when
you are using private API is you will
have problems and but the cool thing
about this project is that it puts them
in a bad position somehow this project
is doing the work that they are not
doing so you don't want to be the bad
guys that will appear in a local
newspaper like big companies shuts down
nice guy that was trying to do a favor
to to the by train users so they they
just ignore it I don't know maybe some
of them even ignored it completely like
they don't even know how it works or how
that happens I remember one day talking
with one guy that was working for one of
these companies as a technician and he
told me oh wow you are the guy that did
this how do you access this information
I tell you I I mean you should know
right and I think I forgot about the
fourth question maybe maybe you guys can
talk afterwards because we're really out
of time and there's the next talk that's
gonna start in two minutes give them a
big hand for the brilliant project
[Applause]