solo everyone next up we have ed Felten
and he will be talking about cloud a B I
enjoyed the talk so hi there
good afternoon so my name is eskelta I'm
an open source and flues yes from the
Netherlands and today I'm going to talk
about how I've been sort of spending my
time for the last two two and a half
years so first I'll give a sort of a
short bio of Who I am
I started using open source software
back in 2003 that was a year I started
studying and I ain't over and there was
a UNIX users group at my university and
at the UNIX user group was the only
place where they had free Wi-Fi back
then so that was sort of a reason for me
to became a member of the UNIX users
group but soon I discovered that the
free Wi-Fi was and everything and I
actually became interested in all of the
hardware that they had them display over
there so that sort of got me dragging to
acting on open source software so what's
actually pretty awesome is back in 2004
so that was the first year of my studies
I actually attended foster and I counted
around a bit and I realized that this is
the 12th time I'm actually attending
Foss them so still the conference is all
the same they still have the same steak
breads as they had 12 years ago so yeah
it's pretty nice conference so after
hacking on open-source software for a
couple of years I you started using
FreeBSD as my primary operating system
on my systems and I became really
interested in how it worked under the
hood you know theming all of the source
code that was stored under user source
together with a guy from my studies we
actually even ported freebsd over to the
Xbox one at one point in time which was
a pretty fun project so in 2008 after
sending in enough patches filling up the
the bug tracker at the freebie is the
often enough I was awarded with a SVM
account back then or CVS even still one
of the first PSD conferences I attendant
was BSD can 2008 in camp in Canada and
one of the speaker's back
that the conference was Chris Latner and
maybe you've heard that name in the news
last week or two weeks ago he's actually
one of the founders of the LVM project
and nowadays he's some kind of compiler
tech lead at Tesla I think and he gave a
really good talk about LVM clang the C
C++ compiler so it had really got me
motivated on you know taking a look at
that compiler as well so one of the
larger things I've been working on back
then was sort of integrating LVM clang
into the freebies the operating system
which is sort of the de facto standard
compiler today at least in FreeBSD so
enough about FreeBSD and LVM I'm not
really going to talk a lot about those
projects today I'm actually going to
talk about what I what I've been up to
since 2014 and this talk is sort of a
bit like chronologically structured so
the first thing we're going to look at
is what if I be doing in 2014 so back in
2014 I was working as an expat in
Germany I had some time to kill in the
evenings so what I started doing was I
was sort of created to get repo in my
home directory and started hacking on
some C++ code I started working on a
database server written in C++ and this
database server was sort of making use
of a whole bunch of things I've never
used before so I was experimenting with
with data structures like miracle trees
for making sure that all of the data was
consistent stored inside of it what was
really interesting about this data
database server that I was designing was
said I wasn't using like sequel queries
or something to you know get access to
the data but I was actually loading a
full BART VM in there so dart is the
scripting language that that is being
designed by Google sort of a JavaScript
replacement and I thought that would be
pretty awesome to actually design stored
procedures in like a high-level
programming language like dart for
replicating transactions across the
network I was using something similar to
Beck sauce called raft but the problem
with this project is I was only working
on this a couple of evenings evenings a
night the other evenings of the week I
usually went over to pubs together
if some people sitting here in the
audience even so that project didn't
actually make a lot of progress in the
end it was just a forgotten get repo
that sort of stayed in my home directory
and it might even be the case that I
reinstalled my laptop so that the code
is now gone but it was a really good
excuse for me to experiment with all
sorts of new technology that I hadn't
used before so just to sort of give you
short overview of how it worked you had
a couple of servers that were sort of
connected with each other in like in a
mesh and they would just replicate all
the transactions over that would be
coming in and then on the outside you'd
you'd have sort of a swarm of clients
and maybe even some caching nodes that
would hold on to certain parts of the
tree and would make sure that that would
all sort of get replicated so one of the
things I was experimenting with first
this database server was I wanted to
harden it so the problem is you're
running arbitrary dart code in a virtual
machine what could possibly go wrong
you know it's user-supplied dart code
what if this dart code simply contains
statements in there that simply say like
you know open these arbitrary files on
disk remove slash EDC / password etc so
I wanted to make use of sandboxing to
actually make sure that if even if there
would be an exploit in the dart VM there
would be no way of breaking out of the
VM and running arbitrary code
the usage access pattern is quite simple
it either accesses its data set that the
stored is some kind of directory on disk
it talks to the other servers in the in
the raft consensus group so like the
inner mesh and then you'd have TCP
connections coming in from clients on
sort of the outside of the network so
what I did back then was I sort of got
distracted and instead of focusing on
like getting the database server working
I ended up focusing only on the
sandboxing and getting that right which
meant that in the end I didn't have a
functional database server sort of
completely stupid idea so I sort of
started making an inventory of all the
security frameworks that are out there
and I sort of came up with this this
slide is sort of my observation of like
the current state of security frameworks
I'm by no means an expert on them but
this is sort of my interpretation of
them so at the at like the top they can
be sort of divided in two separate
groups once that I sort of call static
policy like and other ones that I called
dynamic capability like and I completely
have it like a completely different
mindset of attacking the problem of
hardening software so this static policy
like frameworks they're sort of built
from this mindset saying like the
problem with unique security is in its
security model namely in the way file
system permissions work so we need to
extend on that file system permissions
need to be more complex there need to be
more access control lists or more
frameworks provided by the kernel and
good examples of those frameworks are a
Parmer and selinux and something that
they call POSIX capabilities even though
that system has nothing to do with
capability based security and those
systems they're typically configured by
administrators users in some cases even
package maintainer zuv operating systems
so app armour security policies they're
typically written by by by distro
package maintainer state they build what
they do is they sort of run the program
that they want have harden for a certain
period of
and they said analyze it for say a
couple of hours a couple of days and the
output of that analysis is sort of
turned into a security policy that's put
in place so what happens if if there's
some kind of exploit in it and then that
attacker takes over the application that
person can only run the actions that a
part of the security policy that was
generated during the training phase so
what what i've observed is that those
security frameworks they typically only
provide like very little gain in
security so the best examples I can give
you for example a web browser has a foul
open file save dialog you know whenever
you've done download a file press ctrl s
you get this pop-up box where you can
browse the entire file system well that
sort of automatically means that this
browser needs to be able to access the
entire file system of your of your
system so it basically makes it pretty
much useless also what I think what I
really dislike about the system is that
it's configured by users and
administrators people who have no sort
of real deep understanding of how the
software works internally and we sort of
expect those people to come up with
security policies to make the software
secure like the software developer
doesn't even care about it sort of
throws Dakota over the fence and then
other people have to clean up afterwards
and make it more secure so what you also
see if the last couple years said it's
that all these new security models they
sort of tend to pop up and those are
more dynamic capability like so how it
works is that it's not a policy that
sort of installed globally or in the
system and CDC but it's sort of part of
the programming API sware sort of the
program can say like I've acquired all
the things that I need to access I've
got my network connections I can access
these parts on disk now lock me up and
throw away the keys that's sort of how
the security model works and Linux has a
second model I think the most commonly
used flavor of seccomp is ii BPF where
they have some kind of
OpenBSD pledge and these tend to have
like a really big gain in security as
you'll see in a couple of minutes so a
lot of people ask me whenever I sort of
talk about these this topic is where
does docker fit in in this picture and
it's sort of a really tough question but
if you sort of look at how doctors use
typically I'd say it's more like a
static system you know it's set up by
the users to run a program in a confined
space it's not used as sort of an API by
programs itself so now we're sort of
going to discuss how capsicum works and
basically capsicum is a sort of two-step
recipe for making making software more
secure so the first thing that that the
capsicum developers have sort of done is
they've made the operating system sort
of more object oriented you could call
it like that
so what I've done is I've sort of made
turn everything into a file descriptor
so normally for there are sort of
multiple namespaces that the process can
access it has its file descriptors it
can access the entire file system
namespace then there's the process table
then there's the network stack all sorts
of separate frameworks but what I first
did is I sort of tried to unify it into
signal like scope follow scripters in
this case so one thing that I've sort of
really focused on a lot is having
directory file descriptor support so
that you can open a certain directory
that's on disk and then sort of say like
this file descriptor now represents all
the files that are stored underneath
this directory so you can point to sub
trees in the filesystem basically and
what I've also done is I've added
something called process descriptors
where instead of process IDs that are
sort of global system-wide and you can
see send signals to them based on some
very rudimentary mentary form of access
controls they've changed that into
process descriptors so as you'll see
later on they're sort of a special for
call PD fork and that sort of gives you
a follow skipper to a child process and
if you can't read or write over it but
it sort of acts as a handle giving you
ownership of that process on the other
side and if you close it you sort of
lose that process and in practice that
means that that process gets killed and
shut down so the second step that
they've sort of done with capsicum is
sort of now that the operating system is
more object oriented let's actually let
those objects determine what the process
can do so a process can actually give up
rights it can say I never need to access
this certain resource anymore
by simply calling closed on the file
descriptor and it's gone privilege
separation so say if you have this huge
program and you want to divide it into
multiple sub processes that all have
their sort of separate rights
that's called privilege separation
that's something that you can really
easily implement by this model
you can simply fork the process into two
processes one process closes 1/2 foot to
follow Scripture and the other one
closed the other half and then you've
really separated the privileges of the
process another very nifty feature of
UNIX based operating systems that a lot
of people are unaware of is that you can
actually pass file descriptors to other
processes so if you create a UNIX socket
between two processes you can use a
special message type called SCM writes
where you basically say I've got this
array of file descriptors now push it
through the socket and pop it up on the
other side and if the other side
receives those file descriptors it sort
of duplicates them into different
process so that's also a really nifty
trick where you can sort of say like
I've got access to this directory and
now I need this this other running
process to write some stuff into it well
just push it through a socket and it
comes out on the other side and what you
see is a result of this models that UNIX
user group credentials they become less
important so if you're using capsicum
even if you run a process as root it
doesn't really matter anymore because
the the rights that that process has are
largely now determined by the set of
file descriptors that it owns so how
does capsicum work in practice
first of all process starts up like your
ordinary uniques process you can just
run it from them from a command line or
from like an init script
at some point in time the process calls
the cap enter system call and that sort
of locks up the process it switches the
process over into something called
capabilities mode and when you do that a
lot of things are suddenly forbidden so
you can no longer or open files by
arbitrary file names you can no longer
bind to arbitrary IP addresses and port
numbers you can no longer connect to
arbitrary hosts from the network also
regular forking is not supported because
that needs to be done through the PD
fork all the same of killing processes
you can't just send arbitrary signals to
processes in the process table and the
same holds for some administrative
system calls so rebooting a mounting
doesn't make any sense of course if
you're in this unprivileged mode but
there's a whole bunch of things that you
can still use so reading on file
descriptors writing or file descriptors
creating pipes and socket pairs those
are only things that sort of have this
local impact doesn't have a global
impact on the system then you can still
use the open app system call which was
added in POSIX 2008 which is sort of a
special flavor of the normal open system
call but allows you to open files
underneath a certain directory and same
holds for connecting and binding to
sockets I've made special system calls
where you can at least say like I want
to bind a UNIX socket to a certain path
under a certain directory a very
important aspect of capabilities mode of
course is that there's no way of leaving
capabilities Motors no cap leave system
call otherwise the entire security model
would be useless of course because an
attacker could take an open application
called cap leave and then it could just
go on as it normally does so that's a
really important aspect so for my
database server how you use capsicum in
this case is it's you know again the
same strategy the process starts up like
a regular UNIX process it reads it reads
in its configuration file and in the
configuration file it specifies which
directories need to be used in which IP
addresses on which we need to listen so
we create all these sockets and file
descriptors and then at some point we
call cap enter and voila from that point
on we can only start processing requests
that are coming in and we can't do
anything else so
for my database server I started using
capsicum and even though in in theory it
sounds like a pretty awesome security
framework that gives you some really
tight isolation
I noticed that using it in practice can
be pretty tricky so it took me quite a
long time before I managed to get the
dart VM working within capsicum that was
really exciting so the reason for this
is that you end up with all these pieces
of code that are your this slide and
they're used in practice and there's
they're simply there and you'll sort of
have to deal with that so the top one
was somewhere in the dart VM I think
they had some some code in there where
you could deal with times in different
time zones and if you sort of look up
and see how you convert times to a
certain time in a time zone you have to
use the following sequence so first you
change an environment variable called TZ
you said it - the name of the time zone
you want to use and then what you do is
you call this magic function called TZ
at set and it sort of reinitialize is
the sea library to use a different time
zone and then afterwards you can call
the local time function so under the
hood what happens the T jet-set function
tries to open files under user share
zone info but if you're calling cap
enter then that kind of code no longer
works and what's really annoying is that
bursty jet-set you can't do any error
handling so this piece of code it still
works as it does normally the only
difference is that it still either
represents the time in the old time zone
that was sort of active before calling
T's at set or it uses UTC or something
weird you can't really tell anymore what
it does and also this piece of code that
was at the bottom was also fairly
annoying
there is a piece of code that tried to
convert a multi byte string to a white
character string so what does it what it
means sort of in layman's terms it took
a utf-8 string and it converts it over
to Unicode code points so you can
process it character by character and
call it uses this new locale function
that sort of creates a handle to a
localization object and in this case
it's representing utf-8 the problem of
this function is that it tries to open
user share locale utf-8 slash LCC type
or some file on disk and
come come can no longer access it so
this piece of coats of expects that it
can same he convert utf-8 over to
Unicode but then it sort of starts to
fail and this piece of code is actually
sort of the the most interesting one I
ran into and this sort of really
demonstrates one of the weaknesses of
capsicum this is a crypto library you
can find any internet live Tom Krebs you
can find it on github which is the name
of the source file in there I've
reported this issue numerous times to
the upstream offer but he doesn't
respond what happens this piece of code
tries to implement a cryptographically
secure random number generator so it
tries to open that few random and twice
to read some data from it eventually but
that simply no longer works so what do
we do when we can't opened a few random
well yeah then we just call the clock
function to get like the the running
time of the current process and that
should be used as like the initial seed
for all of the random number computation
so we try to make our application more
secure but by calling cap enter we
actually made alot less secure so what I
learnt in 2013
well sandboxing is stupid and you
shouldn't use it that's sort of why my
takeaway from it it's no fun at all you
spend a lot of time figuring out why
your program doesn't work you run into
these issues that you can actually only
discover by tracing the application
system call by system call and figuring
out what's going wrong there's no
tooling that actually helps you along
the way you know you're you're on your
own and yeah even if you get it working
in the end you still can't be certain
that it actually works in the way you've
sort of expected so I want to sort of
close off this part of my talk by
putting this slide in there if you are
considering using sandboxing frameworks
only mimics STR right now or on any UNIX
flavor then please please please don't
use it within any code that makes use of
third-party libraries because you
actually can't be certain what those
libraries are doing on the inside and
the code in those libraries might
actually be changing over time upstream
might actually reimplementation a number
generator by something that was shown on
one of the previous slides and your
users will simply install the
application install of the dependence
and they might actually end up with
something that's insecure so this is the
reason why sandbox in frameworks work
well for Google Chrome browser tabs they
make use of ii and a reason for that is
they only run c c++ code in there that
they've written themselves or maintained
themselves or have part of their own
distribution that also explains why
pledge works really well for the OpenBSD
people you know they've been they
typically post these reports saying like
we've poured it over so many dozens or
hundreds programs over to use pledge it
works for them because applications and
OpenBSD tempt to be fairly small up to
ten thousand lines of C code and they
make use of libraries that are all part
of their base systems so that's why it
works for them but this also sort of
demonstrates why I didn't work well for
me and it also shows you why if you run
PS on your system and take a look at all
of the processes that are on there that
almost none of them use any sandboxing
framework so 2014 was over I moved back
to the Netherlands at the end of 2014 a
gopher and I we found a new apartment in
which we wanted to live so I was
spending there a couple of days in a row
you know sitting on my knees putting new
floorboards in there and it sort of gave
me some time to sort of reflect on
everything that I've been doing in 2014
so one of the things that I sort of
realized while I was sort of working on
my apartment and getting it all
appreciate was this could all be avoided
if we simply had a programming
environment that didn't have this sort
of state transition in it so where you
didn't call kept enter to sandbox but
simply had sandbox in always turned on
where you could sort of assume that the
program was sandbox so in that case you
could sort of design a C programming
environment where sandboxing is always
enabled that's very important that
allows you to remove all sorts of
functions that are only that only work
in a non sandbox environment so for
example the open call you could just
remove them entirely and all of the
remaining stuff you could just
reimplemented in such a way that it
works well with sandboxing so it really
takes into account that it's running in
the sandbox mode
the advantage of having such a model is
you can now compile your application and
it will break it will break in dozens of
places maybe even hundreds of places but
still you know exactly which pieces of
code you sort of need to inspect to get
it working with sandboxing so it gives
you this really good guided approach of
getting your program sandbox you know
you you start up off of one hundred
compiler errors of your program not
working and then you sort of start keep
on working until you've reached zero and
then you your program works well in the
sandbox mode so for example taking this
piece of code that was from the crypto
library if he would sort of try to build
it in such an environment that the sort
of stripped-down you just get arrows
like be so your compiled compiler would
first throw a like a warning saying like
you know you're trying to call an open
function and I don't know if the
existence of any function under that
name and later on it tries to link that
program and your linker will fro default
the error message is at the bottom
saying that it can't actually combine
all of the object files of your program
into a program because there is no open
function function present so in this
case it's like really trivial to get
this fixed if you'd see a piece of code
that tries to do stuff like this you
could just replace all of it by a simple
call to function so I get random or arc
foreign and buff depending on your
operating system because these two
functions they can be properly
implemented in such a way that they work
well with sandboxing so it's it's really
about just detecting break just because
of sandboxing as early as possible so
what I did then is I after I was
finished decorating the apartment open
up my laptop started hacking again I
went to the page of the boesak
specification which you can just freely
access under this really an annoying URL
so I can't expect you to memorize the
numbers at the end but you can just get
this huge list of all of the functions
that are part of the specification and
it's like hundreds of functions and what
I sort of started doing was sort of
redacting it so just taking a list and
removing everything off it that I
thought was either sort of ancient craft
that you shouldn't be using anyway or
stuff that you should only make sense in
an MA
sandbox environment or stuff that only
makes sense in this privileged
environment and also added a couple of
extensions on top things that Linux has
and BSD has but it's not part of the
Bozek specification - bit sad that
that's the case because in my opinion
that the Poe's expect could do a lot
better job of sort of catching up with
what's being used in practice and I
ended up with this list that was sort of
remarkably small so just to give a
comparison Linux has about 300 system
calls FreeBSD has a bit more I think 400
around a ballpark and this environment
that I sort of came up with with looking
at this list would only give me sort of
an an operating system that it would
only have 60 system calls in them so
that's that's tiny also the number of
data structures that was being used was
really compact so the programming
interface for for this environment
against the operating system was just
tiny compared to normal UNIX flavors so
what I thought then was if it's so tiny
would it make sense to sort of come up
with like a formal specification yeah
so this is basically what cloud ABI is
it's nothing more than a specification
of a compact UNIX and it's stored in
this nicely formatted text file
Molly's wrote in all of nice code to to
actually process that file and turn it
into bindings so it allows you to create
C header files system call tables and
even documentation and those C had a
file system called tables those are sort
of copied into can be copied into source
trees of operating systems to provide
support so those bindings are really
low-level you shouldn't be using them in
practice this is really all sort of
machine generated API so instead of
calling printf for you to end up with
snippets that look like this but it's it
can be used as sort of a basis for
building other things on top so if you
want to build cloud ABI programs you can
simply install those header files on
your system and use a copy of clang
should be a pretty recent one 3.8 or
later and call that in the right way to
target cloud ABI if you just make sure
that you sim link it under the right
names and invoke the compiler under that
net frutos symlinks
and clang is smart enough to figure out
that it should be should be across
compiler so what I've also been working
on is AC library called cloud Lipsy I'm
really bad at naming things and it's
basically just a compact C library built
on top of cloud ABI it implements all
irrelevant stuff from POSIX and ISO C
and compared to normal C libraries that
sort of different instead of relying all
of the the false order user share user
shares own info
it has also state the sets built-in so
that means that it still works well in
sandbox applications
there's also a large testing coverage of
more than 900 tests right now and it
works fairly reliably so here's a list
of software have already ported over to
the cloud ABI looking at the time I had
a couple of projects sort of like bold
over there that I wanted to look in to
sort of show the patches to see to see
how those have reported over but I'll
keep that as an exercise left to the
reader so what's been ported over there
is sort of huge variety of things so it
ranges from crypto libraries already the
start of some GUI libraries have been
ported over you know free type for font
rendering and Kiro for canvas rendering
some some database related projects so
level DB memcache D and I'm pretty
excited about is that we've also ported
over Python free recently so at the end
of my talk you'll get a link to my blog
and there's an article on there on how
you can actually run a sandbox to copy
of Python even in there we're also
working on getting django ported over we
can already run some really simple
django based projects but there's still
a lot of work that needs to be done to
sort of make all of it work I think even
templating is sort of still somewhat
broken in there and need some more -
gurus to to sort of get working so what
we've done is all of that software has
been ported over has also been sort of
pre packaged so what we've done is we've
created this repository of recipes of
how software for cloudy guy can be built
one of the things that I really dislike
about packaged collections is that every
packaged collection nowadays has its own
package manager so if you're using
Python then you have to call pip to
upgrade all of the software that you've
installed through that mechanism same
with sipan's heat and
cetera so what we're doing is we going
in this different direction where we're
actually generating packages for
different operating systems so we're
creating Debian packages rpms even
packages for homebrew on Mac OS and you
can install them by simply running sort
of the native package manager on your
system it's also really nice because the
package names have the architecture in
them you can install multiple copies of
them for different architectures so if
you were to cross compile software for
say an arm it's really easy just install
like the arm version of that package and
you can compile compile directly on your
macbook some piece of code for an
embedded system which i think is like a
huge plus
running cloud ABI software there's a
bunch of operating systems that support
it by now or for which we provide ways
of running it on there so freebie is the
11 or later have all of the support
integrated Linux net bsd we've patch had
sets available for those as well there
is also an emulator available that
allows you to run cloud ABI programs on
unpatched operating systems so this is
what I'm using on my macbook I can't
expect people here in the audience to
recompile the kernel Sarah macbook so
this there's a simple emulator out there
that can at least be used to run cloud
ABI software unfortunately it doesn't
enforce any of the sandboxing under the
hood so if you would write a piece of
inline assembly in your code that sort
of tries to call a Mac OS system called
directly instead of going through the
emulator you can bypass security but
it's sort of good enough for you know
testing software before you deploy it
over to your Linux or BSD cluster so
running cloud ABI software this is a
very simple copy of LS that I've sort of
added to the slide so instead of just
reading the directory listing from a
directory which you specify on a command
line it simply assumes that a file
descriptor in this case file descriptor
0 corresponds to a directory and file
descriptor 1 corresponds to your
terminal so if you want to run this you
end up doing this you end up building it
and running it like this so it's a bit
nasty sort of past fresh EDC over and
standard in and voila you've got a copy
of LS that can only access a directory
and access your terminal that's it so
this works but it doesn't really scale
think of the following use case you've
got a web server that can listen on ten
IP addresses and has 40 different
virtual hosts and for all of those you
need one file descriptor passing this in
on the command line doesn't make any
sense or you know it's it's a mess
so I've been working on an alternative
for that called cloud ABI desh run and
what you basically do is you you've just
invoked it like this you say I want to
run this executable and I want to
provide it a configuration file of how
it needs to be started and this
configuration file sort of a replacement
for command line arguments and it's sort
of Yama like and where it differs from
Yama or extends on yamo is that it's
actually it has file descriptors as a
native datatype so consider this simple
web server for which you're writing a
configuration file normally you'd write
something down like this where you say
it needs to listen on this IP address
and each taxes these files on disk with
cloud ABI run you sort of add
annotations to them where you say like
this is not a string of some kind of IP
address this really needs to be a socket
on which we want to listen and that's
what you do with those exclamations tags
that you see in there that sort of a
standard feature of Yama where you can
introduce typing information into the
definitions so what happens is this file
sort of gets parsed and gets converted
by Claudia I run into this format namely
where all of the files all the resources
are replaced by file descriptor numbers
and this is being passed on to the
program there is also an API for
accessing those files from within the
program of course so instead of using
the init main entry point you now use an
alternative entry point called program
main where you have some accessor
functions for iterating over maps and
dictionaries or sorry maps of sequences
and you also have functions for
accessing boolean's integers strings
file scripters so what's the advantage
of using cloudy ABI run you know of a
unified configuration file format
there's no need to write your own
configuration file parsers programs tend
to become smaller as a result of using
this and there's also no way of actually
accidentally leaking resources into a
program what's really awesome about this
mechanism is you can just
as long as you make sure that you're not
using any exclamation mark tags for
things that you don't want to give away
to a process you can run stuff that you
don't even trust so you can sort of say
like I'm providing in to fowl scripters
one of my standard in on the terminal
one of the standard out on the terminal
as well and then the process can only
read and write through a terminal and
can't do anything else and that's sort
of really ensured by using this utility
that there's no accidental leakage of
stuff another really cool thing of this
mechanism is that it makes programs
really easy to test so because you know
what a program is going to access you
also know that it can't actually
interfere with your production setup for
example so if you have a production and
a staging setup you only need to sort of
check the configuration file to make
sure that you don't list file
descriptors that correspond to servers
or datasets belong to the production
setup and now you can safely your run
your process knowing that it won't
interfere so what if I shown you so far
in this presentation you know I've been
talking about the cloud EBI project that
I've been working on with a bunch of
other people and it's a framework for
building testable and secure programs
and it consists of a couple of
components namely the raw definitions of
the ABI the C library that's built on
top of that the package collection for
prepackaged programs and the cloud ABI
run utility that can be used to safely
spawn those sandbox processes so now I
want to close off this talk by sort of
sketching a road map for the future so
what is going to happen until the end of
times 2048 so I've got some short-term
goals I'm not saying that there are
personal goals but these are goals for
the project I think things that the
project should explore so first of all
we need support for more programming
languages
right now we have support for C C++
Python and Lua
I think so just for programming
languages scripting languages but this
needs to be more nowadays you see a lot
of people writing software and go and in
rust and all sorts of other modern
languages we need to sort of be on board
with that as well so we can actually
welcome more people
into the project also so far we've had a
really strong focus on getting libraries
to work you know as you saw in the
previous slides there's a whole bunch of
libraries saidif already mean packages
but now sometimes actually get full
programs to work we have all of the
dependencies ported over and now we can
actually start building full programs
you know having a sandbox my sequel
server where you're you can only sort of
say like this is your data directory and
this is your socket on which you're
receiving incoming sequel queries that's
pretty awesome same holds for nodejs if
you want to run sandbox web applications
of course linux support right now it's
an external repository this needs to be
integrated period or at least the things
that we can get rid of need to be
upstream into the official Linux kernel
so in the end all of cloud EBI support
is nothing more than a simple kernel
module that you can load into a stock
Linux kernel and of course there's
always the need to improve the
documentation always and I already have
a couple of how-tos on like the cloud
API blog but we really need to extend on
that there needs to be good developer
documentation as well long term goal for
the project so a lot of people they sort
of say to me like cloud API is the
stupidest name I've ever heard it
doesn't make any sense
the reason for that is that I often also
have to show this slide sort of
explaining the sort of original mindset
I had for the project so cloudy API is a
way where you can do dependency
injection for UNIX programs and what
would happen if you could actually make
use of that as part of some kind of
cluster management system so say you
want to deploy a pipeline of database
servers web front-ends batch jobs all of
that stuff and you've made use of this
model there you could actually design
some pretty fancy stuff so first of all
you could build some kind of GUI where
you can drag and drop programs on a
canvas and hook them up fruit like
arrows say like this is a web front-end
it needs to talk to this database server
you could just click a play button and
it would automatically set it up it
would know how to sort of connect all of
those programs together you could also
even have like monitoring dashboards
based on this concept where you know the
cluster management system knows the
relationship between programs so we can
actually
if you accurate monitoring for that also
a very interesting aspect is that this
kind of mechanism could be used for like
setting up the connections between those
processes securely so if it knows that
it's going to start up to two processors
on the same server it doesn't even need
to care about cryptography because it's
already sort of secure nobody kind can
eavesdrop on those kinds of connections
but if it's starting those two processes
in different data centers then the
cluster management system could be
responsible for creating the keys
sending them over to the two servers
running the processes and the server
could then automatically set up a secure
channel between those two processes
which simplifies this kind of management
a lot I think using kubernetes a lot and
we have to spend quite a lot of time
getting all of the crypto and all of the
key exchange right and this could be
sort of solved automatically so my
long-term goal is maybe we could extend
sort of tools like cuban 8's to have
proper cloud api support and do this out
of the box so now I'm sort of at the
last one or two slides of my talk I
briefly want to talk about the
sustainability of this project I've been
working on this project for two years I
had the luck of being able to work on
this for for one full year
unfortunately because there is sort of
no full-time headcount on this project
anymore the things that have sort of
shown on the previous slide are actually
sort of infeasible at this moment and
that's why I sort of you know this is
sort of like a call for help to the
audience if you think that this is a
cool project you know at least start
using it you know try exploring it see
whether it works for you you'll quickly
run into bugs hopefully send pull
requests and you know it would be
awesome if like but the cloudy API team
can grow because I think it's a really
valuable project you know in my opinion
that allows you to build secure
applications just easily compared to
toll of the existing frameworks out
there so please give it a try I wanna
give my special thanks to a couple of
people some of them are sitting in the
audience good friends of mine have been
sort of either pestering me with bug
reports or just giving me
mental support or cat ogia our cats
walking on my keyboard all day long
wrecking my code I want to thank two
people at Kuna Bay Bay who've also been
supporting me over last half year and
I've allowed to sort of work on this
part time so this concludes my talk
here's a couple of links be sure to
check them out are there any questions
so thank you for doing this because it's
really important that we finally got a
secure Linux open source and free
software kernel and my question is first
of all the the problems that you noted
we're all more or less to do with the
the VFS and use basically say you don't
have a root VFS you can't do open why
don't you do something like a CX root
and then bind in the appropriate global
state that is benign and my second
question is is that you talk about the
save issue with Firefox why don't you
have something like a power box or have
you thought about how to do a power box
so so to answer your your your first
question which was why didn't you sort
of ever way of organizing the filesystem
layout so what I've noticed is that this
is basically also the mindset that
operating systems like plan nine have
been using you know get give have proper
api swear processes can sort of create
layouts of their own file system
namespaces everything is done in the
falsest namespace but my observation is
is that it sort of quickly gets messy
and bloating because so in the case of a
file system what you can do is you can
sort of pass it on to new processes to
child processes to help or processes but
what you'll see in practice is that
nobody will borrow to sort of clean
those up so then you sort of end up in a
state where you have like a bunch of
sort of privileged separated processes
but in the end I still make use of this
bloaty file system namespace where
there's a lot of stuff in there that
processors don't need to access so
basically how this differs from from
what you proposed how cloudy API differs
is that it's a false Krypton namespace
it's a flat namespace and my hope is
compared to using a false or like a tree
based namespace is that this will not
leak as quickly you know the people are
a bit more thoughtful about this well
maybe it's a bit overly often optimistic
but we'll see
to answer your your second question so
like the example I gave with the browser
I mean it's it's just like a simple
example
that could like be substituted for any
different application so for example
your text editor has the same issue of
course when you're running vim it can
also access a lot of things in the
meantime that shouldn't be accessible
and yeah that could be solved by making
use of different sort of helper tools
but the nice thing about this approach
is that it actually enforces the use of
a mechanism like that you know it's not
about just that I've got like a whole
solution for that in place already set
up but the idea beyond cloud API is to
come up with my environment that sort of
forces people to design applications in
this sort of privileged separated way
that's sort of you know trying to solve
it at the root and not at the top that's
that's what the cloudy API project is
about did it answer your questions or
any other questions
Oh God are you aware of e and so they
have a mechanism called vats and that
more or less does exactly what you're
talking about with respect to
automatically creating secure channels
between between multiple computers over
the network and doing consistency things
so I'm not aware of that project
specifically well what's the name of
that again II just to let her eat that's
it okay oh look into that damn man
if you look for a mark millar and a then
you'll find it ah thanks
well then if nobody else has questions
and thanks for attending my talk later
today there's going to be a talk in a
BSD DEP room where I sort of go into
more details on the kernel side of how
all of this works well I guess not all
of you should be showing up because the
room is a lot smaller than than this one
all right thanks that's for you thanks
in China
yeah so the charger was mine
yeah so I'm going to discuss how it
works because the point is I
because I wasn't sure I would
so I guess I should
I got everything
so fun