good morning everybody our next speaker
is from current to talk to us about
requirements bizarre please give a big
hand to it fun so hello and good morning
welcome to this talk about requirements
bizarre software that we have been
developing for 5 years now
the title is connecting end users and
developers so my name is istvan Koren
and I traveled here one hour from iwth
Aachen University in Germany my twitter
handle is aston here you can use the
hashtag if you want to take a pic that'd
be cool
and our organization on github where you
find all the code is here and this is
the URL of our tool so we're a Research
Institute and we in computer science and
we develop a lot of software in in big
projects and we are rolling out to a lot
of users and we always have the issue of
getting the feedback from the users and
I think that's quite a common problem
and this is how we how we tackle it so
well usual idea is just let the user
send emails or just make a forum a
discussion forum but that doesn't really
scale so what people in the open-source
will do is things like that so issue
trackers for example this is a
screenshot from in Bugzilla but well
it's not really end user friendly so
there are things like refactor string
bundle Jaso they are really confused
this is for the Android project but also
which write sending people to github
issues but then people they saw the
files and the code and they were turned
off and just closed that we also tried
sending them to JIRA with this form but
they were overwhelmed by the number of
fields you have to fill in here so what
people obviously like is when you look
at the App Store's from iTunes or
or place store is apps or comments so
this is for example from taking from
Facebook and people complain about the
software here because they like it's
just a single single text feel then you
just enter the the box there and yeah
but for developers it's really hard to
click through all the comments so yeah
what we want to achieve here is in the
pipeline from continuous integration
continuous delivery continuous
deployment what a lot of us already do
is another continues which is continuous
innovation so we want to listen to the
users and allow them to contribute to
send their ideas because we notice that
those ideas are often the best so we
came up with requirements Bazaar you can
find it under this URL requirements
passado
org and yeah it's a web-based to online
tool for continuous innovation so the
key ideas here are connecting the end
users the with the developers designers
but also researchers and other
stakeholders involved in the development
and you want to allow them to discuss to
post new ideas to send comments to
prioritize to vote to like just just
like on Facebook and also share share
ideas through to other social networks
another key aspect is making clear what
the developers are working on so the
users that they get notifications if
their idea was taken up and is currently
being developed and then rolled out
integrating on any context that means
whether we are on a mobile app or we are
on a desktop app where we're on your web
application
whether we're in the tram or sitting
here and we want to enable to make it
very easy to to submit new ideas and
finally the export options to both
directions
one is to social networks
or end-users to discuss further and the
other direction is to issue trackers so
things where developers can can work on
and discuss the technical details like
github issues or JIRA the before I show
you an example these are the details
that you're going to see it's a
progressive web app it's responsive it's
mobile first develop it installs on home
screen so when you visit it a couple of
times your Chrome browser actually asks
you on Android whether you want to
install it and then it feels like a
native app which is really cool it's
developed using polymer web components
and the backend is based on Java and
Microsoft's architecture we're using OPA
reconnect so we have our own provider
there but we plan to integrate Google or
other big providers as well it's hosted
on github and we use JIRA for issue
management and finally Jenkins for
continuous integration also the
continuous deployment on our build and
production environments and now let's
show you the software
well so this is it it's a requirements
passado org it's actually localized so
here the some languages of our research
group so you can switch over to German
very fast the responsiveness that I
talked about so this is it
all right so this is the domain page we
have some a lot of test projects
obviously and some popular projects then
you can click to explore the public
project so it's you can see everything
when you're not logged in so here is the
list of projects or the most popular so
that's - peer is a Java framework that
we develop in-house we also notice
people from outside of us that we didn't
know started using it for example in
Afghanistan 60 people are using it for
building their IT stacks it's cool our
own project and let's click here so then
you see the categories for example the
front end or the backhand and I'm just
switching over to the front end and
basically this is this is the main
interface so it's a card-based layout if
you know material design and let me sign
in here so that is our
open ID Connect provider yeah and now
I'm logged in and if I want to add
something for example I noticed
yesterday that the statistics on the
main page are not yet localized so stats
are not available in my language bad and
I can save it and it will just appear
here and then I can star it I can follow
it to get emails we have a nice activity
tracker
so you see what is going on so some of
somebody of you here or outside and the
Internet has already follow the project
cool Thanks
yes so that's basically the the web app
and I also want to talk a bit about the
future ideas
right so what we also have is we have
wept because it's web components based
it's very easy to actually export it to
other websites so we have for example
project that's doing augmented reality
learning we have the content the tiles
on their homepage integrated so the
people don't notice that it's actually
hosts and requirements buzzer it's
pretty cool it's so one-line integration
in WordPress
we have worked going on to gamify it so
you get badges and points and all that
we want to add design tools so you can
upload screenshots which you can already
do but also mark and annotate that and
very important thing that we want to do
it also embrace new communities outside
of software development so if we go back
you find a project a category here for
the requirements Bazaar which is target
communities so things like refugee aid
where people come to Germany or other
countries and they want something and
they just type it in here or
neighborhood assistance clubs and
associations a soccer club or and so on
so we think that we hope that this idea
could also help them or other other
fields so that they they learn actually
from how software developers work
efficiently one part of that is the
localization so I already showed you and
I have here a goodies so we already and
in the development branch we translated
it to Farsi so it's partly so there are
some some issues here that's why it's
not a release yet but very soon it will
be available also for in the native
language of the afghanistan community
all right so that was it so if you have
questions here and I will be also
available outside if you want to talk
with me afterwards thank you very much
is fund we can't please so I see a
question there back there
hi good product and is there M
management for duplicates no not yet but
we're working on social network analysis
tools to automatically get that also
something we want to add very soon is
tax so based on tag be hey tagging
behavior we could already well filter
out some of the duplicates any other
questions don't be shy
hi can we add attachment drawings just
to explain a little bit more so my idea
yes you can add attachments yeah so any
more questions another one over there
so the export/import that you mentioned
is it a kind of Excel export or an API
that I can connect well it's it's all a
REST API so today already can ask the
REST API we have axel export already so
C s comma separated values and github
issues export is also already there on
on the development environment so if
there's no more questions then I suggest
we wrap up began fresh fun
[Applause]