but all the background
material into their heads Oh two day
three hours or two two minutes
this is going to be a problem to cover
this area in 20 minutes without you
having all the background but I'll do my
best
ipv6 simple beautiful if you connect to
the foster Network you run ipv6 only
you're happy things work mostly but more
things work this year than last year but
this is fairly simple if you move your
stuff and you portlet ipv6 both server
and client things will just work it's
just more bits on the IP packets dienes
TCP UDP everything works like before no
problems this was the world we saw in
the mid-90s when we said that well ipv4
is dying so fast it's going to be gone
before year 2000 no at least it's gone
so I'm not gonna spend much time on this
you all know ipv6 right you all use ipv6
networks right cool this is where we get
into trouble we have two stacks we have
the old legacy dying creepy scary
insecure ipv4 Network and we have the
ipv6 Network and we end up in situations
where the client wants to connect to a
server and suddenly have the choice of
two different paths they're two
different protocols bringing us from
point A to point B this is like putting
my wife behind the wheel and trying to
explain you can go this way and that way
and she's gonna look like what
and then I'm not saying go that way we
did that in dorsey's we said go ipv6 if
you have ipv6 ipv4
go ipv6 this turned into a problem
Microsoft have done a lot of good things
with ipv6 they actually in a Windows
released enable ipv6 for every single
computer through automatic tunnels so
your Windows desktop believed it had
ipv6 firewall blocked it sites that
actually published ipv6 DNS records for
the same hostname got into trouble
because the browser said Google's not
reachable Facebook not reachable which
wasn't very good for marketing didn't
help the brands when everyone thought
the server's was down so they
immediately disabled ipv6 which is not
what we wanted the solution to all of
this is happy eyeballs in the idea we
created a standard specification saying
you should not start with ipv6 and then
when you fail move to ipv4 you should
connect to both ipv6 could give give it
a few milliseconds Head Start right but
connect to both mostly at the same time
and the first that response you keep
that connection close to other one and
you'll be happy the users will be happy
the marketing people will happy and we
can safely migrate to ipv6 so the
browser vendors they implemented all
this on June 6 a few years ago we tested
live on the Internet
Facebook Microsoft Google everyone
turned on ipv6 on the same host names
and nothing happened all browsing
succeeded everyone was happy in their
eyes marketing people was happy and we
had ipv6 back in DNS happy eyeballs
connecting at the same time not doing it
serially and continuing on the session
that opened first
that's great well on mobile phones I
frequently see that we have multiple
interfaces so now we have ipv4 and
possibly ipv6 on the mobile cellphone
Network and then we have Wi-Fi
who should we set up for connections 10
where's the limit
I have devices with 4 SIM cards and
Wi-Fi so the new world is giving us
problems and what happens what we see is
that the mobile networks that I add ipv6
the ipv4 network it's suddenly behind on
that carrier grade professional high end
cool not not that small and family home
router stuff you have at home this is a
professional carrier grade not which
makes it no better right real
time protocols are not doesn't love each
other that's not it
they have session management on their
network they're adding a lot of boxes to
manage stuff to make your experience
better which practically kills
everything you want to do real time
because to make things better the
closed-down IP flows to get room for new
IP flowers to make new users happy so
your concurrent session in the
background to your ex and people server
go your WebSocket trash burn no fun at
all so we see that ipv4 network is
quickly dying we have cell phones in
production years in the National Public
Radio where I spend a lot of time these
days we're moving heavily towards ipv6
which gives us a very clear path for the
live broadcast audio directly from
otherwise to our studio the ipv4 network
everyone complains we see with these
mobile apps is that networks come and go
suddenly the network you're using and
you're having so much fun with Wow
disappears yet showed up I was really
bad going back this is making life
really really hard to live real time
connections bi-directional so happy
eyeballs well that's a start but we
really need to focus on this in sip we
need to have session resumption like the
previous speaker talked about with XMPP
we need to be able to move our sessions
but in multimedia
that's called eyes there's some cool
stuff in eyes sol mention it but of
course the internet is sleeving IP we're
moving everything on top of HTTP right
and this all the problem will happen
i've also everything is good and dandy
and we're getting the new versions
everything is sexy one protocol for us
all for those of you who doesn't believe
that religion we still have good old set
right so the browser vendors sold this
years ago the offenders sold this moving
to next slide
XMPP while tcp-based have the same
problems as HTTP haven't seen any
discussion about solo days I hope they
cleaned up their illness Oh WebRTC in
the core specs s we're dual stack
right how many have tested that and in
some specs I asked
Oh what about ipv6 or dual stack we'll
take that later okay when are see 32 61
which is 140 pages of fun stated early
sick works with both ipv4 and ipv6 so we
should be good right I mean come on this
was in 2002 tell me your supports ipv6
from day one in our code staying happy
do we have a problem in set I tested it
ship it I've been testing numerous times
we have issues with finding the best
media path but there are standards
setting up a connection to signaling try
hype eyeballs over UDP fellows give me a
solution to that finding the quickest
connection where we have a
connectionless protocol setting up the
best connection between users so this is
rather fun I ended up with this
conclusion yeah we do have a problem
someone is going to fix it
oops someone is me hey join me in fixing
this oops guess not so started writing
some ITF documents I got actually a few
people on board helping me write those
and getting it through the whole process
so we have one or C now and we have two
more drafts coming on how to fix this in
sit what we discovered while testing was
that ipv4 devices with single stacks
crashed and burned because in sip the
iPad races everywhere in the messages
and we injected ipv6 addresses here
they're their software burn so even if
you're not porting your software to ipv6
you need to watch out when you have
these protocols because we're sending
addresses inside also when I said in my
dns that hey I prefer if you connect to
me over ipv6 in my yessiree records the
first priority was ipv6 only the second
was ipv4 and ipv6 many implementations
crashed and burned because they couldn't
real understand that first priority and
didn't understand that they should fail
over to the second priority and that's
covered in the RC you're all going home
to read that I actually wrote so crashes
no connections that's fun yeah for media
we have eyes and eyes have ipv6 editions
you have dual stacks and the default
role is if you are P v6 only you have to
help those poor poor poor pieces of code
out there that doesn't support this by
going to a turn server and applying for
one of these ipv4 legacy addresses so
you have to help others have I seen this
in WebRTC no the biggest problem I had
was in one of the core RFC's there was a
little or so people came to me and said
well Dorothy says
I should ask for ipv4 or ipv6 and ask
for one five years of fighting the war
changing that on and but we did it we we
change that or C so where are we sit one
or C published one sip forum document
ITF drafting process we're making
progress in progress XMPP I have the
same happy eyeballs problems I haven't
seen any don't need and the or sees but
the implementations need to test and
seeing that web RTC should work sounds
promising right yeah we have work to do
and I believe there are many many other
protocols out there that have this
problem but people haven't really tested
haven't considered the impact of dual
stack fully I think in sip we're
actually way ahead of a lot of protocols
so you may ask yourself is this for real
yes many mobile carriers around the
globe started in the US but actually now
in Sweden as well or carrier in the
radio added ipv6 we have dual stacks and
all our office mobile phones
so everything journalist out there dual
stack so that's cool
at the same time they actually added a
carry granite and every week they keep
modifying the session timers without not
which is fun because then I have to
modify to keep allies in my camellia
server which keeps me busy so they're
adjusting their stuff they don't want to
occupy as more people get on board with
this dual stack server the carrier guard
not allocates memory for all the
sessions and they don't want to keep
them in memory so they went down from
five minutes to three minutes and now
recently to one minute
and they also have a session limitation
we haven't found that and they don't
want to tell us but they are confirmed
they have an limitation on the number of
concurrent ipv4 sessions and they're
properly adjusting that as well so this
is fun
we discover that we have those little
access points connecting to cell data
they still run that even though the
network runs not so in those cases if we
use ipv4 we have dual knots
what can be better than a single net
yeah
two knots in the same session we're
happy that little mobile packed bad way
had a sip helper application an
application level gateway that in yeah
key so loves so removing everything all
the media try preview six as fast as we
can so we're really pushing our vendors
and that's the tough problem they are
not ready for this
Oh we tested ipv6 in our lab and it
works ok have you tested this this this
oh I wasn't aware of that thanks God I
can push 2.2 ITF documents and real
stuff in the sip forum not just being me
even though I wrote them you have issues
with this asterisk as he issues free
switch most like to have no solders and
the same thing I think goes for a lot of
these we need to solve the happy
eyeballs problems and I need you guys to
help me would you DP because that's the
missing draft you're drafted right it's
getting painful because this is in
production it's now really it exists in
a lot of products we have a lot of
theories move to TCP and you can do hep
eyeballs fix their eye stuff and you're
ready
you also need to look because a lot of
your applications even though they're
zip web versus X and P P they use HTTP
or LDAP or something else
all of these TCP connection protocols
there will have happy eyeballs problems
as soon as you add ipv6 to the DNS entry
so this is your application soon to be
honest I haven't started testing that
because I've been so fully occupied with
this we said that the last Zipit where
pages APIs actually mold we say that we
need to install not 64 inert
but this has been so painful it's been
enough but you're right we probably need
to look into that as well especially
with the NSA and other things not 64 can
be interesting more questions you're
happy you're going to read all the
documentation the AI downloaded you're
happy eyeballs stay in this room and the
rest of the documentation will be
downloaded at five o'clock or something
into your extra memory thank you and the
same problems that we have with media
since you're lucky enough to have TCP I
mean then you can used to do to have
eyeballs and I'm fortunate enough to