okay thank you for
ending this presentation so my angel
myself read and I want to talk to you
about fascinating convergence of
technologies we have reached a point now
where on the one hand we have basically
infinite computational power everyone
has a very fast and pure on his desk and
on the other hand we've got this
proliferation of small unmanned aerial
vehicles fitted with high quality
cameras and I want to talk you through
the generation of digital elevation
models geo-reference digital elevation
models using such kinds of UAV so I want
to show you a bit what software can be
used what are the flight requirements
and here's an example of two
measurements that were done so to give
you an idea of the area that I'll be
interested in that's about 40 meter
scale so we're talking about areas of
like a few hundred meters side pixel
resolution sub decimeter
and here's an example of braiding and
flow change of a small river between two
weeks where you can have aerial images
with short repetition time so I want to
get through this discussion about how to
generate such ultra photos and digital
elevation models using small unmanned
aerial vehicles that's actually a sequel
to the presentation I made at first 4G
French last summer
unfortunately tutorial I wrote at the
time was in French I had planned on
translating this for first then I
haven't got time yet to do so so if
anyone is interested in getting this
tutorial in English of course feel free
to send an email and I'll be happy to
translate it for you so why am i doing
this basically my basic input for your
morphological investigations or any kind
of geo-reference investigation that I'm
interested in is using elevation as a
basic input whoever I'm instruction
interested in measuring landslides a
glacier that's what I'm interested in
glacial melt material transport flooding
that kind of information now if you just
rely on global digital elevation models
such as SRTM or GDL you have what I
would consider low resolution from my
perspective
digital elevation models which are
typically three second arc over most of
the world one second arc over the US for
SRTM so we're talking about 30 90 meter
solution lateral resolution and
additional usually you have one digital
elevation model so if you want to make
difference of digital elevation models
you need to find some way of having
repeated digital elevation modes which
are usually not available so what I'm
interested to hear is how can i generate
local digital digital elevation models
which means what I mean by local is less
than ten square kilometer area what I'm
interested in is high-resolution sub
this meter pixel size and high update
update rate let's say 1 DM every week or
every month so that I can make
subtraction of zero elevation model and
see material movement or or changes of
the elevation of my area additionally
since I'm splits all started as a hobby
and as usual hobby gets more and more
into the work I'm interested in low low
cost equipment what I can mean low cost
I started this with a less than hundred
euro one of these toys that you can buy
a Christmas and slowly I'm getting into
more involved equipment now I'm doing
this with DJI drones but I'm I'm talking
about sub kilo euro equipment so the
challenge with that will be de tolly
telling to you about is that we will
have to handle a huge amount of images
typically we're going to acquire 600,000
images per flight so huge that might not
make sense to you but 600 to 1000 images
at high resolution images of typically
5/6 megabyte per image we're talking
about 6 7 gigabytes worth of images to
process the generator DM we're talking
about 10 square kilometer we've set this
meter resolution we're going to have
Giga gigabyte sized
orthophotos so I find this a bit
challenging to handle now this means
that hardly will be able to handle a
graphical user interface because such
data set would be
horrendously slow to render so I will be
presenting to you a tool a command line
interface that's been developed by a
French National Geographic Institute
evn which I'm not totally unrelated to
but I got I fell in love with a software
that we developed Macchio disini is in
charge of its development in one of the
labs off of en
and I want to introduce you this
software because at first it might be a
bit you might get a bit afraid when you
have a look at it Midmark and i want to
show you step by step how powerful the
approach relevant to the unique
philosophy of one tool for one solution
and not a fully integrated to will allow
you to on the one hand handle these huge
data set and on the other hand know
exactly what you're doing for each step
we have one tool for each step which
means we had an output which tells us if
this step was successful if it failed
then we have to find a reason but there
is no point in continuing the processing
if one step of processing failed this
will be get clear I think next in the
next slide but before we start
processing images we need to acquire
images so just let me emphasize how
compliance with regulation is important
if you're just doing this for fun you
might or might not comply with
regulations when it gets into your job
you must comply with regulations in my
case I'm flying in North know of no way
I need to get of course flight allowance
or exam I need to get flight
organisation from civilian Authority
this is a 30 page document that you have
to fill you have to check with the
difference ministry if they agree that
you take pictures this is Demilitarized
Zone that where I'm flying so difference
ministry doesn't care you have to check
that you're not harassing wildlife so
this kind of activity you have to check
to get it relation to fly once you get
all the authorizations you have to plan
your flight
so flight planning for making the
validation mode requires that you have
enough surface coverage from one picture
to the other so basically you make must
make sure that your pictures overlap by
at least 60 percent typically Micmac
says you should have eighty percent
overlap so once you have decided what is
your horizontal velocity in my case
typically 10 meter per second and you
know your altitude over the area then
you can calculate how often you have to
take an image in my case for example I'm
flying with a coverage of 100 meter I'm
finding a 10 meter per second I need to
acquire one pictures about every 2
seconds so this is why a 20-minute
flight will generate 600 to 900 images
now
once you've acquired your images you can
do this manually this is what I
originally did because I wanted to track
some features I want to do track some
ever or we can automate the flight but
in all cases you have the angular
coverage of your camera you know the
altitude so you can by knowing the
resolution of your camera you can
compute the pixel size and you see that
the UAV flying at 100 meter high with a
4000 pixel resolution will typically
create a DM with pixel size 4 centimeter
I'm not saying that what DM will have 4
centimeter resolution but at least your
picture your pixel size would be 4
centimeter and of course now we have
automated software this is a TG on one
of a free software that you can use for
to define the flight so you just have to
define the 2 corners of your flight
takeoff the drone get a coffee and come
back 20 meters later to land the drone
in this case it's landing automatically
you have to bring it back manually so
we've collected all these images each
one of these dot is an image how do we
process this image to create a DM first
thing either you're using a DVI or
geo-reference camera and it's easy you
have a exit tag and you've got the GPS
position in your image alternatively
you're putting a high quality camera
which does not have GPS you've got on
the other hand a GPS recorder what you
what I'm doing is I'm using a Jif to
command line interface exist tool
software for tagging my images so I can
say okay if you check the header of your
image
you know what the image is when you take
a clock in this case this is a GPS
discipline clock at Observatory close to
our place and this gives me I have the
header of image I have the GPS time I
can compute the difference between my
camera time and my GPS time and then
exit tool gives you the option - geo
sync and you can give it a whole enemy
are locked for enemy a locked file a
directory where your images are and
Egypt will take care of geo tagging all
your images so once we've got this set
of geo tagged images I will need to
inform my processing software we'll see
why the next step where each picture was
taken so this must be done in the
projector for projected referential in
my case I'm
lying orphan no way no way is UTM 43
north so I will convert all my positions
my WGS 94 84 NMEA log into a projected
framework and I will create a file at an
ASCII file in which I have longitude
latitude altitude and file name you will
notice that I remove a big offset
northern Norway is something like a
million meter sorry a hundred thousand
million North so I remove all this
offset here otherwise you have rounding
error under processing so you just keep
the relevant decimals of your position
and filename and you convert this text
file from a text file into XML and
Micmac is always prefix with mm3d so all
comments are mm3d and I want to convert
the orientation from a text file which
is here to an XML file and we will see
that we need to select a subset of
images for calibrating the lens
properties so we say we're going to use
as a reference image this particular
image which meets some of requirements
namely that there is a maximum elevation
variation in this image and I want to
take 25 images to calibrate the lens so
this is pretty much what you you will
always do you will always have mm 3d
watch what squad command you want to use
and the options to create whatever steps
you want so the first thing I want to do
is why do I need to use the GPS position
of each camera the first thing that a
software processing software will need
is type points meaning points that are
matching on above images so that the
software can say ok this same image was
the same point was taken from different
points of view now if you just do this
stupidly on a 600 picture data set and
you just say I want to correlate all
possible pairs then you'll find out that
you need like 200 thousand matching
steps and each one of these matching
step is tracing something like a second
so you're going to spend a few days just
finding the type points but you have a
good very strong assumption you know
that this image will most probably not
have any red a similar point with this
one because we are so far away so what
we can tell here is you tell Mi'kmaq ok
just consider images that are adjacent
in their GPS position so this is why we
compute
this file previously so we're going to
ask Nick Mack to use a Tapioca tool
using the file the file that we just
generated previously I export the text
file so that I can draw these images in
in QGIS and I asked it to only use those
pairs of closest images so by doing this
instead of having two hundred thousand
points you only have ten thousand pairs
to analyze much much faster and here I
drew pairs that Micmac has identified it
makes sense so the algorithm is working
pretty well and by doing this Micmac is
going to search for in pip points that
are matching in both pairs so here are
two adjacent images and if you follow
the arrows on the on your right you see
that the vector of motion of between the
two images is indeed properly computers
so Mi'kmaq has selected relevant points
on this image and computed where these
various points have moved from one image
to the other this will be the basic
input that we will need so here you see
first step verify that indeed the tied
point identification has worked properly
if you have very smooth areas or
features that are similar in multiple
pictures
this step will not work properly you can
draw the arrows and you can check that
these wizards working properly now we've
got the tied points next step we need to
model the lens we have a UAV I bought a
cheap toy
I have no characteristics of my lenses
so the system can automatically generate
a model of your lens I don't have nice
illustration so what I use is with a
slide to show you how you can help
yourself with Micmac when you don't know
how to do things the tool for matching
for finding lens properties is tapas so
we asked Micmac to run the tapas - and
we will help we have the list of all
possible lens models of course the more
complex the model is the better the
modeling of a lens properties but the
more difficult it is to make it to
converge so it's a trade-off between
complex models where you have a lot of
freedom but chances of not converging
and basic models with fewer models are
poor models but easier convergence I
just show you the output of tapas here
so that you can realize that all these
numbers here are errors in pixel in the
very beginning when you start the model
the length model is very poor so you see
I have errors of three peaks l 11 pixel
that's very bad if your model is
converging properly you will end up with
less than 1 pixel error between your
images so at first it might be
frightening to see these big numbers
coming out of MIT Mac but actually
they're very relevant they tell you the
percentage of tie points that will be
used and your pixel error so basically
if your picture is not converging
towards sub want value well you're in
trouble and something went wrong so at
the end you see that your worse
resolution is 1 pixel and residual is
about 0.9 pixel the lens was property
model properly modeled this is working
fine so once you've modeled your lens
you create a coarse cloud so this
basically to check if Micmac was able to
position properly the path of a UAV over
the surface and if your surface makes
sense with respect to what you expect
from your GM just be careful I was
recently introduced to this paper which
shows that self talkative self
calibration of the lens Matt creates
very low-frequency large-scale
distortions parabolic distortions which
I have seen so this is a caveat about
self calibration of the lens you will
create a large-scale distortions or you
might and if you look closely you see
here steel tracks while on the Sun here
that helped the software match the
features on this snow coated area once
you've done the course point cloud this
is the most time-consuming part you
create a fine point cloud you create the
ortho photo and you create a correlation
map that tells you where you're most
confident that your digital elevation
model is correct so what does the fine
point cloud look like well here is an
example of a fine point cloud of
generator this way so this is the
example of your fine point cloud you see
it's about 10 million points and you can
move around in your fine point cloud
that you've generated this way and
zooming to the area works the other way
and you can check the topography of your
digital elevation mode if I can zoom in
yeah so you see that indeed you have a
topography and as you haven't realized
you've got the hills and the valleys
that you can check so here I collected
these images I have one satellite image
of the region I'm interested in you
remember that we removed an offset in my
geo reference images
I put the offset back I insert this in
my world file so that my dataset is your
reference I correct for altitude I get
an image in pixels I have I get in an
XML file resolution so one pixel is 22
centimeters and if I overlap my DM you
see that I have braiding of rivers you
have fine continuity if you look at the
heal over here you indeed have something
that is relevant with aerial pictures so
the topography is matching the features
that we see on the ground so that's an
example of fusion of qg in qgis of your
digital elevation model with a
background satellite image you cannot
see here but this is a former site image
with 2 meter resolution and I get a DM
Rob sorry and I get GM with sedessa
meter resolution so when you zoom in you
really see the difference between the
big pixel of a satellite image and fine
pixels of a G of a UAV so here is an
example of subtracting 2 DM this 2 DM
were acquired one week apart during this
time interval there was a big flood here
is a channel where the river is flowing
and if I take a subtraction I see this
deep here which is about 3 meter deep
and does this match reality well I
didn't make a practical field check but
this is a kind of Canyon where River has
carved this path in the moraine that I'm
interested in and indeed that's pretty
much 3 meter high so it matches what can
be expected from heavy flooding in this
brittle material of a moraine where
landslides has created this deceleration
model difference now closer to you you
might do the same thing this is
something that was done in the lab I
collected two diesel edition models of
the parking lots next to our laboratory
and here is an example of acquired
acquisition in the end of September
beginning of April I did the same when
returning in May and when you do this
kind of processing you get the
correlation Maps
the correlation map tells you that where
there is grass of course grass has very
little relevant features so that the
mi'kmaq is unable to create a DM but on
the parking lot and on the soil covered
area the correlation is very good and
when you do a digital elevation model
you have a parking lot you have a cars
over here which are parked if I do a DM
subtraction
I see which car have moved from the
parking lot from one time to the other
so basically this is working pretty well
so as a conclusion to this presentation
I wanted to show you that using aerial
images with at least sixty percent
overlap azimuthal pictures you can
create these utilization modes by first
identifying type points lens properties
which are automatically generated from
the images if you even if you have a toy
camera you will be able to generate more
or less good quality lens models and you
need to get the camera position if you
want to have a geo reference model if
you just want to have a qualitative
model without your referencing you don't
even need a GPS it will handle by itself
the variety positions of the cameras we
create a course point cloud to make sure
that the position of a camera was
properly modeled by Micmac and the
result is auto photo the digitalization
model and the correlation maps to make
sure that we can assess the quality of a
result if you want some of your examples
we distribute this through the web
server of QGIS so you can connect to
this website to have the open layer
version of these results for the
french-speaking audience a couple of
articles were written on Mi'kmaq because
again the excellent documentation is not
really introductory Micmac is a
fascinating documentation for
knowledgeable users but here what I was
trying to do is to take you by the hand
and help you step by step so this was
again written in French for French
audience if anyone in turn is interested
in open source software for
digitalization modeling which was done
for auto photo you can also do this for
oblique view modeling of objects I will
be very happy to translate this to
English if anyone wants a basic tutorial
and Micmac any of this I thank you for
your attention
if there's any question so the question
is vertical accuracy what I did is I
went on a flat area made multiple
measurements so multiple slides
separated by four or five minutes and
the standard deviation on the parking
lot was 11 centimeters so let's say this
meter resolution into Moraine here from
two measurements done from two days
apart I get about 60 centimeters so my
current interest is whether I could
measure snow cover Fitness 60 centimeter
is at the threshold of what can be
usable one of the main reason of this
poor resolution in northern Maryland and
what I do in the parking lot is the poor
alignment of the 2dm of the parking lots
even if you misaligned by a few tens of
centimeter it doesn't matter if a very
rough moraine if you misaligned by even
a few centimeters then you have very
strong effect and this is really the
conclusion that I could not introduce
here but using ground control point
reference points is mandatory if you
want to have submitter resolution if you
just rely on GPS this is l1 GPS you will
not have enough resolution you need some
point to introduce GCP to max properly
and then I would expect 10 20 centimeter
vertical resolution so the question is
whether I select my altitude actually my
altitude is a trade-off between the
pixel resolution here you see that v
picks a fact centimeter is actually much
below what I expect the second one is
regulation I'm not allowed to fly higher
than 120 meters and to make it safe I
wanted to stay at 100 meter to tell you
the truth I sometimes went up 220
[Music]
it will it will see this in value
stipends it will be able so the sift
algorithm has scaling invariance
property so even if you change the
altitude the software will still be able
to find relevant Taipans and to compute
what was the altitude yes so then the
angle doesn't change angle is given by
the length properties this is a given
the length properties are fundamental
but what you will change is the area
that is covered here and this area will
be dependent on the height but the
length must not change this is a very
strong requirement this fixed lens
camera are perfect but if you have an
automated camera you must not change the
zooming or the lens properties to get
this to work if anything changes when
your calibration is wrong and everything
so the question is whether we can 3d
print this it's going to be too long now
transfer but the short answer is yes I
printed this on a 3d printer and it
works but you have to be careful to get
rid of all the outlying points so it's I
did it manually in Beamer and you have
to clean it in blender so the question
is at the effect of lightening this DM
were acquired over half a day I needed
five flight 20 minutes long each I never
correlate this flight with this one but
one flight is 20 minutes over 20 minutes
I have a few enough lighting condition
change but I have seen the failure so it
should affect but I have not seen this
on the short flights I'm using
so so I have flown here with winds up to
25 meters 25 kilometres per hour sorry
because the UAV can fly up to 10 meters
per second so above 2 to 3 meters per
second I would not advise flying now I'm
lucky enough to go on the field trip for
3 weeks at a time and I will wait for
the right conditions of course if you go
somewhere and you expect to fly
immediately change the fighters of the
day I flew with 25 kilo meter per hour
wind was we were going to a unique site
and I had to fly I had to try it but I
wouldn't advise it so my question is
about thermal imaging the problem is
that you need high-resolution features
too for a collation match i believe that
i GN EG and the french giraffe institute
has this kind of investigation I have
not I'm sorry I tried so the question is
what / - what open-source - may I have
used I have tried at various sfm
software but I could find I cannot
remember all the features that I used
the solution is at the end of the day I
used the one that was so I have Python I
have some but I tried a few open-source
software and I was confident with that
with the French
sorry not French but geographic
institute was using this for production
I would be confident that it would be a
serious project not that the others are
not but I was confident in the
geographic institute and I got a very
good feedback from the group developing
this software in a TDM so there's no
rationale why I'm using this except that
I fell in love in it I fell in love is
the philosophy of a developer and if you
take a bit of time to go through the
initial difficulties of getting acquired
with it it's so powerful it's it meets
my requirement one tool for one step
checking each step so I could I have not
tried another the other software to come
on why this one of the others
[Applause]