note here and he will be talking about
one of the most exciting and hot areas
in big data these days which is deep
learning yeah
so I'm going to be a researcher at
Swedish Institute of computer science I
was supposed to do the presentation with
Jim during that he couldn't come here
today so what I would speak about is
deep learning on the platform we are
developing can help people to start with
deep learning because the thing is that
my team at the Swedish Institute of
computer science and we have created a
start-up and we are what we are doing is
developing a new adult distribution it's
the first European Arab distribution on
somatic aspect of it can be very useful
for starting with deep learning to start
with raise a question what are the
factors that all back artificial
intelligence today if we look at bender
we can think that it's alcohol on sex
but according to andre capaci I don't
exactly know you pronounce his name if
you don't know him he is working at open
ie he on his blog is a quite entry on
blog in deep learning so this situation
is taken from his blog and they say that
there is four factor that all back
artificial intelligence first one is a
compute its a compute power we have so
this is ad where this is our imagination
you are our power for our GPU CPU on
things like that the second one is the
data is that to do deep longing you do
you need big data you need big data that
are clean that right now it's not so
easy to find them the that are kind of
all over the place on internet don't
really know where to find them and you
when you find some data you don't know
if they are really clean something like
that then the third component it is
algorithm so it's what you will do if
you work on if you want to develop new
artificial intelligence system and the
last one is infrastructure is what do
you run your deep learning system on so
is the operating system but also where
you store your data on thing like that
on what Oh platform address the point
that all perform address is the data
problem on the infrastructure problem so
we'll start with the data problem so the
data challenge how do you find good on
it using data okay if you are in a big
company your Spotify or you have the
data that house they own you can use
them but if you are a researcher and you
want to experiment with data you don't
necessarily have them there and you look
for them and then it's right now it's
kind of going to e care but going
directly to the last part you have data
all over the place
they are all in box you have to find the
box that go together you have to bring
that out on by yourself and then you
build it and then you find out that oh
it's not what I wanted so so how can we
help with that yeah and then what our
problem now as I say you bring it back
home how do you do that right now is
that we don't see but it's not so
important it's a line of code that tell
you how to download some data from from
s3 on most of the time you have to run
it 100 time to have all the data on if
one of them crash in the middle you have
to do it manually to find out we are the
student a PhD student downloading
whether that
it took him one week the first time and
then we implemented the client to
download the data and it went a lot
faster but underneath each you have data
and you want to make them public how do
you do that there is no straightforward
solution now you can okay you can put
them on Amazon or on Google cloud but
then we pay for that so we pay for each
time someone download and then you have
to make some webpage to publish
something like that there isn't no very
nice platform where in few click you can
say okay now my data appealing and this
is what this is one of the thing we do
in no platform I wanted to make a demo
but the problem is that for I can't
connect my computer to the video
projector on the demo so I will describe
the demo on so some squid short because
the demo is dois is running we have
deployed to the automation in my lab and
I need my computer to access to them
because of firewall problem but so the
idea that we are to the optimizing with
a full stack with the hop stack so which
contain we wished all the data in HDFS
and then use Y on thing like that so
it's a full atop stack and we have data
in that on we want to share them and we
have a nice interface to see your data
in the in the HDFS I will show it a
little more when I speak over the
infrastructure but we have data in one
of the via virtual machine and what we
do is just we right-click on them on say
shell is that other is a shelter that
and then this data now public they have
a description which is a file Winley
file that is in
the in the folder on that describe what
are in the data and then we on the other
via termination we can search for the
name of this data or for something in
the description we use elastic search
for the research and we will find the
will get the result of all the the
public that I said that out there and we
will say okay download it screenshot are
very bad when we download it we say to
which project we want to add them and
then if it's HDFS we can directly dump
it to HDFS so if it's stuff that are the
good format for Kafka we can also put
them in Kafka and once we have done that
it stopped downloading and we can start
proceeding on them how does it work in
the bed the background is it's a
peer-to-peer torrent like protocol so if
a lot of people have these data set in
the cluster then it will go faster to
delay them and then we use the lab dot
for let bat for the transport protocol
the idea is that left at it is known as
creative so we know that if you have
that I said that our public it may not
be your priority to upload them to
people that want to download them your
priority is to serve the people that use
your cluster directly so let bat is good
for that because it will use only the
bandwidth that is not used by TCP and so
if people are not using your cluster it
will be able to upload at maximum speed
but as soon as you have TCP connections
that start to use your cluster it will
go down on useless bond with the other
interests of lab rat is that it works a
lot better than the anticip you eyelet
on CI bond with connection which are the
connection you have when you have
cluster on both sides of the Atlantic
sourcing like that
I had number that because the problem
with TCP is that the congestion windows
is patty reacted to a latency and so
when the latency increases the
throughput at which TCP can transmit
over on the network is going down let
that is is measuring the latency on
these looking at the change in latency
to know if it should decrease or
increase the throughput at which its on
so and this has also the advantage that
it's under better packet loss
because it will not take a packet loss
as okay now I need to decrease the size
of my window by half it will say okay
there is one packet that was lost but
globally the latency is the same so
maybe it was just these packets which
can happen on very lonely
lastly we don't load the piece in order
so you can start to process what you are
downloading while it's downloading so
now for the infrastructure part so if
you want to develop artificial
intelligence on you want to be to do the
artificial entities on nose alcoholism
and stuff like that you don't
necessarily want to deal with all the
infrastructure and all that you don't
want to be this guide for that we
propose to use a ton software on a Duke
so white onshore flow if you were there
to presentation ago it was two or three
you saw that there is a lot of existing
system to do deep learning which will
start off low because it's the big one
right now is the one everybody use it's
Google behind it so I guess it's helped
personally more developing the I do part
so I don't know so much about it tons of
flow sorry about that
and then we think that a dupe is a it's
good for because you want to have big
data at the beginning the data you need
to Train
you
your loop is not so good it's the reason
is that the way people do it is that
they have the data in I do they have
tons of ruin on another machine and they
take the data to weapons of fluids they
went on the floor
they run the algorithm and then they put
back the result in art this is not
efficient luckily they have been now it
has been developed system so that you
can run tons of flu use that as a tear
in a dupe and you know platform we have
integrated all of this together so that
people can directly run the are terms of
flow job in Japan on using data in
Hadoop without having to do all this
transfer it's not perfect yet there are
still a lot of work to do and this will
be part of a future work so I will just
do a quick demo for system the
resolution will be shipped so all we
like so the thing is that we we run this
platform so the thing is that we have
the data center in luleå in the north of
Sweden the same place where I do pub the
worst Facebook as a European data center
I just want to zoom out Mitch okay oops
[Music]
yeah but I use the Swedish okay so so
the idea that we have a front on for
Duke system and we have a project system
where everything in a dupe is a project
on inside project you have users that
have different role and we unsure is
relation between the project so if you
have data in a dupe on the part of a
project you know that people that are
not part of this project contacts as to
it and then we can go to space nets it's
so on this data center we get access to
of student of the deep learning course
and they did their homework and on it on
one of the group did the space net
challenge so it's the idea on again when
they run it on the cluster they just
went to Zeppelin on in the plane
creating not book on the idea of space
net is that it's a satellite picture of
so it's not a notebook this is all terms
of Records understand picture so it's
some satellite picture of the
we're on the goal is to recognize if
there is building in the picture you can
see that when there is building it's
easily the part where we're building up
I want to first so so you can see with
this platform it's easy to download new
data set on to start working on the with
Zeppelin
no stinking thing
[Laughter]
[Music]
so future work I only wrote the future
work concerning terms of flow because
it's the only spot I spoke about for
platform so something we are working on
right now is a distributed sense of flow
so this exists but this is the we don't
think that the implementation is so good
right now and it's not it doesn't work
on yawn and as we want to run it on top
of a dupe we want to run it on top of
young so we have some people working on
that making that you can you will be
able in the future to say okay I want to
cluster with these machines and I want
to end distance or flow program on it
and then yon should take you out of that
then that means also adding some thing
too young because we want to be able to
and within feed even on GPUs which young
doesn't underwrite now right now Yun and
Leon the CPU on memory so we will we we
are also working on adding this
information into yarn so I was saying we
have a cluster up in Lille oh it's
already used so it's code that that are
that is in prediction that student on
research are using if you want to test
your code or platform you can either go
to hops dot IO and then you go you have
vagrant you can deploy the full tak with
a quantum start to play with it
we can also give you access to cluster
in Lunia
but you won't have access to the GPU
cards
because we don't have enough so we keep
them for still then I just want to thank
all these people so we have a lot of
enemy because we are research people so
it's a lot of students that I've been
working with us and that I've done the
very hard work but as you see we are
quite a small team working on this
project and we we created a startup to
develop it it's called logical clocks
and then we are looking for people that
want to either use on or system on give
us feedback or develop it it's all open
so you can go on github or ops to
Taiyuan have more information about this
[Applause]
well thank you so much again