time
lemme game okay yes I just say yeah yeah
oh yeah welcome everybody my talk as
patrick said already is about deploying
surfaces with salt i will start off with
covering a few basics we'll see if we
actually need that then i will try to
run you through a deployment process
which i've done on a virtual machine
cluster and in the end i'll go into some
more detail about some features of of
the project how you can customize it and
so on
but yeah we'll see how much time we have
alright so to start us off who doesn't
know salt here okay few people and who
doesn't know safe yet just one - okay we
go through it then so salt is a
configuration management software and
remote execution engine it's similar to
other projects like ansible puppet chef
it does a few things different than
others but whatever it's based on python
pythons templating engine and 0 mq and
the underlying principle is a master
applying state to minions so it's push
based and these states you can define
and a bunch of files that sit in a
directory hierarchy and you can in these
files you can define a directed acyclic
graph across several minions this is one
of the things that it's fairly unique I
think puppet does there too but that's
one of the features of salt yeah the
mission statement of salt you can read
for yourself or you can just look it up
on the github page
Seth we heard quite a bit about Seth
today already it's a scalable fault
tolerant and self-healing storage system
that provides you with block storage
object storage and file storage
and it's mainly designed to run on
commodity hardware yeah this should
suffice for now okay so we want to
deploy SEF using salt and the project
for that is called deep sea it's
basically a collection of salt file salt
state files mainly and they should aid
in the creation of safe clusters and in
the management that's - it has several
or in a by its inception and had several
goals in mind so it doesn't a won't deal
with any bare metal deployment so you
should you should do that before it
won't install an OS or anything and it
won't bootstrap itself so you need a
running salt cluster that's basically
installing salt starting the processes
and accepting a few keys you can look
that up on the salt website that is
fairly easy to do anyway deep sea starts
after you have a running salt cluster
another aim was to automate Hardware
detection so when you want to deploy a
sizable safe cluster you have to deal
with quite a lot of hardware on
different machines and we try to avoid
you having to deal with that so we want
to automate a lot of that steep sea
tries to spot problems before they get
deployed so we have a bunch of
validation steps that we want to run and
warn you that you shouldn't do this and
yeah it's not just deployment it's also
managing the whole lifecycle
ideally there is some work to do still
but yeah we get there it's obviously
open-source license under the GPL and
the current status is we are at version
0.7 one or two I'm not quite sure at the
moment it's usable so the whole
deployment workflow works and basic
management capabilities are there too so
you can decommission notes and add new
notes and that kind of stuff
and yeah you can read more about it you
can report bugs
can contribute on github feel free
anytime there is a wiki too and
obviously the bug tracker and all that
so just go there for now it might at
some point as I just talked to Patrick
it might at some point migrate to the
Ceph come what's it called the safe
project but we'll obviously inform you
of that okay
so basic workflow for deep-sea as I said
you install your OS on all your minion
on all your notes that you want to use
you install salt you get your salt
cluster up and you install the deep-sea
package on your master and then you
start using deep-sea obviously it's
organized in a bunch of stages to get a
running safe cluster you need to run at
least three stages this is one through
three here one two or three stage zero
is kind of optional you don't really
have to do it it would take care of all
your minions being in the same state so
you know run some updates install a
certain kernel version or whatever we do
have some files for that they probably
won't work for everyone so that's why
it's optional discovery will check out
all your hardware then there's a manual
step you have to create one
configuration file that pulls in all
those proposed configuration fragments
and what that means well we'll get to
that in a second yeah this is the one
manual step you have to do after that
you deep-sea will create your
configuration out of that push it out to
all the minions and then stage three
will actually deploy itself in stage 3
you will deploy monitors and OSD so you
will get a fully functional set cluster
and stage 4 will then deploy some extra
services mostly you know CFS rgw ice
cowsy and all that sort of thing
there's also stage 5 which will then
with removal but that's the small
related to lifecycle management of a
safe cluster and in this in the next
part we're will go into into a
deployment process we'll only look at
stages 1 2 & 3 because you know time
constraints mostly especially stage 4
can get quite complex if you you know
look at ice gauzy deployment or rgw you
know you can have multiple gateways that
interact which is with each other and
the whole configuration just can become
quite complex so it's not not enough
time here to cover all that some more
notes about deep sea itself the stages
are orchestration files for you that no
salt that means there are executed with
the orchestration runner and these
orchestration files will take care of
all the minion targeting that that needs
to be done it's based on roles so we put
roles on nodes and salt will act on
those notes depending on their roles but
you can also execute these States
manually but then you have to target
them yourself a common pattern that you
will see within deep sea is this
redirection pattern so salts when you
when you want to apply state to a minion
you can point salt at a directory and by
default it will look into this directory
and execute the init SLS
this is just a convention of salt we
have all our inner tests in a dot SLS
have this include in it they include a
file in the local directory according to
some configuration data that is stored
in the pillow for those of you don't
know what a pillar is that's just a
place where you can store static
configuration data that is available to
all minions it's kind of think of it as
a key value store
so this includes here the specific one
will look into look in the pillar if
there's anything to find form on in it
if there is it will use that as a value
or if not it will just use default which
in this case will then open a default
SLS in the same directory and execute
what's in there and why we do this I
will get to that I will get back to that
at a later stage also deep CEU requires
a minyan on your master node because we
do want to apply some state to your
master
we heard some people saying that this is
kind of a deal breaker we haven't really
understood yet why but yeah this I just
wanted to mention it all right yeah so
let's try it I'm not trying to do a live
demo I you know I'm holding it like lens
did earlier I don't trust the demo gods
I have a bunch of screenshots of the
deployment process I hope you it's not
too confusing with all the different
files that are involved that's not too
important what what I mostly want you to
take away is that that you can customize
third and certain things certain things
are taken out not out of your hands but
are done for you that's the important
part and yeah I hope that works so don't
don't get disheartened when you get lost
and you know what file is open now or
whatever okay so I have this demo
cluster 10 virtual machines fairly small
machines they have two network
interfaces each because that's what Saif
likes stuff likes a clustering cluster
network and the public network there are
six hours denotes all in all four of
them have no actually all of them have
five five gigabyte drives you know if
such a thing would even exist and two
hours these have an extra one gigabyte
Drive so we have 32 drives overall means
we can at most deploy 32 OSDs
they're fairly conveniently named
as you can see so we have mon 1 2 3 and
data 1 through 6
that's I just chose that way because
it'll be easier for the presentation
those names will be used and the policy
dot CFG but I'll explain a few things
if your naming scheme isn't quite that
convenient yeah as you can see there's
nine notes that I'm gonna use for this
cluster the admin node is basically just
my salt master all right
so stage 0 I've talked about this before
it's optional it's at the moment very
Sousa specific we're working on getting
rid of that but there are some issues
and salt that needs solving first it
doesn't do any black magic or anything
so you know it sings your salt states it
installs a package or to run some
updates you can do that with salt itself
fitting for your distribution and then
you can just step skip stage 0 so that's
highly optional at the moment stage 0
and deep sea might reboot your minions
and that includes the minion your
masters runs on so be advised if you do
use stage 0 and you manage other nodes
you know maybe with reactors maybe step
away from running stage 0 it might
surprise you
ok so stage 1 is the first interesting
one for us it does discovery so it goes
out to all your minions and queries them
for their hardware which for safe of
course is network hardware and storage
hardware
it will then write a whole bunch of
configuration fragments in the pillar
subdirectory which you can oh that's a
typo there it should be SRV pillar set
proposals those configuration fragments
will look we look at some in a second or
really just tiny tiny ammo files which
will then make up your configuration
what's important to note here is it will
produce a roughly at least
fragment and minion it will produce one
file so it will produce all the
necessary fragments for all your minions
to be a monitor you don't you don't want
that probably I don't want mine monitor
notes here obviously but it will give
you the option to that it will also
produce all these configuration
fragments for all the salt minions that
might not you know become SEF notes in
the end there's you can see that this
will there are a lot of files that are
created but luckily you never have to
really look at them so yeah just wanted
to mention that this proposals directory
will look like that after you run stage
zero so it's a bunch of sub directories
a whole bunch of role define Minh so as
you can see you know role Mon will be
one important one obviously that we're
gonna use above the roles there are the
profiles those will be the storage nodes
so for every hard drive deep sea
encounters it will try to propose a
storage layout for that particular node
and create a directory that's kind of
named after what hardware it found as
you can see here this resembles roughly
my OSD notes and above that there's just
some general configuration data so yeah
what's actually in those files oh by the
way I hope everybody can see that I was
kind of looks all right hey okay yeah so
the top one is the configuration
fragments for one node that is going to
become a monitor and as you can see it's
they're really tiny fragments so there's
a roll key and this particular fragment
will add on to that to that list and
since the monitors of Ceph have to be on
the public network they'll get an IP
address too
and that's it already
the storage profiles they they're a bit
bigger so we again have this this role
array and in this case you add storage
obviously but you also now have the
actual storage profile so in this case
this is one of the minions that had five
drives in it and this particular
proposal that deep sea came up with will
deploy five OSD stand-alone OS DS all on
their own disk there's usually two ways
you can deploy an OSD and SEF that's
standalone on its own disk but you can
also put the journal on an external disk
so you the OSD will use two separate
disks you usually want to do this when
you have an SSD and spinners for example
then you would put the journal on the
SSD and the actual data on the spinners
to speed up the write and reprocess
that's the other line up there data plus
journals that would be the other way of
deploying an OSD and will again get back
to that later okay so you have all your
proposals now now it's time to come up
with the policy that CFG so as I said
this is the central configuration file
basically what you do is you include a
whole bunch of these configuration
fragments and deep sea will then in
another stage collect or you know
compile all those configuration
fragments and create a config out of it
we only have nine notes here now so it's
not too unwieldy but you know imagine
you have a hundred notes and your
storage notes have like when you four
drives in it also you get a lot of
fragments so you obviously don't want to
list every every single file so and then
the policy dot CFG you can use the globs
that salt uses to UM
I'll show you in a second what I mean
but you can also do more complex stuff
with list slicing and reg X's and yeah
the order in which you list things is
important because later options will
overwrite another incarnation of
themselves but that's not too important
for us now either
so the policy that CFG that I used for
this cluster here looks like that yes
maybe not maybe not too obvious what
what happens here so let's let's step
through it this is a configuration
fragment here that we'll just assign
minions to a cluster eventually deepsea
should be able to you manage multiple
clusters multiple sub clusters for now
this is only used if you want to deploy
surplus err but also have other notes
that you manage in Sault then those
nodes you would actually include a
cluster - unassigned file and then they
wouldn't be managed by deepsea anymore
but since we don't have that we just you
know include the cluster assignments
next step is the hardware profiles so
here I just include all all suggested
profiles because I have a limited amount
of disks only there's nothing I don't
want to use and Tipsy only came up with
one suggestion that's you know you can
see profile - some disk - some other
disk and then there's a - one at the end
of every of every directory usually
deepsea would come up with at least
another with another proposal which
would then be named - - but that only
happens if it finds an SSD so if it you
know is able to create this external
journal OSD which doesn't happen on
virtual disks obviously then you include
some common configuration this mostly
deals with configuration values that you
want to deploy and then you assign some
more roles mainly here the master which
is my salt master all them all the notes
that are called Mon something should
become admin notes so they get an admin
keyring and all the notes that are
called Mon something will become
monitors obviously you can see how my
how my naming scheme here is very
convenient
you might as I said you you know
might have some notes already they might
not be as conveniently named so there
are some other options to use these
gloves you can use other salt gloves so
you can you know list certain allowed
values but much more interesting is you
can use you can give another argument to
it so this admin star will create a list
of all the notes that are called admin
something and then you can pass along
either a slice which will take a chunk
out of this list or a red X which will
match every item of this list against
this reg so you can you even use both if
you wanted to so this should take care
of even the most you know unlucky naming
schemes for hosts for a safe deployment
and avoid you know you having to list
all the files that are there ok so we
have our policy dot CFG we run stage 2
now this will take all those fragments
and produce a configuration for deep sea
to use this is based on stack top pie
deep sea comes with stack top pie but if
you use a fairly new salt version
this will include stack top pie too so
there's nothing to do really it will
write out this configuration to a
directory tree under SRV pillar SEF
stack default this is the configuration
you basically came up with in your
policy dot CFG it will create the same
sub directory tree in its parent
directory and create all the files that
are in the default tree to these files
and the parent directory are for you to
use so you can override certain options
that gypsy came up with and that you
don't like that's yeah just a
customization thing it's you know you
just have to look at it it's fairly
obvious and you can check your config
with by just looking into the pillar so
you target a minion and
do piller dot items and it will list all
those configuration key value pairs that
you have and you can just check up that
that everything's as you want it and
then you mostly none you run stage three
which will take care of the whole
deployment and you have a running safe
cluster one thing to mention about stage
three is that it will validate the
configuration you want to use so it will
run quite a few steps of you know
looking that you have three months for
example that you have enough storage
nodes that you know maybe you have a
firewall running on some of the nodes it
will notify you at least of that
so when stage stage 3 is through and
some things don't work you know might be
a firewall issue or so yeah and then go
out install safe create the cluster and
create a pool this is what it looks like
you don't have to try to decipher that
what what you should take away is that
it's nice and green so we're all good
and then we have a running safe cluster
this is yeah the health warned here
don't worry about that that's just the
pool that I that it automatically
creates is too small
well I want you to pay attention to is
that we have 32 OSD so on each virtual
drive that machines have there is one
OSD yeah and that's it basically so you
finished now no let's look at how you
can customize this whole process hours
are there any questions so far maybe I
don't know is anybody very disheartened
or very confused probably probably too
confused to have questions okay let's
confuse you a little more I've spoken
about the hardware profiles so as I said
deep sea will usually come up with
another profile for external journals
but only if you have an SSD which is
obviously not the case and my virtual
machine cluster here so I just wrote one
what's F what deep sea will
propose will look very similar to that
so it's just a key value mapping of data
drive pointing towards a journal drive
that you want to use on a real cluster
this would look more like that this you
know we want to use the actual idea of
the drive because the the DEF /st
something might change you get an idea
why it's good that deepsea automatically
creates all those files because I mean
this is even a small one right this is
like what seven or eight drives imagine
that with 24 drives that gets a little
error-prone let's say so yeah so but I
want to use this profile no I want to
use I want to create SSDs that have
their journal partition on an X on
another Drive than their data partition
so we are back at imagine we're back at
stage after stage one obviously so we
haven't created our policy dot CFG yeah
another thing we have to look at now is
how to customize the behavior of deep
sea because mostly for this particular
case safe disk which will which will we
will we be using to deploy the OSD will
just refuse to deploy an OSD on a one
gigabyte Drive reasonably so but we want
to force it to do that so I wrote a
custom SLS file which I called fosston
SLS and put it in the OSD subdirectory
of the psaltery I won't bore you with
what's actually in it it'll just
partition the drives the size you want
to and then force F disk to actually use
those partitions okay so how do we get
deep sea to use it now I spoke before
already about this redirection pattern
so it's up here again oh yeah and you
might notice on this slide here the the
there is an inert SLS and a defaulted
SLS those are the files that deep sea
come with comes with yeah and I just
added something there so now we have to
put a key value pair and the pillar
which defines OSD in it to frost them so
deep sea will use my FASTA SLS and this
you can do in the in the stack directory
where the configuration lifts after
stage 2 I've spoken before about those
two mirroring subdirectory trees and I
look here into the global llamó we will
see so this file was initially empty and
it gives you a little comment to you
know notify you that it will overwrite
values in the default slash global llamo
and basically I just put those two key
value pairs and mostly the OSD in it
obviously is here interesting for the
partitioning I've done the same thing
because I also created a default
partitioning a custom partitioning
scheme yeah and then this is in the
pillar so when you then run stage three
that will use your customizations go out
and deploy a safe cluster and we have
now one with 3000 s DS because to the to
one gigabyte disks went into other OS DS
yeah this is just a general workflow
some more things that we can look at is
beyond deployment so I talked about
Stage four already this deals with all
additional services that that AF offers
sacrifice and so MTS's and SEF a fast
deployment obviously I scars the Raiders
gateway we I think we already merged and
as NFS Ganesha or maybe not
but we're working on it so it's it's
gonna be there too and there's some
facilities for managing certain clients
- yeah this is a whole nother
presentation in itself obviously so yeah
but it works the same way it works it's
governed by a policy dot CFG and by this
orchestration file that which you could
customize if you wanted to
Stage five we'll deal with removal of
components so say you want to
decommission one of your OS denotes the
workflow here would be to change your
policy that CFG to not include this
particular minion anymore and run stage
two to push out the configuration and
then run Stage five this will remove the
OSD you can always run stage three and
four - because everything you do in salt
is it impotent so it won't change
anything if there's nothing to change
the idea is that when you decommission
an OSD you you might want to you know
deploy a new OSD with new hardware so if
you do that in one step you obviously
want to run stage three and four before
you take so you want to deploy a new
node before you take out an old one and
yeah this is it we work on some other
Yeah right
okay so question was what about a single
OSD on an OSD note and this is right now
not possible we are working on that
though I mean if the hard drive is
broken you can obviously you know the
osts out already you can just pull it
and put in a new one
restart the service but yeah we're
working on decommissioning single OS
these two yes and that concludes my talk
so any more questions sorry
sorry what
salt SSH I haven't tried that but I
don't see why it wouldn't work
because I mean the the transports are
the question was if this can be used
through salt SSH and I don't think
there's anything you have to undo to to
do that right I mean it's a salt
configuration method so I I would you
know cautiously say it should work and
another question
Oh No so the question was if the the OSD
deployment or proposal process will
include the OS drive and no of course it
won't it will in fact ignore an e
formatted drive that you have in your
OSD notes any more questions
right well I mean no so for two reasons
so changing a Raiders pool you can you
can only increase the PG count and your
salt master has also the admin key so
there is you know in the Raiders command
is already kind of a cluster management
thing so we for win that okay looks like
no more questions then thank you
[Applause]