I'm from
so this is the last session basically
and so we have been doing this since the
since the first since the first open
source designed everyone and it's
basically just a as you could see on the
schedule just a session to pitch your
own project and to ask for design help
so if you have an open source project
where you need any design help
whatsoever like a logo or some
interaction design or just a design
review or something like that yeah this
is your your chance now to put your
project we've it's just yeah voluntarily
anyone who comes up I know some people
who already show their project right you
for example and and so you just have
three minutes and just quickly explain
what yeah it's hardcore so we don't have
a lot of time so just quickly be concise
describe what you project as you can
come up here and just open your website
or your github or any repository or
whatever just quickly explain what your
project does how you need design hub and
how to contact you and your three
minutes that we call and also if you
come up here and present your project we
also ask you to if you didn't do that
already afterwards I go to our jobs page
and submit that what you presented as a
job posting so it's also there for
anyone who doesn't attend right now okay
so who wants to go first
okay okay so who who else also once ago
some hands okay cool okay
nice okay you wanna go first all right
hold this okay with the time does
someone have you over the timer okay
great I'll hold it for you okay so this
is about Carla Carla is like a metal
inter so you may know winters there's
like usually one to doing one specific
kind of
on one language so you usually need more
of those and you don't want to use multi
lots of those tools
koalas like a metal enter and it
basically uses those tools for you is
one unified user interface 466
programming languages and usually more
than one analysis available for every
language we need design help in terms of
usability and what we basically want to
do is a usability test so all that you
get from me right now is koala that I oh
that's our website and I want you to set
that up for a project to do something
reasonable with it and figure out if it
works for you or not especially if it
doesn't work for you you can fill in the
results at qualify there was slash
usability or you could just file as an
issue so it's very simple go to column
value and later to koala video slash
usability thank you thank you remember
to put that in the jobs Fort Eustis
usability there will be like a
questionnaire ok cool I mean it's not
cool that it's a Google Form so whoever
wants to come just come up like I don't
pay attention who raise their hands just
just come on maybe don't open this ten
euros I don't know where I'm just
[Music]
all right so you got a rough idea of
koala no and so you haven't seen
anything
thank you so you got a rough idea with
koala there's something you want to do
like we want to integrate it into github
so it's actually usable it's very so it
can have a seamless integration to get
up and you know I can see the comments
which are the butter Lynch has produced
by koala am i right and github so the
idea said it would look like something
like that so that's the product what I
do when I got you can't see it at all
yes so that's the eventual outcome so
not much design work to be done there
because it's get up basically but what
we are thinking about the cell to do a
nice configuration and so that's our
approach for the configuration so far
yeah we're not designers it's basically
not pretty nice we just try just try it
something but we really need some
feedback on that um how to make that how
to make a good experience for users on
that point so there will be a
questionnaire yet and if you have any
people on there if you would like to
contribute to this summer would be very
happy to see it call that I admit or
visit us that get made up I oh thank you
very much
[Applause]
yep I'm Michael from frontier car 20 car
is a decentralized social network we are
here we exist for several years you
might know the s4 are we are you can
talk to them as well we are open source
based on PHP and coal and we really
desperately need help for designers for
example this homepage here is kind of
ugly it's totally old and we try to
do a new homepage that we really rewrote
everything and it looks even uglier
because it's just yeah like and so we
really need people who are willingly to
help us just these yeah just for from
you users for people who are interested
in it so that they don't sees this mess
and say hey what the yeah so that
they can do the first set can see oh
yeah that's looking nice and yeah and
this is one of the things other things
would be maybe if there are people who
are good and user experience stuff and
so could have a look as well at our
system could try like any one of the
other talks were people well this one
could ask people for testing why people
are creating an account but never come
back and this whole stuff would be and
totally appreciate it so these are all
some weird ugly things I don't know
where the email addresses point to so
best would be on github the keyboard is
really
so this is the address such 20/20 car
and we could be reached over of course
contacting here with issues and so on
and of course I will try to at a job
entry as well yet disregard my history
or whatever I hope you didn't see
anything incriminating
[Laughter]
hello project difference we built our
about free software is nice because we
can modify the sources share resources
edit the sources and pass them on but
with nobody uses sources we use binaries
and we need to believe that the binary
comes from a given source and the way to
overcome this belief is enable everybody
to rewrite this exact same binary so
this is reponsible builds as a technical
project and we are looking for
Louisville and
[Music]
so I'm harder from Debian but involved
is actually not space for Bitcoin who
Abu Dhabi and f-droid free VST if you
don't need to net PSD Nick Salvati
details so we are looking at yoga for
this purpose of its project for
everybody and we have a page describing
the logo
matching the Debian wiki just search for
reproducible Louisville which is not the
right page oh yeah so there is there are
16 ideas for a possible slow boss
some are usable as low but some are not
I like this this is also nice
or this of the rabbit producing I don't
know you can make me my name is saga
from Debian thank you thank you
and just one question how long are you
looking for because you have all these
ideas no I mean how long it wouldn't be
so bad but all the keys have the symbols
rubbed off so you can't see what you're
typing what is this that I need to show
off whatever that's not helpful at all
okay so this is me Daniel Quinn and
anyone here played with a game called
Gowalla do you remember it was a while
ago
no it was a great game I fell in love
with it and then they sold out to
Facebook and Facebook was like screw you
guys and they just closed all company
stole the staff and imported them so
when it died my friend and I got very
upset and we wanted to bring the game
back and we were gonna make it better
and my friend she had this brilliant
idea she was gonna come up with this
really cool game that basically years
later some other company came along he
came up with something you may have
heard of it pokemon gold between the
time that she had the idea and the time
that they came out with it I started
writing it and I swear to God like four
years ago I had a fully functional
it was the coolest game ever if you
really liked talking to JSON API but it
was this cool game where you could walk
down to the water and it would know that
you're near water and it would check the
position of the stars and change the
monsters near you based on that there
was leveling there was upgrades all
kinds of stuff it's still there it's all
on github you can play with it feel like
but it's just an API it's really ugly I
need it to be sexy I need pictures I
need illustrations and I get anything
that's prettier than an API so you're
raising your handle good no not at all
because you know copyright yeah well
that's the other thing but the thing is
Pokemon is kind of a problem because the
the creatures themselves are limited and
the way the game is designed for us is
they're designed to just be we can add
new breeds of creatures based on other
aspects that we can get so for example
right now with your Lawton longitude I
can get the position of the stars in the
cosmos I can get the current weather
where you are I can get the historical
web you also figure out whether or not
it's colder than it used to be and
generate a different cold monster or not
and the region you are nationally so the
monsters all have regions because
there's also like one in a hundred
chance that you may pick up a tourist so
you're in the UK and you're collecting
monsters and they all have little UK
flags on them but every once in a while
ones from Japan and now you get this
idea you want to go all around the world
and collect monsters from all around the
world so look all of this stuff is it
was fun for people like me who like to
collect things so I want to just make
the game so I can play the game but if
any of you guys would also like to play
the game we're perhaps making into some
money if we can actually make it into a
functional object it'll be awesome but
yeah come and get a hold of me my
contact info is hidden by that totally
useless thing at the bottom so just look
at me I'm Daniel Quinn org go to my
website there and you can contact me
through that thanks
[Applause]
let me know if you need help hi
Christine prison means shiver in English
Philistine and German anyway I'm a
researcher in human-computer interaction
at in really ill and I'm developing a
tool to help us researchers and HCI
researchers to observe how people use
their own apps so I'm going to introduce
it by to use cases some time ago I was
working on a project consisting in
observing now some designers fine sounds
explore sounds if it was like ingredient
lists but if the tools that are
available to record this are like a
QuickTime Player or other tools but you
cannot get the click and like input from
the keyboard
you cannot extract it as a separate file
for analysis so it's not convenient to
annotate everything by hand and so we
wanted to develop another solution like
it's going to be really small but it's a
browser that combines similarity of
sound based on tags and based on the
sound itself so to evaluate it like for
usability we wanted to do quantitative
analysis and then we had to compare this
application with another one that they
used and maybe some of you might have
recognized
I guess that is too small this is pro
tools from Digidesign avid there are no
user
available so we had to reverse engineer
engineer some so at last this is the app
I'm working on
it's called inspector widget like there
is a reference to a famous animated
series again back in the days so the
idea is this is the recording of the
desktop of anybody's computer and by
using a scratch like language we can
program annotation annotations and then
browse the video in synchrony
synchronize to these annotations for
instance this is the file browser of
ProTools how can we see when people are
like browsing for sounds making some
cries to find sounds playing back so if
we don't have access to the like the Dom
for web applications or well the
structure of widgets how can we do that
so we select regions and we extract them
from the video so we need people that we
would have the design of the application
but more so users that are designers
themselves that might use this tool for
contextual inquiries or usability
testing I would want them to try it for
now I mean almost the only developer of
it so it's only available for Mac sorry
as well and the time is up Thanks and if
you want to reach me while the project
is on github and if you this website my
contact is going to be visible somehow
[Applause]
hi everybody my name is Rio and I'm from
the dayz program basically we try to
build the Internet's of energy and make
energy as a common basically we are team
F for something like today 10 10 people
it's a weapon design program for people
who consider energy as a rather common
and what we're trying to do basically is
to work on levels you can monitor the
conception and the production of energy
and make it sensible or has a
representation for it for their users
and for the people who are directly in
touch with energy let's say this is a
first level the second level is the
software level so we worked with kind of
block chain technology called FM
basically and what we what we're trying
to do is basically how you let's say
designing an infrastructure for people
to share to directly share or sell
energy to each other instead of let's
say selling the energy to the grid or to
another producer so this is basically
the project which were working on we are
looking for help from designers first of
all for the design of the contributions
because we'd like well this project is
open source so we like people to get
involved in both the design of the
interaction between the people and the
energy actually this is the first thing
the second the second thing is that we
made design help to basically design the
governance of the energy what we are
trying to do is basically to build a
micro scale or micro grid energy
I'll educate and one of the thing that
is quite complicated is how you deal
with the local marketplace actually and
this local marketplace has to be let's
say design as to you have governance
that is rightly designed for interaction
between the peers that is you say the
producers the mill operators the
citizens etc etc thank you so we are
working on the new project which is a
project for implementing a payment
system that allows anonymous payments
but receiving the money is not anonymous
so we have this website talonnet you can
find the developers page and yeah let's
hear it so just very briefly the system
looks like the way you would use it you
have a bank account with for instance
euros you Vidro coins into your wallet
which runs in your browser or mobile
phone that these are anonymous coins
that each represent euro but it can be
tied to dollars or whatever else as well
so this system is not a currency but
just a payment system so it is intended
to replace credit cards and paper and
similar systems so what happens in the
system is that you you have to your bank
and exchange exchange is the your
currency to Animus coins and you pay
with your anonymous coins to merchants
and the merchants can
go back to the exchange and get back the
euros or whatever currency you have and
so what we started doing we we have
started implementing the whole system
and we have a browser extension using
the web extensions API and what we need
healthy is designing the layout and the
design of the extensions pages we have
these browser pop-ups in the corner
usually so we have value need we need to
display the the current balance and
confirmation pages for payments things
that is so all the layout so it's HTML
CSS basically design work that we need
help with and so if you go to Tara
dotnet on the developers page you can
find the contact information we have a
mailing list so yeah discussion so we
have this mailing list you can send a
message there and if you would like to
have with the design of the graphics
engines
that's what it mainly and thanks okay so
that was it
so everyone as for design hope now
please go to open source design dotnet
slash jobs and there is a link to post a
job and it's basically just adding like
a markdown file to a repository so you
just put in the info there and I think
we even have the we have this form up
already okay so it's even a form not a
yeah exactly and right and basically and
I kind of also a job or or if you want
to contribute like we're an open open
collective so we're on github.com slash
open source design if you want to get
involved yeah it's all open to
contribution
question do you think it's a good idea
also next year to have this kind of yeah
thanks a lot so hopefully see you next
year and yeah if you want to give a talk
just hand it in and check us out on
Twitter also