you
we also if you can't hear me to speak up
so it's tailored composite truss was
acute variant composite of framework
it's a very long title and I will
explain it to you in a minute what I
want to tell you shortly about me you
can see Shannon's
I was the Katie projections about seven
years I did a PhD and fancy receptor and
today I'm doing completely different
things at class systems the company of
that doing these big aquaculture
machines so it's really nice to be much
nicer competitors it's about really
really nice technologies that you can
use from very devices for displaying
stuff from several processes so for
several applications with this talk I my
goal is to give a short practical
introduction to this framework tell you
how to use it how you can experiment
with it and make you eager to to really
use it since it's extremely cool I'm not
from the acute Weiland capacitor
developers I'm I know them I work a lot
with them but I'm not completely from
from them I'm looking back from the
really huge point of view on these
frameworks about a really nice practical
example where I won't get any problems
both funny confidential stuff with my
kitchen and a few I would have better to
buy somewhere here that helps me in the
kitchen I want to have some applications
that had be for example for cooking eggs
and for cooking a tea and maybe is
current time and some other applications
I want to have a really nice seamlessly
these applications so no border so it
should be pretty nicely aligned I want
to have some touch guests just likes my
pick to the left to the right and I'm
using some nice more happier like recipe
a pie or some other embedded hardware
that has a GPU so a little bit of 3d
acceleration that means I can use cute
creeks it's just later and the start
actually nobody else you can use it with
out 3d acceleration I'm not sure about
this framework but always a plus and as
I said before it's important point about
or having several applications there is
I have several processes that I somehow
have to compose on the screen so I need
a compositor so usually around in
capacitor and yes everything what I
explained there is much trip much
material to a cheap there's a similar
simple process runs run process
application but well if you're looking
at the modern use case on the automotive
industry or X for example in the
agriculture business where we have
really really hot requirements with
really heavy applications running on
this machine at the same time that you
have to compose so much harder uske is
actually in the air then in the
automotive industry
well you want to have several processes
there so I'm out to a small picture
about what I explained to you that's the
size of a pilot display I want to have
the applications aligned horizontally
I want to have this swipe guests are
left to draw it
I don't have a navigation information so
where I'm currently on my screens and I
want to have some notifications that
should we send it from the applications
and shown on the compositor which is
actually not that favorite as it sounds
of the first hearing okay and the rest
of the stroke is how can I create such a
device Rissa a cube and compositor
framework and actually I want to show a
compositor that fits on one slide for
achieving this so a little bit more
violent assume that all of your heart
name at least once
it's a protocol that explains how you
communicate between a client and to
display server so between an application
with window or several windows and the
application server the display server
which is surveillant compositor which is
responsible for putting the windows
somewhere on your screen and also for
import handling and so on so it's really
easy about this communication in the
embedded watch since several years
Bitsey default standard nobody is using
X anymore at least I don't know it about
anyone since it's simply protocol you so
you can you can implement your own
compositor you can find Sebastian
it's the reference compositor you can
find in the desktop environments a lot
of different composites or for example
yet on one screen and KDE genome has its
own indictment has its own I actually
also encountered a proprietary
compositor somewhere in the field and
well then gives you a basic protocol
sometimes you need a little bit more you
need want to have your own custom
protocol extension for example in KDE
bah the extension for snapshots that you
can ask for a snapshot of all the
windows together that how their current
is displayed on the screen that's a
simple protocol extension how client
communicates with the server it says I
want to have the picture can you start
at some real those protocol extensions
are create defined in a well-defined
standard then you have some tooling that
creates a boilerplate code and connects
it to your programs at the end you can
simply use it there are different
available shells which is well kind of
rich which language do you speak to your
composite or the default one is WL shell
that was introduced in when run on 0 and
we offer the xdg shell which is the
extra successor and we have in the
automotive field especially this IV
shell extension which gives you would a
small tiny interface how you can
communicate
your compositor Andrews ago that it's we
since interchange it's you can take any
compositor that speaks IV gel and you
exchange it wherever that is really
limited in what you can do there and in
my use cases will never brush until now
so I looked at this framework that was
cute veil and composite of framework
with this framework
I don't know how many of you are used to
shoot quick before see few hands
it's it's a declarative language that
well it's it exactly ideal a declarative
language looks like a little bit like
Jason and say what you want to have like
I want to have rectangles then you have
a rectangle and yeah you can do the same
or you can now do the same with secured
been in compositor framework you can say
I want to have a composite or I want to
have an output I want to put my window
somewhere in the output and everything
works nicely together so it's really the
power of declarative language for
creating such things and this acute
backup of the frameworks since or I
think two weeks it's the girls that
really so acute 5h beliefs nor we have
this for these protocol extensions
already taught shortly about last night
you can you know also get a little bit
more tooling that you get cute style C++
API and not only the C style API is
resist those frameworks it's
automatically generated here you can of
course what you want to have for several
screens if you are for the rise and
several money to us that's nice to have
it has it implements all these different
shells I talked about and the car is
actually stable and well it's the
essence of several years it's I think at
least five since acute 5.0 only the API
is new so it's really stable piece of
software up user of frameworks that you
have here and what I did here is really
this really nice cute quick style API to
use it in a really nice way
I shortly talked about the IV IV shell
extension my problem recently or until
now was or is that it's only fits from
my point of view for with aesthetic
settings like I have a screen and I have
some some vendors that I want to put
statically somewhere on the screen
that's really nicely we were doing with
IV
but first global guest shark control and
other stuff I wanted to have it didn't
didn't work and for such requirements I
would actually have to shade rock
directly on my vein and server and I
didn't want to hang on vestan so it's
really not my field not my experience
what I can use there so looking a little
bit more deeper what we can do is when
composite or how as possible system
architecture would look like we have
several applications we have a
compositor and possibly you also have a
well intermediate application would be
called a shell so you have the apps yet
talking to the man capacitor by the
default valid what we call misc in
whizzing huge it's a detective rise
acute plate for an extraction layer you
call it if you simply use - platformer
island and it works magically you can
also use your custom portal called
extension for example for notifications
which I introduced in this few slides
how you can add a small extension for
for notifications or you could also have
a proxy in between this is architecture
on the right side where you have a share
that gets all Z all information or all
these IP C information by some mechanism
and then that's that is the only real
Wayland client that's talking your
protocols and talking to the compositor
if you want to have a little bit more
stability and encapsulation of the
really critical stuff since you never
want to have surveillance so like being
crushy
and you can put your a little bit more
critical stuff and it's a child
I would look at this more simple
architecture here but the other one is
also really simple to to achieve and
well let's mine flight office talk
that's my compositor for what I told you
I will talk a little bit about it's on
this slide and said I will go a little
bit deeper in the next slide so like I
said it's declarative I did some imports
for the basic stuff I need there then I
said well I want to have a variant
compositor and then I want to have an
output like why would you want to have
something on your screen here you know I
have two WL shell from that I get some
notifications hey there's a new surface
so you window from application and if I
get such nor such windows window I put
it into a list model since that's nicely
into you easier since I want to have
some in those lines next to each other
and I simply use the default cute quick
stuff for lining items rectangular items
somewhere on the screen and I put it in
a wrapper called a child surface item
and then cue did everything from you
what I wanted to to have here but look a
little bit more deeper into it so we
always have or typically we have as a
root valent compositor it's well it's
actually representation of the composite
are in the background everything is
created for your brain and compositor
and usually you should have an output of
otherwise don't see anything you should
have a shell extension to get
information that you have that you are
surfaces to be presented the shell
extension actually gives you it from
information sent by the vena protocol
here we have this WL shell and we gets
information there's a service created my
own custom extensions here I can add
several several extensions there I can
also get these informations that I get a
signal from application like shot your
tea is ready
and we have other shells but for the
various cases usually enough to simply
this WHL since we don't have a fully
fledged
that's million excess appeal then we
have the surface surface item and the
cube a lyric item which are nice
wrappers around two surfaces so a
surface is simply field where you have
Sun well some image data and you want to
put it on your screen so you get you put
it into such a wrapper and that you can
use it exactly like it because huge
Creek item so that's a that's the
actually nicest thing about technology
you handle Windows like they are no
business but simply rectangles with some
stuff on it and so you simply should
click developer can simply use it with
only his intuition from what you usually
do does just consider well this surface
it's a rectangle and I move it I do some
animations on it I enlarge it I turn it
I put a trader on it and all the stuff
you can do and that's really nicely
since you're working on capacitor like
it's a simple process application
there's a little bit of cute cricket
that you get from some rail and that's a
real power of it that you can get on
high-level really nice the facts really
nice implicit implementations without or
being brought with all the technical
stuff below yeah it's visibility it's
doing the input stuff so I can
deactivate or the in from stuff I can
hide it I orchid showered and well it's
really acting like it's a particular
item and or of course I need an output
that's simply in vertical area where
show my movie size of the compositor and
I of course I can have multiple of them
I talked a little bit about protocol
extensions for my use case I said well I
want to have notifications at my clients
since they are like your T's very sorry
time to go to bed or what
whatever my my applications want to show
really globally on the screen and what
you see here is a typical XML snippet
which describes such a protocol you can
use a typical valent tooling
surveillance cannot to get the binding
for it
here I'm using the huge tooling since I
get a also synchronous API I can run it
all right and of course all right also
called
code and the Talk Talk slides and
everything is available on github with
all history and what I said you are
running your tooling over it you get
your bone a plate code your bindings you
are put it into your applications and it
works and so you can have your typical
acicular signals and slots me I can
connect to where you can send data and
everything rocks and well actually is
that the small bits from my initial idea
what I have for my kitchen application
that's all well I gotten a notification
yet he's ready I have for two
applications running here and I would
survive I get a live daemon running here
let's start my compositor
there's a compositor and
X application let's see oh there's an
application and maybe it C application
so it is and maybe another egg
application then we have a little bit to
see her at magnification bar and I can
move it and cheat a little bit down I
can simply run the applications and well
it's easy to achieve something like that
and if I would have time would have had
time I could have put it on my Raspberry
Pi and it works I did several similar
things present he's ready and it's
really nicely working also a lot of bear
devices so I was faster than I thought
so we have little question later on I
can already sing starting let's start
syncing so again what I wanted to show
you in this talk is where those new
children capacitor framework which
allows you to simply create Ben
capacitor tailored for the specific use
cases and wishes for your embedded
device you don't have to take a stock
painting capacitor that is maybe come as
some makes problems this was cute huge
event loops which are also have seen
with a proper type proprietary
capacitors you could tailor it directly
to to the user interaction concept your
designers give to you since it's
actually designer cute quick design
artwork
what you do here the capacitor I created
here it's literally a one day job to
create such a composite or even the
first time I worked on it well as at
that time I took two days to get it
working
that's really nice thing and you can use
it for fast prototyping of composite to
us you can also use it well for doing
real capacitors that you want to reduce
later
and whether the problem is I already
said several times I think the power of
this parameter is that it gets the right
abstraction to get you you into a
position where you create a composite
composite or user interface without
thinking about all the complicated
valent related stuff
lower far below the surface but you can
really look at so your eyes or a
compositing and see your overall
interactions you want to have there to
get a really cool and a nice user
interface and the best thing is really
to try it out you find my coach here you
find a lot of examples and the cute
repositories and yeah there's also a
little bit of documentation however the
examples are sometimes more helpful
currently than the documentation I think
okay and there are a few slides for
three pointers
you're on did a nice talk about all the
same from our contracted con there's
online help and most importantly the IRC
channel okay thanks a lot for attention
any questions yes I saw an example my
office not yet but it really works that
you that you have for me
well several displays and several
outputs there are also example codes for
for exactly that use case the multiple
screen demo there are cheat repositories
that Co freedom you have to convert the
framework and then you look at at what
you want to have see want to see there
and the capacitor should handle it it's
your task to create all these effects in
the capacitor it only gives you a
framework to use it feels like acute
click and then you can implement it okay
no more questions then thanks a lot
you