[Music]
so you mentioned I want to talk about if
you have XTP than it is and whenever
some recent developments in linux kernel
a community to start off what is PPF
probably everybody of us use TCP dump in
one way or another if you enter some
filter and TCP lamp that filter gets
compiled down into some pipe code just
by code is called PPF this done by in
the pcap and then pushed into the kernel
and if i could and that is already
existent for a very long time and
nowadays we call this classic BPF 4c p
PF and this quad extended heavily
probably is like one on three years ago
in the car into something that is called
ebps and IPPF is an efficient generic in
kernel white code engine it is used in
many different subsystems in the economy
right now they're probably like creative
team major areas which is networking
tracing and also sandboxing or security
regarding tracing and sandboxing so
tracing for example you have like perf
we can attach EPF programs to trace
point scapes things like that and then
every time an event triggers maybe PPF
program runs and then you can analyze
different things in the kernel can
recall memory and so on and so forth for
sandboxing probably the most popular the
most prominent user is the chrome web
browser where it uses second PPF to
photo
system calls to whitelist system calls
and so on so this is quite flexible that
second people have it's not yet
it's CBP F so still this classic PPF
that is pushed down to the kind of a
networking which is what we want to talk
about here there are various things for
example in sockets you have socket
filters with a packet what I already
mentioned then you have various dimacs
facilities for example SOE use part when
you have multiple circuits that are in a
group that can reuse a specific part
then you can have an EP PF program that
makes the decision to what what that
connection is going to be you also fi if
I could for example fan out we have F
packet circuits and then the traffic can
get load balanced like that to one of
those sockets participating in that
group and then you have X T P and T C so
I will start with the facility that we
haven't TC this is called Co sppf for p
PF classifier it's called like this I
mean classifier for striking reasons but
they can do way more than just
classification so it's it's a flexible
programmable microprocessor and DTC
subsystem you can attach that you can
attach an EP PF program there on the
ingress or equals path of the data path
of networking device and yeah and then
XT P which had recently introduced into
the kernel this is also programmable but
high performance in kernel packet purses
or
that is attachable two drivers that
support it and on the English side of
the driver I will talk about more about
that later I think both things they're
complementary to each other in the sense
that Co sppf can be attached to all
networking devices also retro ones like
we've devices for different four key
names places and it can be attached
ingress and egress and XTP is currently
on ingress and for sppf you have socket
buffer which is the networking
representation at the current
representation of a network packet as
you have that as an input into the PPF
program where it works with that data
and you have which are contacts with
that but both are complementary to each
other and quite flexible so first before
I dive into the details of subsystems
present shortly about the PPF
architecture it consists of 11 64-bit
registers you also have separate users
there you have a stack that is limited
it's currently 512 bytes on the current
stack inclusively premium County of
course the instructions there are fixed
size 64 64 bit wide and you can have
maximum of 4069 instructions per program
which doesn't seem much but you can do
you can still do quite a lot and quite
also complex things with it compared to
the CPF that we know from tcpdump like
what I mentioned earlier there are
various new instructions of course you
have the whole 64 bit range of
instructions for other operations for
example because the CPP efforts only 32
bit and you have things like
you have a call instructions where I can
call into a hyperfunction
what I call explain that later so as
various new instructions and if the core
components after architectures that you
have readwrite access to the input
context the input context as I mentioned
for example in TC is a socket buffer in
XTP it's like a small representation
where you can access the deemed like tip
network packet for the exterior
presentation then you have a helper
function concept which means that the
chrono exposes a fixed fine set of
wipers or like functions that BPF
program can call into so i cannot call
arbitrary kernel memory that just fixed
that then the maps maps efficient key
value the data structures that can be
shared arbitrarily which means one or
multiple EPF programs can access that
map or new space can can access and read
or update data from it at the same time
so then there are tail call stair calls
the concept so you don't have this fixed
limitation or 4069
instruction program but you can also go
beyond that and this is quite useful
uses the same stack frame so it's also
quite fast then there's a concept of
object pinning which means that from
users based perspective programs and
maps their access through file
descriptors and once you load a program
into the corner for example by RTC then
this file descriptor contour just your
file descriptor is basically unavailable
for other programs to use and to share
maps with also other applications you
can you can pin them in a pseudo file
system as a node there and then there's
other programs that can retrieve it and
also work on this map to update or
retail down then in the Conner
there's see people have to be AF
translator which means that whenever you
load your classic TCP one filter in the
corner that gets transparently
translated to EPF and only ones on EBP F
and the nice thing about PPP efforts
that from users beside em has an API
back-end which means that you can write
as C like program and VM translates that
into an object file which has EBP F
instructions that can then be loaded
into the kernel interpreter and the
colonel had also a just-in-time compiler
so whenever you load program and the
just-in-time compiler is enabled and
this gets mapped directly to native up
code so we can run with native
performance all of that is managed
through the PPF system core so it's like
a stable API and also your programs when
they when you implement them they are
basically stable so once your current
supports that it's like guarantee that
your comments will also support that in
future unlike for example current module
where internals can always change so to
give you some
more details regarding TC TC you can
basically attach this your sppf to Q
risk and just like the cutest creatures
called chat Co as act which is just
super cute is similar to the English
cutest in the camera and this is only
there for the purpose of attaching
classifiers and actions if your family
TTC and in that case we want to attach
us of course Co sppf there are two
central hooks whereas Chettiar as act
Cooter's can attach to which is the
ingress and egress code so they are
basically like really central places
where any packet has to go through from
Rx and TX ID yes historically it also
supports CBP F support flavors and you
can atomically update your programs
during one time which is really the
program that is attached to this USB PF
densifier itself those tail calls when
program calls into another they can also
automatically get updated during runtime
networking interface things like that
and see sppf has a fast path which means
that historically TC has classifiers in
actions where I mentioned and classifier
once that's done classifying can then
call into a chain of actions and all of
that is pretty inefficient and can do
everything contained in itself anyway so
therefore this sppf has a so-called
direct action mode where
laughs can classify a mango perform
various actions on the skp on the socket
buffer this is an input and then just
return a verdict and then be done with
it so it doesn't call into chain of
actions or whatever everything is done
in the PPF program itself and there's
also an interface for example the
metronome and P driver if you have such
an acronym smart neck can offload IPPF
programs which means that whenever you
load your program to zero sppf and have
such a cart and it gets translated into
the into native code that supported for
the instruction set on the NFP driver
so a typical workflow would be you add
your C program you compile gets
translated into into F instructions so
into F instructions they are contained
in an elf object form
TC and in that case can read that object
file and note those instructions to the
kernel in the Kannada gateway fight
which means that glow file make sure
that the instructions cannot crash the
car no it cannot create infinite loops
things like that
then it gets just-in-time compiler then
this is pushed down into cos PDF
classifier and then eventually gets
offloaded so that's like typical
workflow for that and xtp on the other
hand this was introduced probably one
year ago on to the car the objectives
there is that it's really
for high-performance packet processing
so what it does is it runs an EB PF
program the very values point in the
driver so this is it so even before you
and an skp made a data structure
this is one of the overheads to kind of
have for doing high-performance packet
processing with small packets in
particular and the nice thing is that
this kind of framework works in concert
with the kernel which means it uses the
same security module you don't have your
NIC representation or your driver in
userspace and have it it exposed there
but it still stays in the kernel there's
no out of tree module needed for
accessing that and the packet itself it
also stays in the kernel which means you
don't have to cross boundaries when you
want to get it out or when you want to
push it back into the kernel which is
for example nice if you want to record
containers for example and when if the
use cases could be that you're
implementing a firewalling application
and I can already filter packets all the
possible point on your NIC and then from
there
part of those packets that can get
further passed to the kernel stack and
then into some of the containers other
use cases includes load balancing for
example there's a return load balancing
is currently possible with that and
mangling and forwarding or anti denial
of service measures
monitoring is also possible so there's
currently an interface where you can
push packets to use the space for
sampling and monitoring from XDP side
yeah and yellow is ready similar to TC
which means either you can drop packets
past and further onto the kernel stack
or transmit them out again and they're
currently a number of drivers that
support that some for example many Maps
drivers ml X 4 and X 5 then we have the
metronome driver again and to logic
there's using the weather net support
that has been merged and Intel for the
posted to the net list so it would be
merged swing and as well be NXT the
drivers some of them currently depending
on implementation but that will change
the future that all of them will support
that most likely allow also for atomic
updates so once you have your actually P
program loaded and you want it with a
new version this can happen without
disruption of any traffic and also xtp
has an offloading interface and again
also an eternal has support for that so
once you load your HTTP program natural
can offload that with a couple of
limitations currently but it's already
good way forward in the web from here
similar to what I mentioned earlier you
have your C program
and this time IP so I linked command can
be used as a loader for pushing the
secret the PPF sequence down to the
kernel and yeah some of those features I
mentioned they're maps which fish the
key value stores you can from an DPF
program lookup update or delete elements
created a couple of flavors which are
our Maps hash tables least recently used
maps and longest prefix match which has
been merged for both types and you also
have variants and there's also
possibility to pre-allocate the whole
memories you have a pool and you can you
don't have to allocate your elements
through the normal education facilities
then there are also specialized maps
which means they can not be used like
those generic maps that they are used
with people have helpers for example the
program map which is used for tail calls
where it can push files to place into
this specific map and then you can jump
into that through that there's direct
packet access which means another
support in both cases you sppf and xtp
direct packet with right means that in
the past cos people have had to use
helper functions where you pass
in a stack buffer and gets filled for
the offset the number of parts you want
to redirect
it means you can for example just cross
your header directly without having to
go through help so it's performance
optimization there for example in the
socket buffer case on sppf you can use
skb mark for example there are various
other things there but so it can work
with other facilities from the kernel as
well we got a packet forwarding SPF as I
mentioned can forward so it can forward
packets to any networking device
including virtual ones so when you push
that into container over we for example
you can put it all to the same port or
can loop it back to the path for XDP
it's currently still limited
so in xtp case you can only push it out
to the same port came in in progress to
also support multi port 2 X 2 X through
a different net device that also
supports xep future but currently to the
same part it's - because for example
when you have to let the lens you use
case with directory turn your note that
once or your local answer that would
once
xtp gets the packet
and rewrites various parts and push it
out again but the reply packets since
its director Witcher and go different
paths so it's still very useful to do
that
that's a miscellaneous things you can do
encapsulation
so there's the excellent genève to IP IP
encapsulation available for CSP PF x to
be way more flexible actually you can do
any kind of encapsulation you want
because at that point at that early
point in time the colonel doesn't know
anything about the packet that is coming
in yet and so you're not limited by the
[Music]
from the itself because you can have
custom own custom structs and and then
pushed out to a high-performance per cpu
memory mapped we afford to use a space
that can be some specific data and
packet itself up to a full packet so
that is useful if you have some
management demons that then listen on
certain events and updates later on
programs for tail calls and so on you
have checks and angling you have to
group supports inverse other things I
think to as the letter I already
mentioned that it has it can push down
the PPF code into the kernel just to
give you an example how it works so for
example MTC case you said that the
cutest first and you can set up the
filter and then you need to find whether
an ingress or egress ID you want to
hope that people have program to and
then you define the object itself and
then the object can have various
sections which contain the program code
to actual program code and XTP workflow
it's currently where I can say I want to
learn to program by an IP link and then
as well as specify the object and then
it gets pushed down and they have common
chat
estimated the back end so it doesn't
necessarily have to be able to you can
also have other letters if you program
them yourself the libraries that support
it so it's just one flavor where you can
do that democratic just-in-time
compilers there's x86 support arm 64
PowerPC and 390x so they all have EPF
afloat yeah and PowerPC quite recently
March which is nice and the same for the
NFP driver which also implements a
just-in-time compiler for the NFP
specific instruction set for the
networking offload is measures against
for those two programs I'm not going to
mention the detail here and the other
recent improvements for example IBM
[Music]
support which means you can annotate
your generated object code with actual
source code that you have and for it's
definitely an improvement for the foot
bagging there were four improvements
that can recognize the better in the
kernel so it accepts those programs as
well and trace points have recently been
merged and
so on so that we have next steps so
definitely they still have to be an
improvement from the verification side
in terms of logging or provide more
helpful user messages for example then
in terms of search pruning the little
verifier can aggressively to verify
doesn't have to do too much web to
verify each possible path of the program
and then there has to be better XTP
driver support in future but that will
come over time and yeah so those are
some some examples of next steps through
adding code if you want to look at some
code and we can recommend you to go to
github.com slash syrian which is a
project which implements basically BP -
XTP for containers there will be talk
afterwards for that and everything else
on the colonel and i period two ciders
merged upstream and for further
information you can also look at the net
deaf conference papers that are there or
the kernel documentation and so on are
there any questions
but there's a symmetry there between the
features or fit between CSS
I don't expect to convert all of that
because I mean those are like two
different layers of the stack and for
some situations use cases one thing much
better than then than the other so it's
it's it's not like it exactly the same
or something right so as I mentioned
earlier they're complementary to each
other so yeah all right
so you definitely can okay I should
repeat the question is it possible to
modify packets based on state for
example for nothing and yeah so it's
definitely possible so state you can
hold basically in vpf maps that's where
they are therefore and you can modify so
as I mentioned Esther agreed Eric right
possibilities so yeah suing for example
does that so I'm not quite well what
features metronomes support but I think
they should be able to write as well
okay the limitation for the neutron is
that they do not yet support EPF Maps
well that will come in future so there's
work in progress from that website I
don't work for them but just to tell you
what I know I think the most difficult
task so one of the challenges an X
appears that you follow this to a
different part and what is the most
difficult task there right is that you
have that you need to have the so
there's currently work regarding having
a page a locator which means that if you
want to format that to a different NIC
even they have to have some common
understanding on how to transfer the
packet from the site to another right
without copying for example so you need
to have like a common shared page pool
the Constructors you can trust transfer
those Patriots to the other one so that
they can try TX that yeah so just still
I think quite some work there to get
that supported from apps so selecting
logic from maps and yeah so for example
array maps on maps
whether you have a perceive you or
numbers not per CPU you're basically on
your own which means that the program
has to be written in a way that it
doesn't have race conditions so it's so
you have some instructions for example
atomic add we can use to increment
counters on that side for the hash
tables you have basically the update
helper car which atomically replaces one
hash table map element with another and
so yeah so there are various it is
dependent on the map certainly and there
is performance improvements to be done
still
all right if you can also grab them in
the hallway if there are further
questions so
[Applause]