so for those who attend the first talk
in the zoom I want to remind the few
couple of things which are the kind of
conduct that we have specially for
during is different from the first one
so I encourage you to go on the page and
read it out if you are developing enough
to know your opinion and try the survey
from bit dot me slash for them seventeen
only upper cases from earlier
presentations encourage you to try the
nightly version of Firefox which can be
downloaded from as lightly that
mozilla.org or as valid or slash nightly
whatever it's easier for you and we are
trying to find out what motivates you to
contribute to open source so I wanted to
complete another survey you always away
these days at B EE /y open source our
next speaker is Nicholas Ronnie and is
one of the Mozilla lovers and one of the
few French people that really understand
up GA is I also created a API a pipes
are using SpiderMonkey on the server
since 2006 without six
Oh
[Music]
I'll talk about this later
[Applause]
to
[Music]
[Applause]
I see from the next idiom I call some of
them some of them okay thank you so much
[Applause]