cool
so thank you for staying because you're
all stuck here anyways
this is extending spark ml super happy
new pipeline stage time yay
I'm holdin my preferred pronouns are she
or her it's tattooed on my wrist in case
you forget don't it up and I'm a
principal software engineer at IBM spark
Technology Center if anyone's looking to
relocate to America for some reason
still come and talk to me and I've been
doing this had a bunch of other
companies for a while you can follow me
on Twitter and it's mostly just tweets
being really sad about America right now
so if you're too happy following me on
Twitter and I'll fix that for you and
then we'll talk about software will be
worthwhile we're gonna talk about what
spark ml pipelines look like and then
we're gonna jump into extending them
really quickly and the topic said it was
going beyond word count but we've got
ten minutes so it's sort of beyond what
counted so yeah spark ml pipelines are
pretty much the spark developers looking
at scikit-learn and going you shiny
steel unfortunately their big data
developers and so they got kind of
halfway through stealing I didn't bother
stealing all of the algorithms but they
they stole the api's so if you're
familiar with scikit-learn spark ml
pipelines are gonna be really familiar
to you and they're exposed in Scala and
Python and you can use it to do
distributed machine learning but the
algorithm selection isn't like 100
percent right you might have some really
crazy problem that you're trying to
solve and you need an algorithm that
isn't already in spark and the good news
is you can implement it yourself
and the stages in these pipelines are
either estimators or transformers
transformers are the little blue boxes
and those are just things which don't
need to be trained on data and so
they're really simple to implement we
can just write in a normal spark job and
add a little bit of sugar and make a
transformer but if you want to build
something fancy you like a machine
learning algorithm or something which
needs to be trained on data you have to
build an estimator and we'll look at how
to do that really quickly
yeah these tourists
whatever just cover up this part of the
slides no one sees this part but we have
to provide a transform schema and a copy
function and these are the two sort of
like non-standard spark bits that we
have to add if we want to turn our spark
job into an ml pipeline component and
then we had can add some configuration
as well and then if you add the
configuration with the spark way you can
do like parameter grid searches and and
automatically tune your models and
because I'm really bad at statistics I
frequently use parameter grid search
because I don't know how to pick my
own regularization parameter you do that
for me so here is our hard-coded word
count stage as a licensed Big Data
instructor I have to put word count
everywhere you may wonder why it's in
every single talk ever and this is why
but we've got a copy function and our
constructor it's not super important you
can pretty much just steal this and
change the name from hard-coded word
count to hard-coded magic algorithm and
for copy you've just called default copy
unless you need to do something really
weird in my sample set of two calling
default copy works 100% of the time if
it doesn't work for you please don't
tell me I'll have to change the talk and
that that would just be sad and so now
this is the part which is different than
our normal spark code because these
machine learning pipelines can take a
really long time to run and because data
frames aren't compile time type checked
we want to do at least some type
checking before we start our like 8 hour
or 24 hour
machine learning job and then come back
halfway through and be like oh it failed
because like I got the name wrong of
this one random thing and so transform
schema is a thing which gives us the
ability to verify that our inputs are
sort of what we're expecting and tell
the downstream people what our outputs
are going to be like I mean if this code
looks kind of weird to you it's ok it's
just the data frame code and it's really
simple there's a lot of introductions to
it and that's where like these types
come from this string type is not the
Scala string type it's the spark string
type which is mildly differ
in ways that are exciting and not for a
10-minute talk and then we can just add
our result here and then we can do our
work and so this is really simple right
we're just counting the words that are
being put in I'm not even doing the
proper word count but it's really simple
and you could do something actually
complex I find that doing this with the
UDF even though spark has a really nice
way to do integrated functional
programming and relational stuff it
doesn't work really well with this part
because generally what we want to do is
we want to just add things to the data
that's coming and we don't want to like
get rid of anything and we don't
necessarily know all of the types that
are coming in so it's hard to use the
full data set API so you end up having
to use this kind of ugly UDF syntax but
it's not the end of the world right
usually this is much nicer than writing
a high view D Athens
I promise you've never written a high
view TF you're lucky and and this is
where your fun can be and if you're a
researcher you can spend like months
working on the code that's gonna live
inside of transform if you're in
industry you can spend like a day or two
or if your boss is wondering what you're
doing just like have them email me I'll
be like no it's super important trust me
and you can go and do some crazy stuff
and then we need to configure our
pipeline stage for pipeline stages in
SPARC we use this parameter interface
and this just gives spark a standard way
of being able to configure and do sort
of parameter good searching you probably
wouldn't do a parameter grid search on
your output column let's be a little
weird but you might do it on your input
cone and you're not limited to strings
here right so these these are string
parameters but these could definitely be
doubles you know floats bins whatever so
you could do a parameter search on your
on your tuna Graham and then you provide
some setters and those are for like
humans use and it's really simple and
yeah so we do it this way so that sparks
meta algorithms can work on it if you
don't know what parameters you should be
adding to your machine learning
you can go look at shared pram Scala
inside of Sparks codebase and just like
steal the ones that you want you'll have
to cut and paste the code or lie about
being inside of package org Apache spark
because it's all private if you lie
about being inside a package org Apache
spark I don't know who you are it's not
my fault but I do it pretty often myself
and so you know no harm no foul but your
cause is probably gonna break me upward
what's the future use problem though and
if I've learned anything about
scientists it's that they don't seem to
think about future you when it comes to
their software no offense
so that's really boring we made word
count and I promised we were gonna go
beyond word count um so let's go beyond
word count
we're gonna make an estimator this is
the fancy thing no one's excited but
it's okay it's fancy it's gonna like
actually train on some input data we do
pretty much the same thing so what our
estimator does is we write a fit
function we have the same parameters to
configure it and then our fit function
is going to return our transformer and
so our it's really simple yeah I owe
this says November oh yeah that actually
is old but let's let's look at a really
simple estimate ah you know oh this is
an old version of the slides dammit okay
well so I don't have the code for the
estimator but it's a fit function which
is just gonna return our transformer yay
so pretend that there's a fit function
and it's gonna construct new hard-coded
word count stage or whatever it is you
want and if you want to see the code for
that it's totally in this really nice
blog post which is a lot longer than 10
minutes unfortunately but hopefully
maybe I trick someone into thinking that
making their own spark machine learning
algorithm is a good use of their time
and you'll publish it to maven central
and then I can use it or tell people to
use it and we can all hang out and have
fun if I didn't trick anyone into doing
that that's okay too
there's also this github repo with a
bunch of examples they're written mostly
by me so they're a little yeah but if
you want to go ahead and look at the
ones that are inside a spark itself you
can find them here and those ones are a
little more I want to say professional
or production-ready
they're not like all great but they put
a lot more thought into them and I put
into mine so you can definitely check
those out and they're gonna use internal
api's but it's okay you can just like
lie and say you're inside a package org
apache spark and there's api
documentation and fun stuff as an author
of some books i would be remiss if i
didn't try and get you to give me your
money and so and these aren't all my
books to be clear i don't have that much
time in my life don't buy this one
that's kind of out of date authors won't
normally tell you that but you should
buy all of these other books even the
ones I didn't write but if you have an
expense account does anyone have an
expense account no okay well and then
don't buy several copies of this but if
you know someone with an expense account
maybe someone that works at Bloomberg
you can get them to buy several copies
of high-performance spark it is the
holiday gift of the season for whatever
holiday is coming up next if for some
reason you don't want to buy a book
which doesn't exist yet that's that's
okay I understand you can give me your
email address at high performance bar
comm and they'll spend the hell out of
you as soon as the book is finished but
please give me your money today rather
than tomorrow because money today is
coffee so thank you
[Applause]
okay Oh doggies name is boo she comes
with me to all of my talks where I
remember to bring her