so I
[Music]
because sometimes
[Applause]
[Music]
documentation
much better
[Music]
because grapes in a page
because
[Music]
[Applause]
now it's not so much
[Music]
Firefox
we can specify we have a simple page
html5 that in image because it's not
working okay it's very simple but they
call this why they must simple because
they only change the document right past
image is a type of script there is also
the one that change
the line babies are extension and you
can see you can get fun I started at
that weekend but to same experience I
defy every translation and I user from
the Opus Palace community that support
50 different languages that are 2008
extension the data browser Firefox just
remind speak very loud when you ask a
question and Daniella please repeat the
question
thank you
[Music]
there was a section there's a to
documentation or MGM three weeks of life
[Music]
okay sweetie interesting direction but
it was a bit illogical in your
presentation because you say that
extension are part of Firefox everybody
it was made what made Firefox from lucky
cities but by the end of the year
2/3 of the important are done I use as
that I use every day we stop working to
change the P I destroy the new at the
station is the future because I should
not devastation is like a rapper
today s education for us then there will
be a change inside Firefox as we need
not cover like before without the CD k
that when they re Firefox the station is
broke and we just a show this problem
main problem because there is a lack of
refer to the inside
Firefox mechanics just work with no
problem using
[Music]
to do
[Applause]
[Music]
because it
[Applause]
maybe you can talk to them afterwards
and get their thoughts and ask them
questions
[Music]