let's love what I say that lovely loved
aromatherapy Molly anyway thank you hi
good morning we can start now
my name is javi how do you appear I came
from Spain and today I want to talk
about the high level synthesis what's
the status of this kind of technology in
respecting to free free open-source
software tools the point is that we will
see we have not very a lot of
alternatives to do this by using only
free open-source software and the main
topic on the main idea of this talk is
to rise the plaque about all the issues
we have right now and to try to to
mobilize to to push the community in
order to to take all this this issue
from our company we have started do some
work in order to reach these kind of
things but as we will see this some
there is a lot of work to be done yet ok
let's start I want to make some comments
about the state of the art about high
level synthesis and we why is this
become becoming very very important
right now maybe you are already aware of
this but in the last year's a lot of
difference algorithms are starting to to
gain a lot of traction and that require
and this algorithm requires a lot of
computational power for example we have
imbalance speed we have better vision
deeper machine learning Big Data data
mining all of these kind of algorithms
is there are not very complex as per as
per design but they require a lot of
computational power a lot of much more
much operation
and an extreme power link with the data
in this situation the von Neumann CPUs
the well-known CPU that used to be
accelerated by the path of Morelos is
not a scaling anymore we need to design
or to develop alternative architectures
in order to take all this kind of this
kind of tasks well this is where FPGA is
come to the rescue
most of this kind of task does this very
computational intensive tasks are right
now I take off by using GPU tools for
example is very well known the Nvidia
CUDA so that you can program program in
a very high level and and they provide a
lot of floating-point parallel lines
very powerful very very powerful one
sorry the point is that for example this
looks like very promising but there are
some algorithms in which this approach
doesn't fit very well for example we
have the inference in a typical vision
that you might suppose the using
floating points our arithmetic is a very
good idea but is not a good idea it
empirical test so that the by using
fixed and pointed metics you might
improve the most all of the matrix you
say silicon real estate because the
logics you need fewer logical gates in
order to implement the thing you also
have fewer power consumption and even
and surprisingly enough even the
algorithm is more accurate by using
fixed point aromatics that using
floating point arithmetic this is maybe
counter intuitive but is how the things
really works some of the some benders on
some hardware vendors for example Google
are starting to develop their own very
new hardware architectures but if you
develop a team a chip from the ground up
the cost are very very high so in this
kind of agonies where you are you can
change the algorithm the software is
constantly
involving your flexibility is a must and
this is where FPS came to the rescue
because poor definition you cannot find
any more flexible
any more flexible than I have PA and the
thing is that the whole industry is
looking at FTEs for answers let's see
some examples for example we have a
winter is striking back the winter the
windows
sorry winter is Microsoft + Intel is
where we used to call that and he says
looking back I don't know if you were
aware of this but Intel has just bought
al-qaeda now this was the the second
brunt of a PE s in market share and it
was funny enough that a couple of years
ago in the first either EDF room in the
in the digital design panel we started
to talk about a rumor about Microsoft
get it involved in FPS and so on and
about project catapult that is an SDK
that Microsoft Harper just released in
order to accelerate the to accelerate
software by using fps they are pardoning
in some way with Intel and for example
they are already using this in the beam
search and game and they are planning to
use this also in office365 in this
picture I really like it do you have a
see on professor in which in the same
package you will have the multi-core CPU
and an antenna FPA all packets in the
same in a same socket so this kind of
technology is going to be pushing the
it's going to be pushing the data center
a lot of but not only the consortium
formed by Intel and Windows I'm sorry a
Microsoft is using this approach there
are some other examples too for example
we have basil Bob I do I don't know
whose spring news that is accelerate in
SQL at the Dutton said at the data
center by using silence Kintex ultra
scale
parts I don't know if you were one of
these was very interesting
still if has said before Amazon Web
Services are already offering
some units in which you can accelerate
the which you can accelerate the
software by using up to eight shillings
FPGAs and IBM and with these
intelligence our main concept I started
to work with Cylons and by using the in
order to integrate their power PC CPUs
with the FPGA is coming from in front
silence sorry and even more they have
designed the own chip for deep learning
that is called true north and what is
not more people know that the this chip
is actually designed by the Cornell
University FPGA experts so what is
really in the industry is a very
specific @pe area so after these
examples let's focusing how how level
synthesis work what the target is to
accelerate software going by using an
FPGA what does this mean
okay we can do we want to automatically
generate a code for a high level
definition for example OpenCL the
language a decision in Kilda sorry the
language that is using for and give you
another another hardware platform stood
for acceleration is becoming the de
facto standard for most of the APA
vendors - namely silence or internal
formally and alpena the idea is to take
all the this growing community of GPU
based programmers that are very used to
to use OpenCL on this kind of technology
and take them and provide the FPS tools
- in order to allow them to program an
API without noting that they are using
an FPGA
these are very complex and expensive
commercial tools in which they do
provide an application the application
get profiled by a Bulgarian machine or
something similar and the most computing
intensive task even I identified and
there is a an automatically generation
of the
of the vehicle that cover these parts of
the software that is most intensive then
the software part is compiled and the
scene and the hardware part the gate
were part the partner is going to be
deployed in the PE is also compiled and
generated and then another piece of the
of this of these tools is a special
kernel model that is in charge of
logging and logging and unloading the
PGA's course as they are demanded by the
by the algorithms who is how are we
approaching this this kind of stuff
from our company because there is not
the in the past that have been some some
tries to to develop high level synthesis
tool in which you can program almost
anything and it gets automatically
profile like like in the tool the the
band or FPGA vendors are providing but
it is very complex there is no actually
there is not any free open-source tool
that is working right now in this way so
our idea is to provide that set of
hardware accelerated libraries for a
specific port purpose let's see for
example if we are going to program
digital signal processing we want to
have a set of libraries in which the
most common operation are already
present Assizes so that you can use the
call of function and what you are on the
thing what is doing is taking this
presenta sized thing this is also has
application for on a liberal such as
embedded vision inverse kinematics and
so the provided libraries must include a
software side providing the wrapper like
a ipi api in order to live with the
standard software so that you can
program a standard program and call this
kind of libraries and i wanna get wurr
side the fpga side in which the
optimized HDL code is already present i
sized this must be transparent for the
programmers
we can yes call the use the API make
some includes and use dysfunction and
and the system as in the in the previous
case need to be in charge of logging and
unloved in the FPGA part as the as the
called the binary that you are executing
the program in the CPU is needing the
Pierre part in order to accelerate the
thing how do we can integrate the FPGA
into the operating system earlier to get
this kind of him for sure first of all
we are only focus on Linux I am not
going to talk about Windows or nothing
at all and what we need as I have
previously said is to have some hardware
accelerated libraries with the own
associated with the stream for the FPGA
we need to know that different library
version is talking about libraries in
the standard software in the server
software point of view might require
different bit stream versions too so we
need to match the first the software
part and the bit stream part so what we
are doing is to package to packaging the
Associated bit stream for each of these
libraries as a little package so that
you can we can establish
interdependencies between the FPGA part
and the software part so that it you
need to install a software by instance
of this kind of libraries the bit stream
is also deployed and the person matches
the version of the software library too
and it's very important also this a
comment that the bit stream needs to be
present aside why this is also important
well because synthesizing a bit stream
is very a very time-consuming task you
can lose a lot of time you cannot be
synthesizing
on the flight and even more important
because only a x86 processor are able to
run the the most of the synthesized
tools that are available today may be
yoshie-san expecting well kin-por later
about this because
you are using an ARM processor you
cannot synthesize the thing inside the
inside the chip we are using dr. project
as the building system so that
everything including the bitstream of
the frame with the string associated to
the libraries are are monitored and we
use HDL make in order to integrate the
bitstream synthesis inside the system
the operating system generation so that
by using HDL make we can generate some
resides in with the Willis if I doctor
project the building system all need to
hold the Ignat how it needs to handle
the the APL call code in order to delay
the the package the package including
the midstream as a couple of examples we
have used this with the CERN open
hardware kit in order to provide yes for
internal use by the way by the moment to
provide the automatic to provide
automatic support for all different
different mobile different hardware that
can be inserted in in a carry about this
sorry I have not explained this because
I bring a little bit out of time
this board is supporting grease you can
plug different hardware models and each
of them have different functionality
these are controlled by an FPGA and if
you depending of the on the depending of
the model you are plugging into sorry
depending on the mode you are plugging
into you will need a different bit
string of the FPGA to so by using it
will make we have generated different
packages different Linux packages for
each of these different models that not
only include the sorry that not only
include the kernel model but we have
also package for the users by program
and also for the PA salafi we
- to make a linear run time in which the
sorry in which one of these models needs
to be support by just installing one of
the packets all of the different ones
are generated and installed the user Spy
the usual space program the kernel model
plus the PDA system another very
interesting example that we are using is
for robotic controls I don't know if you
are have heard about Ross the robotic
operating system that there is one of
the parts of this project that is called
Ross industrial that is devoted to
applying robotic operating system to
industrial manipulators and it's also a
free open source sdk in this kind of
robotic controls there is a need for
massive computational power we are part
of this consortium and we are in charge
of in trying to accelerate the the most
in intensive algorithms that they this
robots use by using FPGA and for example
the most the most appropriate examples
in order to do this is the the inverse
kinematics
the distance you know you take robotic
arm they tell the tell it wording need
to put the tooltip and it automatically
calculates all of the movements or the
different service it has it has a very
computing intensive task and in order to
clarify a path or movement a robot my
lost about tens of seconds tends not ten
tens of seconds maybe even a minute he
is compress enough
another one is point load that is more
related to artificial vision and so on
yeah I feel the abyssal zone we are
working in applying the the previous the
previous approach to this kind of to
these two examples we have a mission
feature that need to need to to get into
the FPGA
in order to be able to use this approach
of having library accelerated by a few
years that is the that is the partial
reconfiguration maybe you have already
heard about the Pareto rule that applies
to libraries in general so that not all
the libraries had use at the same time
and most of the and the libraries are in
the professor's as low that are unloaded
in the cache cache a memory as they are
required in order to perform to
implement this approach in an efficient
way in in FPGA in order to accelerate
libraries in an FPGA in efficient way we
need a way in order to we problem only
slices of the PA not all the TA we need
to handle the FPA configuration memory
uses the CPU handle the cache and the
cache a memory there are already some
tools are able to do this but they are
authoring but they are very expensive or
they are not commercial turna tips there
are only supporting high grant devices
and but they are very expensive and some
conclusions they are no a lot of flows
freely very open source tools in order
to do this SDL make is a very
interesting tool that allow us to at
least to manage all the pain of handling
handling a PE and PL libraries together
and we need also an SDL library standard
may be IP exact can be a good candidate
we need maybe another alternatives and
we is very important also to have a IP
integrator and maybe field so can be a
very good idea in order to to use in
order to do this kind of things and
finally to have a workaround for partial
reconfiguration and that is sorry
yes but I I don't run anything okay okay
okay okay I have told before about the
atl make I under maintain a novice will
make I have told you about since high
level synthesis but this is my core my
core tool and this is a an assistant to
a common line to in order to to make the
life easier for FPGA designers I have
some stuff that I want to show you a
video about the whole you can about the
brand new graphical user interface I am
developing for for HDL baked let's see
sorry okay can you see that
I am in this video I am just going to
create to plan an ETL make project taken
from the open harbor repository a site
maintained by sir once why am have
already download this these repository
because HDL make is very useful in order
to to use controlled version for your
HDL code I have all right now know that
the signings IESE tools and then I am
going to learn the HDL what right now I
call the dealmaker is like no javascript
wrapper for HDL make so that you can
open it in a in our web page so that you
can run the synthesis even in your own
computer and open this graphical user
interface or even run it in a server in
a server with all the tools installed
and just accessing with any other
computer we have some different controls
now I am fitting the Cove because it
automatically fits the libraries it need
the IP core libraries in it in order to
make the machine places and
as now I can make a pouch because
synthesis process is very very
time-consuming very time-consuming task
now here we have run in the we can see
that the synthesis is running what the
FET is running and now I am going to
make the auto so at a makefile synthesis
makefile has been just generated
synthesis make file generated and now I
am going to run the the make command
because it will make produce make files
we are running in in local mode and then
all the IES see stuff from zionists
start appealing in the in the in the
screen now we need to stop because this
is very thank consuming and after some
minutes she want to be faster
right now the synthesis has finally
ended
okay that video is not okay the
synthesis a finale oh I saw the video
was sorta sorry okay now we have a
programming file we have for religion a
the bitstream and then we could go to
the to a file browser and get to grab
the byte stream and to download it this
is very usefully you are running the
synthesis in a different machine so that
you can access through your web browser
and the synthesis is perform in another
big machine and you can just grab the
devstream one of the cool things we can
do with this maybe this is the most
interesting one is the one you have for
really parts of the design and you have
the relation between the inner parts of
the design itself we have other projects
alligator so that you are you can see
the whole structure of the of the design
itself you can browse the design you can
close and you can close and collapse and
expand the
different branches from the design I
think there is no much many more to
explain in this well we see that we can
film and to navigate and we can collapse
the different branches also in order to
focus in the parts of the design we we
really want to focus on and I think the
video is yes a minute left but it's the
same I need not move from from the
browser