or
being here I have 40 minutes I hope to
have some time for questions for you
guys as well I'll try and talk in say
3035 minutes I'll give you an overview
of free and open source software in
public administrations in Europe I've
been writing for a project at the
European Commission for 10 years so the
main thing I'll try and do here is give
you a set of tips a set of things that
public administrations need to do as a
set of things that we can check whether
public administrations have them in
place that will make them slowly switch
to open source a few disclaimers I am an
external contractor I'm just a
journalist I happened to be in the lucky
position to work for the European
Commission I am NOT the European
Commission so the things I say here are
my view not the Commission's view and
when I talk about free software I mean
open source and when I say open source I
mean free software for me as a person
it's more or less synonymous so when you
see it behind me on the screen go either
way
this talk has six chapters I'll give you
as I announced the that yes
we'll need a bigger Beemer this is as
big as it gets
sorry you can control in the plus button
once as long as I don't use my lose my
notes better again can we have your
votes again so I'll give you the the
main things that I see that are
requirements for public administrations
I will quickly this is the desktop
development room I'll quickly run
through the main desktop implementations
that we have in Europe I will give you
the key policies I will talk briefly
about what are the expected benefits
when public administrations go to open
source one of the things that worries me
is the point that's called what's
missing because there's a few things
missing but I first need to talk about
the OSHA project but so just to bear
with me for five seconds I'll show you
how it works this is the how-to these
are the main implementations the key
policies the expected benefits and
what's missing some of these slides go
deep so that's what happens here
so first the open source Observatory we
have more than 2000 news items we have
case studies we have best practices we
have how to's the project tries to cover
any public administration that uses open
source that implements open source is
thinking about doing this or is
considering to stop doing it we bring a
lot of positive news because the trend
is public administration's are going to
open source but every now and then it
goes wrong so we report about that as
well
it's the open source Observatory and
repository so we have a catalogue of
solutions made for and by public
administrations there some 4000 of them
that's also but it's not all done at the
Commission level that we link
repositories in the Member States
there's a whole bunch of them like 12 in
Spain there's a bunch in there's one or
two in Austria we have one in the
Netherlands there's one in Belgium when
you search for solutions on the ozone
you will find the solutions in the
Austrian and the Spanish repositories
and vice-versa and the collection of
these tools and all of this is for
chronic identification or for electronic
procurement anything to do with a
government those solutions are being
built increasingly as open-source it's
you will hardly come across the public
administration that these days is no
longer developing tools as proprietary
that the hardly ever happens something
that we're very proud of or happy that
we have done it is developed the EU PL
it's sort of a fork of the GPL why was
that necessary the Commission has a
principle that all of the software that
the Commission now publishes is done as
open-source a whole bunch of lawyers
looked at the GPL and sort of feared
that if the EC would do this and there
was some kind of problem somewhere down
the line they would have to fly to the
US to argue in the US courts something
about European made software that they
didn't want to do so that's one big
reason that they use the GPL and change
the bunch of things so that they could
say you go to a court in one of the
Member States and if that doesn't work
you can go to a court in Brussels in
Belgium so that was one reason another
thing that is I think personally really
cool is that they did this license in
all the languages of the European Union
that's 23 if I'm not mistaken that means
that you can use as a German developer
the German EU PL and it's legally the
same as the Dutch or the French or the
Maltese or the Greek so that makes
working together as public a message is
a lot simpler so
some a little bit of context the the
odor is part of the is one of the small
programs of the ISO square program I
don't I wouldn't want to bother you with
the details but the Commission has a
bunch of ministries one of them is the
Ministry for IT it's called DG IT digit
they have a program that looks at the
Member States
DG IT is concerned with rolling out
software for the workstations and the
services in the Commission itself but
the eisah program is more or less the
only program that looks at all the
Member States and tries to get them
together to work on solutions to share
and reuse and in this sharing and reuse
program they figured we need open-source
is a very easy way to get that done and
that's where also comes in its support -
for that goal as I promised I will this
is for me it's the main part of the
presentation how to fix open source so
that how to fix public administration so
that they do open source so the first
thing we need to do is to make free and
open source software a task for the head
of IT for the head of the department for
the head of the IT department or the CIO
at the ministry level or the
municipality level or for the decision
maker at the national level I've listed
three of the main advantages that if a
CEO these days does not have an
open-source strategy you would be you
should be able to tell him that he has
sort of he doesn't know what he's doing
because you really need to have an
answer to open-source as a decision
maker and IT these days the license
costs I will maybe touch on this later I
just that's just the tip of the iceberg
you're looking at scalability you're
looking at flexibility you're looking at
the velocity of innovation in your
organization that's what open source is
doing that's what public address fascias
across the EU are discovering there's
like tons of examples of this and so
it's good for a CEO for a decision-maker
to have a policy in place to say we're
currently not using it a lot
we're using it in the servers we're
using it in our data warehouses but we
should be using it across the stack so
this is where we are and this is where
we need to go like the EC they have a
policy like that they say let's say the
back off is a lot of open source at the
workstations some open source the target
is we should move to more open source
across the stack that's the policy and
then they can start disrupting parts of
the infrastructure say that's too much
proprietary we need to you know roll out
a switch program one of the main
strategic goals for CEO the last one is
a is basically a quote from Lea Maxwell
a few years ago the CEO for the UK
government it's taking control and get
rid of locking it's a main thing well as
I said there's tons of examples I've
arranged them here at levels of
government so you have the national
government the United Kingdom's the
digital services they have an
open-source lead she is looking at
currently she announced recently she's
looking at all the big applications out
there which are already developed under
an open-source license which is not the
same as saying you do them as
open-source because that would require
support and a road map and a community
and engagements with his community so
she's trying to fix that part of the
strategy in France you have a CIO who
has a big government modernization unit
dongsik they have a very good very solid
very well thought through policy on
openness which includes a lot of open
source of course
at a multi municipality there's a lot of
municipalities across Europe that
realize that they're doing the same as
their neighbor and they could be using
the same tools as the neighbor and
they're starting to work together I've
listed a few examples in Denmark you
have os/2 I think that has now 60% of
all municipalities and they are pooling
their budgets and it's making it a lot
cheaper and they're using a lot of
Drupal based web-based solutions and
they're rolling out fast and they will
pretty soon have maybe all of the
municipalities and their model is
challenging the traditional model of the
proprietary vendors and the proprietary
central sort of proprietary
decentralized government department
because here all of a sudden you see
municipalities working together solving
IT issues which actually solve public
administration issues and it goes much
faster than the central government
department that tries to bring this
top-down can-do Norway we have the
Kongsberg region near Oslo where they
are doing a lot of web-based services
that increasingly other municipalities
can use so its helpdesk its training its
calendaring and other solutions that
they host in their cloud and other
municipalities can say oh we have that
as well we need that as well here's a
bit of our IT budget because we would
like that feature to be implemented and
the group as a whole
starts fixing it Belgium a great example
email it has about 200 municipalities in
the french-speaking parts of Belgium
they're all working together on Python
and zopi based based solutions that's
like really great it's huge to go to
somebody at the municipality itself of
course Munich I will not have to talk
long about many here it's work world
famous a region
there's loads of regions in France or
several regions that do a lot on
open-source I just pointed out here the
Basque region by the way the slides are
already online and all these blue words
are links to directly to the author that
will show you the article where this is
based on the bus has a free
software policy they want to
do free software everywhere in the whole
stack for everything a bunch of years
ago the country the autonomous region
realized it was going to run out of
money and it gave their it gave their
staff the choice either we do something
about RIT because it's really expensive
or we start firing a bunch of people
watch which would you prefer so they
chose for the software but that maybe
makes sense and at an organizational
level
the Ministry of Finland I don't think
it's it's a very interesting for me very
important case but I think they've
rolled back they actually came back on
their decision but the bunch of years
ago ten years ago five years ago they
did a comparative study between
OpenOffice Microsoft Office and IBM
notes office or IBM office they ran the
cost comparison
they concluded that IBM would be the
cheapest they chose for OpenOffice
rolled it out and why why did they do
that why is this an interesting case
because they realized the free software
license gives you scalability and and it
gives you freedom to experiment that
they already were able to implement it
in a pilot program and it ran so well
and it implemented so easily and it was
maintainable so easily that before they
kind of made the decision process run
through the process they had already
installed it in the whole ministry and
that was something that they had never
experienced before and they liked it so
much that that's why they even though it
was maybe a bit more expensive than IBM
they they went for it
the CIO of the ministry did its PhD
thesis on this and they'll come back on
that because he made a few
recommendations that are in here the
second big thing that we need to do is
this is strange because you know I go
from CIO all of a sudden to a tool but
there is no real order in the sequence
we have to make Mozilla Firefox the
default browser
it's a complete open source browser at M
you a lot of governments are looked in
or maybe I should say we're locked in in
Internet Explorer they might be moving
away a lot of them are actually using
both Firefox and Internet Explorer
Internet Explorer is maybe on its way
out but it's still very dominant in
public administrations and it's not only
a way for a proprietary browser vendor
and operating system vendor and office
solutions vendor to lock in the public
administration but you have a lot of
service providers that say our solution
requires ie and it therefore they
piggyback on the lock-in and they can
keep milking the public administration
if they if they believe that they they
need to require ie so we need to force
public administrations to say Firefox is
the browser everything that has to work
through the web has to work through
Firefox Mozilla is also very active on
the open standards front and this will
be a way to reward that as I mentioned
it breaks the lock into ie a breaks lock
into a lot of proprietary technology an
anecdote would be a small Dutch town
that decided that this is what they
would do and they started the go shading
with all of their vendors saying okay we
have this web-based - we have that web
base - if you do not support Firefox we
will move to a different vendor and all
of the vendors started tooling around
there so far so that it would speak the
same things in Firefox it's available in
all operating systems so then you have
the freedom to say you want to use a Mac
go ahead use a Mac you want to use an
expectation go ahead use a Linux host
and that's what we need to do there's
tons of examples and sorry my notes are
not here so I'm going to miss a few
things so I remember that quite well the
Supreme Court of Slovenia it's a very
interesting example this is the main
court of the country they have people in
place that understand very well how this
thing works how lock-in works how
competition works and how the legal
system works and so they rolled out they
have complete open source workstations a
lot of them the country however that
this project is in trouble because the
minister that is doing public
administration is in the US every like
month every other other week and he
speaks to all the big vendors and then
they gave him a reward and they give him
a you know a medal and then they and he
comes back and he says Oh Cisco this or
HP that and it makes problems for public
administrations that that try to do the
right thing the ministry also realizes
that he is a small country and like one
of these big American firms makes more
money than the entire country they can
buy Slovenia main the biggest European
of the biggest European examples of the
French and armory I will not talk about
it long cuz I'll come back on it later
interesting is let's see which one here
interesting Aarhus in Denmark R which is
the second largest town of Denmark and
they are one of the main drivers behind
the O is too weird I mentioned a few
slides ago and so their policy for
Firefox is interesting Arnhem is
interesting because it had a huge fine
they had a pilot project that was going
to to figure out an open-source switch
Microsoft heard about this install the
network sniffer a license network
sniffer in the network
and the fine was in the millions and it
it rubbed the city of its of its
financial power to do the pilot so that
died the what is interesting in our
enemies that the councillor has a PhD in
computer science this whole house runs
on Debian so I hope that he will
continue to try this the bus country I
already mentioned
Munich is very famous and so in line
with making Mozilla the default browser
this is why open standards have to
become mandatory so this is very tricky
because you know now we have a debate
about what is open what is an open
standard and what's the definition so I
don't think I will do it here but we
need to be mindful of their definition
what can I say what what I would find
practical is that we should say that a
standard that is open it needs to be it
needs to be implementable in open-source
software that would make it open we
could require that the NOPA standard can
only be put on an open standards list by
any government by saying it needs to be
implemented actively implemented in an
open-source tool that would that would
bring threshold that some of the full
open standards are occurring out there
wouldn't be able to jump Oh XML is the
best example I think it's a standard
that we should not have allowed in i0 it
should be taken out of either that's my
personal opinion
but it's that use fake open standards
are making it really difficult for those
that try to use open standards that's
what we see in also time and time again
European Commission is one of its it's
here is a problem by itself because it
publishes a lot of documents and they
don't really understand at the right
level the importance of this document
format we keep telling them and
eventually we'll get through to the
right persons but they keep publishing
it in this non open centre that is
called an open Center which is not an
open Senate and it's making it really
painful for all those that are trying to
use our EF so you need to take care of
the selection process if you want to
know all the details
please look at Sweden they have figured
this out they have first they took the
Dutch list and the Dutch already made a
nice selection then the suite says ok so
we have to desist we need to make sure
that these are really open and so they
had to scientists Pierre Mendell and its
colleague
think
about so how what what does that mean
that means you need the community and
your needs to be an open process it
needs to be low threshold that everybody
should be able to pitch in now let's
look at this Dutch list and see which of
those actually have a community which
are actually made without financial
thresholds and then they read it down a
little list so it became a little bit
smaller that is a good list to start
with and you need to walk your talk I
already mentioned the Commission it says
it wants to do open standards it
believes strongly that open standards
will fix the lock-in and now we need to
get the Commission to commit to its own
statements and actually walk its talk
examples I a great example is the UK
they have a fantastically well thought
through open silence policy which is
really driving change in Great Britain
we it's hard to say that the effects are
already visible but they will become
very visible very soon
you I keep asking the GDS to send me
concrete examples and and that's slow
but it will come France already
mentioned a few slides ago also have a
very well thought through openness
policy open source sorry open standards
is a big part of that they have recently
published the RTI which is their list of
open standards which in in the first
version the first draft version had only
ODF and not oxm L there was a bit of
pressure not from the proprietary vendor
itself but from the public
administration's that are using this
fake open Center and so they put it back
on in the published version but they
said warning this standards has a lot of
proprietary links it's very unclear it's
very difficult we should you can only
use it for Excel and you can only use it
if there is no way you can you can
escape in your in whatever you did in
your excel sheet that you cannot use ODF
otherwise you should use ODF the
Netherlands I already touched on it they
have a good list to have a
standardization forum standardization
board that is also trying to drive
change the Dutch IT policy when you talk
about
this topic free and open source they say
look open standards are the thing that
is what we're going to implement all
over our public conversation and then
the change should come by itself to open
source because it's just the best way to
implement open source open standards
Sweden I mentioned the list and the
European Commission if you want to study
this more in detail they have the
sharing or use framework which is where
OHS are fitting and where open standards
are defined or we're trying to define a
per sentence we have the EIF where there
is an interesting debate about how to
define this thing that's where it takes
place and we have the cans which is a
monitoring process that will show you
which countries have which standards but
so there you can just pick out it for
example you will see the ODF is
basically in almost all Member States
and docx or XML is in a few like five or
six that's interesting the fourth main
thing we need to do we as groups that
are interested in this process or they
as public administration's is help the
organization change yeah it's it's like
this you have a proprietary workstation
income the open source people they take
away your proprietary workstation put in
place a taboo to workstation belieber
office and there you go for a public
administrator they don't understand what
we're doing because they say you replace
the stack with something that was
exactly the same why did you do that and
and then you have all the other problems
that the button isn't there like the
printer won't work and the telephone is
not connected and my calendar doesn't
think that you have all the little
technical things but they don't get why
we're replacing one stack for another we
need to communicate
the best way to drive this change is to
do really small-scale pilots and
convince the key people in those
organizations why this change is
important so that they can talk to their
colleagues when their colleagues are
like that's not working they can say
look it is working you just have to you
know click the other icon or fix it for
them
and communication is the key aspect you
need to talk and talk and talk and talk
and talk there now Regent PhD thesis on
the Ministry of Justice that was his
main conclusion you need in every
organisation what he called a innovation
champion somebody who can talk and
convince and fix and do and he will go
to your desktop and he will fix it on
the spot that he will go to the other
desktop and explain it to you 10 times
if necessary and he will convince
everybody in the organization why this
is a good thing communication is key
tons of examples both on the good side
and the bad side good for me update at
this moment the greatest example is not
Eric Fisher is the IT manager that has
set up the change amount he is the
change manager and he has been
publishing a lot and he's been talking
on conferences such as this one about
how to do this change justice ministry I
just ran ahead of myself clearly what is
an interesting example it's a good thing
here that my notes aren't clear the term
notes are invisible and after me for
memory the city of Munich they also
understood the importance of change and
they did the entire desktop as we all
know they had a whole bunch of things
they did newsletters leaflets brochures
workshops conferences for their staff to
convince them explain them they did
awards for you know make the best
picture of Munich and the best three
pictures will be the desktop def default
desktop images that you can choose from
when you start your Linux workstation
and that was this sounds cool to get
people involved in making pictures of
Munich but it was also a way for the IT
department to control the desktop
pictures
and there are plenty of reasons that you
want to control your desktop pictures to
make sure it's professional because not
all the staff will choose a professional
picture the defense ministry in in Italy
it's currently the largest European
maybe globally the largest rollout of
Libre Office on the desktop they use the
document foundation change management
manual and it that's a pretty it's at
the bottom it's a pretty good document
people should you organization should
use it as a template to consider okay
this might not entirely fit my
organization but these are the things I
need to do on the bad side the city of
Eden they had it's a Dutch town they had
it rolled out they were going to do the
whole stack they had everything on open
standards they had somebody convert all
their proprietary document formats to
ODF and now they're rolling it all back
what's the reason yeah I teach your IT
manager changed that in came a new IT
manager who had a whole bunch of things
that he needed to do and then he had all
these resistance in the desktops because
people were angry because I just
explained you have the desktop you
changed everything nothing works people
were frustrated he blames of course the
open source tools he doesn't blame the
change process and the easiest way to
get around this is but which is roll off
everything back and he calls his friends
and that's just the usual way to do
these things and I try to get in touch
with these people to figure out what is
wrong and then you you you just call
somebody in the in the city hall and
before you even start talking they
become frustrated yeah and these IT
people they just change your software
and they don't realize that things don't
work we have to do real work here it's
that kind of emotion that the CIO is not
going to deal with if the easiest thing
to do is oh you want the other tool fine
you get the other tool five work famous
example because they tried Libre Office
and then eventually roll back to
Microsoft Office there's one thing in
Fryeburg that's interesting is that they
all used Munich's template and document
and procurement process manager called
wall max
this is a tool that helps you generate
your forms it has the stamps that's the
seal the signature the whole thing and
if you do a procurement proposal it
fills in all the details that you need
to normally take into account and it did
it so well that it saved you a whole
bunch of time so when they went back to
Microsoft they said that chemical ease
please keep will mix that unfortunately
only works on LibreOffice so okay pain
points maybe they will go back
eventually all the other ones Italian
towns there's a whole bunch of them
Basel oh there's the first one Emilia
Romagna region and South Tirol province
they all stopped there Open Office
pilots I think it's key that it's
OpenOffice not Libre Office there's a
lot of rumors you want to talk to the
Italian people to hear the details but
you can say it's corruption you can say
it was false information you can say
it's a bunch of IT people that thought
of their career long term because having
libre office on your resume might not
get you in a job in the next career path
that you're choosing it did there's all
kinds of things to go on there the one
thing that happens with all these towns
is that they will start to break
procurement law again because soon they
will have to buy licenses and they will
ask for max of licenses the European
procurement laws do not allow you to
procure brands or products that set you
can procure Linux because it's a brand
but there are tons of people that can
send it to you and therefore that
doesn't inhibit competition it's a major
thing to note and you need to engage the
community that's the fifth point I think
it's also the last point now how do you
do that this is a headache for all the
public administrations here are a few
ways to fix it you make sure you require
open source skills the European
Commission like one or two months ago
did a call for IT staff and they really
asked through over and through whatever
they require that people have
experienced an open source the change
will come from it in if there's more
people that understand open source that
work for the Commission it'll become
easier to install open source tools
because these guys will say oh yeah but
we use this in Debian or we use that in
for Dora
that does it like this and before you
know it it'll be all over so when you do
your procurements you can also optimize
it for small and medium-sized companies
and do not require that the company has
50 million turnover the past five years
because that's maybe only two companies
that do this you can look at Sweden
again a good example for the way to were
learning how to organize this they do
frameworks that so they negotiate with
everybody and the negotiate on behalf of
all the public administrations and the
free - Swedish framework for open-source
has basically all the main big not big
small medium-sized companies that do
open-source services are in there
they're like tested and they were
approved and so a municipality doesn't
have to go through this whole selection
process itself it can just use the
framework and say I want this Drupal or
I want this Red Hat or I want this
fedora or whatever brand of open-source
product and they will get the surface
they can just say give me the the five
so service suppliers can send an offer
but they even have the independent
entrepreneurs in there so single person
companies can in that way get jobs the
public administration's helping them
roll out open-source and you need to
promote and facilitate open-source
developments and there are a whole bunch
of ways to do that we shall go to the
next slide and give you a few examples
the city of mount I already introduced
them that's one of the bigger cities in
France I think it's the 8th or the 6th
they first they realized by moving to
libre office we're saving an X amount I
think it was a million for ten thousand
desktops or some like that it doesn't
really matter that's money that
disappears from the IT budget but that's
like not a good thing for the IT
department so they said let's give them
30% and they can keep that for the next
year the next year so they can do other
things with the savings otherwise it's
like thank you for the savings and
that's not an incentive for the IT
department
and so that's one thing they can do
other interesting project but they also
said now we have LibreOffice and there's
a few things that don't work the right
way LibreOffice I'll give you a famous
itself an important example suppose you
have a legal document that does your
that fixes the houses and the land
around your house that you want to buy
yourself or if you're a farmer and you
have there's a whole bunch of
requirements and it's a bullet list and
then you send it to the next level the
prophets and for them all of us on this
changed into a numbered list it will
lose the legitimacy it will lose the
value this is a problem and in document
interoperability problem that really
makes it difficult for public
administrations to use the mix of Oh X
ml and ODT this is like but the big
headache announced that okay so let's do
a procurement proposal where we will fix
this and a few other problems that we
have and we will return the fixed
product to the upstream of the office so
they're working
I think the procurement is was launched
last year it's it went to a consortium
two companies including Cola Borah one
of the libreoffice developers and so
they are fixing this upstream and this
is a fantastic example of how public
administrations realize that their use
of our tax money actually benefits not
only then but it benefits every other
public administration and every other
citizen across the world if we want to
go further than European Union and that
fixes that day that nantes fix are now
fixed for people in Denmark to unique is
I think in Europe the biggest public
administration that contributes two main
open-source projects if you look at all
the code then the Commission will win
but that's maybe a different battle but
at the city level Munich is by far the
biggest day contribute well it's right
the notes are not there after this my
memory you'll forgive me if I have it
wrong but there's they have 500 patches
or no patches into Libre Office they use
I think Libre Office for and their
patches are in upstream in five but they
have a few issues why they can't upgrade
itself so they have fixed the office for
those code improvements are available to
all of us in five
they have wool mix the template manager
that I mentioned they have an
implementation manager they have tools
to manage the rollout upgrade and
implementation of workstations there's
there's a whole bunch then take the
French government modernization units
one of the ways in which they organize
this is in hackathons I can say a few
nice things about those things it was
France has they open-source the tax code
they also open sourced the code that
selects which student goes to which
universities and in both cases it was a
sort of a same Drive let's do the
student example first so this year or
last year the student allotment system
had a few glitches and there were
student unions that were trying to
figure out why this didn't work the way
it should have worked and they started
asking the members in Parliament and
they started asking the minister and the
minister gave answers and then they they
looked at and it doesn't make sense
because that's he says but that's not
what happened
can you send us how this is done send us
the source code and then the Minister
printed the source code and gave them
the source code
this is ridiculous so it's no way we can
check this so then eventually the whole
government realized okay so we need to
check we need to you we need to start
considering source code the way we
consider data we need to publish it if
you need to make it machine readable and
available because we this is how we do
openness this is how we are being
checked by the citizens these days and
it changed the law so now in France if
you want to know an algorithm that is
used in your process you can go to a
course and say can I have that cold
please doesn't really make it available
as open source but it's a start and the
other example is the text code where
what are the guys that worked at then
SiC on a Friday afternoon had you know
his tasks ran out he was an intern and
he said you know what I'll just see if I
can maybe improve the the income-tax
application and so he started digging
and it's a long story and he had to go
to court like two or three times and the
minister said no it is like way too
complex because
it runs on faxes and it runs on PDP's
and it runs it doesn't you know we can't
give it to you or floppy and and then
the minute the the guys that overruled
that decision say yeah technically
difficult that's not a good answer
so you know make it so eventually the
text source code also became available
as open source and so they organized
hackathons where they they asked these
people the use and the means to come to
the Ministry and then look at the code
and see if we can do something more
interesting with it and it's a great
example France is leading here it would
be nice if others do the same main
implementations I will speed up because
I think most of these are known for you
and the most running out of time and
maybe there should be some time for
questions I've arranged it in three big
parts because this is the desktop room
so you have the main complete desktop
operating system implementations then
you'll have the ones that basically do
Libre Office and then I have an annex
which are all the others which I would
do if you want the city for another hour
or something so operating systems and
office productivity the first one 72,000
workstations across all the gendarmerie
in France they everywhere here everybody
always says price it's the first thing
they say but the French also make is
very clear that price yeah that's nice
interesting it lowers the total cost of
ownership by 40 percent but man does it
make it much easier for us to do IT on
workstations his open-source stuff we
should have done this years ago they had
a guy he would fly to Australia and then
fly to an island in the Pacific and then
had to go to an island by canoe and then
by ferry and then he had to visit all
these islands to update the police posts
antivirus definitions he would come back
he would make it to Paris and they would
give him a new desk set of city rooms
and he could go back again he would be
gone all the time
fantastic job I would love to have it
but with the window which is what they
use they don't need that because it
rolls out automatically and
Isis whole virus thing is much less of a
headache they also they this they say
our eating steak is much easier because
we can control everything and it is P
now we program it here and it rolls out
across the whole gendarmerie 72,000
desktops yeah about almost it says here
I have 41 minutes and so and they say
it's priceless to be to get rid of
you're looking the second one is city of
Munich that's 18,000 desktops also MINIX
and LibreOffice the city of Saragossa
which is 1200 it's a fragile process
these are a few like a handful of people
that are doing this and they're under an
enormous amount of time pressure and
using all their free time to do this a
quick list of the ones that are doing
Libre Office or OpenOffice but it's
mostly Libre Office
so first the ministries in France has
500 thousands of there's half a million
and they really use it I've checked
there's a few times over the past few
weeks they read it's their first it's
the only operating system office suite
on those desks it's 17 of the 33
ministries and in the Dutch central
government that's all about a hundred
thousand that number is not entirely Shh
they couldn't really know they couldn't
really tell me how much they have but
this is the total number of central
government civil servants and they all
have access to it
Ministry of Defense Italy that's going
to be a hundred thousand workstations
with Libre Office it will make it the
biggest one Extremadura this project I
put it here because it's famous but it's
broken
these numbers are no longer valid and
they're rolling it all back to Libre to
Microsoft I'm trying to figure out
what's going on but that's basically a
dead project to lose 10,000 workstations
bust country 8,000 workstations the
police in Lithuania 8,000 workstations
down to 5,000 so this is the
I'll skip the annex the key policies
that you need to look at if you're
interested I already introduced France
so that's the one the other one is you
know take the United Kingdom's there
open source
sorry open standards policy and Bulgaria
also famous because they managed to get
into law that all code developed for and
by public registration from day one must
be done on a repository which will be
mirrored to get hub this is the way to
do it
for for a public administration you
hosted on your own repository and you
link it to get it keep it on the console
you expected benefits how much salary I
still have minutes I'm sorry
I'll just this is one more slightly
expected benefits it's clear for all of
us here autonomy sovereignty and control
the efficiency in the growth that's an
important one the growth of local
enterprises it really happens in France
and in the bus country you can see this
so what's missing this is the last slide
we need more politicians that know how
this works we need more politicians that
realize these are the benefits and these
are the disadvantages of proprietary and
we need well-organized the focus e so
this is slowly happening but it's not
there yet and we need patches for
procurement because procurement in
Europe is really broken and it's in
favor of proprietary and that needs to
be fixed ASAP and that's it
thank you very much
[Applause]