right now so we could start with the
next presentation we're going to hi my
name is Bhavik Roddick I work at Samsung
currently Institute Poland I'm a member
of
Tyson common Linux distribution release
team and since my occupation I am
involved in lots of testing lots of
verification and validation of system
images for embedded Linux devices today
I would like to be your guide through a
setting up of your own lava laboratory
because that's something we need to
automate most of our work and to focus
on much more interesting tasks that we
have to do in our daily jobs I will
start with a short introduction to what
lava actually is then I will move to the
main section which is actual setup of
the laboratory I would like to share
with you some tools that we used as well
to simplify your work even further
next I will give you some hints what can
be done next
and if there's time we'll have a short
Q&A session and some final thoughts
so what lava actually is lava stands for
in our automated validation architecture
and serves as an automation system for
deploying operating system and not only
embedded into devices but also any kind
of analyte or virtual device it
can't deploy what a fast car now little
be anything that is needed to boot up
your device once it prepares your device
it allows you to run boot boot loader or
even system level tests on your device
but some extra hardware might be
required for the full support of all our
features and one actually does it come
in handy in the simplest use case well
do just a single boat for example began
born black which is reference device for
many on open source projects it's easy
to manage just one on your desk also
with just a single instance you don't
have to worry about managing resources
of your miniature boat forms but sooner
or later you might come across some new
interesting target devices you would
like to support for your open source
project for example Arctic 10 in top
left corner or a droid check Co 3 on the
bottom that's when things might get
complicated
adding to that even new architecture
like me no BOTS which run on Intel based
chip might complicate it even further
because all of these devices have to be
flashed in a completely different way
and support different communication ways
between your test server and your actual
device what if you'll have to complicate
things even more and have to manage a
whole build farm or whole boat from
actually with multiple instances of each
of your device well
that's where lava comes into place and
because it provides an abstraction layer
for the whole board form this way all
the complex device management is put
onto the lava itself and is no longer in
your own task also so many different
devices have various capabilities it
would be much easier if you don't have
to worry about finding an actual device
that supports all the capabilities you
need for tests and with lava you can
only define what do you need and this
way if your board farm has proper device
you'll get what you request it also you
don't have to worry about scheduling and
dispatching multiple tasks on numerous
devices so if you would like to paralyze
all of your tests and get your results
quicker
that's what lava I can provide you and
what you'll get out of the box is an
unified device environment so each
developer does not see boat anymore it
just general device which can be flushed
with operating system image and which
can get some tests to run and all the
developer sees is just a bunch of
results that he gets with no worries
about mmm
flashing device about running running
tests on them or how to get results back
also the
direct connection to the devices is
still available in lava
for example we are hacking sessions or
both overseer but these topics more
complex than just setting up which will
be focusing on today lava is currently
in used in use by multiple projects by
multiple companies for example by
leonora for the bot farm in Cambridge by
colonel CI
for the tests of current colonel trees
by automotive grade Linux and the Debian
as for Linux distributions so once we
realize - what can we get from on lava
laboratory let's go to the actual setup
for just for start it's the best to
focus on standalone instance with no
remote workers with no distributed
environment standalone instance will
allow to get the most of lava as quickly
as possible we also focus just on the
virtual devices and the tests that
should be run at the beginning should be
as simple as possible
just health checks if nothing else comes
to you during the setup one is that we
need to reduce the complexity of the
whole process also it's best to
familiarize with possibly new workflow
of your testing automation procedures by
not going
some caveats of specific boats but
having just a virtual devices also it's
much easier to understand
lava concepts when you have the water
stirred and quickly to set up
environment on your hands and lastly
although lava will allow you to reuse
your current test cases it's best to
open the process of learning the new way
of running your tests on the lava board
form as for requirements for your own
lava laboratory the only one is to have
Debian based machine currently support
for Ubuntu is frozen
more details you can find in the link on
the presentations but for now any Debian
instance that you have to spark will be
sufficient exactly that's the host if
you'd like to other distribution on the
actual device under tests
I believe currently open embedded Fedora
Debian are supported out-of-the-box and
other distributions will require a
little tinkering as for other
requirements that you need to set it up
of course system image for your Linux
bot and some healthcheck job which
together with system image is already
provided in lava by leonora also device
type temp
and for qmu which will focus today it's
already available in lava in default
lava distribution as well and actually
the only and a file that you would need
to set it up is device dictionary which
serves as a definition of the instance
of your device and for qmu it's just
three lines yuo see on the bottom which
only gives you an info which the vast
template should be in use assign mac
address and set an available memory
thanks to the lava packagers all you
have to do on your host machine is to
prepare data base for the lava and let
install the metal package package all
you need further is resolved
automatically with dependencies as for
the common post install tasks default
Apache configuration is already
available as well and if you disable
default pages and and replace it with
lava server configuration with enabling
of two additional modules for Apache
you're all set to go
as for the host configuration of course
you all have to create super user for
your lava laboratory and finally
actually other devices adding the
devices consists of three steps first of
all you have to add device type to our
lava laboratory with the first
command on the but then you have to
inform your level laboratory about a new
instance of your device and finally and
define all the remaining information
about your virtual boat instance with
three line file you saw earlier actually
two more things are to be done to have
the whole system fully operational
you'll have to assign a worker for the
for your device and define a health
check
so that lava can always verify that the
device is fully operational once this is
done you're good to go you may safely
submit your test cases lava supports
both CLI interface for the automation of
the whole process as well as web UI for
quick tests if you would like to check
your new changes quickly having it
already set up you might consider some
notice I would like to propose to you
which may make your future deployments
easier quicker and safer having it all
in a reproducible way first art I would
like to show you the configuration
management suite for lava it it is
equally well
whichever tool you like so if you prefer
salt stock chef puppet or ansible it it
won't matter as long as you'll have a
producible environment for all of your
future deployments and the same exact
configuration on both your testing
environment and your production
environment so choose your personal
favorite and other boroughs should be
published for setting up the for a
virtual just starting lava instance in a
next couple of days as for the
environment virtualization which I
believe you will be interested in having
for your first lava instance you might
choose from different virtualization
providers I would like to propose to
depending on how much time to have and
how much flexibility do we need from the
provider itself if you need to have set
up really quickly vagrant would be your
choice it allows you to bring up new
instances instantly and it provides you
with wide range of credit machines by
Atlus service but do be careful with
pre-built images since you have no
control on what actually is on the
system image and if you would like to
tinker mode to adjust it to your needs
you all might consider levert currently
maybe one of the most flexible tools for
these kinds of tasks still
it with really user friendly above CLI
and GUI tools once you have it all set
up you might consider your next steps
and one of the possible follow-ups to
setting up new level laboratory and it
could be adding completely new device
types to lava this time actual devices
physical devices and all the
documentation for doing so is already
available you might also be interested
in writing your own tests or migrating
your current test cases to lava devote a
lava documentation you're covered as
well but if you'd be more interesting in
contributing to some other project you
might consider adding your lava instance
to the kernel CI project you know what I
believe you would also benefit from
familiarizing with both a GL test
framework set of instructions and with
documents that civil infrastructure
platform testing initiative prepared and
if you'd prefer to watch and listen
instead of waiting you might be
interested in these three talks a little
more detailed introduction to a lava
veto by Bill Fletcher
all having direct access to your devices
within the laboratory instance by three
electrons you also could benefit from
the next presentation that is right
after this one
by young similar of course if you
wouldn't need any help
and if further help the exhaustive
documentation is already available at
each instance of lava laboratory and if
you'd like some direct contact our users
show their questions on mailing list
either on mailing list you know - lava
IRC channel on freenode - solid rock to
sum it all up I hope that I showed you
that initial setup of lava laboratory is
pretty easy thanks to already in place
package repositories for Debian platform
and that setup is instant once you know
what to expect and what do you have to
prepare before also an environment
unification for a various device type
the types is something that you might
benefit from in your automated testing
process and wherever you get power test
execution with no cost and you don't
have to manage all of their devices by
yourself and also developers do not have
to worry about managing devices all by
themselves those responsibilities can be
moved to the Java laboratory operators
and as for the final thoughts I would
like to share with you is that
though it might seem intimidating at
first with such an exhaustive
documentation as levar has it actually
has no downsides when y'all get through
it or you have someone who got through
it earlier and shares just a quick start
you'll get everything you need
also there is absolutely no need to
reinvent the wheel with modern testing
laboratory management and software it's
already there just waiting for you to
use it and although the initial cost
might be high if you're not familiar
with all these tools for automation and
always price off in a long term if you
have some questions I would be more than
happy to answer them since we've got
still few minutes yeah hi
so it's great that you're yeah sure so
good job
I believe so but I am not experienced
user enough to answer your question
fully I believe that so you would have
to add two different devices and if the
child one has direct access that there
would be no trouble in that and if it
has not so maybe some talent following
through the parent device will be
required as well if there is no more
question thank you for your attention
[Applause]
you