yeah hello everyone thank you so hello
I'm Andrea from University of Leipzig
and today I'm going to talk about
frequent subgraph mining on Apache flink
which I just hide behind the title of
from shopping baskets to structural
patterns because it's kind of related to
something some of you might know from
the term of a shopping basket and edit
analysis or Association rules so first
of all my question who view regulatory
works with graphs and with Taita mining
or reciter Mining yeah and and cross
anti-de mining only alright so there so
alright so I slowed down a little bit
and yet I try Q to make the talk not too
much scientific and rather give you a
problem introduction and challenges in
the implementation on Apache fling core
and distribute the data flows in general
so the contents are as follows
first I introduced the problem and
explained details about the current
state of this of these algorithms then I
proposed a solution which we found on
top of a patch of link in the context of
the group framework not a question who
was attending the talk before so all
right quite a lot so all right so um
yeah it's it's in the context of an open
source framework for distributed graph
analytics called khru loop and finally I
talked a little bit about about some
optimizations of our solution if I find
the time and of course conclude so part
one is the problem
so the general beta mining class of data
mining problems is called a frequent
pattern mining so and we are talking
about the transactional setting which
means we have a collection of things for
example shopping baskets click streams
XML documents chemical compounds
whatever it's just depends on the data
structure but we have a collection of
let's say data sets which might have
different structures and infrequent
pattern mining we're interested in the
patterns that for example occur in 80
percent of these things and the frequent
pattern mining can be categorized into
the basic ones the frequent itemsets
mining for example shopping baskets
where we just interested in which things
frequently co-occur together then we can
if we add a constraint that seek mmm the
order of items matters then we have
frequent sequence mining for example a
clickstream we're interested in which
paths on a website go uses regulary or
something like that then we can again
extend it if we also consider branching
of path then we are at frequent subtree
mining which is a little bit more
difficult in sequence mining but still
very closely related to these things and
then at the end if we are also
interested in all the relationships so
trees might have may have closing cycles
and stuff like that then we have the
problem of frequent subgraph mining and
an example are chemical compounds so
let's first go back to the simple
variation of this problem some of you
might know Association rules that this
is something like people who brought and
brought bread and butter often bought
cheese and wine so we can use this for
recommendations that's what some web
shops do I guess for example if you
already added two items to your shopping
basket and Amazon for example then one
way to recommend you other things is
using Association rules which are based
on the results of frequent pattern
mining on past data sets in the frequent
subgraph mining we can use it for
similar things for example if we know
that a substructure often occurs in
legal stimulants and we have an unknown
chemical substance which contains a sub
structure which is known to be often
part of illegal stimulants we can have a
look on this substance if it's maybe
it's a candidate for a new illegal
stimulant I don't know if this example
makes sense but I hope you get the idea
so the problem definition just to
conclude the introduction is our input
is a graph collection so our collection
of things in this case our graphs and we
have a min support rash hold which
specifies the minimum percentage of
items of
such a things which have to contain a
pattern to be considered to be frequent
and the output is the complete set of
frequent subgraph patterns which are
supported above the given threshold so
them in support and to pray wait just
give you a toy example on the bottom I
hope it's with bull for most of you guys
know so on the bottom and just and just
believe me there there are three graphs
this is often called a graph database
and yeah Fairview I mean it's smaller
but now more people enjoy the fun on
seeing the graphs so this is the input
it's a graph collection so we see the
first I need to tell you in our problem
scenario in the context of groups we are
talking about directed multigraphs which
is a difference to typical solutions so
which means our edges have a direction
like also in graph databases like near
future and our we support multiple edges
between any pair of vertices which is
which changed the problem a little bit
from the algorithmic point of view and
yeah then we have now with three graphs
and we're interested in sub graphs and
which we can describe by patterns so a
sub graph just to not confuse you a sub
graph is a part of the graph and we're
interested in such sub graphs which
occur in at least 50 percent so in two
of three and typical algorithms use the
abstraction of a frequent pattern
lettuce so which contains different
levels in the first level there are all
0 H sub graphs which means just vertices
and we see we have a vertex a here and a
or curious in this graph in this graph
and in that one this is we have a
frequency of 3 the same for B frequency
of 3 we have C frequency of 1 because it
only contains in this one and that we
can say alright it's not a
the threshold of 50% which would be two
and that's we can prune it so now we
continue and grow children from that we
have for example a ap a BB or this loop
pattern and they have their children of
the 0h patterns and we still see okay
this one has a frequency of three one
and two one is below the threshold
that's what we can prune it and finally
if that's the largest frequent subgraph
contained we have this 2h sub graph
which is contained in two graphs at k
tune this is T actually does the desired
result but it's not and we do not
implement it as a data structure it's
just the theoretical model behind these
algorithms and from the data structure
point of view of course we have graphs
and we have patterns which we need to
store somehow but the most important
thing are embeddings it's very similar
to the previous talk with the pattern
matching so we need embeddings which
mapped the patterns to two actual sub
graphs and in this case we can we see
that due to Otto morphisms so a graph
might contain a pattern multiple times
which means this pattern is contained in
this graph two times so once it's the
Green Line so this vertex is this vertex
and this vertex is this one and because
this this vertices cannot be
distinguished by their pattern we create
a second embedding because of that so
this is everything you need to know
before I start explaining the algorithms
so we have graphs which are the input
elements we have sub graphs which are
parts of the input elements we have
patterns which are notes and our pattern
letters which are isomorphic to sub
graphs so isomorphic means there is a
one-to-one mapping between vertices and
edges and this is the tricky point of
these algorithms the same as pattern
matching and we have embeddings which
are mappings between patterns and sub
graphs and the challenges in
implementing such algorithms especially
in the context of shared-nothing
clusters is that we need to meet the
dataflow programming model in this case
of Apache flink but this also applies to
a Patras
park or actually even Map Reduce and
what we need to find is an efficient
algorithm which does not rely on shared
memory and I hope don't want to become
too scientific now so I just explain
your algorithm efficiency the problem of
these algorithms is they contain the so
called sub graph isomorphism problem
which is np-complete
we need to enumerate all isomorphisms
between graphs actually where this very
expensive and we cannot avoid this
completely if we want to have the
complete set of frequent sub graphs it's
not possible to avoid this problem but
what efficient algorithms can do to
minimize the isomorphism testing effort
so let me explain you the most of this
work has been done in the early 2000s
and but not in the context of
distributed data flow systems but for
single machines so there were a priori
approaches these are based on a so
called breadth-first search in the
lettuce BFS which means we process first
all frequent sub graphs of level 1 then
generate candidates do pattern matching
in the graph database find out frequent
ones and join the frequent ones to two
children and then we again do the
pattern matching and repeat this until
there are no frequent sub graphs left
the good thing about this these
algorithms is that they only need one
iteration per level and it's allows a
very effective frequency pruning but the
problems of these algorithms are they
contain the sub graph isomorphism
testing in a pattern matching they
contain additionally sub graph
isomorphism testing in the candidate
generation so when you have to frequent
patterns you want to generate the child
you need to enumerate all sub graphs of
a certain level to generate children
which is also very expensive
you may generate candidates that don't
even occur in a database because there
are just candidates there's no guarantee
for them to to a cure and the candidate
generation itself is hard to paralyzed
without shared memory because you need
actually you need to build the cross
product of all
combination it's yeah just a lot of
combinations this is why the more
efficient a single machine approaches
are based on a depth-first search in a
lattice which means this is the BFS and
this is the DFS they need they go from
let's say from this pattern this is
let's say the root pattern to to this
pattern then go to this and the until no
more frequent patterns are found then
they jump back to a frequent parent and
and so on and so on and the idea behind
these algorithms is that we can skip
some of the links in a lattice due to
specific tricks which I will not explain
now because this then really takes a lot
of time but it's possible with these
algorithms to avoid checking all the
combinations so and the idea is we have
an edge wise extension of frequent
patterns and the growth rules can reduce
the search to retrieve for example
there's a G span algorithm as some very
popular example of of this category the
problem is where the item is amorphous
and still occurs is that sometimes we we
don't want to visit for example this
edge and or link in the lattice but we
accidentally a wizard it this this is
why we need to we need to check the
graph representation if it's really a
valid if it's really on this tree that
we wanted to find so we look at these
algorithms okay it automatically finds
canonical labels which means we do not
we can compare them graph patterns by a
simple string comparison the isomorphism
testing is reduced to a minimum we just
need to validate these labels which is
the end we only checked patterns that
actually exist so we solved a lot of the
problems of the a priori algorithms but
a problem is we need a large number of
iterations for that and it can lead in a
shared nothing cluster rich with many
many many many workers it can lead to
unbalanced parallelization because we
can maybe paralyze a single paths but
not a whole level the more idea of the
new data flow systems is to bring the
computation to the data which means
processing all the for example all the
embeddings
of the same edge count at the same time
and this is not easily possible with
this DFS approach come back to our toy
example we see this is why I use dotted
lines for some of the links in the
lattice so the a priori approaches would
go all the links or there are even some
optimizations which maybe skip some but
still this is the basic difference and
in a pattern growth one we can just
leave out the dotted ones okay so now
this is everything you need to know
about frequent subgraph mining and the
research in the past and now we we are
facing these problems in the context of
distributed data flow systems on
shared-nothing clusters and the solution
to this problem is something we call a
level wise pattern growth which means we
just do a parallel depth-first search in
the lattice twins we process the lattice
level wise but but still skip the links
we do not want to visit and still avoid
the isomorphism problem due to change at
candidate generation for example and
this means we only need kmx iterations
which is the maximum edge count of the
largest frequent pattern and can skip
these links and we still minimize
isomorphism testing and this approach
fits the data flow programming model
very well I will show you the using some
pseudo code how we can implement this on
a patch of link so for all who don't
know a patch of link the basic
attraction is you have data sets and
then you have transformations on these
data sets which where an high order
function is a parameter and it's similar
to lambda expressions but for data sets
and the idea is that the function is
executed for each element of a data set
or for group of elements for example so
but there's no they completely run
concurrently are executed concurrently
and all things which require global
knowledge exchange I need to artificial
artificial
I need to create a careers in the data
flow to exchange global knowledge so
that's the the problem in the
shared-nothing context and what you
would do in a usual programming language
okay you know these constraints but the
native programming would be there would
be a data set of graphs there would be a
data set of all frequent patterns and
there would be a data set of kedge
frequent patterns that's all all the
data sets we need and then we have a
loop which terminates until we do not
find any K edge frequent parents anymore
and at the end we're interested in all
frequent patterns that's what our
algorithm should do what can we do for
example we do a pattern growth in the in
the beginning which means in which we
use something called broadcasting and
think it's like a very efficient cross
product in a distributed data flow we
just sent all K last iterations frequent
patterns to all machines and then we can
access them in the pattern growth step
and initially it's empty so this is the
dummy route in the lattice we apply the
pattern growth using a map function
which means we update the graphs because
we not only the graph dataset does not
only contain grass it also contains a
map in between patterns and embeddings
so which means in the pattern grow step
we just check the map all the keys which
are also contained in the frequent
pattern set we need to grow and then the
next step we report the patterns so
after we grew patterns we report them
using flat Maps flat map is is a like
map function but can be an arbitrary
cardinality output so it could output 0
or many patterns then we it now it
becomes a little relational we group by
patterns so it's just the key or it's
very similar to the reduce function of
Map Reduce we just group by key we sum
the frequency we filter out frequent
ones and we additionally need to filter
Bell at once because sometimes there are
some false positives and we found out in
our evaluations that it's far more
efficient to group and filter
invalid patterns instead of validating
them in this step because in this step
we have to validate for each graph and
each pattern and here we only have to
validate for each pattern in the whole
system which means imagine we have an
input size of like ten millions of
graphs we do not repeat the same
operations ten million times but do it
here and this is in comparison to the
complexity of counting a large data set
it's it's basically free
yeah and finally we add the current
rounds frequent patterns to the all
frequent patterns data set using a Union
operator and that's that's how natively
everyone would program it but a problem
is that
Flinx iteration it's a dataflow
iteration it's not like a typical while
loop it's something related to the batch
API of Apache flink it allows only
exactly one data set to be passed along
iterations and problem is here we have
actually we have three data sets which
which we manipulate during our
iterations so in but there is a
constraint that from iteration body we
cannot access these data sets so this
doesn't work so the first one the fpk
there's a quite simple solution to that
we just pull it out of the iteration and
repeat us a little bit and just
instantiate the set of KH frequent
patterns inside the loop so we do not we
can avoid the external access but this
does not work for the for this Union
operation and our data set collecting
all the frequent patterns of all
iterations this is where we use them
very hacky approach we just at the
beginning of the data flow we added to
the graph data set a new empty graph
element which is um which is actually
and it's an empty graph with an empty
map and because it's an empty graph and
we ensure that it's the only empty graph
in the whole data set we can identify it
and then we extend this map function not
only we do not only apply pattern growth
but pattern growth or store so we just
check if the graph is empty we can
use its pattern embeddings map to store
frequent patterns so because we can
reuse we don't need any additional data
structure we could just used in the data
structure we already have and at the end
we filter out this single dummy graph
which was collecting all the frequent
patterns and use a flat map which
creates a new pattern element in the
output dataset including its frequency
frequency we also can encode in the
mappings and have the same result so
this really works there was a solution
to our problem okay so this was the the
basic idea how we hope you understand
the problem and how we implemented this
on a distributed data flow system like
Apache flink and now we did some
optimizations to this problem so
actually there are four of them and
because two of them are very difficult
to explain without becoming too
scientific we just skip them so one is
it's even more efficient to do the
validation step in the combined function
because it matters to have fewer tuples
before you network traffic this course
is for everyone's programming with
distributed data flow systems it seems
obvious and we use a merge-join
instead of a cross - during the pattern
growth process but this needs a lot of
explanation now but what we also do we
do a pre-processing where we use
dictionary and code a dictionary
encoding and label pruning to reduce the
input size and the most efficient thing
is we do a pattern encoding and with a
fast and effective compression technique
so the pre-processing
idea is basically we keep only vertices
with frequent labels then if we if we
remove them we also remove some edges
and then we consider only the remaining
edges which are not which never occur in
Congo with frequent labels frequent
vertices and also count their
frequencies and we can also drop all the
edges with infrequent labels and based
in in these steps we have the
frequencies and all the labels so we can
just reduce them to create dictionaries
between strings and integers and because
the frequent sub graph mining
maintains a lot of comparison equality
hash code building whatever that's it's
it's much more efficient to use integer
labels and set of strings and the
workflow is then as follows we first
encode graphs we process the actual
mining and we decode the patterns
because in many scenarios we we do not
want patterns consisting of numbers we
just we really want our patterns like
RDF patterns for example so just to
explain this approach we see here
there's a vertex seal which contains
it's only contained in a single graph
and we see here is a edge labeled B
which if we only consider the edge label
it's it's still frequent because it
contains in here and here but if we
first remove this C guy then this p1 to
preserve consistency with gout U and B
is not frequent anymore and if we do
this in a pre-processing these patterns
will never be discovered and the second
optimization technique is the pattern
encoding and compression so we do not
store the graphs in a typical way as you
natively would program graphs using Java
objects and so on because we found out
that avoiding Java objects is one of the
most efficient tuning techniques you can
do in a patch of link this is at least
for this scenario so we use multiplexed
integer arrays to represent patterns and
graphs and embeddings we represent
everything in multiplex integer arrays
which require K times so the edge count
we need six positions in the array for
each edge and we know that we only have
positive values and we have very low
upper bounds of the values so the upper
bound is each count or the size of the
label dictionaries and typically we do
not exceed four to eight bits for this
case I say just typically of course you
can create datasets where it's different
but just say in the most use cases
that's enough this is much less than 32
bits which is usually required for a
single integer so we can use an integer
compression and we can roughly in our
data sets
encode a complete edge from six to one
integers in this case which and we use
simple 16 from this nice open source
package for this and the effect of this
is we decrease network traffic because
the patterns are traveled over the
network are smaller we have a smaller
grouping key in the group by operation
which means this is notably faster and
also the map access when we access the
embeddings of our patterns that we have
much smaller map keys so also this is
more efficient then additionally we
experimented with graph and embedding
compression to mainly to decrease memory
usage and to allow fastest a realization
between transformations and this is also
something we have learned this really
matters in a patch of link and the
decompression we execute only on demand
for example and beddings
of infrequent patterns will never be
decompressed and so on though there are
a lot of detailed optimizations yeah
then we did some optimized evaluations
so we used I do not talk about absolute
run times now because it doesn't make
sense if you do not have any background
knowledge about the datasets and was it
mean but what we did here in these
experiments we have two datasets one is
synthetic 2 we have 1 million grafts 90
percent support but it gives already a
lot of patterns this dataset and
contains directed multi graphs and the
classical scenario which is used by all
other work in the field of frequent sub
graph mining so molecular data set with
undirected simple graphs with 1 million
graphs and 10 percent support so it has
a quite low support and it said it's 1
million molecules it's mean with other
types of data you can have big data
problems with much larger input sizes
but here the problem is the are the
intermediate results and computing
complexity so we see we used this data
set and scale up from 6 to 96 threats
which is roughly the same as 1 to 16
nodes in a cluster machines and we see
that especially on this synthetic data
set for which we we optimized our
argumentum for directed multigraphs
it's shows we're quite good scale-up and
for the even for the molecular database
its it's not bad it's not linear and
it's a but still quite good and then we
also evaluated the impact of our
optimizations so depending on the data
set in this data set again we created
many many infrequent labels that this
technique is very efficient too of
course but there are maybe there are
real-world data sets such like RDF for
example which have these characteristics
which we consider at the design of this
synthetic data set so we see that
overall scale abilities all parallelism
levels so from six to ninety six
parallel slots we see that the
dictionary encoding in this case can
slow down the total run time by up to
400% then we just avoided pattern
compression so we only use the integer
representation which is already like ten
times faster than using strings
this goes brings is a notable effect
especially on the molecular database the
embedding compression still has a
notable impact we probably due to the
serialization time but graph compression
it's it's a little tuning effect but
there it's not too much all right
so conclusion what we did is the first
approach to graph collection frequent
sub graph mining using an in-memory data
flow system they are MapReduce
approaches but in this kind of system by
best of our knowledge we were first and
we support direct with multi graphs from
arbitrary string labeled inputs or you
can just enter a string labeled input
file and you get string labeled a
patterns we do not need to do any
external pre-processing it works but
using flink requires some workarounds as
is you have seen and we think it's a
much better choice than MapReduce
because in each iteration you have to
update three data sets and this is some
this is also from MapReduce you also
need workarounds to solve these problems
but these MapReduce workarounds are by
far more expensive than the workarounds
you need for the
laughs link based approach and the
availability of the it's part of the
group framework this distributed
framework for cross processing it's it
fits its algorithm API the current
version you will find in the master
branch it's not optimized it's still
using Java objects and strings and stuff
like that so it's not very efficient and
the optimized version is still a messy
research prototype but will be merged to
the mrsa soon so thank you know we have
the problem is the availability of such
data sets so we have a data generator
which creates this type of theta but
this is why we use the synthetic data
set which contains loops parallel edges
some some many autumn or physics yeah
[Music]
yeah yeah but yeah molecule data of
course I have there are tons of
molecular data sets but the thing is
that they do not in molecule datasets
you have only two types of edges it's a
single a single bound and double bound
you have a very limited set of vertex
labels and it's very they're a very low
number of specific patterns that are
cure like you have at some cycles so
molecule of course you can tune the
algorithm to molecule databases but it's
we wanted to make a general approach
fitting all the data sets and because we
have no data set