thank you
to start talking as usual I was
finishing my slides just five minutes
before the talking starts which means
that I never finished had my stuff my
phone which is quite okay because I
never actually finished anything that I
started like I'm still ten years on the
university no twelve sorry and when I
started doing programming I was five
years old because my dad is crazy and I
grew up I started doing other stuff and
one day I was seated in my computer
trying to program and I saw this and
this was an invitation for cute
developers to start trying to port an
application that was initiated by Linus
Torvalds using CNG GK and man I was
thrilled because well as as a kid I
always wanted to actually start
programming with my heroes of
programming like I am honored for my
whole life and I had my first computer
when I was 2 or 3 years old it was an
Atari I don't even know if they make
them anymore
and Dirk Honda was a second in command
of the Linux kernel and he started this
programming with Minister Hodes it's a
diving application I never dive it in my
life but I really wanted to do one thing
well I like to experiment with new
things so I did origami after origami I
felt that I was an OK origami artist so
I did pole dancing
I did one or two years of pole dancing
lessons I tried to do a
semi-professional pole dancing
presentation in Brazil but then I
started doing theater after I ended on
the theater I was a KD developer and
Phil fizzle is the biggest free software
convention in Brazil we have 10,000
people going there annually usually and
well I don't I don't feel shame about
that and then I started tap-dancing for
some reason but I really wanted should
program something Williams mostly
because he thinks that C++ it has
horrible horrible language and it's made
more horrible by the fact that a lot of
substandard programmers use it hello to
the point where it's much easier to
generate total and neuter crap with it
quite frankly even if that choice of C
were to do nothing but keep the C++
programmers out that itself would be a
huge reason to you see
yeah I made Leo store all Co C++ and I'm
not afraid of that I actually put that
on my resume
[Applause]
it is awesome because I was yelled two
times two today which is nice because
usually aliens don't just yell he throws
people on the windows oh if I have time
later
if anyone dude the question are you give
the Fez you have
so I really like to be a vector entropy
I like to make you know zo C++ I like to
make my wife that is they're afraid of
me sometimes I like to make my brother
say oh my god no well I put my pole
dancing picture on his Facebook profile
then I download that the gets worse from
subsurface oh man it was UI application
done by kernel developers it was a
really big spaghetti code nothing was
happening as I wanted as a UI developer
I I know that I need separate code I
need to do some stuff as MVC and Lina's
told me that well that's just theater
crap you have no game from doing that
yes so I had those were the original
problems that I saw on the original code
base from subsurface there is no
separation between the UI and the car
whatsoever
the lack of the knowledge in the
original library now I need to stop a
little bit because I am a cute developer
and the application was dedicated Lauper
GTA that locked up GT K and cute are
usually seen as fighting with each other
but there is not just through the
problem on this application regarding GT
k is that the developers of the
application limos and Dirk usually they
didn't know how to use the TK it's not
just case fault the fault of the
educator was they didn't found people on
litigate your problem the lack of UX
well they are kernel developers they
don't care about you like but they
really needed to do something quite
pretty if they want people to use it and
they had in the time 50 users now they
have more than 3000 so good lack of
integration the base systems they had an
application that look at like really
almost not user crack on Linux and it
looked like user crap on OS 10 and
windle's it worked but it was not
integrated whatsoever
and lack of anyone who give it a ship
because nobody was actually helping them
to
anything so they did sorry that they
invited people should try to help and I
saw this I was bored in my work and I
saw this and since I was doing not in my
work I was paid should just stare off
the roof I use it my work time to
develop super surgeries and this was the
original subsurface code but not really
but mostly like that I mean they they
have their around ten files for
everything it was a scary it's too scary
because on the parts from C to C plus
plus I had to give a lot of the C parts
and the civil sauce part and well it's
now like this after two months of work
I've managed to separate the car and the
interface I'm gonna show a little bit of
the code I'm gonna show the interfaces
but I have no experience joint
presentations I usually and latex guy so
it's usually worse than that car it's a
mess and the interface is a stillness
because I am the only one that knows how
to do the interface and the carbine a
mess I cannot actually make a really
good code for the interface because I
have to deal with the mess that is the
core and well mess mess mess mess mess
mess mess mess no it's not no no not
that
yes so you know that there is four on
C++ and that we can iterate over
collections but because the core is
write it in C our collection is actually
a linkedlist so writing in C and we have
up for each something for all of our
types and I have to use that it's a
macro
back back back back back back back back
so the car is not my responsibility
you did the car is responsibly from
Leno's and Dirk and I actually don't
want to touch the codes because well
there is a function there is around a
thousand and five hundred lines that I
could replace by three lines in C++
that's the reason that I don't want to
touch the car so I joined my work on the
interface and on the interface I did a
massive entanglement but I couldn't
really do what I wanted because both you
guys needed to co-exist for a while the
JDK should continue working and I had
shook creates the cutes based on the
same car so I couldn't really break
anything and as little changes as
possible in the car because the car
people are see and they still wanna you
see so I fix it the spaghetti codes and
now I had this I had a few classes that
mangle the top window the main window
the models for the data structure on the
C everything was done inside of the
interfaces now we have somewhat clear
and we see model for that there was one
file that had 15,000 lines that created
all of the graphs oh let me try to show
you this application because I'm not
sure if you guys know what I'm talking
about
that's where's the mouse help me hang
the mouse
so this is subservice and this is
basically one of my hobbies nowadays
after theater and tap dancing and
origami this graph here it has more than
seventeen different types of gravel
running here and this little part here
it's 200 lines of code usually the size
of this graph in the C code was around
15,000 lines but it only had six grabs
now it has 17 graphs and the size is the
same because we actually managed to
organize the code in a way that work it
and this is actually really cool if you
guys like to dive I have no idea what a
dive is I've done a diving lessons after
three months working on the system to
actually understand what the hell I was
doing this is a dive 200 meters and
going up slowly for more than 40 minutes
yes microphone take it how are you
one two three
I would but I have a bigger problem than
that and you see in the lens of the
thingy where I was here so now the
application works we already have a lot
of users and it's working on a lot of
computers we have every programmer is on
Linux but the most user base is on
Windows which is a problem because we
have one windows developer that's not
paid to work and subsurface actually
nobody is actually paid to work on
subsurface we do it because we want to
try to see if we can scale in us and
make him Elias now remember this
interface how can we put that thing
inside of this it is too big
I mean
the interface is revolted there is a lot
of information there is no native code
area I mean we are using cute video gets
to three tickets we work on different
operating systems but it's not prepared
to work here it has a deep integration
with cute video cats I mean there is
buttons there is lists there is texts
there is everything here is acute
Wiggins
besides the the graph the graph it is my
code entirely and not a really good one
and there is a globe here that is pretty
and you don't need a globe if you're
trying to run this on a mobile because
on Android you already have the maps and
on iOS you also have the maps so we can
just remove this but the problems are
there is six tabs there that's too much
information there is seventeen possible
graphs here I cannot show seventeen
possible graphs here there is no space
and there is fifteen columns that you
can show on this list which is quite so
much as you can see this program was not
for arrow to run on a mobile and this
was a problem but we managed attributed
and we run it completely like that
inside of I don't remember the name of
the tablets but it was an entire block
and it run but well it was made for the
mouse it was hard to use it was made for
the mouse not fingers so you try to
click on one thing you click it on three
things at the same time it didn't felt
like a mobile application and the
dialogue the the files should be
reassured somehow some way and the
application didn't had access should
Android operating systems to actually
get the files because I'm riding iOS
they have some strange ways of having
the any fact that you want it's not
really like a UNIX based system or a
Windows or anything so which was its
workers but dealing really what work is
and enters liggett liggett is awesome
and I'm not sure if anyone here did that
because they didn't thought that this
was possible with kids but we are
actually using git as a file not as why
do you use guitar yes repository we are
not using it for a repository we are
using it as a file format which is
awesome because now we are stirring
everything in the gates not as a text
not as an XML file we are using git
storage information should save the life
which is right okay and it's fast and we
can apply dips over files and if we sink
something we can just do a git pull and
pull only the difference of the git
repository which is awesome because that
file that I open here on subsurface it
has 8 megabytes of data because the guy
that did those dives is just stupid and
he dives with four different live
computers should test the software yes I
still think that he is crazy
and that's Lee knows better but with git
we have a lot of things we can add
something and it can compare this so
it's really good for a programming
perspective because we can give the the
file format that it generated and it's
easy to spot regressions it's using to
improve you get repository for free so
you can send your dives to github and
then just get poked and you can use that
should get the files on the computer and
on the mobile and because of that we
created the subsurface cloud service
that is also free well it's free for the
users because Linux is paying for that
and the problems of youth really gets
that I said before it's proven it works
it will not crash it's really
lightweight I mean really really
lightweight for people that thinks that
cute is not like to it as gtk for
instance if you use the same stuff from
gtk and from kilts
they both will use the same amount of
memory on your computer so not really
different and it's used for another for
everything there is skin okay it can be
you can use the cord directly means that
I can call the C code that the code is
made of and I've done that I show that
before so I'm gonna just pull over that
enters KML people here do you know KML
two three four okay
quite much KML is something that you'd
created another long time ago was when
kids was social Nokia and then NACA so
to another company and then another
company split into other company how can
people trust that if the company is not
solids well you guys know Bentley right
Bentley uses Chanel
you guys know Tesla Tesla uses KML you
guys know Mercedes BMW they are starting
to use came out some song is using KML
so how can you trust a company that's
never really solid and stable I'm not
sure they do Terps for some reason and
one of the reasons is that this thing
can run everywhere on desktop on mobile
on KNX do you guys know KNX yep so Ken X
is one of the most used operating
systems for vehicles for cars and it's
being used currently on embedded systems
it's been used currently on airplanes on
cars on smartphones on drones on fridge
on boats and I actually did the first
drawn using he ml it was amazing I crash
at 3
III yes literally because when you have
the drunk and you have no idea how to
counter it well that was my first crash
and then I actually I put some
parachutes on it so it wouldn't actually
crash that way and on my job I had to
replace an art core and change it to
Intel I was into the developer so we
were trying to make the drone work on an
Intel chip the problem are the problems
Intel chip was choose low to actually do
the mathematical calculations that we
needed for the drone on the first trial
and it completely collapsed said when it
started to roll down on the sky and
crashes and the parachute didn't work it
because it tried to open but it was a
spinning just awesome we have the video
for that cam now started a long time ago
when this was considered that smartphone
this was yes it's working it was the
green phone thank you because I forgot
it was a little bit sluggish because we
didn't actually have the OpenGL work and
on that thing back back on the time but
it was the first trial of having
something declarative to work it uses
tilt wickets so it had a lot of
libraries to load it was a little bit
bloated but it work at it work at on OS
10 it work at on Linux Windows connects
Android iOS and now you remember
probably on university or when you guys
were starting your program or you'll
hurt this that Java is compiled ones run
everywhere but it's not because you have
Java say Java made Java something and
here you have actually a sequence plus
code that you can code once and run
everywhere you have to modify a little
thing here and there sometimes but it
usually works
and it's kimmel a language that runs on
top of v8 v8 is the library from chrome
to run JavaScript but it was a little
bit modified Shallotte small files
instead of big Java scripts and it also
uses a gift and it can interact directly
with cue object so you if you have in
your program a cube object you can just
pass it should deviate to the kml engine
and it can interact with it you can call
the properties you can call the
functions but it doesn't interact with
SiC codes now my whole core is in see
how the hell I'm gonna interact videos I
cannot so I need to do oh sorry
there is no drawing primitives on KML
which also bummer because if there is no
drawing primitives I cannot do the
profile the profile is the little fancy
graph honking now I can do rectangles
and I can do texts and I can do a
combination of rectangles and rekts for
real for real I don't have anything on
KML that is more than a combination of
rectangles and texts and maybe a pigs
map no you can't you can't load any kind
of cute' will get inside of came out
unless you go to c++ and you create a
new Cannell object that loads the pics
map for that we get ok so there is
nothing ready for that but it can
interact directly with two painter so
you could use cue painter for that but
is not really performance because it is
done in OpenGL and if you use cue
painter you are interacting actually
with pix maps and the act of sending a
pics web to OpenGL every frame is time
consuming and you can also use GES
canvas because Kimmel's butan top of Jas
and Jas has a converse you could use
that not performance don't do that
nobody does that don't don't even try to
do well actually we on KD we are doing
that
we have three libraries for that because
I only had two experiments and for a
desktop that's mostly okay but not from
Ohio mobile doesn't have the power as a
desktop has so we could not use that
because our graph is just too huge this
is painful so strict I've uses a double
link at least with shook pointers that
have a few other members as a sip
pointer that has a few macros to work on
it and we need to transform that on C++
object should troll this show the KML
and create a model because NVC and KML
are made should be used together
so let's duplicate the code and by
duplicating the code we actually managed
to make this work and now can now has
code to deal with dives and related
things because well we need to work with
knives but it was thankful but it works
this is an actual picture of the program
working on Android and it's even
blinking because it was really a lot of
work to make this work just choose
Summer of Code projects because the
first one the guy just gave up and never
answered our calls
yes not really good but we still had the
problem with the profile oh this is
using kirigami do you guys know kirigami
yep
so kirigami is a library that the KD
developers are building on top of kml to
make the application not use the device
specific information for vidiots we want
to use something five minutes okay I
need to run we need to
damn it I hate Iran we need to show the
application as a unity on everywhere
every device should have the same face
so we started to using Gmail kirigami
sorry but the profile was also problem
and we couldn't use the J's converse we
couldn't use the opengl by hands because
opengl by hand is just too painful and I
don't have the time to learn that if
anyone of you knows how to use opengl by
hand please help us
we had KD charts q charts and we could
try to export our current charts somehow
i tried to charts and key charts and
none of them working for what you want
because you were ready to talk about
this no current charting library had
what he had what do you wanted because
we wanted to put a lot of axes
overlapping on top of each other we
wanted to make them not really show
because we already have the information
on the curve we wanted to invert some
axis to show the graphs upside down and
it was hard to do that in a pretty way
using the currents things that we could
so we parted everything that we could
check email and the profile the cute way
to get the right order
how can you put a cutie will get we have
to write a C++ class and it's a little
bit of magic because we have to do this
bit of code just to make it show
correctly on the screen and I don't
think that you can read this it's not
made for reading is just because I want
to show you how we did it
and there is a lot of magic functions
there there is a lot of magic numbers
that we have no idea why they are there
but they seem to work yes and it work it
appeared and we are happy and these
applications actually running here in my
iOS that I can try to show you
ah this is the application I don't have
access to the data right now so I cannot
show you running that but it's loading
we still have a lot of coal don't see we
still have the lack of an actual KML
developer because I am a cute developer
cute with Achatz I've done 10 or 12
years of C++ development with cute for
the desktop my head doesn't works for ml
and we have a constant API breakage on
KML because we have cable controls one
true they are incompatible
we have kirigami one and true they are
compatible but they are using Gmail one
or two that are incompatible so we had a
lot of issues on that and it's hard
should get the documentation because
there is to creating it so so we need
more people please if you guys wanna try
to work with Windows and annoyed him
please join yes we need artists we need
testers we did divers preferably
programmers yes
it's actually true come join us you
might miss limbs and he will pay you a
dive someday
and questions sorry I don't have the
time I have a plane to catch right now
and in each one
in time which is more awesome so I think
I have one minute
anyone has a question yes we look into
that but for that we need to know OpenGL
I have no idea OpenGL and you want the
fast people thank you very much
[Applause]