okay so I will be talking about
monitoring applications and evolving
from text logs to extensive automatic
monitoring my name is certificate I'm
working at shop where in Germany I'm the
one of the developers for shop where
connect yeah you can follow me on
Twitter maybe one of my my main project
is shopper Connect I were using this as
an example because I'm mainly
responsible for DevOps in this project
and taking care of the service keeping
them running and if anything bad happens
I'm the person who will be asked and I
should at least give them some Intel
what exactly is happening right now yeah
so just a little bit about what shopper
connect is connected may application
where suppliers immersion is an
e-commerce application where suppliers
and merchants can connect to each other
suppliers can supply products to the
platform and merchants can subscribe to
the products the order is then if
somebody orders something in the
merchants shop the order is directly
submitted to the supplier for me that
means that I have to synchronize product
data including prices descriptions
availability everything images I have to
synchronize orders I have to make sure
that if an order is being placed both
supplier and merchants are on same term
on equal terms on this order so that the
prices are right availability is right
and everything is fine so the system
really needs to run but all the time and
if anything fails that can become pretty
bad one of the things we are using and
that is all the images of crop dam one
of the things we're using to make sure
that we are finishing all our tasks in
time this being so I'll be talking about
this throughout the application a few
times because it's hard to analyze and
find out what's going on
something crashes with some bins of jobs
Beanstalk is a message queue for
everyone who does not know that the
message queue can be used to make tasks
run as a Cronus lease so you put them
into the message queue and some tasks
handlers pull them from the message
queue so they will be handled that way
you don't have to wait for long running
processes inside your requests or if you
start a command you can just create
tasks push them to the Beanstalk and the
responsible handlers will take care of
it yeah in connect we have seven
individual components index update
specialized components that take care of
several things we have force service I
have to manage two of them are in the
life system behind the load balancer so
they should always be equal the other
two are used for staging systems stating
one is saving to the one is used for QA
purposes there is some stuff going on
and often things break due to do
testings at the demo environments which
can be used to show the stuff to
customers potential customers I have
running 22 cron jobs on each of these
machines that I have to keep track of
which is also sometimes not that easy
33 workers that are managed through a
soup
and
total we have currently two thousand
three hundred users roundabout and 690
thousand products just to give you a
little scale and reproduce around 30
gigabytes of log files each month in
case there goes something wrong I have
to dig dig through these log files so
that might be a problem
Becker monitoring through these we have
a lot of data that I have to manage and
so what is background monitoring
background monitoring monitoring is a
term used to say that I want to find out
what's currently going on monitor show
me the status of my current processes or
whatever is used and managing it with
background I mean that I want to track
keep track of all the other stuff that
is going on here in the background that
I don't have track off through any UI or
anything I don't have no weapons a face
to call my mic runs off to see what a
micron job is doing so any kind of
process demon work whatever you may call
it anything that runs in background and
is fired automatically I want to track
that but how is it working right now
without some some monitoring you
probably get feedback because you don't
have any any measurements you to fix
something before a real crash happens
you will get feedback probably from the
customer so yeah you get a message the
sink is not working right now hmm bad
maybe you there's just some data wrong
for the customers who so you can look
into the database and hopefully fix this
very fast maybe some products are not
updated also thumbs something you
hopefully can fix very fast without
having too many issues or maybe the site
is down this will create chaos this is
not a good good thing to happen you
don't want your site to be down and in
case something like that happens you
need to fix it mmm and to fix it yeah
you probably need to gather some Intel
this is a little screenshot of the log
files we have for connect these are by
far not all of the log files and you see
that there are some
filled it away by lock rotate so these
are old files from the last days this is
a current file if there's something
happening I need to dig through these
files if it happens right now that might
be easy just open the latest log file
and tail it and try to cause the error
again and you may find the exception if
something happens at Friday afternoon
and you're looking at that on Monday you
probably have to go a few files
backwards depending on how many locks
you generate maybe you just have to look
at the lock - or maybe you even rotate
them more often that depends if the
exception happens just in your in one
component that might also be quite easy
just open the log file and everything is
fine you will get a big problem if an
exception is not occurring just in one
simple component but there's several
ones so it spreads throughout your
application then you might have to open
two or three log files to really see
what is happening what caused my
problems and how can I fix them if
that's a few days ago you have to find
that exact time in the log files and
that might be a pretty horrible task so
but what's the problem
the errors already exist if you get
feedback from someone that something's
crashed yeah it already crashed so yeah
that's bad the error already persists so
if the synchronization is not working it
was not once not working
it's not working right now and that's
not good customized regular customers
recognize errors so they lose trust in
your application
if this happens more than once they will
become probably become pretty angry and
if they have to tell you that something
is wrong that they don't have
they can't have trust that you can fix
anything beforehand that you have
control over your application finding
stuff is hard like I just mentioned with
log files and time like I said the
errors persist if you have an error
that is not easy to fix it may take a
whole day or longer to fix the issue and
that whole day the customer can't really
work depending on the error that happens
or your site is down for for about half
a day or a day that's not good
yeah monitoring to the rescue um I will
talk about three different components
local Gators metrics aggregators and
performance analysis these are the three
components we're using connect and these
are three components that really save me
a few times when something was going
wrong on or made me realize that
something can go wrong in the next days
so the first thing lock aggregators what
exactly is a log aggregator or more
precisely what does a log aggregator
first thing it gathers logs so all the
log files we've seen in the past will be
gathered by the log aggregator and
centralized it will index log files this
gives me the ability to search them it
will add a search full-text search for
all the log files and it will add a
chronologically for me so I can jump to
the Friday afternoon and see all
everything that's happening there I can
filter that log files for that exact
time and see what happened what caused
my problems I can group stuff by
environment like I mentioned earlier our
life system is made up of two servers
that means if I have to find something I
would have to jump to each server and
look at the log files and find out is it
just happening on one server or on both
or anything the log aggregator groups
off by environment so I just look at the
production environment at the live
environment and I will see is this
happening just on one server or on both
servers what's going on and something
that's maybe more subtle I can make it
locks available to more people I don't
want to give everyone access to my
service I don't want to give the trainee
access to with SSH to my servers to look
at log files maybe by accident Libre
something on the life system not a good
idea so with the log aggregator it's a
it's basically a website where I can
visit and I can grants more people
access to this service I can also grant
access to the log files to people who
are not familiar with the terminal who
wouldn't even know how to to open the
log files on the service another cool
thing I can learn some messages but
let's look at the log radio the quality
is great this is the this is the
overview of our production environment
you'll see a lot of log files and here's
something I had to jump into and fix it
because we have a critical error here
but I can immediately see that we have
to okay it's not visible we have two
different environments some of the
messages come from the backend one and
some of the messages come from the
backend
too but we see them in one big overview
I can filter the filter the messages
down below and here I could select
production the environment I want to use
all the time by the way this is a tool
called paper trails I'm using there are
plenty other tools out there that can be
used I'm also open source tools this one
is is a paid tool a paid service which
has the advantage there don't have to
set up my own lock aggregator service or
anything but yeah just look for that and
you will find different solutions here I
can see that I am displaying two
different log files in fact there are a
lot of other log files in here but not
currently visible I can also filter them
out so I just see the log files of a
specific file or specific environment or
just one specific server so I've plenty
stuff I can do their alerts I have
quickly mentioned that earlier I can
define alerts we just have basically two
different different alerts they are
duplicated so we will receive a message
in HipChat if something is going wrong
if one
these triggers and I will receive a mail
about the the issue so that even on the
weekends if something really critical
happens I will get a mail and maybe I
can try to fix that or say no I can wait
till Monday
mmm this is how an alert can be
configured you can basically write a
query and just what you've seen down the
search fields you can just copy that and
paste it there you can limit this to a
specific log file or anything typically
you can define a frequency so something
is going wrong I want to be informed in
this case every hour about this error
and you can define a threshold and
sometimes if the filter is getting like
five messages per hour that's fine it's
okay
things can go wrong that might be okay
but if you suddenly receive 60 or 70 of
these messages something may might be
wrong so yeah you can define that some
other things here are some some
definitions for our set yeah that's how
you can define an alert of course this
is bit different from tool to tool but
basically this is this is how things can
be set up but how can you define this
how do you set up such as such a lock
aggregator it's quite simple for UNIX or
Linux system locks you just have to do
these three steps you just have to
detect your system log of at first the
different ones out there so yeah then
you have to change something here this
log and recon file
I had a few lines there and yeah that's
oh can I cannot scroll there it's not
everything yeah Wow the third step was
hidden in the third step you are going
to kill the service the the old service
and make is accept the change that's how
we do it for system logs but in my case
I don't
we want to use system locks I have my
own custom log files I want to to lock
most of the system files don't really
really interest me at all but there is
also a solution for that I can push any
any existing locks to that here is
remote this love that's a tool from my
thing provided by paper trails I just
download that one install it and then
they provide a configuration file this
is the standard setup for the paper
trail I can define different log files
here okay in fact our definition rule is
a bit longer and I can set up the
destination not only for papers for this
also works for other tools here after
I've done that I just start the demon
from for remote this log and the log
files are being pushed to paper trails
yeah so the setup is really quite easy
we've automated this with ansible and
there are just three commands and you're
good to go
very simple that this is also not only
limited to PHP obviously you haven't
seen any any line of PHP code here yet
this can be done for for anything you're
running on the on your machine yeah the
second part the metrics aggregator
what is a metrics aggregator guessing by
the name it's pretty much similar to the
lock Agra Gator just it just uses
metrics but what is the metric metrics
are basically just numbers but in the
context you can see here this is a quick
overview of our metrics this tool is
called liberato same here there are lots
of tools out there depending on what you
currently have and what are you or what
your needs are pick the right tool for
you in this case we have some metrics
here
we have up here you can see we have 164
metrics
push to to the service and the metrics
are really just a number so you can see
here we have both environments back at
one and back and two and every peak or
every point where this line change this
is a number that has been pushed to the
service we define the name for this that
tells us how what kind of data this is
these are really just integer values
float values depending on the context
and without knowing what they are it
wouldn't be very helpful with this data
you can create dashboards like this this
this gives me some information about the
current status of the application in
fact this dashboard I have that on the
TV screen on the opposite side of my
desk so we'll always see this one and if
something goes wrong I can clearly see
that a little example you can't see that
example damn mmm okay this is a view of
the past four weeks down in the left you
have the Beanstalk jobs that are
currently in the EQ and it should look
like this you should have these Peaks
and everything is fine jobs are being
pushed to the queue they are handled and
everything is good
what you don't see here we have I had a
very high peak to the left here so you
basically can't see the these piece from
before there I had around 40,000 jobs in
the Beanstalk hue it was not that bad
it's because yeah nothing was really
broken broken the memory was not super
full no processes has been killed so
without monitoring I wouldn't really
have noticed that something's going
wrong but the queue was filling up more
and more if this would have gone going
on what's going on after one of one or
two days the memory would have been full
and I would have had a real problem the
issue for that was simply that the jobs
couldn't be
as fascist they're being pushed to the
cue if I wouldn't have reacted to that
and seemed that in the right time
process may have been killed or anything
else that would have happened and yeah
that way with the dashboard I have seen
that and I can react to it and fix the
issue before any anyone notices
in this case we also can define alerts
so this is a definition for this as we
only have numbers you can just select
the metric you want so the context of
the number and what the trigger is so in
this case if the average is above 50,000
for 30 minutes then there's something
wrong and the alert will be thrown in
this case this is the indexer so the
component that that takes track of our
products being indexed to an elastic
search database and yeah how is this
being done it's even more simple than
the other one it's just one curl I have
my my user data up there
and I just give some some data so I have
the name for my metric I can define some
tags in our case we have to find what
environment we have so that's back at
one or back and two or whatever and I
just have the name of the metric and the
value this is just a curl I fire in the
PHP code we have written the wrapper for
this so that I just have to pass the
name of the value into the function and
you can call this at any time in your
code to to push the values in fact we
have written one command and symphony
that collects lots of metrics like the
current amount of users and products and
stuff like that and pushes that to to
the brothel
yeah so far so good the last component
performs analyzes this is not only
useful for yeah making your application
run fast yeah why performance this is
not only useful for for making your
application run faster if you realize
that it's quite slow
you can also recognize irregular changes
so you haven't done in deployment or
anything changed and suddenly your
response time of the live environment
goes up then there's something wrong
that might be a bottleneck but you won't
realize it at the beginning
I'll come back to that later and you're
able to gather some Intel so if there's
something going wrong if there's some
regular changes you can easily identify
which exact function call causes the
trouble or if it is a slow SQL statement
or if you have very much data in one
response or anything yeah so this is an
overview of tight ways again this is not
showing completely we have two
environments located here this dashboard
can be used to see what changed in this
application over the last time so I can
see hey the response time dropped by 33%
this is okay for me if it would have
dropped
further or if there it never really
fluctuates in that area and it drops
really to an amount that is not normal
to your application then you also should
worry so not only if the response time
increases also a sudden decrease of the
response time could be bad so this gives
you a good insight what happens also
some requests for minutes and we have
some other data but how does this look
at detail this is the overview of our
social network so the main front entity
customers use we have an average
100 milliseconds here and we can see
that there is some peak in the request
for the side and yeah all the side
reacts to the stuff but we can also see
down here how fast some requests are
like some of them use just 80
milliseconds and we have one here that's
a bit higher it's around 1.3 seconds
maybe we should take care of that what's
currently not visible on the right side
to the memory there is also a row which
indicates the impact of that request
because even if the one action is
needing one point three seconds or
anything if it's just called once a day
it might be okay
it really depends on the situation in
fact the it's they're ordered by impact
so the top response and the 80
milliseconds has the far most impact on
the result from all these other results
the other ones are just around 5% or
something so yeah but let's look at
these start action because that's quite
high we can also get a bigger an
overview of the last calls and how
things change and here we can also see
that some of the calls you just need if
you tie a very very low time so 500 now
okay very low as is ligh but 500
milliseconds and sometimes the database
call takes over two seconds
so yeah you can investigate further you
can also see here with these labels they
indicate slow queries not so slow
sometimes not so slow that they will be
recognized by your hardware monitoring
or anything or your hoster but they are
regularly slow for you or for your
applications so you can handle them you
also can get tech traces and more
information if you need that but this is
really a good tool to give you an
overview
something changes because the change
from 100 milliseconds to 300
milliseconds is an increase of 200% but
you won't recognize that nobody will
recognize the response time change from
100 milliseconds to 300 milliseconds but
this tool will show you how this being
done we're using tight ways here and you
can simply install PHP extension on your
system and the daemon in most cases you
don't have to add the extension to the
PHP any but what you can also do is sell
sideways which framework it uses you are
using in your application so in our case
instead of work press we have Symphony 2
in there so tight ways can guess a bit
better what's happening in your
application if it knows what's what
frame over here using yeah so we have
these three tools they give you a
getting a good insight and you can use
them all together so yeah hooray awesome
but is this really unnecessary do you
need all these three tools to to handle
that stuff yes I have taken some of the
issues we had in the past and one of
them I've already talked about what the
Beanstalk you being running full that's
one of the issues I would have never
recognized without the background manual
monitoring this way I could solve it
without it becoming very bad
the response time increase we actually
had a case where the response time
increased you 300 milliseconds and we've
just realized it through the performance
monitor the course of this was a
bottleneck the bottleneck that was not
really bad right now
but if we would have suddenly had a few
more customers that would have uploaded
several 10,000 products it would have
gone bad this way I could fix it before
the response time goes up to
two or three seconds or any thoughts one
in two timeouts or anything and this was
a good thing without this monitoring I
would have never realized that
supervisor tasks being killed one of the
things in the overview of the metrics
monitor actually was how many of my
supervisor tasks are currently running
if one of them fails it was killed due
to some reason I probably won't notice
that depending on what kind of service
it is and yeah maybe this organization
for a customer doesn't work anymore
because of the metrics I will see if the
task is killed
I will see the supervisor task is killed
so the supervisor talk to all the
workers running in the background they
are doing stuff like synchronizing you
know fetching updates from products
starting index the indexing process and
anything like that and something else
specific tasks crash due to some
exceptions the exceptions I can pretty
easily see them in the paper trail if
there are currently exceptions being
thrown
I will clearly see that due to these
stacktrace that will be visible in paper
trail at least in our case and they are
clearly distinguishable to other log
entries so they are easy to detect we
also had this a few times and yeah
so that's that's it so far from cases we
had where really we needed all these
tools and they every one that every
single tool helped me a lot but not to
every single one of them we have the
logs
the logs are very useful for complex
applications with many components if you
have a more simple application that has
just one component and you just have one
big log file where everything runs in
two then you probably don't need a log
aggregator also if you don't have
multiple servers in one environment it's
also probably not not necessary to use
the log aggregator
another thing where local Gator is
useful if many people who benefit from
the access to the locks so if you have
the QA team or support team that would
benefit from being able to read the
locks if they if the customer comes
toward them and says that yeah the surf
shop synchronization is not working that
you can't log in anymore then it might
be useful for the fully support to be
able to open the lock files and see if
something with the customers wrong and
sometimes log files are located on
remote machines you can't quickly access
this is not a problem we generally have
in web development but I had this in the
past that I would have to call somebody
to give me access to a remote machine
because it wasn't an internal network
and that can be a pain in the arse if
you just have to wait for them to react
to you if there's a serious issue right
now yeah that could also be solved by
this log aggregator if he is pushing the
messages of course if it's an internal
network and the machine does not have
direct internet access you have to think
of think of solutions how to make the
access through the lock a greater
possible but yeah that might also be a
case where a lock aggregator is useful a
metrics when are they useful first and
foremost do you have data that can be
trapped if you have no data that could
be tracked with metrics you probably
can't use them if there are a lot of
stuff in the background even if you
don't have that clear numbers you might
be able to create some numbers by just
we have things like for the for the
Beanstalk if the task is pushed to the
Beanstalk we increase the counter and if
it's finished with the success we
increase the different counters so we
can clearly see how many tasks have been
pushed to Beanstalk and how many have
succeeded and how many should be still
in there I'm all failed maybe or sent or
something like that but to do that you
need clear workflows without clear
workflows clearly defined workflows this
is not
well you don't always have them in most
cases you will have some starting points
some end point and you're good to go but
you will not always have these clearly
defined workflows and one other thing
for the metrics sales department
sometimes they just want some numbers
they like fancy dashboards but if you
have no clear workflows or anything if
they can't see any numbers there it's
pretty useless for them - yeah and now
the last component again the performance
and Lysa's you will probably need it if
maybe you can use of it if you have
complex tasks that use a lot of
performance or are potential to use a
lot of performance one of the things in
development for for detecting
bottlenecks is pretty hard but hard
because we're working on machines that
don't have that much load on them like
like the Life Service finally have you
can simulate that of course but in many
cases that simulation is not close to
reality or yeah but if you have complex
tasks that potentially consume a lot of
performance on life server performance
and lysis and monitoring might be a good
idea also is your application likely to
run into bottlenecks this is a bit hard
to determine beforehand but if you guess
there are a few functions that might be
a bottleneck in the future so if there
is a sudden increase of products or any
other data in your application and they
all need to be processed it might be a
good idea to use these movies monitoring
just to find bottlenecks before they
become bad and of course is your
performance already bad if you already
have a slope slow application it might
be a good idea to use performance and
lysis to get rid of these these slow
parts of your application fix them and
then keep this afterwards to identify
other areas that of the applications
that are becoming slower over time yeah
that's so far from me for the 40 talk
any questions yes so the question was if
I've considered using things like Cubano
locks - things that might group some
functionality from my application
instead of using all these different
components yes I've considered that I'm
already right now I'm looking into
finding more centralized solutions for
this but even if it's centralized these
three components remains so we have even
if metrics and lock aggregation is put
together into one one application I
still have the benefit of separate I
still have the local aggregation and the
metrics that I can use separately in
some cases we're currently not using
things like locks - because all these
tools we have shown here are projects
hosted somewhere I don't have to take
care of any service I don't have to take
care of another server that needs to be
running as far as I know right now lock
says is is a server - I have to set up
by myself ok yeah but this one of three
why we are using this right now these
tools right now because they're hosted
solutions and yeah this has been set up
quite a few years ago so I'm not sure if
locks - they're already provided the
hosted solution
and I was not involved into the picking
these exact tools but yeah I'm currently
also searching for some more combined
tools no this is just like yeah fire
forget we just fire that to the service
we don't really care about the response
of that thing if it presently these
service is unavailable we don't really
care and it doesn't really affect our
performance yeah I forgot to repeat the
question I think the quality of the
metrics aggregation if when we are
collecting this this data if that
affects the performance of the
application in any way and it doesn't
for us yep any other question
okay thank you
[Applause]