the way are some technique
don't problems the talk today is about
frost set which is an acronym for free
operating system for tiny embedded
devices we are making it fully GPL so
the whole kernel is fully open source
licensed our group is called insane
having machines and we're trying to do
nonprofit development and research into
Internet of Things especially free
software the management platform we
chose to use is get up because it's
quite obvious so the target is the main
target at the moment is the cortex-m
family they're not too big yet so it's
still a challenge we had we go from
cortex-m 0 to cortex-m 7 support at the
moment
so the cortex-m family is a 32-bit
architecture it's a low-power devices
with physical addressing so there's no
memory management units they have
integrated network and a whole bunch of
buses the m4 m7 also do digital signal
processing and they also have
accelerated floating-point so yeah the
thing is that we want a real-time OS and
if you look at embedded Linux it's not
really feasible because it's grown very
big even the MMU variant like mike micro
C Linux it's too big for the reason for
the resources these boards have so goals
are primarily to have a POSIX API to
allow easy porting from Linux user lands
to frosted it's very easy to port
applications because at the moment if
you pour something and there's something
missing it's just a library call or a
Cisco that needs to get added in frosted
and then things work we have a hard
kernel uses the space separation
approach we can do physical memory
segmentation using memory protection
unit on this family of microcontrollers
and that allows for the kernel to have
its own memory segment and every process
as well and they cannot access each
other because yeah then sec fault we
also want to be real-time so at the
moment we already have real-time
capabilities the ultra-low power is
something we're still working on TCP
connectivity is already there we have
both normal Ethernet and USB Ethernet
using Piko TCP as tcp/ip stack in kernel
so yeah all the kernel code this is GPL
but you can run any license in userland
as you please
so at the moment we're almost fully
profile 54 posix-compliant it's
real-time multi-pronged multi threat but
the threading still needs a little bit
of polishing so the components we have
the application layer is in userland
then we have a modified new Lipsy
library that we compiled into our own
cross compiler tool chain then in the
core you have the the core itself the
scheduler networking virtual file system
file system memory manager then under
that you have the device drivers and for
the operating system to know which pins
do what you also need some more specific
whoops
some more specific code to define which
pins are aware and stuff like that so
the record area size is fixed and base
applications and shell scripts are
compiled into a binary fat and then
stored into a zip FS that's execution in
place so for the application code in New
Zealand the goal is that it's basically
no work to port mix executables to frost
it the reality is that some stuff is
still missing in frosted and we don't
have fork but we only have V fork so the
applications are in binary flat format
they're compiled with our own tool chain
and with some flags here if you're
interested we also have a frosted user
land repository with some base user land
utilities the context separation is such
that the processes are really executed
in their own context they cannot access
supervisor code they cannot access
kernel memory they cannot access each
other stack and they have separate stack
pointers and through the mpu we can
enforce this this is a overview of the
system interrupts so the power on state
reset handler accessing memory are not
supposed to mem fault handler and then
the process gets killed of course system
calls come in to the supervisor call
handler which then executes Cisco and
then we have GPS with with sistex
basically the scheduler is a double
lists we have processes even marked as
idling or running it's a round-robin
policy so every process usually gets
scheduled the same amount of time and
once everybody got this chance to do
something just goes back but we also
have a real-time priority option so in
the real time if there's an interrupt
coming in for a process marked as
real-time immediately everything is
preempted and this is scheduled for
execution and the latency for the
real-time processes it's predictable so
that's really good
this is just a nice graphic
so they're repositories we have the main
repository of the kernel which is the
whole kernel we have a repository for
our own tool chain which we build with
cross tool ng and we also have
repository for that but we also make
periodic releases of the tool chain
we have a special headers repository
because we need to include some common
headers both in user land in kernel and
in the tool chain then we also have the
frost at user land repository and as the
hardware abstraction we use unicorn MX
which is our own fork of lip open cm
tree this is a nice graph of the
dependencies and interconnections of the
different repositories to change its I
takes a while to build and that's why we
make releases periodically why our own
tool chain because we want to be able to
compile our applications and be able to
automatically resolve include parts and
stuff like that and also to produce fat
binaries the nice side effect is that
the two chain can both compile the
kernel and the user around application
so
number of difficult
for a number of popular boards like the
stm32f4 six disco disco here so we also
borrowed the K config system from the
Linux kernel because it's quite quite
handy and applicable in this case the
user land configuration is also done
with da coffee the apps that are
selected are archived in CFS and that's
getting mounted to /bin not start up
when the system starts sliding slash in
it is executed and if slash in it that
is a she is present it's going to be
parsed using the default shell which
which is called fresh for where does it
come from the options are selected just
make to build and then you end up with
the image that bin file that you can
flash there's a couple of binaries
produced actually so there's a elf file
of the kernel there's an image file of
the kernel and there's an app store
image and then at the end the kernel
that emission app goes up that image
gets concatenated together to image
stored in and that's the one you flash
we also have a report that has a
modified entry target to have a bit more
resources so you can also run frosted
increment with networking and stuff all
works really fine we also have CI using
Jenkins so every commits Jenkins
rebuilds stuff and harasses us on our
see if it fails
they're flashing to the target you can
do either over the st-link because those
birds have their own ISP on board or you
can copy it over USB if it has embed
bootloader or if it's supposed efu you
can also do that okay that was it now
we'll see if something wants to work
if you want to show the shell and you
should probably be here yeah yeah yes
yes first flash
[Music]
yeah
in the meanwhile if you have questions
most most of the development team is in
this room so I can be able to answer
those get this question there okay
the typical size okay depends
yeah this the question was what is the
yeah what is the typical size for
installing crusted on the flesh and
depends of course on how much features
to enable in the kernel we were able to
build the kernel as small as 25 30
kilobytes but needs to be a power to the
flash part where it starts to the kernel
so I would say that the minimum of 32
kilobytes of kernel size is needed and
then of course on top of that there will
be a partition on the flash that
contains all the applications and that
would be sized of course so based on the
size of your of your applications well I
would say that about with 64 2 1228
kilobyte is able to run a minimal
trusted
yes question there is fasted really
ready for production and we have real
example of companies in that the answer
is no but we are having a lot of fun
with it and it's getting better and more
stable by the step by the minutes and so
we're looking for some money - that's
daring - to use it in a production thing
but it's for sure ready to show this
like we supported the this historical id
Software's duma
game that's now running on the frame
buffer that someone wrote driver for and
yeah so it's it's quite stable as you
can see and the nice part about it it's
it's mostly POSIX so it's basically the
really tiny tiny Unix
where you can put your UNIX application
Linux application - with with the most
no effort yes yes the question is can we
run gdb to debug I think about the
kernel nerdy applications yes we can run
gdb directly to the target to debug the
kernel and we can run a gdb server from
the user space to debug single
applications so you can actually connect
the gdb to a different ports if you want
to debug your own application yes so our
- chain contains a gdb binary as well
maybe
do we have time for another question No
[Music]
okay that was not an observation but
zubaba made the abductor chain in case
someone wants to try that on their own
Laptop Per so you don't need to download
every single component or clone
recursively the github but you can
don't let the docker image one more
question no question maybe there
okay so the question was what are the
actual imitation harder limitation we
met on the on the target the basic
targets to be chosen is because exam
yeah maybe one bigger impacting the
first thing that comes to my mind is
that the court exam as a limit of eight
different memory areas for the memory
protection unit so we're not able to
protect different areas of the heap at
this point so the hip is still shared
but the stacks of the single processes
are isolated with more flexibility in
this area we would be able to have a
better memory protection but arm is
already worked there on the mv8 family
and they already have a data sheet that
explains that the number of MP you as
lots as increased so we're looking
forward to two-port thrusted as soon as
possible to the cortex m23 what is
called the new one just yeah the v8
architecture that's that's coming up
this year
[Music]
Oh architecture if you want to have a
full POSIX system I know the either
keeping a record exactly so that's
that's a very interesting question and
I'm really glad that someone asked this
so why didn't you guys use a cortex a
that already has a menu and a lot of
resources to run a UNIX or you just
stick to the cortex M which is limited
in resources and just have a pure
real-time operating system the answer is
me luck something in the middle
we like UNIX real time UNIX on a small
chip embedded CPU that doesn't have to
have an MMO to to to run smoothly and
the approaches on the embedded world for
what is for what embedded OS are
nowadays are a bit too primitive if you
can tell me this like three artists for
instance it's not much of a mess it's
just a bunch of a schedule with with a
bunch of support for a finicky mechanism
and a very basic heap but for the rest
is still as a number of limitation
especially on the readability of your
API so you can't have the flexibility
that you have if you're coming from the
linux world on the other hand they've
simple big data slides we did Linux
kernel ramping up insides because nobody
in the Linux Foundation right now cares
about the embedded developers and that's
that's a major problem I'm not saying
that we a small group of independent
developers are providing a solution to
this but I hope that this at least gives
some kind of point of to reflect upon
that we really need something unix-like
to to look at except when we crash on
the pinging
it's a network manager of some other
operating system then yes basically what
I did right now was boot up the board
with the USB Ethernet configured and
connected to a USB cable to the laptop
assigned an IP address to the interface
that we got and pinked the board over
USB Ethernet and as you can see the
board is replying so you have
connectivity
[Applause]