i
in his own way
question follow
ah
in the states
and
there are actors to the family
x
and
to be with him
Sometimes also
32 overall
perhaps
I'm going to be
in families
for pursuers
[Music]
ace
only
swipe the aps yeah
we were
two
well
Y
sight
something thanks
[Music]
and up
Wow
to them
the same special
everything
stations actions to be followed by which the operator
to
ace
with him 2
well
but
boeing
spirits
in peter a
after decades
now
and them
good so
[Music]
It's important, sorry, hello
rivers rivers
before
Y
wings 27
to try there are 2
good in this video
sometimes the extractions we choose
truth
--classification
or
Thank you
animals
three things dominated by females
these two classes or
floods then
for more people
the pretty cat
Thank you
situation
no doubt today
the wounds
with three stations
Thank you so much
and ah
next saturday
and the
and until now
ah
when
[Music]
and borges
sometimes 25 great people
and music]
there are the waters of circulating
Yes
paint the end you have here and
two
sometimes you learn or not
ah
They are
i
namely
lord in life
[Music]
Y
spanair address but yeah
and ah
expected
physically hello
now
Y
final quarter
but not
and the reason
they
because yes and
then
this
well
ah
Thank you
on
yes when walking
[Music]
about that kingdom formula
and here
Y
ah
a massoni latency
at least today and look like
Y
d
[Music]
yes to
here
Y
and ah
license
So
a turn
ah
Y
and
[Music]
ah
but not
to see [Music]
ah
and sincerely
if you are any trace
and and
Y
the audio of the Seville book
the truth
is [Applause]
the director
s
and you will not lose
as [Music]
ah
to light
Y
two
special 2
we leave it here for itself
ah
to the market to
if you belong benítez to the streams
Sure
sometimes
s
but yes
but it is not easy algae
selector
the questions in the management files of those who lend
the truth
not
Y
ah
more interesting
[Music]
more