good morning so my name is Mikkel I work
for kinfolk
we are small company from Berlin we do
mostly Linux software and among many
other things
it's a BBF today so the talk is about
copy BF it's a fairly new library to
work with a BBS programs from go and it
aims to help you to access the IPPF
subsystem from your go software the talk
is basically two parts it's the first
part on a BBF in generous or what is it
how does it work the basic principles
behind it
and in the second part we are going to
look into go PPF which is also split
into two parts depending on what you use
cases and yes just see how it works in
general so EB PF is a so-called bytecode
virtual machine in the Linux kernel
today it's used for tracing networking
so software-defined networking for
performance analysis for security
purposes and so on the classic PPV F or
the Berkeley packet filter is much older
sauce or the the functionality to use to
use it for packet filtering has been in
the Linux kernel for a long time and
it's used by for example TCP dump in
1992 there was no unified way to filter
network traffic and the beastie packet
filter paper brought such a system which
then was
implemented for the Linux kernel as well
and today it's called enhanced PPF
because it has grown a lot more
functionality over the usual packet
filtering use case you can attach to
kernel events you
modify network packets
drop them or to route them you can use
it to do Cisco filtering and a lot more
stuff a nice property is the safety
guarantee you get through the BPF
verifier so when you load your BPF
program into the linux kernel it first
gets verified because the kernel needs
to make sure that your program isn't
malicious it doesn't block the kernel
forever and so on
so after you're to get through the
verify you can be sure that no loops in
there that there is no invalid memory
access and so on
and of course you are running in the
kernel so it's very fast and it's all
also cheat compiled on some
architectures so fast is a requirement
to do for example networking so it's
good we have done so from a high level
perspective it looks like this in this
space you have your program and from
there you use the PPF Cisco or some
library which makes your life easier to
interact with the Linux kernel and load
your program or your programs you can
have many of them those live in kernel
space of course and then you have ebps
maps to share data between be BBF
programs and to share data between the
IPPF program in kernel space and your
program running in user space
so first a couple of details on a PDF
programs they can be attached to sockets
that is again the traditional use case
so if you want to execute some IPPF
program whenever a packet arrives you
can use that feature you can attach to
kernel trice points the Linux kernel
already does define a lot of trace
points so you often you can just look
into what you want to trace you can
check out kernel source tree see where
the trace points are but what is
available there and then maybe just
attached to a trace point if that
doesn't work for you k probes maybe do
you can use k probes to to inject a
program as a handler at a certain
address so for example if you want to
trace sis call a Linux Cisco you could
use the K probe which then always
triggers when the Cisco is executed and
there are you probes that's basically
the same as K probes the only difference
is that those were are for a user space
function calls so if you want to trace
something there you would use u probes
then we have maps maps are the data
structures to share data between kernel
and user space when you create a map you
can say what data you want to put in
there so it's up to you if you want to
have an integer value in there and you
only need to store one you can create a
map with a size one and define that key
and value is of type integer for example
and there's one special a special map
it's called a proc array and this is
of a lookup table in the eb PF system
which contains entries to other EPF
functions so if you want to replace
you're currently running a p PF program
with another one you could look up one
there and call it and you should be
aware that the main page for BPF is
rather out-of-date so it's it can be
pretty hard to to get information under
available programs or map types and you
should look into the source code so I
think right now maybe for map types are
in the main page and in Linux for two
point ten or eight or ten map map types
so it's not super up-to-date yeah that's
the list of existing Maps right now we
have a hash which actually works like
you would expect from a hash or map key
value we have an array and then we have
different types for special use cases I
will show you one in detail and that is
type perfect mental ray so it's an array
of file descriptors with perfect when
theta and the nice thing about it is
that kernel can just write into a ring
buffer and doesn't have to wait for you
in user space and the user space program
can then map the memory of the ring
buffer and read from it asynchronously
and that's also a type of map that you
often would use when you use K probes to
trace something and we will see that in
one example later so to give you an idea
how BBF looks like when you really write
a BPF assembly or soda assembly I will
show you
a short code snippet but you don't have
usually have to do that so that's a very
small program you could load into the
kernel as is to count FJ its syscalls
so whenever the Cisco gets called it
increments the counter by one and exit
and yeah as you can see is it looks
rather tricky and it's not very
approachable so fortunately we don't
have to have to do that but we can use
tooling around enhance PPF and modern
tracing tools on Linux there is the the
AIA Weiser project you can find it on
github and also on irise the dot org so
if you are into that and want to learn
more about the available tools find
documentation and so on that's a good
place to start
so now on go BPF it's I said before a
liable library to create load and you
see BPF programs and it's actually two
subjects addresses it's one which allows
you to use Segoe and the BPF compiler
collection and a second package which
allows you to use pre-built elf object
files and we will have a quick look on
both part why go PBF when we started
working in that area there was no
library yet which did what we wanted to
do but we found who a project from IO
visor which wants to be they call it
data plane so I think the idea is that
you have a demon on your system and then
you ask the demon be an API for system
data and the program then loads for
example some eb bf program to provide
you with the necessary data and second
reason is we work on with scope which is
a tool to do cluster monitoring so for
example Kuban it is and this is written
in go and it also needs to get a lot of
data from your system so for example
running processes containers network
connections and right now their approach
is to to pass proc and check the
contract tables and this is rather
difficult to do because you have to scan
a lot of data and that's very fast and
when you have a lot of processes or a
lot of containers it can be tricky to do
that reliable and fast and depending on
the use case it's much nice that you
have a BBF there because the kernel is
doing a lot of work and you just have to
read the events then
so when you use the bcc package from go
PPF you can write your program in in C
it's a modified C language for BPF
back-end so it feels like C you have to
be careful about a couple of constraints
because in the end the BCC will build an
e BB F tool out of it and it has to pass
the kernel verifier but it makes things
a lot easier you have a lot of helper
functions interacting with a map is much
more comfortable than assembly code we
saw before and so on lips easy lip easy
C actually is not only the library which
helps you to write your program but it's
also a compiler so the it works like you
you pass it your program a source code
either you read it from a file or you
just have it in your go code and some
constant for example and then it
translates your program into BPF
bytecode so we can actually verify it or
GCC verifies it for you before it gets
passed to the kernel and BCC also
provides you with a lot of headers
before you often had to import kernel
headers to have all the necessary
definitions for BPF and all that is in
BCC so it's really a nice library and
you should check it out if you want so I
will show you a bit of source code this
is a snippet from from the example tool
in the go PPF repository and as you can
see here we just define a source were
variable and put our C code in there two
important things here one is
we define a struct of type Joan event
and then we define an array and it's of
type perfume and as we saw before where
we are going to write those events so
that's the map which we then can read
from user space later and the go part
looks like this here we load the source
code then we get a reference on the
table then we get the reference as a
perf map and we pass it the channel and
then we can read from the channel the
events so we have a loop we just wait
for data and whenever there is data we
print it and in copy pfpc see it looks
like this we open a perf buffer and we
give it a callback cookie and then we
have a gateway function which takes the
cookie looks up the handler data and
sends back the event data so I will
quickly show that to you so here we have
the example program and since you need
root permissions for the EPF syscall I
am root here and when I now do some
action here you can see we get an event
and we get a correct report on what was
happening and also the return value so I
was not allowed to do the second
operation permission denied and here is
the return value not zero yeah so
the second package in Gil PBF itself so
if you don't want to translate your
program before you actually use it or if
you cannot ship BCC le PCC on all your
systems because maybe it's too large and
your containers should be small and tiny
then you could think about using
precompiled object files this feature
relies on elf sections so in Linux else
fails you have sections and by defining
by setting a particular section name so
here for example okay Redbridge for a
return probe we allow go PPF to detect
from the elf file how the contents
should be loaded if you are interested
in that you could have a look on the TCP
tracer BPF package from with works it's
as the name says a TCP tracer and we
plan to use that and scope so it does
exactly that it's a very small C program
it gets compiled to an alpha object file
and dividend later loaded with copy bf2
to trace TCP connections yeah you can
create such object files with clang I
think the BPF beckoned has been in the
static compiler for quite some while so
you first produce bit code object file
and feed that into the compiler and then
by selecting architecture BPF you
generate the BPF bytecode for later use
nice or tricky feature of go ppl have
alpha state you can create your program
for multiple kernel versions usually you
have to tell the colonel when you load
the program for which version it was
written because the kernel will only
accept the program which was written
exactly for the version you are running
and this can be tricky when you have a
patch release of the Linux kernel you
maybe don't want to recompile your
program so we built in this feature when
you set it to this constant we will try
to guess the the current kernel version
during runtime and then just say to the
kernel you have rebuild it for the two
version you can do that it can be tricky
because sometimes kernel structures
change functions change a bit depending
on what you do in your EB bf program it
could break afterwards so you should
know what you can expect from the corner
or what you rely on and one last word
continuous integration is also tricky
you need root access you need a modern
kernel you often don't have that so if
you ever need to test Linux kernel
features have a look on stage 1 builder
on the stage 1 build a project with here
we used rocket for custom we use rocket
with a custom stage 1 image which allows
us to test any workloads on CI systems
and time is up I believe so that's it
we have time for questions wrong need
some time to build up anyone having a
question yeah yeah actually I have two
questions first I don't I didn't get the
main idea behind using BB F in that
context of tracing and it's firstly used
in networking especially for filtering
packets so what are the the new features
that give it this good reputation second
in the context of tracing what about its
overhead compared to other route racing
towards like the truss or system tab and
how we can measure it thank you
I think I will start with the second
question so I think the main feature the
main advantage is that you can have it
in mainline kernel you don't need to
need to have any extra modules it's
supported by upstream yeah and regarding
the first questions or many a lot of the
functionality wasn't possible before so
maybe you know Brendan Gregg from
Netflix who has been doing this for a
long time and dtrace from Solaris always
was quite powerful of to trace systems
and Linux for a long time didn't give
you the same features to trace programs
[Music]
regarding networking of one feature from
EBP eff is fast data path xdp it's used
for example by the cilium project so
they do contain a security and
networking with EP PF and this is
something you couldn't do before
any other questions nope okay thank you
very much
[Applause]