so welcome third presentation this of
kids about result of this program Google
Summer of Code last year at the Ostia
I'm margarita delay oh she's so so
google Summer of Code is a program that
has been launched okay okay so Google
Summer of Code is a program that has
been launched by Google twelve years ago
now and it's aimed for student
developers of university age to write
code during the boreal summer so the
northerner misses any sphere summer
so during around three months mentored
by open source developers Danny yes
that's it so the students apply in
around April they get selected by open
source projects that participate to
Summer of Code they get paired to Mentos
so each student gets at least one mentor
that takes care of guiding him or her in
the first steps and on the Google side
of the organization Google selects which
organization take part for example with
G OD bein kDa or other universities
other projects who have worked on open
source and then the organization take
care of selecting students I live so in
this context of geo applies as a
mentoring organization what is geo is
the open source geospatial foundation
that is an umbrella organization that
groups
most geospatial software open-source
software that you can find out their
most famous maybe are some of them like
quantum G's or G dolla which is beneath
several software but there are many more
for example
awesome for example at geo node and so
on so we are geo just celebrated its
11th birthday yes yes yesterday of
course if you if you want to know more
about it
just visit on our website so geo has
participated to google Summer of Code
since it began basically because we have
participated disease
we are applied also this year and this
is our 11th year and here we present our
statistics about our participation so
this is the number of students per year
and the student that passed the program
so we did quite good I would say so this
year we also plan actually to apply also
to a similar program that is dedicated
that is targeted to high school students
that is a Googler code in because we we
saw that we can get such good
participation such a good outreach to
young developers maybe it's time to
address also the younger generations and
so we put up in
place a broader team of administrators
so for this year we are not only me and
Ann but we are seven people taking care
of the administration staff for us Jim
so last year we got 22 students are
accepted and I we asked the student to
describe their own work we in in their
own words because of course they have
their own mentors so we are not here to
explain in detail the work that has been
done because we are not competent about
that we our task is the selection of the
student taking care of them but then all
the work has been done by the students
and by their own mentors so here we
present a list of the the projects that
have been developed and in the
description so we gave them a template
to fill which is the description of the
project so in this case the student
participated with the G doll and he's a
happier Kumar seeking mentored by the
Rob Emanuel a raw and it developed and
[Music]
basically the support to ogr for some
geometries that were missing so it's
triangulated the surface
polyhedral surface and entry angle so
yeah they did those API to do GRE
geometry so we asked them to provide a
description of their own
idea and then at the state of the
project before the google Summer of Code
so in this case he says that according
to the standard that there was no proper
implementation for the distri type of
geometries so the addition to the
project provided by him it's such such
modification so here you can find also
they are lost at this link you can find
also there are lost the report where
there is also a link to the repository
and all the documentation that can be
useful for for you to to go into the
detail and here there is a graphical
representation of his project of course
he represents the ogr classes and he
adds the three one that he developed so
the second student also for adult
project is Alexander boards ik but I'm
sure I don't pronounce it well so the
description here the the W DWG support
to the GD Allah and this was a long
wanted feature because the DWG is a
proprietary format so it was hard so far
to deal with this kind of data that
comes from a proprietary card the
software and but it's it happens very
often that this kind of file has to be
processed in in in GIS so he added
support that is totally opened finally
so the third student is for a grassy GIS
software is a other Malaysia that
completed the
basic cartography suite in grassy areas
through the graphical user interface so
basically what is this is and when you
want to do hardcopy Maps you need to put
together the maps in a way that look
look good to the eye so we developed the
graphical user interface to do that so
here is an example there is the legend
there is the the north
okay so the addition to the project he
mentioned this commands that were
previously only the command line and now
they have a propeller graphical user
interface so another project for a grass
ejs is developed by Andrej Pejic that is
a pie cut implementation of the
graphical user interface generated
automatically from XML what does it mean
Graci GIS has a graphical user interface
based on WX python but this create some
problem because we noticed that it is
strongly platform dependent in a sense
that for example Mac user had some
specific related platform issue so since
the pike Kuti are a little bit more more
let's say used also from other software
and they are doing good the community
has decided that this is a good way a
good direction to take
in order not to let's say in order to
maintain the graphical user interface
totally separated from the rest of the
software
this is generated automatically through
XML and he started with an
implementation it's this is really a big
big project but he started and developed
a good part of it
so another project through another
project for a grass jeez sorry ok
because we asked that the students to
provide their pictures but they are not
obliged to so for those who didn't
provide we choose a picture so there is
a troll face so this student developed
another project for a grassy GIS is my
akka Agrawal and the title of the
project is web grass basically what he
did he developed an interface web base
the graphical user interface for the
software
graça and this is very useful also for
example when you want to give courses
because the installation can be some
sometimes tricky during the course so
you may want to skip this face so but
it's also a good way for example for
collaborative use of the of the of the
software and this is how it looked like
so I will go on with the gvsig spanish
GIS software and with one student
: bono who worked on DVS education
project that was about creating
automated tests that are for example
used in a school environment and
teachers can fill up a template in open
document format and this generates the
Associated maps that could be used as
quizzes and this is already used in its
committee to the source code we had a
second project that was done by Silvia
Franceschi and it's about ideology in
the mountain areas and especially in
wooded areas and this project is about
the modernization of floods in process
of wood cover because the models that
were available before are not so exact
so the actual runs of the model could
not correspond to real situations now it
is with this improved model you have
visualization of the actual stand and a
better modernization of the flow we have
projects students who worked on East
sauce that is a fairly new piece of
software that is this project focused
these and the next ones focus on giving
unit interfaces and joining it with
other pieces of software so flooring
Daniel shorabak
working on an android client I want to
add only one word about our student the
Florina who joined the the admin team
this year so after being a student last
year it decided to help us let's say
reaching more students yeah yeah I
forgot to mention that
among the Mentors many of them so I
think around half of them were former
students so we are very happy very happy
this that there is this turnover of
people who
know what it is to be a student know
what the student could need in terms of
help and they are really the right
people to provide eye to eye level help
to new students so this is the scheme of
flowing work Luca on Easter's work on
web publishing of East services so a Web
API and these are some of the
visualization that is now possible with
these tools so some graphs this is the
configuration area the map and some of
more compact visualization Philippe
provident work specifically on charts
that I show no I think it was very much
picture I'm very sorry it's it's present
on our like online presentation I hope
it doesn't happen really frosty Filippo
worked with the NASA world wind and
Gabrielle he was actually member of the
team of the previous presenter so a very
power that is also present here with
NASA and NASA is actually not a popper
with geo member as a project but this is
I mean this is a big discussion of what
was you should should do as in certified
software or being open to to consider
open source geospatial even software
that is not under audio hood this is a
big thing that is continuously being
discussed in algae but in Summer of Code
we wanted to be open to any open source
geospatial project so we had every year
guests project guests in the south of
West geo and you want to consider them
as proper part of our top and Gabriela
made the web application that uses NASA
web world wind framework as a base and
then adds plots three dimensional plots
on it and it's really fancy
we had one project on openlayers three
from someone Lapointe mentored by
Jessica lap and it is not a religion
they said and she was one of our
students for example for a couple of
years and someone worked on the upper
layers three google maps library that is
the library that allows to overlay
Google and not Google Maps the problem
was that when this library was used the
functions and the the animation that
wasn't done on the maps was not
consistent in the rest of the
application so you rewrote the library
sort of and now the Refresh of the map
doesn't show these distinct
organizations anymore so this is what he
did as in the code as in you see the
visualization doesn't change much but
it's really much more fluid we had one
guest project is in transit time that is
about public transport oats and routing
and Brendan Egan worked on a QuickStart
setup for this application because it is
it is a very new project so installing
and running it is sort of troublesome
for non developers and even for the belt
that developers they were they were
telling us and so it provided this
QuickStart that is also a demo so one
can also just use it to show to see the
functionality of this project and or to
set up his own instance on your own
computer
and this is what you see so you see for
example how I wrote for public transfer
with the stops and each stops as proper
information
so this is another project for awesome
developed by Martina dorita she did with
us more than one year Google Summer of
Code project and she completed them err
a project of complete a photogrammetric
awesome tool of forum for the generation
of DSM from us our images I think we
should go a little bit faster so this is
how it looks like but in the
presentation you will find out all the
links to find all the material related
to although of the project this this is
a PG routing routing developed to
project we do student first one andrea
nardelie developed the flow algorithms
for a PG routing that specific flow
algorithms not just routing so this is a
graphical representation of it and this
is the second for Apogee routing sanke
paliotta ready implementation of a
framework which supports addition of a
contraction techniques
[Music]
this project is a very nice explanation
because you can simplify a graph when a
graph is very big you can simplify all
the segments that are linear with
several nodes on it you can compact the
nodes in this short notation this
doesn't influence the connection of the
graph but it makes it simpler and
smaller in memory so you can this is the
other contraction that is implemented so
when there is another linear path with
more nodes they can be condensed in only
one and this speedups computational lot
by the DPS Ian Rudolph worked on a web
interface to start stop and pause
processes that are run by pi WPS so now
you can actually do that that those are
functionality does not yet available
akbar kabira worked on QGIS so he
developed a plugin for sharing symbols
and style size symbols for for maps for
the the user to to share this this kind
of the same resources yes
so here it is how it looks like finally
there are two projects developed within
zoo project one is bringing the PI
modest to the web rule zoo project
so this basically brings the the
functionality of a tool called the PI
modest that process downloads and
processes modest to the web basically
seamlessly and and the last one was
actually a project not only for a sous
project by the combining zu j grass
tools and geo paparazzi that are three
software and this is a sort of binding
from between them so if you received so
much information you can visit this
webpage to find out more I just wanted
to okay
yes we want to thank our Google
administrator in the fund and you can
find her and other google Summer of Code
people at the stand in building K so
you're welcome to directly ask them
thank you thank you
[Applause]