good afternoon my name is Maria De Sica
I came from a new versity in PI's and I
walk on the Jeep active for those who
don't know Deepak I will do a quick
presentation then and we'll talk about
the key tools in G pack and last news
and then I will talk about the delivery
of VR 360 videos using tiles and they
will show you some demos there at the
end so what is Deepak Deepak is an open
source a multimedia framework it's under
the LGPL license a hosted on get up and
can be used in all desktops Mobile's iOS
Android and embedded Linux so what do we
have in G pakka
but basically two sets of tools one tool
which you may know mp4 box which is we
which we are happy to call it all why
the reference for mp4 files manipulation
it does pick - many people in pic -
generation for mp4 files but not only we
can do an encryption of your files you
can concatenate files so you can do
segmentation we can also add streams
remove streams Ida terms the movie terms
and things like that
we have also play which is a bit more
than a simple audio video player it's a
half way between a player and the
browser you have support for CD 2d
graphics we can use any protocol that
you want including HTTP you can use
almost any codec we use a fan peg we
have support for open HP VC
and scalable extension and I forgot to
say that G pack is a research oriented
the project here we have some some
latest news so now we have a public test
first sector we have support for Raj
extensions for ABC and eg BC we've
improved ttml support we have now the
support for hardware decoding in OS X
iOS and Android and we walk into a brush
to support more P iff and smoothing
streaming files file format and a
hardware acceleration in the encryption
we have also a lot of interesting
projects which you can check in our
github I will talk to you now about the
delivery of the RT 60 content using ties
so as you may know to play a t6 TV do it
while at least a 4k but some claim to
2020 k4 achieved 4k field of view
resolution like we seen in the
illustration and to achieve this we have
the necessity to reduce the bandwidth we
can do this by act by acting on the
compression compression into can do a
compression of 2d video after some
projection or some chafing and packing
also we can act in the delivery part we
can deliver a part of the video based
based on the on a viewport and put a lot
quite outside the outside the viewport
what here we have the facility to
reactor
quickly to motion here we have some
examples of perfections have the simple
one quaked angular projection and equi
rectangular projection with the specific
packing we just take the top and the
bottom of the video where we don't need
a lot of precision and put it on the top
we can do also a coupe map projection
with the with packing so we think videos
will probably be packed and compressed
based on a rectangular region and his
noticed for for tiling so the principle
of tiling is quite simple we just cut
the video in two different parts and we
have the possibility to do to play at
which staff different quality in h pad
we can also have the possibility to play
just some tiles with just only one
so in MPEG - we have a notion called is
Rd which is which represent the 3d
relationship between videos it's in the
source content its codec agnostic
there is no assumption of tyree encoding
tools and can be used with multiple
independent videos it's already be used
for projects projected videos but there
is some discussion to extended to 3d
relationship in our player mp4 client
which we have support for for two
different adaptation here we can see
using the our GUI we can see here
different tiles in this adaptation we
have actually for this example we have
actually nine videos nine separate
videos so which means nine
decoders as we can see here different
buffers and we have also and other
adaptations which called each VC motion
constrainted tile-based adaptation in
this adaptation we have just one video
so one decoder and here we can see
different types nine times
with the different SRD and qualities
also so for this for this second
adaptation after tighten we encode the
the video is in a motion constrained hvc
encoder and after encapsulation we have
the tile tracks and the tile by stock
after that within you can generate MPD
using a MPD generator to have the MPD
file and the mp4 tyler segments then you
can play it with with our play for
example using HTTP requests you can
choose any tile that you want to to play
as I said before just one type using
this link you can have the whole
description of this adaptation and how
to encode how to create files how to
play files etc so as we don't have now a
standard to choose which quality which
which tile to follow we have some
streaming strategies configurations
finish strategies that you can configure
eight-hour player before client we have
a lot of strategies here we have for
only phone priority row based purity
center based purity or current based
priority so as I said we don't have a
Thunder but it can become it can be used
with the gas trucker or a head tracker
for example then after this I will show
you a demonstration where we do an
adaptation in function of the of the
viewport so we will have the highest
quality on the tile visible the visible
type and after that I will show you a
demonstration using the on station of
the implementation of vampy of hard work
the code the decoding using media codec
media codec in android
so here in implicit Clint we have this
beautiful tool we can check which
decoder is used we have the possibility
to to change the bandwidth we have also
we can see the quality's different keys
and now here we have the adapt Asian as
you you can see the quality will change
we it's not very visible but the quality
children fraction of the of the viewport
here we have a demonstration actually we
we under just the tile which should be
visible and we can see also the
adaptation of the quality in function of
the viewport hey it was very very
visible so we don't render without under
the other PI's and here we have the
demonstration of the mediacodec the
difference between the mediacodec
hardware and the software decoder we use
ffmpeg
we can see here that the FS does not
exceed to the 16 frames per second we
have a lot of drops and one frame can be
decoded in more than 100 millisecond but
in the other hand we have the media
codec which can decode the one frame in
20 millisecond and have a constant space
equal to 25 with no drops
we can see also the do cut in the video
and it's quite a similar idea one
I forgot to say that ICI is an it's an
4k video resolution thank you and I will
be happy to answer
I understand which part I think it's
already in the in center which I think
your question is if we check the
statistics using the coop map projection
no it is not that doesn't happen
yes did actually
the question is is if we did some some
statistic to to see if we have any
improvement using tile using tile in
encoding videos using tile using the
constant tile constant motion time this
is yes we did this but there is no a lot
a lot of difference you but you just
need to use 25 tiles and there is quite
good
[Music]
but in the encoding we have we encode
all all the time with all the queries is
just when we play the different types
when we when we do the adaptation
if we supporter as the question is that
if we support using mp4 client which we
support the all the the the devices if
we can actually in Android we have the
milk view support HVC yes and we can use
it with with Google cardboard yes we
have we can we can play actually we can
play all the we support achieve
asymmetry view then you can use to play
a meet review a file you used in side by
side for example or you play it with in
3d screen we tested it with five five
use a 5 MP 4 5 8 5 use and we can see we
support it actually
[Music]
the question was what is the difference
between between the first adaptation and
the second adaptation I adopted a video
player which we use use tile with a lot
of videos suprise videos and using it
with the just one video let's do a
question yes
the current equation it is the question
is which which algorithm adaptation
algorithm we use for this for this using
tiles so here we will check just to
check just which tile is visible and we
have configuration as I said to choose
which quality to use but we will soon
support
bula algorithm for adapting videos as I
said before yes we support the question
is if we support me to view videos me to
view files yes we support it we can play
it we have two streams in one file
yes we have two streams in one file and
we can play it as I said side by side or
you choose which which you you can thank
you
[Applause]