this a developer ad
get for the Google cloud platform ray is
also a DevOps guru has built a number of
applications for a number of different
companies worked on a lot of open source
projects and in likes photography and
traveling yeah so good right all right
thank you very much thank you I hope
you're all applauding at the end of the
talk as well yeah it's a cool so this
talk is going to be G RPC 101 now what I
learned yesterday is that 101 it's not a
common concept in Europe apparently 101
just means that is the first University
session an introductory course kind of
thing and my name is Ray I'm a developer
advocate for the Google cloud platform
and if you have any questions about
today's talk please please contact me at
Twitter on Twitter Saturn isn't that is
my twitter handle if you don't like to
talk please contact me on Google+
because I don't think you will be using
it so skinny now I hope you do know I'm
just kidding if you have any good or bad
just let me know on Twitter all right
aside from developing applications being
developer for a long time and did a few
architecture really to work project
manager and all that but my other
passion is definitely just traveling in
photography so if you want to see some
of the faces at being to you know check
out my Flickr also under the name Saturn
ISM as well now I have a lot to talk
about today some guys now breeze through
some of the introduction stuff and then
jump into some of the code to show you
exactly how this works and the reason I
wanted to do this talk as well which are
constructive is because that there is a
trend of you know micro-services right
I'm not going to go into any of the
theories or whatever like what you
should be doing and what you should be
doing it but if you do want to say
create a micro services application or
if you do want to develop any sorts of
distributed systems one of the things
that you're going to realize really
really quickly is that we're gonna be
breaking down like a single application
potentially that we traditionally do
into multiple ones and there are
consequences for doing this so you need
to know why you need to be doing this in
the first place right and also the
consequences are potentially you need
more
DevOps you need more ways to be managed
and being able to deploy and monitor
these different individual instances of
your application or your services you
need to you know provision for them and
such but there are a lot of worries but
there's one thing that people often this
is how do you communicate between the
two services right how do you actually
do that and I think today most of the
times we kind of flow back to well let's
use rest right it's JSON over HTTP it's
well-known and that's kind of the
default choice today all right but be
careful they'll just because you know
remember you know 10 plus years ago
where you know some other technology
what's the Depot choice and you also
have consequences for those as well so I
want to show you something new hopefully
something you'll like today as well but
then you may be saying RPC that sounds a
little familiar no RPC is being around
for a long time I don't know anyone here
used core body for anyone yeah you love
me I think so just for the research for
my talk I mean I've done this a long
time ago but I found this great tutorial
I mean it's a really good tutorial on
how to use crowbar and you just make
sure you can see this right I mean first
of all first off with most of the RPC
frameworks you're going to start off
with the IDL interface definition
language this is so that you have
something intermediate that's a language
agnostic but then you can use this
interface definition language to
generate code for many other languages
right so that's pretty straightforward
we have a in this example there's an app
you do addition for two integers okay
just two loans just make keep on your
mind just to owns okay and then you
generate the code this is a tutorial for
bar right if you're not ready code you
have to stop and then you implement the
operation right that's pretty
straightforward - I mean yeah not bad
you just one one method and then what
got me is when you want to implement a
server yeah just to add two integers
together this is what you have to go
through to start the server which I just
got completely lost all right and then
they screw it down a little bit more I
mean this is a great tutorial if I ever
need to do core by against is the
tutorial we'll look and this is what I
need to do to to generate the client or
is to use the client and again there are
a number of things here that I don't
understand for example narrow anymore
and naming contacts and all that stuff
so now what's a state of art for RPC no
wonder I guess you know nobody really
think about RPC anymore and then the C
column is RMI which is great for Java
developers but the problem is well first
of all you can you can create Java code
write you can write interface you can
write implementations you can expose
them I say remote you know service and
then you can just invoke it it's really
nice it's really easy to do however it
is not so interoperable right even
though it's so easy to use
you can't really interrupt between
different platforms different languages
and then somebody had an idea of what
wait a second why don't we just use XML
for the interchange right for for the
messaging format is machine readable and
it's human readable kinda as well
and then we have this thing called soap
which we can do both styles of remote
country can do document style codes you
can do RPC its style cause as well
regardless well we came a long way right
now today they set up our this JSON over
HTTP or rest folk services in most cases
but why would you even consider RPC
after what I go went through in the past
couple minutes well I think about this
first of all RPC is hopefully or
definitely gonna be a little bit more
efficient than say
juice I'm over HTTP why because in most
cases there are going to be binary
they're binary photo codes right
so I remember years ago people are
saying well soap is too slow XML too
slow well guess what
anything with text it's going to be too
slow for you so so that's why RPC still
has a place in the world because there
are mostly just gonna be binary
messaging there are strongly typed
because you defined everything through
the idea is strongly typed across
multiple languages unless if you use
something else that's you cannot do
typing I don't know what one I mentioned
which one and then
think about this there for the restful
services most of the times you operate
on a resource and you're limited to kind
of the the the semantics of the HTTP
verbs which are the guests that put the
patch right they delete they're mostly
CR UD operations now if you want to
implement some more complicated business
processes in a remote procedure call for
example or via JSON over HTTP right how
would you actually do it suppose you
need to transfer money between two
accounts right what is the right verb to
use for that how do you actually
implement a restful service for that in
RPC you can simply define an operation
that says transfer and then taking two
parameters and that will define the
service so RPC can in my mind can only
be great it was great but it can be
better and be great and being used today
only if it's simple to use and
interoperable between different
languages and that's where G RPC comes
from
now at Google we actually use a internal
framework code stubby stubby is our
internal RPC framework is used for it
just about everything for remote
procedure calls and we handle about 10
to the 10 RPC calls per second with
stubby it was made to be very very
efficient now just imagine if we need to
make that pin to the 10 number of codes
with rest or anything else it may not be
a sufficient right now only that if it
just takes it one byte bigger in the
message size means necessary we're
looking at 10 to the 10 more bytes that
we have to transfer across the wire
right across the data centers and what
happened is that Google wanted to
open-source your stubby and another
company code square was trying to like
make the next generation off their RPC
from work as well so I think what
happened is that I heard this happen is
when they joined forces and they said
well why don't we just open source this
stubby thing all together and call it G
RPC and that's what your RPC came from
it's actually you know coming from the
best practices of both companies in a
way now the G RPC is fully
open source the G in G RPC does not
stand for any companies I know of but
it's a recursive acronym it's G RPC
remote procedure code framework okay it
is simple to use which are hopefully
you'll agree the general idea Matic
bindings for the languages it is
definitely performant and scalable as we
saw you know in the past white and its
interoperable extensible the underlying
technology that's being used are also
open source aware there are standards
for example for the IDL it used to
support about by 3 which is another open
source project from Google and the big
yellow sorrow binary in there of course
put up or three payloads as well which
is you know maybe into efficient binary
payloads the underlying transport
between services is being is using HTTP
2 rather than HTTP 1 now why is that
important well HTTP 2 is also a binary
protocol so number one what happens is
then you don't spend a lot of bikes on
just describing the verbs right the gets
to put the patch whatever the headers
are being compressed for you okay in
HTTP 2 header compressions there so
rather than spending again a lot of
bikes just to specify all of your
headers they're all going to be
compressed for you as well
we are the algorithm codec pack the the
streams are multiplexed so in HTTP 1
what happens when you need multiple you
know connections or strings while you
open multiple connections or you do
pipelining and such well in HTTP 2 the
multiplexing is default in in the in the
transport so you can multiplex multiple
streams so you don't have to open up
multiple connections and I said the word
string streaming is also default in
native in HTTP 2 so rather than dealing
with WebSockets you can actually do
client-to-server streaming and server to
your client streaming and bi-directional
streaming as well yeah and that's a
beauty into HTTP - ok
and just to show you what that feels
like to be on a binary protocol here is
a demo page ok so if I have internet
here
so that's HTTP 1 which you know it's
loading what 200 more
and that's http/2 but here is some I
guess Fossum just really fast here yeah
but yeah there you go so I'm average you
know you can definitely see HTTP 2 is
going to be much faster now you're not
really really me thing is the server
casually pushed it up to the client
before the client even asked us for it
now that's really cool just imagine
you're in a situation where what the
client requests is like index.html and
you know you know for a fact that they
need like a CSS and all these other
things well guess what you can just push
it to the client before they even ask
for ok now it is a binary protocol so of
course we expect it to be faster so this
is a comparison that they have posted on
a public blog actually the throughput
comparison in with the same machines you
can see that you know obviously you can
get more throughput but know what is
more interesting to me though is the
throughput per CPU okay and that's
important because we're quickly moving
into what people call it cognitive world
and that doesn't necessarily mean you
run the cloud but what that means is you
want to be as efficient and nimble as
possible for your services and with your
PC you can you know process more with
less CPU now what I also entails is that
if you do run this on a mobile devices
or smaller devices or IOT devices well
it's going to be more efficient as well
it's supposedly hopefully also use less
battery for the same amount data you
transfer transfer now I want you to
focus on the language is that that your
PC can support a number of them my
favorites Java here but I want to focus
on three which is subjects at C C sharp
and Java that's because these three
languages are being used in mobile
devices as well G RPC was made with
mobile first in mind right so you can
use G RPC on the client side from these
mobile devices whether it's an iPhone or
iOS or Windows Phone or Android phone
okay so let's see it let's see how much
time I have I got 30 minutes
well great
okay so with your PC I'm going to do
first of all I'm gonna implement a very
simple client-server thing so you just
get a feel and then next I'm going to do
bi-directional streaming with a
real-time chap application with jar PC
I'm going to hopefully I'll do that
within the next 20 or 30 minutes or so
all right hopefully I said all right so
with your PC the first thing I need to
do is to use the ideal to define your
payload and your services and these
files are going to be called the portal
files please there are put up up for
three definitions and to make sure we're
using put up our three we need to press
a syntaxes photo 3 ok now I see I seen a
lot of many hands who were Java
developers it's ok if you you're not
because hopefully the simple wall makes
a lot of sense but in this ideal its
Universal for all languages right and
just like in Java or in many other
languages we have the concept of a
package or namespace so what I can do is
I can say well let me put it under this
package right so oh the payload over the
services is going to be generated under
this type of package this file is going
to be processed by a generator right
basically something that generates the
actual source code the stops in that
generator can taking different options
so for example I can say something like
option Java multiple files is equal to
true when I means is what by default is
going to generate all the classes into a
single giant Java file right with
everything inside you can specify
options for the generator and this
specific one just says well for any of
these payload and services let's
generate a different Java file for it ok
so that's how you can I set this up now
the next thing you do is to define the
message ok and the syntax is pretty
straightforward you just say message I'm
going to say hello request example T RPC
is just you know working based on the
operation and the requesting the
response ok in this request object or a
payload
structure whatever you want to call it
you can define multiple attributes so
for example I can say string is equal to
name field and I can assign it a tag now
you can see here is strongly type the
name of the field is right here
but then you're saying it an integer tag
right that's because this tag is
actually going to be the bikes like is
sent across the wire to identify this
field uniquely within this message pelo
so rather than sending the string that's
you know name which is sending the bike
over okay however it takes to send the
integer over okay so I can strongly type
everything here so I can say age is two
for example I can even do enumerations
or in ohms so for example I can say enum
is sentiment that's how good were
feeling today I'm feeling pretty okay so
I'm gonna say happy is equal to one
I see and it could be a little sleepy
right now which I hope not but I saw
somebody yummy but so sleepy imma gonna
say three kids go to one happy is zero
and then by the end of this talk it
might be extremely angry at me so I'm
gonna say angry is equal to two right so
once he has defined this you know you
can say sentiment is equal to three
right again don't don't get messed up
with the Eco signs because if you say in
the tag is equal to three right you can
do if you need list of things you can
code you can use the keyword repeat or
repeat E string and going to say hobbies
is equal to four something like that and
you can also do strongly type in maps or
just you know hash tables or something
like that so I can say map and I can
strongly type the key and it's wrongly
type development and gotta say bag of
tricks
it goes to five okay now life coding is
definitely not my bag of tricks here
alright so so you can do all those right
pretty straightforward and I can't do
the same thing for the response string
and greeting it is equal to one now
the tags just need to be unique within
the message payload itself the next
thing that I can do once I have the
request in the response then I can
define the services so I can define a
service code
creaking service for example and here I
can define the operations the RPC calls
itself so here I'm going to say greeting
and go to taking a hollow request I am
going to return returns
hello response okay and that's it that's
all I need to do - you know define this
interface now in geo PC you can do
streaming as well you can do
bi-directional streaming client side to
server server to client and that's
because we are using HTTP to behind the
scenes to make something streaming all
you have to do is to advocate what
stream and that's it so in this case if
I add the keyword here that means oh
this is a client client side string so
imagine if you have like devices
assigned you to string metrics to the
server well that's probably how you
would do just say coin size string if
you want the server side to stream
responses back liking a chat application
then you just put that stream in the
response and that becomes a server side
to client side stream okay all right so
now that's so good now next thing I need
to do is to generate the actual stops
okay now the generation of these starts
is a little bit different across
different languages but they're tooling
for it now in Java I like to use maven
so you can use so plugging in a been
working if you're using Gradle you can
use the plug-in Guido as well so what I
can do is go to the G RPC page so here
is the G RPC source code - RPC statue
RPC Java and they got the different ones
for different languages as well now if I
scroll down they got instructions here
so for example I can add in the
dependencies I don't do this very
quickly dependencies okay and then and
I'm gonna add in the de putte plugins
here now that's maven don't don't be
scared
if you're in gueto you can see it's
slightly easier right all right it's
really up to you on what you want to use
okay good now that's uh sorry let me
just go ahead and do live and clean and
let me do a maven package so happy now
is that that the the generator is
tidying into the packaging face or the
compiler face
sorry the compile phase of the cycle now
what's interesting here though is that
this plugin actually downloads the right
binary for your architecture so if
you're on a Mac it's going to download
the Mac version if you're on Linux it's
going to download the Linux version of
the compiler
it's your PC compiler with a generator
okay different platforms needs a
different binary but they really may be
easy for a Java developers to get
started as well okay so that's great so
now if I see target I see it I should be
able to see general resources and here I
got pulled off and I got Java and here
you can probably see it I have the
request and response generally this is
kind of expected right then let's go
ahead and implement some of these things
come right about 300 lines of code
I'm scanning now so first of all I'm
gonna create a implementation class I'm
gonna say greeting service info no
please don't hurt it and there you go
okay so in this class what I want to do
is to extend for example the stops in
public I'll be doing this for most of
the languages as well so I'm going to
say extend the info base and then I just
have to override a implement and method
itself which was called greeting right
and here I can see that I get a request
and a response as a observer now this is
interesting because in this stop on the
server side this interface with this
implementation or the symmetric
signature looks like something that
should be invoke a synchronously right
so rather than having the response on
the left-hand side as a return value you
give the response
through the observer as a callback okay
so on the server side everything is
implemented with async in mind okay now
the client gets to choose whether they
want to invoke this synchronously or
synchronously but the server side to
handle all of the cases its implemented
as a sync by default
okay so here I can do something like
gone print out the request for example I
can do that
I can create a response hello response
now in Java in G RPC implementation they
love to use the buter pattern so
everything is down the puter so what I
means is I can't get a new butor I can
set the tweaking field for example I'm
gonna say hello plus requests that can't
get name there you go and I'm going to
do this I'm going to assign this to a
local variable called response and then
what I can do is to return this to the
client guess what I use the observer so
this is called the response observer and
here we have three messages we got up
next completed and on error what that
means is if you do catch an exception
you throw it back via on arrow if you
want it to be sent to the client if you
need to send data to the client you call
next now even though this is a unary
code meaning the client is only
expecting one response you can actually
call next multiple times which is not
good right if you do it it's going to
give you a runtime exception but but
that's the way that this interface works
now are we done
so I say hey go and send this response
to the client now here's the tricky part
you have to call uncompleted as well so
you can close the string otherwise the
client will be hung and it will be
waiting for the next thing forever I
want to tell the connection times out or
on here you go
I'm completely for it to move on okay
all right so far so good
all right so now let's go ahead and
implement this server to start this to
start the server is extremely easy
they love the pewter pattern so there's
a server fever
zooming a little bit here I'm gonna say
server beautiful port I'm going to
listen on port 8080 and then I can't go
ahead and register the service that I
just created basically you can just give
it a new instance of that implementation
and Bute and assign this to a variable
Co server and you're done okay and once
you have this reference what you can do
is to just go server that start and
that's going to start the G RPC server
in the background thread and so before
they I don't want this man's right to
exit so I'm going to say await
termination okay and that's it that
should be it for the server
I hope how many people think this will
work oh wow
Wow thank you thank you yeah just for
the record on the on the video nobody
raised their hand here I said thank you
alright anyways I don't want it so sad
all right let's try this it's
unbelievable that this will work and I
agree with you let's so let's see can
actually award so what happened is the
the server is in the background thread
and I'm not printing anything so this is
it so the server is running I think all
right the server is fun so the only way
to try this out is to implement the
client alright so if it doesn't work I
got I got six postings right now for the
client I got establish a connection to
the server now rather than dealing with
the TCP connections yourself or even the
HTTP two connections yourself
they abstract everything away and they
give you this thing called a channel so
what I can do is to create a new channel
and I do that through a pewter of course
I can't do for the local host port a DD
okay and I'm going to use the plain text
just because I mean the bevy of Armant
I'm not setting up any SSL and let's go
ahead and beauty okay
I'm going to assign this to channel now
this interesting part here is that um
let's see here I can't do an in
voiceover yeah so this is currently this
is just going to point right the client
to the server that's well-known if you
do need to low balance across
to both services or multiple G RPC
endpoints well you have two facilities
that can help you one is called the
neighbors over basically helping you to
give a service name in identify and
return a list of endpoints that the
service is being served from and on the
client side you can then set up a load
balancer factory to you know low balance
across the list of endpoints and you can
provide your own load balancing strategy
or you can use the default one which is
more like run wrapping strategy ok so
now once you have the channel you can
you you can create a stop to send
traffic over the channel and to do that
I'm gonna say G RPC Kesari greeting
service in co2 RPC I can say a new stop
now here's the interesting part right at
least in Java
when you do a new stop you have three
options I mentioned before the server is
always implemented as synchronously but
it's up to the client to decide whether
they want to block or not so you can
create a new blocking stop which will
block this call and get the return value
in where we expect you can also get a
future stop with your returning your
Java feature where you can use the
synchronous stop as well okay so for
this example I'm gonna go ahead and just
use the blocking stop okay and we come
to assign this to a variable stop okay
now we can actually make a call so I can
say stop treating okay hello request I'm
gonna use the new buter okay and in here
I'm going to do I'm going to set my name
- ready set age Oh 18 yeah
at hobby so I can say coding right I can
put back off tricks coding not live
coding okay something like that right so
if you can see generates all the methods
for you it's so typesafe as soon as you
stick with it the schoolteacher nari the
right pelo for you and then I'm going to
get the response back now because this
is a synchronous stop I can't just get a
response back I'm sorry
yeah it's a blocking stop so I can't get
a response back in the return value
and in the end I'm going to go ahead and
print it okay I'm gonna try this again
how many people thinks it's a quirk wow
the same number of hands okay I guess I
have to work harder okay so here I'm
going to do package and do it exact
let's see let me just zoom in here I'm
gonna move the response out of the view
so you can't see it I think it worked
I'm just kidding alright let's scroll
down hold on a second I'm gonna scroll
down there you go right so you can see
that you actually connected well thank
you
and on the server side you can see we
also generate all the two strings for
you so you can you know if you really
want to you can print this out so you
can see all of the things I entered okay
so that's not so hard that's pretty
simple and straightforward for a simple
service I would say right so the next
thing I need to do I think I have on tou
live in 20 right even the 2015 is left
great so in the next couple of minutes
what I'm going to do is I'm going to you
know write some a few more lines of code
to basically create a real-time chat
server in the chat client in Java with
your PC by using bi-directional
streaming okay so I'm going to close
this out and if I go to the chat server
most of the bootstrapping here it's done
because I went through the basics
already so the only thing I want to show
you is the proto file now in this
profile like I mentioned if you want a
streaming service you just put stream
the side that you want to string in this
case I want bidirectional streaming so i
got stream on the left and stream on the
right okay it's going to generate stub
that looks like this line to implement
so i'm going to open up the service
implementation here okay now don't be
scared again everyone going she's a
little bit different this is just how
Java works so it's a little bit more
verbose here but it's fine it looks
perfectly fine now so a few things I
want to touch on here is that oh the
message passing is being done through a
Kobach interface code the stream
observer whatever the client sends the
data to the server guess what is the
server will have a stream of server that
listens to all next what you want to
send the data back to the client
we already saw you're going to get a
stream observer reference and you're
going to call next and send it out to
the client so in this case since this is
bi-directional streaming so what I'm
going to do is I'm going to create
basically return the new stream observer
that will have this uh next
implementation that's going to be
listening to the data from the client
and what I have done here is every time
the client connects I'm going to add it
to
a list of clients that's currently
connected and so what happens when I
receive the message from the client is I
need to broadcast it to all of the other
clients that's currently connected as
well so for that I can do I have a list
of observers I can use the string and I
can say for each of the string
Oh observer and I can't do O'Donnell
next right and here I can give you the
chat message now what the gentleman said
she looks like well I'm going to I typed
it specifically to call a chat message
from the server so that there's no
confusion so I can do a new butor right
and Bute and can assign this to the well
I can send this to the variable chat for
example now what goes in here is going
to be the data payload I want to send to
the client so I'm going to say oh let me
see here new pewter yeah there we go
so I can say set message and I'm just
going to take the message in that's on
the client okay that should be it so I'm
iterating through all of the currently
connected clients or observers I am
going to send everyone the same thing
okay number one number two if the client
gives me an arrow so Java developers -
we do nothing here I actually probably
remove the observers from this stream so
I do a response observer all right and
I'm going to do the same I'm complete
let's see that should be the server then
you should make sure icon oh the means
close all right
that's not so hard despite the original
trimming in a few lines of code mostly
auto-generated for you by IntelliJ
alright so let's see here so I'm going
to wrong this server hopefully this will
work as well okay very good
server it's home just like before yeah
okay that's a good sign
given the history alright so let's go
ahead and implement the the client okay
so now I have a Java FX client so just
so I don't have to deal with other front
ends right so what this client looks
like is if I - JavaFX wrong
okay so basically you can whoa what just
happened all right
basically you can type in the name and
you can say hello and hopefully when you
click on that same button it's going to
go say to be sent to the server and
hopefully also you're going to see the
message payload coming back okay so
that's the thing we want to implement so
here I already have establish the
connection I'll open up the channel just
like before I created the stop now this
stuff is actually the async stop so what
that means is you actually get the
streamlet servers in both ways as well
so let's make a call so let's see what
that looks like
so chat service dock creaking the chat
sorry it's going to taking a stream of
server and it's going to return you
extra my server as well okay so Chad
chat message stream observer okay so let
me just make this a little bit more
stands I'm gonna say chat messages to
server okay so in this aisle next this
uh next Kobach will be triggered every
time the server sends the message to me
okay so every time that the message the
server sends message to me guess what I
need to add the messages the message
into the view so what I can do is say ah
and here I can say well what do I need
to add I'm gonna add the content of the
whatever that's being sent to me so I
have the front field okay I'm going to
plus I'm going to add in the message
field as well the actual text and I
should be it now because I'm running
Java packs I should be running a
platform run later and what that means
is because I need to execute this in the
UI thread so that's what I'm going to do
when I get the arrow from the server you
guessed it let's not do anything for now
when you're complete I'm not gonna do
anything either
okay now when somebody pressed on the
button to say hey I got I want to send a
new chat message what I do well let me
make the call so I'm going to say the
same but instead on action right and
it's going to community vent
and what I can do is here I can then
make the call to send the data to the
server how do I do that through the
observer um next right and I can say a
chat message new pewter copy ute and
let's just make sure I cut this Oh cut
it out so I can say the message from
which is the name docket text so that's
what people entering the name field and
then I can't say the message and that's
message you don't get a text okay who
live coding all right I think that's it
I think I really think this is it I
think all right hum I'm gonna do another
poll how many people think this will
work
Wow steel okay I'll get more hands all
right all right let's try this nice
right it's gonna have no idea all right
so I'm glad you jump all the way that's
not gonna work I need to if you I need
to compile I need to compile for it so I
can do either way let me do package in
oh boy all right so just so you know the
sorts call you if I open it up so I'm
not cheating or I'm not like running
this off on another server here logo is
going to localhost 149 90 which is what
I'm listening out all right so let's try
this ray hello Boston huh
first thing first thing that's very easy
though that's the only one client I
could easily have chillie so I'm going
to do is that I'm going to start another
one
okay and I'm gonna zoom in a little bit
do I see you often in your faces here no
not yet so what I'm going to do I'm
gonna be my manager gonna be a great
that's my manager I'm gonna say good job
right alright so that's how easy you can
use GRP see hopefully you see the some
other benefits you know again it works
with multiple multiple different
platforms now before I close up and see
I got three minutes if you want to say
there's a lot more than just simple
request and response in streaming you
know streaming is simple now you can
also set deadlines so if you're making
multiple services calls and just imagine
you're doing that it should be the code
to multiple multiple services and
servers and one of them is really slow
what some of them is really slow but you
got return stuff to the client well what
can you do is you can actually set the
deadline for the top-level service call
and it will be propagated to all the
services beneath it so if the first code
takes one second right and then the
subsequent code takes like you know two
seconds and your deadline is two seconds
you know you're currently you have the
total of three well guess what that
entire stack will be cancelled and the
the client so the server side will
receive a cancellation notification as
well so you can close up the transaction
cleanly
you can also propagate a metadata so you
can do this via the HTTP two headers and
you can also propagate a context so you
can pass the same variables across
multiple services within the same
if you need to go across the boundary
across Network boundary then you need to
propagate the data via main idea and
that is particularly great because then
you can do something you can do
interesting thing like hey putting a
security token on the top right you can
do the trippity tracing with
interceptors you can passing the trace
IDs across all of your services there
are actually really really good
ecosystems around gr PC at this moment
you can do load balancing and service
registries and you can do some kills
tracking as well you can find a lot of
this information on the gr PC website
just go to gr PCI Oh we want to hear
your feedback and we want to get your
contributions as well it is fully open
source they'll come to the IRC you know
check out the Twitter and join the forum
groups and a lot of these things are
actually on like github so if you want
to find some of these code just go to
github.com slash Saturn is in and you're
going to see some GRP C Java examples so
thank you very much for your time
we got time for questions wait we have
five minutes for questions so questions
question number was already at the hands
over there first
yeah I'm definitely having a really hard
time to here sorry I can't hear because
of the auditorium could you be up to
speak
you'll save later okay I'm so sorry oh
yeah so so go to the to our PC website
and repeat the question so it's a
holiday featuring easy how do you check
right if you go to your pc website
there's actually a link to the ER PC
performance testing suite so you can
actually see the historical performance
is that they do on the gr PC releases
and that's all open you can actually
just check the link and see it there
were other questions here yes yep thank
you
[Laughter]
right gotcha yeah so I think that
there's a trade-off between something
that's fully customized over you can
even do more efficiency if you go over
your own transport for example go
straight to tcp/ip but I think there's a
balance between the efficiencies that
you get the interoperability that you
get based on their some of the de facto
standards out there so yeah I absolutely
agree I mean you can always go more I
love to hear more of these to be
feedback afterwards as well yeah yes one
more question here is it faster with
multiple phones and d-bus well I don't
know if that's a good comparison to be
honest so no comment on that I don't I
don't think that's a good comparison
yeah nice yeah last question over there
does your PC have some of the best
practices more for API versioning so yes
actually one thing I didn't mention is
the message palos because it's based on
polar buffer you can actually it's
backwards compatible in most part unless
you delete one of the fields and if you
do delete some fields in the same
payload in case you do want to do it
what you want to do is for example you
don't want to reuse the tags right if
you use the tag that was deleted in a
new field then the kind of server is
gonna get really confused what you can
also do is to reserve some of these tags
so that they don't ever get ever used
again in the future right yeah so I
think that's all the time I have one
more all right I see over there yep
services right so the GRP see how do you
address that and also multiple services
right so how do you create loosely
coupled but strongly type system well I
I would actually want to think of them
as separate right I mean you can be
loosely coupled but still tight right
think about in the rest world where you
are loosely coupled but not so me type
what happened is potentially you will
send data or receive data that you never
expected and people are trying to you
know kind of make that slightly
different right by having a really good
definition language of swagger yeah so
what you want is to make sure that you
define the service contracts in the
payload cleanly in the Pullo file and
that would be the thing that defines the
contracts and that's the thing that you
pass it around to different services
that needs to consume the service right
I mean think about this it's not many
the IDL you can think about it's not
much different from say a swagger doctor
cleanly defines the rest service or I I
hate to say this but it's like a whiz
though but much much more complex right
okay we take one short question short
cut short question I'm sorry
oh I see it's mostly composition that's
disappointing
paratis it's mostly composition but in
short yes in a way but you can compose
the objects together you can also import
so one thing that I didn't get to show
is that you get you can elute that one
sorry for example you can import types
and types from another profile as well
and you can reference to that type
strongly we are strongly typing as well
okay yeah yeah thank you all right
[Applause]