right
so I'm aleeah's we're going to talk
about some fun stuff and well
OpenStreetMap I'll start I guess with
the usual question who here knows about
the OpenStreetMap awesome now who here
does not like the OpenStreetMap
oh that's great you're a terrible person
we would need to talk
but when opposite map well gives plenty
of reasons not to like itself and it's a
great project it's open under license
much like build which must so make sure
you'd stolen happy it was made by a
programmer who didn't know anything
about geography
it has great data model which leaves a
room for some creativity and when I
explain OpenStreetMap I usually after
that mention that the moment you click
the Save button all your changes
I immediately uploaded to the server and
in a couple of minutes everyone can
season
that's awesome there is no moderation
you can just map and in real time see
the changes in the map and interesting
basically the first question everyone
asks not about how to do something with
OpenStreetMap but you know what if I
would like to draw something like this
in OpenStreetMap or sometimes this or
move somewhere else around well what is
it is people wanting so much to break
things or like this or maybe delete some
stuff yeah will it break the
OpenStreetMap well for a bit but those
communities that
all the time watches edits there are
some very useful tools that like who
digit in which you can subscribe to area
you live in like jet analyzer which
relies edits that are suspicious and we
have tools to deal with that so it's not
a long-term solution to break your
helper system because in a couple of
days or if you're like in a couple of
years all your vandalism will be
reverted and the map will still be great
so we could look for another solution
because you know opposite map is open
it's based completely on open-source
software stack so maybe we could just
sit and wait for it to break by itself
not open-source you know will it work
well indeed once there was a time when
some identifiers surpassed their 4-byte
a signet int limit and some core
software broke broke but in a couple of
days the community has fix it and the
project still works so you might think
that opposite map lasts and nothing can
break it but actually we found the
solution it's not I think we're proud of
and the key to break in the project is
basically you don't you need to not want
to break it you need to visit well and
to work everyday on improving it and
then one moment you you'll find that the
comments saying if that you've heard the
thing most that you laugh applies well
to the open projects a bit about me I
work at maps me this is an app for
Android iOS it it's basically a river
for OpenStreetMap started a long time
ago just out of a need to have some
offline maps on travels without
requirements for Internet it's
completely offline and from that it
started to grow nowadays it's got better
UI and 3d buildings you see and some
useful stuff on main to cards routing
sharing whatever a lot of stuff it's an
app store on Google Play you can you
should download it and a lot of people
over the time have liked it installed so
right now we have 11 million users who
use the application monthly to give a
scale that's exactly the population of
Belgium well in the time where is no
FOSDEM around but yeah so we thought
that we really liked OpenStreetMap it
has allowed us to make this great
application and to get some money so we
want to contribute something back
but we're only a team of 20 so directly
mapping won't to give much failure to
post it up so we decided to share the
thing we had the most least 11 million
users so we implemented a simple editor
in the application it's really easy just
click a point and there are some
a simple form and stuff like that no
checks no geometry just sends data top
of statement no you have to log into
opposite Maps through the application
yeah and it works not as well as we
hoped not millions of users but still
many thousands it immediately increased
new contributors user base as you can
see a lot of graphs and we consider it a
success
I've built a tool to monitor the edits
and as you can see recently we surpassed
1 million edits with our application
it's around hundred thousands of users
and the thing I'm proud of the most is
that it's not regular people from
regular countries that you can see on
OpenStreetMap like Western Europe and
yes you can see Iraq Philippines in the
top ten and so on so it's there are
people from all over the world
improving opposite map through the
editor and from the opposite website it
is really really simple you can do
basically there's two things with Maps
Mir is either create new points or
change attributes and that's all it and
this is about the directly opposite map
without any practice and stuff so what
could go wrong basically it's very
simple you can you cannot do you cannot
break any relations with it and stuff so
but some people have started to notice
some with weird things like quite a lot
of people we're very very many people
have started to mark their forums homes
on the map it's it's weird you know
there are a couple of security tricks
going on right now somewhere around here
how to protect private information stuff
but a lot of people don't care they just
this is my home this is home homes of
all my friends and there are roads which
I take to get to them
it's weird when there were some Chinese
tourists there okay but they started
renaming all the attractions adding a
name in Chinese or in Russian or a
Korean which also looked weird and
mappers didn't like it and there's
basically a lot of stuff that you can't
explain
mostly looks like people just making for
themselves like adding these Caravan
sites and mobile phone shops which are
obviously not there look yeah and of
course mappers from a post even came to
us and said you are breaking the
OpenStreetMap please fix it and we
started to think how do we do that
okay another month of work they finally
within fixed yet so we put a big panel
with warning that everything you map you
are sending to the global database and
billions of people will see that so
please don't add your homes and we
forbidden to edit default names that
shown maps so users can't at Chinese
names trees and it is some monitoring
invalidation just to be sure okay so
this should have worked but not as great
as we hoped first since we forbid a
vision editing default names the
multi-language names which started to
differ from default names as you can see
here and here is just in one hour so it
was little frustrating and people were
still adding their homes
but but now we could say that that is
not our fault
every user have seen that warning so can
check this users it's not our problem
and then the code of dealing with
OpenStreetMap of converting our fill
types or field values toca system has
grown big and some our mistakes that
started seeping on the map like some of
my internal checks were editor opposite
up not much like a hundred texts on the
home world but some mappers made a big
deal out of it with posts and a lot of
Diaries with discussions of forum foul
maths me is destroying their map with
their stags that can be easily cleaned
up and stuff yeah
then we found out that we broke in some
addresses in some parts by translating
the street names it is really a big deal
and we're working on fixing that well we
fixed it in the application but there
are some left but nobody in opposite map
virtually nobody has noticed it and
which I think proves that mappers are
not concerned with data quality and
mostly with maps me but still and the
licensing issue we see a lot of well
some people that are adding thousands of
addresses onto the map using our
application but we're not sure they're
using proper sources or open license
sources but we can check it not sure we
can what we can do with it right so to
go a bit back first this is really great
application and it allows you to add a
lot of places to update open hours and
stuff if you like to improve the map and
a lot of people are using it so when we
had the editor I finally mapped a show
you know my home which has which I was
too lazy to map for previous two years
stuff and OpenStreetMap is not only
great it in most cases the only choice
you have when you need to when you need
need a map and of course will have it
very much and I myself bill being on the
board adore it very much but underneath
all the all the success stories so the
great data the data module of opposite
nap is not as good as it could be so if
you try to do the simple editor for
people who don't care for OpenStreetMap
who inator
not for ten thousands of people who know
how to choose text from ten thousand
different texts they use you know that
taking wiki pages sound like 50 screens
long and it's impossible to select so we
wanted just to make an it or for
millions of people just to make it
easier and when you try to Mary Mary
there too is the opposite map data model
most times you feel like this and there
is always something for that you need to
fix yeah but we're still working on that
we're improving validation and other
companies are looking for quality of
data so yeah with that are not big
problems just things we're working
working on and nothing from the start
opposite my project like any open
project out there wanted to have more
editors it was its goal since day one I
guess and in the last year the number of
its daily contributors has doubled from
three to six thousand editor daily and
it's great and maps me has contributed
to a lot and pokémon's
Canty visited but that's another funny
story and somehow mappers are not happy
they've got thousands new contributors
but well not as great as they'd hoped so
I guess the lesson is be careful what
you wish for
Yeah right
I guess we have a lot of time patience
well first our yeah do I think that
opposite map would survive a coordinated
big attack on it and first they pay slow
enough that you can add a lot of data in
the short time and if you do there are
always backups from a previous day from
the previous hour and if it's really bad
and the map is broken then you can just
revert it all the history is stored so
it's not big deal and well our system
means up pretty active and they tend to
notice this stuff early on right about
maps me on f-droid that's not for us we
don't plan to support an F droid version
but all the code is open it's on github
so anyone can build an Android version
and the main barrier for publishing it
on F droid was that nobody could find a
server to host their own version of maps
so if you have a server with just 40
gigabytes of disk drive you can go to
every f-droid ticket in math nice easy
tracker and offer your help and that way
we can have an F Jewett version right I
can answer questions for OpenStreetMap
for maps me whatever
right a question about maps me slowing
down in the in past months I guess
well obviously when you're improving
application gets slower this time but
first of course it's all for reason
because for example just a month ago we
edit real-time traffic information and
to render it is to get some processor
time from other things so it gets more
slow and stuff so yeah it gets slower
but we have really great graphics team
graphic engine team so they're working
on improving things a bit so yeah it
will be just you have to wait yes it is
a companies that that was bought by a
Russian company mail.ru it has long
around 20 people of them around 13 are
programmers and yeah it's not a separate
company its subdivision but we're pretty
independent
the business model of maps may currently
there isn't one that's sustainable we
still spend more money than we earn but
last year we started to make partnership
with our other companies like you can
book hotels from WebSphere we are
booking.com and you can call it an uber
and some other stuff so we have these
partnerships and we have some plans to
make it sustainable but it's absolutely
not in an experience of the core
functions it will always function of
line it will not send some private
information to servers so the core
functions and security status thing