it works with Mac Book I'm gonna fight
it yep
please sign them
I'll introduce you and then we can get
started okay so welcome all thank you
for saying the let's last lightning talk
of today we have Andrea freaking Mundy
talk to us please give him a big round
of applause and Floyd shows hi everybody
I'm and Rafa c'mon yeah let's talk about
how to write a novel using an
open-source software introduction to be
Bisco the story of the disco started in
1997 when we are published her third
album homogenic the trunk number four
was the beautiful Bachelorette at that
time I was 22 years old and I used to
watch the video of the song on the
newborn MTV Italy the video features
Bjork has a Bachelorette a young woman
who finds a book buried in her garden
that begins to write itself
she takes the book to a publishing house
and the book becomes so popular that
everyone in the city start reading it
ever since I was a child I've loved
reading but the video impressed me so
much that I noticed she to write came
over me in that period I spent so many
nights in front of my text editor this
one writing one word after another
following the idea of the story had in
my mind but every time I read what had
written
I felt a deep disappointment I didn't
understand why but it didn't work so
after several times I give up they did
kill myself to finish in my study of
computer engineering to reading to being
a 20 year old guy but many years later I
happened to watch the video game on
YouTube and that urgency to write came
back over me but I decided to stunning a
different approach so I started to study
dramaturgy and everything became clearer
and I learn
some important lessons lesson number one
the idea of the novel is to write guided
only by the sacred fire of inspiration
is quite nice lesson number two the most
important the concept of each character
is the driving force of every novel but
what is exactly a conflict a comedy is a
a desire to be realized is a reaction to
an external situation it is an inner
need conflict leads a Carter to action
and to change the condition of things
so a novel is the story of a change in
the condition of things and of the
evolution of characters during this
process there is no novel without
conflict that's it so it's all about
characters and novels only work if their
characters are believable characters
that are completely good or completely
evil are stereotypes and for these are
not believable characters are believable
when you can understand the complexity
of their human nature their qualities
their defects the contradictions so how
can create a believable characters the
only way is to know everything about
them behavior the physical aspects
sociology psychology all their life
before the novel begins with this
lessons learn I decided to get do--make
artist through a long series of
questions such as an interview so I
provide a Carter sheet on a simple text
document like this when I start to fill
in the form the cards graduate took
shape became real it was wonderful
because they were telling me their
stories and I just had to listen and
write down what they said when I
completed fill in the forms I was ready
to write the first thing of my novel
but soon I found myself lost in a
mountain out of the text document files
I tried to organize everything in
folders on my notebook but but wasn't
enough what I really needed was a normal
development environment a unique program
in which defined the architectural
elements of the novel to know my
characters to write my scenes with a
fully featured text editor I looked for
a soft like this but I couldn't find it
so I decided to make it myself because I
thought I'm a developer I have the
superpower of create things I soon
realized that project was complex and
ambitious but at the same time was
extremely exciting because it was my
project and I felt deep sense of
well-being a fulfillment in seeing my
literary soul and my computer soul which
said I have always considered as opposed
merging in the construction of something
new I used to work at the project in the
free time ahead after my family and my
professional activities and my mantra
becomes what have you done today for the
Bisco after Twitter was at least the B's
41.0 in the April 2014 Alice has to be
based on the GPL 2.0 the project was
well received and the help of the early
adopter were crucial they helped me to
find months they suggested me new
feature they translated the news from
their own languages they support the
project with posts and article the
supported me with beautiful messages I
had never received as a computer
consultant and this is the magic of the
open-source community where people from
all over the world
without knowing each other work together
to build something beautiful for the
benefit of all okay let's have a look a
brief look at the application the
viscosity is divided into section each
one accessible from the main menu bar in
the project section
there are some useful tips of dramaturgy
that can help riders especially the
beginners to find their workflow in the
architecture section you can define the
architectural elements of the oval there
is the premise the public contains the
entire narration of the third level in
one sentence conflict and resolution we
have the fabula the fabulous narration
of the ends in the enduro logical and
chronological sequence then we have the
settings the description of place time
and social context where the story is
developed then we have the narrative
strands each one connected to the
development on one specific conflict
fabric are as it's a status flag to
indicated the steps of the work by
default is red for to do and but you can
easily change it to yellow for not yet
complete or green for complete you can
define your architectural elements using
the discotheques Toledo is a fully
featured text editor with all the usual
command for bold italic underline and
for the other formatting needs there are
also a specific comments and shortcuts
for the dialogue symbols on the bottom
right you have a running the word in the
character count while in the bottom left
where you can change the status flag
this is the character section in the
culture section is divided into main
character in the secondary characters a
main card is a conflict a driving force
of the plot while a secondary car tests
don't have a conflict but it's use is
useful for the story development let's
go inside our main characters detail
here we can find all the cars that you
need to know everything about your
character and every car as its status
flag and we also have a card for the
attachment of the images over your
character in each car is a series of
questions that let you know your car
turn through an interview if you don't
like an interview mode that you
describe a particular aspect of your
cartel using a freelance mode in the
location section you can describe the
location of your novel and you can
attach images at every location and this
is the chapter section the chapter
section contains the chapter of course
of the novel and every chapter as its
card with its a status flag and its
count badge and you can use the
drag-and-drop to reorganize chapter
inside the novel let's go inside our
chapter detail view here we can find a
card to indicate the main purpose of the
chapter and account for the notes then
you can create the chapter by creating
the individual scenes every screen as
its card with the status flag and word
count badge you can use drag-and-drop to
reorganize the scene inside your chapter
visco saves all the revision of your
scene that you can always view or a
store a previous version when you write
your scene you can always view the
architectural elements of the normal car
test location and chapters we have
already written in a box next to the
text title it was extremely useful
because it's the one problem the novel
development environment you can also
target the scene with name of stock
characters point of view location time
and narrative strands if you tagged
probably the scene you can use in this
section it was a very interesting
because the analysis section show you
where and how often characters location
point of view narrative strengths show
up in your story and in exactly what
chapter all in a visual way for example
here you can see the chapter the Carter
distribution through in the chapters of
the audio Norman and he here you can see
the chapter length graph
finally in the export section it's
possible to export the novel in PDF RTF
or as archive some numbers at the moment
we despise more than 40,000 downloads
and is translated in 8 languages miss
quiz 1 is the one of the 7 cool little
open-source projects that stood out in
2016 in the ear book of open source code
come let's get one more technical the
actual version of this with the 1.5 1.6
is a Java desktop application that is
available on Linux Mac Windows is it's
written with eclipse absolutely
framework but but the user interface is
written in html5 and JavaScript for this
reason the next release of abisco
2.0 will be a full fully html5 and
JavaScript application and I will use
electron framework baguette up to write
the next release here there are some
reference to get in touch with the
project these we have we have a website
we have a blog we have a mail of the
project personal mail if you have a
Facebook page we have a Twitter page and
of course we have our github repository
about me and I'm a graphical and I am 41
years old I'm from Bologna north of
Italy and I'm a family man and I love my
beautiful wife and my two kids I'm a
passion software engineer named a city
on a software awesome Bologna love books
music movies that will sync battle and
label I have not yet written my novel
but but if it's true that a person is
happy when is able to fully develop its
potential I can say with certainty that
we Bisco made me unhappy opers better
thank you very much Andre I think we
have some time for questions so Annie
take us I see a hand over there can you
wait one second and I'll bring the
microphone off to you okay so how can
you use all your cards like you
described them in your PDF or something
as a graph you know and use like I don't
know something like BDD programming you
know and order generate like words or
using some adjectives or some I don't
know some stuff about the characters in
order generate like chapters or
relationships because between the
characters and so on are you asking me
about the relation of their kind yeah if
I I know it's possible but have you ever
thought of it and with your contributors
slide but at the moment you can write it
in the sheet or in the curse of the
characters but I mean I'm thinking about
to insert a mind map to map the
calculations in the next release of the
disco I do know of any success stories
in these in your software with actual
books published okay we have just in the
start of the this year we have started a
blog to collect some success story and
we have we are waiting for the success
story of our users to publisher in the
spread
so any other questions spear and raise
of there
hi I tried to run be Bisco on Linux
distribution with open JDK and it didn't
work because it seems that to be
basically niché's version ships with the
Oracle Java client Java server
implementation he said like consider the
bug because you mention open source a
lot so ok I have to what I have to if
you open an issue on a guitar I can work
on it maybe but it's a in the next
version of visco we it's a full
JavaScript html5 and so there is no
general problems ok so I think we have
time for one last question if there are
any take us at the moment not at the
moment oh I we are thinking about it
but we so what format do you use for
saving the data in Bisco ok at the
moment you using a local database hh2
database is a local database in java but
in the next release the 2.0 I I think
about using a simple JSON file to store
everything in then I don't understand
the question I'm sorry ok ok
I think about it but I able to it's
difficult for me at the moment have an
Austin the
do that okay as I prefer the people
download on another machine yes yes it's
also this aspect
so I'm sorry that's all the time we have
Andrea thank you very much thank you
[Applause]