all righty
hi there hello to everyone listening and
watching on the Internet
my name is Jose this is a sheikh we're
here to talk about hyper-converged
persistent storage for containers with
cluster FS all right
we just I just recently came down from
giving a five minute version of this
presentation a couple hours ago some say
little jest from that's a bear with me
or from plucking a little fast all right
so who are we
I'm Jose I work for Red Hat I'm a member
of the kubernetes third sig and still of
the Samba team they haven't kicked me
out yet I work on in a mostly
integration to work with container
platforms distributed storage systems
Network protocols and things like that
most recently I helped develop a tool
for deploying destra fest into
hyper-converged scenario and kubernetes
and we'll be demonstrating that later on
in this presentation I am a so I
work mostly on Leicester
containerization and the integration
part with Cuban it is an open shift so I
I kind of contribute around all the
components which is required for the
integration and that's about it
alrighty so in this presentation we're
gonna go over you know a little bit of
obviously why we're doing this and what
problem were even trying to solve we're
gonna go over what it took to solve this
problem and that's gonna be a lot of a
fair amount of technical detail as to
how we created hyperconvergence that way
and then we're going to have
unfortunately not a live demo because
you know networking at this conference
so I recorded a video that we're gonna
be talking over instead all right why
are we doing this so basically we found
we could solve a profound a problem that
we could solve effectively containers
being ephemeral in nature or wanting to
be a feral
nature conflicts with a lot of
traditional and even just modern and
even some modern applications that just
cannot be ephemeral and stateless they
need storage and they need storage to
persist between you know service outages
or restart of the service to do
persistent storage especially in
especially in kubernetes usually
involves investment in some sort of
external infrastructure whether it be an
on-site storage solution like like an
ass device or something or going to or
going to a cloud cloud backed storage
solution if so requires a fair amount of
investment whether it's on one honkin
piece of hardware that you then have to
service or some bit of storage that you
have to rent out in month after month
and we wanted to do something that cuts
that cost down as much as possible while
at the same time being relatively
transparent and easy to use both for
administrators create using providing to
storage and users wanting to make use of
that storage and while we're at it let's
make it free and open source with the
support of community because we're Red
Hat all right so our target platforms
are kubernetes and OpenShift because Red
Hat and the technologies we're using to
solve this problem are ghost ifs and
Poquette e those are their cute little
logos up there and the URLs you can
catch these slides online right now
actually I just uploaded them yesterday
all right so blister us is a distributed
software-defined file system it creates
what are called bricks which are just
what what most people know as logical
volumes on on on starch devices so you
take a starch device you put partitions
on it and usually those partitions can
then become bricks those bricks are then
put together into Gluster volumes which
can be accessed from any node in the
cluster
so if you have a client that's trying to
access your your Gloucester cluster you
can go to any one of the nodes to any
one of the server nodes and they will
all have access to the volumes that they
know about some interesting some cool
things about this is that Gloucester was
designed to run on commodity hardware
there's a link up there show for a blog
post showing it running on a Raspberry
Pi
it has a scale out design meaning that
it's easy for you to expand your storage
just by adding more nodes to it
obviously I don't need to be talking too
much about this here and provides useful
features like cross node application
usage balancing a nice cozy storage axis
now the part that most people probably
won't know too much about hey kitty
hey Cuddy is the restful volume
management interface for Gloucester FS
it allows you a consistent and
programmatic interface for performing
most of the common Gluster volume
management pass like creating volumes
deleting volumes expanding the size of
volumes etc it can manage multiple
clusters from a single instance multiple
Gluster clusters specifically from a
single instance and it's fairly
lightweight reliable and simple by
design when you put it all together it
looks something like this where you have
your kubernetes or openshift cluster
running various pods in it one of which
will be your Hettie pod for your restful
api if it goes down obviously kubernetes
will just move it around or spin up a
new one
somewhere around somewhere in the
cluster and then you have various
Gloucester Gloucester pods that are all
logically joined together into one
cluster cluster on top of the kubernetes
cluster and each node has some store
some nodes as you can see there have
some storage attached to it doesn't all
have to be it doesn't have to be perfect
mirrors of each other across the
topology it can vary some can have three
disks some can have two and then you
just put your Gloucester pod on whatever
node is running storage and now you can
access that storage via cluster
and you can find out and you can find
our work that it that we put into sort
of glue all this together on the
glycerin eighties project on github URL
is up there it documents how we put all
this together and how you can put this
together in your own setups provides an
easy-to-use deployment tool that thing I
mentioned I worked on earlier and has a
QuickStart guide for those who want to
start playing with it right away in VMs
or on bare metal whatever you choose all
right so that's kind of the set up of
what we're doing and what we decided to
what we decided to do about it now
here's how it all happened hi so when we
started converging the blest repairs on
kubernetes or open ship first ask for us
was to containerized Lister
so Glessner was mostly system software
kind of a thing but it was user space
software but it it it was dependent on
those nodes more so because of the
devices which we need to access to
create the volumes so this is how the
docker command looks like if you run it
it's pretty big and that is the
kubernetes ml file which we have so what
we faced when we container is Lestrade's
what I'm going to talk about now it's
just these are the issues which we faced
so come in Gloucester runs more than one
process from blister so it has its brick
process running under it and it has its
sponsored separately and it it has its
own interface serving service running so
these these processes need to be ran
along with Lester's so we needed a
container which can hold more than one
process so we move to system D with Dan
was help so we moved to system D and
then we needed privileges because we
were running a system D container and
then this startup script I will explain
about the scott startup script little
bit later and
the buy mounts for the glacier
configuration so these configurations
shouldn't be moving around along with
the containers so it should be spawned
on the same node with the same
configuration when the glacier goes down
and comes back up so we need we buy
mounted from the host and the devices
were buy mounted from the host and we
use we prefer using horse networking for
better performance so this is basically
what I am supposed to tell yes system D
container so we needed someone to manage
all over the process all the glycerate
process which we run to clean it up and
also we need more support to run lister
containers because we add more process
before running before running Lester I
mean when we wanted a containerized
Lester so we needed system D and
privileges we don't need privileges
anymore for system D to run in a
container because of the OCD OCI system
D hooks so we don't actually need system
D mid privileges for system D container
but we need privileged container for
accessing the devices and to create the
Elvis from the container so we create
logical volume from Gloucester container
for Lester to use it and the startup
script is just a initial script which we
run which does all the things that and
rpm installation does before running
cluster so in case of upgrade this
script will take care of doing
versioning for Lester which we do in rpm
installation or rpm upgrade so we needed
a placeholder for these things to do so
we have a initial setup script which
does these things in the container and
these are those persisting
configurations we need from the host so
Waddle Abdullah study is required to
manage all the glyceryl volume
configuration that's where that's the
working directory of glister that's
where we store all the context of
glisters and the Hualapai service is
just a log and easy Cygnus Rufus is the
configuration file for the glossary
which is a manage
demon of glister so all the
configurations for that is in a DC glass
surface so by mount devices so we we had
to buy mount the /dev inside the
container but the initial plan was to
create the LVS on the host and give the
elvis to the container and then use it
so that we can get rid of /div but it
was really hard to scale because when
you want to create one more volume when
you create another LV it's it was tough
to create a done on the host and then
buy mounted again because you have to
bring down the container and bring it
back up with the node so we decided to
put /dev inside the container we had lot
of issues with judah and it is solved
now so it is working completely fine
with /dev I'm outing inside the
container it does not mess up your host
device so first Network host network we
could have done the we could have
maintained same host name for the
container and still use glister which
could have but we just thought it will
be one more network hop instead we can
use the horse network as we are not
moving listed pots around so we we use
lesser host networking for cluster
containers basically and it gives better
performance for because it's a network
segment then container raising equity
hecka tea container using was not that
tough so before telling this what
hickety does it it gets all these mean
let's say if three nodes are there in
the cluster and you install lesser on
all these three nodes and there are
three devices on each so you hand over
these devices to hickety so when hickety
starts with this topology file
Hecate goes and peer probes with all
these nodes that's what we call in
cluster terms like creating a storage
pool this is how it forms a pool we peer
pro from one node to another and form a
pool and then hickety goes inside these
devices create
the pv required and the VG required for
those devices and when you give a
request of volume from equity it comes
to the Glessner nodes it has a ring
algorithm inside which decides where the
bricks will land so it it takes each
devices and creates logical volumes from
each device let's say replica three
volume if you want it goes to three
nodes and creates bricks on each node
and then creates a volume out of it so
that if one node goes down the volume
will be still serving that's why we use
replica three mostly in this solution we
ask prefer replica three so hickety does
this volume creation for you you don't
have to actually worry about the Glasser
commands it is really easy with Hecate
ii on it and it needed it has its own
database to store all these
configurations of these are the nodes
and these are the devices which which
blesser can make use of so it stores
that in the DB which was really a
problem for us because the DB will go
down when when a big heavy pot goes down
so what we thought of doing was creating
a glycerol um-- for it and putting the
DB inside the volume when they Kathy
comes up so that's what we do we give
persistent volume and we use it as well
and and it was rickety was using through
SSH now we move the cube exit which
needed few secrets in the equity pod so
we also need to create a service account
which will be used by equity to access
the Glessner pots that's all about
equity container raising and deployment
and usage so persistent storage in point
of cuban it is an open shift they have
lot of volume plugins inside if you all
know so volume plug-in is just a way for
different kind of storage providers to
use their volumes so in case of glycerol
you what we do is we have a gloucester
volume plugin inside cuban it is if you
want to use a glycerol um-- inside your
part you will mention the
be of the node and the volume name in
the mean in your volume mount section
what internally the kubernetes volume
plugin does it it will by mom mean it
will mount the glass surface on the host
and then by mount that mount point to
the container wherever you specify for a
persistent volume so that's how our
volume plugin works in the kubernetes
world and there are two ways to
provision volumes one is static
provisioning so you request for a volume
in cuba release unix request for volume
through persistent volume claim and
admins will create persistent volumes
which will be back ended by some network
storage provider can be amazon can be
gloucester can be self can be anything
so so he has to create a static probe it
so admin has to go back in and create
the volume and give it to the customers
or users in the kubernetes as a
persistent volume when a user asked for
a persistent volume claim if there was a
persistent volume which will support the
persistent volume claim it will get
bound if it is not there then you have
to request the admin and he will create
it and give it to you that's what static
provisioning means I mean that is static
reasoning and dynamic provisioning is
when you have a storage class defined in
your kubernetes saying this is the
storage pool and if someone requests you
for a storage go back end and create a
storage for you so that is what the
storage class does so now when you
create a persistent volume claim you
will specify the storage class it will
go to the crew go to the network
management network storage and create a
volume and mount it on the persistent
volume claim so that is what dynamic
provisioning means that's what we do in
Leicester in the kubernetes so when a
persistent volume claim comes with
request for a volume from Leicester
admin has
admin does not have to do anything it
just goes back in and creates a volume
from the glacier pole and
it creates a PV for it and admin the PVC
is bound automatically to the PV so this
is persistent volume claim and
persistent volume and stories class so
dynamic provisioning this is what I was
explaining so dynamic provisioning it
has a storage class storage class is a
way to define your back-end storage so
this this is your storage this is your
URL and these are the option to create a
volume is what you give in the storage
class mostly I will show you how the
cluster storage class looks like so we
have a persistent volume claim which
which is nothing but a user request for
a volume and persistent volume is the
actual volume which is back-end network
storage and the PVC is bound with the PV
based on the volume size and access
modes so this is how it works
dynamic provisioning you get a claim
with and it points to a storage class it
goes behind to the storage and creates a
persistent volume for you and attaches
it to the persistent volume claim so if
you can see that the name of the storage
class is Lester and provisional the API
and the endpoint is the point where you
have all that lester ip's mentioned for
using those volumes and the rest URL is
the URL where riccati is running so all
the requests from the storage class will
go to the equity and equity will create
a volume for you read the rest user and
the user key is also for equity so this
is the name username for you at the end
it is a user key which hickety wants to
use to access and create volumes to use
a glister volume inside a container
these these two things are important in
point and service so endpoints define
where that lester volume is so if you if
you if you have created a replica 3
volume say
so it is from three notes we specify
that all three IP in the endpoint file
and service is used to access those IPs
and these are the options which you can
specify in the storage class so as he
already said hickety manages more than
one cluster of a cluster so let's say
you have two cluster clusters one has
faster storage SSDs and one as smaller
means slower storage devices and you can
mention those cluster IDs here which is
which is created from riccati so you can
create you can create a storage class
which will create a volume from this
faster storage cluster of bluster and
you can create a storage class from the
slower accessible volumes so that idea
is given Omega T and you can create that
you can mention that in the storage
class so that only that volumes are only
that cluster is used to create this
volumes and they user name is again the
same hickety user names and for security
we have GID so these are options which
you can use if you want to secure your
wash bin contents in a word persistent
volume so only if you have them exact
GID that you requested in your part
that's when you can use this volume so
if you don't know the GI DS which you
are going to use in your part and the
wall on the GID of the volume if this
doesn't match you cannot use the volume
or you cannot see the content of the
volume so you have user has a user has a
mean secure way to create a volume and
put his data inside so that no one else
who has access to these volumes can
still read the data or right into the
data right into the volume so this is it
all righty thanks chic well thanks a
sheik at this point we've achieved
[Music]
effectively full hyperconvergence as
mentioned gloucester FS and hickety now
running containers with with within
kubernetes these are just some
iterations of things we said earlier in
the presentation
yeah it's about right so now is where I
would normally be showing you a live
demo but unfortunately I destroyed my my
demo cluster so instead I'm gonna try
and talk over this video I recorded
which hopefully will be visible enough
especially for the people watching at
home already
so we're starting with a three node
kubernetes cluster one master three
nodes and we're running nothing other
than kubernetes the kubernetes service
so now we're going to run our GK deploy
tool with a couple options and a
topology file I should mention the
topology filing question is just a
properly formatted JSON file that
describes the layout of or describes
which note which IP addresses correspond
to the servers and are going to have a
cluster that are going to be running
cluster and also a listing of the
devices on their servers that to get
that heck Hettie is going to be
co-opting for use with Glosser FS
alright so at this point we have started
label we have started deploying woofster
on the nodes that we specified here the
containers are spinning up on those
nodes this should take only a couple
seconds and now we're deploying Tecate
so as you mentioned one of the things we
had to do is that we needed to store
piketty's databases somewhere that was
persistent so what we do is that we
bring up hick heady one time and
generate a debt and use it to generate a
dead a database file then we go through
heck Ettie
to create a Gloucester volume within the
cluster that it's managing so here in a
couple seconds you'll see that that's
the output from letting the topology
file and adding all the devices so now
we're creating a list of all um-- and
then copying the contents of our
database into that gloucester volume we
just created and then killing the deploy
hickety pod as we call it and then
spinning up a new Acadie pod that uses
that glister volume we just created to
run its database and now hey katie is
running and let's see to show you here
come on there I go all right we are
running several Gloucester pods and one
Caqueta pod and an endpoint service all
right
so now I'm going to show you a quick
demonstration to air-quote prove that
we're using persistent storage
underneath here we have a Gloucester
storage class that is there's an example
of what it looks like
notice that we specified the endpoints
at the endpoint and URL in the storage
class this is all being done whether in
the guise of an administrator setting
this up so this first step would be the
administrator studying up the storage
class we specify the Emma file and it's
done all right so now we're moving into
user land we're gonna create a PVC a
persistent volume claim as a as someone
tried to deploy an application in
kubernetes rather than providing
kubernetes so we create this persistent
volume claim llamó file and you know we
have an access method as to how many
people should be accessing this and we
want to size that's all fairly standard
persistent volume stuff or just storage
stuff in general the only thing to
notice there is that we're using a
specific storage class name that
corresponds to the storage class our
administrator provided for us so then we
cube control create the cluster PVC and
it's done all right so now we're gonna
try and roll out an application for this
demonstration I'm just going to use
a relatively simple and gen-x
application you know it it listens on
port 80 it serves on port 80 it uses the
nginx slim container image and it mounts
a glister volume to store its main HTML
files so we're going to create this
resource and it's underway so we created
a service and a pod and now if we go
look they're all running so now I just
go and curl at this URL just to show you
that it's running or that IP address and
sure enough it's running so now I have a
little test file where I pre wrote a a
quick line to insert some data into the
index.html of the nginx server we are
now running and sure enough if we curl
the same address again we get hello
world from Gloucester FS now I'm going
to I believe delete yes I'm going to
delete the nginx service I just created
deleted I'm going to delete the pod that
I just created one I typed so slow okay
and then get all to show that it's to
show that it's not running anymore and
then we go back and create the thing
again and it's creating note that this
time the service has a new IP address so
this is a new service new pod using the
same storage and then if we try to curl
the same address again it's not gonna
work because the old service is gone and
it's been given a new IP address so we
grabbed a new IP address curl that and
hello world from Gloucester FS all right
now I wish I could show you the real
sexy thing which is where you take down
a Gloucester node and it's all still
running because obviously three-way
replicate
but trying to do that thing that's
exactly what killed by virtual
environment because I use libvirt
snapshots and I forgot to take it out to
undo the snapshot when I was taking down
the node so things got messed up and I
don't have the network bandwidth at this
conference to redo my entire VM setup so
apologies for that
[Music]
all right demos and with 15 minutes left
we're done that's it for the main
presentation you can find us on github
and supposedly me on Twitter though I
don't use that as often as maybe I
should here we have a couple URLs to the
various projects that we've mentioned
and are working on so with that we are
ready to take your questions
well in the back there in the gray shirt
that is currently being worked on the
question was I see the question was is
there a hump there are we considering or
working on a helmet art to deploy all
this instead of using a instead of you
say a deploy script the answer is yes
we are working on a helmet right here
okay so can we say a little bit about
the chicken and egg problem of the fact
that we're using a district volume to
store the database that manages our
cluster volumes that is indeed a known
chicken and egg problem the only reason
we're doing that is because we needed
something to persist the database
between restart to facchetti
that we didn't want to be bound to a
particular host so we didn't just want
to use local storage on any particular
node so we figured hey we're providing
to storage let's just throw the dip
let's just throw the database in there
this is kind of awkward but it works for
now we're currently exploring other
things to sort of distribute the
database like using that's using sed as
a database store for instance or just a
slightly longer term product of getting
rid of the database entirely and just
trying to read information from the
nodes directly but that requires some
modifications on the Gluster side as
well
all right any other questions
that's a backpack all right we got one
sure
a scaling preference excuse me
well scheduling okay so if there's a
skit the question was if there was in
kubernetes if there's a scheduling
preference when a node goes down in a
new one needs to be spun up is that
right
okay if the pod gets restarted and
there's already a volume about and
there's already a volume mounted for
that pod I would I don't know
specifically but best I've seen it just
gets it just gets remounted to the new
pod so the vault the volume the volume
never gets detached from the persistent
volume claim unless the PVC itself is
deleted so there's so there's the slight
distinction between the PVC the PVC and
the PV yeah again yes
Oh like that okay so is there a
scheduling preference on whether the pod
will be restarted on the same node that
already has its volume mounted on to the
node and I don't know for certain
my current observation of just as a
kubernetes user indicates yes that I
will just get started started on the on
the node that already has the storage
mounted right you there I couldn't tell
you the question was what does the
person comes between HDFS and cluster of
us I have no idea officially all right
there was something down here okay yes
what same way same script yes the same
script handles both kubernetes and
OpenShift
one thing I don't show in there is it
will automatically detect whether you're
running kubernetes or OpenShift
and if for some reason it detects both
it'll ask you if you want to do either
kubernetes or openshift ideally you
shouldn't have both but there have been
some strange configuration cases where
it can detect both so it just lets you
choose but yes the same script will do
both let's go back up there since he's
been waiting any non containerized tools
oh okay so the question was do you need
any extra any non containerized tools
for using the Gloucester volumes is that
right
okay best I know the let's see the other
thing you'll need is that you need the
what's called the hick Hettie Hettie CLI
or hi kitty client say that again and
yes you need Gloucester clients
installed on all the nodes on all the
nodes that are running Gloucester and
you also need to open a couple firewall
ports that Gloucester needs to be able
to communicate with itself and its other
member nodes the Gloucester processes
run in containers but it needs access to
the raw host system in order to do most
of its actual job so the processes
themselves are containerized but the
tests it needs to do require actually
require access to the actual storage
devices I believe so
all right anyone else this side of the
room back over here aha
the question was can we do storage
tiering not automatically but you as an
admit us an administrator can define can
define this via storage classes of
course you have to communicate that
information to your user somehow so you
would create usually the standard
demonstration is you create a gold
storage class a silver in a silver
storage class and then you just tell
your users all right gold is like super
fast non-volatile memory access
silver is SSDs and then like Stone is
you know spinning rust all right
anything else doesn't seem like it I'm
calling a dumb thank you very much
[Applause]