good
so if you have any questions about
prometheus and/or graph honor this is
now a Q&A session because reasons does
anyone have questions
sure testing testing so many questions
for permit about me as a user of influx
TV short explanation difference between
influx and so the question is the
difference between influx TV and media
so I guess the main difference is that
Prometheus is a full monitoring system
which comes basically was end-to-end so
we have instrumentation libraries that
you can use for instrumentation
instrumenting your codes then we have
export us for a bunch of different tools
that out there like my sequel so that's
the instrumentation side let's come
about from easiest and then we're
parisa's itself which is the monitoring
system which includes a time series
database as well as actually the
collection so it can talk to service
discovery systems to detect what is out
there to be monitored and then fetch the
instrumented and metrics right and then
you flip every language on top and you
of the alerting on top and your field of
management i'm so basically whole chain
from imitation happen for graphing and
everything is covered by Prometheus
where syntax to be is first and foremost
time since database of course there are
also tools but they are sort of more in
spend alone manner I would say so I
would say it's like you know if we're
going to try and compare apples to
apples we need to compare Telegraph in
flux capacitor to previous exporters and
not the client libraries because in flux
doesn't have those and then you've got
Prometheus and then you've got the alert
manager because that's the fair
comparison because those are roughly the
same things and and there's
architectural differences there so on
the way I see in flux is prometheus is a
metric system you just saw my talk those
of you are here and metrics give you
breaths not deaths in flux I see is
actually an event logging system sort of
the log system that's actually are also
fairly good at doing metrics like it can
ingest graphic data but it's
fundamentally is an event logging system
not a metric system so that's kind of
how I see a difference and then like
capacitor I would like it is fairly
powerful but like all the things people
say with me it doesn't scale
horizontally it turns out yeah capacitor
uses the exact same way as skating out
that Prometheus does which is you get to
vertically shard which I find amusing
and so that's the way it seemed like if
you're looking at something like say
IOT the obvious choice there is in flux
all are living equal because that's
general tend to be event logging if
you're looking for a general monitoring
system you know I would suggest for me
is what I have meatiest developer do but
I'd say I would say thanks question
about alerting
in the latest saravana I want to have
some template for many many servers and
have at least when I receive I left
notify a notification I want to see the
host name what host name is - is it
possible to make I don't think I quite
understand a question I think the
questions he has a kind of dashboards
and winning it has alerts he wants to
know what house name created the alert
so so alerts in Gravano right now only
support Syria names and not tags like
server know there's something like that
eventually the alerting will also
support tags you can include know there
are Siri name or data center or
something like that but right now you
would have to format the legend to
contain the server name or data sense or
something like that I'm not sure if that
answer you
you could use a wildcards query it's
saying in graphite you would place a
star where the server is and then only
the series violating the threshold will
be included in that learn so if you have
ten thousand servers and two of them
have high CPU or something that you want
an alert on then Holy Ghost series will
be present in alert I have a question
regarding graph another sink as well
what is the roadmap for development of
distributed others in California the
roadmap will be presented later yeah I
don't wanna take bits of my talk off
right now if that's okay it'll say for
happened to be utter monitoring system
altars here as well this is the
monitoring track not to provide you some
profound track so come down
in Flex DB has pretty weird attention
schema and girl fauna doesn't work with
his retentions within flex DB how and
who will solve this problem when you
want to make some aggregation and of all
the metrics and just see them with the
same dashboard instead of creating
different dashboards for different time
periods so the question was about
retention policies in Flex to be tenant
Ravana right so we have been talking
with the influx data team and we have
not found a common way of making that
configurable in some ways so right now
you would have to configure each
dashboard for certain policies and
that's very cumbersome you could use
interval templates or something like
that for the policy selection but
there's no automated way
hello yeah what's the ETA on retention
for Prometheus I had one time that's
only a few days or a few weeks I know
either in unlimited retention from from
is Earth so do we need to put in place a
strategy to back up the data so the
question is Prometheus and long-term
data storage basically so the thing is
that Prometheus is designed for
reliability which is different from
durability and basically if you want to
have infinite retention that means
you're basically creating a distributed
storage system which is really really
really hard and in the context of
monitoring unreliable because you want a
monitoring system that if your network
starts falling apart it still keeps on
working so our approach to this is to
see the storage for medias more as a
cache which might be a few weeks of the
cache and then there's something else
which has that a long term so our
strategy is because we want to base B
total time to build one of these are
cells are busy with other stuff that we
will have interfaces and so there's all
ready to promote write code and it's
been there a few months now so
Prometheus can write out to another
system and that mode would like there's
weave works cortex which is an open
source and that can accept this data and
as other systems as well as you build
there and we're also some voids going to
add the read path as well which can read
the data back in so you can
transparently access your data and then
you know you can basically have
separation concerns that all your alerts
are based on the cache which is all
local all cypher media is all reliable
and if you want to go back more than a
few weeks or whatnot you can have the
rouse the unreliable query to your
long-term storage and if that's broken
well you've just lost graphing until you
fix that but you haven't affected your
cornering abilities but a date is that
this will be a separation concerns
between greediest and long-term storage
because we don't want that sort of CP
system with strong consistency when we
care about availability for well
alerting because I shouldn't use the
word monitoring after my own talk
alerting and
critical dashboards but not trending
next question never when I raise the mic
you can just raise your head then
because that saves time and just to be
clear day we head to the projector
working again because I've had time
slots work we need to use up time if you
have your own cell matrix storage you
have to read the system for analytics
because we're vigilant and storage
result large-scale analytics doesn't
that make sense no sorry can you repeat
the question a little closer to measure
okay with the wrong time mr wegg without
mass analytics using MapReduce or a
framework it doesn't make sense because
okay you feel better upright but we are
not very very capita bility to retrieve
it and analyze it simply no I think the
question was that only I think the
question was that only having long-term
storage without having a and ability
capability of Prometheus wouldn't work
at the answer is you should know this is
good
can you please stop talking or leave
thank you so I say the question was if I
write out over this remote White Pass
how do I read back the data what's that
the question okay so so basically answer
right now is that we have three males so
JP I said that you write out data in
arbitrary systems but there's no read
back API yet at this point I'm sort of
you can build your own on your own
remote storage integration but there's
no generic read paths at this point but
there will be hopefully within the CM is
a long time goal to work side by side
with traditional monitoring and alerting
systems like icinga well it's the
long-term goal to replace these tools I
would pretty clearly say it's they go to
replace these yeah okay I mean this
thing is mostly focused on checks and
alerting so my talk kind that goes into
this like what our approach is to sort
of solve this problem in a different way
so we're gonna come around later for
this talk you will see more so I have to
see your talk okay yeah I guess
does your talk also cover multi
datacenter application monitoring
I mean it's serious you will see that
the concept is kind of agnostic of that
right foot totally work and in in like I
want two sentences the basic ideas we
connect time series data and then we
have sort of our state of truth in terms
of sample data and then we can define
the writing on top of that and about
what we collect this data and how we
collect it it's completely separated
from the alerting layer it's sort of the
short story is what's mostly interesting
in this because what you have is multi
data centers hosting one application and
then how do you alert on what's going
wrong yeah I mean so Prometheus is
collecting time series data right so
Prometheus can monitor much for the data
centers they are like patterns how to
set it up and then we have time series
data and this is completely separated
from it and on top of that we define the
lower things so as to ice every
monitoring system that can connect time
series data in multi data center sort of
playoffs you can also load on it so
editing with Prometheus is if you can
graph on this you can alert solution and
you can certainly graph multi data
center metrics like they can see and so
on there are some reliability questions
about you know being time to be bound to
those data centers being up in order to
be able to be the nursing as well I
would generally advise as much as
possible
push dealers down to the data center
level to avoid the LAN links being on
your critical paths for alerts but if
you want to inertia like global latency
you can just be aware of reliability
implications that - depending on how you
do that you might get no alerts if your
networks dodgy what's to request so
extracting metrics from logs obviously
isn't ideal like lots of logs metrics of
metrics to your earlier point but in
terms of support for doing stuff like
that anyway these support tools like
logs - that kind of stuff as well so
long term stash is just a transport
layer and as fluent ears just moves data
from A to B so as I said in my talk long
story for breaths
so for depth and
down bred by depths you'll end up with
much information but in four communities
two tools have been written called the
croc exporter and M tail googles M tail
which can do that and fluency might also
be getting support to extract some
metrics logs because my stance on it is
like it's know if you want logs use logs
you won't use math tricks use metrics if
you only have logs well at least try to
get some metrics although most we can
fix things to be proper because let's be
honest the world isn't perfect you need
tools like these sometimes and it's
still the only way to discover this
failures is actually logs we've checked
clinics at least when I check to three
years ago Linux the knowledge sports
metrics to let you know if it is to fail
your only choice is looking for syslog
you know all those messages MIT is
failing that's how you find them only
way like now yours or less important
ones like usinga if you have an
environment which is absolutely not
cloud native and it's even not
distributed to a lot of systems but
consists of industrial controllers
robots whatever boxes which can be
checked with a small script very easily
how do you think you can you replace all
this knowledge that has been built up in
the last years you can't write exporters
for everything
Ritchie wants answered our as someone
who's not working at a cloud native
company yes so if the if you have
caching concepts in your in your
monitoring where you basically have some
notes which cache for you for higher
level of monitoring notes you have to
take that into account but it works you
just have to plan for it accordingly but
yes so even without anything dynamic or
even with really old legacy applications
we see huge benefits with promises and
performer a huge
so a little secret is that per medias
doesn't know what a container is
Prometheus does not know what a cloud is
per medias just has labels would you put
your own ideas onto so if you want to
monitor actual hardware you can like
I've got a Prometheus running at home
monitors like tree machines in the
switch don't ask why it's out of 48
ports which at home but like you can do
all these things wanting to watch though
is the trade-offs we make are the
engineering trade-offs around alcohol
we're losing a little bit of data is
better than losing monitoring if you're
talking industrial control like actual
industrial control I would be evaluating
fermius very carefully to see if the
trade-offs we've made which make total
sense from talking about web servers or
network switches whether those
trade-offs also make sense an industrial
control sense because we have made
trade-offs there in terms of precision
just to get better availability well you
have any idea how memory intensive I can
permit is get I think I have a VPS
there's a limited amount of memory and I
was pretty surprised that I made about
100 lines in the metrics file starting
like memory that seems quite loud
research this recently so the default
for Prometheus uses about four gigs of
RAM passive one for these days it's
probably down spider shrieks ish but
special vlog there's Nashville there on
it how much RAM this for me yeah also
you might have to look at the storage
flex right there like several knobs you
can configure two ways you tweak the
memory usage at runtime we kind of know
that's not ideal
and so actually we're working on a new
storage layer actually have the
benchmark running right now so hopefully
we're gonna cut down memory usage by I
don't know like 70 or 5% or something so
everything goes right who definitely go
down significantly in the next month
could the next speaker get hooked in
because we've got like five minutes into
the next talk whoever the next speaker
is so I think we can fish in one more
question follows next speakers get ready
more like so first there was a request
about putting up the slides right now so
people can look at them we will hand
them over to to our back office so to
speak and they'll put the link of the
presentation into the description of the
problem so if you want just want to look
at the slides you can go there and while
we are waiting show of hands who is
using nachos who's using a singer who's
using zabbix yay who's using prometheus
who's using graphite who's using
grandfather do you see that anything
else which I should ask or mocks -
Greylock that didn't work out the way
you wanted
what RTG well mrtg yeah with a crank on
it