Wayne and Orson I work at CERN and today
I wanted to present you a feature we
recently developed that is integration
of spice simulation engine into kicad
I'll start with a quick agenda so first
I will give you a bit of background what
were our goals and what features we
currently support then a bit of
technical details how we did that
followed by a to-do list and then live
demo hopefully it will work so how did
we start with where does the idea come
from so it was essentially a quick hack
that turned into a useful feature some
time last summer we accidentally
discovered that ngspice can be built as
a dll it was actually some Python guy
who made a very nice API and turned
ngspice simulator into a shared library
for the purpose of processing signals
within a Python based framework but we
thought well this is an easy way of
integrating a simulator into account
application and our aim was well why
don't we try making something that looks
and feels a bit like the world non-free
but industry-standard ltspice but in
kicad so our goals were to have a
simulator integrated into the eeschema
which is well the fancy name for the
kicad schematic editor that is
compatible with spice models that is
reasonably easy to use so well ideally
one click to run a simulation and that
in the longer run allows for the choice
of the simulation kernel currently we
support on the ngspice but this will
likely change in the future so what do
we support so far
we can run operating point AC and
transient analysis we have a road built
in plotting application we also support
live voltage and current probing so once
the simulation is running you can
basically click on to a component or or
a wire the schematic the automatically
updated plot with the corresponding
signal value think of it as a virtual
scope probe and another nice feature is
that we can adjust the values of the RCL
components in the real time
this lets you observe as the operation
of the circuit changes when live so how
did we implement it basically the
simulator is a separate key card
application that is linked together with
the schematic editor so we have to edit
or frames the schematic frame and
associated simulator that frame that
runs in our in a separate window and
then they both use an abstract class
called
spice simulator which provides an
abstract API that is that is simulation
kernel independent provided that the
simulation kernel supports a spice
compatible netlist then we specialize
that class for instance here to ng spice
and then use lib ng spice Tata so or a
despised or DLL the dynamic library
using its native API this way we can
provide as many back and says we want
right so what is on our to-do list it's
still an experimental feature and it
lacks a lot contour to cooks for
instance so we would like to have to add
more analyzes types for instance
transfer functions noise analysis the
plotting app is a bit quirky for the
moment so it deserves a bit of user
interface fixes
we also like to have storage of the
simulation sessions in files we need to
work on the printing and PDF export the
well one ambitious feature that we don't
know if it will ever happen yes support
for micro a simulation probably it
through through another kernel I cook
satyr
the support for Ibis models for for
signal integrity simulations then the
last point is about life tuning of also
sources and parametric variables as we
currently only support our CL components
so I'm gonna make a short demo showing a
basically I will draw a simple circuit
and simulate it just to show you how how
it looks like before that well under
under Windows you just need to download
nightly I think the same applies to the
OS X it comes already with built-in
spice support under Linux you need Lib
ngspice installed and most likely you
need to compile from the sources so here
are the magical incantations to do that
just remember to have Lib ngspice
installed it's available in most distros
as a package and remember to be it with
the key cat underscore spice flag
enabled ok so it's time for the demo
so let's try designing something simple
like rectifier or something like this so
most spice components are in the P spice
library let's take a voltage source and
then in order to edit it spice
parameters we need to go to the
properties and select edit spice model
here you have a user-friendly way of
entering all the sorts of source or
component parameters so let's say 5
volts sine of 1 kilohertz then let's add
maybe a resistor
maybe another one
a diode
and some capacitor for small thing
and now while some values
let's keep some more or less reasonable
and wire it all together
of course we need to add a ground net
because every single ator needs that as
a reference node otherwise it won't work
and let's annotate the schematic so that
every component has a unique name and
maybe label a bita for a bunch of wires
I'll save current ass okay so now
in order to launch the simulation we
have a simple circuit done go to tools
simulator and then well it's easy run
stop simulation well it reminds me that
I forgot to select the analysis type and
duration so yeah we need to go to the
settings and let's write transient so
let's say 10 microseconds times that 10
milliseconds total run so no errors so
now let's put serve some signals in the
circuit for that we have either the at
signals option where you can basically
pick from all the units available in the
design or we can use the probe tool
but for some reason it is all flat did I
do something wrong yeah I think so
and it spice model transient singer saw
it down strange maybe I forgot to save
it so it defaulted to zero okay now it
should work
so yeah let's restart the simulation
voila the other thing is that I
connected the diode with this polarity
but there is something wrong the plot is
upside down right it's in the negative
half so you know there was a common
problem with kicad libraries when the
transition was done before one between
one version of library and the other and
this changed the node mapping so if
you're not in the spice model editor we
provided the means for for overcoming
such such problems and also for adapting
your symbols to spice models which might
have arbitrary terminal sequence so here
we can invert this and this applies to
all the components so now it's as it
should be what else so I mentioned that
we have like tuning of the component
values so let me show you how it works
so we can pick the screwdriver tool here
and then let's say we want to see how
the operation of the circuit changes as
we change the capacitor value so a
slider appeared here let's increase the
range a bit to like something like this
so as we increase the capacitance the
signal becomes flatter
yeah so this is not only a well a nice
feature but also something that can be
used in education - by the teachers to
show people how how the operation of the
circuit changes as they mess around with
the components on this relation let me
show you another circuit just quickly
okay I think this is not me maybe not
needed so it's basically a simple filter
so here we can also run AC simulations
and use the tuning feature to design
filters without too much math so as I
change the capacitor value the transfer
function also follows and basically
that's all I wanted to show you if there
are any questions I'm happy to answer
them thank you
oh yeah so where is it I forgot to
mention one important thing so this is a
macro this uses a macro model of an
op-amp and it's quite easy to select so
to assign so you need to edit the spice
model go to the integrated circuit tab
select a file with the corresponding IC
and in this drop-down box all the models
that in the our data read that file will
appear
can you just select it yeah standard
spice model in this case it comes from a
lot of devices right any questions so
the question was if I can add spice
directives right to the schematics yes
we can in fact we even have one here yep
you can export a spice netlist from
kicad so it's to generate netlist file
here so you can use it with an external
simulator
I didn't try but whatever spa so the
question was if I can put a white noise
as the input and see the frequency
response so you can do whatever the
ngspice provides I never tried this in
particular 'but is if we are generating
a text netlist and passing it to
dissimulate or if we are doing it in a
let's say more binary way so we just use
text the data is extracted basically as
tables in the memory but netlist is
parsed the normal way and passed to the
simulator
okay let me repeat so Orson the cold
sore of the simulator feature said that
we are not using files for for passing
the netlist instead the API provided by
ngspice basically inputs a netlist
as a string that's a big string and
that's it so there is no intermediate
files and now there was another question
whether we did a Python wrapper over
ngspice no we did not it's pure C++ so
the question is if we do have to rerun
the entire simulation in order to tweak
a value it depends how ngspice handles
it because when you change the component
value I don't think it reruns the entire
simulation setup completely it just
reruns the transient part or okay so
somebody says yes it does but well
computers are fast these days and for
for AC analysis or relatively simple
circuits it works quite in real time
so the question is if there are any
plans to annotate schematic symbols with
spice models I wish there were but I
don't think there are any such plans for
the moment this heavily depends on the
library managers when would you like to
add something
so in short people have their own
library standards every company every
designer uses concert components in a
slightly different way so there is no
gold plated solution to have you know
like a single simulation library that
will match everybody's requirements yep
so is it possible based on the schematic
to run the simulation and so on I have
this system or you can just take the
schematic on whatever the question was
if it's possible to run the simulation
from a command line on a headless system
well you can always export spice netlist
and run ng spice from the command line
is a graphical application
so the question so the question was how
do we communicate between the between
the simulator window and a schematic
editor window whether we have some IPC
protocol there is no protocol because
they both run the GUI GUI runs in a
single thread the simulator runs in a
separate thread and all the
communication between the windows is
passed through standard vics widgets
events okay so when just mentioned that
in the version six we will also have
Python scripting support for the
schematics this will allow any sort of
processing of the schematics will be
done with from within a Python script
including or perhaps simulation any
questions
[Applause]