to introduce a putz in my fight all
right thank you thank you for to FOSDEM
for having me here I apologize for my
appearance I'm from LA and I forgot that
it rained anywhere else in the world so
yeah I am Angela presto I work at Horton
works on a project management committee
member and a committer on Apache knife I
and the sub-project Apache minify and
we're gonna talk about intelligently
collecting data at the edge so I don't
know if you can quite read this its
introduction both to the application and
to myself I have been working on
security topics for about 13 years
I joined the knife I open-source team
got here as I said from LA and that's a
little bit about me so we'll talk very
briefly about what dataflow is and what
the challenges involved in collecting
the data are I apologize this is a
fairly long presentation that's been
compressed down to combine multiple
things I will stick around afterwards
for any questions but I'm gonna go
through a little bit quickly today it's
very simple right data flow is getting
data from one plate one place one point
to another we have producers so that
could be computers log files it could be
devices it could be user interaction
send it usually over the Internet and
then somebody or something needs to make
sense of that data but it's hard and
it's not the first time this problem has
tried to be solved and many people have
tried to do it in many different ways so
the classic example of 14 to 15
standards why is moving data effectively
hard because moving data is not that
hard right you can just put a modem
somewhere and you have data flow but
doing it correctly doing it effectively
doing it in a way that makes sense for
the consumers and producers of that data
is very difficult like I said we have
standards we have different formats we
have exactly once delivery right which
if anybody has worked with data before
is a really difficult problem we have
the protocol
the veracity and validity of the
information ensuring security over
comings of security which as a security
person I object to this completely
accurate statement compliance schemas
etc etc and again exactly once delivery
so we're gonna connect a to B to C and
it's very simple and straightforward
we're gonna read log files off of the
system we're gonna ingest them into
sequel we're going to collect all that
data from a bunch of different instances
put it into a data Lake and run all of
our queries and machine learning and
modeling and everything on that data big
data well this is easy right you write a
bash script to put onto every computer
you have a little bit of Python and you
can script it together and there you go
let's look at a model of courier service
so I guess DHL is the mid 1 over here
right we've got mobile devices everybody
has a scanner that they're scanning the
packages doesn't deliver them there are
registers in the store where we're
accepting and delivery parcels
we have trucks we have delivers and all
this goes to a gateway server that's in
each store and it goes up to a
distribution center where we have a
cluster and we even have a data center
right professional data center and we
can do all of our machine learning and
Big Data there so great I could get all
this data now what I'm going to do with
it well I'm gonna throw it into Kafka
and use that to send it to storm and
spark and flink and apex and anything
else that's on Apaches homepage today
you you can send it to any other
consumer right I mean somebody is gonna
want as soon as you start collecting
data somebody's gonna want it ok that's
a universal truth usually they want the
data you don't have yet that's even
harder so now let's scale this up
because we're going to be an
international courrier service and we
have people and computers on every
different continent every different
corner of the globe raise your hand if
you want to maintain the Python scripts
for that for the rest of your life so
let's talk about Apache knife I I've
definitely stated some problems let's
try and solve some knife I is an open
source project part of the Apache
Software Foundation it provides a ton of
features that
or we're gonna be very important for
your data flow and data collection data
buffering is huge now if I comes from an
area where the importance of data can't
be overstated and protecting that data
but also not losing that data is really
really important one of the features
that I probably won't get into in too
much detail but backpressure allows you
to provide custom configurations so that
if some piece of your chain starts
slowing down it can actually send
information to the predecessors and
inform them of that information and
allow them to either prioritize the data
that you need and stop sending
everything that's just first-in
first-out
it can start sending it to a different
flow and backing it up putting it to
buffer all kinds of things you can do
with it that's really valuable
like I said prioritize queuing we have
quality of service that can be
customized based on the flow data
provenance is something that I will get
into a little bit more detail we support
push and pull models and it's a visual
tool it's it's not something where you
have to have a masters in order to start
the thing up it's something that anybody
with domain knowledge can use which
really makes it easy to get the right
people involved right because you're not
always gonna be able to say everybody
who has valuable insight to this problem
is able to run the terminal and do
everything there right so we're trying
to open it up and make sure that you get
the right people involved in your
process not by originated with
consequent flow based programming
so there is some vocabulary basically a
glossary here you'll hear me talk about
flow files that's basically your atomic
unit of data okay that's the thing
that's moving through your system flow
file processor is some component some
black box it doesn't matter what the
internal implementation is it's
something that you can connect data in
to get data out of and operate obviously
in order to do that you need connections
flow controller is essentially a
scheduler right it's the the overarching
system that's running all of this and
orchestrating it and then a process
group is basically just a collection of
these processors and connections
logically grouped together
so knife I use completely data agnostic
we really don't care what you're using
it for but it was designed understanding
that users have to care about the
specifics and it allows you to do a lot
of transformation or manipulation of the
formats and protocols within the tool so
a really good example to understand a
flow file is to think of it using the
analogy of an HTTP data all right so
this is an HTTP response you can see
that there's a header and then there's
some content below a flow file is very
similar we have attributes which is key
value mapping and then we have the
binary content of the flow file and the
reason that this is important to be
separated logically is that the
attributes are maintained in memory
they're accessible all the time they're
usually pretty small right they're used
for routing they're used for
classification tagging access control
the content could be anything from a
couple bites of text to ten gigs of
video okay when you're routing data you
really don't want to be moving all of
that through the heap constantly right
so what we do is we've split this into
two different storage capacities one is
what we call the flow flow file
repository which stores all of these
flow files with their attributes but it
then has similar to a pointer write a
reference pointer it has a claim to
content that's in a content repository
so what we do is everything is dealt
with through streaming interfaces the
data the content is read into a content
repository it's referenced from there
but it means that it's not always on the
heap whereas the attributes are always
available for operation this allows it
to process a ton of data very quickly
and respecting the resources that you
have available I'm not gonna pretend
like you don't need to have resources in
order to do this if you're operating on
that scale of data but it makes it
easier and it's not unnecessarily
wasting the resources that you have
available let's talk about the user
interface we want less I mean I like
this but in general we want less of this
and more of this okay and let's talk
about the your interface I'm actually
gonna go up to the board a little bit
so here we have what's called the
navigation palette and then the
operation palette down here across the
top this this header these are
components which you can drag on to the
flow the canvas on the far right the
hamburger menu I guess we're still
Conniff that allows you to do get into
some of the system maintenance and
operations and then you can see on the
graph itself your components connections
etc this is mostly to illustrate that
people tend to think of data processing
as happening just in some core data
center somewhere right you have a team
that only cares about doing something
with the data they really don't care
about how the data got well they care if
it doesn't actually get there but they
don't care about how you're collecting
the data where it's coming from
on the other hand you have people and
resources out in the field or at the
edge which are doing the data collection
right and not only that there's usually
some other value they're providing or
all the tool wouldn't be there one of
the things that knife eye allows is for
bi-directional data flow what I mean by
that is we're extracting or exfilling
some kind of important data from the
edge and bring it back to a central
resource but we also need to be able to
send commands communication out to the
edge in order to update the flow
prioritize what we're getting ask
somebody to resend something right so
with this bi-directional data what we
call the data plane and then the command
plane or control plane it allows for us
to improve the data collection
make sure it's robust and stable as we
move on we have over 180 processors that
are available as part of the default
knife I installation everything from
sequel and sequel like data stores to
Big Data to all the different edge
formats and protocols that you might
encounter
so listen TCP log readers just file
extractors kafka database integration
all kinds of stuff there
so HTTP email basically if you can think
of it if we haven't written the
processor for it already we can probably
knock one out unless it's the new
version of Kafka which will take some
time
uh-huh we can do a ton of different
operations to that data so usually
manipulating data transforming data
requires some custom knowledge of that
format right I want to go from XML to
JSON well I understand X and I'll have
to understand JSON I may have to
understand different schemas that are
involved here you drag a box on to the
canvas and you have XML to JSON like I'm
it really is that easy
so now let's talk about minify and and I
am blazing through this so I apologize
if anything's getting a little confusing
minify is gonna let us get out to the
very edge so everybody in this room has
a computer that's capable of the
calculations needed to put a man on the
moon 50 years ago right that kind of
data collection data processing is
unprecedented and will only continue to
grow right data lives in the data center
where knife I has has brought it in
transformed it and provided it to
whatever follow-on system exists but the
data doesn't start there and so the
closer we can get to the creation of the
data the better quality will get the
better control over that data will have
we will be able to prioritize it we'll
be able to secure it will get
granularity of provenance of history in
a way that we've never been able to
before why not just put knife I out
there
well knife is big 726 megabytes for last
release okay it's not a tiny thing it is
respectful of the hardware like I said
you can run it on a Raspberry Pi but you
would like to run it on the heaviest
machine you can find right we have a
friend who has a machine running right
now with 768 gigabytes of RAM and it
uses it
but what we'd also like to do is have
minify where we can put that out on to
client liberate library on somebody's
iOS or Android device on every IOT chip
with six legs that you can stick on a
wall somewhere all right
connected car knife eye 726 mix minified
Java is 45 mix okay minify c++ is 700
kilobytes so it's a 1,000 times
improvement on space requirement so one
of the things that we we did all go into
an example here of putting minify on a
connected car this is a project we did
with qualcomm it allows us to tag data
immediately so this is a model of the
network inside of a car and I think it's
still a little new to a lot of people
that your car has computers in it now
and really can't run without them unless
you have a 50 year old car you have the
can bus which is your main network
within the car there's usually Ethernet
onboard there's also like an
interconnect Network and then there's
whatever else has yet to be invented
right Tesla is certainly not stopping on
their cars every car manufacturer is
moving in this direction minify living
in the car I mean literally on that chip
in the central computer of the car can
ingest
all of the data that's flowing across
these different networks so everything
from speed data to break measurements to
GPS process all of that tag it
prioritize it maybe filter stuff out
based on geographic location if you're
operating in China you're not allowed to
send any of that information to a
computer that lives outside of China so
you can't just say oh well Ford has a
data center for the entire world we'll
get all the information in we'll do some
machine learning and modelling there and
then we'll send out our learnings now
you have to have one I think maybe even
now one for Europe one for the u.s. one
for China one for Antarctica whatever
you want to do
so men if I can start routing that
information encrypting that information
prioritizing or filtering it while it's
still on the car taking data off of a
car is very expensive if you are near a
Wi-Fi hotspot the car will prioritize
that and send more data over Wi-Fi but
when you're driving on a highway and
there's somebody around it uses an LTE
modem that's in the car and that's
extremely expensive so you really don't
want to send a bunch of wasted data a
bunch of unnecessary data or
uncompressed data over that if you don't
have to so here's a little diagram the
map on the right and the boxes there are
actually showing the ratio of the data
that's getting exfilled live via LTE
versus Wi-Fi on the left you see the
data flow from knife I and that is
ingesting data off of those networks
processing it filtering it and then
sending it via the radios that are in
the car one of the next things that
we're really focused on developing is
the flow versioning right as you develop
your data flow all of this we'd like to
use the analogy you're not building
pipes you're a farmer digging irrigation
ditches right that water is always
flowing that river is not stopping
because oh I need to update this
processor so what you can do is continue
a data flow build something new
alongside of it make sure that works on
the same data that's coming through
without stopping anything any follow-on
system and then when you have a new flow
that's better you kill the old flow
you've never stopped moving the data
from the source to the the destination
but you've improved your system as
you're doing that unfortunately you
can't prove that and then six weeks
later you find out oh I needed something
from the other flow that I didn't forgot
to check well how do you go back to that
old one so that's where flow versioning
whether it's on the six week time frame
or six seconds right I'm reading from
IOT sources and I need to change the
priority based on the available
bandwidth I might want everything if I
have the bandwidth I might want only top
priority data when the bandwidth starts
to get spotty so I can have my might
control my command control system knife
I write these rules into my flow and
then send them back to minify and not
just one instance event if I all 6.2
million instances of minify they're
running on that flow and that's all
going to be taken care of
seemlessly think I am getting close okay
there's plenty more anybody who's
interested is welcome to come talk to me
I'll hang out outside and thank you very
much for having me
[Applause]
sorry yeah question is it possible to
make cues that are consumer controlled
in knife I I don't understand the
question fully but my answer is yes yes
almost definitely it depends on what
specific consumer format you're talking
about but yes yes knife I will yes it's
the opposite of Kafka yes yes yes yeah
the question was about exactly once
delivery knife I uses what's called our
right ahead log to track all of the data
that's flowing through the system and so
it will guarantee exactly what's
delivery here so that that's actually
this copy-on-write the data is not
manipulated in place the data exists
permanently as long as you have storage
to hold it when it gets sent to a
follow-on system it receives a
confirmation it's a two-phase commit or
signal that the information was received
if it wasn't not if I can replay that
information to the following system yes
and back
I'm sorry can you repeat that a little
louder please is it possible to make
data transformations on the fly yes
that's that's the whole point of knife I
I mean that one of the whole points and
I find so acts like format XML to JSON
yes
CSV to parsing records into different
atomic units yes absolutely
yes the question was performance versus
Kafka or other systems that's a whole
nother talk I mean that we could talk
about that for an hour I'll take it
offline with you if you want absolutely
yes system requirements for minify and
embedded devices the ability to run C
and 700k minified bundles it's a
completely new implementation of the
same system so we have it in both Java
on the JVM and a C implementation bare
metal so Ram I believe it's four
megabytes of RAM yes
the question was schema list versus
schema formats yeah we have plenty of
processors for Avro we can immediately
there's one literally called infer Avro
schema so you bring in arbitrary data
and it will basically build out the
schema from that that Avro and
information
yes sure the question was two-phase
commit right ahead log cluster scaling
okay yeah it scales extremely well it is
built to be a clustered system so
there's an entire cluster coordinator it
uses embedded zookeeper if another
instances and available resource
management in allocation is still
something that we're continuing to work
on and integrating with like Muzo sir
yarn or some other resources manager for
that but knife I will encapsulate the
resource management it has cluster
coordinator heartbeat and all that kind
of stuff as well two-phase commit that's
for the following systems to acknowledge
they've received information the right
ahead log implementation is so that
we're again the copy-on-write so that
it's not manipulated data in place you
don't lose the the record of what that
data was was there another one okay
[Applause]
yeah sorry the question is autonomous
cars is that appropriate for this
I mean morally or just like technically
but technically absolutely yes