Azari from the course f team
talk a little bit about our object
storage the ratos gateway insect hello
thank you for coming so early on Sunday
I know it's hard
I'm on it I'm part of the safety a mean
way that and I work on cloud of storage
set and today we're going to explain
what what cloud objects toys is how
different regular search types a little
bit of a fresh suppose music much we did
no hands so explain provide cloud
storage interface for few questions so
in then I put for people to ask
questions during the presentation so if
someone needs a question just raise your
hand so let's start working with this
cloud object sort so we have a black
shirt anybody
Google Website although first fold is
divided into those fixed blocks
depending on the device metadata related
to the data just write the data
somewhere and device of circular and
application need to manage to know what
that we tweaked and their wealth within
you can have several devices but it's
really fast for storage and today this
protocol private Janus cars a satire I
study and some people even use fiber
Java of a 10-8 method of using black
stars really hard applications a bank
loan assistant for this data file
conveys in any place you can overwrite
it in the middle and allocate on demand
it's much easier for application through
the search but it's rather block lots of
elements sometimes system people not all
five systems with many have sharing
semantics to the same of the same time
we have like a five system protocol like
exit for XFS and so hard and we also
have network protocol like in the first
an SMB and SP the apple protocol by the
day it was the cloud
[Music]
like complex systems have is really hard
so just two levels we have these buckets
switch Gordon containers reports
so just container of objects is Terrell
to organize your objective to groups and
maybe add some properties for that
so that's bucket and inside the bucket
or of those objects and I'm doctor not
just Delta you the body you can add them
all sort of metadata summer fix that
some you can decide on your own so you
can learn let's find the right now
what's the data in them your views wells
and tenants which is like an abaya for
user to share the same data between them
you have authentication and ownership
access control list and we talked about
large objects really large so that means
you need lots of storage become very
large object mutable object are
immutable that means you're either
months if you decide to change them we
need to actually override all the
objects you cannot write in between and
it's much more efficient for those large
objects to be immutable and it's
simplified to allocation save the
particles today the most common one is
valid on XP it's beautiful and even
though scale hours on edge balancer it's
huge I can't imagine how much search HP
has kept in stock we have Swift and the
Google Cloud Storage put rights and
observe
was in hell you can believe about that
we're to an object that it's not a
symbol of collaboration
this is such a simplification because
this is service so it's all sort of
metadata or maybe make the potion more
complex so we talked about really large
objects we can get to giggles sighs so
these it can be really hard so for that
we have removed apart you want to upload
an object but you want to maybe stop it
maybe we try so total big objects you
divide it to small parts and each part
is been uploaded or downloaded parallel
so you can handle network problems and
don't know me and it you can continue
where you stopped and you can step start
upload download and also it's good for
streaming for example when you don't
know the size of the objects you're
actually going to upload the download
but the smell it's hard for the storage
because I'm
your uploads we burn at the object will
be every caffeinated so we need to start
on the temporary parts and sometimes we
start again
so when you switch value differently so
sorry user password Samuels lose user
and a security key and a secret
everything is really different so the
question is complex object lifecycle for
example we can separate an object and
when
so that base of the preparation website
can be deleted automatically or move to
cold storage and lots of good features
any personnel custard let's talk about
safe
so staff is soaked up with cephalopod
which is the family about to process in
school so our version occurs of one
animal that name so the latest stable
version a Joe I think that's funny to
you if I remember so sorry weapon sauce
this is where I give up we serve all
under is over South quad it's not a nice
truck we have our own testing for
multiple challenges Ross open and
additional tests like restful path but
this is free compatibility we have other
component of safe society represents we
are in for them so it's applesauce LGPL
it's such a different stage where we are
in the software if I schedule that means
it can run on many kind of platforms you
can configure an adaptive to different
parodies and scale it disabilities thing
and like and I will have anything good
for the favor when you have a large
number of nodes you cannot handle the
single point of failure you because they
assume everything will not scale means
failure happens it's massively scalable
it was built to be not scared
so we can be free nodes but the minimum
is five and I actually recommend more
it's a large-scale system not for
according to be more efficient space
because we assume they don't have good
left so we need more copies so lied
system very happen so you want safe here
in because you cannot handle the
struggles Vanilli everything should
happen automatically and we have unified
access rather sacrifice is the name it's
the file system access it's a positive
time file system we can use our client
kids or our camera client and there is
introversion to oppos'd at Manila and
you can use any first Ganesha with it
for an FSO samba simba I believe the
black route affects many nodes for water
stop it's suitable control with qmu so
you can use it with kimi o 4 n oq k vm
and you can use the caret right if you
want you're on the device and web
spectral width which is the component of
the right cloud object storage
underneath we solve the earth brothers
and I'm going to batters the distributed
object storage so we see in phenom
dacoits which is interesting so once
that started it
let's build a very fast
I system and the star would read us to
be lever which objects oil but you can
build up a system on it really wet
working with the beauty fascism is never
simple even if you have used to build
object storage underneath
and in the movie I will put to the web
so fast the style BB and others great
life and now we have such a fascist
production so are this bar Travis does
it does all the distributor so it's does
all the application and recording it's a
slight object constants and we call we
have a pair of object and we can
configure it for that could be available
to be butchered application to be free
role could be Reza codes that would
strongly consistent system and it's up
to define that minutes is the word tulo
infrastructure and the topology and it
matches two different archetypes turbine
systems for placement
we have a house based algorithm with no
lookup called crush anyone performance
so we serve to the but it's not very
efficient in large-scale it's a
bottleneck surprise seven choir may look
up it is
so that's men you can actually put in
crowd I can say this is where Rick and I
want don't want to place two copies of
the same work so you choose no just are
not at the same way you can configure
the application and if you do wait and
it should be fast calculation
deterministic and it's evenly
distributed that were called so the
wander because that way we can benefit
from all notes so so far this cluster as
two kinds of not the first one all of
the objects storage device those we have
lots of those nodes demons tends to ten
thousands
I think they followed it out maybe but
[Music]
it's because we do occasionally know
we're going to do additional replication
in the storage layer and its main for
about a third object to the user it's
smart storage node that's mini that's
tearing and in case of a failure without
the other two dollars days after
community each other and we'll work with
coordinated that are all communal comes
it will be balanced the storage
[Music]
they are called of no diem is the
monitor notes verse says the old
clustering logic they maintained
improper memberships of noise default
monitors with an obstruction because
it's very notice that there is not
responding and it will notify the
monitors failure and then the monitor
will spirit to the otherwise doing and
when you add in our food same way we
have a small number of birds five so on
they do reach taxes
it doesn't step any Delta to the usual
just for the clock just remember ships
they are cluster we want actually sorry
the group Redis and and it will need a
lot of performance and you are willing
to actually interact with actually some
user use the brothers because dining to
super party there will be Python I don't
remember
probably more and it's very cheap I it's
not the sweet web map so inside one
object you have a key value store and
you can use this to serve example the
first upstairs
the director-general map a rubber skirt
by the bucket index
is map its support atomic single object
operations you can update attributes and
keys and gautama see in our objective
one operation it has snapshots per
object its objective notable that mean
you can actually pass you overwrite
object and we will discuss clusters of
very similar to start procedures and a
database you can actually write code
that will run directly on the earth
given an object's changed truly strong
feature it allows lots of performance we
around the surface and we have a watch
naughty file server circle webiste an
object and when the object chains will
get a notification across the cluster
everyone ready says verification so it's
a very strong API but it's okay plasmid
web self and as we already need to
replicate one another one can be the
bastard some case it's other cases thus
we a replica so we talk with each other
and they can be text with this folder
because to meet it up in chatter then if
they get all that they notify the
monitors and then the cluster start to
under that case so you need that do that
failed
- marketers help but then it's fall you
know all the bad open things need to be
replicated traverses so then they do it
automatically the side of the object
maximum size of objecting there are this
is for mega for mega would be it that's
a reverse apricots of yours develop
those for mega if the object is larger
than
no no yeah you need one to read yeah
- right you need food that's dope even
fit freeways you need free copies
without full-time with the preview radio
would need one copy yes many if that's
the same only high quality machines the
more you can do large-scale now we're
going to register that more about for
this paper which is the component in
fact that provides the crowd of the
search select always important for the
structure uses no borders to communicate
through the artists cluster so we have
discussed avoid these Americas and
that's where the work I'll start another
straightway is a service built on top of
that so weather is object storage so
that scale should be simple we can
actually start so it's not just to
provide the API and matching with the
API we have when we look at our
objective for abuse or a biscotti way or
crowd we see some difference so first is
the big five every object is four mega
and we talk in our cloud so we talk
about pretty large object so we need
somewhere
bigger objects and divided to those four
mega sized objects so what is objective
neutral ball-bearing cloud we talk about
immutable objects the hardest part is
that the poles inside of others are not
indexed but we want to list all the
objects in the bucket sorted by name
that means we need to add some indexing
for the bucket to allow those listing
and suppose like a bucket but we need a
sales per object so to implement the
cloud the research top of it so in case
you see that you have lots of actions or
an equation and the audits way is
whether you can just one another
instance of water circulate on the same
set crafter and both can work together
and continue and that's why we can scale
up so again this is object storage we
have usual antennas with metadata which
is really complex because we support
several protocols to very support to our
private protocol as fluent switched in
many cases you can use back in the same
time
[Music]
okay to allow that
and also if you have won the credit
application there's no reason that's
very basic stuff then you can use it but
so you try to be ready Scott very
possible that everyone can access all
the time
I'll go bit about those so first we have
the front-end content is not provide the
rest API actually so it's helped us we
need HTTP so today the forces the old
and under commanded way so we support
absolutely di
the party and the other web service
there in a snapIt remembered is because
Casa di is lots of security issues so
but some sometimes if you already have
your old Apache you handle the security
issue with a CGI it can be an option
today from hammer action I don't
remember
we have seen that web channel various
web server inside of the web escape way
we then we go to the west where it's
actually below that converts from the
dialect between the protocol so it
passes as free Swifton AR API then goes
to execution which we also
sometimes you need to abdicate again so
we support the OWS for about four to six
times so it will move to election in the
background
[Music]
the bucket sorted by name but when we
talk about club ever spirits were
careful that one bucket contain millions
of objects and then the bucket in looks
is also a bottleneck for performance and
also because it's in the end starting
and all that weather subject if you pass
one object line it also inefficient so
first thing if you have lots of lateral
but the staff members up to rather okay
object with one bucket in it that's fine
if you have one more than one under case
then you need to use shaadi we track the
bucket in depth and split to several
object depending on the number of
objects you decide whenever of charge
you want we have that support for of
Seshadri and it's in and we're trying to
work on the elevation in battle you will
need to offering the bucket as the pilot
rate can do it with IO skip that
so I thought I'd be able to build system
object can be written for many many
places several rebus gateways we need
farewell to coordinate the quota so we
the subject plus objects to do that so
when you actually write objects
embarrass do we update the quarter the
thing the quota is not completely
consistent with something looks a bit
but I think resistance have the same
issue we dot we were the middle of the
class and we use watch notify 200 that
but mainly in case whether the change
the other were discovered retina
fication and then can involve that at
entry from the cache so notice so we
take in our cloud but cloud is never one
data center many times we want several
data centers anyone to a disaster
recovery you actually wanna use all of
them for that well notified of your
application so you can take perfect
clusters and configure them and there
will be a super-racer professional rub
each other
it could be active operation which is
metadata alterations are suppose because
they are really important staff and we
cannot have a difference in those so we
have a mega master and in Calcifer CD to
do fell over and configure you make a
pastor but the data is completely a
secret that means all the different
the object and there will be replicated
or Tomatoes thematically to the aisle
casters down in people cluster
[Music]
okay so we know it's good points to the
same that eyes a different object we
have a crucial occasion
thanks to Von Teese so the power cube
shape we have compassion also we want it
work with support and we have started
website through anyone wants to use
static website which you can be exported
out our to elastic search and you can
search the metadata and we're working
about doing a linebacker to Charlotte
not about time two questions no
questions
one yes
[Music]