this will be an introduction
to graph databases so for all the people
who are thinking about them and
basically asking patients what are their
four yep this talk is for you for the
more advanced it talks in topics stay in
this room and from what we saw you will
learn some things okay some some things
about me I'm the chief architect in act
imagination it's a big polish IT company
and there I am help in running one of
the biggest Dalton's projects in Poland
after hours
I basically dig into data so basically
here neo4j is for this and making sense
of it and also distributed systems and
I'm also running a pet project called
cookies Pio
it's a contextual search engine for
cooking recipes and we will look at it
later okay
so graphs what a graph this is a graph
it's a bit lonely graph it's a single
single node but still it's a graph so
let's make it about more interesting
let's add a friend and if we are doing a
friend we are adding a relationship as
simple as this graph is its way useful
because this is basically Facebook I
know you you know me yeah that's it and
if we like to spice things a bit we can
add a direction to this relationship and
this actually is if I am observing you
you are not necessarily with me so
ass-fucker relationship don't do it next
this is the we are adding to weight to
the relationship so this is basically
the most common thing that people are
thinking when they're thinking graphs so
basically cities sittings cities roads
and roads also have direction next let's
get a bit funky so if we allow for two
nodes to have multiple relate
relationships of the same type between
them we get multi multi relation graph
well while there are funky they
basically don't have that much of a news
and they can in most cases be
implemented by this just basically
counting the edges let's go next
and next we have a labeled graph so
basically we are able to add labels to
nodes and relationships it's kind of
useful there are some implementations
but the best graph and most practical is
the property graph so we are able to add
labels and basically any method metadata
connected to the nodes and the edges and
one question does this remind anyone of
something and if I do this I had one too
many many to one and someone and if I do
this no there won't be any treats
basically when I was starting through it
it's this is how we draw relational
databases so there's a guy standing in
funny pants saying queue that basically
we have graph databases but we have
relations that abbreviations are in the
relational databases and we have
relations in graphs so was up to
understand why relational databases are
completely not similar to graph this
basis let's go a bit into history
because history is fun and but the
creation that we started in 1970 by mr.
Edgar Codd who wrote a paper it had some
Patterson to best understand why did it
gain so much so much traction that
basically relational databases are
everywhere now let's see what always
happened in the 1970s well run got
actually quite cheap because for $700 we
could get one megabyte and for those
young people in here megabyte is the
lesser of gigabytes yeah and it got
cheap because two years earlier it was
about two and a half thousand and next
IBM released is first
dishwasher with 100 megabytes of this
space and when I'm saying this washer is
basically because it looks like a
dishwasher
it's here so and it has one also one
common thing with a dishwasher the
access time and the read time in the
specs they are they are actually down to
the bytes how fast you can transfer it
and it's like 1 megabyte comma 0 0 or
something
so yeah it was slow and next Intel
releases its processor so we can play
Mario and we have almost 800 kilo Hertz
it's again gigahertz megahertz kilohertz
yeah it was slow and free years later we
have 16 bits and one megabyte of memory
so yeah things just got got awesome and
next Oracle's of course implements the
implements the relational databases
paper and we have we have our relation
address and Apple releases is its first
and only not non-white computer next we
have the absolute grand-grandfather of
almost every processor you have in your
notebooks or PC so and I think the Intel
8086 and we have a massive whopping up
to ten megahertz of processing power so
yeah this is the relation that the
creation of the database key sorry let's
now in contrast look how the graph one
looks first in 1736 it's the graph
problem by mr. Euler and this history
has kings and queens and some one sound
but basically it's it's so we all agree
that it's the beginning of really graphs
in mathematics next map coloring problem
and we'll get back to it in some time
because it correlates with computer
history next if we are talking about
math and we want to be serious we should
have a book so in 1936 we have a book
and then it's the official moment that
graph theory in mathematics officially
starts next map coloring problem is
partly solved well why partly because
basically the proof said yeah we are
right we can color color every map using
four four colors but basically there are
about 20,000 maps that should be
processed manually it to actually prove
that they can't this can't they can't be
colored color with less than three
colors and because we didn't have enough
crayons and we are lazy we had to wait
30 years for for actually solving it and
we actually solved it you
our computer of course next into the
rhesus is Pentium 4 and it has a
whopping almost three gigahertz or
pressing power and another question does
anyone remember Oh is old enough like me
to know which part of the PC also
evolves quite rapidly thanks dude thanks
to the Intel for the right radiator it
was the time when we thought that yeah
water cooling will be in every PC
Pentium 4 had such massive heating
problems that basically Intel said well
let's put it in a drawer
they took pentium free put two chips in
one processor and this how we got called
Co duo and next in 2003 the first
commercial graph that graph databases so
why aren't why I'm showing here because
if you look this history is completely
different when we got the relational
databases we had a massive gains in
computing power and we when we had
graffia the business we already knew
that
we can't go faster on one one call one
call and if you think one more thing if
you think about relation databases and
you think about the normal forms and
think for a moment why do we have normal
forms it there was is what simple to
actually save the amount of storage of
this space that we are using if you are
if you are replacing a string with the
end so creating a creating another table
you are actually reducing the space it
will actually take and now gigabytes a
chip why okay so we know what now let's
see how the landscape actually looks
like first we have flock flock is
basically database written database for
the poll why because flock actually can
get only the parents of the notes it
can't reverse for the graph you may
think why why would someone implement it
and that's quite simple flock was
implemented by Twitter and Twitter has a
use case that if you tweet something it
it gets all all people who are following
you and moves that with today to to yo
Twitter feed and that's all so it
actually shows that many graph databases
are implemented in some specific problem
in mind if you will use them in the
Pacific problem they are awesome they
are mostly sit not not general-purpose
databases as we make relational
databases as through 50 years next like
the Trinity Project it's then been
called graph max of graph then it was I
being killed but basically the idea
behind it is like Microsoft has a sure
so they thought let's process massive
graphs in our row so what it did is
basically created a graph engine that
only sends messages basically so they
abstracted in a way credit of virtual
actor for graphs and so yeah it's what
it was printed in with after in mind
next Titan now it's been replaced with
Julius and it's a craft engine that
basically you can swap storage engines
and it can combine a lot of things let
next or in DB if you don't know what to
use or in DB basically has relational
capability is graphically capabilities
key value store capabilities and
everything you can imagine yeah people
are using it next affinity indexed one
is for IOT and low light and see the
other is for mobile devices if you have
a case that you actually want to use
want to calculate graphs on a mobile
devices why not next neo4j and it's
without no reason that it's in the top
right corner we'll be seeing a lot of
you know even in the stock later so I
will I want concentrate on it next
Allegro graph and the hyper group the
beam those databases are being developed
in in one use case in mind basically
graph storage
sorry knowledge storage and basically
going through knowledge okay let's go
further usage this is the Amazon page
and you can't see it but yeah basically
when you go to Amazon you can see that
Amazon basically it doesn't show you
similar books if they show you books
that people frequently bought together
and so on someone so how does Amazon do
it this is my guess so what people let's
take a net one person he goes into my
zone bro stab it and buy something let's
take another person so basically what
you see is when you think in a graph way
those are pages and so our sole product
products you actually can see the
patterns in data some some notes and
some edges that just just are thicker
and lighter pass us a Christmas tree so
what do we see from here basically if
anyone enters this note we should be
showing this note because people people
aren't buying us often this note but
from this node going to this node so the
they they in some way may be similar
that we can't know precisely but yeah
this is our buying path
let's go now similarly okay so of course
also connected with money money
laundering if you have a million new
euros you can't actually buy a house buy
a Porsche and so on because the IRS will
come and ask you some simple question
where did you get the money and then you
will be said yeah so basically what you
do is basically is give this money to a
lot of people and and basically they go
through through the chain of restaurants
and so on and this is exactly the same
as was done in the Panama papers how
they did it they just inputted each
invoice at a time basically who paid who
and how much and after some time this
they started seeing some some
relationship relationship ships and
thanks this they were able to see a
really stupid face of a prime minister
of Iceland when he was asked what are
his connections with some foreign
offshore company yeah and well my
computer's attacking me so sorry and
some technical problems sorry ok let's
go further
NOP and this is oversimplification I
know but stay with me if we have
something saying sushi find me all sushi
restaurants in New York that my friends
like we can easily understand each word
world of the sentence so she restaurants
that my friends like but answering to
this question is quite complicated well
it is not because if you grab this
basically get me my friends basically I
don't have that many but yeah let's say
get get a no note of lucky location
Location New York get the tap tap of the
type of the cuisine so as you see we
have this part we have this part so the
answer to this question will actually be
the notes filling filling the graph it's
basically that easy and there's also one
interesting thing because if you what
are talking about for example Facebook
we are talking billions bills I heard
billions billions of notes but actually
you know in each square in each part of
this query we actually triggered each
note and its children so it's fast yeah
Nach next knowledge graphs so basically
Newton had this case that there have a
huge not huge knowledge graph because if
you write any article you want to have
contextual actual actual news actual
actual data so if you take Apple Apple
can be a fruit can be applying can be
some some things there are even a static
episode yeah there's also Apple Records
that's the Beatles Russian a party is
nickname Apple so there are a lot of it
and if you look at those types of data
in a relational model so basically you
have the Apple it's one Apple then you
label each type and according to the
each label you look at the different
relationship you can do really awesome
stuff like knowledge graphs from Google
it's the Euler and order has some fields
like born diet education and influence
and basically influence is a field you
wouldn't normally put on a person but
someone someone may argue that yeah it's
for famous people and so on so you have
the field influence but then again you
have spoke and
Gaza how the field species and with
a value of volcán and this value is a
link so with graph databases you are
when you are adding acknowledge you are
not changing changing you are adding
knowledge and this this knowledge
influence your database you don't have
to think in a head of your structure
your tables relationships because if you
do it you won't have Spock next
performance and short-short theory
basically what are you doing if you are
implementing a relational database in
curricle structure in relational
database you have a let's say table
table persons which is quite long as
many columns and you have table person
child and a pronged first person child
is that it's quite narrow because it has
ID parent ID chow-chow already and what
you are doing when you are asking a
relational graph question is basically
you are taking one ID and matching with
this huge huge table with parent child
then you have an some some IDs like five
ten and then again once again you are
matching it with this huge table it you
get the point it's it's not the best way
to do it in graph even graduate
databases you actually store the IDS at
the node so getting note you actually
have the IDS so you don't have to
process it individually and do this
drawing all the time but enough talk
let's see examples let's take Twitter
from 2009 basically you will have the
slide but this is the whole description
almost almost two billion watches more
than 40 million users and with the
statistics what it done is using Titan
it is basically both 40 the cheapest
virtual machines on Amazon and six three
expensive ones and what they will able
to achieve is don't machine code
pressing all the time in a loop
basically so this is the time that I got
and it's quite fast and it's what what
is even more interesting it costs them
11 bucks an hour and that's cheap yeah
let's go neo4j y4j whiny of
I did did I get interested into neo4j
because there's a side DB engines come
and on this side neo4j is that twenty
four twenty first the most product
database and it's a really good position
and of course it's what is the number
one graph database there is it has
drivers for almost annual any language
cipher just got it is we have we have
open ciphers so cipher is basically the
in the industry standard for asking
graph questions that's it and of course
there is a free version and yeah so my
problem we have I have to cook it cook
it is a contextual search engine so what
it does is basically scribe scraped the
web it's looking for page that has a
cookie recipe then it extracts the text
then from the text it extracts the
ingredients amount unit sends a lot of
data it's it's it's doing it in
automatically so one part of one of most
of the most critical parts is basically
and connecting those ingredients found
in the text with the actual ingredients
and this is actually the graph of my
ingredients
viens have are about three thousand
nodes they have mold more than three
thousand edges and because this is a
treat so there are no cycles the deep
the depth of this graph is about the
ninth level and eight many ingredients
so basically what it so buddy what was
my problem is that I have errors and
sometimes I misinterpreted some
ingredients so I basically wanted to do
a some sanity check on my data so and it
to well ask this if there are any ink
recipes that have fish and sweet drinks
like our Cola you don't normally see
those two things in one recipe if and
he's saying not not student person is
cooking it I used to do really crazy
stuff cooking studying so basically
let's do it
first I have a match and match is the
keyword and this will be suffer and
suffer is it's a crazy love between SQL
and ASCII art so yeah but it's really
good it's better than SQL you have a
match and much sale says that yeah I
would be showing patterns and this is
very important world I will be showing
patterns now not exactly they not
exactly matches I will be looking yeah
so next I'm saying that I want to I want
to find a note if I put anything in a
round braces this is a note so yeah you
actually can get the Ascot and this note
has to be type of recipe and I'm calling
it our next I'm also want it ingredients
there's a notation next I want our
relationship between those and this is
the name of the of the relation this
means this actually shows you the ASCII
art part next I would like to return
return them so yeah are and then next a
bit more funky part and the most awesome
part it's like I get the I get the
ingredient and I saying that will
traverse from this note through through
through relationships of type from and
specification and do it from one to nine
Flavell basically so I'm doing yeah and
until you get to to the note of type
indigent which has made data of name
sweet drinks and I'm doing exactly the
same with fish turns out you really
should put a limit on it yeah
this query actually takes on SQL server
about 20 seconds on the near I was able
without any problems to get to a hundred
milliseconds yeah because I am asking
our relational graph query and it's
frequently fast and what's fast I could
do it faster probably on on our relation
the
but I would have to do normal as my data
and in this case this is a sanity check
it's not a part of my domain so I don't
want to have any I don't want to change
my domain term at the database to fit to
answer this query faster yeah so to wrap
up because my time is actually ending I
think when to use graph database
databases when you are talking about her
article data structures basically next
where there's a saying that you should
use you should choose graph it places
when your relationships are more
interesting than your data so what is
the sentence is saying is that basically
if you are more interested in the
relations than your data like actually
the text and the blob storage and so on
go go to gravity the basis next for
searching patterns in data you can
actually visualize quite easy and they
are really good tools also integrating
with neo4j very very easy used in Panama
papers for example and to get the sense
of the data where and when you should
not use graduate abases first for data
manipulation and heavy systems and if
you know if your nodes will have
hundreds of fields or will have huge
blob objects and so on so on think about
it twice because gravity bases are for
relationship not exactly for storing
blob files we'd have solid megabytes in
each node next when you are thinking
about big data is it transactionality
it's won't probably be your best pick
because it will be heavy and the last
but the most important i really wouldn't
like for someone saying yeah yeah i will
just grab my relational database and
replace it with a graph database because
in some cases it will be really awesome
and fast but they are not the most
general purpose databases that basically
racial basis database are also bad
during those 50 years we we we were able
to make relation the basis good at
almost anything but not super good and
and but not super good at anything
yeah so questions and I will wrap up
thanks
[Applause]