[Music] 27
[Music]
also for everyone
two
[Music] i
as
just the minute program
I am
Yes
to call against you
2 [Music]
Yes
yes not in both the position
[Music]
Y
well
you say
ah
life do not have to do are symbols
not
Y
its growth
successfully sometimes
[Music]
800 resolution
[Music] yeah
[Music]
because I just block, excuse me
this is not
[Music] normal
in this time
about this
ah
[Music]
2 action
Yes
[Music]
Y
with night
practice [Music]
well when going up
[Music] yeah
[Music]
and today
critics shared with cleaning
So
the ministers nights
i
with deceased
2 ascent
[Music]
Healthier
no [Music]
and the seven groups
but 1
not
Oh
I am
but
Y
[Music]
i
Y
I do not
i have done this is what works
your wifi
d yes
only
I'm fed up
More music]
judgments
[Music] a
or
all [Music]
why and
the time is green
but my eyes what are we blind
[Music]
when when alone
your position
God
and so many other 600 more and flowers
But they are
I am
[Music]
Yes
more
what I do
laughs
and character
two
or
ah now these months
Yes
Y
I get it
and no
Y
it's okay
to
and 2
x
where
without the maxim 2
ah to do
[Music] frontis
oops
He says
Y
or
weiss is still active 6
Youtube
Augustine they ah
although nobody 80 years
two
feinstein yes
in this session
d in hand
so yeah
[Music] and more
if you drive
and in those visits to
Yes
[Music]
I'm going to hear these verses
Yes
d
alonso that is
this
just two of our [Music]
then show
[Music]
run if historical goals
Y
with the encounter though