it can anyone hear me at the back is
okay
I like cool I can see hands over the
back side there we go so let me just
adjust this
so Who am I as I said it's a Peter
suitor my senior pro service engineer at
puppet labs I've been a puppet for two
years have been using puppet for I say
close to six years now it says five on
there but yeah so i i'm a senior pro
service engineer so i work with
customers i do stuff like this so i do
talks and things like that but i also
work in the community and i like opening
pull requests on modules i use so I
should give a quick warning before I
start is that I speak quite quickly even
now like the brain power to make sure
that in sweida my normal speed was like
this it's like taking up half my brain
and remembering my slides of the other
half so if I go too fast
someone just wave or you know just say
slow down and I'll see if I can calm
down myself out of it and also I should
probably put this disclaimer up as the
as someone who is not a lawyer or an
auditor or you know signed an NDA if
your company or anything like that make
sure that anything I advise in here you
don't just tell you hopefully you should
need to be warned about something like
this but it does happen
don't just take the stuff I'm talking
about and just go and implement with
your company without talking to someone
who knows what they're talking about
first so why are we here Sherpa in the
room who has to deal with some sort of
compliance at their company oh it's a
lot of people so it makes sense cuz it's
the color court so white compliance and
what does it actually mean so it's a
pretty good definition here from the
computer weekly website basically
compliance the TLDR is that there is
some sort of legal obligation or not
always legal sometimes it's just an
agreement like a framework but basically
someone has told you that there are set
of rules that you need to follow and
this is a kind of a side thing here but
it's an important though that compliance
is not security or more accurately
compliance doesn't directly correlate
security it's a part of a secure kind of
framework you have your company but just
because something is compliant doesn't
mean it's going to be secure it might
help but it's not just that
and a good explanation and I'll put a
link to this blog post later on is
basically compliance is the
there's a plane and verification of
scale because the the general idea is
that if you think about your system if
you had to document every single like
file that's on there and how they're
working it's gonna be pretty difficult
so compliance is basically a framework
around making sure that at your company
you've got an agreed-upon kind of
framework for how you're doing things
and as people who probably put their
hand up and so who in so people put
their hand up for compliance put your
hand up is the compliance or sort of
like stuff you have to do your company
just gets thrown over the wall at the
last minute there's a few hands there
okay
so the thing about compliance is it
often kind of straddles different
organizational silos at least with some
of the customers I've worked with
compliance is sometimes literally there
is a compliance team which is separate
from the security team which is separate
from the operations team which is bad
generally you know the whole point of
DevOps is it's not just a buzzword it's
for everyone to kind of work together on
the same team but because of that
compliance often ends up being thrown
over the wall to the last minute you
know someone just comes in and goes oh I
ran an esse scan across your network you
need to fix all this stuff and that kind
of stuff need to be brought left you
know brought into your kind of workplace
but regardless of you know what the
definition compliance is or if you even
want to do it a lot of times you don't
get the choice and someone's told you
that you need to follow the rules so
there's now for that soup of all the
various acronyms and things that you
need to follow there these are quite
American bias because a lot of the
research online is American bias but the
one that you probably recognized from up
there if you I vote if you're not
American or you're working in Europe
we're going to be PCI DSS maybe ITIL and
some others stake maybe if you're doing
work in these states
there's a bunch up there and even if
you're not following any sort of
governmental compliance or legal kind of
requirements you might have compliance
based on an agreed-upon framework
internally so you might just have a set
of what you know most people call
hardening policies so they're not
directly correlated to you know some
governmental standard but they're just
like this is what we need to do to get
stuff working at our company and in that
this is one that comes up quite a lot
the center Center for Internet Security
it's basically a kind of
non-governmental fork of the stig
standards but it is fairly popular
because a lot of you know banks and
stuff they
scared of using something like stick
because it explicitly made by companies
you know organizations like the NSA and
they're a bit worried about that kind of
stuff so this is like the CIS is the
kind of more business-friendly version
of it but essentially a lot of those and
we'll see later on a lot of those CIS
what other compliance standards are
pretty similar to stick if not the same
yeah I got a reason to say I so popular
is that it covers a lot of stuff so the
huge list there if you can pretty move
to see most of things that you can think
of you know FreeBSD very Microsoft
various databases Amazon Linux and
things like that you know it covers a
lot of different areas that are so the
thing about compliance is that another
good note on compliance is that
sometimes it doesn't directly correlate
to actual technical requirements you
have to dig through a lot of legalese to
actually find something you can work on
directly with code so an example is the
HIV HIPAA which is basically just in
American law around health insurance in
the States so this is the actual text of
the requirements around that so if you
look at something like that and if you
actually go to that website you have the
full like because the whole compliance
stuff around HIPAA is basically it was
written for senators and for lawmakers
and stuff like that so you have to take
this document that's in legalese and
drill down to what you actually do
though so if we go through that we need
to look at 45 CFR part 60 and parts a
and C apart one six four so let's go and
do that so you have a bunch of headlines
like this and you know if you're bored
maybe you go through a single one of
them looking for so the bit you probably
care about this bear here the technical
safeguards so tender people safeguard
seems like something that we care about
so these are the technical safeguards
and some of these are more kind of
engineering problems and some of them
can't really be covered by conflict
management
so some of these will be directly config
management tools and some of these will
be may be installed by configure
management tools so the idea that you
have to have you know specific logins
and you have auditability maybe you
can't do that with your config
management but an LDAP tool that then
logs into some sort of you know syslog
or something like that would you then
toward it so your company management
tool helps with that but it can't work
directly and basically the the level of
compliance you can give and the
difficulty you have with compliance is
directly correlated with how friendly or
how kind of adversarial you are with
your auditors because the end of the day
the auditors are the ones that actually
decide whether you're in compliance or
not so depending on how you're auditing
is being done whether it's an internal
team or an external team you ultimately
have to work with them and it can be an
adversarial relationship but it's a bad
idea because as I said they're the ones
that hold you're sort of the key to
actually getting signed off so it's good
to work with them on this kind of stuff
I'm probably problem of this is that a
lot of time compliance the manual
process especially if you are in a
company that hasn't gone through this
kind of DevOps kind of transformation or
any sort of agile transformation there
you a lot of these processes are being
kept in emails or in PDFs or even dead
trees you've got you know I've seen
pictures of here is our compliance stack
and it's just a stack of paper this big
if someone's printed off the sticks then
it's something like that or the worst
story to information which is humans
because you know Cubans are an unsolved
problem in IT it's very hard to get
information from one human to another a
lot of time especially if you're in the
adversarial kind of a relationship there
so you know put my best infomercial
voice there's got to be a better way so
if you think about it what is IT
compliance is a series of rules for
systems that need to be enforced and
reported on and what is configuration
management it's a series of rules for
systems that need to be enforced and
reported on so we can use config
management tools for this stuff and if
you're here you probably have very
experience with this so what's the
advantage of actually doing that we've
got reduced in top cost and time per
release you know automating stuff makes
things better it means that you have a
sort of creed upon standard for things
you've got the idea of sharing every
youth and I'm gonna talk about like the
size Newton once said you need to stand
on the shoulders of giants a lot of
people have already done the work for
you you don't have to tell the stuff all
over again
and for example DDS the government
digital service in the UK they open
source all their work because
technically taxpayer money is going
towards all this code so they try and
open source as much as possible and then
you know they've already done the work
for you there's no point having to do it
again
yeah you have a single source of truth
if you have compliance as code then you
have a single place you can go look for
it instead of having to dig for a bunch
of emails and talk to a bunch of people
and I at one point I had no argument
about semantics but more accurately is
less arguments about semantics because
if you've got a knack read upon standard
a DSL the main cific language you can
you don't have to argue about like oh
what you do this we've said or we do a
fork and that kind of stuff nice you're
arguing about semantics yeah and as I
said a lot of the requirements for these
compliance standards some of them aren't
actually technological things so if we
go back to the HIPAA standards and their
some of them were stuff like you need a
security guard outside of your data
center and that kind of stuff you
unfortunately we can't automate that
stuff yet so the more time you have to
get rid of the technical stuff the more
you can sort of push the soft skill
stuff away so how does it actually look
like in action let's to pick a really
basic example on how we would actually
do this with company management tools so
talking about the CIS standards you can
actually go and get the COS benchmarks
there so we're going to talk about the
central 7 machine and here's central 7
rule 1 2 3 I just picked the most basic
one just to show because I'm going to
talk about one given both face example
as I can obvious is going to be more
complex ones but the TLDR of this is
that you should have GPT check keeping
checking with one if you're a Red Hat
system and you want the standards cuz
hopefully your packages should be signed
and you could you sign
but it's not the greatest color there
but you can see there's a really basic
example of how to do in puppet you know
there's a million ways you can do this
you can use all gifts you could use an
actual we can manage the entire file but
to make things simple I'm just me use a
file line and if you're not meeting with
a puppet this is basically gonna red X
look the key PT check one if it's there
if it's there something else is going to
change it my way and again as I said I
work for puppet I'm gonna try and be as
bipartisan as possible and give the
other examples so there might be some
chef people out in the audience to
probably say there's a bow of doing this
but this is just the first one I could
find so similar thing usually replace
the rad resource and then go through and
look for DPG check and then similar in
salt look through the young calm look at
upp check and similar ad support and as
I said no put the hand up and say
there's actually a better way of doing
this because a most experienced with
puppet I just went for the most basic
solution that kind of illustrates what
you're doing
so one of the things that comes up a lot
so I think first services so one of the
resort basic requirements of puppet for
Pro Services is someone's come along and
told us that we need to be you know PCI
compliant something like that and they
want some coffee managing to do it and
there's a few different approaches to
how you actually use conflict management
to do this so one would be you already
have a bunch of config management code
and then you basically just make sure
that that code you've already written
gives you the compliance you need so for
example I'm going to be a puppet example
here for that young check if you had
before maybe you already have a young
module that you've got and you just go
in there and change the parameter make
sure that your PT check equals one so
that's the and that's the method I
recommend the most you should be using
the existing calling that you've got but
I talked about silos earlier on
sometimes
someone's primary use case for
compliance and config management is just
for compliance or nothing else they just
want to use this tool maybe they've got
a different tool and they're using this
just for this one area so in that case
you might use a dedicated CIF module or
Steve module or something like that and
then you actually use it for that way
and a lot of people end up using some
sort of if they're using their
compliance tooling as a scanner as well
so not just enforcing it or maybe they
can't enforce it cuz again they're very
siloed maybe they've got a change freeze
but they need to scan through your
system most config management tools have
some sort of dry run mode and puppets
know up in chef it's try run in ansible
I think it's dry run anyone is it dry
run oh that's cool check just check the
asset and then I think there's anyone
salt in the room is there with dry run
and salt testing is cool true ok next
thing so some people you know if they're
in a siloed place or somewhere where
they can't easily they're moving on that
journey and they can't easily just run
stuff on their systems they can run
stuff in a dry run mode and go through
that so the few approaches you can do
here and remember we talked about
sharing reuse we don't have to write all
this stuff all over again because lots
of people don't for us the ones out
there is dev sector IO is just a website
where there's been a bunch of code
written in chef puppet and ansible lots
of pre-existing stuff of this and
they're not perfect again you know as
you said need to find something and
don't use an input media implemented it
there's some common
on there saying this doesn't follow that
in the right way but there's some good
stuff out there and there's a lot of
existing code that you can use so that's
deficit that I oh so there's simp the
system integrity management platform
this is a kind of is an entire stack
written by onyx point so this was
something that they built for the NSA
and for an American government systems
the idea is that the simp stack is
puppet with a bunch of pre-written
modules that follow the simplest
standards over in the states will be at
NFA standards and then they have some
cool stuff on top they're actually got
some really cool kind of higher at all
that will go through and it will
actually write compliance logs and write
those kind of reports that were your
compliance people like HTML reports that
say this is what's changed from the
puppet run you just had and a lot some
of that stuff is in public yet if you
talk to Trevor born on the puppet slack
in the security room he'll talk about
that stuff one way this ends will be
locked and again this is just some quick
bruising as I said I mainly puppet and
I'm trying to be bipartisan as possible
if there's level stuff come and talk to
me afterwards so I can add in for next
time
the danceable lockdown Mansel partnered
up with a security partner and they
wrote some I think these have sitting
yeah these are the stig standards so
they've written some pre-written play
books for the stick standards and for
all the stuff you go in the community
hubs if you go to the Falls you go for
the cookbooks you get the galaxy if you
look up like a CIA source dig
lots of people have written this code
before you so don't write all the stuff
yourself if you have to try new
something that someone's read before and
for kitten
however there's a two parter compiler to
IT compliance there the enforcement and
then there's reporting so conflict
management can be used for both but I
tend to saw say that you want to use the
config management part for the enforcing
and use a separate tool for reporting
and there's a few reasons for that one
is that as you said some of the stuff
can't be caught with config managers
much the other thing is that a certain
standard yeah so for certain standards
there are what are known as ASVs so for
certain compliance standards only people
that have been officially given this or
kosher stamp like this is the thing you
can do can do that so sometimes you
can't use puppet or chef or whatever
because it's not been signed off yet
and a third player is we're at FOSDEM so
the sad part is there's not as many open
source versions of compliance tools
because compliance you know it's a big
business it's a lot of enterprise
companies they have lots of clothes or
software and I'm not saying that those
tools aren't good I actually have some
I've actually had some pretty
interesting conversations with the
nessus team about some of this stuff but
you know we're at FOSDEM so let's talk
about open source stuff
so the most popular one and this is
something there's actually I think I
looked through the foster schedule and
there's been I think there's two or
three talks about open s camp it's
putting the words popular one out there
there's lots of tooling around it
Red Hat maintained a lot of stuff for it
there's lots of pre-existing standards
things like FISMA and DSS and yeah it
plugs into a lot of things so the most
basic implementation of that is the
actual command line tool so this is me
running it on a vagrant box I'm just
using it and just doing a yum install to
install it I'm running in a vowel with
the most basic report and then it gives
me a file on disk like an actual HTML
file I can look through and see all
those compliance damage there's also the
scat workbench which is just a GUI for
this and this works of SSH as well so
you can do it on remote systems just
means a slightly easier than having to
do on the command line and save one of
the good things about open escape isn't
because it's a standard people have
written a lot of tools to use it so you
don't have to do on the command line you
don't have to do it exactly with the
benchmark they're out of the way there's
api's and stuff like that so Foreman
actually has a plugin for this and
satellite is built on top of Foreman so
satellite also has an open air that s
cup scanner and funnily enough I just
added this light in five minutes ago
because I checked and there's actually a
talk about doing Foreman with open s cap
so if you want to go learn more about
that there's actually a talk tomorrow in
the security track so go see that as
well an open s cap the only one I saw is
Linus I think it's fairly new I think
it's about two or three years old this
point and it's pretty cool it's open
source it works on a lot of platforms
it's fairly simple to install I think
it's just a binary that you can get the
sad thing is that the actual compliance
standard plugins like so where your
works is it has like a sort base system
and then your plugin for the various
compliance standards you've got so the
compliance standards are actually
they're commercial and it not open
source so you can run it on a basic
overall scan that looks something like
this I can't see it but the idea is that
you run it on your system and it just
goes for and looks at this or standard
stuff makes your etc' password has the
right permissions make sure that your
grub has password and that kind of stuff
and the last one which people don't talk
about so much is using Packer
for compliance so they're looking really
good talk by Verna buck at the
last hash econ and he was talking about
how they use packer with AWS and am is
to do compliance because some of the
compliance standards especially on
things like file mounts and you know
grub settings and things like that
they're hard to do on running systems
it's the kind of thing you probably want
to bake into your golden image process
sort earlier on in the stack because it
makes you a lot easier to do and yeah
like you know how she can't actually
cope do or some products and packet and
a lot of cool stuff and the thing about
factories that have provisioning
provisioners like pretty much all the
popular conflict management tools out
there so you know has a shell provision
our puppet for business chef for
business so you can use that code yet
you've already written use it and bake
it into your a.m. eyes and your various
kind of gotten image things so how do we
actually report this stuff other than
using open SKF and linus and that kind
of stuff there's a Wynonna system
testing dear self so the most popular
one who everyone's heard of so who here
has heard of service spec or he's even
using service pack right cool that's
like twenty thirty people all right so
it's fairly popular and if you're not
familiar that looks something like this
it's basically if you're familiar aspect
looks something like this basically sort
of our spec helpers to do things like
check like files our own system and they
have the right permissions so here's a
really basic CIS check it's for the one
we talked about earlier on the GPG and
it makes it go through make sure that's
all there so you run this on your system
and it gives you I think saying note
that files not there or had the wrong
permissions so if server spec is so
popular that's inspired a bunch of other
kind of port of it so you've got got
which is pretty much the same thing but
we and then go
you've got infra tester which is
basically the same thing but with
reserved keywords for things like HTTP
requests and headers and my ceilin stuff
like that
you've got gaunlet which is more of a
BDD version of this and similar we have
BDD security so those are same they're
written and gherkin their feature files
that you run but it's basically wrappers
around actual security tools so things
like making sure that your that's more
of a kind of app set kind of side of it
but you can do some of that for your
compliance stuff as well and even though
it's compared to the operation mention
this to this quite cool tool in specs by
chef it's pretty much kind of like a
clean room color for cover them service
pack it works in a similar way it looks
something like this again that quotation
token better color for this but the idea
is that it just extended key words on
top of service pack kind of language to
say you know this is the compliance for
all and it's lift level of security that
has these tags then the code itself
looks quite similar past config file
each ECE uncom should contain GPT check
is one and then there's a talker
complete a config madison county 16
about using this and actually the
beginning part of it is quite similar to
talking about how compliance shouldn't
be a bunch of papers and it should be
actual code that you can give out and
stuff like that so what are we learnt
compliance enforcement of standards it's
not security but it's part of a security
flow and in the best case it should be
moved left you shouldn't be throwing the
stuff over the fence the last minute
yeah as me said compliance
responsibilities can be tricky like who
ultimately is actually responsible for
this stuff is the octene is the security
team do you have a dedicated compliance
team
Kovach management fits really well with
the compliance kind of use case the idea
that you have to enforce standards based
on that pretty close and regardless of
the tool you use there's a lot of
pre-existing work so don't just start
all over again and enforcement just part
of the puzzle reporting is out there as
well and unfortunately there's not much
open-source software for this stuff but
there is lots of existing tools that you
can use but ultimately depending on the
compliance standard you're following you
might actually have to use a commercial
product because they're the owns have
been signed up for it they keep things
like PCI so if you want to know more
there's a bunch of awesome talk they're
out there this one from last year's papa
comp it's actually Trevor talking about
Sims and how it all works and have an
open-source compliance they talk about
more of the complex news cases they
actually have some pretty cool stuff
where when they were testing all of
their state compliance stuff they were
using beaker which is like a Test
Kitchen like for automation tool and
they actually caught a bunch of kernel
bugs in various Linux distributions so
using this automated software and using
this they actually caught problems both
in the compliance standards and in the
actual upstream which is pretty cool
and if you've not read the DevOps
handbook there's a really good section
by Jean Kim and others there's a really
good section on compliance and so that's
a love it's hard to find a lot of real
life use cases of compliance stuff
because people don't like talking about
their compliance because legal stuff
people get scared about it but they
don't have a bunch of case studies and
there that's really good so I've gone
way faster than I thought I would so
when I tie myself doing this at home I
did about this about 55 minutes I've
done this in about 25 so got lots of
time for questions that people have
questions no okay then I get to go
they're going up here I think the summit
is I know for PCI it isn't I went
through the ASV for PCI on 40 open s cap
isn't but the general use case I've seen
for it and talking to companies that use
it is that it's a good way of catching
that stuff before you have to hand it
over to the official scanner kind of
team so it means that you can bring
stuff on earlier on instead of having
all that stuff out there and then having
it back and going oh no everything's
gone wrong the nest skank all the stuff
you can bring it earlier on okay yeah so
the question was is open s cap signed
off for compliance standards and the
answer is it depends but I know for PCI
DSS it isn't but yeah it depends on the
standards and a lot of time people kind
of use it internally for their ops team
and that the compliance team handle the
actual kind of official audit compliance
mess any other questions no okay well
sorry about going too fast and come up
and talk to me if you have any more
questions thank you very much
[Applause]