good afternoon good evening my name is
Rory O'Donnell and I'm gonna be assisted
with my gorgeous
co-presenter over here dalla boar so I'm
the openjdk group quality lead dalla
burro is the wonderful title of
principal product manager for the Java
platform group and between us we're
going to talk to you about the JDK 9
outreach that the awesome parts so
prepare to be dazzled the obligatory ten
seconds we don't yet you're fast readers
right okay so this is what our agenda is
about so I'm going to take items one and
two and Alipore is gonna take three and
four so let me just give you some
background
what is this JDK nine outreach for jdk
age we wanted to make sure that we
didn't have the same situation when JDK
7 when GA and we had issues almost
immediately thanks to who we add Apache
loosin so we wanted to go out and talk
to the community at large and say come
and work with us download our early
access bills test them as let us know
what issues you find so the first person
we approach was ooey and he was
delighted to come aboard and suggested
others that might be of the same frame
so before JDK 8 actually shipped we
actually got some like 20 open source
community members to actually projects
to come and talk to us and work with us
downloading and logging bunks at the
moment we're up to a hundred and one
we've just broken through the 100
projects so we are communicating the
changes that are in early access bills
to over a hundred open source projects
I'd love to know if any of you guys have
ever heard of me before coming in here
and actually had received emails on
device main
lists or anything that you see me
annoyingly sending out these emails all
the time anybody one yes sounds great
okay it's me okay it's all my fault
okay so so this is a continuous process
and in the last 16 months we've added 18
new and actually we've added 20 because
another two came in in the last two
weeks since these slides were actually
created and one of the great things that
we measure is how this is how successful
we are but this is the number of bumps
that are coming in from the community in
the last year we've had 60 new 64 issues
loved and I'll show you how some of
these break down into different
priorities and components and stuff so
in total since we actually started it's
a hundred and seventy-three bugs have
actually been logged and I see lots of
phases here of the people who have
actually logged those bugs so it's great
to see you here it's so simple to
actually join I would like to recommend
it to every single one of you here today
this is something that you will we give
you information about what's going into
the latest build and changes that might
break you and advise you okay if you're
doing this you need to test on this
particular build so all you have to do
is send a mail to the quality discuss
OpenJDK or you can send a mail to me as
well if you prefer and the great thing
is what you can't really read this but
if you if that was a little bit clearer
you would see that stefan bought a vague
from apache ant i had being annoying him
for so long to come and join us and he
was actually doing testing but he didn't
want his stuff listed externally because
he thought everybody would be annoying
him so eventually he sent me an a and
they'll either 8 a.m. in the morning and
by 10 minutes past 8 I hadn't listed on
the OpenJDK quality external page so I
can't guarantee every time that I'm
going to get you listed within 10
minutes but I will you know I will do my
best to get you on there
now these are the guys who are this is
just five but these are the guys that
love the most bugs and the highest
quality bugs in the last six months
number one Apache loosen and that's
usually Hui Apache Tomcat came in with
six bugs in a row just together just
here you go six boats thank you really
really you know this is what actually
helps us to make sure and improve the
quality of the release that we actually
release at GA time so thank you to these
guys they've done a sterling job they
you know it makes our life so much
better and when the books come in
Delabar and I will make sure that they
you know and these bugs are given the
proper viewing by the right people so we
try to get them because we know the
quality of the bugs coming in from the
people are absolutely first-class
and need to be fixed now just give you
an idea of the overall from from the
when we started this so we a hundred and
seventy-three bugs have been logged as I
mentioned lovely to see that we have
zero unresolved p-one and p-two bugs
from the loads that are come in from the
commuting we still have fourteen three
threes that we have to work on so that's
work in progress but you can see here
that we fixed 94 or sorry 96 of these so
they're obviously bugs that we
interpreted as being high quality needed
to be fixed before we actually shipped
the product out so thank you again for
logging all these bugs so that's my
priority now if you looked in at the
different components when if you were to
look at a similar graph whereas this 12
months ago he would have seen that hot
spot was the one that was getting the
most bugs
client and core libs have caught up very
much so in the last while so they have a
total of 46 and 23 whereas hotspot still
is just up there with 51 but what we can
see is that you know the the number of
bugs is actually going down and with
that I'm going to hand over to my Abel
that's wonderful so before I get started
with the slides right that's the boring
part what we usually do here is we have
a governing board session afterwards and
these guys drinking beer and there are
five governing board members I bought
six beers so what I'm gonna do is I'm
gonna give one beer out to one of yous
whose project signs up for this quality
outreach stuff on quality - disgust at
hope adjudicate java.net by the end of
this talk right so get on it and then
come back later get a beer and now we
can go over the slides so the thing
about nine is of course we've been doing
this for a while and the one question
people ask me a lot about nine is does
anybody really care about nine yet
aren't people just moving up to eight
like this average stuff the developers
really want to know about this stuff and
so what do we do well worry since a lot
of emails so there is that but a
question is you know do do other
projects care the people already filed
box against issues in line on their own
this is something happening there so one
way to look at this is looked at their
main list traffic through archives like
mark mail and just search for subpoena
and we find Rory a lot of times right
this guy is sending out a lot of email
and getting a lot of replies back too
which is good but you also find that if
you look at how that's developed the
past couple years when I started out
there were like a thousand messages
across various projects in Apache and
Eclipse and so forth this is ground six
fold in the last two years in part
because we have worked diligently to get
more projects to sign up and participate
and they spread the word
and more importantly if you compare the
this to where we wear with JDK 8 a 1
year before it's J we were you know more
than double today in terms of jetting
down traffic outside of interest then
we're at the time of 8 at the same time
and if you look at how encouraging you
know the community reaction was to eight
how much people people cared about
getting their self to work with a I
think this is a really good you know
data point to look forward to so next
slide please
now the other data point to look forward
to is that you know one thing is to try
to extract random data of the Internet
the other is to just ask people directly
so in this outreach effort we have this
project participating so what we did
about two years before Jia won this this
autumn was to this short serving and
just to ask the participating projects
you know if they're testing at all how
far along they are what their you know
success is and so we had about a half of
the projects that participate in Kauai
cartridge
came back to us filled out a survey
around 90 percent actually tried already
to build the project with nine and had
some success and about 86 percent plan
to support nine within the first year of
the release of JDK nine and I think this
is really really a good piece of data to
have because if you if you look at the
talks you know like us and so forth
there is work to be done I work to be
done on the JDK so of course to make
sure that we have a great release work
to do bound to be done on a bunch of
libraries to make sure they work really
well with nine but there is also a
willingness in the community to
participate in this and I think this is
a great great thing to have it's a great
community were part of next slide and so
to give you some examples of the things
we've we've done in the past year
like I said Rory saying I'll send out
these emails tells people about the
builds tell us what's in them and then
hopefully some of them will try things
out let us know about things that break
and Rory mentioned that Tomcat project
was very active in giving us similarly
good bugs to work with so for example
Mark Thomas submitted an issue JDK
something or other about the default
behavior of your connection which was to
use caching and that turned out to be
problematic in particularly on Windows
or when you're using jar your
collections you may have having
descriptor leaks or you know fast may
end up dead locking and so he made a
suggestion there was a discussion first
between us where we try to figure out
this is something that we can resolve
between us already then the discussion
upon a suggestion was carried over to
the core lips - their main list in open
JDK and their Markey and members of the
jdk team discussed various ways to
address the problem it was finally
resolved by adding an API for this by I
think Michael a man while maintaining
the current behavior so that existing
code that relies on this doesn't break
so there's new API for this since Java 9
there's a Get Set default use caches in
Java natural connection and this is just
one example of the kind of interactions
we have with developers participating
projects it's not all just box they find
it's also extensions they need is those
are things they find that should be
working better in a future release where
they need functionality it isn't there
yet next please another example for
example is with ant as Suba mention his
talk the Apache ants team has actually
done a really good job of getting their
code to work and pass all the tests with
nine and then it turned out of course
that it had one month much more problem
and usually we can help with the simple
stuff where people forgets to set their
release flag or whatever if we can't
help directly we direct them to the
right mailing list which also can be
challenging because their main listen
open JDK for stuff like this
in this case Stefan was having one
testing and that was failing due to well
the things people do you know
reflection trickery to get at internal
API in XML posit to do something or
other and of course we cannot with
modules that doesn't work anymore so
what are you gonna do well you can
complain you can write a blog post you
can tweet angrily or you can go to core
leaves there and that's what he did and
said you know I would like to find a
good way to solve this
and so there was a thread on core Lib
step which went on for unix-like for you
know for a few weeks
right they wanted to use an excellently
pass from within eclipse will ask your
manager how they make this work it was
resolved with a couple of weeks with a
change both in a JDK where turn out to
have to be a bug in our implementation
of the XML functionality and also by
making some small adjustment to the test
code in Apache and so that's the other
thing we you know we try to work with
with community projects to make sure
that their code gets better as well and
uses the new friction ID and then of
course there is more some of the project
we started to work with because we came
across you know their own efforts to to
get the code to work with nine like a
Patrick health side and Julian heinously
I think the the VP for that in the
Patrick when it started out they had
some challenges right we spoke we got
him on board and eventually you know
their stuff runs annoying happy about it
other projects are actually using the
soul moved to nine thing as a way to get
the users to move off old versions lock
for J who here uses apache log4j right
everybody uses a bachelor for j2 right
because we're using one one is kind of
end-of-life and so it's also broken on
nine due to new versioning changes and
so the log4j team has gone off and
contacted their users in apache to help
them to upgrade to move off lock for j1
with a more current version that works a
nine of course
similarly other projects that we are in
touch with in the same maven ecosystem
you have done a lot of good work over
the past year to make sure that the
functionality we provide
is actually supported by the tools
result a number of issues and made a
number of you know incremental releases
improving their their facilities to work
with the release itself and sometimes
this is sometimes a bit challenging
because what we try to do is we try to
sign up the projects from our side
approaching directly there are the most
popular ones and that sometimes also
means changing chasing down they say
Diaspora of google codes or of code
house of these various hosting sites
that if over time you know they manage
disappeared and finding out you know who
is still running these projects so we
can actually get them involved because
many of these things like cue dogs are
eventually dependencies that a bunch of
popular projects will depend on so we
want these dependencies to work with
nine and future releases and of course
we want your code to be part of this too
next slide
yeah awesome and so for us the question
now that 9 is you know getting close to
the end game and 10 is opening up what
do we do next so where do we go with say
JD King 10 outreach what should we be
looking at doing better and different
for the next release and with that I'd
like to open up for questions because I
think we have about seven more minutes
[Music]
so developers from both maven and Gradle
are in both there are of course for some
of them in some cases challenges in
graybles case there's some interesting
issues have cropped up because the
module system does restrict access to
private classes so there is for example
in Gradle there is one one
dimensionality that's there to be able
to set environment variables on demons
and to do that it goes into you know an
unmodifiable collection using so
accessible of environment variables and
makes it modifiable again which is maybe
not something you should be doing right
but the thing is it's really a tricky
problem setting environment variables
under state jelly PC he's not as nice
and easy as it sounds
there's a wonderful manual page page in
joseon linux that's basically tells you
don't do this in military programs or
bad things will happen so this is an
example where you know the Gradle team
has look at issues they have with the
code and figure out if there is a better
way to do this if there is a different
way to implement punch 19 in 9 or if
this is something where we would need to
think about providing adequate
interfaces insulator release if we can't
do this you know at all right if the GFC
says you can't do this then that's a
problem for me even Robert from the
mainland team has been around here as
well and they've been working on a
number of things I don't think that all
of their tests pass yet they don't if
you know
the issue right so we have a number of
things to go through to make you know
things work as they as we hope they
should but what we're trying to do here
is create a channel between developers
of the major projects and the teams
working behind you know the scenes on
say JDK and direct memory mapping is who
we mentioned so that people who you know
work together can actually work together
in open JDK yeah absolutely I mean
that's why that's what built tools and
low that libraries like that have been
you know our first kind of target to
reach out to we have since try to expand
this this coverage you know to cover
other areas of the JVM as well so we
have as we've seen before
a lot of good input from say Hoover and
these themes about hotspot issues we
have really good about core elaborates
issues areas where we would like to see
more projects come here say things like
job effects where we only have a few
project participants so far or
serviceability and and parts like that
so you know if you don't if you do this
though if you the all project that works
in these parts we would really welcome
you over here right to participate in
this and let us know about issues that
break if you do work on build systems
that are not maven Gradle and something
else
you're very welcome as well right
yeah there'll be a number of recent
changes in as Superman should bill 148
that have that's a bit of you know
struggle for a number of tools but I
think this will gradually get worked out
it would be very useful as well if you
could go to the quality outreach page
and look at the list see is there any
projects on there that are really
missing that you think should be on
there we'd love to and if there if you
have contacts we're more than happy to
go talk to them I don't think we do
have you talked to Apache Felix or or CI
framework people for Jada k9 built
pretty sure we talked to Apache Felix
I'm not entirely I can't remember off
the top of my head whether we got a
positive response or not so um we have a
kind of 50% if race we think when we go
out to people and ask them do they want
to join us it's like if we go out to 150
then we'll come back and say yes okay so
sometimes it's because we don't know the
actual you know the real person who
should be caught and we should be
contacting two so that's why it would be
really great if you guys could have a
look and see are we missing projects and
if you know of context that would really
help us tell your friends tell your
friends
tell where we have one person signed up
[Music]
[Laughter]
[Applause]