so if you were here previously you know
my name is kasper and I'm an electronic
design engineer and software developer
this talk is well a web service and
browser extension that I worked I've
been working on which is to make it
easier to replicate electronics projects
once their design is finished so I'd
like to give some context for the
motivation behind this and I grabbed
some statistics from various places
about to try and gauge the number of
electronic engineers they are in the
world and how that compares to software
developers so in the you know you can
look at these statistics here and kind
of guesstimate the amount of people
there in the world working on so on
electronic engineering versus software
and so kind of in summary there's about
one Yi to every 3d program is maybe and
then I was when you think about it
there's maybe you know 1 in 10 software
engineers know C and if you but if you
compare that kind of forums on
electronics versus C programming if you
just reduce the subset you you get quite
favorable numbers into pitting for
electronics really and the question
really is where what why where's the
Linux of electronics and this is a lot
of people think about this is actually
logo from the open hardware repository
from CERN and I think it captures that
idea quite well you know where what why
isn't this happening and of course you
know it's not software and there's a lot
of labor and kind of physical movement
and things I have to happen for to make
electronics happen but there's a lot of
automation as well so this is a pick and
place machine which you know it's quite
advanced automation and board prices are
going down you can iterate as a design
engineer you can iterate quite quickly
on a hardware project
you it doesn't cost that much to make
her get a boat made anymore
and it's more accessible for everyone
and we do shake projects so I did a
survey a while back and there's about
3,000 Cod projects on github about 7,000
ego projects and ash Park which is a PCB
batching service they have a kind of
little project they're sharing thing
where you can download Gerber's for four
projects there's about 9,000 projects on
there and there's all hackaday and
ee-vie blog forums and all these
different ways of sharing projects I
think and it's an interesting problem to
to look at I think and I think part of
the problem is maybe we have a heritage
of doing very amazing things but not
making it so understandable for other
people to replicate that this is a
picture from oh I didn't run down
the reference I think it's at the end is
Bob it's Bob peas I can't remember the
title of the book but and so my my kind
of approach to this was we want to have
all these different way of doing things
like the Chi card and all the different
ways of sharing things and all the ways
of different ways of making PCBs and
kind of munch it all up and at the end
of it what do you really want you want
the PCB and you want the parts to make
the PCB so my approach to this is the
kidney kit website which is a project
sharing website and the one-click bill
of materials browser extension which
works in your browser to replicate
replicate web requests to try and
automate automatically put things into
retailer shopping carts so this is the
one trick one browser extension that was
first presented at first I'm actually in
2015 and it's still it's still there
still works it automates purchasing by
replicating the web requests are sent to
use retailer sites so it currently works
for digi-key Mauser RS New York Farnell
element14 and you might ask why why does
this need to be a browser extension
can't you just make a website that
he puts things into carts well not
really and there's some exceptions to
this but basically the the retailer
website would have to allow pretty much
you your specific website or you to do
this so this is a quote from the same
origin Percy is what is implemented in
browsers basically to prevent one site
from messing with your data on another
site and there's a good little comic
about that but I'm not sure see me now's
a good time favorite reason I'm not sure
what I put the hem there but I'm going
to skip it so this you can you can look
up the slides and look at that coming
it's a quite it's cute this is the kind
of request you have to send for what is
this the Mauser site to add something to
your cart and there's quite a lot of
stuff in there and maybe you don't
strictly need but there
the crucial thing actually is this
viewstate element which goes on
thousands and thousands of bytes for
some reason and you need to send that to
its to to modify the user's cart so in
the in the the way I kind of handle this
this complexity of all these different
retailers all the different countries
and these kinds of the kind of lengthy
requests is I use a lot of testing and
make sure that it works across all the
different sites and all the different
countries but with using this
integration testing so this one's a test
for funnel and it checks for each
country that can add some parts to the
car checks the cart and you can empty it
and if there's a failure if there's
something fails it'll notice and also if
but it won't like it often the way the
retailer sites work is it if something
fails it'll be in your cart for you to
see but really it it if you if you want
the extension to work that you should be
able to clear that out again and try the
next operation so this is what the
extension looks like and it's kind of
meant to be used in conjunction whether
with the spreadsheet on one side and you
can copy from the spreadsheet into the
extension and
and copy out of the extension back into
the spreadsheet so they're there five
retailers are currently supported and
you can add to the cart and empty the
cup so this is available for Chrome and
Firefox currently it works on
tab-separated values which is the
clipboard format for spreadsheets you
can also load an online bomb so if you
share below materialism on github or
somewhere in the right format you can
just load it directly into the extension
it can I've been working on features
where it can try and complete like if
you if you give it a description for a
part it will try and find the right path
for you it'll be more on that later it's
open source
Cpl license ever and it has about 500
users so back to this kind of a weird
analogy here we have a way of
replicating purchases from one person to
the other and you can do that across the
globe but it doesn't include the PCBU
necessarily and there's no neat way to
package everything together so this is
kind of what the kit nigut website is
for and the way that works is you put
everything into a git repository you use
the format that the extension
understands and the website understands
as well which is that one click tab
separate values you need a leaf
references quantity and a power number
two kind of that's like the minimum that
you should be able to specify about your
project and we use r27 4x Gerber's and
excellent drills and so this is kind of
the minimum file tree that you would
have you have you have the TSV and the
Gerber files so we're going to try and
do a live preview of the website
oh right yeah here we go
one second
so that's the front page
and there's a where's my scrollbar hmm
I'm sure that's not the websites fault
how do I screw on this have you know one
page down will always work great here we
go okay so these are some projects that
are on there ready we can make me select
one so it's a small FM transmitter kind
of demo project so it's got a nice
rendering of the Gerber files and it's
got a link here to get service there's
links here okay short descriptions and a
website link for more info and the
repository link and here is kind of the
magic where you need the browser
extension except in some instances I've
actually found that digi-key is enabled
cause requests to add parts completely a
new arc and fernell as well except the
extension kind of works better because
there's less friction in doing so you
won't be prompted for decisions for like
for New York you might be prompted to
make a decision on whether you want to
buy more parts for less money which you
don't really want to be prompted for
that so that's lit it's even less still
less friction with New York if you extol
the extension and for we did UK if you
install the extension and in new I can
find out that the way the extension
works it adds all the all the references
line notes to your to your shopping cart
so that when you get the parts you will
normally have in the in the in the you
know the printer details there what
parts are what already so it's kind of
the idea really is to to have a transfer
without the creator necessarily having
put to put together a kit they can
transfer all the information you need to
buy your own kit without them having to
bag components and things that's really
the big idea
should we try and buy something mm-hmm
so this won't actually use the extension
so this prompts you like I said do you
want to buy more parts for less money
yes I would like to right
there we go and there's all the parts
you need and you can go and buy that so
what I added a few days ago here we are
I'm a bit confused sorry we're more
right so this is what I added a few days
ago is because previously the way we
handed handles submissions was you sent
a pull request to the gab repo where the
site is in a way all the site source
code is and there's a boards a text file
where you add your the lines your
publicly accessible git repository and
then if everything looks ok then I'll
add that to the main branch the master
branch and the whole site is rebuilt
with your project in it so now I added
this a few days ago and you can try and
instead of you know just blindly going
does this work does this work you can
now get a kind of a better idea by doing
a preview so this is the kind of Arduino
example project and then renders the
thing for you and you can change the
color but they still they still know
there's still no accounts on the site or
anything so you still have to go by the
end of all of this if you've checked
everything seems to be in the right
place and there's the readme file and
the links and things then by the end of
it please send us a pull request so
there's still a lot of work to do there
no work maybe I've never seen that
anywhere so I'm not sure but right I'm
not sure how to get back to my
presentation all right
I don't think Mike even okay hey right
now this my okay so yeah like I said the
idea is really this virtual kit you
don't have to lift a finger you can
transfer all the information you need
through this through the website the way
it works right yeah the way it works we
use static site hosting for the moment
minute we I used continuous integration
to build the site and to kind of preview
you've seen me messing about with these
preview domains let's actually a branch
on there so whenever I make a branch and
I push it up to get up it'll build it'll
deploy it to my AWS server so I can have
a look at the side end and I can show
other people what's going on there and
like him I already went over this so
there's a lot of planned features really
it would be nice to add accounts and
have a management feature and have file
uploads and not necessarily force
electronic engineers to use git and
really I quite enjoy making tools that
help make Bills of materials I'm gonna
skip over this because I'm running out
of time
this would be a nice feature if you
could like to help you build the kit
even if you hover over somewhere you can
see we're on the boards with this is
kind of a philosophy that I take when
when implementing this is and like to
build them the the minimum thing that
could be useful and then to add on top
of that instead of trying to build the
whole thing at once
yeah that's a good question like I said
there's already caused requests there's
some pros and cons you can read up on
that oh that's supposed to be a nice
thing right um I guess the question for
me as well is how do I make this
development sustainable really there's a
lot of so far there's a lot of expenses
and there's there's some potential to
track referrals in the site and try and
try and make money of that and to
support the verb development or the
potential to you know add paid private
accounts and have people pay a
subscription to support or maybe some
other donation mechanism to support the
development write some code I don't
think I have a lot of time for the code
are there any questions at this point
yeah yes it would be possible very much
so I'm gonna continue sorry I shouldn't
have it's all JavaScript
everything's JavaScript I'm gonna I'm
going to come back to questions
afterwards initially if you look at the
old presentation it was CoffeeScript and
I've stopped using that to get advanced
features JavaScript features because
CoffeeScript was kind of getting in the
way where we still compile JavaScript to
JavaScript brilliant so the kidney
insight uses react as the front-end it's
kind of this this view layer made by
Facebook where you define lots of
different small modules you pretty much
writing HTML you get JavaScript to
always generate HTML for you instead of
getting JavaScript to manipulate HTML
for you so it does one pass and it
renders it and that's your static site
and then it uses this react front-end to
modify that I started building out micro
services and making use of micro
services so that what you saw there
their preview thing I've made a project
out of that it's a
it's kind of a little service where you
can put in a URL for a get repository
and it will serve all the files to you
so I think I want to continue to split
out little projects like this that could
be generally useful and open system this
is not my own thing I make use of this
for geolocation but that's another
service that's running for to support
kipnuk like I had a lot of things to say
about JavaScript which are probably one
at a time for but pretty much the gist
of it is that it's it's there's a lot of
bad things to say about JavaScript but
the ecosystem is pretty amazing right
now it is the people make little tiny
packages for everything so there's even
a package to left pata string that's one
JavaScript package that you can you can
include in your post and there was a bit
of controversy around this because the
person that was in charge of this remove
this from the repositories and it broke
a lot of important projects so there's
that you know upsides and downsides this
this is an amazing library that we make
use of a kitnik it's bit written by
Micheal cousins and it renders gabber
files using javascript it will work in
the browser it will work in on no Jess
in the backend and those are kind of the
dependencies that it has but Michael
cousins written all of this and want one
kind of neat thing that we've done well
we've collaborated on is what's that go
where which kind of takes all these
different ways of naming Gerber files
and and tries to figure out what the
stack up is and make the right
we were rendering right more codes I'd
plan to show you where I made use of NPM
packages to to make this feature which I
will skip ahead to and it's kind of
combined with the CPL data from octopod
so is it thing it does a quick look up
from your description
yeah I shoulda put me
so you kind of give it a description
paste that in there and press complete
and it figures out what parts you wanted
just from the description and this is
especially good for kind of generic
components if oh these are not actual
Windows Phone and you can put that back
into your spreadsheet or go and buy that
with the extension so I'd like to work
more on things like that to make making
Bills of materials easier right now this
is a bit like a self-driving car with
just one button you've got no control
you can just say complete and then you
have to check over all the mess that it
could potentially make so on my own time
three minutes ago I should have finished
including questions so I'm done right we
any questions yes yes there's I mean I
mean not like concrete plans but that
seems like a great feature to have yeah
so the question was why not generate
work file sorry yeah yeah yeah because
it varies so much across retailers so
what we have what I'd like is to have
the same way to do it across all the
different retailers and always this kind
of always the same steps yeah yeah it's
the it's it's it's actually the
clipboard format and it's just
tab-separated values so it'll work with
any spreadsheet multiple yeah multiple
vendor alternatives are currently not
supported in the format the only thing
that is support is multiple manufacturer
part numbers on the bill materials so
you can say the all these parts are
possible to be used here and then there
you have a selection for specific
retailer yeah exactly that so you can
have multiple manufacturer part number
manufacturer part number in your bill of
materials and then you could have us the
you could have a selection of one of
those for your retailer columns
the operation today on not atomic no you
pretty much you I've only tested this
doing one retail at a time and it won't
the website won't currently let you do
more try and add more components while
the other components already being added
but you can have quite large Bills of
materials so you can all add at once
well it would be quicker if you all did
it if you did it as one requests yeah
that's the trouble trying to validate
and making sure that it's it's correct
[Applause]