so good afternoon I'd like to present to
you ideas to people should really can I
have your attention please
[Music]
okay so basically what we want to
present here is some discussion we had
among inside today the document
foundation in how to modernize and to
bring to 2017 the liberal office help
what we have in the user knowledge
ecosystem is that we have the help
system that is bundled in in LibreOffice
we have user guides and books that are
written and published by the community
we have a very extensive wiki for a lot
of information gathering we have as an
ask bot it's a question-and-answer
website for the end user and we also use
mailing lists and also the user is able
to look into Google for information
sometimes Brown some some videos in
YouTube there is also a partial
OpenOffice forums and wikis and also
independent forums like Reddit and so on
okay so this is the universe of
information that you can get for the
LibreOffice technology so what we have
at the moment is the following the
liberal of this help is designed into
XML and it was designed about circa 2005
and at that time we had issues with
browsers the browser's browsers war was
full
in full no compatibility no one no
browser manufacturer was comfortable in
adopting standards so at that time Sun
Microsystems adopted an internal only
solution which is a specific XML to hold
the contents and the navigation of the
help system the internal browser is
writer web that was easy because you
just have one tool and you don't need to
test with several other browsers of
other browsers so then they develop a
C++ type wrapper to create an index and
to connect the dialogues to the do the
help pages okay the issue is that now
when you look at 2017 we have a complex
which we did and update hard to test and
visualize the XML that is written for
LibreOffice there is no rich text editor
available so what what we have is a help
authority Authority authoring extension
that you connects in your writer
document and then you start writing your
text your help page the problem is you
need quite a lot of skills in XML and
specificity of the schema to understand
what the help content is so for
end-users and for people that wants to
collaborate there is a quite steep entry
barrier to start writing help files is
also we considered it's an absolute
technology and for example we cannot
insert in the hub content we cannot
insert multimedia we can insert images
but not videos so this is a very old way
to assist the user looks old and
cumbersome to read because it's fully
textual
it's turns in terms of information no
animation no videos so the idea is to
move forward okay and to get a better
liberal office help okay so some
requirements that we have in this
challenge is first of all preserve the
legacy content we are not going to write
again everything so we have to use what
we have and transform it into something
better we want to lower the barrier for
the community participation so make it
easy for the newcomer to start
contributing to the help contents it's
much needed to give volunteers an
objective to contribute because some of
the community is eager to contribute but
they are not skilled for development and
they wants to add to to be part of the
of the team and by writing help pages by
by giving to the community to everybody
they are knowledge it's a good way for
that we want an easy to update and easy
to track software development we want a
dynamic vivid and pleasant way to to
read and watch use modern technology for
animations videos support the current
process of translations because in
libreoffice we have at least 30 to 50
active language out of more than 100 an
easy way to find informations in online
websites and to work online and offline
because in some in some locations you
don't have access to an Internet ok so
basically the idea is to start phasing
out the xhp technology and perhaps this
is just a suggestion start phasing in
html5 which contains a lot of
improvements from HTML and at that time
10 years after the H HP x HP
design html5 seems to be to cover most
of the requirements okay and also to
assist the offline help is to develop a
small JavaScript page server okay you
load a page that has JavaScript and the
JavaScript will help you in the
navigation okay so why phasing out this
XML well
the XML and exit a transformation has
issues it's not so standardized as we
see for common html5 I spent a lot of
time making discovering that the
transformation works in one browser
doesn't works in the other okay so it is
different and we would like to avoid to
have to be very specific to a to a given
browser okay and also it's not X s LT is
not a technology that is so easy to get
in the first greens ok so you need to
study on that understand what the
transformation are doing ok so it's
steep ramping for neophytes and the
community contributions and updates on
new contents X s LT is not by very few
its it wasn't important maybe 10 years
ago but today I don't think we are using
that much
this technology ok so what I see in the
W w3c web site is that this seems to be
a technology that is slowly phasing out
ok so we have this browser difference
that in the implementation of this pair
of technologies and I think that it's
becoming obsolete to replace it by a
richer
HTML well okay so this small JavaScript
micro server is will use be used to
first display the correct help page
required by libreoffice applications so
that when you click in the hub button
your dialog you need to go to the right
help page it's used most of the
resources such as navigation history
bookmarking caching included in any
major browser we handle the indexing and
searching text amounts pages so that we
can find and look for a specific string
whilst we're seeking specific keywords
and gets a list of pages and perhaps
supports X the old XML and the new HTML
simultaneously okay well this is
basically the idea that we have in terms
of evolving their hub contents and the
help technology I have been spending a
lot of time looking at what we have
there is good the results so far tests
were quite encouraging and perhaps we we
have a good way to not open the help
contents to a broader audience of
contributors so that's my message for
for you about the help of LibreOffice I
can take questions
[Applause]
no questions yes no timeline exactly we
are working on the availability of time
of any of the contributors so the
foundation is analyzing a possibility of
opening a tender to quickly have it
implemented the complexity is is low in
that case but it's an extensive work
some some issues has to be considered
specially to preserve and support the
translations of their contents
nothing more
okay thank you
[Applause]