you
[Music]
all right I'm late let's go
so that's me I'm working at canonical
packaging Libre Office for Ubuntu and
also I'm in the board of directors for
the document foundation and well let's
go back to 2010 because that that was
when the whole thing started with the
new build system you back then and I
wanted to just just have a look at what
we thought we would do back then and how
how we thought we could improve stuff
back then and what we actually achieved
from that so yeah that was one of the
original slides from the OpenOffice
conference in 2010 except that it didn't
have this branding but and well that was
the goal back then and for the most part
I think we achieved that but it it might
not look like that if you're building
Libre Office now but you have to think
about how how Open Office was building
at the time there were many many things
that were broken there there were manual
dependencies there were incomplete
dependencies there were incompatible
bills which means that you could build
one part and you had to know which part
would change if you change that and if
you didn't horrible things would happen
and all kinds of other issues
so those were the goals we had back then
actually I thought by now we would all
use 32 core machines and that didn't
happen by now we just use all very nifty
laptops but the other things still are
true and are things that we very much
profit from now and if you if you use
leaper office now on thing well Libre
Office is still slow
that was the comparison from just
building a few modules that was back
then and it's pretty much the same like
that now except that we almost take as
much force then that Senate run of these
modules because we run all the tests by
default all the time or lots of them so
we got a lot faster and then we added
lots of tests that you can't disable so
that we Dec as Louis as we were before
unless you know how to trick around that
but I'm not going to tell you so one
other goal of this was to not repeat
yourself
one other goal of this was to not repeat
yourself because repeating yourself
stupid and especially if you're in the
build system you have multiple things
that tell you how to build something
that can again be inconsistencies and
stuff that can create issues for
comparison this is how it is in leaper
office right now you register and if you
want to have a new library there you put
it somewhere which says in there Jassi
repository m'kay which essentially says
where it should end up in the final
build and well then you say how to build
it like I want to build these C++ files
in the old open of this world well it
was a bit different so
that was one of the issues we had with
the old stuff the other thing was Tim
tough TBI so there's more than one way
to do it and well that's always a bad
thing because you have to know all of
them to to read actually what others are
doing and again by now if you wonder for
example export a symbol and Libre Office
you do something simple like this you
add something
DLL public to the declaration and then
the symbol is exported in OpenOffice me
yeah you could have multiple ways to do
that and every one what would cost
interesting different slightly different
effects so again it was troublesome oops
same slide so this this was the initial
implementation of the back then new
build system we had all these targets in
one huge dependency tree and that meant
that we were aware of all the stuff that
was happening and in all the build we
didn't have like the horizon effects
where you would do an incompatible build
which meant you built something and said
I'm pretty sure this is binary
compatible with the rest and trust me
and it actually knew if it was binary
compatible or not and most of the stuff
so the core stuff of this is still like
that today a few things changed like the
backwards compatibility is gone we we
don't need like to deliver and copy
stuff five times around we needed to do
that in the old OpenOffice build system
to be compatible with the old build
system so thanks to all these guys who
helped contributing to this the
important quote here is I say we take
off a nuke the entire site from orbit
it's the only way to be sure that was
the
the last comment when we killed the last
part of the old build system so that
needed to be in the commit message there
so with this we had the whole build
system on essentially on one build
system and not like we had before - or
rather three like the old one the new
one and the one that mixed everything
between those which was some ugly pearl
hickory and then I got bored and I
wondered if I could do more than the
stuff that I originally planned for the
new build system and one of the things
was well actually syntax highlighting
and using IDs is a pretty good thing but
it's it's hard to like manually tell
your IDE where all the the include paths
are and things like that on the other
hand well we can't just say use Visual
Studio and then we build everything with
Visual Studio because that's kind of
heart of linen on Linux and on other
platforms so using just an ie s the main
build system doesn't work but what we
could do is have even the normal cross
platform build that we had before and
export solutions to different ideas so
they could be using this to give you
syntax highlighting debugging and stuff
like that so the first I did was care
develop because well seemed to be easy
to me and again as I said that was not
not something that was initially
patented was like an afterthought so
what it did was you didn't make and P
which prints alt out all the build
information and then it passed that and
try to build the IDE solution from that
turns out that something as simple as
make MP
isn't really stable over different
versions of make so the positive for
this turned to be it always added more
stuff and I looked at this and this is
not good we're taking more time to pass
actually being full then then it's
actually in there was always flaky
because people were using different
versions of make and it was kind of
tricky to to use this in a reliable way
and the goal of this was to have people
who were new to development to get there
on an IDE and well if the first thing
they do is is failing and they need a
full bill to get there that's the kind
of sucks so I now reorganized that and
did all the tricky stuff in the build
system itself and then it just dumps
that in Jason so that the simple Python
script can read that and translate that
to whatever ie you want to have so this
is the solution right now and I think it
it mostly is reliable and we can look
here right there was a question from
where's young its young here nope
yum asked me well I looked at the files
and and the the compiler switches oops
wrong slide that actually are given to
to compile a C++ file on Windows and
almost all the stuff all the method or
the data about what definitions and
flags and stuff ought to be used for
this target or in the JSON file with a
few exceptions and this is what he was
asking about and that's these few a few
things still missing that is like
generally config specific stuff like
which flex to use for exceptions and
stuff like that which is not target
specific so
when he wrote this email should they
have been in the Jason I said well no
because they are configuration specific
and they are the same for for the whole
bill but maybe we should I should just
drop in Jason found next to it which
which contains all this info so that you
can actually from the JSON file find out
all the Flex that were used to build
this on your specific platform so which
are the EES do we have well k develop
that was me in the beginning then Han
saw did Visual Studio and young and
others did additions to that Xcode was I
think initially done by Cho and then a
lot of work by young so we have like the
major platform major IDs for each
platform being able to to work on
LibreOffice code in the native native ly
feeling environment and we have amend
you completely by moggy for the old UNIX
guys who wouldn't use anything newer and
well we have to create and actually one
of the cue Creator guys came up to me he
can't attend this talk but he said well
I really want to help out so we we
should we should get contact with them
and get your Creator to be nicely
integrated with that
[Music]
so the path was what what I aim to do
with the original new build system eight
years ago and this RTE stuff is just
like a nice additional feature and that
were like the ideas - maybe after eight
years we should again use a new build
system just cause and well I felt like
the old UNIX guy that said no not with
me but there's this thing if you work
too long on something that maybe maybe
you're not entirely well neutral in on
this so when I said well you should
never look at this I looked the next
thing I did was look actually how much
of this build system was actually done
by me and hey good news although I
brought the original stuff there are
other guys who own a lot more lines of
it by now than me so it's not mine
anymore great David Michael
congratulations
you own this thing now so again and also
the distribution of country so this is
the lines of code and who lost touch
them and it's pretty ly even distributed
and there are a lot of people touching
lots of areas there
[Music]
so looking forward in to using something
completely different
these were the original problems we try
to solve with with eight years ago when
we did this some of the stuff creep back
in I think cargo cool programming is
already in the make files is again on
the rise because well it's been eight
years and stuff collected in there but
in general the other stuff is mostly
reached and I would add one more thing
the tool that I that I spoke about
do not repeat yourself and don't do tint
of PDI and that's one of the main
arguments against something like let's
let's use Visual Studio directly then
like export that to somewhere else
there's more than one way to do it
so again I'm kind of reluctant to use
something like Visual Studio solutions
directly and then have to maintain
different build systems on all platforms
because that will always break in this
more than one truth to the build so
someone does something on Windows and
then he changed the solution files but
not the stuff for the other platforms
and stuff like that so that that unless
you find a way to synchronize all this
is really tricky the other challenges so
I think we we should stay with with
something that is one single build
system whatever that is and well the the
other stuff like having water generated
intermediates who here uses automate and
auto comes and loves it okay we got a
talk the other stuff is well custom
targets like again this is having more
custom stuff in in the build targets
which is not like the usual
cross-platform stuff and the degrees of
freedom in oh great later
right so we have way too much degrees of
freedom and the configuration especially
on Windows where there should be pretty
much only one mostly and so we that's
the goal again to to get away from the
build system and that means for example
well the candidates for this are
obviously see make or maybe use use
scheme in in make as a migration path
but the advantage there is not to
rewrite everything from scratch again
but - softly migrate to it but the the
most interesting issue probably is the
build execution because Ninja is a lot
faster than what we have now because
make is just awfully slow pausing all
the dependency files that we have which
are just huge
I mostly agree but I'm I mean I want to
fight against my inner in a feeling that
everything is fine so yeah but if I look
at all these if I look at all these
things problem injures is the first most
useful things of trying to attack within
these rather than the others yes so the
externals are actually yeah yeah
interesting
all right yeah anyone else but no but
having questions yes
generally usable bottles of their
project so how much liquor
well this it it there there is somewhere
deep inside is something that is
generally usable but you you will have
trouble finding it if you're not knowing
about Libre Office because there are
these things like these multiple layers
of where to put libraries and stuff that
we are actually not using that much
anymore but they are still in there I
think my gosh once did an experiment to
just get the build system out of
LibreOffice and then try to to get rid
of all the Liebherr of a specific stuff
so it was just one huge build system
that built hello world
yeah also there are lots of
optimizations that you you probably only
need if you're as big as LibreOffice
like precompiled headers and windows
having all this parallelization and read
so stuff like that and having for
example the GCC creates the dependency
files those are huge that's huge to be
just well normally you would just use
all of them pass all of them and be fine
well that that doesn't work fully
profits so we are taking all these
dependency files and pre passing them
and kicking out all the stuff that is
actually superficial and stuff like that
so if your project doesn't need 20
minutes on a 32 core machine so you
absolutely invited to look into the sir
and it's luckily not only me who who
knows about how this stuff works which
is good and well feel free to to to take
a look at it looking forward for
contributions
yeah so again in the comparison to the
old build system the most important
thing was not even the speed that was
also important but more important was
getting rid of all the craft that wasn't
the old stuff that collected over 20
years yeah right the possible meaning
that you touched one file and says it
would do an incremental build and
actually would work because that didn't
work in the old OpenOffice build system
you would touch one file and everything
would be broken mostly most of the time
okay nothing I'm over time already yes
thank you
[Applause]