hello everyone
welcome Sol is giving the next talk
about Li both live please welcome him
thank you thanks so I'm Sol or saku
everywhere else on the Internet
and one of the League of ecore genders
and can I get a quick show hands who
knows about Livia me all right so you
may learn something hopefully for those
who don't
it's a cross-platform asynchronous IO
library with which does a little bit
more so we try to do networking stuff
but also other cross-platform stuff that
we need it's relatively small that is 30
thousand lines of code without tests
which is not a lot for a C library that
tries to do anything and everything we
have an extensive test suite which so I
waited and counted for this but we try
to test everything and we have a vast CI
infrastructure kind of donated by the
nodejs project which makes it robust but
of course I would say that right it's
designed for C programs that means the
joy of callback held in JavaScript I
guess and it's used by many many
projects these days if it started off as
a way to bring Windows support to no js'
like in a good way so Windows is a
first-class citizen here in case you
want to support UNIX and windows with a
consistent API and we have a wiki link
there with all the projects that use it
if you want to use it from programming
language X is very possible that
somebody wrote bindings for it because
there are many bindings out there
I personally wrote the ones for Python
and that's how I got starting into all
these things so what is it we do it live
UV it's an event loop so it's a single
threaded event loop follows this model
and everything that that surrounds this
is life it's actually tied into this
event so we can do timers signal
handling so there is no problem with
where the hell the signals get
dispatched we go child process
management TT is TCP UDP name pipes
file system operations this is for
example a thing that you don't typically
find on a networking library but if you
want to do a cross-platform application
you will need to access your file system
and Windows is a mess and nobody knows
how it works so we take care of that for
you and you just have to use it we have
some trading utilities and the coolest
logo in the open-source community as for
if you approach leave UV I think that
the best way to approach it is from the
outside to the inside so in a nutshell
we have three constructs the biggest is
the loop so everything pretty much runs
in the context of loops all operations
are related to a loop and it's where all
the magic happens if you will and then
we have handles and requests so a handle
represents a resource something that is
there to do some job let's say a TCP
connection so this is our representation
of something it's a handle and a request
represents an operation and has an
starting and ending so for example
writing on a TCP connection is a request
we use a request for it and this way so
when we do it this way we can know when
an operation ends and if it finishes
successfully or not so we have these
these differentiation and requests
always operate on some handle and then
we also have an vast array of other
utility functions for example a way to
get high-resolution time which you can
use for benchmarks and the like let's
look a little bit at like a block
diagram here so we do a bunch of stuff
as I said so network i/o related things
file system IR related stuff other stuff
and then other always independent stuff
because in some cases we have
implemented it in such a way that is not
tied to the operating system necessarily
and then we can reuse it so for example
when it comes to the networking io part
we have TCP pipes and TTI's which we
have struck them as streams so they have
a certain API and they behave like
strings so they get the read callbacks
called you can write to them
send file descriptors over them and so
on UDP and pull handles are also dealing
with Network IO or sockets but they are
not strings and they are all backed by
these internal kind of thingy which is
what abstractors from IO polling in
different operating systems on the UNIX
side on Windows we don't have this
because Windows works different but on
UNIX we have this layer and then every
different unique system sits on top of
it and we can implement them easily for
file IO or related utilities we have
file system requests work requests which
allow us to get a get a piece of work
spawn it to a thread do the work there
and then come back and we have name
resolution functionality as well so get
a DDR Infoblox but we run it on a thread
and give the result back to you just a
quick Morden threads we use threads just
for file system IO not for Network IO
the reason why we do it is very nicely
summarized in this blog post by the
BitTorrent guys there is no way to a
synchronous file IO cross-platform in a
reliable way
our default thread pool size is four and
let me say it one more time we don't use
it for Network IO the Internet is
usually wrong often times and I've seen
many diagrams of people trying to
explain what livia V is with incorrect
diagrams looking at queues and thread
pools and I don't know what the hell we
don't do that we only use threads for
file operations so it's single threaded
there is a thread pool but that's for
file operations and we get the results
in the loop thread anyway so to the eyes
of the user
there is no thread pool we have other
stuff that you can use as well so we got
timers some other types of handles that
operate in the loop at different points
of the event loop execution and then
well signals and processes that are
operating system dependent for instance
so how does our event loop run well so
we start by by thinking do we have to do
anything
because if we don't then we're done and
then we run the do timers so timers that
are you right now because we schedule
them in 20 milliseconds and they hit so
it's time to run their callbacks and
some pending callbacks we also ran them
at the top that is for example callbacks
that have happened as a result of a
write operation we report the result
there then we run other types of handles
that are loop Watchers these things that
run right before polling and right after
polling when we paul for i/o all the
read and write operations run and at the
end we run close callbacks so when you
close the handle when you want to
dispose of it not use it anymore
this operation is asynchronous so you
call UV close and then when the callback
hits you can free the memory this is
because we need to do some work in the
background sometimes now I mentioned
that levy we came in because no one
wanted to use it so let's have a quick
look at how leave you be used with in
node so the node event loop in a
simplified way basically runs timers now
the thing is no changes for performance
reasons doesn't use one live UV timer
equals one no the timer they coalesce
them so they have like one live yuri
timer backing potentially multiple node
timers if they are scheduled at the same
millisecond so they have different sort
of buckets there then ran some pending
callbacks the polling happens so all the
data received callbacks are also fired
and so on in connection callbacks as
well and then there is two weird things
happening the first one is set immediate
so set immediate runs on a check handle
which is after polling for i/o so it's
called set immediate but it doesn't run
immediately yeah and then there is a
process dot next tick which you probably
know which is supposed to run a function
on the next tick but what the tick is
nobody knows and in a nutshell it
doesn't it actually runs those callbacks
run every single time
we call into JavaScript from the C++
code there is a helper function called
node make callback and it drains a
little bit of the callback you from
process dot next tick is a little bit
counterintuitive and you should never
program or architect your application
with any of these in mind it should be
transparent to this not like oh I'm
gonna schedule this and then because the
umbrella ms gonna do that I'm going to
not don't do that because hopefully one
day we will get this sorted out and then
your application will break so we're not
a good thing to do so if we look at it
from notes perspective we follow an
onion architecture so we got your net
sockets wrapping a TCP wrap in C++
wrapping a UV handle in C wrapping file
descriptor on UNIX or a handle on
Windows and the idea being that you can
happily live at any of these layers as
long as it's above this one the
abstraction levels should be high level
enough so that you don't have any
problem there or you don't need to take
into account that solaris that's i don't
know what and that mac OS behaves as
some other way of course a good way to
learn all this is to write your chat
application of course why not so I wrote
down I wrote one it's a nice repository
I wrote it to show different usage
patterns in using live UV so it's a TCP
server you it accepts multiple
connections to each user that joins the
room gets a Pokemon name assigned and
the idea is that you can see how the
different moving parts work together and
different patterns on how to Bill for
example with memory allocations because
we got a little time I'm not planning on
showing it to you here so the idea is
you go and look at yourself and let us
know if you run into any issues or
whatever only yesterday I learned about
two other applications using live you
read while I was in a different Devon so
what do you know if you're already using
it please do come talk to me
and let me know I mean sometimes some
problems may happen in your van loop so
I want to give a shout out to everyone
in the in the core contributors team
it's seven of us at the moment five of
us are active and we work on it the
release currencies when we feel like
it's a good moment to do a release and
sometimes when nodejs us just hey can
you please do a release because we want
these features in it's basically do you
want something done driven development
so if you want something don't you do it
and otherwise well things would stay but
we're actively working on it and hoping
that maybe this year we can get 2.0
release with clearing up some craft like
Windows XP support which was like 2,000
lines or something that was very nice to
delete and if you wanna reach out our
website is just a quick way to arrive at
the others so our API documentation says
dogs WB org there's an IRC channel
literally also google group and also we
are in Stack Overflow and I believe if I
have time for maybe one or two questions
if there should be any I have a question
about comparative boost SEO because its
use similar model what is difference
from boost library right well so live UV
is very small very self-contained it
doesn't depend on any so boost my I
haven't used boost myself other than in
other projects so my perception of it is
that is a big library with different
components live UV was initially from
the beginning it was designed to be a
small thing that you could use in any
project I mean would abstract you as
much as it can but it's not the kitchen
sink solution we're actually thinking
about creating a work we're going to
create a new project called leave you be
extras where we're going to add some
more stuff that doesn't belong in core
but can be useful for some people this
one is also written in C
so there's also a bad difference but in
a way they solve the same problem so you
want to do some cross-platform
networking operations and and also sis
file system utilities and different all
abstracting all this is our job as well
so I would of course say LaBrie is
easier to use but that's what I know and
yeah so that's pretty much the answer
they solved the same problem but they
are different yes would you recommend
libuv for a very multi-threaded
application well so as I said the event
loop is single threaded but the event
loop is the context so you can
essentially run multiple threads with
multiple loops on each of them as long
as you don't do cross calling because
our API is not thread safe that's fine
so many projects do this so for example
if you want to do a similar model to
what nginx does for example so multiple
multiple processes and then some event
loops as well you could do multiple
develops on multiple threads and that's
perfectly fine so I think that's all
very quickly very look wants to know it
they don't wind the clock to blow up
right since we all like schwag here I'm
gonna drop some things on the table
right outside fYI after a leaf
in case you're interested hello just I
would like to ask for lip Yui xx whether
it's official xx there's a cheap as
possible per oh so no basically Livio B
is written in C and that's their one and
only official anything there is to do
however all the projects there that wrap
it or not wrap it some of them like
we're close cousins let's say so for
example Aiko maintained library and I
also write the python binding but it's
not official let's say we don't bless
anybody
he goes that's all guys touch thanks a
lot so for the top
[Applause]