hey guys good evening welcome to the
very last slot in the open document
added to staff room happy to have so
many of you still here it was a great
day wonderful program here in this room
so thanks to all the openoffice and
libreoffice and well to Serie B charger
guys I'm presenting so let's finish off
this day with a session of lightning
talks we got 7 talks recruited here
perhaps one more if you have the time in
the end yes the rules everyone got five
minutes
I'm having some stopwatch here 30
seconds before times up I will be
standing and looking at you and at the
five minute job we will all kind of get
up and and give you some applause so to
properly cut you off in a friendly way
and then the next guy comes up and so
the order is 2 times Markus more heart
then sponsor then Samuel and then I
forget oh yeah call two times and J
looks in the end so without further
adieu Marcos Marcos we talk about Marcos
talk about UI hacks Marcos is one of the
one of the early contributors to the
project has been active since I think
March 2011 so hey go Marcus thanks
so I will talk a bit about UI testing
there was a tenor from TDF about a year
ago I think about developing a UI
testing framework we have a lot of
testing frameworks already for normal
stuff but developing a UI testing
framework is not that simple there are a
lot of different approaches but most of
them have some really really active
parts I think that the best ones at the
moment are on the four web stuff but
yeah I've been thinking about that for
for many years so I've designed one and
implemented as part of the tender it's
an own implementation it has two parts
we have an introspection library in the
deep office code that provides
information about our UI elements to the
outside world and allows us to send
commands to these UI elements so it's a
short a really really short layer above
our UI elements and this year and then
we connect to that introspection code
with piping code to a you know interface
really really simply you know interface
so that writing the Python code does not
require any new you know knowledge if
anyone has ever done some you know
coding you know that not requiring the
you know is actually a feature not a bug
element discovery so finding a UI
element and for example a button in a
dialog happens through the IDS that we
have in UI files the advantage of using
the the IDs
is that they should be stable and that
they are locally unique so if you have a
dialog it should be unique and
if you move for example the button to a
different place in the same dialogue you
should still get the the same button by
going through the idea
well our Travie API test framework that
we inherited from openoffice.org suffers
from a lot of sleeps that when and if
the test fails and you notice okay let's
increase the sleep time a bit it does
not fail anymore you realize okay you
don't want to have sleeps and your test
frameworks in UI tests where a lot of
things happen unpredictably you need a
way to issue a command and wait until
the event has happened for that we sent
now events for quite a few things and
listen to the events on the testing
framework side and resume our work as
soon as the events are there so what's
good about the framework most of our UI
elements are already covered so most of
the stuff that you find in a dialog has
part of this introspection library
support the elements are easily
discoverable by the framework so you can
address them most of them have an ID
some of them have none yet especially
the ones that we create and don't load
from UI files that we don't have any
test failures if you just changed the
dialog a bit if our UX guys decide once
again let's redo the dialog as long as
they keep the idea yeah the test will
still work because it's our own code we
can support any feature that we have in
the profits for for users anything as
complex as we want it we can implement
it on our side and
quite importantly we can place the code
at the correct location so that it's as
close to the code path taken by user
events as possible which also helps in
finding bugs so the bad they are key as
I mentioned no UI testing framework is
perfect yeah if you want to support a
new UI element like a special type of
button you would need to add some code
to the leap office core to make it
available on the pipe inside because you
have to change leap office you can't
just run the tests against any older
versions the tests are quite slow
loading gear office takes quite some
time waiting until the UI is ready even
more so currently a normal test is
around 5 seconds and yeah we need to
maintain our own framework which is good
to some degree but also again some work
for us that's it
Cisco is already writing tests so with
that so apparently it works if you want
to do it
talk to me I will help you
[Applause]
yeah but we don't yeah we don't need
these sleeves that we have so that's why
we have these events so we wait until
the event is done so I talked about UI
testing while looking at our manual
testing which was more or less the
source for all our UI tests in the
beginning well if we did not have
automatic UI testing framework we used
manual testing for that which looks a
bit like that you have a simple
instruction you repeat that but yeah it
somehow doesn't state how do you do it
in the future if you want to increase
the tests how if you want to do more
tests run it on more platforms do you
want to do that trust more people doing
stupid instructions that were written
down what do you want to actually use
that that scales perfectly like taking
Amazon Cloud you could do as much work
as you want so I've started working on
that recently the idea comes from the
crash reporting that I wanted to test
and which has some problems that we
can't cover in our current test
framework so these tests run all on
country on release bills and the idea
would be that we start a virtual machine
to whatever we want there we have a
clean state we have can install any
dependency that we want
can test the integration with the system
for example does the installation work
does the connection to another service
work all the stuff that we currently
can't do in our test because it either
requires to change the system or because
it requires some dependencies that we
can't assume in our tests our repository
some tests already for the crash
reporting I've some ideas how to do it a
bit better with the VMS there's some
Python frameworks that you can use and I
want to do that for a number of things
that we currently have in the manual
test that we can't cover with the UI
tests but taking the UI test into these
tests allow us to Tomales to whatever
a user does even if it requires change
in the system I think that's all
[Applause]
test test can you hear me simply stop hi
I want to talk about changes and I hope
that in a few years we can use it
different David Bowie song may be heroes
so hopefully we can do this way so I
want to talk about ODF so what is from
one side ODF is just the state of the
users work right it's can be used by but
it's used by LibreOffice it was the
right from star fees so it's very
typical to libreoffice maybe that's one
of the reasons that Libre is so dominant
here in the ODF editor def room right
and it consists like we heard before
about XML so and images is quite open
but there's a different angle
ODF is also a blueprint it's an
interface between different applications
right so that's very important here it
is specified by Oasis for companies and
people like me are might join and soup
loo print that others use this to use
the data and give it to someone else
like once on floppy disk and also very
important it's an ISO standard there are
many standards but the ISIS then that is
very important because this is only be
done by countries like Dean in Germany
and also very important the country like
Great Britain Netherlands did can say we
have to or we we demand that this file
format is being used and this is very
very important because some you might
there's the biggest impact that only
have had was on Microsoft Microsoft
created in a very very small amount of
time the oxm L standard and it's not
even the name maybe you know it was
confusing me a lot in the beginning the
first version of open document format
was called OpenOffice 6 ml but then was
changed because what too specific to one
application so it
go to a standard we want to use a more
generic name so others people can join
yes
so it's called was this name was dropped
office open and office open XML was born
by just switching the words I find it
very interesting that they didn't it the
the most in part is why did they do this
I mean why did they invest it so much
money into creating their own iso
standard and to be honest I'm not sure
but it has to do with the ISO standard
that governments can demand that the
companies have to fulfill the standard
and I believe that what we heard that
it's like a domino chain but this time
it started when the biggest player the
government's going to be like SP and
Oracle were large companies that supply
this far from it so there's a lot lot
power in this and I guess this is all
quite often forgotten here that when I
talk on the table and I want to sound
like my software and I care about
I'd say Libre Office and I can't sell
audio if I don't care about audio yes
this is very powerful I cannot explain
how a powerful and cannot estimate it
but they they did it once and I believe
there's a reason that they have to do it
again and there's a maybe a leverage how
to how to break the monopoly on the
business market so first what are the up
stockists that we do currently have
there some of them so first of all
collaboration it's not good enough to
send documents around this times are
over like nowadays we are all have
smartphones we are all connected and so
sending this documents around is it's
not good enough because you don't know
what the others has changed you want to
merge easily and we do it for software
all the develops know we have source
control system for the files and you can
do merges there and we having a way to
say like and like and get for source
code what does the was it diff and this
should be defined by changes the next
time there's no runtime api like HTML
head with the Dom this is very important
for third parties of then there's one of
the biggest obstacle for for selling and
last time there's no feature testing
testing if I want to buy me a machine
then I took like a test and what's the
feature the pair's them
comparison and nowadays I see
applications that they say on we support
ODF but when I test a few documents I
realize they're very lousy and there
should be better testing and this is not
possible yet you can only load save and
test but if we would have something like
a feature testing then we but very
powerful so how we do it as I said with
changes the documents are too large and
what we're doing we are not we're going
on higher level and we say something
like I've changed the one millionth
paragraph - Rhett that's what I did and
we we abstract from the details like XML
we go to what the news knows by this we
can go across as many applications as
possible and of course I talked about
this little earlier we have to refer to
a cert version that's develops no they
use hash but I'm not again on XML
because the verbose we use it on this
logical box so what's in ours do we have
in mind it's as I said I can do like in
github I clone the document of this
read-only document I said oh by the way
there's a typo I do like you fix it I
only sent this small change or if you
say have a contract and then you return
only the change not the full contract
with some kind of hidden changes are not
aware of you can exchange no longer only
documents but changes this is very
powerful and also a versioning system
like give me all the changes since I
modification and also powerful you can
sign the document this is basically of
XML not the zip and this signed document
can be documented and changed by
changing side and still yes the signed
document so you can do a ping pong of
documents with with signing which is
currently not possible on there lot of
other features and I want to tell you
that this should be our future and you
shouldn't get this either standard
opportunity out of him and that's it
Thanks
[Applause]
so next one has some kind of I think I'm
gonna share that with Simon Beaufoy
Samuel another one of the early liberal
office contributors I think June 2011
was your first right so so this is about
something that we just started to do the
project's called GPG for libera it's
about integrating the new privacy guard
into Libre Office is this is all about
document signing and document encryption
based on public key cryptography using
lots of cool stuff that's already out
down the project is funded by the German
federal agency for information security
they do all kinds of things like audits
like security recommendations but they
also look into how to strategically
change the software landscape to make
everybody more secure and this is one of
that so conceptually it's about using
the new GPG can improve see guard and
another set of axillary tools that are
there like key management and
integration for example into Windows and
there's a noise API wrapper for that GP
g m-e and that goes by IPC to our
process tools and kind of offload all
the security relevant stuff to those
tools so liberals doesn't really have to
bother with keeping the the the
passphrase secure and not just growing
up bethey with the algorithms so and in
the end what should much would happen is
that liberal office is able to sign
documents and also encrypt documents
worth so signed documents with your
private key and encrypt documents for
recipients that you have the public key
for so you find it on a key server and
your
able to encrypt a document for that
recipient the advantage to the
established x51 certificates is that
it's much better for decentralized
organizations because you always have
the problem if you're not a single
company how to distribute the keys
without trusting an external source like
a CA for that so want to take over from
here can do but I don't know what I'm
expecting yeah screenshots yeah the
first steps we did was to make it more
[Music]
they say and when the document
encryption is broken the signature the
current signature there was an dialog
shown earlier which not even had a
warning box or something so no I can
just wall of text and you could easily
easily ignore it so the first thing we
did put an info bar right info bar when
the signature is broken and orange one
when it has issues like an untrusted
certificate or earlier Open Office
versions and signed only parts of the
document yeah and the next steps are
yeah we are currently integrating GPG
for me into libreoffice to build it and
there is a small wrapper for c++ which
makes it even easier to use will be also
integrating that yes I think that's
called clearly for me plus plus or
something yeah and then we're going to
make the your own certificates your own
keys visible in the digital signatures
dialog so you can use the existing
dialog to sign with typically and later
on awesome
tripped yeah and there's all sort of
wonderful follow-up projects there so
including PDF signing and and stuff like
for for documents so for PDF there's a
nice feature that you when you sign a
PDF then there's a little area where you
can put some some flex Emily off of
yours actual signature there that then
gets integrated to the document and
something that's like that we really
nice to have for EF as well it needs a
little bit of its need some kind of
field special purpose field them to to
contain that and um so for this
signature stuff I think that should be
covered by the existing or EFS back I
think for encryption we will probably
have to propose something to the OT FTC
but it's the second step okay so that's
about it it's broadly an announcement
that we started working on that so then
this is the first step spam any
questions yeah they will be stacked on
each other so they all will be shown so
you can you can have a full screen of
info boss
[Music]
yeah pretty much I mean there's already
pretty nice PDF signing but it's still
using I mean it's it's again using this
x5 4-1 keys and it will be great do that
with GPG keys as well I've no idea it
might be completely unfeasible but it
would be nice no I still I haven't
looked into the into the PDF spec but
we're running out of time so I guys um
next one up is I think you core
[Applause]
yeah so I'm course gonna talk a little
bit about it cause here since forever
cause one of the founders of the
document foundation has been active in
the Open Office or project since I don't
know two thousand two three four or five
okay
[Music]
Tolson tapped on my shoulder some hour
or so ago if I was interested in a
lightning talk so I couldn't make a
choice as usual so I got permission for
two lightning talks and I think I want
to start with this one and that's about
document foundation many of you will
know and some many maybe want oh about
all the good work that's being done
behind the scenes to support the
development of this great ODF tooling
it's called Libre Office the document
foundation it's this foundation behind
it and apart from the the LibreOffice
project it also hosts the document
liberation fronts so providing all the
nice document filters and adding new
ones who did so very short front it's
the document liberation project to be
honest but it is so yeah I like
liberation fronts okay TDF is houses
libre office and yes we started in about
2010 and this is solid
berlin-based stiff ting behind it and
statues and all the stuff but what is it
about basically people that are active
working on all kind of LibreOffice tears
can say I want to be member and later I
will explain to you why it is important
to be a member and and of course there
is a there you can be accepted as a
member for one year and after a year you
are invited to apply again if you are
doing good stuff and there's a
membership committee it's mentioned
below that's looking over the process of
people being member of not in between
there's the board of directors
the Board of Directors does great stuff
to make the whole sting the whole thing
going on both the membership committee
and the board of directors obviously are
chosen from the members and then we have
the engineering steering committee where
oldest engineers and people that are
related and interested discuss about
what's really going on and and not an
official body in in the sense that it
has a voting right or whatever it's
advisory board all kind of organizations
interested and this is the last slide
about TDF and this is how it shows the
Board of Trustees below it's not just
members but there's also some formal
legal legal Rose death White's Gold
Board of Trustees and from the board of
trustees we choose the Membership
Committee
every two years and the other two years
so that's intermediate the board of
directors is chosen and why the Board of
Directors is so very important because
Libre Office apart from all the great
stuff that developers do there's a lot
of work behind the scenes that's
enabling the work in in case of
infrastructure and people supporting
and whatever and that is made possible
by all people that make donations and
the board of directors nits off together
and finds the the the projects and the
tooling that needs support so the Board
of Directors looks after spending money
well for Libre Office development so
that's about TDF and anyone interested
in being a member because if you are a
member you can vote or even stand for
the board of directors is welcome to go
to document from decision document
Foundation Board or work so far this one
so that was my presentations one anyone
else questions
TDF okay then on top here in the maybe
I'll just start the second thing I want
to talk about is is a product called
leave relax and let me just show it
leave relaxed is something that gives
you a dialogue and to start document
production and it has some nice features
and it has some old-school sides as well
it started years ago I'm running a small
company in the Netherlands and we doing
some support for organisations using
LibreOffice and prior to that
openoffice.org and this is typically old
school within your office application
you start something and to create your
documents and even a long time ago it
was all a hard coded and this is
flexible it's based on configuration
files so here if you choose and not
document you see that this this dialogue
dialogue is dynamically built rebuilt
based on the on the configuration files
and if let me take this one as you see
there are some language information here
and you have some Lester's they are
madam and if you choose to make it
English you see that both the date and
the lists all the stuff changes it's all
based on configuration files and you
have if you prefer your settings well
also you can have choices in templates
for presentations for example if you
have a this is a memo document and you
can start it and this is demo and when
you hit OK you get both the document and
you get some predefined file naming and
you can start the content in case it's
in some protected section whatever stuff
you can edit it and there is some stuff
that you might want to print it with
logo on black and white or send it as
PDF or stuff like that and emailing that
it automatically is mailed as PDF with
logo or as word file to someone if he
needs to edit it that's that kind of
stuff that makes working in an office
documents often easier there's one thing
that I want to show about flexibility so
we have the the memo document here and
for example this it can be made shorter
this
and you can add extra fields and I can
show that here's the configuration file
and I just prepared some new lines
[Music]
I have to save it
of course maybe see now this is a short
one and additionally there's this type
of information available well that's all
nice and fun I started to open sources
last year this is now open source code
it's all old-school basic old-school
basic I open sourced it it was in the in
in the planning anyway and there was
some some work in in the dialog handling
with GTA III or whatever and that's
fixed now but if you look at the
configuration stuff that's a bit
old-school and of course the the ideas
that it's it's it can be easily linked
to documents management services or that
you create the documents from a document
management system and that if it is
needed it can be picked up in
LibreOffice and do stuff with with auto
text files and stuff like that that's
all well ideas that are possible in
future but this is just how it should be
to start from yes it's just here and
when it's published somewhere I I can
just share it with you but it's not CSE
not in a public repository yet
[Music]
I I think it's LLL do p3 plus something
like it yes what's the difference
any more questions okay thank you
[Applause]
so we have two more talks
genex perhaps next next one up with
young Malik gloriosky from city of
Munich one of the really large German
deployments of libre office some 17 K
seats I think running lib refers most of
them on Linux and he's been even active
in the project since when 2008 nine
[Music]
okay okay so instead we have while we're
solving the technical issues and this is
Olivier and you will be talking about
the new help system yes I would like to
show you what we have achieved so far
and it's basically a new URL it's VM 173
that document foundation.org and of
course we have some issues on the on the
CSS but what we have here is a an
imitation of what is the help system
this is the browser this is the page
rendered by the transformation we have
also collected all the bookmarks in the
XIV files and if you click on one of
these you get the page and on the top
you have a search bar that if you type a
specific keyword it's supposed to be to
collect all the mentions of calc into
this and then you can then navigate I
have one more things to show what we you
see here is is on debugging the XML you
see that you can this is pure HTML that
is has been transformed okay so we try
to preserve yes what we have here is
only the the index dot XML which is the
entry page there is a there is a
JavaScript micro server running there
okay so that takes the links and
transforms inside with JavaScript I also
would like to show if you can type after
the URL slash index dot HTML
and then a question mark question mark
page equal equal share it share it slash
test dot X Ashe HP test dot x HP yeah so
I have modified the transformation to
include a new multimedia so you can have
at the page with the multimedia right
now on the browser ad but you can't have
it on the current help system so if you
start the multimedia it goes to YouTube
and brings you the ok so this is what we
have achieved so far in trying to bring
the health system into a more modern
technology that's it ok just one thing
we plan I think it's a good idea to have
this system bundled into an extension ok
so it can what it may be interesting to
distribute in a different way rather
than installing packages ok and it can
be you can run locally or in a server
yeah thank you
[Applause]
okay so let me try - okay help me which
what's the name of the of your slides
after those technical problems or laptop
and everything this is just a little
overview about stuff and I've been doing
in mini for the last two months
something like that with some breaks
Libre Office processes all stuff to do
in an event loop and Libre Office it's
called task loop and the current origin
where I'm coming from
yeah there are two different types of
tasks some are timers which are
somewhere executed in the future and
some idols which executing instantly
some definition of busy so at some point
Libra office says I'm busy so at this
point no idle tasks should run but this
is very strange implemented in different
backends
and some pecans even do not implement it
at all so this is kind of a crazy
definition of busy there's the main
problem is that it's really kind of
random how LibreOffice processes the
stuff so even if you say okay process
the next event or tasks or whatever
sometimes it processes - if a system for
event is there sometimes it was in two
LibreOffice events this is not really
idealistic from the point of view if you
want to know how stuff is running in
libreoffice and then there are some
really
freaky stuff like there is some commence
and Omega aspect and we're saying Oh at
some time we are losing timer events
nobody knows why it's the commenter from
2000 really yeah they are quite from
very old code and yeah so this is really
what the code at that point and we
have heard that today and talk from
Michael Meeks about parallel processing
with talk with threats that already
there are a lot of problems there and
when I was started and looking into this
code I can understand why there are
problems because seems that everybody
just for every pack in that code they
implemented rocky rounds instead of
rewriting the whole stuff from scratch
with a normal idea and how a normal way
normal tasks and event loops working two
days and two wickets so where we are
currently we it's only scheduled by
priority now so like all the normal
event loops every event or tasks as a
priority and it's gated like that so we
do you know are completely those busy
stuff that's really crazy anyway the
other thing is that libreoffice was
mayor more or less polling with a task
with just occurred in because we were
missing some time a timer toss sometimes
so we started just to polish so in case
we missed something we found a way to
continue the stuff the single system
timers work except for macros because I
don't have a Mac OS platform yes I will
get one yet sometimes I trust them and
then I hopefully can fix a Mac OS back
and to said it has a single system
timers then there was a strange we have
feature that every task has to wait at
least one milliseconds for what ever
reason I don't know this was very
strange to I dropped a two and I didn't
see anything
while that couldn't work in the future
at least all the units which were there
still are working the refactoring of all
that code made also I made it in that
way is that all single tasks and patches
passed all the unit tests and even I
added some more unit tests to tests real
strange stuff like round robin when you
have two tasks with the same priority
they are currently scheduled no they are
not scheduled because when first the
first task is working all the time until
it is finished
even with its protests multiple times
and then the second task is just
tackling and a little around running at
that point fix that too and one really
stressful test which I finds because
sometimes I really made passionate and
all the unit tests still passed but for
the desktop unit tests and LibreOffice
kit UNICEF's are so complex that
normally they instantly fail if
something is wrong in the event
management or in without handling so
that's the current status that missing
is basically even make arrest stuff so
what we are coming to is that we run the
LibreOffice event loop just from a
system timer we don't have the polling
so we just restart the system timer to
to execute exactly when the next task is
valid or even if it's zero seconds which
exciting we instantly returns and
process that we I had the strange
situation when I reflected some code and
merged it that it became faster that
unit test broke because they were too
fast but I fixed those unit us now and
what we are going went and won to have
us to have locking so currently the the
unit main loop is not multi-threading
safe we
have already have those problems where
are some events and our tasks are
created in an hour strats and then
around in the main loop and then stuff
simply breaks and we want to get that -
this is currently hard because the tasks
they're owned by the threats so I guess
it really basically the only solution to
that it's currently to have a main
global lock for the event loop and lock
it and so you can release the stuff just
not owning the top and then normally on
by reinventing food and we want to have
certainly brofist - crazy stuff get rid
of that my original point was that
something's changed in there and made
much got very very something changed in
that codes and managed got very very
slow for more than 300 documents and I
said every time I thought I fixed it
I found something new it's crazy and
it's a little bit hard because yeah it's
a very lower ground and plumbing in
libreoffice and if you change something
there everything by expectantly it's a
little bit hard
I mean I already landed some refactoring
patches but we're really hard stuff is
hopefully landing in the hackfest
next Monday Tuesday probably that was a
little bit thanks a lot everyone
yep in government very caring with me
very disciplined presenters thanks for
that you've been a wonderful audience
thanks for that and we have five minutes
left
um what I would be curious to hear some
feedback from you guys so what was the
talk that you missed that was not here
in the staff room so that we should
really have next year or any other
feedback you you want to say something
I'm only a user of it and I use it maybe
half a year no longer because before I
came from Windows and then they changed
to Windows 10 and then I changed to
Linux and I'm happy the set but there's
no office and I need office and so I
used to leave office so you would have
liked some some more user focused topics
or I mean there was the sleep relax that
was clearly um I really loved it I would
like to try that do anything that when I
call this out
once again homie ok it was ok
interesting what kind of problems we
have with a smiling face anything else
any kind of feedback anything at all
otherwise get home safely enjoy the rest
of the FOSDEM