so welcome all welcome to Michael and
then sorry if I get your last name wrong
Valesky from Lizard a CFS and the floor
is yours now
okay so we had some problem connecting
my other notebook so I don't have the
introductory slide what what I just want
to show is I'm the community manager for
visit FS and we are basically a
distributed file system and what I just
wanted to show was how easy it is to set
it up yeah we I have another talk
tomorrow in the SDS deaf room where I
explain for 45 minutes how it all works
but for me the most important part of
our project is it's just a 10 minutes
job to set it up right so I just
prepared a couple of containers to set
up the system the system consists out of
always the metadata server and a couple
of chunk servers what I prepared the
prepared containers already have the
packages on because I didn't know if the
network would be working two years ago I
had the experience that it didn't so I
didn't want to risk that yeah that's why
the key so
I would first create a master server
that a little bit here yeah that's what
I'm just trying anyway so but I think it
will be so simple that there is not that
much that you cannot see so by by
default the system assumes that the
master server is called MSS master so my
most of my configuration is just to add
an entry into the host file for MS
master
and then just go into the configuration
directory and copy over the the sample
configuration files so this is all too
small for me
and then copy over an empty metadata
file in the EMFs direction
and then all I have to do is start oh it
but still have to let the master server
own the stuff and then all I have to do
is start the master server
come
can I have a running master server you
can treat that well where is it
yeah I can't
no a doesn't work let's wipe that
already wrong desktop for me yeah I
wanted to present it on the Apple but
the converter to vga does works
um anyway I can't do it so yeah I cannot
do it
ah and I have all the links on the other
computers yeah I can't I don't see it
myself
great no no and I have to start the
monitoring service as well
what
blind typing let me see what port it's
running on four to five
yes it's a thing what am i doing
what is wrong
okay
no it's 9 for 25 at least that's what it
writes here
but I can see
great
but what spine 425
okay yeah
but
yeah
[Applause]
so I can see that my master was running
right that's all I wanted to show I just
tried it on the wrong machine anyway so
what I do next is connect the junk
server if I would do that on that
machine on my machine that would be
simpler but all that one I don't know
how anyway
you have to get a different converter
for tomorrow so what I did on the tank
server is basically the same entry in
the hosts file
I think that's visible it's just for the
NFS master so that the chunk server can
find its and find the metadata server
[Applause]
okay yeah the MFF master entry is not
that our decision so the container has
the chunk server package installed it's
just on that units apt-get desert FS
chunk server and on CentOS it's the same
stuff with yum right and again I
prepared a directory for the chunks over
where it's going to keep its chunks it's
called wizard fs1 so all I have to do
now is see the right keys in the dark
and just tell the chunk server where it
can find its stuff
I just put here
the directory and just copy over the
default files and start the chunks of
oops
probably running alright so I got back
to my monitoring I see my time zone okay
see my chunks over I can see that it has
a disc that's basically all what I can
do next is add another track server
now this chunk silver is sent off I have
another chunk server that's running on
Debian so I do exactly the same thing if
I see the keys
good guy
I really don't care
[Music]
so now I have a second one on running on
center no let me see if I managed to
connect a dark client so for my clients
I do exactly the same with the hosts
file so that we can find the metadata
server and then I just tell him to wait
yeah
I set him up where he has to mount when
he said mount we we distributed file
system and just tell him go ahead and do
it oops
yeah there so I bet they can now have a
mounted distributed file system on two
servers any questions
that's a very silent question thank you
for the talk is there any possibility is
this deport over to say BSD family all
these straight Linux BSD I run it on
Solaris you can probably run it on H
bucks as well I didn't try but it
shouldn't be that much of a problem
ax should work as well there is
commercial Windows client and there is a
commercial type chunk servers so that
you could basically talk to a tape
library like to each other so if time
for one more question
anybody well up so no are no more
questions and thank you all and
you