and software as a service by zine
because processing happens on the server
side in the cloud is - and there this
model in many cases is based on new
Tizen personal data through targeted
advertising means data is is not in our
hands anymore it is coupled on to
servers so by the way and and will reuse
your catch phrases you've probably fear
with there is no cloud the cloud is
someone else computer that's that's a
very nice way to introduce the cloud to
no ordinary people with thing the cloud
is something magical though the cloud is
just someone else's computer and in the
cloud data is centralized there's no
freedom for users to have any you know
impact on the data because well maybe
there are some free and open source
software on the servers like the curl
and a few things but really the
application itself is not free software
and so the user hasn't control over the
education and therefore has a control of
Y being what is being done with his or
her data so you're probably all familiar
with the fate of our Edward Snowden that
was lower which basically no has
released a lot of information he's had a
lot of information from his employer at
the sa-2 journalist and and what really
boils down to is data centralization
makes mass surveillance economically
possible basically the NSA and and
deverel other government agencies want
to listen to everyone they want to
record every conversation whether it
happen on the phone or on a computer and
they do that because it's their mission
and because it's too expensive
to do surveillance to seven billion
people on earth right now it's a lot
cheaper sin go and fetch the data from
the very companies that concentrate our
data into a few silos and this is an
issue as it explains here this is grain
bill wool was which is one of the two
journalists that met with Edward Snowden
first it's basically if you are under
surveillance you do self-censorship mass
surveilling em here mass surveillance
creates a prison in the mod if you are
under surveillance you change your
behavior and this is not just no
something we think it's it's
scientifically proven we do self sensor
and here's the here's the the proof so
wikipedia has a lot of pages and it's
it's totally okay to be visiting
wikipedia pages you know it's it's legal
to visit would if you get pages I mean
right we we agree on that but there are
some pages we discuss which discuss
topics that are today all touchy Islam
or jihad or you know terrorism are such
topics and pages that people may you
know they hear a lot about this in the
media and it's really good that as
citizens they won't know more go to
Wikipedia to learn more about these
topics but at the same time if you look
at the jihad page maybe you could think
I couldn't into trouble because we'll
think you know someone they could think
I am doing it for the wrong reasons
and so what you see here is basically
the mean audience of the these search
pages with touchy subjects only on the
US version of Wikipedia
and so as you see the trend is
increasing really fast and then here
that that mark is snowed the first
Snowden revelations we're learned that
surveillance mass surveillance was
happening and people knew they were
under surveillance probably not for sure
but there were programs and surveillance
and as you can see the trend here
suddenly there is a sudden drop and
visiting these pages which once again it
is legal to view and read these pages it
is a good thing but as we know as we are
under surveillance we change our
behavior in many cases we don't know we
change our behavior but we do not dare
visiting Wikipedia anymore but as we
could you know catch a bullet for being
around so this is this is a real example
significant our behavior when we are
under servings and this is why it's such
a big issue with with mass surveillance
you have heard I'm sure Larry Lessig
which said basically caught is low if in
the digital age the people will write
the software the people who decide what
the people what other people can do
because you know software is all
everywhere in our lives and and so well
we we as software developers decide what
other people do and this is exactly why
if we have free software we can have a
free society and there's a another thing
which is really nice that if code is law
and I think it is then architecture is
politics the way we architecture
software and stuff is is we would decide
how things are gonna work
so it's to us hackers
I mean that force in a good way till the
Internet we want the Internet's that we
want and the internet that it ended
dozen down to us so here a larger viewer
a picture we have to build a new one we
need to buy the new Agnew whatever
decentralized internet instead of
centralized intent owned by a handful of
operations we need all kinds of free and
open source decentralized efforts build
that internet start with a personal town
solution which is I'm working on cozy
but there are other solutions why you
know hoes sandstorm or clown annexed
cloud are examples of such open source
and free software solution to give back
control of the insight to the users but
there are all sorts of projects here
today that are going to be presented in
this room there are so many and so
diverse I could not come up with proper
categories to explain there are you know
people who do service hosting like
shuttle one and fama so there are you
know of course software they're a
do-it-yourself ISPs Wi-Fi for structure
based on free software and all that kind
of thing so there are many things and
this is what is going to cool today as
we are going to discover all of these
new approaches to build a decentralized
internet with the hope of making this a
movement just a bunch not just a bunch
of projects but really people working
together and that was the goal of these
day today is to get people together and
connect them so that we build teller a
decentralization thank you
I see that we all would have a question
here ludo two missions the internet made
of cables connecting data centers to
others so in the data centers we can
have all the solutions we want but like
the cables thrown by nutrition do you
know of any efforts of I mean cables
owned by the people not owned by orange
Pocky be like efforts to knife through
the cable between the US or well we like
more European century cable between say
Europe mainland and UK I need to repeat
the questions keep your questions short
because there you're not heard on video
and so whatever the cables that make the
internet they the fickle Internet they
do matter they need to exist and I think
the issue is more like on the last mile
or a few last miles and this is why they
do it yourself IPS are really
interesting the the actual cables the
big cable xeno optical cables under the
sea and stuff I got
we are totally not there yet but if we
do have encryption enable I think this
solves a lot of the issues connected
with that it's not solving all of them
but if it's encrypted they are not going
to be you know doing internet neutrality
stuff against internet ID and stuff like
that so I think we're pretty say there
doesn't mean we don't have to try but I
think there are more urgent matters that
are mostly related in my opinion to
devices and servers and such the good
news is that we have raspberry PI's that
for basically 50 euros you can build a
decent sort now the question is is it
going to be safe and secure and easy to
administer
that's that's the question we need to
solve but at least the whole we're here
is easier in extremely promising is
there I'll take your laughter keep it
short because I have to repeat it
yes and so what's your pian sir its
encryption the solution no I I agree
it's not there it's dangerous everywhere
I mean the internet for the people is
under attack prema on every front
so encrypt banning encryption is a major
issue and it's a political one and need
to fight in favor of encryption pretty
much everywhere we go I'm it's gonna be
hard for me to fight for the Chinese but
I can fight in here and I do fight in
France where it's my country and
everywhere here
so yes the encryption right to
encryption is something we need to fight
for absolutely is there another question
so we're the idea of building a
decentralized internet from right that's
if I understand your question well I
I wasn't like I said with Mozilla for 17
years and 20 years ago I was at foes dam
which if I remember quickly was old owes
them at the park at the time not not
frozen air because the free part was
only open source natori and richest old
man came and yelled in well of course
and and so it changed was the works
there so yelling worse and and and I was
with a colleague and we had the first
[Music]
mozilla dev room and in after 17 years i
was like now the issue is not so much on
the client side it's also on the server
side this is why I've joined kuzey to
create that and of course I ended up
knowing a lot of people in in Sim things
and and and Julia see then and and I'm
together came and well we know people
that are interested in you know somebody
which is pretty similar tested and is
involved in a DIY ISP bomb is involved
in and why you know host and together
well connect with our projects and we
say yeah let's let's request a room a
dev room and at first them like I did in
Mozilla like 17 years ago and it
happened thank you for them and I hope
says that the first one the next one
there's going to be a lot bigger and
bigger and if you see you know the first
Mozilla at that room was like pretty
much this size and now it's really huge
so so this is this may be this history
you know you will be able to say to your
alone I was there
[Laughter]
trade trade so yeah your question week
is how is is there a chance that we win
with the centralized approach as opposed
to centralized first I think the
Internet is inherently decentralized
that's one thing it was built to be
surprised a second there are things that
are working for us the smartphone
industry is building power efficient and
powerful chips that are very very
inexpensive think if you if they're the
new tripled a new board called the
orange pie zero which is seven euros and
it's squat core 1 2 gigahertz you know
it really is something so even the
rabbit pie which is inexpensive it's
just the beginning and it thanks to this
learning industry with that staking our
idea
we're actually it's impairing us with
new hardware which is very different so
it doesn't have to be fully
decentralized and there's my personal
opinion I'm a pragmatic pragmatist and I
think that if we start a halfway decent
Erised
and we do surprise
not well we decentralize halfway and
have like I don't know
regional servers it's a lot better than
hanging a worldwide server so we could
use we could leverage the efficiency of
data centers but have more control over
that and just something we're going to
see with the D Google lies your life and
their their approach with FRA myself you
you will see it's very yeah and you read
French do you I encourage you to read a
book because that's what I explained on
300 pages basically yes it's it's so I
repeat question is it going to work with
email the email question because of spam
and protection against spam is really
hard but who owns a gmail account here
in this room raise your hand okay now
this is the problem if you if you
started removing your email from Google
to an your ISPs email that would be a
lot of progress not the perfect solution
but progress and you know in really
centralizing the email so yes we can
start with that and and and the world's
can page but giving up you know just buy
your own domain
and use the email servers of your hoster
that's already yet start and these
people know how to run a mail server
that is recognized by Gmail so
[Music]
so what about ordinary users for having
a decentralized internet yeah so if I
may and we have like two more minutes
I'll give you a very quick example where
we do at Cosi which basically enables
you to connect your data from all your
devices and with connectors or all your
services
on your personal cloud and this personal
cloud you know it's like personal or
like this Matt phone is personal no user
name it's you just enter the password it
entered and you have access and you it's
just like a smartphone you know you
become buttons they have calendar
contacts and found photos you can import
your data for Google can add connectors
and applications you see your files you
see your contacts and such your calendar
all of that works and it runs not
necessarily at home it can run on a on
the server that you pay for and so there
is no incentive for the the hosting
company you pay to data on your data
because they already make good money by
renting you server space so that's
that's what we want to do I'm not saying
it's perfect but it's a good media term
solution it's easy to use and you don't
have to worry about the security because
you have you know professionals that's
managed to manage your server that's I
think we will need to prepare for the
next one you don't have a one last quick
question before anybody at some point
I think Snowden attending pack because
it made the front page of the media
that's pretty much it
I think it was better than that but it's
re pretty good
Amy's up we need to prepare for the next
talk thank you very much
[Applause]