so everyone this is Peter my name is
Adam we're from Red Hat and we are
working on a project called Fedora
modularity by the way we have stickers
for you so if you come here after the
talk you can get one or two yeah
only 25 but that's fine so I'm not sure
who of you was on language talk last
year here enforce them he was talking
about how distributions are great but
not really and how many might need to
change them to to be ready for the
future so let's start with why I they
are great because I think that's still
true they should package software which
means it's pretty easy to install they
also ship dependencies and everything
else with it so it just works the
integrated untested so nothing breaks
really and some important thing it's
also paste for security vulnerabilities
because brings up if you are a developer
and you're developing your application
which is included in the distribution
you might not have pretty much time to
patch for some security holes so
distributions can do it for you
and this does have a life span which
basically means they're released at some
point die at some point this is for
example Fedora and if we have if you
have a look at bit more detail we can
see that I for example distribution
version one it includes some libraries
and software which is pretty much frozen
for the whole lifetime and then I have
another distribution another version and
the same story there this is fine but
there are some problems because for
example applications are released at
their own pace independent of
distributions and they can also come in
multiple versions which means conflicts
right distributions often include only
one version of every application because
they go dependencies they can configure
to each other and it would be impossible
to install so we need to choose a
version but how to choose the right one
that's a tricky question
because for example if you are developer
you might prefer this one fast and
latest because that's what developers
want but if your assist admin for
example you're running an application
you don't want it to change so much
right so you might prefer the other
scenario so I guess the right answer we
need all of them we can't just choose
one but how to do it well there are
several several solutions to this so for
example we can have distribution on a
fast track and another one which is bit
slower so for example this can be fedora
this can be sent to us or we're going to
go to LTS
if I'm a bit more crazy maybe I can have
continuous upgrades but this still
doesn't allow me to mix and match
versions as I want so the solutions are
software collections how many of you
heard about software collections all
right so that's like half so software
collections are kind of special packages
which enter software in a separate space
so I can install like more versions of
the software on the system but it's
pretty hacky he doesn't work always so
that's a solution but not ideal another
thing would be Linux containers who of
you know Linux containers almost
everyone
that's great so yeah you know it's an
isolated space which looks like system
and it's for single application and I
can run multiple containers on system
but sometimes if I put stuff in the
container I need to look after for it I
might have problems with updates and
still I'm building containers out of a
single distribution so if I install some
different version of something this can
be conflicted as well so that's we
that's why we are working on modularity
which kind of combines everything
together
and now I have like one minute animation
with subtitles so I won't be talking so
if you could preserve it
or you can just read this away so this
is a talk I'm not supposed to be talking
here
all right so that's basically it so it
will look like this we will have
something some something called base run
time it's just a neat system with a
pretty long life cycle and another
software and this will be like how do
you call it in English
independence sorry independent of the
distribution right so as I said based on
time this is what Peters going to talk
about which is a small system containing
software with proven API stability like
kernel and GFC and some kind some basic
tools to make it boot and the software
you run as a module and module is
similar concept to Android applications
or iPhone applications so it's pretty
independent on the system and it
includes all the dependencies in itself
and as I said modules are like
applications so it can be database it
can be Firefox but it can be also lamb
stack or basically any group of packages
and it will looks like this so I will
have packages and some metadata and I
can also have packages as an API and as
a dependencies which the difference is
that if I for example have a Firefox
module the Firefox package will be API
this is the only package I care for but
I can have dependencies libraries etc
which are not guaranteed to be stable
but uses one care about this users care
only about the API
and modules are defined as a by module
MD file and it basically defines
everything we shall show you right now
so this dimaggio md it's kind of cut off
on the top but there's nothing important
the important is that we have some name
string version which is an ID of the of
the module description licensing some
references where the project lives
backtracking so optional metadata and
here is the important part so I have
dependencies there is the base runtime
and to build it up build requires which
is based on time and be some time built
I guess Peter will tell you more about
it and this our list of the components
so I can include packages in my module
and I can include another modules in my
module which might be useful for example
if I have an application requiring
Python I don't have to list all the
Python packages I just placed the Python
module and in the RPM world if I have a
source package I can build multiple
binary packages of it but
I'm sorry so in the appian world
I have source RPM packages which are
packages containing the source code and
if I build it I can build multiple
binaries and I don't want to probably
include all the binaries they can be
develop acquisition and stuff so I can
filter them thanks to this filter here I
can specify the RPMs API and in the
future there will be more types of IP I
just then notice rpms and also something
called install profile which is
interesting it basically explains how to
install the module and I can have more
ways to installing so for example if I
have web server I can install it as a
production or as a developer with bit
different configuration so that was
module MD and module on D is modules are
built in something called factory 2.0 I
don't have time to talk about Factory
2.0 but if you can google for example or
find chalk recordings from Def Con which
was like last week last week you can
find some interesting stuff about that
and
yeah and we build and modules are
delivered as multiple artifacts which
can be rpm Reaper willingness container
flat packs or s3 I saw whatever and the
distribution when we put it back
together will look similar to this
picture so I have based on time the
minimal system which we'll be talking
about and I have the modules running on
the system in this example I have RPM
packages here and container images here
and as we can see as I say the module
contains packages and all the
dependencies right so there are some
challenges how to deal with for example
conflicting packages in these two
scenarios so that's why we use
technology similar software collections
to avoid that or we can use containers
and
what you guys use rpms or containers
well I don't really care because the
reckful can be pretty similar so for
example this is pretty bad I will just
make the window yeah
so in Fedora we use DNF to install
software so I can type the NF installed
httpd which is a web server I can
configure it by editing the
configuration file I can add my
index.html and I can be a system control
style httpd so that's the workflow in
current fedora this can be the workflow
in the module fedora and I can say if
it's container or RPM packages it's
really pretty same for both and maybe
even few days later I can the end of
updates so the workflow will stay the
same even with modules which is I guess
importance so how all of this works
so we focus on the package instead of on
the register version so for example in
Fedora East we store all the packages in
this gate which is distribution gate and
each package has similar has several
branches so for example F 24 F 25 which
is like Fedora 24 or 25 or 26 and we
want to change that to reflect the
package so for example I can have
package and have branches according to
the versions so instead of building
distribution versions from the list
gates so taking like all the branches of
24 to build 4.25 and talking all the
f-35 branches to build fill about 20
sorry 585 I can use modules to build
modules yeah so I can in the module MD I
can specify packages I want to include
in a module and I can just mix and match
whatever I want and then I can install
it on base runtime we call it module
streams and that that's like very end of
the module we don't call it versions
because in some cases it will be true
but if I for example I'm stack I can't
say what this version of lamps like
because I have version of database a
version of PHP so that's why we call it
streams and these are basically just
variants of the modules and before you
install you will be able to choose the
right version or you can just download
ISO with the versions pre-selected so
there's experienceable kind of same like
with federal today
and you can use DNF DNF update will work
it will keep your system up-to-date so
that's basically it about the module
destroy and now but I will tell you
something about the base one time which
is the minimal system
you give me a microphone I can give you
a microphone
I guess I'll just hold it okay so a
sudden mentioned the bass runtime is a
module that sits below all the other
modules all the other specs that we have
this part is main generational core
though so I will provide some background
on what generational quarry is but base
one time really is and the difference
between them based runtime was
originally meant to be only the the
lower layer of the abyss diagram
it was meant to provide hardware
abstraction layer with system tools
utilities and shirt libraries to be
provided by other modules included in a
stack that we wanted to call the
generational core this initiative is
temporarily on hold however because of
the complexity and the introduction
introduction of modularity to fedora we
don't have all the resources and the
plants and the and the clear idea how to
actually separate it what what
components go into which module and so
on also because the name is quite quite
long and nobody could pronounce it
nobody really understood what
generational meant in this context we
decided to just broaden the definition
based on time itself include some of the
system tools and libraries
naughty-naughty shared libraries layer I
will get to that but basically when we
talk about the base in February 6 we
mean based on time no generation core we
must be may still revisit the idea of
the generation core in the future
so the implementation don't don't worry
about the picture isn't really important
if you can't read it
yeah it's a module like any other it's
defined in a module and e-file it lists
all the components that we want to build
as part of the base one time module it
provides stable and minimal bootable
system on bare metal machines and
virtual machines it also defines the
container based image for both system
system the N spawn and dr. files just
okay the components that we include were
inspired by the LSB curse at POSIX
userland and the atomic host currently
we include 700 binary rpms defined by
roughly 170 source rpms when installed
is a container base image for docker
it's 82 packages and takes roughly 88
member maximum of all this space how we
actually implement it is that we have
this the module I just described which
is something something we want to ship
but we also have to build it somehow so
we have another module called temporary
base one time built environment which
includes all the bill dependencies of
the components in base one time it also
those bill dependencies and all the the
entire records if the bill dependency
chain currently it's roughly 2008 800
packages which one build is roughly six
six thousands binary rpms although we
will ship the base base runtime built
environment we won't be supporting it in
any way and in the future we hope that
parts of the built environment will be
split into into the applications
themselves and based on time we'll build
depend only on itself and the
applications that provide the components
needed to build it
so okay yeah yeah I will I will try yeah
I know I'm just quite speaker so the
challenges that we face when developing
based on time is that there's more than
one way one way to do it actually
so choosing the right content is the
biggest challenge we decided to to go
with the yeah we did that was because
that and yeah timing how certain and the
POSIX user and cert I mentioned in
previously but it's definitely not if
not the finalist we may or may exclude
some of those components or or add
something else to do to it keeping it as
small as possible is important because
we minimize both team memory this space
displays footprint as well as the attack
surface and of course smaller set means
that we can rebuild it more much more
faster and we can also test it faster
another problem is building the whole
set
we started with Fedora beta federal 25
beta and just hope that selected those
3,000 packages we needed for the for the
basement iron-based runtime built
environment and hope that they would
magically rebuild themselves and it
would just work that don't work is
expected we get like 400 failed to build
from source issues in the bin the first
run that was mostly because parallel was
removed just before federal 25 beta was
branch many packages build required
peril but don't explicitly state a bill
dependencies so they were failing and it
was mostly caused by auto tools and auto
comfort
so we fix some of the issues and then
rebased our sets to use federal route 25
for his candidate 3 which and the bill
dependency favors the bill favors drop
to 180 back then so we created a new
tracker back and we vary reporting all
the FFTs
issues due to the package maintainers it
was mostly in being under missing well
dependencies but it was also in a more
poor packaging practices for example and
the lack of CI n fedorov wasn't helping
another issue was the unresponsive
maintainer z' for example when we
reported those ft BF s issues we gave
all the maintainer s-- two weeks to
respond otherwise we would just fix it
for them in most cases we had to wait
the whole two weeks because there was no
response whatsoever in other cases the
package maintainer had a different
opinion how to fix the issue which is
not always a problem but it it just
slows down the progress of course the
discussion helps if it's if it has
potential another issue is that we are
developing based on time and all the
modules in parallel with the traditional
release we since we are trying to build
it we haven't actually got past that yet
we are working with the frozen packaged
set and Federer is still introducing new
changes in rawhide that includes GCC
seven package conf
basically anything also when a
maintainer fixes an issue for example
when with the building the package they
often a rebase the package which means
new dependencies and new build failures
caused by the battery base that's not
always
this is a picture with with the bill
dependency graph of the current base
one-time self-hosting prototype it
includes those 3000 packages and the
bill dependencies between them as you
can see when trying to minimize the bill
dependency chain both for runtime or the
service team prototype because it just
takes forever to rebuild and with all
those issues it's it's just a nightmare
many of those dependencies are obsolete
and could be removed because they were
added like years ago and nobody really
cares anymore but finding them that's
that's the problem
I can provide SVG picture later so what
we plan to deliver in ferret 26 the
proof of concept based runtime module
with the first version of the API
hopefully all the packages in the API
will also ship with the devil's uh
packages so people can actually use our
API that's not as easy as it sounds
because the Devils Devils are packages
often does require stuff like Perl and
we don't want perylene based on time of
course we will also ship development a
built environment module
although unsupported we will ship
several a vo ship system and container
management modules such as DN F which is
not part of based on time because it
moves at a different pace the same for
docker for example we will also ship
you know like a proof-of-concept of the
selection of the dynamic dynamic
languages modules mostly for Python
again the same situation as with peril
we don't want Python in the in the base
one time but many of our tools including
rpm build
unfortunately required in the long term
we would either ship like a small set of
Python standard library including a like
small small Python interpreter similar
to system Python we have now but
completely disconnected from the Python
3 fellowships today we will also ship
project Voltron which is a funny name
for further 20:26 server composed
entirely out of modules unfortunately
for 26 won't have any updates since the
reason is big that body cannot handle
any artifice besides our PM's we are
working on fixing that though and it
will be made entirely by the majority
working group members the reason is
again that we have no infrastructure for
end processes to do process like this
for example module submission requests
and changes in the package database
4:27 beam hoped that base one time will
be much more stable all the API will be
usable the packages that are not meant
to be a part of API will be repackaged
and shipped differently so that couldn't
be accessed by anybody who is not meant
to be using them the same for the
dynamic languages runtimes we hope to
finish this system pattern and pattern
tree split for instance we will support
automated builds and rebuilds so
whenever you push the diskette you will
you will both build the component and
the whole module and all the modules
that depend on it we will ship updates
the update for bodies is in plan the
modularity infrastructure will be open
to public so anybody will be able to
submit a module and build it there will
be a new new release of failure server
and more content it doesn't have a name
doing everything and be on federal cloud
federal workstation hopefully that
building good modules like norm for it
for example
yeah we hope that module releases will
become our primary deliverable and the
traditional release will be still
available but will be composed out of
modules so we will pre select several
modules for the users and flatten them
out into a traditional release and it
will be awesome yeah so that's the end
we have plenty of time for questions
darling
[Music]
you told Benson open an adult
right so yeah the question was if I for
example have an application that depends
on the library so how do i how do I make
it not conflicting with other libraries
right so as I said I can maybe switch
back to my slides so you can use
container so the module can be installed
as a container and the container will be
we have solved that already or if you
want to install it as an RPM we might
need to repackage the libraries or the
dependencies in a way that will be
installed in a separate path yes yeah
not in containers containers are meant
to contain everything in themselves so
base room time we'll have some libraries
that are shared amongst other things but
at the beginning it's probably going to
be more stuff than we would like so
ultimately we would like that shared set
to be smaller
right yeah Doug yeah they only need to
be optimizations but yeah but that's I
guess more for the future in the RPM
world yeah if we have one library of a
certain version I think it will be just
once on the system still but yeah in the
containers that's no choice basically
but we can still use layering so for
example I can have the base on time
layer then I can have some libraries
layer etc and if they're the same for
the same container they will share both
storage and runtime resources yeah
another problem is that we want oh not a
problem
we want to offer applications not
packages and we want them to offer them
an upstream driven life cycles not the
distribution driven life cycles so we
will we will ship the RPM repository or
container depending as the as upstream
releases new versions not as we just
decide
the question is about is basically the
same the same packaging is basically the
same version but built against different
different versions of dependencies we
will build all the variations against
all the all the dependencies in a chain
so yeah there will be a lot of artifacts
and available in the repositories on the
service and mirrors but the build the
install the system management tools
should choose correctly which module
variants to install for you well there
is because we track how we build it so
we know
so yeah maybe I'll try to answer
differently each module will contain all
the dependencies but also the build
recipe so it will be always built at the
same time so for example it will
reference particular version of the base
runtime it will reference or write
basically if there are more versions of
race entirely built against both against
all of them but in a module I can
specify all the packages by branches for
example but when I build them the Bata
stem will save the exact Commission
cheese so it will be reproducible at all
times and yeah the module defines all
the software it needs this isn't really
meant to be exposed to end users per se
except that you may have multiple
versions of something available to
choose from
so but that doesn't mean that you can
arbitrarily create your own modules me
as a developer you could but that's not
the concept here the concept here is
that these things are still all the find
on the server side much like our cams
are today but the units of measure are
quite a bit bigger for the most parts of
it the individual things can have
individual life cycles that doesn't mean
that you can't go in there and Twitter
with the packages but I mean the reason
why I'm asking those questions
and this very problem there's been a lot
of interested in the last two or three
years and most people have tended
towards the punctual declarative
approach that's used by system centers
but you're still adhering to the variant
approach so obviously you
you don't agree with the other that's a
big move so that's a that maybe even
long-term right answer but that's a
that's a gut rewrite and no way to
distribute the existing distribution so
you know even even if we were a hundred
percent sure the next answer was the
right answer
we can't just turn it on so you know I I
think we're kind of walking towards that
direction
interim mega well mean going to the
supreme perfection good one since think
we want those we're trying yeah so let's
let's put it together it's not it's
disruptive but it's not trainwreck right
and see how it works and then you know
and then iterate rather than to make the
Big Ben oh you know questions
just
[Music]
yeah okay so question was how do you run
containers do we run them on docker do
we run them on system Lian spawn and the
answer is we will be using OCI
containers which will be able to run on
docker run on run C and for example if
ever
no CI image you can imagine I had pretty
nice example for example you can imagine
PDF which could be built by different
tools but you can open it in a browser
you can operate in this reader on your
phone so the OCI image will run on
multiple container engines but I'm not
sure which which would be the default we
can do both we can do both here yeah but
I have to find it
oh there isn't all right so what's the
carbon footprint well as you can see
it'll be a lot of building because yeah
I'm building a module made to build all
the packages but I hope there will be
some optimization some nice filters to
not have the calf with painlessly as
bigger than this picture yeah comments
pouring container runtimes the
continuous base is still a warfare zone
so if we were declarative about any
particular tech there we were wrong
right so the objective here I think is
that we want to do kind of the OCI model
which is the open standard and then use
different technologies to run them
depending on scenario like you know
there's some of the reasons for the
system lead container stuff is because
you sometimes want to run a container
before something like a docker demon
comes up so you need to know just like
everything else meant to be kind of
flexible about the container of runtimes
that we want to use because we're going
to need different ones for different
kinds of containers
yeah
so do we have any more questions
all right so I guess we can wrap up
thanks for coming
[Applause]