okay that's fine okay so good afternoon
everybody my name is Raymond knob I'm
very happy to be here actually like this
venue of a lot it's it's much more
relaxed than normal presentations so I
work at Adyar come in social tea police
which is in the South of France we have
a new name to our lab it's called the
open 5g lab and what I'm gonna do is
talk a little bit about some of the
things we're doing in open air interface
for network signal processing I don't
know if everybody here is aware of open
air interface it's one of the open
source projects that develops both
either B and UE implementations that run
on on us are peas and on other platforms
as well and I'm going to talk about some
of the stuff that's been going on in I'd
say the last six months on how we're
changing the architecture a little bit
to address some of the the research
goals that are that are going on in 5g
systems all right so what do I mean by
network signal processing there's a
trend and I'll show you a picture in a
second to you know to start it's
actually kind of funny because 2g
systems if you look at them they were
already split between you had the the
BTS and the MSC okay basically the BTS
was running the physical air and they
and the other was running the mac layer
in 3G there was a bit more going on in
the in the node B and but there was
still at the beginning of 3G the the all
of the Mac layer was running in the rnc
then when when 3G started getting faster
with HSPA and we came came along to 4G
they decided to put everything into the
Ino beat basically it's you have the
entire layer one and layer two stack in
the node B and the rest of it is in is
is for long in the network well it turns
out that now the the the operators and
the vendors they would like to start
splitting things again and but they're
doing it in a different way in a very
flexible way so this talk is looking at
how
you you you you you take a radio system
and either split it or there are other
terms that are you slice it that's more
from the perspective of services or from
from a computing perspective
distributing the computing in different
parts of the network both in the radio
processing and in the protocol stack
right there we different reasons for
doing this one of the reasons is to do
spatial signal processing if you want to
centralize the signal processing in
radio node that's connected to many
radio heads that's one reason for doing
it another one is the trend towards
doing a lot more network function
virtualization so some of the protocol
stack gets put into a virtualized
environment and more generally to do
processing of both access networks and
the core networks in a data center
environment that's that's that's the
reason this is happening so I'll go over
a little bit of the current
implementation that we have in open air
interface and a bit some notes on how
we're actually going to try and test
this and then some maybe at the end if
there's sometimes some generic
information about about our community
all right so this picture shows more or
less what what the vision of one of the
operators this is actually the vision of
China Mobile the way they see the the
the evolution of radio networks so
basically they have the concept of
what's known as as a remote radio system
the RS inside the remote radio system
base stations have different names they
call them remote radio units okay today
in 4G systems you have the remote radio
heads so it's an evolution if you like
the remote radio head now inside there
are different there are different kinds
of remote radio systems you have the
classical one this is what we have today
in 4G you have what's called a
a remote radio system where there's a
lot of collaboration between the nodes
so you have big base stations so
tri-sector base stations with with with
6 or 12 antennas and then you have
smaller Pico cells but they're all the
signals are all collected at this radial
node here where this is different from
from from today's networks these these
radio sites here will have a fiber optic
connection from the radio head down to a
control room at the bottom which is
basically where all the baseband
processing happening so you might have
at most a 30 40 meter optical link in
the new networks that 30 40 meters is
going to become 10 kilometres okay and
these notes here or potentially already
the ones closer to the central office of
the operators are going to be doing a
lot a lot of signal processing for a
whole network okay so that changes the
way you actually you actually do things
they changed the way you architect the
the signal processing system so you
would have something like this you might
you might have others that are quite
similar this will be the indoor system
so this could be in an airport and your
shopping center is something like that
you would also have one radio
aggregation unit and several remote
radio units or you would have the
massive MIMO remote radio units or radio
aggregation unit this is if you like
these two things are the same the only
difference is here the antennas are all
collected together and here they're
distributed in space but ultimately this
is the way the networks seem to be going
in if we consider this this
next-generation frontal interface this
part of the network
which is if you like where all the
signal process isn't happening there
call it they they're calling that the
frontal network and the network that
goes towards the core network is the
back home network those are the new
terminologies and you also see something
now called an X Hall or an X all network
and I'll explain what that is too
but you see there are basically three
entities here you have the radio units
of the remote radio units the
aggregation units and the radio cloud
centers so this this is this is the
terminology that we're actually also
using now in in open air interface so
we're trying to take our software which
was written sort of in a
monolithic form for an e not B and not
splitting it again into pieces now the
thing that becomes interesting is when
you split it into pieces you have to
interconnect those pieces together with
a network and then in the end you're
doing signal processing with the network
that's where that that's where the
terminology came from and so this kind
of splitting in the network there are
different languages if you ask the NGO
fine which is one of the I Triple E
groups they label the split points this
is though this is a protocol stack say
of a 4G base station you know the radio
interface so this is your IQ streams
like you would you would be handling in
in UHD this is the first stage of the
input so that you transferred in the
frequency domain and they get that name
and into a a number they call it an
interface for then you can go up further
in the stack they define this one
interface 3 which is just before the the
bit little level processing then another
one interface 2 and then there's that
one up there interface 1 prime from what
I'm seeing out there
this interface exists today 4G uses this
they put a fancy label on it but that's
what this is the C pre interfaces this
today this one is coming okay that's
actually interesting because here this
is this is a split between if this is a
networked interface here this these
these operations the Fourier transforms
are running with the radio and then this
is running somewhere else
all right that's that one is that this
one is definitely one that is going to
happen now why is it gonna happen
because basically here you get a certain
amount of compression I show you how
that's done later another one that would
surely happen is this one here this is
something called fatty or femto access
it's the femto api there was there's a
there's a standardization form called
the Fanta forum which became the small
self forum
they standardized an API for basically
for this interface and at the time it
wasn't for a network
system it was the interface between the
system-on-chip and the or the baseband
processor and the protocol processor so
base station vendors that were making
small cells they could use this
specification here and interface with
another chipset and that's basically
what it was for and now they're
extending this to be networked in this
sense they call it in fat B the other
one that you're going to see is that one
all the way up at the top there because
it's very likely and I'll show you the
picture why that's what's going to allow
different systems 4G 5g Wi-Fi
millimeter-wave Wi-Fi millimeter-wave 5g
all to interconnect in the same data
center and so that if' one prime is also
one so today an open interface what
we're doing we've already implemented
these two and we're in the process of
implementing the one up on the top there
and there's also this one that we're in
discussion with with an industrial
partner that would like to see this all
right so there will be several splits
now what's important in in these systems
is that the the software that you have
be flexible enough to change the the
split not necessarily dynamically but
semi static depending on the types of
deployments you would use different
strategies it's not really that it it's
not really that informative this is more
informative because this shows you now
how how you you would instantiate these
things so this is a picture that I you
know sometimes when you go to
presentations of companies like Nokia
and Ericsson they flash a lot of slides
you don't get the slides and people are
always taking pictures I took a picture
of this one last year because it was it
helped us a little bit understand where
where people were going this shows you a
little bit what the way they need
the big guys they see the evolution of
the network so everything forgetting
about the core network everything seems
to be centered around this PD CP that's
called the packet data conversion
program and you'll see different kind of
systems eventually connecting to that
the LTE 5g and even Wi-Fi and very
likely also some of the the IOT based
air interfaces but what's important to
see is this this cloud that they have
here it's not it's it's a cloud because
it's running in essentially the central
office of the operator which is if you
went to the first one of the first
sessions this morning one of the first
presentations this morning in a session
on NFV and Sdn they were talking about
the this this the evolution of the
central office to an architecture like
this so basically this cloud which is
which is running radio processing both
protocol and potentially physical air
will be connected to different types of
systems with different types of latency
requirements if you're connecting for
instance to a over a 10 kilometer link
to a radio site from the central office
so replacing that hundred meter optical
fiber by by a 10 kilometer optical fiber
well that's a very low latency thing and
then there's physical layer happening
here in this data center the other types
of systems distr more any more classical
to what way in comparison to what we
have today very similar to what we have
today these would be you know hundreds
or maybe a Gigabit Ethernet link but
with a fairly high latency because your
your interfacing way up in the protocol
stack and so this is you know the this
is the way things are going so how are
we approaching this we define several
entities now in in our software we have
an entity that we're calling a radio
unit we have entities which we call the
actually the you know B's which are
separate from the radio units
and we have the the product well the you
know the physical layer part of the you
know be and the protocol stack of you
know be know we can further subdivide
this into things which weren't what
we're calling instances a radio or a
physical layer instance could be several
equivalent base stations inside and I'll
show you a picture why you would want to
do that one very clean clear example
these could be three sectors of a big
base station they're they're independent
protocol entities in some sense or they
could be what you would call a virtual
base station if you have an antenna
array if this is acting as an antenna
array and I purposely chose a different
number here here I put six radio units
and there are actually four base
stations here so there are more radio
units than base stations that means that
there's some sort of a mapping from
logical base stations to physical
antennas or physical radios and that's a
way that's also the way the systems are
going to be going for instance that
indoor that indoor system I showed you
before inside a building you might only
need three protocol instances but you
might have twenty antennas okay the same
thing for the massive MIMO the base
station with 256 antennas you're not
going to drive more than the equivalent
say of eight base stations or more maybe
sixteen base stations but you're using a
lot of antennas and so there's a there's
a notion of a mapping here from from
something that's that has meaning in the
protocol stack to something that has
meaning in the air that's that's that's
that's what it means
alright so that's how we've divided
things up now let me just give you what
is a radio unit the radio name is
something that's managing a physical
antenna which means the any can have are
there a local radio unit or a remote
radio unit okay so what that means it's
a two sided thing the radio units can
talk to each other one is on let's say
on the protocol side and the other is on
the radio side they're implicitly you're
putting a network between the two things
a fixed network between two three
now what does that actually do it
performs two operations it performs what
we're calling precoding and i'll explain
what that is so you basically that's
that operation of taking several logical
base stations and generating the signals
on the antennas right that's the notion
of precoding and it also does OFDM
modulation okay it does the it does the
conversion from frequency to time on the
transmit end and from time to frequency
on on the reception in the the instance
of the protocol stack is a separate set
of threads and contexts which implement
the the procedures of the base station
okay so it's it's a it's a it's a notion
of of processes I mean it would contain
the same Mack and RLC entities on top of
the physical here the component carrier
that that is actually the the entity
that manages the physical layer
procedures for a particular for a
particular carrier which could be a
separate frequency carrier but it could
also be a virtual carrier which is
controlled by the antennas and so that's
that's what these notions actually mean
[Music]
and just show the pictures so this is an
example of the radio unit that
implements the interface five so if you
remember that the interface five was the
one at the bottom of my picture there
that was a time domain signal so it's
the IQ this is equivalent to HD it's
completely equivalent to that so what do
we do here if let's look at the the
receive path alright so you have to see
this these are the inq signals that are
coming in on the receiver now the sorry
this is this these are the inq signals
that are coming from the the the the
radio unit on the other side so this is
this is a network input the first thing
we do is is decompose it's is is
decompress the signal so when we
transmit inq samples if you want to fit
them on Ethernet you you compress them a
little bit okay you can compress it and
we actually use a lock compression for
this you get a compression factor about
a half without any signal degradation
all right so this is coming from the
network we decompressed and then we
convert to the frequency domain so this
is the front end of a base station in
the other direction when we're
transmitting from the the protocol
context it goes into a block which does
the Wichitas precoding it has conversion
from frequency to time and then it
compresses so this is this is what this
is what happens in the radio unit on the
side of the of the protocol now let's
look at let's look at the other type of
interface so the the the 4.5 interface
so that's a little bit higher up okay
again if we look at what's coming from
the device we decompress the signal but
actually here there are two types of
signals
there's the there because in in a system
like 4G on the receive path you have the
the the terminal can transmit two types
of signals it can transmit the normal
uplink signal and control channels or it
can transmit the random access signal
those are two different kinds of signals
so you actually need two kinds of
packets to encode those signals and two
different types of processing
to wait when you receive you all right
so again this one the the data signal
part is compressed and the other part is
not we're going to the other direction
we have precoding and compression but
there's no Fourier transform because the
Fourier transform is done on the other
side all right so basically you already
see with this simple example what we're
doing is moving around pieces here I
have them on the side of the network on
the other one I have them on the side of
the the remote end so this is the remote
end so on this side on one side we're
connected to the network on the other
side we're connected to an our RF device
that could be for instance the USRP but
it could also be whatever we like there
is a notion here of splitting the
processing into the different types of
things we have so on the transmit side
we do the modulation and on the
reception side we do the demodulation
and we do a part of the the random
access channel demodulation in the radio
unit itself I'm gonna skip that let's
look at another example so the ones I
just showed you now were the examples of
the the the the radio units when we were
connecting directly any node be to a
radio unit in the in the first set of
slides I showed you there was also an
intermediate node this is an example of
what an intermediate node could look
like on one side you would have a
frontal interface for instance a little
bit higher up in the in the protocol
stack okay because this this would be a
note that might be a couple of
kilometers from the radio station the
radio stations and it would be connected
to a central office maybe 10 kilometers
further away so you have an optical link
there and an optical link here but this
signal processing is happening somewhere
in in the middle of the in in the middle
of the deployed region so in this unit I
put in two base stations or two logical
Bay
stations to Eno bees which are running
the physical air signal processing of to
base stations and it's connected to a
pre coder which is which is driving for
radio units okay so here's a mapping of
two base stations to four radio units
that that would be for instance
something that you could do if you were
in a small rural village right you would
put four maybe four radio units to cover
the village you would have one central
location which was doing all the signal
processing and then sending the the
protocol information back to the to the
central office this would be one example
another example would be a massive
mining base station it's essentially the
same thing on one side you have an
Ethernet frontal and on the other side
you have a sorry
Ethernet front altar the radio units and
on the other side you would have a
protocol interconnection this was an
example where you have eight base
stations or eight illogical base
stations driving 64 in Tennessee this is
essentially the same thing and the key
difference here with the respect to the
previous example is this block it's much
more complicated the pre coder is a much
more complicated block so let me let me
skip these things and talk a little bit
just how the processing is actually done
the radio unit itself if you think about
a a 4G system it has to do the
transmission and reception in parallel
and in in the system like LTE the the
signal that you're receiving at time n
is used to generate the signal that
you're transmitting a little bit in the
future so there's a dependence between
the signal you transmit in the future
and the one you're receiving a time in
so the way we decided to implement this
was to to that that fundamental thing in
in LT it's it's at time n + 4
milliseconds so the signal you receive
at time n
is necessary to constitute to generate
the signal that you transmit at time n
plus 4 milliseconds and that's that's
the way it works so basically every
processing thread does the following
thing it reads from what's below the
south whether it's a networked interface
or an RF interface it does the
processing for subframe in it wakes up
all of the the base station processes
that are waiting for it it waits for
them to finish their completion then
they have all of their their their
information necessary to generate the
signal at time n plus 4 and then we send
it out good n before so this is this is
quite simple that that's and you know
that's that's the way it works we have
another we have another thread that's
there just for the random access channel
by itself because that's a completely
independent independent thing and then
there's also one other thread which is
there when you receive on the frontal
interface so for instance if you're in a
radio unit the signal you receive from
the frontal interface is what you use to
transmit now if you're on an Ethernet
network there's a lot of jitter on an
Ethernet network it's not a real-time
thing it could be it could be real-time
but in if if it's very long distances
there is a significant amount of jitter
so you need some sort of an asynchronous
process to handle that that's why
there's that's why there's that kind of
a threat all right so this is really the
bait that the the basic mechanism of the
thing is this and you can see here the
overall picture of the way it works up
on top there you see the the the timing
of the different sub frames and
underneath you see how processors are
scheduled yellow means receive red means
transmit so we're always receiving and
then transmitting receiving and
transmitting now it turns out that you
can paralyze this by a factor 2 you know
in order to improve the performance so
if anybody's interested in the inner
workings that's that's the way it works
so let me just switch over to the other
part
yes this is the one you just that's what
I just said just the other one yes okay
I should be it should be a few minutes
so this is basically what we're building
here at your home to test this kind of
stuff so we have a we have a little data
center here which is basically a 5 5 Z
on servers so these are multi core
servers and 20 cores each in each
machine some of them are protocol stacks
some of them are for the physical layer
and then there's a network here of
switch switches these are standard Cisco
switches and radio units those remote
radio units that was talking about so
basically the open air interface is
going to be deployed on this data center
and segregated and split and and do some
of the processing on the radio units so
just to give you an idea what the the
the radios themselves are they're using
us artbeads they're using actually b200
meaning we want it we wanted to have a
very cheap very cheap hardware that you
have some external or F on top so we can
transmit in an indoor environment up to
15 DBM and each remote radio unit is
driven by an up board I don't know if
people know what that is that's a very
small intel architecture it's the size
of a Raspberry Pi and that that's
running enough signal processing to
implement the radio unit and the rest of
the stuff is running in the cloud and so
this is something we're in the process
of deploying now we have an order with
edits for 5,200 minutes so just very
quickly general general general
information for those that are
interested our software now will support
Lima steer we're still testing it with
with the most recent board we got from
them but it will work up to 10 megahertz
FDD today we've stabilized the you know
to be quite a bit in the last in the
last year we have full full applique
downlink throughput and ten megahertz
bandwidth and full downlink on 20
megahertz bandwidth we're starting to
test our scheduler of loaded schedulers
to load it with with terminals and soon
we'll have the mime emotes running as
well
another thing interesting for some
people are here there's been a lot of
development on the terminal side so did
any open air interface will run on the
terminals at full throughput up to ten
megahertz bandwidth just 35 megabit per
second down there and we're testing the
my moments now as well and just finally
for the core network there's work in the
community to get today testing with
commercially known bees in order to
robust apply our confession we've
integrated the dedicated bearer support
for those you know what that is that's
that's the support voice over LTE that's
that's in there Knapton I'm very happy
also say we've defaulted now to the Osmo
come gtp module this is very good that
helped a lot and now with some of the
partners in the community where we're
integrating some of the missing
procedures in the core network which
will make something much closer to the
commercial commercial core and so that's
it I'm sorry there was a lot of
information you will have to fly
[Applause]
yeah yeah well not in 40 in in five
years yes yes the evolution yes the
evolution well okay there there are two
things there are two things they want to
bring it down but they also want to
relax it at the same time so there will
be some services where it does have to
go way down and in that case those very
low latency freight front hauls are
gonna have to be even lower latency you
to support the the new waveforms I don't
know I don't have numbers for you here
oh that's that's that's doable as long
ago we haven't tested longer than a
hundred meter it's okay it's all copper
so basically the the way the network
goes I didn't have time to explain it
but these links here are copper links
maximum of 50 meters so it's standard
Gigabit Ethernet right so the the and
the the throughput that we need is on
the order of 200 megabits per second so
it's it's it's it's more than feasible
there and then the link between here and
here that's optical fiber but we're not
going to be doing ten kilometers in our
lab okay if you go to 10 kilometers then
they're issues but at the same time
there are there is one group in in our
community that has done the same
experiment with 20 kilometer fiber and
the only thing they have to do is adjust
the timing a little bit in the in the
radio unit itself so it was an FPGA
based radio unit they had to advance the
signal a little bit in order to to
handle the latency of the of the fiber
over 20 kilometers so it's feasible but
it's you have to you have to you have
the question for 5g is another one oh
sorry