why
now
nerd
and the players
two
not
or
story
and one year for the amount
but and
for very little
a court to 20
they are adopted by the senate asked
racing has caused us all
Y
d
yes we are good
goodbye
but all
because there are many
if you search
and the moment
shadows with these backgrounds removed goodbye
or
both
me
but
with the pain
Y
we removed
finally about the study
two
Y
not
or not and land
I am not
Yes Yes
well I just went
the acquaintances
[Music]
two
the municipal star [Applause]
me
are 1
Y
no it's not all
best
it's me
strong
well they have doubts
goods and furniture
in 2000
two hours of work
but man
not with books
about it as i say
my favor
and
242 longás morán
i
Yes
the foundations
there is a lot of sun in everything fixed
pintos
for you
in process why
many [Music]
2 normal
this
light devices
is that they are like someone cloud in wisconsin
i'm not a little lonely
overhead
people you can't
when
Y
in front of
is this having things
and the present
and christ
why
for suns
or we invest
well, not
we are accurate on behalf of public data
two
and baseball rangers elvis then to follow
roman
2 [Music]
so it was
it is love
We are going to be
help you hear it
people why
happy me
there are several settings
according to pajín
at least
the grass
two
more
I'll be let's see why
two
in the weight of pounds look for substances
and per share
or
two
bedroom
why take photos
2 bruce
after more
is water
d
Y
wrong
correct with the verb let's say the 12 austerity
king and we put
love 2
ah
here
baby
Y
although there is one
today
normal
i
well
more
and I am and well familiar
Y
let's see god they also steal
is very good
to
come on I live
bone
would have reasons [Music]
wow
and me
in the
European chicken someone and that I make you liquid
and then another and another in seven very big games
Y
romanians
or
He passed
the whole I am very happy where they go persie
ah
not equal
like this oh
or
[Music]
i
above I don't know why
Let's see
he
1 story with a sixth
with them
Y
i
Yes
They are
is ours
2 [Music]
well
ace
or
i'm good good
how how
Y
like two convicts
two
How, where else, not Nabai?
and what not
their assets do not carry them
when we come back sweet
So
j
Y
I am so
and some
your suppliers
with some spain fine
or
ah
they have two children
now
j
love you and
and a man
with and so
in water
well
two
Y
red audio
it all started a story or rather
and then
not
Carmen Moriyón can avoid no
and beautiful
I am then how there is
Y
two
Yes
and music]
and others
There is not
as
but it's all
2 I know that they
God
All this
two
I also asked you if my prayer
hopefully
I do not want
not to kill
i
Y
then thanks and
with this for dead alone
Y
to the person yes
namely
[Music]
The Shepherd
Yes
use and parent
powell risk
why
the same
worry
and then
Y
in any image
as everyone
retention for next post why