and then a bit below your view okay
otherwise
[Applause]
I think it's time I have 20 minutes okay
okay thank you
okay
right thanks everybody my name is Thiago
Jaggu Santos I work for a company called
matte box we can introduction we we make
maps and we love open-source the name we
love open-source we are very excited to
be here and we maintain several popular
open-source projects like leaflet open
source routing machine and we also big
contributors to OpenStreetMaps
yeah like we work with tools like ID and
we contribute with data fixing data on
OpenStreetMaps
and developing tools to make improve the
quality of the map but then but today
are going to talk about this particular
tool is we call it map walk share native
is not exactly a product we offer is
actually the base for our products like
we have a map rendering engine SDK for
Android iOS and is based on this what I
would say it's a vector map rendering
engine which is open source and and I
think it's a very cool Bliley bleeding
edge technology compared to raster tile
rendering engines I realized when I was
making this talk we don't have a cool
logo for this many open source office
they have and it was was Friday night or
designers they were sleeping so I made I
made one
I think they're gonna come up with
something better Monday okay but what's
a vector tie so was I was very fortunate
because the less talk was awesome and I
was talking about a problem we have with
maps it's a huge volume of data and the
satellites they they keep increasing in
resolution I have heard that the army a
that in the US they have satellites that
take resolutions they can see if you
have hair or not but so you want to
display this huge amount of data in a
computer that is somehow limited by
several factors for including memory so
we have to tile the map right even if
you take OpenStreetMap the sheer amount
of data there is like several gigabytes
and you cannot display everything at
once and just zooming in in your
neighborhood or in your door and expect
that to work so even a vector vector
data you have to tile so so one strategy
we see often like when you're using
leaflet for instance like you take a big
image and you tile and as you go in like
as you zoom in you stretch the image so
for a moment like between the zoom
levels you have a image that doesn't
look that great and then boom it gets
replaced it to a new image and so on so
the nice thing about vector tiles like
the if you do the same thing with vector
it works exactly like a SVG so you can
stretch that because it's pretty much
saying I have a line from this
coordinate to dis coordinate so when you
zoom in you just stretch that obviously
what defines the resolution is the
amount of points you have in between
this line like if it's a curve
we don't really draw we don't say like
you have a curve like this we have
several points in between that makes a
curve so when you're zooming you're
going to see it turn into something a
little bit squarey
but it still looks much better than a
raster image so the vector x we-we-we
rendering here it's based on an open
standard okay so it's not we developed
this this tunnel but we keep it open so
all the vendors they can implement that
in fact their competitors opens other
open source projects using our vector
tile specification so this technology
for rendering this vector tiles like so
you can have your beautiful beautiful
maps in your application it's not really
let's let's say vendor locked in a way
that we are giving making this open
source project so you can use our
services so in fact you can use create
vector tiles from your own data if you
want to and we also provide open source
tools for creating these vector tiles so
for instance like we have this typical
move I'm still have to learn how to
pronounce this it converts geo Jason to
vector tiles view Jason's fairly
established format so I think one cool
application for this I I saw like we
have an app for the lectures here and it
has a map so I've seen people doing
using these vector tiles for creating
indoor maps like this we could have
could have like just make a map of the
University using I don't know geo Jason
convert this to vector tiles and render
an app in the app like with we've
completely
offline data I think that's pretty cool
like it's I'm not sure if when we
designed this we had this use case in
mind but there are some people doing it
and I find it really nice so I think the
advantages of rendering your map in the
client side are this like you can do 3d
effects you can shoot the map we don't
do this in our engine today but we are
bringing this word engine like the
native this native engine like you could
do 3d extrusion so you can see buildings
in your city the nice thing is when you
have a raster image like imagine like a
picture of myself rotated what's written
here in my in my t-shirt is going to
look upside down of course but if you
have a vector tile and you're rendering
a map on the fly client-side you have
different layers you know what's what's
the road what's the building and what's
the label so knowing that your map is
rotated you may you may keep the label
up right it's up to you because we also
support styling so styling meaning you
can change colors of your map whatever
color you can hide and show features
depending on zoom level you can change
that on the fly like if you have a map
in an app and you detect that the
Lightning is weak you can make your your
map less brighter so it's less
aggressive like if you are looking at
night and also it's more compact
compared to PNG it's often more
compacted that that kind of depends is
depends on the area you're looking but
most of the cases you're going to get
better style size compared to russet
eyes and as I mentioned before you
also have smooth zooming you don't lose
too much resolution when you're zooming
in to closer to what the place you're
looking so this is one example as the
map of the university is tilted and it's
using one style like but just changing
one one flag of one property of the map
this style you boom we have something
completely different without downloading
a whole set of Russia tiles like it's
all done in client-side so this is one
if it would be a receipt I would have to
redownload everything the other thing I
find very very cool about using vector
tiles is you can query features actually
so if if you click here you can say give
me what is in this area so the map could
give you back like I you have a road you
have a building here and the name of the
building have the label here right so
you don't need to go to a server and say
a give me what is at the coordinate X &
Y you can do it completely locally
awesome alright so and about this style
it's also open a standard so
specification though it's open its open
for suggestions and again it's not
implemented just by us like so back to
the engine we have we be doing the
development of this engine in the open
source it's on github so we brought this
engine to different platforms like
including Linux Mac iOS Android and most
recently we contribute this engine to
the cute project which is right doesn't
know it's established C++ open source
framework so
was very interesting to work with the
company we're still working with them
and and so you can use what they call
key ml it's the language for describing
user interfaces it's very easy it's way
better to compared to something like
HTML I mean III think it's the last time
I do a talk using a HTML slideshow it's
horrible to make this really like put
this image a line in the center here it
took me 30 minutes anyway so we have our
engine on cute now it's going to be
there by default from cute 5.9 which is
the upcoming release for this year and
you could do in the future something
like just like this like window you
change the string to map off gel here
put some coordinates if you're familiar
with KML this code it's a bit simplified
here but with six more lines of code
this is enough to have a window with a
map centered at a coordinated system in
Oslo at the zoom level 10 so I camera is
pretty cool it's very easy to read and
yeah and you can get the QT can get the
same map on your phone on desktop and
we're trying to get this running on
Windows today because we don't support
Windows at the moment but with cute we
saw maybe a window open intended for
that so what about a new platform
because the idea one of the ideas you
have this talk is like to invite
developers to get a vector map better
maps in other platforms like I know that
genome is using our roster tiles I would
love to see I don't know genome apps
maybe using vector tiles I don't see why
not
we we brought this too cute so
competitive
in his own so what do you need for
having a this engine running in your
whatever framework you have could be say
I'm using gtk here as an example but you
need a decent C++ 14 compiler we use
some features and it's not every
compiler that can do it for instance
clang recent versions of claying
can do it fine but this is C you need to
CC 5.0 we had some issues with customers
using GCC 4.9 and complaining about ah
this is C 5.0 is to Neil even though I
think it's 3 years old so we had bring
it back to BCC 4.9 maybe that means
you're using 4.9 I don't know
apart from there you need OpenGL we rely
on OpenGL it could be OpenGL ES if your
platform supports that and you you need
to do a little bit of plumbing because
the engine is designed in a way that you
have you have a decor core of the engine
and you have the platform bindings so
you can plug your platform we for
example II did some experiments and we
had got this running on the unity 3d SDK
but just replacing this part so we need
some main loop like if you're porting
this to gtk I think gee lip gives you
that you need some Fred IPC again like
Ghalib gives you that I know there is
this G async method or some something
like that and you need a network stack
it sounds big but we we have in our
engine some implementation
of portable network stacks for instance
we have already little curl implemented
so if you're using a port into gtk you
can just keep using the lip curl
implementation is going to probably work
on all UNIX platforms and if you don't
if you don't have a main loop or Fred
IPC we have this implemented for you
already this libuv I don't know if you
have heard about libuv is it's the main
loop implementation that nodejs is using
in fact I I look at I look at that
because I've been calling this libuv lib
ultraviolet for a while because I don't
know UV but in fact it stands for
unicorn Velociraptor which is which is a
very interesting name so so we have a we
wrote the the point I will talk more if
I have more time about the details of
porting days to a new platform but a bit
short on time so we wrote a blog post
about describing the details and again
we are doing the development in their
open so we have I'm usually hanging out
on slack channels
IRC channels especially on the cube
mobility IRC a tree node so I invite
everyone to help us I would especially
the gtk guys there is anyone here doing
gtk to join us so thank you and if you
have any questions
[Applause]
yeah so when report this too cute was
the core of the engine this 100% C++
like portable you don't have to change
that we rewrote the platform adaptations
to work with a cute main loop and the
cute Network stack and now cute is gonna
ship or engine inside the QT SDK so it's
there so we make really are making
release for cute and it's if you
download the Qt SDK 5.9 you're gonna get
this engine included for free
okay so the question so I forgot to
repeat the other one but there is about
the platform requirements yeah so the
question was about platform requirements
so the cheapest Hardware I managed to
get this running with decent performance
was the the latest raspberry pi
raspberry Pi the board yeah yeah you
need a GPU yeah you need a GPU but you
can also if you want to rasterize things
using our ancient server-side it's also
possible you can use these master
software rasterizer
it's going to be a bit slow but it works
we do that because we have you do for
running unit tests and stuff like that
we know it works in more questions okay
if not thank you for your time and I
will be hanging out - you have any
[Applause]
[Music]
you