okay good morning everyone
hi welcome to the second edition of the
HPC big data and data science the room
here at FOSDEM we are very happy to to
do this again after a very successful
event last year so this dev room is
organized by four people so Kenneth here
II won back in that in a video I Roman
on the other corner and myself
I'm Vasya so please please reach out to
us if you need anything like
organizational or administrative or if
you're a speaker and you haven't tried
if your laptop is working okay so this
year we have again a lot of submissions
I think 42 or 43 maybe a few late ones
and we tried our best to accept as many
as possible that's why all the all the
talks are short so we have 15 full talks
20 minute talks and 5 lightning talks in
the middle so as you will see this year
strands evolved I wrote a lot around
containers machine learning and
streaming a stream processing so in that
we've tried to somehow group the topics
together so in the beginning it's more
let's say related to HPC topics and then
gradually moving towards big data topics
through data science somehow like like
that so I hope you all enjoy you have an
exciting day I only have two requests
for you one is if there is an empty seat
next to you and you can squeeze so that
more people can see it please do and the
second is please use the feedback forums
on the website so if you go to the
schedule and you click on its stock then
underneath you will find a link where
you can give feedback so if you like the
talk or you didn't like the talk or if
there's any comments you want to leave
for us for next year or anything from
great job guys to
I don't know this didn't work at all
please let us know so we can improve
okay so any questions okay thank you
enjoy the day so