my first talk today is optimizing my
sequel felt sick or touching my dot CNF
and there is a reason why I called this
talk like that because it's a bit of
information about me I'm sweet for last
10 years and joined Dropbox as sre in
2015 but despite him working as a member
of storage team and I'm working on
metadata storage and touching my sickle
a lot I had known GBA experience
previously so I have no idea about how
to optimize or speed up Mexico a
modifying Mexico configuration and let's
look what is a Dropbox today
so Dropbox days actually is 500 million
users we have 200,000 business users and
the users are uploading 1.2 billion
files every day it's a quite big scale
we have tens of thousands servers where
we are located in multiple data centers
across multiple continents in multiple
countries and we're storing petabytes of
data and exabytes of raw data and that
leads to quite obvious problem that we
need to optimize our performance because
we want to say from the power we want to
say from the number of hardware we are
buying and we want to reduce latency
sets theorem so this talk is covering
optimizing my sequel and mostly we're
cover I'm covering how we are building
in Mexico and just rebuilding like is it
is it make sense to build Mexico in your
own infrastructure or is it just enough
to use vendor packages
and for every performance improvements
alright for every performance change
it's actually reasonable to use
benchmarks information marks were using
sis bench and this is example for
configuration we're using for running
sis bench so we're running several tests
of different number of threats and
number of races variable in this
particular test we reason number of
threats from 1 to 60 for each test was
running for 5 minutes for testing
compute it's enough to run on 5 minutes
so we're just using standard law LTP
read write test from C's bench and for
this particular test reason master
branch and this is quite fresh check out
of C's bench
sergeant stand there would be a this
bench talk later this day so just we're
creating 16 tables each table contains 1
million rows so these are testing
subjects
this is examples of hardware not exactly
hardware but systems worth testing on
we're historically work for quite long
time on Ubuntu 12 hour and we still in
the process of migrating to Ubuntu 1604
and both systems have different kernels
we are currently running 3.16 on 1204
and 4.8 on 1604 there's a different set
of compilers available on each platform
on 1204 these are just EC 4.6 4.9
incline 3.0 which are pretty old by this
time and 1604 these are GCC for point
nine which is just back ported for
Becker's compatibility to 1604 see five
point four and rank three point eight so
both machines are running this specific
CPU and both machines are completely the
same in terms of hardware so speaking
little bit about built infrastructure
Dropbox we use basil as an our build
system and basil is tightly integrated
and our build system but my Seco uses
CMake as a build system and basil is not
compatible to open source software and
if you're trying to build something of
based on integrate something to your
basil build is it auto tools based or
cement based or any other build system
you're literally screwed and we need to
do the same or maybe we were going to
open source that we actually did we
actually wrote C make two basil
converter tool which actually helps us
to integrate into basil build its
section of that part to write that
actually did that during one night so
important stuff before running any
benchmarks and actually made this
mistake another one of these machines
and thanks to boon to developers
starting from 1 to 1604 cpu frac scaling
governor set to Power Save and your CPU
is justin power safe mode
so don't forget to set CPU frac
performance governor and let's start so
what we are going to optimize is
optimize my sequel just rebuilding it
and one of advanced compiler techniques
is profile guided optimizations and what
is the profile guided optimizations
you're literally very building building
special build of your binary which
starts collecting training data and then
when you have enough collect enough
training data you're rebuilding your
binary again and it optimizes branches
use better branch prediction it
relocates code paths it has better
inlining because it actually no
statistics on how the code is used so it
usually requires to rebuild but not in
the same not not in every case in case
of clank and as far as instant thanks to
google clan can use perth data so you
don't need to rebuild you can just
collect birth data and build using pair
data which is a bit easier so a common
mistake collection profile data from
unit tests don't do that because union
tests usually are checking corner cases
and you don't want to optimize for
corner cases
so literally your code would be fast on
some corner cases like RIT are an
exception but not in any other case and
let's see how we're building with GCC so
to build a profile guided optimization
built with GCC we have two flags one of
them is to enable profile data
collection F profile generate there's
another variety of this flag which
allows you to set the output year where
you want to write or file data and
second flag is F profile use it actually
when you're booting your binary it uses
profile data and in case of mexico
mexico it doesn't work and it doesn't
work because Mexico is multi-threaded
application and profile data would have
incorrect counters and in order to fix
that
we need to use F profile correction
which would tell GCC just try to fix
counters for us and bad news for Ubuntu
6:12 for users it doesn't work with GCC
4.6 and 4.9 and flags are working but
pgo doesn't work for my sequel and yeah
that's that's about GCC so another
compiler we have in distribution is
clank-clank is they set up a bit
different that has a little bit
different set of flags and it's F
profile generated but before they
introduced
comment line are back compatibility of
GCC it was called to be different it was
called profile instruct generate and
there is a interesting languages F
profile sample use which is exactly the
flag I mentioned to use their data so
bad news again for Ubuntu 1204 users no
Pedro support and Clint 3-0 at all at
all
so we rebuilt my sickle with the jaw and
we ran tests with this bench and we did
several passes so we don't have any
rotation Center or test and here results
for 200 I didn't know how the colors are
looking here but I can I can tell what's
there so we have Glenn 3-0 is a winner
it produces binary of highest throughput
and throughput is something about 10%
more on using building of Clank and then
building a GCC but in the same time both
GCC and clang Kira which old but if you
stuck with TOEFL for and you should not
do that because TOEFL for LTS ends this
April it could be in good choice to just
rebuilt going 3.0 and get like 10%
performance improvement
and here our response to n looks and it
is the same so the lower is better and
gland produces lower latency by nurse as
well which is which is good so that
slide is more interesting here we have
these bench results for 1604 builds and
on 16 are for we're actually able to use
PTO and there is a bit interesting and
we haven't found out why but GCC 55.4
produces really bad results maybe
something's broken of our compiler and
not not the problem GCC but of our built
infrastructure but we decided just to
include that to be honest and GCC 5.4
with PTO produces pretty good results
it's generally 20% faster than just GCC
5.4 and you can achieve that just just
rebuilding your Mexico binary isn't good
job and any every other compiler is a
little bit slower but just using PTO you
can achieve 20% performance improvement
and gear latencies so looking at it
lower the lower part is GCC if I went
for the job built for that test we did
not write Clank
be job builds so we don't have Clank
data here yet but it will be interesting
to compare client B Joe built versus GCC
with Joe built but licensor latencies
also something like 20% lower for each
or builds
so this is one of interest in
optimization techniques when you are not
just you're not touching bicycle
configuration at all and you're speeding
up your Mexico
another interesting advanced compiler
optimization technique is link time
optimizations also known as full program
optimization and it is supported by both
modern GCC and clang but my secure code
base Mexico code base is not healthy all
compatible top and a little bit what is
the LG o until is when compiler instead
of producing object code in compilation
units it produces intermediate
representation and linker does actual
compilation and optimizations so you're
postponing actual optimization to the
link stage and linking the linker sees
all object files and knows how how to in
line like it can inline code from other
object files which is not available with
all tells you and but actually it's easy
to fix in code base and we're going to
start working on that pretty soon so
we're going to send patches for that and
it would be interesting to see out your
results on other projects we're using we
saw something or something about like
five percent performance improvement so
which is also interesting and so that's
basically it what we accomplished by
this time with optimizations we we have
like 20 percent performance improvement
just rebuilt in Mexico and we have
actually more ideas what we want to do
next we're working on because we were
using this bench as a training data for
B jaw
we're testing with this bench again we
actually point to start using aerial war
Canyon data and for that we are going to
start we actually started contributing
token of playback and we're going to
just play back the real reduction
traffic we have in order to optimize our
builds for production and another
interesting thing that it's leads to
interesting question that we don't have
only one single database we have many
databases and workload profiles are
different and we we haven't decided what
to do here because it would be
interesting to build to have some some
generic training data we can use some
every production database so another
interesting option is building with M
our native I have missed out there so it
it allows compiler to use latest
extensions like a VX or a x2 and usually
it just uses some generic compiler set a
compiler spew instruction set but the
that you can also achieve like free for
sense of performance boost and another
interesting thing that when we are
running my second production we're
usually usually running one single
instance multi-threaded instance on
single machine but we actually see in
birth data cqp i interface and usually
when you have multi-core machines you
have usually you have two slots and CPUs
if one CPU want to access the memory and
from another cpu slot you use this keep
a link and it actually slower than using
local memory not significantly slower
but still we see like three four percent
here and another option we we probably
would run to Mexico instances to
are some single hardware machine and
each amount of Numa CTL to each slot and
to each memory slot so that's that's it
questions
[Music]
so could you repeat the question yeah
could you repeat the question
do we have some public Debian package of
oh so yeah like as I said we are not
using that meant packages for our built
infrastructure where isn't it with basil
so we're unfortunately we're not we're
not building that packages
so yeah it so the question is how pgo
works so Joe built collects data on
branch uses and it writes that into the
ccda files in case of GCC and using that
statistics it just writes its statistics
it can understand which branch branch
branches are curved earlier which are
not yes yes it's exactly what it's about
right an object called
without
so we are collecting basic events I can
yeah I don't recall correctly what is
the size of data we have but we're also
running an a table on the machines yeah
okay yeah thank you
so Maxima be around and so if you have
questions just take him go outside and
ask them so many question pave a beer
and it will speak for a full day right