so right I think I should start hi my
name is Sebastian Mueller I'm a student
at Kait in cars for Germany
you
analysis it's also about automated
signal analysis automated signal
reception or if you want to call it that
way
signal intelligence and what first of
all reasons for doing that stuff so
first off you may want to do spectrum
monitoring for example in Germany
there's the fundus nets a contour which
has to make sure there's no misuse of
the spectrum and that everyone stays in
their pens and for this purpose they
need to identify where signals are and
what signals are or where they belong to
second it's super cool if you can
explore real world signals especially
when you're a beginner so for example if
you want to have a look at an LTE signal
and have a look at the frame and where
are the pilots and so on it's very hard
to do that if you are not like an expert
in that topic so it would be very cool
if everything can be automated and then
beginners can figure out why signals
work and why are the parameters chosen
that way and yeah why they maybe
wouldn't work otherwise also you can do
live modulation simplest example would
be if you want to listen to a local
radio station you you're actually doing
live demodulation and you can do batch
processing of several signals so you
don't have to look at one signal because
everything is happening in the
background automated there can be
several signal chains that deal each
with one signal so okay what what do we
have to do if we want to receive unknown
signals first off we have to detect them
so the question is where is the signal
located in the spectrum and what's it
bent with if we have done that we need
to mix it down into complex baseband and
then we would do something like filter
decimated yeah two to two
able to handle the amount of samples and
next you you would start like an
iterative cycle of analysis and then
yeah you're doing step two the
modulation then analyze again some
parameters and so on and if you did that
some some time you will be able to
delete a signal and if it's encrypted
you also have to decrypt it so these are
all the tasks that are possible so what
was - workflow before this is like I did
it maybe you you have you have it
smarter than me but I did something like
this so first off there is a USRP source
so I just received the signal and
chopped it in a queue teasing or
frequency thing so I just had to look at
a spectrum and look and search where as
energy located because normally energy
means there could be a signal if I found
what I have been looking for I would
yeah assume or estimate by thumb the
center frequency and the bandwidth and I
would try to remember that and chop in
the next block which would be the
frequency translating FIF filter this
block does everything including the the
down mixing the decimation and the
filtering and the basement so I would
enter my parameters here which I found
out while looking at the sink the
frequency sink and I would just try to
sample as a way to a file then I would
do some analysis which I have done in
MATLAB I have to admit and for example
there are other tools like Python Skype
high or in spectrum and yeah I would I
would try to estimate all the parameters
that would be necessary to finally do
modulator signal and for the emulation I
would use can radio or other tools like
MATLAB or
whatever there is your name it so what
this flow graph is not that cool why is
it not that cool first off you have
often to stop in a Chester flow craft
like you have to start it have a look
estimate some things stop it again
shopping and more blocks and then fire
it up again and yeah I'll do this all in
a in a cycle you would often or I at
least would often try to estimate by
thump all the parameters like okay this
could be two point four five gigahertz I
don't know and hope that it will work
out and yeah it's not not possible to do
any real time analysis with this because
you always have to stop the flow craft
so you you need much expertise to
perform these steps and it's not
possible for a beginner like a one-click
solution so you have to really know what
you are doing if you get tried it that
way so and this is exactly where the
inspector comes in and it tries to make
these tasks I just mentioned more easy
and I will now go through the components
or the plugs of ER inspector and tell
you what they can do so first off we
talked about detection and if you want
to detect the signal normally we do
energy detection like okay we assume
when there's energy in the spectrum
there could be a signal and this block
can do this for one or more signals and
it works either by setting a threshold
with the block parameter or there's also
an automatic algorithm that tries to
find power chums in the PSTN and
interprets them as signal edges
there's also functionality to suppress
narrow signals which which helps to
avoid false detections
and the output of this blog is first the
estimated PSD of the input signal and
the second one as you see this is a
message port it passes the information
about the center frequency and the
bandwidth of the detected signals so
next what you would do is you want to
visualize what you have estimated so
there's the QT greasing for that and it
just takes the estimated PSD from the
plug before and plot that in a cootie
window also it takes the pant Worth's
and center of center frequencies of the
detected signals and marks them with H's
yeah and next to to the markers of each
signal they're also the properties
plotted like Center frequency and
bandwidth and there can also be more
parameters that I will show on the next
slide and this block also enables manual
selection so if the automatic signal
detection messes up because you have a
bad SNR for instance you can you can do
a track and job selection here and this
is a screenshot of how the the GUI looks
like so what you see here are three
signals in the spectrum and as you see
the one on the left and the one on the
riot they just have their center
frequency and bandwidth plotted next to
them the one in the middle has more text
so what's up there I don't know if you
can read it and in the back line so this
is an OFDM signal and there it's an
analysis block that feeds the results
back through this group lock and the the
results get appended to the text printed
next to the markers so what we can reach
here is the center frequency the
bandwidth but also of the mo of the M
specific parameters like subcarrier
spacing number of subcarriers cyclic
prefix length
so now when we have detected the signals
that we want to use we have to do the
down mixing and decimation and filtering
and this is exactly what the signal
separator block does it calculates an
FIA filter for every detected signal and
applies that in complex baseband or you
can provide a chase and file with pre
calculated tabs so to save CPU usage
during runtime the output is a bit
complex here so as you see it's again a
message port and its format is like
first of a header that contains the
signal information like signal number
center frequency and bandwidth and then
what follows are the complex samples of
the signal now if we want to protect
process the signal further we have a
problem because there are nearly no
blocks that would take my my message
format here that I chose so there is the
signal extractor what it does is just it
extracts the complex samples of one
signal out of this message and passes
them again as complex stream as most new
regio blocks takes complex stream
samples yeah right yeah and also the the
sample rate of a signal is not known
during runtime because it tries to
sample following Nyquist criteria so
there is it depends on the bandwidth of
the signal
what's the sampling rate of the of the
signal after the signal separator and
there are applications where you need to
know your sample rate exactly and
therefore this block also has the
possibility to resample the signal to a
well-defined
sampling rate so the the second bigger
topic I dealt with is OFDM and there I
tried to
Ryden of the MSD major parameter
estimation we have seen the result of
this blog earlier in the in the GUI
screenshot and what it does it estimates
the subcarrier spacing the symbol time
subcarrier number and cyclic prefix
length of an OFDM signal and yeah as I
said the results can be fed back to the
Qt GUI inspector sync and will be
plotted next to the signal also there's
an OFDM synchronization block this is a
surprise it performs a frequency and
timing synchronization for of the EM
signals and we have also some modulation
classification ability this was not done
by me but by Christopher Richardson who
was a Summer of Code and space student
last year and he dealt with yeah
automatic modulation classification
using tensor flow so and now the cows
has demo time so what I want to do now
is show you a typical cheer inspector
flow graph where we try to listen to a
local radio station so I have my us F P
right here and these are just blocks I
just introduced to you so here's the
user P source to talk to my user P here
this can be exchanged by any other
source that provides a signal and then
here's the signal detector the the GUI
inspector sink and the results from here
will be fed back to the signal separator
where all the mixing and down sampling
and filtering will be performed since
we're only listening to one signal we
will extract it here and pass it samples
as a complex stream and what follows
then is just a basic FM demodulation
chain so this thing right here is
completely ignore a do so this was here
before and this box down here this is
all cheer and
spectrum so let's fire it up okay it's
flashing my FPGA so I maybe should have
done this before it should only take a
few seconds okay
so now we see here
actually now I have enabled manual
detection because I assume the the SNR
in here is too bad to do anything
automatic as you see it's pretty noisy
so we have one signal here and I already
have seen at 100 megahertz there is a
local radio station here in prison so
you can try to listen to that and I
don't think it's it's quite good printed
on the Beamer there our signal access
right here and right here and I can drag
and drop them to adjust the bandwidth of
the signal so let's try this
there's some kind of sweet spot for the
bandwidth let me add some more gain
okay only noise oh no okay I didn't
think the s and I would be too bad here
because at my place at work so let's try
this one more time
yeah I don't know what we can try that
down no so I don't know maybe you can
hear the bid there's some music in the
background but it's super noisy okay a
pity
yeah you can hear there's some music
maybe okay okay for the audience and the
scene yeah so okay yeah and that's it
thank you for your attention
and yeah we had it earlier about
participation and getting started and to
radio and I think google Summer of Code
is the super thing to to get started
with like I did okay any questions
Martin yes yes I think okay I know what
you what you want to point out so yeah
at my university we had the I Triple E
signal intelligence challenge and which
Martin did bring to life and it's all
about detecting signals in a in a known
band but you don't know anything about
them so you have to do the things I just
mentioned like detects error
as I said started with MATLAB and and in
spectrum and such things and yeah that's
that's what got me into this this kind
of topic and that's why I also applied
for ji-suk last year right yeah yeah
yeah it's so basically this just an
algorithm implemented there from a
published paper and let me think if I
can recall what it really does so yeah
right it's cyclo stationary features and
[Music]
if you if you do a fixed length
correlation over the time signal you can
find out the be used use symbol time I
think and then you can do the cyclo
stationary analysis so in frequency
domain and in time shift domain to to
find the the cyclic prefix length yeah
so it's just to peek searches in these
two directions
concerning which which the OFDM it's
it's a number of samples that you have
to capture and it's it's about I think
in the in the area of 7,000 samples
right yeah right if she has an arrow
spared estimation will be better so and
of course yeah yeah but I have tested it
and below 7000 samples there are no
reliable results available okay
and I think that's it thank you
[Applause]