okay well
we're going to get started could
somebody in the back please close that
door please so we have more quiet thank
you I am working to get my one slide up
so that I can have the names of the
panelists in front of you here today
we're going to have a a panel on
European legal entities for free
software projects a lot has been
happening in this space and particularly
in this past year and so what we'd like
to do is give you an opportunity to meet
some new organizations and hear from
them what I propose we do is give each
panelist of just a five minute
introduction or a brief introduction to
their organization I'll ask one or two
questions and then we'll open it up to
the audience for questions
oh well finally I have my my slide with
the names on it in fact is this the one
that okay well let's that way you can at
least see thanks first of all slamming
tips hello good afternoon and welcome
from all of us I'm up first because I
managed to get to the starting line
first out of the the three of at this
end of the panel here over the last few
years it's become increasingly obvious
that it's important to have
organizations who will look after the
administrative and legal duties of
growing communities of free and
open-source software and so we've seen a
growth of demand from organizations that
do this organizations like the software
freedom Conservancy organizations like
Apache Fit Software Foundation and there
seems to be an infinite amount of demand
and I realized about two years ago that
all of the organizations that did
general
purpose fiduciary hosting were based in
America and as somebody who's also
involved in digital civil liberties that
alarmed me because I felt that I don't
necessarily want all of the assets of
projects I'm working on to be under US
law because you never know what might
happen in the United States thank you
[Laughter]
I'm coming on to that so I started
throwing the idea around talking about
there being a year European fiduciary
host now by fiduciary fiduciary is an
English word that means to do with good
faith and so fiduciary hosting means
looking after all the things that are
done in good faith to meet legal and
good governance requirements and so I
started thinking about how one would
create a fiduciary host in the UK I did
some research I found out in the UK
about a thing called a Community
Interest Company which is a
not-for-profit but not charity
organization and I decided I would start
a fiduciary umbrella in the UK to serve
Europe at the same time as I was doing
this moritz was doing the same thing and
Michiel was doing the same thing and we
hadn't bought that we all know each
other we'd forgotten to mention it to
each other and so we've all three gone
ahead and created organizations they are
they are quite different from each other
in character so public software is a
term that I didn't actually coin it I've
not found out who coined the term public
software public software is a term to
avoid the need to decide whether you're
going to say open source or free
software and it means software that has
got the software freedom included inside
it and so software freedom is the the
baseline of what public software does we
are a community interest company that
means
we are able to engage in trading and
commercial activity but we are not
allowed to use the proceeds of that
commercial activity for anything other
than the service of the public community
we've declared we will serve and the
public community we've declared we will
serve is those people who are the users
and creators of public software and so
we we have the same constraints on us as
would be on a charity but we don't have
the ability to recover tax benefits and
that's probably the largest difference
between us and everybody else I don't
really believe that matters because I've
tried making donations across Europe to
other organizations and the cost of
recovering the tax getting the tax
benefit is has always been larger than
the tax benefit because the process that
you have to engage in is always a heavy
bureaucratic process so while in Europe
we do have an environment where
theoretically you can make
tax-deductible donations across borders
in reality for most country pairs that
is not practical and because of that I
believe that the the recovery of tax
benefit is a very marginal benefit for
an organization providing fiduciary
hosting in Europe now when larger sums
of money are involved such as the ones
that that Moritz is working with I think
there is a case to be made about getting
tax-deductible donations so public
software started in February last year
we have one project working with us now
a project called travel spirit travel
spirit is a community of quite diverse
community of individuals and companies
working on mobility as a service
software that's the idea of creating
open source frameworks for running
things like uber at a city level
probably through a public transit
authority rather than through a
predatory private corporation and so
that project is going fairly well that's
been going for nearly a year now and is
doing doing ok so public software now
we're based in the
okay.i I hadn't anticipated there will
be any problem with being based in the
UK a European organisation and and then
you know you know how bad things can
happen to countries sometimes well
unfortunately we have very very
gentlemanly and refined fascists in the
UK and they've they've managed to
persuade the country to vote to to be
unfriendly to the rest of Europe and so
that complicates public software and our
queue of people wanting to join has
become much much much reduced we've
discovered oh that's all very much to
the advantage of the gentleman over to
my right who was next I think you were
next when you Lawrence Oh Mickey I was
the next so oh so am i audible so I come
from assignment as is a well-known open
source VIP I come from from a far lesser
known region I work for a small charity
called an illness foundation we twenty
years ago in actually thirty years ago
an illness sort of came into life by a
group of Unix engineers that announced
the EU net and an L net was a Dutch part
of that it grew grew grew ten years
later seven years later that became a
separate foundation it was a sort of a
network for that a grassroots network
across Europe that grew into a basically
European Internet in 1997 everything was
sold and all the money went into a trust
fund and that's where it that's what the
story starts because we started giving
out money to all these projects hundreds
of projects that are doing all kinds of
cool open source stuff and over the
years we just watched people suffer and
suffer and we met many people that
wanted to do stuff about it we saw I
mean we worked with with many people in
the field and as time grew we wanted to
find a solution to the problem that when
you get a bunch of really good engineers
and
they create something cool and then they
become so successful that you send them
to lawyers and that is just a very
painful thing for them to live through
and then yeah give them money and they
have to to get a community to build the
community by the way it's interesting is
that we're programmed against the
community track I I think I feel more at
home in the community track than in the
legal track because I'm not a lawyer but
I this is for us is this how do we build
communities and so the idea was let's
take the whole burden out of the whole
pressure out of getting organized
because we are as an element we are a
charity we can receive money we can pay
money there's a huge tax benefit to
being paid by a charity at least in some
countries there's no income tax on that
so you get a pretty nice in some cases
half of your wages suddenly become
tax-free that is a pretty attractive
benefit but as a charity we're a
professional manager of funds people can
give us money and we can professionally
manage those there's oversight and we've
seen so many small foundations where a
couple of willing people are able to do
this sustained this for a couple of
years but the 75 years of copyright
after the death of the last remaining
code author is nowhere near to be seen
in any of the foundations that we see so
we thought why don't we create a vehicle
to end all vehicles so we named our
project this is a funny name as a
hypervisor for free software foundations
so what we what we do is we we give
people sort of their own environment but
instead of putting the money into that
environment we ask people to just just
like a squirrel put out the nuts
everywhere they can for instance at an
illness foundation or any other place
and all that we do were illegal Dropbox
in a way people can put their code under
copyrights and their assets in a safe
place knowing that it is community
governed and that it will always be that
way so it's a there's a zero
[Music]
we don't we cannot make profits because
we actually promised to not have a
single euro ever in our foundation so we
are completely separate ethereal only
intangible assets and our dream is to
completely automate things so that
people can just put stay safe stuff in
inside our foundation have programs that
manage these so the the virtual
organizations can exist and there's a
mechanism for people to decide on on
creating yet another license on top of
their code or changing names or for king
or whatever but there's no reason for
them to to go to and spend a lot of
money dude do three monthly tax payments
even though there's no money inside you
still have to file these things so
basically our idea is to simplify and
automate that and we've we've gone for a
very promiscuous model but we don't
impose stuff because anybody it's just
like getting children anybody can get a
child than anybody can start a
foundation they can buddy well do what
they want so we're not gonna sit on
anybody's chair and make them do
anything we will just hand them best
practices what we feel are best
practices and they can sort of ask us
for rational sane templates of doing
things and those are then just like
virtual machines you can create virtual
organisations any way any shape flavor
model that you want yeah I think that's
enough for now and we'll get to the real
news maybe later
hello I'm Moritz I was active in the
kind of free software space mostly in
the Internet
what's the so-called Internet freedom
space and in 2013 I joined a foundation
called the Renewable Freedom Foundation
it's a charity in Germany and the
mission of the Renewable Freedom
Foundation is just to strengthen and
defend civil liberties in the digital
space so I began in 2013 together with
people at the foundation to
come up with a concept of what the
foundation would actually be doing it
was set up in 2012 by a Bavarian
newspaper publisher so he set aside some
of the money that he's been making we
are not officially affiliated with the
newspaper we are sort of affiliated with
the founder the current publisher the
publisher of that newspaper and in 2014
I took the guy who was back then running
the foundation to roughly 40 events to
introduce him to many projects different
communities in in the space of
opendata New Journalism kind of
whistleblowing
and of course the whole space of
technology that I was familiar with and
over time we the foundation is it was
meant to give out funds so quite similar
to a Nelnet but on a smaller scale and
we kind of positioned ourselves as an
intermediary so what I noticed very
quickly that there's a lot of funding
potentially flooding into the Internet
freedom space and that it can be quite
damaging if you don't if you don't
handle it the right way if you're naive
and you take that money you're going to
end up with a broken project and the
broken community so my my stance always
was that we have to address this we a
lot of people and a lot of projects that
I talked to they want money they want to
grow and think that money can be an a
enabler for that I am very skeptical
about about money in the space of these
these very enthusiasm driven efforts in
in the human rights space but of course
I it there's a valid point in saying
that you have to have something to eat
you have to have have some kind of
stability in your life that you can you
can continue doing what you what you
want to do so in being a funder you can
interact with other foundations that do
grants and I help people write their
grant applications
I was able to kind of explore the space
of potential funders that fund whether
human rights angle so I participate in a
lot of human rights conferences where
the digital does not play a big role not
as big as it will become in that space
because of all the stuff that is
happening there with targeted malware
attacks against activists journalists
surveillance and and all these these
topics and I build bridges between a lot
of different communities and so most of
what I do is just listen to whether
people are what their problems are and
and to see who I can point them to or
how I can help them with their current
efforts and at the same time since we've
been handing out a bit of money it's I
that the problem is for that for that
problem when you when you have money as
how to how to make sure the team
understands how they will do things
sometimes it's very organically that the
founder of a project would start a
foundation or some legal entity or he
already has a for-profit that that he
starts using and there's never the point
where you make very conscious decisions
about who is in control of the assets of
the projects and who is in control of
like the financial assets and I think
the the major benefit that I see for for
a for a fiduciary sponsor is that the
the moment you you join a fiduciary
sponsor there's certain things where you
we should make clear agreements and this
is the point of realization within the
community of around the project of what
their needs are and how to protect those
those needs and the communities and that
led me to I can host some things at the
foundation but it's not that
straightforward so we have been hosting
a couple of bank accounts for some
projects to hold some of the funding and
in March we started creating like
developing this the Center for the
cultivation of Technology
we registered in October so it's a
really recent development we we are now
organizationally ready in the kind of in
the legal sense to be active our legal
form is we are based in Germany with the
company the company is fully owned by
the foundation which is a charity but
the company itself is also a charity but
it's a it's it's a limited liability
company it's a gmbh in germany with the
charity status so it's a combined with
sig again bihar it can do for-profit
activities so when projects want to
engage in minor for-profit activities
that's possible and I'm mostly focusing
on on projects in a stage where the they
they they've been successful they they
are around they have they have a sort of
community maybe of the community of one
developer that is fairly common and they
need a legal entity for some specific
thing like a grant that is being offered
or people coming they want to donate
they want to contribute 10 euros the
project is not going to actually benefit
from the 10 euros that much but if
there's some bank account somewhere
where there's little complexity they can
fill it up and use it for hackathons or
for a bit of travel so a very light
involvement and on the other hand all
the projects in the Internet freedom
space where there is this NGO ization
there is this movement to getting
funding and actually the first project
that I I didn't even like ahead on on a
mental map we're now the first project
that we're taking on is a European
Commission funded consortium and we are
one of the partner organizations in that
consortium and I think that's a very
good example because they they expect to
be a limited liability company they want
usually consortium like university
partners and some for profits and the
traditional for profits that are part of
these Risha research efforts
usually file patents do do some
proprietary stuff that never sees the
light of day because it's just to get
the money out of the European Commission
funding flow and we feel the need there
because we can add we can we will be
responsible for a work package that
integrates the research into open source
and into an existing open source
application so my focus I think the very
much complementary I think it's perfect
that you exist and you you you you
alright let's talk about just one one
last point is that we we want to get the
financial stuff right we want to make it
easy that people can see how much money
they have in their accounts do some
budgeting bookkeeping make it very easy
to interface give us receipts and invent
something that is scalable across many
projects and that can be used in varied
various different entities to handle the
management of of 50 projects or whatever
in in a nonprofit environment so that's
our focus and we need the work that
makiel is doing at the Commons
Conservancy because he's detailing out
all the decisions that the projects have
to make before they reach the point
where they can come to us and say okay
give us a bank account
okay I think I'm gonna troll this panel
a little bit okay okay so some wait so
hi I'm Karen Sandler I'm the executive
director of the software freedom
Conservancy in some ways we are the
oldest and newest organization on this
panel because we are a us-based
organization and being the software
freedom Conservancy but we're also
ramping up a Conservancy France so
software freedom Conservancy as a as the
u.s. organization has been around for a
while and has been active in Europe and
the UK for quite quite a while and you
know we've held assets in Europe and
done quite a number of things in Europe
and of course the participants of our of
our projects are global and I totally
agree with what s'en said before that
there's so much room for a lot of
different organizations but I think my
biggest role of this panel is to say
that I'm so glad that we've made it look
so exciting and fun that wants to do it
too but so and then I would say that
that that these problems are hard and
many of the the things that that you're
hearing are true of our organization too
we we have are the home of over 40 free
and open-source software projects
including get samba wine Inkscape
selenium PHP myadmin the list goes on
brew network stream owner I I'm always
told by my colleague Bradley that I
should not try to listen them because
then I'll just keep keep going and it's
hard to choose we're also the home of
rhe which is a diversity program for
women and other underrepresented people
in freeing up and source software and
participants are global there was one
round we do about like 90 interns per
year who come through our program and
there was at least one round where there
was one intern from each habitable
continent so a truly global program and
and we also are known for being the one
of our member project is the
coalition of kernel developers that
asked us to enforce their copyrights and
we have funded the lawsuit of Krista
Helwig in Germany against VMware so so
as you can see we are active globally
and the way it works with Conservancy is
that when a project applies to
Conservancy they become a part of our
organization we are their nonprofit
identity they are analogous to a like a
division of a corporation and part of
that arm boarding process and come in is
is some of the like virtualization ideas
of organization so when organizations
when people offer our projects and
communities join us we help them figure
out how their governance exists and
instead of having to form their own
organization they kind of they they form
a virtual organization within us where
they don't need to file a particular
form of organization with three members
on the board or whatever the the
particular laws are instead they can run
the project however it works for them
and within our remember projects that's
totally different from project project
some projects have big communities where
they run elections and some of our
projects just have a small committee of
five people who are three people who
always make their decisions by consensus
and we basically can tailor it project
by project so that's really really handy
we also I guess the bad news for
everybody here and I think everybody
here already knows it is that this is
really tough work and and not very
hazing overt sexy but it's not glamorous
well thank you it's it's it's it's hard
work it's thankless work and and it's
very hard to fund and I would be remiss
if I didn't mention that we have a
matched donation now and so if you
donate to Conservancy just for this week
there it's matched so it counts two
times I'm so sorry
but we need to fundraise from the public
in order to subsidize the work that we
do for our projects but we taken money
in a number of different ways from
sources all over the world so we have
some grant funding that we take in
individual donations
also around the world we're looking at
wrapping up conservancy France because
there's some flexibility for handling a
there's not a lot of things that that we
found that that we wanted to do that we
couldn't do with our own organization
but we just have a few things that will
be a little bit easier one of the main
things that we're doing is is creating a
system for tracking assets and
accounting that that will create a free
and open-source software solution that
everyone can use and this is a challenge
that that a lot of free and open source
software organizations have experienced
in this space that it's just it's the
mass of transactions is just huge like
because one of the things that free
software projects want to use this these
entities for are sending people to
conferences and each person that goes to
a conference has all these receipts and
they have receipts for their flight and
receipts for their hotel you have to
track each one and you have to make sure
that everything is is handled properly
not just for whatever rules you might
have to follow depending on your
jurisdiction but also to make sure that
we have decent governance transparency
and make sure that the funds are being
used properly so it's just incredibly
hard work and we've been focusing our
entire operations around making this in
a solvable way that is transportable for
everyone that actually leads in the
mining might my question for the panel I
just said I'm only going to ask one
question and then I'll open it up to the
audience just because you know the time
is getting kind of short so I'll just
ask each the panels to this question
what checks and balances do you have in
place so that we can trust you with our
assets both tangible and intangible in
other words how do we avoid repeating
history of like let's say the talks
foundation X augur openoffice.org
[Music]
kick to you yes those are all very
different disasters you mentioned that
so public software we we are a limited
liability company and we have to
maintain accounts like any other limited
liability company we additionally have
to file an annual report with the
Commissioner of Community Interest
companies in the UK where we demonstrate
that we are continuing to serve our
declared community on top of that what
we're also so we've got we have one
project and it has quite a low
transaction rate because it isn't
generally sending people to conferences
at the moment so at the moment we have a
public an open ledger that anyone in the
project can see and that is available
for all of the participants not just the
formal participants who signed the
contract but any of the project
participants to look at and they can see
exactly what assets we hold we hold all
their domain names and their trademarks
for them and they're in the register and
then we also hold all of their funds and
we identify all of the deductions that
have taken place from their funding so
that it that is all transparent that I
would say that the the the main check is
that transparency and the main balance
is the fact that we have a public duty
which is inspected by the government so
at the Nelnet we we've been running sort
of this same thing internally for about
twenty years so we give away money to
people they ask for it and he asked for
it in small chunks and so people have
been sending us receipts over and over
again and so this is something that we
have a person handling professionally
all the time we every decision that is
made is is is made through specific
process where all the the whole
governance body is notified so if
somebody sends in a receipt then that
would be a decision that everybody knows
of so
and that's an internal that's internal
mailing list for each project it's we're
just starting and it we're not we're not
so we're not sending lots of people out
on trips as well so but the the and it
would be just before the program for
each program right so not for every
program to receive all the traffic of
other programs but just from the five
people three people working inside as a
project so that it's just it's an open
book so yeah and yeah our guarantee is
that when we focus more on the larger
say you want to do some somebody has to
build some really boring testing
infrastructure and and and he has to be
working on this for six months and the
community decides to pay up for that
particular bit they they apply for
grants with us and then the whole
process is handled like it would be more
more grant so we dude do you do all the
checks and balances for the project to
make sure that it's it's stable and then
the project is called saying this is
what we've arranged with that person or
that company or whatever so yeah we
first the the professional management is
really important and as regards to the
assets basically everything that's
donated to us is sent through again to
that to this decision mailing this
incoming traffic is just there's an
oversight and there's a stack of things
so that you can just always look at it's
a right only mechanism all our
legislation and so on it's like a not a
blockchain but a blockchain like idea
where you can only tack on new versions
of new things I mean in the like Simon
said these cases that you mentioned had
a lot of different circumstances and
different reasons but I think there's
things to say about transparency in many
different angles as well and I think
that transparency is mostly something
that the project should the project
community should decide what kind of
level of transparency they want within a
guiding framework that helps them to
make useful good decisions that avoid
conflict in the future
and I think all these examples are more
problem of bad governance models or bad
adoption of structures within those
communities rather than a question of
transparency in these cases cases that
you mentioned transparency wasn't the
issue
and I mean we are a limited liability
company in Germany there's some filing
public filings that you have to do as a
limited liability company there's public
filings in the sense of the of the
charity status so you have to file an
annual report and the difficulty we have
is that the stuff will happen in German
the the interactions with the government
entities will happen in German and we
will make some effort to translate that
so an annual report will be published in
English that is very near to the
requirements of the German government
and I've been suggesting that we use the
formula 90 that is used in the US as a
template of something that we don't file
anywhere because we're not under the
jurisdiction but I think for anyone
who's familiar with the 501 C 3 s can
then look at because basically their
numbers and the details and the
narratives in the 990 are close to what
we have to file anyway so why not use
the form and produce something that is
very similar to that so that's that's a
but the minor thing about transparency
in some sense but I don't want to speak
for the projects that use us for example
the European Commission funding there is
si P in the consortium they have some
non-disclosure stuff happening they do
some proprietary stuff that we're not
even concerned about so we will have to
find the right balance there cut out the
stuff that but that's kind of the
decision in the consortium and the
decision that we have to make as far how
far do we want to go but we're not there
yet so I cannot really comment much on
that I have to say that's so exciting
that you're I'm so surprised and excited
to hear that you're thinking of using
990 as a template for information
elsewhere because we've been working on
nonprofit accounting
towards having just the accounting
system generate the 990 so if that's
useful in other places that's even
better like it's just that there's like
simple manipulation
of assets that you can you can script
and so it should be easy to fake form 99
you're not something that takes weeks
and weeks so so we're working towards
that for us for transfer as far as
oversight and assurance that we're doing
what we should be doing we have multiple
levels of that we have an evaluations
committee that evaluates that projects
that come in to Conservancy are a good
fit for Conservancy and they meet our
standards then we have an intake process
where each project is helped with their
governance and like marts was saying we
tell our all of these things for the
projects they may decide to do different
things but they all have to meet a
certain standard and we have to be sure
that there's not going to be any undue
influence by any one company or or some
other kind of control that we wouldn't
be comfortable with in a free software
project we have a board of directors
which oversees all of our work and we
have a charitable mission that we have
to be accountable for having an
organization like one of ours
participate with the free software
project means that there's a kind of an
outside party which means that when
there are kind of like inappropriate
things suggested that people tend to be
a little more sheepish and there's a
third party that that that somebody can
contact whistleblower considers say hey
you should look into that transaction
because I feel uncomfortable and it's
it's no problem at the same time when
you have problems that happen in some of
the examples that you mentioned where
you have like we don't have to worry as
much about not filing things or getting
things in time because we're doing it in
a consolidated way so all of that stuff
seems to really help ok well that that's
really great we have about five minutes
for questions so as Disney learned from
the audience have a question for the
panel
[Music]
to start so the backstory in 2011 I
started a non-profit and that grew into
a network of nonprofits which are 20
organizations in 14 countries and that's
how ever I became quite familiar with
the different structures the different
nonprofit laws different charity
approaches and that unfortunately that
it spread that I knew about these things
so many who have been coming to me since
then to help them create the
organizational structures look into the
bylaws stuff and things like that I
think for the rest we should take that
offline but like the I think an
important point here for me for me legal
entities are tools and they shouldn't
become something for me you're creating
an a living organization and it wants to
eat and it wants to grow and anytime you
create a legal entity you need to be
careful to not turn it around that you
become a tool of the legal entity but
that the tools stay within like and to
use them properly so the tools that are
available to me at the moment are like
nonprofit associations a company
foundation and things like that so I
flex ability to help others so happy to
take this offline
more one more thing on the previous
question which which you you sort of
when you said that you can't you need to
make sure that the organization is the
is the tool one of the things that
Conservancy does on that front is that
we have very strong termination for
visions so our projects can leave easily
and we've helped many of our projects
leave either to form their own
organization or to do something else and
I think that that's a really important
part of transparency but it's a really
important part of fighting the right
governance structure to add on that is
not just leaving it's also splitting
apart because I think there's a gilded
cage where you're in we're in a
foundation there's some money there are
some assets there and the guy that
leaves is the guy that has nothing or
the girl that leaves so people tend to
fight over assets and we've we've
designed we went out or away spent a lot
of time in designing procedures to
basically also fork an organization so
that you can part just to have separate
ways so that each and every one can just
continue to do what they're good at
rather than to fight for either all or
nothing so it was a comment that mihail
made about people who sign which leads
to this question which is to me I was
sort of intrigued by the the ambiguous
nature we talk so loosely about projects
but in reality there are people and so
how do you decide how do you identify
who has authority to speak for the
project and I think Karin when you say
governance like eventually you force
them to that point but sort of how do
you manage even are the people I'm
talking to the right people and is there
somebody else who should be included in
this conversation and what kind of what
kind of legal commitments or what kind
of who can make the commitment and what
kind of commitments can they make so
first we've put this into lists so
everything is handled by lists so the
book at intake we have a quartermaster
that appoints somebody appoints a group
of people to be the governing body and
whatever they call it it doesn't matter
but it's a mailing list and we only
accept messages that are CC to the
mailing list so when there's a contest
within we recommend 48 hours but it can
be longer there's a contest of any
decision that goes over that list it's
it becomes something that has to be
redone it was no contest we can we can
take action
and so when organizations join public
software they they sign a service
agreement with us and that the entity
that is signing that agreement is an
unincorporated association in in UK law
which is the form that's used for things
like Cub Scout troops and in to identify
that unincorporated association we name
the individuals who are considered to be
that association in the legal agreement
and we make clear in the legal agreement
who is entitled to to speak for that
group of people on what topics and then
we only accept instructions from the
named individual or individuals who are
named in that agreement to take the
tasks so for travel spirit there is one
individual who has to agree when no
matter who asks to to dispatch an asset
that name individual has to be copied
and has to agree and they have made a
commitment in our in our service
agreement that they will consult the
other named parties on the document so
we do it by explicitly naming an
authorizer and by explicitly making that
authorizer responsible for getting
consensus from the other parties US law
comes from UK law so we have a very
similar approach we Nate we have an
agreement and the template that's
families for a moment for many of our
agreements we try to be as transparent
as possible so you can look on our
website and see an example of it and we
we also name the individuals that come
in and that the part the agreement
establishes a governance procedure so
that those were the initial people and
then the there's like a more legal
effectuating body that transfers but
there's still this question that I think
Pam is getting at which is how do you
know you have the right people right how
do you know those are original names are
and it was something that we struggled
with a lot and so we belt-and-suspenders
it so what we do is we take the project
whoever it perches us at face value and
and explore the community we read the
mailing list we check to make sure that
the people who are are talking to us are
in fact involved with the project but
then we take it a step further and we we
post messages on every possible place
that we can think of that or like a
thought like authoritative places where
these people are participating and say
this agreement is being signed these are
the people that are being identified if
you have any questions or object please
review all this stuff please let us know
and so we're pretty we're very confident
in the end and then similarly we have a
representative that is identified who
can speak and then we know the the the
committee or whatever governance body
that will identify that new person going
forward there is about exception and do
you think that do you provide or provide
order provided or some kind of exception
in within a European counties that what
we are going to accelerate the
involvement for business which work with
us also make profitable open-source at
reception would be great great way to to
get involved but do it exists as a
Italia as an Italian business may donate
some money to some kind of association
formation and get back some exception so
we aren't aware of any mechanism that is
devoted to public software at the moment
and we've we have we've talked about
setting up for example reciprocal
arrangements where you where somebody
British could donate to public software
and Moritz would then pay money out in
Germany to the that was and deduct tax
there are actually already charitable
organizations across Europe that do
tax-deductible exchanges across Europe
but they're typically set up for large
donations so the costs that are with for
example in the UK there is there is an
organization that handles charitable
giving on payrolls so as if your company
offers to make a charitable donation on
your behalf as a salary deduction they
will then put the money into the hands
of the charity that's involved and the
fees that they charge for that are
scaled to the amount of money that they
think they're going to be transferring
and they are beyond the means of most
it's small donations for individuals
they are suitable for trusts that are
making grants but so it would be it
would be feasible for exam
two more for Moritz to make a grant a
tax-deductible grant into the UK of you
know the three thousand three thousand
euros but it wouldn't be feasible for me
to pay my fsfe fellows fee in Germany
because I tried to I actually tried
doing it and I found the fees that I got
charged directly more than the fsfe
fellow fee so I haven't done it again
okay I'm gonna have to think it really
very much for a pal thank our panelists
please
[Applause]