okay we good okay so we're gonna be
talking in my part of the talk at least
briefly just a quick introduction to
singularity which is the software that
I'm a developer on here's our website so
singularities developed as a container
solution for high performance scientific
computing as opposed to docker where
they mainly developed for industry
solutions they're kind of three main
reasons that we've been finding it
useful to have containers in scientific
computing one escaped dependency how
somebody having to you know go around
and manage everybody's versions of their
libraries for every single scientist
number two is that you can ensure that
your code is gonna work on your laptop
the same way that it's gonna work on the
cluster every time and that's a huge
benefit and a third also very important
kind of point for scientific computing
is we can take one file and we can send
it we can send it everywhere and you
know that's really great for repre doose
ability of your research you can take
that file send it to some other
supercomputer and have somebody verify
your results so I'm sure many people who
have worked on at HPC are familiar with
the scenario you know on the Left you're
working on your computer you run some
code and it works you send it over to
you know run on the HPC and all of a
sudden nothing works anymore so that's
what we developed singularity for so
singularity anything any user on the
cluster they can run a container without
any special privileges as opposed to
docker where they're kind of always
having a root level daemon running
singularity integrates right into an HPC
infrastructure so when you would
normally run whatever code that you've
built you can instead just run a
singularity container as an executable
but instead you're executing now
inside of a container singularities
portable between systems we allow you to
run your singularity container on
essentially any system that can support
singularity and we actually have users
that are running on you know incredibly
old kernels we don't require any new
features so you don't have to take use
of namespaces if you don't want to and
I'll run back on you know kernel to even
and then any user can bring any
container onto the HPC and so you don't
have to worry about screening a user's
container for malicious content you
don't have to worry about security
implications of people bringing any
container that they want to onto your
HPC system and that makes the job a lot
easier for administrators and IT
security people who are worried about
malicious code being run again here I
kind of reiterate the same points
something really important to note is
the concept that we have one single
image file and for you know scientific
work that's we found that's really
important one of the things that we
talked about in a paper that we
submitted for publishing about
singularity is the fact that we can now
use just an image file to distribute not
only the code that you've used to run
your experiments but also the
environment you use to run it in and
data that you used to generate and so
you can you know ensure that somebody
who wants to reproduce your results has
the means to do so so here's a list
incomplete list of some of the places
that have installed singularity there's
a couple places I think in the top 10
from the top 500 list like impede is on
their GSI which they're still working on
their cluster there so the basic usage
of singularity kind of falls into three
main parts for the work flow your first
part you're gonna be working you're
gonna create an image file so that's
usually done with pseudo singularity
image singularity create and you give it
a name and that creates a physical dot
IMG file on the disk and then the second
part is to bootstrap it and that's the
process of installing whatever software
you want on your image you know
configuring
inside the image your operating system
and then you're gonna run it and we can
run it in you know three separate ways
singularity shell just opens up an
interactive shell inside the container
singularity exec
will open up any executive or will
execute any file inside the container
that you want it to and then singularity
run is sort of a special command we can
on the bootstrapping process we can
actually generate a script inside the
container that will do anything you want
when you do singularity run and that's
actually what happens when you just
directly execute the image file is that
it will execute that run script and
allow you you know to just execute the
image as an executable so this is kind
of a just a small comparison in contrast
between a couple other container
solutions so as far as HPC goes
singularity fulfills what we had
determined were some very important
points and you can kind of see that
docker doesn't fulfill a lot of things
and stalker is is developed with a
totally different kind of goal in mind
and shifter and Charlie cloud are
similar to singularity and that they're
both developed also for HPC environments
however we do have some slight
differences between them and this is
just just an overview of a couple of the
commands and what we are able to run as
far as container formats and so now I'll
turn it over to you
okay what a full-size please so I would
normally to everyone I hope you enjoyed
last night I'm this guy sets our
government which is the guy that appears
in every on the website and every other
place had a medical issue his well I
don't mind on him
but we will have a little secret between
all of the room and me and this talk was
given by say sir
so if anyone asked you I'm say sir are
we talking about given the introduction
Michael gave a sensing variety I'll be
talking about a specific HPC use case
for a singularity for those of you that
hadn't work as systems of many as
administrator on a supercomputing Center
the real pain is done when one user
opens a ticket pushing you to upgrade
some kind of library it's a the hull
there's there's no worst thing than that
you have a very stable configuration
very well performant configuration and
the trickiest part of that is
maintaining it over time so as long as
you don't I upgrade anything everything
will be well so by the time you ask
someone to install this 1.0.0 p4 of
OpenSSL
because you need that for that Python
library that connects to any other place
you are totally screwing them up so
don't do please but given that we have
singularity to rescue us
I'll be talking about I will to be
talking about the creation of a portable
container because Michael did better
than me so I'll be talking about two use
cases for singularity in the HPC
environment one of them is having access
to InfiniBand interconnection and
actually using that and the other one is
having very expensive gpgpu cards
installed on the machines and actually
using them with the same software stack
you are used to in jury room - or in
your Debian laptop so well text is very
small because I didn't do the
presentation I'd do it very but it's
uploaded to the website one of my slaves
uploaded like five minutes ago so the
finishing files will be available to all
of you so you don't get blind by having
to look at this small text size in this
part are the basic comments of creating
a container do you select this as
parameter is important as you select the
size for the container you can have
container as big as you need because it
creates a dispersed file on the file
system so let's say you need 32
gigabytes but maybe you want to be using
them since the beginning of your
development you will create an actual 32
gigabyte file but it will be like maybe
200 megabyte um on the file system so it
can grow us as you're putting things
inside the container the bootstrap
definition is the secret sauce for
singularity it's all of all of the work
we singularity will belong in the
definition files it's where you have a
minimal set up of them of the language
distribution you are going to use within
the container and then you add as many
software as you need and as many stages
for
building the software or installing any
code you need to install inside the
container and one of the options is
expanding the container given you're
running out of space because you have to
download those Nvidia drivers that take
one gigabyte compressed and like five
uncompressed you will have to expand
your container the easiest definition
file is in this form the breakfasting
just specifies the bootstrap method you
are going to use it almost all of our
work has been done on John with center
ways or the bootstrap with Debian where
you want to you select the operating
system version and the mirror you are
going to download that there's a very
clever solution for that given you can
install a PT catcher ng thing the
Machine you are creating the containers
and you only download the RPM or DEP
files once and the container creation
will speed up over time on the running
script section it's you write the code
that will be executed when you call
singularity run or slash dot slash a
container name and in the post section
is the secret sauce part for your
reproducibility as Michael was talking
to us let's have a look at the example
these guys have been working in a blind
association in Spain so they do so tiny
text in order to push you to our
association of blind people we all have
to concentrate on this part we are
creating a bunch of directories for the
paths we are going to bind between
outside world given the machine and
insect world given the container so
let's say we have a parallel a very high
speed parallel file system for scratch
we can bind a
this scratch inside the container so
when our application running inside our
environment needs to write local files
per node they can be written in the
fanciest hardware available and if you
need to dump some of your partial
results in a shared file system you can
point them to a scratch file system that
is shared among the machines so it gives
you access to the actual enjoyable part
of running code on a supercomputer on a
supercomputer which is everything is
faster than interrupted and by this part
of the definition file you are
installing every dependence you are
going to need this step it is run on
your local machine so the root
privileges you're needing are more or
less granted or can be run inside a
virtual machine that you have stalled in
a machine you don't have root access
let's say for the run script you are
loading as many environment variables
you're going to need as possible so in
the case of the examples you are going
to it won't be there you are going to
use openmpi libraries with InfiniBand
with local InfiniBand drivers bind it to
the image and you are going to use the
openmpi version that sweets must your
code so you are not limited to the
openmpi version or internal MPI version
available at the supercomputing Center
given that we have almost magical
example as Gregg told us yesterday of
what can be wrong with containers this
is actual coding and Spanish super
computer
this is native code it's a longing Saval
you it's the same code run inside a
saint always singularity container and
the same honor you want to singularity
container as you can see there's our
improvement only by objecting the
version of the operating system on the
other hand if you follow the path of
center weighs 7.3 within singularity
you're not going to have so much
bandwidth and the scale doesn't make
sense because there's no such difference
between the parts but the general idea
is a container is performing better than
negative code for this specific use case
in terms of bandwidth a container is
performing almost equal that native code
within the cluster now this is the setup
for the benchmarks will be uploaded with
the with the presentation to the webpage
another example of trying to make you
blind as you as you cannot see how I
will tell we are installing a DQ'd
abrasion we are going to need within the
container and the only thing we have to
have is the driver available at the
external file system given it can be
loaded as a model to the kernel we can
run this code with the libraries we are
needing and we can take the advantage of
having a very powerful DP GPU card in
the in the host and we have all all of
our stock values to outside the host
so another example this time is with
China it will be hard if you thought the
other slides were the difficult ones
this it's Pablo's fault now we are the
bootstrapping the last person last LTS
version of you want to and for the post
part you can see we are compiling
openmpi installing cuda inside the
container so it will have much in
versions of the cutest AK and killer
drivers inside and outside the container
and you are loading this those libraries
when running the container so you don't
have to take care about running some
script just before calling as much or
any other queue manager you are going to
use because the container will take care
for itself of setting up the correct
environment more crappy small text now
you are compiling actual actually
downloading and compiling the source
code for change and by the time you need
to run that you are going to call the
python executable inside the container
with the channel example code the blacks
inside the container in case you need to
write your home directory will be binded
directly inside the containers way so
anything you are writing in the home
directory inside the container will be
outside also and if you need to bind the
special folders for let's say drivers or
libraries that for the InfiniBand stuff
you combine them by passing outside path
and inside path and the container run
script will set up the environment for
using this
I'm a bit long on time so I will give
you some time for questions and thank
you very much for the presentation
[Applause]
[Music]
somebody has to act something we were
guessing about newer based versions of
the of GCC compiling the libraries
inside the container but we didn't
profile that that's something we found
but it's more likely that you want to
sixteen is using GCC five and and sent
always is using a bit older Bastion so
it's it's likely it could be like that
but we don't have data it's just
guessing
oh you will have the same permissions oh
[Music]
he was asking if you are binding host
director is inside the container you can
skylight privileges inside the container
for actual file system outside the
container when you are running the
container for the creation part you need
root privileges in the machine but by
the time you are run in the container
you will be running them with the actual
user privileges that is running the
container so in a short supercomputing
environment it's likely an unprivileged
user let's say you have to bind some et
saliva bugs for infinite ball libraries
and those files are all borrowed and
only right below a root inside the
container you will have the same
permissions for this file so you you can
not do anything inside the container
that won't be allowed to you inside the
country outside the container yeah you
have to have module installed inside the
container
okay I'll just with it yeah and so the
answer is essentially yes so that's the
entirety of how singularities working is
we're either having a set UID binary in
which case all privileges are dropped
before any user code is run we only use
it to do certain things like that
require you root privileges or on some
newer kernels you can do it entirely in
user space and in which case then you're
using user name spaces instead
[Applause]
those green hats
let's