okay so I'm going to to start so this
talk is about GPL enforcement this is so
I kind of envisioned that that Karen
and/or Bradley would be in the room and
this talk is sort of in some ways
conceived of as a sort of troll of Karen
and Bradley but but I think for various
reasons they're they're not going to be
here because they're busy with other
very important things so that's that's
okay that's actually maybe maybe better
for my purposes but this is kind of a
talk about GPL enforcement from
perspective of some of us lawyers at Red
Hat I should I should explain I'm a
lawyer at at Red Hat and we've been
we've been talking about this topic
among ourselves quite a lot recently and
I'll explain a little bit like why this
is an interesting topic to us and then
like how so I want to sort of like
presents the sort of very very rough
tentative framework we're thinking about
for how we're looking at the question of
Glenda's GPL enforcement appropriate
when is litigation appropriate in a GPL
enforcement situation and then if to the
extent I have time I'm going to talk
about some related issues that don't
quite fit neatly into that idea of a
framework and also so I should also
explain this is so usually when I give
talks they're just like you know my own
thoughts on things and this is a little
bit different because some of the ideas
are things that I've sort of developed
collectively with some of my colleagues
at Red Hat on the legal team and so
that's that's like different from the
usual talk I get but this is not this is
still very much you know my own thoughts
my own perspective
I'm just influenced by some of the ideas
of my colleagues so it's kind of a
mixture of my own ideas and my
colleagues ideas and it's so it's not
you know it's not an official Red Hat
talk by any means but it definitely
grows out of the experience we've had at
Red Hat and thinking about this issue
okay so why why are we even in red hats
legal department looking at this topic
of GPL enforcement I mean GPL
enforcement's always been an important
part of what's going on in free software
and open-source law but it was you know
to me it was like this topic that was
kind of in a way minor in nature I was
sort of primarily interested in it by
the time I started working at Red Hat I
got interested in it because I noticed
that there were Red Hat customers and
Red Hat partners that were very you know
very very concerned about the risks of
GPL enforcement litigation perhaps
unreasonably concerned and I used to
give talks to lawyers where I would
really de-emphasize the risk of GPL
enforcement in general or open source
license enforcement in general which i
think is actually accurate I think that
there really is not a lot of active
enforcement of of these licenses and
that's actually the one of the most
interesting features of this whole
system so I really tried to de-emphasize
the the risk because I saw that it was
hindering to some degree adoption and
and participation by those companies in
recent years this has become I think a
more interesting topic so a few things
have been happening
that sort of make it more interesting
one is that in the US and maybe some
other countries as well we're starting
to see a bit of an uptick in GPL
litigation brought by commercial
entities so typically this is kind of a
variant of a what bradley Koon calls a
proprietary relicensing type of
situation where you have a company that
sort of monopolized GPL code base and is
for whatever reason bringing
lawsuits alleging Jeep GPL violation
copyright infringement based on GPL
violation with you know with some sort
of business goal of monetization or or
or what have you
scrum so we saw that within the US with
the this very complex set of cases
associated with a versus odda and simple
where that took place a couple years ago
what's also happening also in the past
few years is the software freedom
Conservancy so Karen and Bradley's
organization has been they've been
involved with GPL enforcement really
from the beginning but I think in the
past few years they've they've kind of
taken on a more active or expanded role
so Sol Conservancy started the GPL
compliance project for Linux developer
so they started doing GPL enforcement
for Linux kernel copyright holders which
is something they hadn't done in the
past hey Bradley so so so so that's like
so that's that in a sense in a political
sense increased the stakes because the
kernel is such an important project
commercially and it's so pervasive that
once one's Conservancy started doing
direct GPL enforcement for kernel
copyright holders that that was you know
sort of inherently a high profile
activity and then of course Conservancy
has been funding the hell would be
VMware lawsuit I guess is part of that
GPL compliance project for Linux
developers so that was filed a couple
years ago and it was dismissed currently
on appeal I believe still on appeal but
also I don't know if anyone has heard of
some of you have heard of Patrick
McCarty so what's going on in parallel
is to conservancies activity and this
increased commercial gpio forcement
there's a Linux kernel developer named
Patrick McCarty who over the past couple
of years has been bringing a large
series of lawsuits in Germany alleging
GPL violations and we don't have very
good information about this
part because there's the German civil
litigation system is is sort of very non
transparent by default and so there's
been just this atmosphere of rumor
around McCarty's lawsuits but but
there's been a lot of concern among
among you know commercial entities
involved in the linux ecosystem about
what McCarty has been doing basically so
we don't have like reliable information
but what some have said is that McCarty
is basically adopting a kind of
extortion it's sort of strategy around
bringing litigation sort of in a sense
getting companies to agree to these
settlements which have penalty clauses
and then the penalty clause is triggered
by an allegation of a subsequent GPL
violation and it's sort of meperidine
have knowledge about this
McCarty has been you know amassing
significant damage Awards or settlement
awards based on this this kind of
strategy so so the assumption that his
the motivation of Accardi has been in a
sense of wealth acquisition rather than
compliance percent compliance for some
sort of social purpose so the
Conservancy and the FSF published last
year I think or the year before a set of
principles of community oriented GPL
enforcement you should you know look it
up I won't go into into them here
actually and I don't think that that
Conservancy has actually given public
talks about the details of these
principles but I think these principles
clearly came out of the concern over
McCarty and a desire to emphasize the
difference between conservancies you
know rationale and methodology for
bringing GPL enforcement and McCarty's
tactics or alleged tactics so so that's
the the purpose I think the primary
purpose that that the principles will
serve
so why is this interesting to read out
so everyone one interesting thing is
that I mean companies have not really
publicly talked about this issue at all
Karen and Bradley talked a lot about GPL
enforcement you know we we just we don't
really see companies publicly willing to
talk about this issue but there's
there's a lot of back-channel discussion
among especially legal representatives
of companies about McCarty and so forth
but no one's really known from from a
corporate point of view is really
talking about this issue so we sort of
think that it's probably time for a
company that's you know especially
involved in a lot of development of GPL
licensed open-source software to start
talking about this for for Red Hat it's
particularly significant for a lot of
reasons Red Hat distributes lots of
upstream GPL software Red Hat uses the
GPL for a lot of the software it
develops Red Hat has a lot of employees
who contributed GPL license projects and
many of these employees I would say are
sympathetic to the GPL enforcement being
done by the Conservancy and we're you
know we're certainly aware of that
they're very frustrated by the the
degree of non-compliance I think that
they they see so so it's very for
multiple reasons because Red Hat is kind
of standing in a lot of these different
worlds
surrounding the GPL it's it's very
relevant for us as a topic so our
perspective is so first um we I think
there's been this this assumption that
companies are just sort of unthinkingly
opposed to GPL enforcement are we want
to emphasize that that there is a place
for certainly for GPL enforcement and
you know the question is how much
enforcement should there be what is what
what tactics should be used so we've we
actually think that conservancies
principles are a really good starting
point in terms is really the first group
to try to articulate you know what
what kinds of characteristics legitimate
versus illegitimate GPL enforcement
should have so a very good starting
point we think that that there's more
that can be said about the topic and we
kind of want to research CEO Charles as
starting to think about contributing to
a dialogue on this topic that that sense
Conservancy started so we have a kind of
rough very rough tentative kind of
framework that with we're discussing
about this where we we think about you
know what are the objectives of
legitimate objectives of GPL enforcement
and GPL compliance and and then what are
the characteristics that that that such
enforcement should have and then what
kinds of tactics are appropriate for for
that kind of enforcement okay so the
objective so for us you know if you go
to conservancies talks on GP enforcement
I think they'll probably emphasize the
the traditional conception of what the
goals of the GPR are so so maximizing or
protecting user freedoms for example we
you know our view is is kind of
different in perspective we we certainly
recognize the importance of of user
freedoms as part of the design of the
GPL the GPL is designed to do but from
our point of view the the goal that we
we think we want to achieve from GPL
compliance is promoting more
collaboration and promoting more more
participation in in developments and I
don't want this just sound like it's
kind of a sort of an old-fashioned type
of open-source versus free software
thing cuz that's not really how I was
certainly not how I conceived of it it's
we see social as well as economic
benefits to to participation in free
software projects including copula
projects and and we want to promote both
the social and and in the ethical and
the commercial benefits and the other
objective that we have have sort of been
formulating is this notion of a level
playing field among vendors that the GPL
is something that
attempts to achieve this level playing
field too and it's actually sort of
subsidiary to the previous one because
it the level playing field promotes more
participation in the system okay so
collaboration so the collaboration gulps
you know so this kind of implies that
the goal is not compliance per se or
compliance at all costs its GPL
compliance should aim to maximize
promoting collaboration and
participation including commercial
investments in commercial participation
and it should be measured by you know
the extent to which it achieves that
kind of goal you know the the we've
we've been talking a lot about about
this idea of uncertainty that that the
more uncertainty you have surrounding
the GPL and GPL compliance and GPL
enforcement the you know the more
concern there is about about
discouraging participation so there's a
certain point where where GPL
enforcement activity might be negative
in nature because it discourages rather
than promote participation and the level
playing field idea from so so the the
the nature of the GPL is this this you
know this basic rule of copyleft they
that distributors can't impose any
further restrictions on downstream users
this is something that that I think
Conservancy actually has emphasized in
some of their talks that that the this
the shared expectation of the no further
restrictions rules creates an incentive
to contribute to GPL license products so
so we we we certainly agree with that
and this is you know historically this
was a big motivation for many companies
that got involved in in Linux
development the the the idea that all
participants all corporate participants
will be held to the same rules was a big
sort of motivator that they all be
limited in their ability to
quiet eyes it's called a restore
prevented from propriety Singh the code
so when you have non-compliance this has
the tendency to reduce participation
because because then you no longer have
this shared the rules are no longer
being observed by all participants so
the the the system is not really working
properly when you have some companies
out of compliance so based on those
kinds of objectives we've we've been
thinking about you know what are the
what are the ice a lowercase P
principles because I don't want to kind
of confuse this with the principles that
Conservancy and FSF have been talking
about it's it's these are more like the
characteristics of enforcement that's
that we see is sort of legitimate versus
illegitimate so or
or well-intended versus not well
intended and so there are four basic
principles or characteristics
predictability enforcement should not be
done for gain for financial gain and
transparency the importance of
transparency and the importance of
resolving conflicts of interest
surrounding enforcement so I'll I'll
talk about some of these in a little
more detail so the predictability is
just a very high-level kind of
characteristic this is just the idea you
know I talk about uncertainty so so
enforcement should be done in a way that
is predictable
it should not be done for what will you
know be perceived as arbitrary reasons
because that the arbitrariness is going
to reduce the incentive of companies to
be in compliance
[Music]
and now the the idea that enforcement
should not be done for for financial or
personal gain this is something that
that Conservancy in the FSF have
emphasized so we totally agree with that
as a as a fundamental principle so you
know why it's kind of obvious why this
this is bad so so to do enforcement for
personal gain the way for example
Patrick McCarty is alleged to be doing
you know so enforcement that's done for
personal gain is going to be it's going
to increase that uncertainty because you
know you why should i why should a
company invest in compliance if they
just don't they don't really know you
know they're trying to play by the rules
but they don't know if they're going to
be you know enforced against for some
reason having nothing to do with the
goal of furthering compliance for its
own sake it's a problem this also you
know enforcement for personal gain just
just increases cynicism around the whole
topic of GPL compliance so so the GPL
sort of loses respect because
enforcement and compliance is seen as
something that is not done for social or
ethical reasons but rather for financial
gain and copyleft is seen as something
that you have to worry about so the
cause for concern rather than something
that is supposed to benefit the
community and this this concern fits in
with things I've you know talked about
in the past about for Praia Terry
relicensing about that business model
which is now a bit outdated but still to
some degree with us
so proprietary licensing creates that
business model creates incentives for
unreasonably aggressive enforcement
tactics and what some people would call
shakedowns and in sales tactics and and
also encourages the companies that
operate those kinds of business models
to promote very restrictive unreasonably
restrictive interpretations of the GPL
so this is this will you know for many
years this was a concern that what that
surrounded MySQL a B for example and
other companies not
that used similar models so fits in with
what we've said about you know what
certainly I have talked about in the
past about about that topic the
transparency value is something that
that concerns he and FSM have not really
talked about in this context so we think
it's something that that's really been
missing from from discussion of this
topic so you might say that that
Conservancy has put forward this model
in which nonprofit organizations
especially charitable ones or
specifically charitable ones play up
should play a prominent role in in
license enforcement that being the case
the the it becomes very important to
have adequate disclosure of donor
relationships for those kinds of
organizations we we don't really see the
the kind of disclosure that exists today
being adequate in sort of giving giving
us enough of a degree of confidence
about the motivations for GP enforcement
so so we think there has to be some
pretty high standard for for disclosure
of funding relationships for entities
that are engaged in GP enforcement as
nonprofits the another thing that
another issue that that should be
discussed in a transparent way is you
know just the methodology for deciding
if your if you do go to litigation why
do you pick one company as a target
versus another so if you're suing you
know you're suing the even given company
what led you to that decision when there
are other companies that are engaging in
the same kind of violation also this is
maybe a fairly controversial point the
thinking about about both McCarty and
the hell would be VMware a case we've
been really concerned about the the the
sort of by default secret nature of the
German civil litigation system it's in
this respect so there's a lot of
benefits to
the German Civil Procedure system
relative to what we have in the United
States one one big disadvantage that
that exists is in the u.s. you know
litigate the facts about litigation are
public by default it's the opposite
situation in Germany where where when a
litigation is going on it's very
difficult to get information about about
about those cases and this has this has
been I think sort of used by based on
what we hear by litigants like by
Patrick McCarty is because it the
secrecy surrounding the litigation has
made it made it in difficult if not
impossible for companies that are
targets for potential targets of of his
litigation to share information and
share strategies and so forth so so the
secrecy secrecy is is is very damaging
so you know all things being equal
non-transparent litigation forums should
perhaps be disfavor or there should be a
higher burden to justify bringing a
lawsuit in a in a jurisdiction like
Germany or in some way the the the
problem of the the non transparency
should be addressed and I also the one
thing that concerns me enough is I do
emphasize in the principles is the
importance of confidentiality which is
kind of at odds with this this emphasis
on transparency so we would say that
that that maybe they're overstating the
value of confidentiality perhaps you
should be having more information
disclosed about enforcement cases
including those that are that have not
gone to litigation and then an issue
that has really been ignored almost
completely maybe completely is is the
issue of confidence of interest so
conflict of interests arise in GPL
enforcement and we would say that you
know these should be acknowledged they
should be disclosed and addressed and
resolved in some way so the the main
concern is this idea of divided
loyalties so if an employee of a company
gets involved in GPL enforcement
activity that activity might be in
conflict with duties that they have to
their employer
imagine if the gpo enforcement involves
some some product of the employer or
some part business partner of the
employer or a major customer of the
employer so there are all sorts of
possibilities for how an employee
getting involved in GP enforcement could
kind of create a conflict a conflict of
interest in relation to the the employee
status as an employee of some company
this doesn't mean that if such conflict
exists the enforcement shouldn't go on
or or or any anything like that it's
just that this these issues have to be
have to be made visible and and they
have to be resolved in some way and they
could be resolved in a way that would
facilitate the enforcement to happen
it's it's just that this this issue has
been as I say kind of ignored and I
think to the extent that that we sort of
get close to talking about it that it
comes up in a way when we talk about
copyright ownership and that's something
that conservative talks about a lot but
the even if employees have copyright
ownership of their of their work their
contributions GPL license projects that
doesn't eliminate this compact of
interest issue because you you can have
copyright on on code and you you could
still give rise to a conflict of
interest situation if you have you're an
employee who has a duty to an employer
or or in other there be other issues as
well like you you maybe maybe you have
your business partner and there's some
conflict
caused by your GPL enforcement activity
in relation to your business partnership
or various various possibilities the one
that we've kind of thought about a lot
is this employment situation okay and
and then so what what tactics are
appropriate given those kinds of
objectives and characteristics of you
know good GPL enforcement what are the
appropriate tactics so here we we say
you know education is very important and
litigation should be your last resort
these are also emphasized in the
Conservancy and FSF principles but
there's a kind of a difference in in in
some of the details we talked about so
we agree with with conservancy that you
know non-compliance is generally a
problem of education and awareness and
this can be addressed in many many cases
by working with with the non-compliant
company to learn about how they can come
into compliance and and so you know
there should be a big emphasis on
finding ways to facilitate self
compliance by by a target company that
that is is not comply of the GPL in in
talking about education we don't I would
distinguish that from the the separate
topic of general education initiatives
around license compliance which may have
some value themselves but but I think
the general education around compliance
and and learning about you know
licensing and so forth and and enabling
better tools for compliance that's not
really going to address the the kinds of
GPL non-compliance and I think for
example Conservancy or the FSF or other
GPL license projects not to deal with so
that's kind of a it's more than the
one-on-one education that we're talking
about there and so everyone says that
litigation should be a last resort and
you know we certainly agree strongly
with that but I think I would say that
that we
we would emphasize this more than we
think
Conservancy is doing so so what's what's
wrong with with litigation as a solution
to to GPL non-compliance
so litigation is just a really bad
mechanism it's a it's a bad tool it's
it's um too highly structured it's very
expensive very time-consuming the rules
differ from locality to locality so it's
just not not a well-designed mechanism
for achieving compliance in general it
also has the the detrimental feature
that it it is basically a form of
shifting power away from developers and
towards judges judges who in general are
not going to be familiar with the
technology or the kind of cultural or
social background you need to have to
understand how the GPL is actually
interpreted in the community the outcome
of litigation can be very bad and you
can get bad results and this can
sometimes be heavily dependent on the
knowledge level or skill level of the
lawyers on the various sides of the
litigation dispute so it actually you
know litigation tends to increase
uncertainty along one dimension and the
you know the visibility of litigation of
course is going to have some effect on
on making companies very concerned and
about risk and so forth my colleague
Scott Peterson has has written this
interesting article that kind of relates
to this this concern about litigation he
says that open source licenses are
shared resources and what he means is
that that in in this system licenses
like the GPL are reused extensively from
project to project and that's really
something that makes free software and
open source very different from other
other forms of software licensing we
don't see this in proprietary software
licenses we don't see that that reuse of
standard license text and the the
problem with this is that when you have
litigation
the the effect of 1:1 lawsuit brought by
one litigant can be very extensive if if
the lawsuit results in a particular
result which may you know I you know
it's as likely that the results going to
be very bad from the perspective of
someone concerned about the integrity of
interpretation of the GPO as as it might
be good so so you know there's at least
a high risk of really bad result from
from a kind of community GPL perspective
so and and one of the problems also is
that if you get a bad legal result what
do you do then it's you can't easily so
these licenses are not easy to update
the GPL was updated three times over a
period of twenty five years it's not
these license are not really well
designed for frequent updates and so
you're kind of stuck with a license text
and a set of bad legal rulings so the
you know the counter-argument is that
litigation is potentially beneficial
because you get more certainty the
problem is that sometimes less certainty
is actually more beneficial because
because of the risk of a bad result so
anytime litigation is contemplated in a
GPL enforcement context you have to
consider the likelihood of a of a bad
result based on you know what the what
the facts and the legal issues are and
so you know what kind of follows from
this is that you know what's the the
most appropriate kind of GPL enforcement
case that would be brought to litigation
so you know it would be one where you
don't have strong disagreement on the
underlying legal interpretive issues and
the risk of a really bad result in terms
of like GPL interpretation is relatively
low and also these are going to be cases
so the intransigent aspect is that these
will be cases where you know education
is just not going to work you have a
repeat violator and so this kind of say
this kind of sounds to me kind of like
the the busybox cases that were brought
several years ago so I think they fit
well in in this kind of clear and
intransigence standard
I'm not so sure that that vmware lawsuit
really fits in well of this kind of
standard so there's there's a subtopic
here of defense of GPL claims so there
have been a few notable cases where
companies have been sued based on some
legal theory and they've brought a
counterclaim or a lawsuit against the
person company suing them based on an
allegation of GPL violation and so three
examples that I know of our skov II IBM
so schoo suit IBM many years ago IBM
brought a GPL violation counterclaim
against go Red Hat was sued by a patent
not a patent troll exactly but uh but a
company I'm sort of transitioning from
operating entity to patent troll called
Twin Peaks and Red Hat brought a
counterclaim based on a GPL violation
and another one that didn't involve the
GPL is Jacobsen versus cat sir where
cats are sue Jacobson or Jacobson's
company alleging patent infringement and
then Jacobson sued cats are alleging a
violation of the artistic license and
this resulted in a helpful legal ruling
in the u.s. that that open-source
licenses suggesting open-source licenses
can be enforced through copyright law
but notice that the the lower court
decision in Jacobsen be cat sir went the
other way and so if if the the appellate
court had gone the other way and agreed
at the lower court we would have had one
of those really bad cases and you know
several years ago this is what many of
us were worried about so we were kind of
lucky with Jacobsen beef hats are anyway
so so with defense of GPL claims we
think these should be subject to a
different kind of standard because they
don't really raise the same kinds of
concerns that that typical GPO
enforcement claims and litigation will
raise so there isn't the same concern
about about abuse there's no real notion
of doing this for financial gain these
are done because you've been sued by
some company and you want to stop the
lawsuit this is not a matter
the GPL litigant trying to find targets
to sue because the the the target is
already selected itself because the
target has brought a lawsuit against the
defendant and these these cases the ones
that have occurred in in the real world
so far have all involved some kind of
legal threat to free software so patent
infringement against free software
codebase in two of the cases and then in
the case of Cisco a you know a very
broad sort of dangerous copyright
infringement violation basically so so
defense of GPL things we think don't
raise raise the same concerns introduced
kind of viewed by a kind of lower
standard
I think Bradley Koon is has spoken
otherwise he's kind of criticized Red
Hat for having settled with Twin Peaks
but but I think that the you know the
the the way litigation works is it kind
of motivates you to compromise and and
settlement and I think it's kind of to
set the Bradley was sort suggesting that
that you should sort of fight to the
bitter end and make sure that you're
gonna bring one of these counterclaims
make sure that you fight to the very end
so that you win that I think that that's
just not really a realistic view of how
the litigation system works but again as
I say the the concerns that arise with
[Music]
non-defensive GPL claims don't really
rise in that context so that was sort of
the the the framework the tentative
framework that we've been talking about
very kind of rough as you can see but
it's but you can see that we're sort of
building upon the ideas that Conservancy
started to talk about and thinking about
you know what what is Conservancy
overlooking what are some some issues
that really need to be brought to the
fore when thinking about when GPL
enforcement is appropriate when
litigation is appropriate or not there's
a few other issues that I've thought
about that relate to this a little bit
in more or less direct or indirect ways
and I'll just in the remaining time I
have I will talk about those so one
thing is this I call this back travels
problem so so one of the problems I see
in the current state of affairs is that
we have different entities that are
concerned about GPL enforcement they
aren't all really talking to each other
fully so we have these these
opportunities for companies to talk to
each other about you know concerns about
McCarty and how to think about GPL
compliance but the these these forums
are not really open to all stakeholders
in the in the GPL Forsman world so I
think that we should move away from this
tendency to have these closed forums
that are not open to everyone and I'd
like to see us have a more multilateral
kind of dialogue on these issues and I
think not having that multilateralism
tends to just escalate the divisive miss
that surrounds this whole topic I also
think that some of the rhetoric that I
hear from Conservancy around GPL
enforcement is maybe also problematic in
some ways the rhetoric which I mean I've
got kind of engaged in it myself in this
talk a little bit is kind of aggressive
and almost kind of violent in nature so
so the the very term enforcement is sort
of suggestive of force violent force and
I don't I mean apart from compliance I
don't have a good alternative phrasing
to use but but I think there's something
to be said for thinking about about
rhetoric and I don't want to sound like
tone police but but I think possibly the
the divisive nough surround this whole
topic could be improved by thinking more
about how you know the kind of language
we use well so Ted show has raised an
interesting issue of like who should
really have the authority to enforce we
have a product like the clinic's kernel
with lots of copyright holders you know
is it really appropriate for a
representative of a minority of those
copyright holders to enforce this is I
think Ted suggested that maybe leanness
should be the one to to make the
decisions because that after all he
ultimately makes decisions for what goes
into
Linux kernel I don't think leanness is
interested in doing that but I do think
that that you know we knew how a project
like the kernel you have lots of
corporate copyright holders as well as
individual copyright holders the the
corporate copyright holders are
stakeholders as well and they ought to
have some some sort of say in how
enforcement gets done I don't really
have a good idea for how that can be
done but I can envision some more
multilateral way of dealing with this
when you first had this dev room the
week - Olli gave this talk about
basically saying that it is possible for
for companies to enforce the GPL without
being corrupt I actually I'm not sure I
agree with what he said in that talk
entirely because I think that when
individual companies bring GPL
litigation it's sort of inherently
suspect but maybe there's a way of
multilaterally addressing the GPL down
compliance problem involving companies
and I think I'll just close on this this
point that I think one you know one of
the concerns we have about we hear about
the McCarty lawsuit is that he's
bringing he's alleging very frivolous or
questionable interpretation of the GPL
that are inconsistent with how I would
say we we tend to assume the GPL should
be interpreted in in the community and
so maybe we can address that by having
projects do more of an effort than they
do today of documenting how they
interpret the GPL has applied it to the
issues that arise in a given project so
so maybe we could have the kernel start
to put down on paper an attempt to kind
of derive some kind of consensus view on
you know for example the proprietary
kernel module issue or or any number of
other issues that can arise in GPL
enforcement issues in or GPL compliance
is used in the kernel context so I don't
know there's time left for questions but
I'm going to end it there
[Applause]
check we do have a couple of minutes for
questions and I'm gonna start so Richard
you've mentioned a number of things that
kind of go beyond concerns these
principles of GPL enforcement and you've
made a personal statement that Red Hat
is actively thinking about that so my
question for you is what do you kind of
envision that this is a a trendy want to
be a model do you want red hat to sort
of set the tone that maybe other
companies will actively think about this
and come up with their own principles of
GPL enforcement I think I'm not done do
you think that we're going to have
Oracle principles for GPL enforcement
and IBM principles of GPL enforcement
sort of like we had vanity open-source
licenses back in the day or
alternatively is it are you making a
call for the community to come together
and harmonize around principles for
cheapy law enforcement yeah it's it's
the latter of course we don't want each
company to come up with his own
principles we want to have we actually
want to have the whole community come
together and agree on what those
principles would be so Richard you
talked about it being important in your
view as I understand it for
organizations doing GPL enforcement to
provide clarity and transparency in
terms of things like who will get sued
you know and to make sure that that
decision is not capricious or arbitrary
I can understand the value of that but
surely the difficulty is then that you
end up with the whole I don't have to
run faster than the why and I just have
to run faster than new thing where every
company brings themselves into kind of
minimalist compliance just beyond the
next worst company in the list according
to the principles such that somebody
else will get sued apart from them and
whereas normally you would negotiate
with a company saying we would like full
compliance please they would just say go
well as long as we're doing better than
so-and-so your principles say you're
going to see them and not us okay
I don't yeah I'll have to think about
that
no problem
so I hope I can be adults with two
questions and she mentioned me I think
23 times during a talk sorry no photos
of you I was I was in the back now I
could hear the whole thing so so first
of all you youyou claim that the defense
of lawsuit against Twin Peaks meets your
lower class P principles in fact I think
it doesn't on every count it was not
transparent there was no discussion with
the community about what you were doing
it was not predictable because as a
complete surprise in the end of that
lawsuit or I'd had executive declared
that proprietary kernel modules are not
required to be under GPL and I suppose
it resolved yeah it's I mean it's in its
own archive.org you can read the
deposition I would assume you have so
I'm sort of sort of completely confused
about your argument that that
oh that basically you're the only law
that you said fit your principles is
basically red hats one against twenty so
so maybe I didn't explain this one up
I'm saying that these defensive
counterclaim issues shouldn't be held to
the same standard so so to some degree I
guess you're right about you know that
the point you're making about
transparency for example it doesn't meet
the same standard of transparency that
I'm suggesting should be part of how we
think about you know GPL enforcement
should be done but I'm saying that's
okay because it slits a confined issue
it's it's the the defense of its because
its defensive in nature it doesn't raise
the same kinds of concerns about about
abuse and so forth that arise in a non
defensive context so my second question
is is you you just answered Tom's
question saying yes you want to engage
in the process of discussing and
principles in a way there has been
multiple forms available since the
principles are published to do that I
haven't seen you or Red Hat do that
instead we have a surprise talk where
you criticize everything about our
principles and didn't even tell us you
were going to do that so so the little
confused like why why why you're saying
you want to have discussion but you
aren't engaging in the forms that exist
there public and transparent to discuss
the principle my view is I think it
would be a great idea for Red Hat to
participate in development of the
principle so evolution of the principles
going forward I don't know if that's
that's of my own
personal view I don't know if that's a
view of like some of my colleagues but I
don't think it's a surprise talk because
you were one of the people who voted to
have it in the Dever I'm sorry time for
one really great question if you how
much do you think the SEO lawsuits of
done reputational damage to this whole
field of GPL including gpo litigation
and in how much because this is kind of
something I missed in your presentation
what are you gonna do to kind of take
away that negative feeling that those
lawsuits have given to the whole field
of village legislation enforcement well
I I don't I mean the Skoll lawsuits are
now kind of really like deeply in the
past I think we've got so at the time
there was a lot of concern about about
whether you know free software was
legally dangerous but that that was a
long time ago and I think everyone kind
of got beyond that the Cisco lawsuits
were seen to be ultimately you know
essentially frivolous in nature and so
III don't think that that's an issue
anymore okay great thank you very much
Richard
you