right
first a welcome for coming at the aware
of lunch
I'm also suffering and I'm hungry so I
would try to be fast I only have 20
minutes I'm here to speak about privacy
in practice for our self listing and
when I say the self first thing is not
only for hosting your own stuff it's for
Ossining for other people because when
you also on social you do not act
privacy of your own data I would like to
ask to people to not take too much
picture of me if we see board zero let's
talk about privacy so I expect people to
respect that quickly about me I'm a
system administrator working at reddit
in the open source and Stoddart team we
help a between project with the various
things such as community management
event management design and in my case
cleaning everything the developer did on
the infrastructure when everything is
broken which is a topic quite
interesting so I do a lot of security
stuff I try to care and so about privacy
for community I have a very strong
opinion as my your coworker can attest
so yeah what is privacy for me privacy
it's linked as I say to security which
is linked to CIF not the bad guy in the
James Bond movie but our confidentiality
integrity and availability especially
the part about confidentiality where I
want you data to be kept secret and for
example not been used by bad actor and
which is something that usually happen
when you start to trust Google Amazon
Facebook and etcetera etcetera as I
assume that there is maybe some people
who were not here since the beginning of
the track and are just listening because
I'm ear I want to remind quickly why the
Deaf are bad for privacy
so first it's a question of
contradictory incentive on one end I
know people there and I know they want
to protect privacy on the other hand the
world business model is getting private
data and reselling them so you cannot
really get something completely private
when you need that to get money and to
live like getting word getting food and
everything it's quite important for them
as it is for me
sometimes they fight back against
parliament and write sometimes I do not
and the main and I think the biggest
issues we want that we tend to forget
it's the lack of diversity in technology
when you have someone in sao francisco
it's easy to say yeah i want to share on
my picture on whatever Google decided to
do because nothing bad would happen to
me well when you are someone in some
ways to achieve country and more ways to
achieve than a current USA I would not
make joke about it right not now well
maybe you have a different point of view
but you are not working at Google and
maybe Google is not asking you anything
because you're just a user
well maybe they would not take care of
anything you want and this were self
wasting is quite important because it
goes privacy beyond GLA so it's not
Kaylee's or control system
it's a three-letter agency like NSA FSB
DGSE which is for later but uses or
which is a point and in order to do that
you need to think about the first model
which is basically try to decide where
is what people wants to do like bad guy
from generic bad so most of the time
people say yeah there is a state level
adversary and there is NSA and China
anyway thing wants to get to me well
most of the time no unless you are a
tourist and if you are please do not ask
question about I'm a tourist what can I
do during the question for the recorded
at worst what you can get is the cops
are a lot of people doing activism and
sometimes cops just knock on your door
saying oh you want you to organize a
protest against that whatever so share
stuff everyone master stuff and
everything like we have to ask you some
question sometimes they go to the wrong
person sometimes they go through the
right and everything and sometimes while
you are just attacked by your coworker
that guys that you decided to kill at
Turk wake your ex lover with the abusive
guy maybe your neighbor because you said
that his dog is really loud and you call
the Cohanim
or your family because you are obviously
user and they are all different
they do not need to know so yeah when
you think about it previously can be
anything one of the most common example
is IP address you could say it's bad but
they never explain why it's bad so from
the wall let's say that you are on IRC
you connect so that's me
connecting on from some provider I
joined the film channel and then the
with someone else Arirang which may be a
year or not year we were speaking one
hour ago and you connect from the same
ip address so based on that you think M
maybe they are at the same place and
depending on the circumstance maybe they
are at the same workplace which is fine
if we are working together but maybe we
are not working together and why am I in
the office of arena maybe we are at the
same home while maybe we were connecting
during the night and that's where I
start to say why I am sleeping at our
warehouse and maybe if is what's called
Adriana maybe things will be different
so that's the kind of stuff when we say
privacy problem that can be in a sound
like I'm connected from my phone that
with one medium person with the same ip
address ok no problem I'm connected from
a specific IP maybe there is something
and if you got say yeah you can ash IP
no I do not add for example people
disconnect at the same time because
network is crappy well don't have that
you found something
so right back to the basics I will focus
on the web because everything is web and
it's easy oh I have 20 minutes
so first jealous I mean everybody can
use that song script you have to use it
there is no reason to not use it at
least no good reason so you need to use
good cipher but it's only if you want to
protect from a state level adversary and
everything so it's everything you need
on Madeira wiki you can use a search
engine for that
I also recommend to take a look at the
crypto policy project it's a project
aiming at making one single
configuration for reward system for
cryptography like strong future a normal
week which is much better than what we
have now which is a 20 different or
syntax for setting every single cipher
and the order for every project which is
bad we can take a look at
okay IP etc etc so there is that of get
out there I'm not gonna repeat them but
what you need to do is to discuss with
your author with your user because some
of them have older browser right
sometimes I do not have choice
everybody can remember the old windows
from the school and this kind of stuff
it depends really on what they want to
avoid so if you want to protect people
you need to get some set of cipher and
sometimes you block access for other so
what I will recommend is to provide two
videos one for insecure stuff one for
secure stuff and you can then
communicate with user without trying to
track them I mean at the world point of
privacy Eastern not track people set up
by Network great Bob this kind of stuff
because remember biggest which is not
always Jedi sometime it just someone at
your school sometime it's someone living
with you and everything another option
is to offer onion services people who do
not know what this it's onion when it's
on top of tower you do everything with
store I will not explain what the story
I hope that someone can do it for me
data again 20 minutes exit exit from it
can add to avoid the IP leak it require
a specific setup currently it's quite
hard to scale properly it's research
topic so there is a lot of specific
attack where people try to steal your
key and everything so if you want to be
sorry for that you need monitoring and
spend a lot of time to research what is
going on I'm pretty sure that in a few
year it will be easier but for now it's
not exactly a but that's a great idea
because then you can make a talk about
it for next year another issue is the
use of external javascript
again it's a web you know that want to
start to Oh store 1 million version of
jQuery but it turned out that it's an IP
leak so if you can avoid while avoid it
now we go to the biggest issue which is
the logs that's an issue because well
lock the critical if you get attacked
but the problem is pressing an attacker
it's the same data user I'm not saying
that you are attacker at least
not on record but it kind of the same
for that server solution first one easy
no drugs no drugs no program it might be
the girl I'm not a lawyer do what you
want sometimes I find might be okay
because it's not so expensive when
compared getting someone to jail
sometimes it's your money so you decide
what you want some people try to
anonymize the log which is usually
working fine that reduces the risk of
the risk of leaks but yeah when you have
something like this in the log you can
anonymize the IP address as you want you
will see that there is still my name and
so yeah you need to reduce information
logged as soon as possible for Amber do
you need a user agent maybe maybe not do
you need the APS referral one
interesting trick is to use an ID for
each user and you keep the mapping of ID
out of the log so everything will be
user number of something and someone
asked for the rug well none of that if
they do not have that mapping because
it's not on the log you cannot do much
to that protect against accidental dick
for example cut and paste on bug tracker
ought to make it cut and passed on back
tracker description on IRC and
everything it mind or my not first red
chilli which might or might not be a
good idea again depends it's also nice
because it is user name change sometimes
you do not want to keep a nice guy from
some department and get moster mr. nice
guy or if you change name because you
are married this kind of stuff
obviously you need a CL for the log if
possible separation of access which
means that you need to have more than
one admin which can be our if you want
to avoid abuse there is a three-step I
did hide it and put it if possible no
direct access to log now you can use
something like elastic search but I
cannot free commands the tool because
it's quite hard to install and it's not
exactly good from a security point of
view but something like this but not
this
if you can get a public trail of who
with the log that's usually prevent
people from abusing that if you know
that or if you are looking at the same
person every day maybe people would not
do it so is the issue for a long-term
storage as well you decide that we do
not do that because ok or you decide to
use aggregate log in the end you need to
decide why you need logs in the first
place maybe if you have set for one week
it should be sufficient maybe you need
one year because this is zero maybe so
you need to think about what you want
and what you need another issue to keep
in mind it's big backup so obviously it
needs to be encrypted
I say obviously but people do not do
that you need to test them I mean people
have seen what happened to get lab and
it remind one interesting question is
what to do is back up when a user leave
and that's quite complicated because
sometimes user early but it's not the
user someone get access to the password
or decide to dig to destroy so account
what do you do if you do not keep backup
it's fine when people want to disappear
if you keep backup well if someone makes
someone else disappear you can save the
day usually what people do is to stop
cleaning like you say okay we clean the
back up in two weeks in case you change
your mind
but the third so the kind of trick that
Facebook is using so that's not great
yeah whatever you do we can award weapon
there is no perfect choice something
also that I try to recommend is to use
open infrastructure so you publish the
configuration that make adder to do
something fishy like the sidings I don't
need to collect more information you
cannot do that without being seen in
practice not much people will win but at
least it's better it will first with
user it allow people to for can listen
for eyes this is decentralized internet
whom so it's good we're showing more
information there is a website that just
started two weeks ago and if people have
lots of money you can go to scale in
South Korea South California there is a
world dedicated to that another one
interesting thing to take in account
it's centralized authentication so for
me
is great I mean it's easier to attend a
baby that's why is the catchy smiling it
no need to have two-factor
authentication or more easily but at the
same time it's easier to trace people
because the same people will connect on
once on file system and it will have the
same name everywhere and most of the
time it require upstream work so I know
that for example for myself which is a
group writing services do not want to
set up some college education for
political reason so again no perfect no
perfect solution so you need to be
proactive look for a way to attack
privacy which basically mean be a
stalker let's be clear you need to think
about sharing policy I would recommend
to see which is what Mozilla is doing so
they have six principal the first one is
no surprise surprise as well but only
for Christmas as birthday you need to
tell people what you do that means that
you mean need to make sure that they
understand basically do not get a lawyer
to write a document to explain that you
really do not work so it needs to be
tested with user discuss with user make
sure that they understand something and
not something else you need to make sure
that you give them with choice again as
I needs to be clear you need to discuss
with user user
everything you need to have sensitive
sense your default if you create a
system for blog a blog is supposed to be
public if you create the same system for
a private URL it should go to be private
it's technologically the same stuff you
write stuff and it's recorded but the
default will be different of course you
need to limit the data data that you do
not ever data that are cannot be leaked
that can only be private and you need to
make sure that the users stay in control
and that you trust sir party make sure
that sir party are taking privacy
seriously and everything which is quite
out to do everything but it's up to you
to decide Tanya and there is the world
importance of two weeks which is by
itself a world topic that will span one
hour description so in C that we just
remind discuss with user and discuss
with more than your friend because if
you are in this room you are likely to
more power on wheels and regular user
and you may well you may not see that
yeah maybe gbg is great because you can
select whatever you want okay wait what
Kyle size of key you want anything
but most people will not want to do that
they want a checkbox private and that's
it so you need to discuss with with user
or more mainstream one because your
friend must have the time I will I mean
it's fine if they are not I'm not
judging anyone but yeah so what to do to
avoid see son Minister King and witness
that's your skies attack because that
someone will come for everything with
some time can be as we sure and that
very time season mean that's called the
confused deputy problem with that of
description about that again I keep
waiting repeating myself because when I
was in university we are saying that
repetition is everything so audit what
is going on so you can see if there is
something you can go back that's what
she said means this I mean if they are
volunteers I need to be aware that they
will be spied on by other OSes admin and
everything the world watch the rest of
stuff I cannot speak that you know or I
would have said in that in again provide
direct access if you can use coughing
management do it if you cannot go to
coffee management come tomorrow in Gant
learn how to do it and go back to that
slide if you want to be 20s or is the
world's our last continent stuff because
if there is no server to connect there
is no problem and if there is
configurations that cannot be changed
because container everything well it
cannot be changing there is less risk of
abuse if you have more time you can take
a look at various research topic such as
peer and everything where people do not
give you data they give you encrypted
data and you can make computation or on
it something like zero past the open I
think is working like this the server
has no knowledge or anything everything
is done client-side but for more than
app has been because that's quite
limiting and to conclude think about
week's discuss with user I said that's
where time so just make sure you
understand that communicate if you can
patch security extremes that great so I
do not have to do that
and that I'm not corrected is that that
cannot be leaked it's quite easy you can
print it in your office think about it
if you want to connect to contact me
well you can use whatever you want as
long as it's IRC or mail thank you and
if you have a question it's the right
time we have seven minutes if I'm not
wrong if you do not have any question
I'm okay with people clapping for five
minutes
so the question is is it worthwhile to
encrypt a disk and in a server if you do
not look anything and if the data are
are we doing 15 it depends because you
can still have someone going to the data
center taking the disk pretending like
there is power cut changing the data and
then putting it back
that's unlikely to happen but that's
something that can happen and the other
problem is even if you need to encrypt
the data sometime you just take out of
the box for software such as might not
know web mail and most of them do not
have encryption right now you can add it
but it require to be able to code that
we help students we accept and
everything so if you want to get
something fast maybe not and no matter
what you do is always so that you cannot
run fit for example you want to make
sure that people do not know you can
access with the server there is SSH key
you cannot encrypt them I mean they need
to be in clear text when the service is
started on this kind of stuff so I'm
so it cannot add too much to encrypt the
data then of course it become
complicated because you need to have a
specific in etiology you need to have
some specific process I know that people
that wear that are working on that you
can take a look at an Italian macaroon
walk is likely giving a talk somewhere
at first them about it so what you were
recording but for now the people are
people who are doing that are just using
out of the box in etiology stuff which
would be where someone connect and
decrypt that's for fine you have more
down time so you have to decide if it's
okay or not again there is no perfect
solution you just need to decide is it
false word is isn't it works file you
can try and then change back because
that servers are supposed to be through
a row board and again coffee management
reinstall everything it strikes it well
so it depends now when has any question
I cannot transfer but confuse people
like this yep
so the question is if I do self-esteem
in my house I cannot prove to people
that I'm not doing anything with the
server I think you cannot prove it
because even if it's data center if you
pay for it you can likely access it I
can say yeah I'm hosting something on a
data center from OVH which is a famous
European provider and if I pay enough
like if I do not take the cheapest
possible way but I can get access to the
work and do whatever I want and even if
I do not have access at the hardware
level while I'm root I can refresh abuse
I can do whatever I want
so yeah that's quite hard you cannot
really prove that the with people
working on it with a remote attestation
and making sure that you execute the
code and the code is not modified with
TPM any roofing I think that's still a
topic of open research but in the end if
you want to delegate something to
someone you can I have to trust that
person to not up the system because
they can just refuse to do something and
that will mean a lack of availability
which can be a problem for someone so as
long as you delegate and people can
decide to not do anything that's an
issue so you have to trust someone but
yes that's a complicated topic and I do
not have good answer
so maybe one more question because of 1
minutes 2 minutes 1 minute yep so I tend
to prefer some oh yeah what is my
preferred hardware start to use well it
depends on how much people I need to ask
for work while we are basically getting
expensive server because we want to get
lots of memory to run Jenkins great and
everything at my home when it's me
paying out of my pocket with my
electricity and everything I just get
cheap possible board either was verified
because people are throwing them away
and it cannot be cheaper than free or
getting bigger bone because it's well
supported by federal 25 and I can add a
TPM for crypto acceleration and this
kind of stuff I do run a tor node in my
house because the fiberline do not feel
by itself by just by me so I can use it
and it's running fine there is nothing
for remote access except serial port and
I have the full control it's cheap
enough to not have any internal stuff
and it works well except when it's
broken in upstream kernel but let's not
discuss about that and you can get a TPM
and the crypto cap so you can do all
kind of security stuff which I do not do
because I do not have time but yeah and
it consume almost nothing and it's
powerful enough to run a tor node which
is doing a lot of CPU so it should be
fine for I don't know mail spam
filtering and everything any chip
[Applause]