oh my name is David I was working on a
project called project lighthouse which
I usually plan to introduce to you today
things were a bit complicated there are
a few interesting plot twists between
the time I submitted this talk than the
time I finished the slides than the time
of when I'm presenting but so let's
start with the plot twist the prototype
has broken at some point so I'm not
going to make a demo of this but
so what's project lighthouse project
lighthouse was a project of Mozilla's
connected devices branch dedicated to
helping blind people live in their daily
life this talk at some point I
considered renaming it how not to die
when you're preparing a hardware
prototype which is pretty ironic given
that connected devices died two days ago
so I'm still going to present
so about us we devices was a set of
internal nonprofit startups inside
Mozilla the idea when it worked was to
have great ideas make great prototypes
try to convince people to give us money
to turn the prototypes into actual
products and hopefully to make products
that will help users connected devices
has produced a total of zero products
which might be somewhat related to the
fact that we don't exist anymore
[Laughter]
at some point and since we were the
rebels we were still using the Dyne user
and not the new funky weird logo of
Mozilla this might be the last time you
see the diners are tell you what this is
about I mean what project light house is
about because initially project light
house was about we know how to use
cameras we know how to program this kind
of thing can't we do something not
creepy because if you look at the use of
cameras in connected devices in IOT
these days just about everything is
about watching you do something and
telling someone on the cloud exactly
what you're doing which is incidentally
one of the reasons while company why
some many big companies are interested
in this for strategic reasons for
insurances and I mean there are many
companies that have interested in
knowing what you're doing at home either
to sell you things or to charge you for
things you're doing and that's one of
the reasons why there is so much focus
and so much money involved and invested
in Internet of Things these days it's
not just because it's fun it's also
because being creepy is profitable
but we wanted to do something not creepy
so what can we do with the camera a
Raspberry Pi and a microphone and a
speaker that happened to draw more juice
than the element ation of the Raspberry
Pi can provide which is pretty much why
I cannot do the demo today do something
useful so sometimes the solution meets
the problem because there turn out to be
some people who have interest in having
a camera and something interesting done
with the camera some people the life can
be changed with camera so according to
the World Health Organization there were
close to 300 million users sorry people
who live with a sight impairment about
30 million of them or entirely blind but
still that's many people who have
trouble in everyday life recognizing
objects for instance this means that in
shops these people have lots of trouble
they need help to find out exactly what
they're buying and since shops tend to
at least in big shops tend to change the
place of things regularly to force
people to revisit everything if your
sight visually impaired you're in
trouble because they are actively
working against you against all your
brain or muscle memory
they are trying to force you to not know
where you are anymore
there are basically basically the
solution is find help so there are a few
devices that I know of essentially two
specialized devices to help people in
this kind of situation
they both are pretty much more than
$2,000 for something that actually
contains this kind of hardware so the
idea is
I mean that's worth about $30 maybe 40 I
don't remember but that's the battery so
the idea is can we do something open
source open the hardware and chip and we
set out to try that so more specifically
we wanted to help visually impaired
people recognize household eat items
because if you have two packs of the
same size it's pretty hard to know well
if you have two cans one is coke and one
is Fanta you have no way of knowing
which one is which if you don't see them
but in that case is pretty easy for
camera to make the difference
other things are much harder but we try
to see if we could do that so we
actually got good results with the for
the one above and pretty bad results
with the one below but we only had a few
weeks of development so so we get little
software to developers oh sorry yeah
lots of open CV - so - developers
working for a few weeks time and we
actually managed to users
so I have pictures of actual users but
I'm pretty sure that I do not have the
right to put them in an image so I used
super villains instead so we have 24
test users so we actually tested
something that was a slightly more
refined version of this
this was prototype number one there is a
prototype number two that still is
somewhere in California and probably
going to stay there so I could not show
you it would have been a bit easier to
make the demo because it does not rely
on so many outside stuff
and so I call this presentation lessons
learned so lesson number one nerd if it
hasn't been tested by users it doesn't
work it just because it's cool just
because it has code just because we had
fun developing it doesn't mean that it
works so we were lucky after relatively
few either eight iterations we got
something nice so that was prototype to
our lessons were yes not all of these 24
users who are interested but enough of
them were interested that it was worth
doing they thought it would change their
life not everything in their life but at
least shopping which is an important
part of life if you need to you know eat
so we're supposed to work on making on
keeping it cheap making it simpler and
have a better form factor
cookie so that was making a prototype
how do we get from deer there to a
product
so we put some designer to design some
stuff we put a factory and that's pretty
much not it not how it works it's a bit
more complicated so for the documents
and on a blog that details a little bit
more the process from the time you get
the hardware prototype and a good
industrial design to the time you can
actually ship it so forget marketing on
the top
forget the app development at the top
you still get all these three four lines
and our estimates were that they could
take about six month time to get done
could actually be worse when I wrote
this slides I was preparing to tell you
that it's probably going to take more
than six months in fact it going to take
forever so I was right so the question
here is
what do you do
are you going to sit down during six
months and do nothing how can you not
waste your time so again this lectures
lecture sorry this presentation is about
lessons learned so we actually came up
with a solution and it's actually simple
one you are building a device you want
to test it so test things if possible
with devices that people already have
most people these days have a smartphone
or tablet some have a small TV so if you
can find a device that your users
already have you can paralyze things you
can have someone possibly you working on
the hardware finalizing the hardware
getting the providers getting the supply
chain getting everything together
testing actual hardware components etc
etc something that's going to take you
insane amount amount of efforts and time
and you can also work on the software at
the same time which is the things that
some of us do best yes
so in this case we set out to use a
device that blind users have and this
device is called an iPhone it turns out
that a huge number of we actually have
no numbers of blind users not visually
impaired users but for blind users it
turns out that many of them have iPhones
in the US it's like 85% of those who
have a smartphone have an iPhone and
many of them have a smartphone I don't
remember the exact numbers so this means
that we got ourselves working on a third
prototype that was that we all fold them
we are in open-source stuff if you want
to develop for open-source for this
let's just say that I have seen many
platforms on which developing open
source software is nice simple easy
stuff works this is not one of them
Apple is going to extreme lengths to
make sure that everything is locked down
and you have to go through them for
everything so part of the lessons
learned yes you need to go where your
users are for testing if you can avoid
that platform it's worth trying
so
we actually only got three weeks of work
on that so most 35 weeks most of the
time for me was spent actually getting
Xcode to work getting unit testing to
work and trying to actually release
binaries we have not succeeded at that
yet everything is locked down really
tight so it would be a great time to
discuss the next steps what have we done
we have an early prototype of that I
could actually do a move that let's see
if it works so
[Music]
you don't hear anything do you bunch of
people behind the camera
oh gosh completely so it was trying to
find out which was the interesting
object in the scene and apparently the
interesting because also the microphone
is dying so let's pretend that I have a
very nice demo what should the next
steps be okay fair enough make the demo
work that would be a pretty good next
step
what should the other next steps me at
that stage at that stage assuming that
we have software that works nicely
assuming that we are still on track to
get hardware oh I'm actually we do have
many nice hardware designs I did not
include them in the slides because I
think they involve commercial partners
so that we probably do not have the
right to put them here it doesn't matter
anymore but hey so at this stage our
next steps would be ok so make it work
for real the prototype apparently
doesn't work at for them so opening
issue doesn't work at for them so we
have been working so far on making some
basic computer vision algorithms
obviously making better computer vision
algorithms would be helpful
but in uniting is once since we have the
ability to prototype on the this ugly
stuff we can iterate and paralyze so
people working on improving the computer
vision people working with actual users
on improving the usability and the
accessibility people working with users
not necessarily the same ones on coming
up with new features we were also
planning to go further because at this
stage this is an IOT session I was
talking about tea but there was no I
there is no I in team so one of our
plans was to make it social not in the
bad way let's add Facebook everywhere
but in the good way as in sometimes
people need more help than just
identifying something easy to identify
sometimes people need help to find oh
gosh I'm wounded does it look bad one of
my breasts feels large you know sick I
mean that's a pretty good one and that's
the kind of reasons for which you need
more help than just what the Machine can
help so we wanted to help people share
their questions with people they trusts
and possibly in cases that were more
much boarder share questions with just
about any volunteer so we were in
parallel starting to work on a platform
for crowdsourcing questions from people
with sight impairments such as what is
that object what am I doing here going
to be released ever because there is no
single line of code written yet as I
said if you don't want to die to avoid
multiplying devices real devices but you
can again fake stuff using existing
devices once you have software running I
mean one of our industrial designs for
instance was actually a necklace
relatively heavy necklace containing
well basically this and that's something
that we can fake easily if we have
software we can easily make prototypes
that don't have to go through a factory
flat you can pick a real necklace or
anything that fits around your neck try
it and attach stuff that's not
sufficient for commercialization but
that's more than sufficient to find out
whether it's too heavy for users or
whether users actually manage to point
the camera in the right place because we
actually got tests and just actually say
that when people point cameras very well
that's that was a very good surprise
they have difficulties judging the
distance so it's sometimes it's too
close but it's Center and that's good
because that's something that needed to
be tested anyway if you want to avoid
relying on having a finished hardware
device before you can iterate and one of
the ways to do it is to have fake device
so just something rigged together using
a device for which you already have
software
so one thing you do not need to forget
if you are working and if you want to
somehow release a hardware device is
that it does not stop there you probably
have lots of legal things to cover that
we are not used to in the open source
world in this case people could possibly
have accidents because of this physical
accidents people trying to use it to
identify 25 medications for instance
could end up with the wrong medication
or they could add a period with rat
poison eating rat poison because we had
told us that it was beans red beans
something like that that's pretty tricky
so we of course we want to make sure
that the software works but many of
these things are have real-life
implications which among other things
involve lawyers in this case we also you
should also have been in touch with a
number of people such as organizations
helping blind and sight impaired people
because that was the best way to get in
touch with our users one thing that's
often overlooked is the Kickstarter
Kickstarter people generally see it as a
way to raise money
the secret of Kickstarter is that this
is not true Kickstarter is actually a
marketing tool used by companies to
measure interest in a product before
they develop it if people are willing to
invest ten thousand dollars of ten
million dollars that depends on the
product and this means that you can sell
the product I know of a number of cases
in which Kickstarter has been used to
sell a product that had no kind of any
kind of existence in the real world just
to measure whether it was the world is
worth worth it was worth trying to build
such a product some of our potential
partners did that for instance and we
had surprises so again if you're trying
to build something and turn it from
hobby to something that you can
distribute Kickstarter is a pretty good
tool for that not just for raising money
before to check if it's worth doing you
can find all these software prototypes
of project lighthouse on github and we
have a discourse forum if you want to I
don't know sympathize with us thank you
very much for listening
and if you have questions I will be
happy to try an answer yes so what's
going to happen with the prototypes of
lighthouse will they be released so the
software prototypes are on github
already I mean we need to put a license
because we just forgot that in the rush
but on github the hardware design
prototypes I don't know I would like us
to release them I do not know if they
belong entirely to us if they belong
entirely to us I think we can release
them if they don't we probably can't
yes
so the question is if so many blind
people and vision-impaired people have
smartphones why not just make an app we
also considered that yes that was a
separate track I am I'm an IOT session
so I was concentrating on the IOT stuff
but yes we considered continuing the app
track past the prototype phase
okay great thank you very much