shut out anyone reasonably fast can you
hear me now okay fine
okay so I'm going to show you for gaming
and I'm going to show you how to do a
rate program in this language that I
developed with along with other people
called foo talk I'm going to show you
how we cow new language cannot all be
useful by showing how it easily
interoperate with Python and I'm going
to talk a little about how the performs
of this language is compared hand
written GPU code okay first thing that's
two kinds of parallelism the one that
most people think about when they say
parallelism is tough parallelism may you
spawn a threat of the thread can go and
do whatever on some data and you can
spawn another threat we can go and do
something entirely all sums on some may
be the same day that may be something
else but the two threads are clearly
independent of each other their
parallelism is where I take the same
function or do the same operation on
multiple elements of some date set so
the simplest examples is what we in
function program hold the map which
takes two arguments a function and an
array and just you back a new array
where that function has been applied
each element of the array so I'm going
to use in infotrac with us notation for
add function applications without
parentheses so this says apply the
function map to F and this array all
right no nothing magical going on here
array programming is an instance of
parallelism and you've probably already
done do because numpad for Python and
similar Lari to other languages is an
instance of array programming what we do
Bach operations so we just say we want
an array of 10 elements each of those
elements we want to multiply by 2 and
keeps giving us back a new array and
then we can multiply these two arrays
point-wise and then some of the results
as a dot product doing here but this
idea of doing bulk operations on
untraced which can be very large is a
very good way of to heroism in a way
that's easy for humans to think about
and very efficient on massively parallel
hardware like GPUs array programming is
act a pretty old model
it's was seen first APL which was not
popular for some reason he wasn't
especially portable so
let's uh let's do anymore I feel this is
retire which you can type with ordinary
keyboard is it's a very small language
it's kind of a it looks a little bit
like standard email or Haskell or some
other generic function language if
you've seen ot for we can define a
function that takes this input an array
of length in and give suspect and the
array of length in and just as to
trailer element of that array or we can
find a function that sums an array using
reduce which is a function language
lingo for uses function to turn this
array of values integers on one value
concept it just puts this function if
it's this operate between each of the
elements on the race so that's that's um
sorry and this function can be any
binary function it has to be associative
to be parallel but let's not worry about
that that's a little esoteric the nice
thing of like I said is very freedom so
when you find a function that it has
some parallelism inside you can still
use it inside of another peril context
so you can do map while we use the sum
function that we define up here so now
we have two layers of parallelism you
are map on the outside and refuge on the
inside that's called nested parallelism
and its comparative rare because it's
triggered compile and one thing that the
from a compiler will do is turn this
little parallelism which is neither
humans and nice and composable in flat
parallelism which is only kind of
hardware can be handle so you have your
own level of parallelism that's tricky
and it won't finis an explanation of how
to do that or fortunately you can fit in
at twenty minutes or so I won't show
that much of about that futon also has
sequela loops it's a few language so
there's no destructive update so you can
kind of fake them by saying okay start
with a with the value X equal to one
then run this number of iterations and
for iteration computer new value X with
this equation so multiply X with I plus
one and then run the loop again until I
hits n and then X is is returned so it's
also just a sitting sugar for chain
recursive function if you use the
function programming
arrays can be constructed in rhythm
building constructs iota which gives us
back
and it's us just like range in pylons
Egyptians began there in range of a
figures of integers or replicas which
copies some of you and the Irish
replicate can also be released but we
won't i won't be using that so aren't an
example this is a man brought sit or
this is a actualization of part
Mandelbrot said the way to create these
nice graphics is just to applaud this a
simple function written in Python to a
bunch of comic numbers and you can turn
this function busts sees how many times
this comic number can go through this
loop without this condition becoming
true and with this part of point zero
neither forever and you just return how
many times you went through the loop and
you can use that number to turned into a
pretty car and then you can get a nice
visualization but it's basically just
boy starts running this pretty simple
solution and but since you run the same
phone on a whole bunch of comics numbers
at once you can do that in parallel in
pi it would look like this where we have
an array of complex numbers and then we
do some some weird operations with for
each of these some complex numbers we
compare them to this is the stop
condition and then we figure out which
ones did not stop yet and then we for
those that didn't have didn't stop yet
we set the escape count to the loop
counter and it's very complicated and
the original simple controller we had
before in our mathematical definition is
kind of gone and obscured but invoice
now not only is it unreadable is also so
and that's what I care the most about
because every iteration of this loop
which is usually on the order of maybe
200 200 could cut whatever you want but
it's usually very large we write three
arrays so that means we have found a
memory speed we can't see writes these
arrays that might be very large memory
with a problem because memory is very
very slow and also just how slow in a
moment in foods that looks like this we
have our sequential function I showed
you before which will be in Python
before it just is right to written food
truck that's the same thing let me just
map that not two-dimensional array of
complex numbers and it's two dimensional
but you really use this normal
visualization of the complex plane it
could be one-dimensional if you
the interests so the interesting thing
here is that so really that's only a one
every written because we just overall
complex numbers on this simple scalar
function which don't use any array so we
can skip it all in registers
that's a compiler to here but that's
something that the program can rely on
the primitive values are kept in
registers and at the end a
two-dimensional array is written to
memory so the moments difference between
the two styles is something like this I
mean they both scale right it will as a
number of complex number working on
increases don't do why they talk about I
mean this is an umpire's I whether you
write a lot of arrays it's hot at 12
times faster than sequential code that's
all this is not this is not Python code
this is cstp code written in a non pie
style but it's not Python code
we're in futhark style where we don't
have all these memory accesses it
becomes 350 times faster and sequential
code sequential C code there's a
significant difference and that's
entirely down to this what's the circle
memory wall that modern computation is
so so much faster than than modern
memory bank said that you really the old
I mean touching memory is just a killer
if you write real life from memory your
programs could be slow that's it
so we do it because we kind of have to
sometimes unfortunately we the user
can't see the value of registers of
sometimes we do have to write memory or
even worse to disk of the screen or what
have you well you want to avoid it it's
a very very bad idea if you want our
coaching fast so foots a little bit
tricky because it's a pure language so
one thing is you can you have mutable
variables you also don't have the
ability to write to the screen or to a
file or anywhere so running it is a
little bit exotic you have to can
compile a food-truck program and that's
start by writing a main function that
takes some input and produce some output
in this case I just make up some numbers
I haven't shown you this one doesn't
matter it just makes play an array of
complex nervous runs function I showed
you before it's some small up to reduce
one incision so that sums all of the
escape values of all these complex
numbers doesn't
doesn't cover anything meaningful we're
going to run this program where Patil
food are okay run this function with
these are guns and leave me the result
and do that by just compiling it using
the compiler and then you pass this
input internal input and you get back
output and standard output which is
weird thing but UNIX people like this
in this case I've all asked the Pico
when compiling a food-truck program
standalone program it's not for
production uses for tp3 bugging and
benchmark so it has some some useful
flags one I use is - T which asks it to
benchmark itself so in this case ok I
can this is a result and this is a
runtime in microseconds so six hundred
and eleven thousand microseconds this is
using the foot pack C compiler which
generates security code that is in
combat with GCC with also the photo
album shield Pilar which generates GPU
code and it runs just seven and 1/2
milliseconds so eight it seems faster
without any changes to the program
itself and the perks of doesn't really
talk about GPUs at all it just uses
these the parallel Opera Berets map in
this case and it geometrically runs
faster when I when run with the in
compile with the OpenGL compiler but
this is not the way you want to use
future you have a nice command line
program for some you are handle brush
sets but that's not really what anyone
needs in practice so the trick is how
open shield works which is the library
it used to me there's two libraries for
communicating with GPUs one is cool
invidious prize everything and OpenCL
will use an open standard but this much
masters you should use for manual
program it's not as a compiler socket
though so the way it works is actually
have two programs you have a program
running on GPU called the host which
offers code and data to the GPU which is
for as iconic as later they just
sentence and the command and data to so
the interesting thing is that the CPU
code doesn't actually compute that much
in a well-written organ whether by the
peril seams are large it just
bookkeeping
it doesn't have to be fast in particular
you can have the spew code be in some
high-level language and easy to
integrate with
but but and just talks with you for you
so the way we don this is that we have
added a code generator where the host
level code you know the CPU level code
the code that you see is written in
Python so this compiler generates Python
that internally makes holsters ohms you
live it's you upload code and aces GPU
so it just use a different pilar called
pi open shell and you ask it to create a
library and then you produces a python
module Bantle brought that pi which from
the outside looks like any ordinary
python module to even start a Python you
can import it and then it's kind of as a
kind of strange thing about how you have
used it it defines a class that you
instantiate some GPU States and then
that class or that object defines a
method for every entry point original
food-truck program in this case there's
only the main function and just pass
that ordinary Python values and you get
back ordinary Python values as result
and behind the scenes it has compulsive
GPU code and is asking is if you take
through this function for this argument
and you can call it again and it'll give
a parity for assault and for passing
erase and get back erase from the cheap
you it uses an up hi mary so you can
pretty easily integrate it with with the
existing pattern libraries all those
numpy array is going to be on the cpu so
to be some cost of copying pat fault so
you can use that if you really want to
sum up Mandelbrot sets or we could
modify that from a little bit and
instead of just arming up those escapes
if you compute and turn them into a IP
pixel values and give us back an array
it's really a pixel values and we can
use something like PI game to just lead
it to the screen and then we would
something like this and incisive
Mandelbrot viewer with a Python
front-end for meddling all the keyboard
commands and all that stuff but with all
the completion happening and my insult
GPU in real time much much faster than
the CPU could ever hope to this so
pretty nice division of work between a
restricted high-performance language and
a very flexible dynamic and little
Python language okay so the old reason
you would ever want use a restricted
high-performance language is to get high
performance because it's
it's not a terrible language I don't
think after all this time maybe that's
my Stockholm Syndrome Auggie but it's
not as nice as you didn't have to use it
so is it fast it's worth it well it
depends because I can easily just show
you some Finnish markka show that is
mattress and everything else but you
should we trust that because it's very
very hard to quantify whether life is
fast the only way I found that I just
trust the this least amount is take
existing programs that I'm that are set
to be written in good a decent way and
then pour them to my language and say
well this is how fast it is now almost
benchmarks not mean are not really
really don't really implement algorithms
that are designed to be parallel so it's
kind of I can't use the line normal
language benchmarks you doubt game then
when the TV on has however because
they're mutually sequential programs and
many of them require side effects in
writing to file screen and whatever and
I mean language can't really do that
there is a benchmark suite called Enya
which I don't like anyone to know unless
I've done HP in academia yeah
it's Henry no OpenCL code so hidden GPU
code of very varying quality much of
industry by doctors who did released it
to human parties or write code or by
physicists which is we are needed but at
least fast so we Paul
so we've so we've folded some of these
Virginia paint marks the photog and we
run them on put on in immediate review
and an AMD GPU and this is the speed of
speed compared to original code I don't
know if anyone if you can see these
small numbers but for this one the food
truck versus four times faster than
written version on an immediate review
and on an MD cheap use two times faster
of course this you misjudge this most
means that original program is ad that's
the way a compilers will generate code
that is significantly better than
something didn't by an expert who put
who put enough time to it to write good
code so you so not these benchmarks are
not sufficient are not very good except
some of them where we don't any speed
handle code but we get clips and of
course the food track code is vastly
easier to modify and understand and
extend that that's what we're going for
not really trying to beat handwritten
code with experts we're just trying to
get closed loop era and providing a much
better programming experience along the
way
this times we have seven teams time
faster because they were something was
parallel and really isn't time so it's
not true that your language is good when
everyone writes so slow code so and
sorry it's a small language is very
simple to learn it's high level so it's
not actually cheap you are in we could
generate multi-course view code as well
it's purely functional just weird what
fits this hard I'm pretty well it's data
parallel so there's inbuilt the operator
sort of pelham meaning and the compiler
understands I can optimize them and we
encourage Aaron curry imapilot generates
good GPU code and the future it will
also be able to generate good secure
code and may even cluster code we
haven't gone there yet we haven't a good
idea how we can integrate that with the
language and applications not just Pilon
that's what we right now but we could
easily create an Lang a ruby or C sharp
or whatever front Java doesn't matter
this is the host code is variable and
the moments is is okay we've also tried
them on more challenging benchmark where
we don't eat them quite as much but do
pretty respectively and of course the
foods are called much easier to
understand and it's all available online
and August and online is license and all
and all that off right that's it
thank very much true questions
yes
yes it's a I got a question we have a
pattern interface and I was out of all
time a C interface do is not quite as
mature because C doesn't have I will
define step for the multi dimension or
it should look like for example I think
we could just use numpy pensions but it
should very easy and we do generate city
code that works fine as a standalone
executable and you pieces to make that
alive with you yes yeah that's what
that's what the so I was also that we
have a compiler use the C wrap instead
of those Python that's what this with us
AJ doesn't have the - library option so
we don't integrate fully reusable code
just iterate the fight the nice rare
code but that's just because I can see
doesn't have a table enough numpy that
we know some convention so we can just
adopt so it looks a little bit more for
about how we create an API furs yeah
yeah sure yes if you wouldn't manually
sorry
so hey it wasn't by much because in
video don't bother support so I'm asked
about which watched what I was bored is
necessary now okay so that's two answers
that the first is I have often
questioned this time of doing a PhD that
requires working graphics drivers and
Linux you can't get your window you all
know the problem the second is open
shell self NVIDIA doesn't open shell
much they support it but the support of
value version and since vidya hardware
so popular we can't use features that
are newer than from OpenGL will - I
think that's the newest video support
that's all we need
it works on all CPUs I've seen in via
empty and in cell and also a name do you
want I think an r1 at some point I think
try it out so we don't we don't use any
fancy features
yes that's right on the C and Phi it
doesn't run very fast
once correctly it's supported
oakenshield code but the compiler has
some assumptions about how memory should
be accessed to fast that is valid on on
all modern GPUs but it's not well and
they don't see and Phi's as far as I can
see so there's a significant slowdown
but there could be fixed that's just
about tweaking the collation pipeline
for CFI so I think but I don't know that
much that's what knowles here and fire
they made a new one i haven't tried that
one you
[Applause]
[Music]
Oh
yes yeah so we loaded on this laptop
right and the song is you don't really
specific that you need us to like the
memory using before okay it's being here
already the last speaker for lighting