as you know this is the microkernel and
component-based architecture ich room so
I'm going to talk about microkernel um
can be expected I do not know everything
about that microkernel so if you have
questions feel free to ask them if I
look stupid and and try to when I try to
answer don't be surprised
so what's redox redox it is a
microkernel yeah big surprise it's
rooted in rust and one of the leading
objectives was to not compromise on
safety so also an interesting thing
about the design of redox is that we are
trying to be UNIX most of the micro
kernels I know of not all of them are
trying to be not UNIX they are trying to
be their own thing which is entirely
fine we went in the direction of trying
to be kind of UNIX not entirely UNIX but
kind of UNIX what does this mean it
means basically that everything in the
file is a file not necessarily a file
based on disk but it's a file in its
current state
it runs on existing Hardware I actually
don't remember the list of architectures
not many of them but at least x86 64 and
arm and remembers version of arm it's a
clean slate implementation as many
projects around here
it's young I don't remember exactly when
it started but I pretty sure it's less
than one year old so expect that more
than one you're wrong ok fair enough
so the repos are less than one year old
so anyway expect that there are still
holes in it as you can see from my lack
of knowledge of the history of free
docks
I'm less than one year old in that
project as I say it's young so things
are missing
it's full-featured enough that there is
a bare-bones browser working on it in
graphical mode but it's still pretty
pretty bare-bones at the moment and it's
MIT licensed I've gathered the list of
about 40 contributors I'm probably
missing a few but that's roughly the
number of people who have contributed to
the project so just yeah it exists it
exists you can take screen captures of
this the best demo being the web browser
but I'm not going to give it today too
many changes of me screwing things up
okay so this is the microkernel rule I
don't know whether people are here
because they know about microkernels or
because they want to know about
Nocturnals so just in case I prepare a
few slides but for people who want to
know about
microkernels I'm not going to say much
about them but I'm going to explain to
you why micro kernels are cool and in
particular in the domain of IOT which
interests me I mean that's why I have
this t-shirt so the idea of a
microkernel is to remove as many things
as you can from the kernel and put it in
userland
so regular processes some micro kernels
are extreme and managed to remove even
memory and any kind of manual memory
allocation from the kernel we're not
that far we might reach that far
someday possibly but we're not there yet
in particle this means that file systems
are not privileged they're just regular
processes drivers are not privileged
there are regular processes some parts
of the notion the very notion of
security can
processes and microkernels are cool
microkernels I mean there is of course
the fact that micro criminals are
obviously cool if you can remove
something from a place where it's
privileged and put it where it's not
privileged of course it's good
why well one of the reasons it's cool
it's actually because you cannot upgrade
your smartphone I mean most smartphones
have it cannot be upgraded for you for
more than a few months maybe two years
why is that they are I think every
single one of them based on a monolithic
kernel which pretty much always needs to
be patched I mean unless you're apple
and you own the kernel you are running a
custom curve because you probably need a
patch from this version of Linux and one
another one from that version of Linux
they're not together for in the upstream
version so you need to customize it also
you have an extremely exclusive
licensing agreement with where whichever
manufacturer and you have some new
camera or may mean it's not a new camera
but just the camera was not supported
and not supported by your kernel so you
need a device driver that's somehow not
in the kernel at this stage you have
lost unless you are willing to hire
people who can manage to get your code
up strength and that's a pretty smaller
community than people who can quick
things together because typically you're
going to write patches and they're going
to stay in your custom version of the
kernel which is kind of ok until the
kernel evolves because sometimes you
know kernels are patched by upstream
that happens kind of often if you need
to deal with your patches and the
upstream patches ok you are have reached
the stage where
you need someone full-time just to deal
with resolution of dispatches know the
drivers evolve in ways that may or may
not be compatible with these various
evolutions of the kernel you have
security issues of your own and pretty
soon you need to be come a tournament in
here you need to maintain a kernel
maintainer for your device but true for
smartphones that's going to be also true
for smart fridges smart
scary stuff that is looking at me when
I'm taking my shower or smart whatever
you have a problem I mean okay if you're
a big company you can do it but if
you're a small outfit if you're if your
startup if you're doing this on your own
if you want to provide support you have
lost at some point you're good not going
to be able to track upstream patches and
combine them with your patches it's just
too much effort so one of the reasons
why micro kernels are great is that they
make things these kind of things
possible just the fact of tracking
upstream fixes so in the world of IOT
it's not necessarily just IOT but that
is exacerbated in the case of IOT oh by
the way just one quote a few months ago
we had the presentation we have the
Linux kernel recipes conference in our
office in Paris and one of the things
they said they are very aware of this
problem and one of the things they said
is the only reasons for which we do not
have widespread attacks on smartphones
at the moment or small devices at the
moment is that people throw away their
smart phone faster than people write
viruses
that's a pretty bad reason and that does
not fail up two fridges because the
light on your fridge is slightly higher
than the lifetime of your smartphone so
back to microkernels why are our core
criminals great in that context because
anything you have customized what ok
maybe not anything but there are very
good chances that the things that you
have customized live out of the kernel
they'll even user net and certainly
things communicate using API is that do
not need die knowing that do not break
when you upgrade something so you can
upgrade independently the kernel the
drivers your code without friction this
has effects on life patching too and
also this has effects on safety and
security and there is another reason
which is actually cool too is that since
your kernel is small since you can
pretty much easily pick what you put in
your distribution well you can probably
trim your distribution to something
small well I make no promise here but
that sounds reasonable
so other reason for which micro kernels
are great in terms of safety and
security micro kernel means that you
have a much smaller trusting to trusted
computing base the kernel is easier to
read to audit to check to it's easier to
run static or dynamic analysis on it and
in many systems the worst that can
happen to your security is your your
kernel is compromised
since you have moved many things away
from your kernel a compromised in a
driver is not the same thing anymore as
a compromise in the kernel same thing
for file systems even better than that
compromised in a driver is not the same
thing out there's a compromise in the
file system and vice versa so you have
isolated stuff which makes it much
harder to attack to get to grab a
foothold in your system for an allegory
also having clear separation in
processes means that if you invest in
this
as if you spend time freaking your
operating system for that you can
actually track more easily things like
how did the attacker break to the system
what did it compromise what do I need to
shut down can I survive away with
shutting down is part of the system with
rebooting them can I track the taint of
the attack ok that was all about
microkernels let me tell you why ROC
sorry white rest rocks I'm trying not to
make too much propaganda so let me
rephrase this let me tell you why rust
is a good candidate for people who are
interested in writing code at the level
of a microkernel or January operating
system development rust is a new
programming language it has reached even
1.15 I think this week it's designed to
be both safe fast and high-level fast is
one of the reasons for which it's fast
it manages to have zero cost
abstractions in most cases not all of
them but most of them I'll show you an
example soon zero cost safety in many
cases so safety is enforced by the
compiler by static analysis in really
many cases which saves you from having
to implement things in your code which
also saves you from forgetting to check
things the objective of the arrest team
is to provide an alternative to C++ not
necessary to see but to C++ for a broad
range of programming applications again
not all of them and one of the nice
things is that the compiler it can be
scripted to pretty high levels which
means that for instance in theory I
don't think that anyone has done it yet
but you could even implement things like
address space randomization and things
like this in the compiler which is also
good for security
so here is a quick example of zero cat
abstraction this a bit contrived example
so we take the list of integers do I
have some kind of pointer no this takes
a list of integers from I'm going to
succeed if the vintage is from 1 to 100
keep only the ones not even once
sorry fair enough 1 to 99 then divide by
2 everything and then print them all so
not a very interesting example in the
per se but if you disassemble it you
essentially realize that these lines
take zero assembly instructions and this
line is basically the entire loop that
runs this and that which among other
things means that there are no memory
locations here no hidden costs and the
for function calls are pretty much the
printing stuff and converting a number
to a string and then displaying stuff a
string which is pretty good
I mean you can of course get reach the
same result in C but having obstructions
when you're using them correctly is very
useful
very short example of safety it's pretty
common to have to process IDs in kernels
a process ID is typically an integer if
you use integers everywhere you can
screw this up by I don't know doing
parts or aromatics by accident on
process IDs or whatever I mean anything
can happen so many programming languages
I mean pretty much all programming
languages process provide at least some
way of encapsulating your PID sorry of
not addressing this exactly as integers
well this is how Russ does this so the
interesting part being does this
operation increment which actually looks
like it's creating a data structure to
get a new value of the integers etc it's
actually compiled exactly the same way
as a classical one would be compiled in
C so the compiler will tell you if you
mistake a PID for general integers and
but it's actually going to generate the
same code again you can do this in other
languages ref is convenient it makes
this easy but it's definitely not the
only languages that really let you do
that another example this is an example
of allocating a pointer and so this box
new allocates the simplest kind of
pointer in rest we put here 40 to
indicate in the in here and in some case
with a locate the pointer the compiler
will refuse to compile this because it's
telling you that this value the pointer
has actually been so the term in rest is
moved so drop which has the allocated
the pointer has actually eaten the
pointer there is at least one path that
has it on the pointer so this function
call this expression makes no sense and
the compiler is going to really reject
that expression
and the same kind of mechanisms work
very well to discuss threat safety here
you have located the same pointer and
you are changing it in another thread so
in this example because nobody's s
exists in the world that might work but
in general that's probably not good
because who does this point you belong
to does it belong to this thread or to
that thread so you can specify that it
belongs to the thread that you have just
pwned in which case the compiler would
let you safely use it so you have
allocated it on one thread but then you
only use it on the other thread that's
okay you have a zero cost zero cost here
you don't need a mutex or anything and
it's going to let you run your code of
course if you try to use it on the
process on the thread that has allocated
it it's going to tell you again oh sorry
this has moved this has been eaten by
the thread so please rewrite your code
you could of course either also shared
pointers etc but if you start having
side effects to winning the mutex or an
atomic value which is exactly what you
expect okay back to redux
as I mentioned so microkernel is all
about moving things in user space this
being UNIX family operating system well
everything is most mostly a synonym of
file systems and files so as in many
modern unix's you can have several file
systems coexisting in the same world on
the same system
redox supports this by plugging file
systems so the difference between the
main difference between this and say
what happens in most unix's or Linux is
that each file system is explicitly so
each path is explicitly prefixed by a
URL scheme that tells you which other
file systems handles this path so maybe
you're interested on the file in a file
that's what people commonly call a file
so something that's on your hard drive
so it's the file scheme or maybe you
want to pipe it's a different scheme or
maybe you are looking for the random
number generator it's a different scheme
each of these schemes is implemented by
a process I mean you could write a
process that implements several of them
but that probably doesn't that could
happen so plug your processes in
userspace the kernel itself tracks file
descriptors so it guarantees that file
descriptors cannot be forged it helps
you with its issues fresh numbers for
each process it knows what each number
sorry
if you closed if a producer and process
closes a file with file descriptor 52:42
it knows our 42 for this process
is implemented by that process so it
basically routes
fiscals to the corresponding processes
most of the Cisco's in redox are
actually implemented by a simple route
to the sorry a simple check of memory
and then a route that are routed to the
implementation of the file system so
again the kernel only handles pretty
much the Scriptures registration and
dispatching everything else is
implemented by each process so the
actual notion of path can be widely
different from one process to another
one
everything that's dealing with access
control is implemented by the file
proper by the schema sorry so by the
implementation of the file system and
that works nicely so if we look at
drivers know so just as we have
pluggable user space file systems we
have pluggable user space drivers the
kernel itself basically the only thing
it does is address mapping so as in I
want to use to map this physical address
which corresponds to with this physical
device and I want to be able to read and
write it that's basically all that the
kernel does for drivers and then there
are interruptions but since everything
in the everything is a file
interruptions are just a file system
drivers themselves everything is a file
so a driver is a file system so if you
want to access the graphics card you're
going to use your currently your visa
file system to send instructions to a
graphics card
having everything as file system
simplifies the life in a number of cases
such as not needing to introduce
gazillions of new Siskel's we have
simple tracking of who's using what
again one abstraction having just one
abstraction make things easier one of
the things we are interested in and
that's I'm working on this at the moment
so it's very much not landed yet is
capabilities so recover view of
capabilities of sorry of capability
based security so just for people who
know about projects capabilities that's
not the same thing at all just happen to
use the same name the notion of
capabilities is something that actually
comes from programming languages
initially so a security capability is
the unforgeable right to do something
typically in a programming language well
in an object-oriented programming
language you're going to have objects
with private fields and the capability
to access something is if you have a
handle on one of these objects and there
is a public method that lets you somehow
affect the private data or you read the
private data then you have the
capability to read that private or to
write that private data or if you're not
do in a programming language with
objects but one with closures exact
exact same thing capabilities you can
use them to do something you can it's
quite important you can share them so as
soon as you have the ability sorry to
read that data well you can read the
data on behalf of someone else and you
can possibly give that ability to the
other person you can use it you can
share it you can of course stop having
it and you can possibly weaken it maybe
you have the ability to read and write
that data and just you want to only keep
the ability to read it that works too
that's the kind of thing if you need to
implement this in a program England in
whichever is your favorite roaming
programming language you'll manage if
you want to use the to do this in your
favorite operating system that's harder
there are a number of operating systems
that offer capabilities several them
have been discussed today in this room
that they're not that many of them in
total
oh sorry forgot what's the point of
having capabilities the point of having
capabilities if you look at it from a
point of view of safety and security is
that pretty much anything can serve as
sandbox for anything if there is in
other words in programming languages if
there are no global variables but only
local variables then your the function
you're calling if it does not have
access to any global variable there are
limits to how bad it can behave it
cannot have side effects in safe
language that are not on the arguments
you pass to it or you have some hope as
to it it's critical if you want to
analyze the behavior of your code both
statically and globally sorry both
statically and dynamically and again I
mentioned that having a microkernel
could help you with looking at changing
of compromised processes well that's
that's here also the same thing the more
you make dependencies explicit the more
you can analyze changing so in the UNIX
world typical UNIX implementations do
not have this kind of capabilities the
closest thing you have is file
descriptors but then any of my
applications by default I mean on Linux
can read any of my files so that's a
very very broad capability restricting
this is pretty hard so there are
attempts to make things
finer but the only implementation of
capability is the only full
implementation of capabilities for UNIX
that I know of is capsicum and it's
pretty sophisticated and it is all the
entire network the inter Sri kernel of
Linux or I think it's FreeBSD one of the
BSD I'm not sure exactly which one so
let's look at how we could implement
them in redox I mean there are patches
while they're having several prototypes
but nothing landed so far so in the
world of UNIX everything is a capability
great sorry everything in finest crater
great so a capability is a file
descriptor
the final scripture that opens readme
dot text is the capability to read in
that file descriptor or to write in that
file descriptor but we can extend this
since well since Redux has a pretty open
to interpretation of what a file what a
path is the idea here is to introduce
path and file descriptors that represent
the opera's ation to do something so for
instance this path
so file my directory store the text
reader well it's a glob say that says I
have the authorization to read all the
text files in the directory that's
something that would be interpreted by
the file system so not part of the
kernel so far we have not patched the
current model what we actually have one
patch one patch which tell which tells
the kernel here I can open this file
because I have that capability so this
is using a capability of weakening
capability into actually doing something
the only patch in the kernel at the
moment is just rooting that information
and checking that the file descriptors
match the file system is in charge of
ensuring that this policy is a proof
that you can do that again delegate as
much as possible of security to user
name then of course we have the problem
of distributing these capabilities in
the first place and for this we
introduced essentially a variant of
pipes which currently have the name
cables and a cable is used to drag a
file descriptor across processes so
that's something that you can do in
POSIX using sockets but this is more
much more restricted version that also
doesn't require your privileges
trivially you can exchange file
descriptors with your children if you
have a cable established and well since
everybody is the child of someone and
ability is somehow the sibling or cousin
etc of someone if you want to introduce
a communication from point A to point B
if everybody in the path agrees you can
get one might take a few steps to
establish the community initial
communication but then after that you
have a direct communication and this so
I mentioned that we are there many
things that are not implemented yet so
we do not have a full IPC yet but this
would probably be the first step of our
IPC at least for establishing the IPC
okay so I'm going to start wrapping up
so redux it uses a microkernel to reduce
the TCB because we want to be safe it
uses rust to make the TC bit more
trustworthy because we want to be safe
there are many things to do left in if
you want to help us yeah you can find us
over there thank you for having listened
[Applause]
if you have any questions I'm all yours
yes sir as far as I know it nobody has
benchmark it yet I'm not optimistic but
I know that some people are optimistic
so you get you have all the information
I have now yes so if your route it's
easy you can do anything so there is an
implementation I don't know how final it
is in which any user can locally for the
children of a specific process install
an implementation of a file system so
you have a local implementation of a
file system sorry I didn't
in what in which context I missed half
of your question sir yes soulless so
it's attached to your user instead of
being attached to a process is that what
you're saying yes what does it change
but here we're not to be able to manage
things
that's what okay so that specific
example is home but you could of course
do something entirely different you
could so are we still talking about
installing file systems or are we
talking about okay so for instance let's
say I change my heart and return to
being a Firefox developer Firefox has
any basically kind of operating system
running inside an operating system needs
to be able to send box things in
internally so the boundary is not the
home file system or the home directory
the boundary is things that can run on
the web things that can run as add-ons
think that can run as the browser and
these are entirely different boundaries
so you typically might want some of your
web stuff to access the phone directory
for instance for reading but possibly
not all of the web stuff things like
that so you want something it's pretty
fine-grained so I think that word has
something for that but I'm not sure okay
you're doing your jail is that it yeah
so that's yeah that's a higher it's a
more heavy-handed approach in your case
which again it works we're trying to do
something more flexible
oh that's quite possible actually I
believe that we can implement jigs using
that too so I'm not sure that maybe
there are just equivalent to it we can
discuss that so fine yes so yes so so
rest has at least three no four moment
too but there is a third one distributed
layers of how much you can build in so
you can either put the full kitchen sink
I mean the full standard library or you
can get only the core library which is
designed for embedding which is what we
are using and there is a proposal for
something even smaller than the core
library but oh nice I said we are
proposal something smaller I don't think
it's implemented yet I don't think they
have a fixed list of what it is but the
I mean I know people who actually do
embedding with the embedding library it
works I does it's answer your question
because I could not give you the number
of lines
[Music]
yes so that's basically the difference
between the core library and the
standard library but there is something
even smaller than the core library and I
don't know it don't remember exactly the
difference maybe you want to provide
your home your own we are from zero
point zero point seven so far I mean
there is the redox kernel you could put
anything on top of it we have a number
of utilities on top of it I don't think
you have plants that go quite that far
yet
I think anything can be changed at that
stage if you want to download an ISO
it's going to come with a few standard
stuff of course but that's the best
answer I can give you at the moment
sorry that was someone here that's a
good question so actually have been out
of touch for one month so it's quite
possible that everything has changed in
the meantime
but things such as so going further into
jail or our capabilities or things in
that direction there are attempts to try
to reduce the size of the kernel
microkernel further and reduce number of
Cisco's for instance there is some magic
involved in pipe at the moment and we'd
like to get rid of that magic things
like that there was something else
important in that direction I don't
remember exactly what I tell you if I oh
there are people who want to work on
getting rid of memory memory allocations
inside the kernel I don't know if there
are actually going to work on this but
they said they are interested that's one
direction the other direction is we want
to have a full-featured web server
Redux and we are pretty close to this
actually because we already have the all
the IO layers maybe it has been finished
in the last month I don't know I mean I
think a person who wanted that told me
and who's our benevolent dictator for
life said he could have something done
at the end of March
maybe it's done already I don't know so
these are the general ideas yes the all
the platform stuff is well as related so
I know that it's ported on several
platforms already I have not even looked
at these directories at all so I cannot
tell you the actual difficulty I know it
needs an MMU things like that I don't
remember what nips has I think I don't
have anything
each other I think um I mean I haven't
she was missing 10 years so but I'm sure
I think nips has everything that's
needed so I don't know it has a too many
cooperations right so I think that's all
that's reading medium - so you have my
best guess there was a question over
there yes
oh that's very easy
100% rests oh I mean okay sorry no there
isn't the architecture part so it's like
there are five files or something
written in assembly no no see in between
I mean rest basically produces C code so
there is no reason to do see the worst
case you can do if you won't really want
to do rest is put everything annotate
everything is unsafe and actually write
C code with the rest centers
[Music]
so for the most part we're going our own
way we sometimes do read papers from
other stuff but it's mostly the idea
mostly work let's not hide it this is an
open source project we're having fun so
the objective is not to do the same
thing the exact same thing as someone
else we can draw inspiration but that's
we try not to do the same thing thank
you very much