so a service industry stymie how I
worked I work in Kimble company I am a
contributor of kubernetes currently but
before I was contributing to OpenStack
and mostly to OpenStack Cola projects
which parks the OpenStack components
into docker containers and runs
OpenStack as in container environment
and I'm working for kimbop which is a
company based in Berlin we are doing
general Linux related development but
the most of work done bulk invoke is
visible in rocket project but also in
system D or with scope and you can check
our activity on our block you can check
our github as everything we are doing is
open-source or you can just write us an
email if you have some questions
regarding a company so I will start with
explaining some basic concepts around my
presentation
first of all container and virtual
machine I think that most of you know
that difference so I'll not focus on
that that much but you know container
doesn't use any new kernel insights and
virtual machine uses the separate
operating system and is simulating the
hardware container is just isolating
several things in Linux system and by
cloud I mean any kind of service which
is provided over network to the user and
user doesn't have to know where the
service is actually provided in case of
container based clouds
container-based cloud is cloud
environments where the user demands some
containers and doesn't have to know
where where they are physically located
this they are scheduled automatically
and though today there were a lot of
talks about kubernetes that's the most
popular container based clouds system
which is open source but there is also
misses and locust swarm and there are
two are machine based clouds OpenStack
is the most popular of them from the
open source project from no open clouds
which are focused mostly on virtual
machine there is AWS and there ec2
service and yes what is the problem and
what I try to address the problem is
that these clouds container and virtual
machine-based are separate so for
running a cloud consisting conference
over to our machines booted from some
kyouko or raw images you use OpenStack
for for running containers you use
kubernetes
and yeah it's very hard to maintain a
single environment single infrastructure
which provides both of them to the user
and that's the problem I would like to
address so how to create about genius
cloud environments which addresses both
VMs and containers and one of the
answers which is implemented in several
ways and I will show them is putting
virtual machine inside container it
sounds crazy but it works and it's in my
opinion makes sense and I will explain
it in this presentation but first of all
let's beginning with question what needs
to be
to run a virtual machine inside
container
what what does the what characterizes
that container which can is able to run
virtual machines first of all it has to
be privileged so we need to give the
most of Linux capabilities to that it
needs an access to see groups because
for example libvirt is using c groups
for resource management for virtual
machines it spans for queuing processes
response we need also to provide an
access to all the needed devices we
would like to share with VMs and if we
want to use kvn we need to also share
the kvn devices it's yeah it's just a
device in the dev directory and here
comes the question whether this idea of
putting VMS inside containers whether it
improves security somehow mmm and the
obvious answer is no that's because it's
privileged it has access to the devices
it has an access to see groups and
that's why if someone gets inside the
container in virtual machine we should
assume that he has an access to the node
to the host so it doesn't provide any
security the idea of packing virtual
machine inside container is only for
simplifying things and creating a
homogeneous environment but the security
of VMs
is the same and we should care about
bugs in any software which manages our
virtual machines or runs it so how to do
that and how to use the concept of
continue rising virtual machines in the
cloud environments there are two most
popular ways first of them is to put
every qmo process in the separate
container and the second one is to just
put Liberty demon inside container and
have mana qmo processes inside that one
container with liber8 in case of qmo in
container we have in this case we have
some hosts I'm not we have two or more
qmo containers and which run the virtual
machine and the two most known examples
of cloud systems which are using that
approach first of them is Borg so Google
Borg internally for virtualization is
using containers and this putting each
virtual machine beside another container
and just scheduled them as the other
containers and also Ranger OS has a
control plane for virtual machines and
it's using exactly the same approach and
they have a docker image for with qmo
you can you can even just pull it and
write in docker run Rancher VM something
something else you have run in virtual
machine and the advantage of that is
that we don't rely on any other tool for
managing this lifecycle at the lifecycle
of VM and if we for example should dump
devi empty queue amma process jettison
goes down and for docker or any
container runtime system mmm it's just
closed it's just a shutdown of container
and then in the same way you Burnett
and the other container cluster systems
see that fact but there are two
disadvantages the first of them is that
you have to somehow manage the images so
if you have kubernetes environment in
which you would like to run the
containers with VMs you need to somehow
provide the Kiko or roll images and if
you are developing such a solution you
need to somehow provide the image
service for that and you have to put
your own efforts on providing the
external storage and play with qmo
options in case of clifford in container
we assume that every node in the cloud
is running one level container so in
case of cube entities it could be daemon
set and there are a lot of human
children of liberal libertage as their
lives their life cycle and the most all
examples of that are the the most known
example is OpenStack Cola project which
I mentioned on the introduction of
myself so it's project which contain
arises the OpenStack at they also have
an option to run open stack on top of
kubernetes and there is also valid which
is a project that aims to run which aims
to make a VM a native citizen of
kubernetes so it's implementing the VM
pot feature and there is also a cube
root project which the guys developing
developing it's had a presentation
yesterday and the virtual machine and
infrastructure-as-a-service
track
and yeah main advantages is that Liberty
provides an abstraction for managing
images it manages the remote storage and
it's much easier than dealing with cuomo
directly but on the other hand you need
to somehow interact with that libvirt
which is itself a layer of abstraction
so it's not very easy to decide whether
we go with qm wobble or libvirt there
are some projects which is the first
approach there are some projects which
are using the approach of liberal tents
we may see in the future which approach
was better and which layer of
abstraction provided more problems so
how exactly it relates the clouds as I
mentioned where that is a project which
uses waves in kubernetes and how it do
that it uses the container random
interface there was a presentation today
explaining what it is but I will explain
it quickly quickly
so CRI is a mechanism in cuba Nettie's
which allows you to write your own
server which provides some run a runtime
service to kubernetes by the photo
kubernetes uses docker so if you run
some port on kubernetes you receive a
bunch of docker containers running
somewhere in the cluster by sierra you
can replace that with any kind of
runtime system you want this is how it
looks or in notes in kubernetes there is
a cubelet which is daemon managing a
lifecycle of the container and mode so
it's only receives information
from keep scheduler what it has to do
and the most not example of this Eri
service is rocket lat which uses rocket
but for virtual machines you can also
use CRI and just by getting a definition
of thoughts run the virtual machine and
interact with liber8 instead of rockets
so these things work but do we really
need such an inception it may be sounds
crazy because why do we need to run
virtual machine is inside container but
I think we need this inception because
the goal of Cuban Nettie's and container
management system are is to be as small
as possible and do not implement a more
complicated logic instead of that they
want to give the people the opportunity
to create this logic itself a good
example is concept of operators there
were a bunch of talks in this truck
about an operator about operators and
there they are using kubernetes but they
prevent they prevent kubernetes itself
of being too big so that's why cuber
Nettie's community doesn't implement
logic of upgrading stateful applications
except the accept the concept of state
who says but that's why people are
moving more complicated deployment logic
to outside things like operators and I
think that we should see any solution
trying to run a virtual machine inside
container as a solution of such kind so
we are just using the simple
of kubernetes to achieve something more
complicated and we just add one layer of
obstruction to achieve something which
gives profits because I think that
separation between VM clouds and
container clouds it's a huge problem
which some which even somehow may
prevent some people from thinking about
using kubernetes if they are using a lot
of VMs and have an instructor structure
acting with just virtual machines so
unfortunately I cannot show a demo
because I have no adapter for my laptop
yes BC so we try to be before the talk
unfotunately I cannot show it demo on my
laptop we have some time so I can there
is a one demo on github over that how it
works
so
okay
you see everything okay it's maybe that
would be better so in this demo first of
all we run the vert led server and then
start the local kubernetes cluster and
after that we have a definition of pot I
will try to stop it here yeah so this is
just an usual pot where we define a
container named Fedora it uses the
fedora image which is served by some
high HTTP server it's just a nickel oh
maybe that will work so display port
and now it's the CBC I'm not I'm dubious
this didn't work before
oh it's just DisplayPort let's display
okay so yeah yet another try off say
week my demo okay so that's the
definitional pot and we can just create
the spots by cube City air create and it
will work let me continue until more and
it takes some time to run the virtual
machine that's first why for some time
the container is in creating state knots
after 14 seconds it's became running now
we can get into the container so that's
why there is docker compose exactly Bert
brush list so the leopard is the name of
container which runs liberal and yeah we
can also access a console no kind of
container and rights revert
okay here's just slow typing okay and I
can also show you I have a project just
called da curly beard which is very tiny
docker environment for putting liberated
container just to not make docker run
comments very long I noted this
definition insights docker compose and
file so I exposed part of libvirt here
there are the necessary mounts I
mentioned in my presentation and there
are also volumes for libvirt were the
actual instances and disks for livers
are stored so we can just use named
volumes for that and I have also here a
start script which wraps libvirt here I
do some magic with detecting whether
which type of processor we haven't which
KVM module I have to load and also some
necessary chmod CH routes for
configuration files that's because if
you mount some fire to the container in
docker there is no way to define to
which user it should belong and what's
the whatever the permissions for the
file so if we are mounting this
configuration files here we need to CH
more than inside start script
and the configuration of liberals of q
and q mo is very small so for liber8 we
just wants to make it listen on the
sockets so we can contact with libvirt
outside the container to not have to
enter the container every time and just
is be able to use verge on the host or
even invert them in a graphic of
virt-manager
on the host and we have also here no
config which defines the here's our
group and that's that example i
mentioned also about Qbert project so
the definite so the difference between
birth and Qbert is that benefit as a CSO
on the demo uses a pop definition for
running the virtual machines Qbert uses
third party resources for that not so
I'm not going to explain it in details
because Q Bert was explains yesterday on
the talk
let's go back to pre presentation that's
unfortunately all I wanted to to show
I'm sorry again for not showing you live
demo from my laptop we have any
questions yes so the use case is okay so
the question was why do I even want to
run rahama she's in the containerized
environments and what's the use case for
that use case for that is I think the
migration between virtual machines in
containers so some company which was
using virtual machines for a long time
thinks about kubernetes doesn't really
want to manage to separate clouds for a
long future and they want to be able to
use keyboard Nettie's but on the at the
same time provides some option for
virtual machine a traditional virtual
machine users without necessity of
maintaining the virtual machine oriented
cloud I realized that it's not a problem
in case of a WS or clouds which are not
managed by also but I think that you
know using kubernetes as a main
infrastructure without managing separate
OpenStack for example without having
eight roles in top of kubernetes or
using something else like virtual for
meter machine I think it's really
simplifies things and that it's my
assumption maybe I am wrong but that's
the idea I have behind it
this is very clearly here and dear to
our hearts and four of us a lot of this
work fits into our work and Crockett is
our project and I spoke earlier today
about operators like this kind of
dovetails under that as well and you've
touched on this a little but I want to
make sure we draw it out one of the
reasons why you would want to package
virtual machines and in containers has
little to do with what you think there
was the execution isolation the
convenience of packaging and
distribution the ability to do
verification on that package that's at
the street can discretize package and
most importantly to schedule it
dynamically around grid compute
resources with an orchestration system
like kubernetes so the units of
scheduling the thing we know how to move
around between computers in these
systems is a container not a virtual
machine right so that is a whole other
set of reasons why we would want to
package virtual machines inside
containers is to give a handle to
orchestration systems on legacy
applications that that exist at this
time already in virtual machines you get
the container around them as a package
and now you can schedule them
dynamically on on your cluster resources
the way you can containerized
applications which certainly he touched
on but I want to make sure to kind of
bring out and put a nail on top for now
it doesn't but both effortless and cubed
words want to address it somehow then
I'm sorry again I probably I keep
forgetting about it the question was
whether we want to address more
complicated operations for each Ramos is
like life immigration for example and
that isn't implemented yet I think in
of projects but the most probably we
will need external controller similar to
operator which will consume the
third-party resource called live
migration or something like that and
call live with API underneath what about
scaling so the question was what about
the other operations like scaling over
to our machines and to be honest I
didn't think about it yet and yes but
life I probably liked migration would be
the first you know more complicated
feature of virtual machines which will
be total Bart project and it's I think
designs now and maybe implemented in the
near future okay
like this because unless you so the
question was the question the that Aziz
was that putting open or open stuck
inside kubernetes doesn't simplify
things because you still have Nova you
still have heat and a lot of components
and it doesn't really simplify things
for the operators I only provided Cola
as an example worklet project isn't
using OpenStack at all so I just wanted
to make this presentation you like
objective don't promote a single
solution but yeah if you want to throw a
throw out OpenStack er very sweet
okay so part of why we invested a lot of
time and effort and and and friends of
ours in the community and contractors
and other folks we've worked with invest
a lot of time and effort specifically in
porting OpenStack the OpenStack control
plane into containers and running it as
a kubernetes application is actually
that our findings are quite contrary to
what your suspicions are by unifying
around a single management interface
that is the kubernetes api by deploying
OpenStack which is just a bunch of
applications as wonderful as it seems
and as magical as it seems because it's
a VM management system all it really is
is a big stack of Python apps so we put
them in containers we've run them on
kubernetes we schedule them with
kubernetes we recover from failure which
are quite frequent in those Python apps
with kubernetes and actually we've found
and and I think there's there's a fair
amount of stuff on the core OS comm blog
about the the project between Koro asked
in bulk Intel the rocket open source
project and all of the pieces that fit
into to the OpenStack port for
kubernetes the finding actually is that
we reduce the administrative overhead by
unifying around a single cluster
management interface instead of trying
to deploy OpenStack applications in an
open stack silo outside of kubernetes so
that's like the aims there to to answer
the speculation that that adds to
complexity and what only to make things
more difficult all I could do is
encourage you to grab the stuff and try
it out and see if if you find that
that's true
okay so tenant application payloads the
folks you're serving they still consume
OpenStack api's and schedule their
virtual machines through the OpenStack
facilities well actually let me back up
for a minute there it is not necessarily
true that customer VMs are running
inside containers when we're kind of
talking about two separate things here
and would blended the issue together a
little bit the talk is about running VMs
inside containers the OpenStack work
which relates to it and encompasses it
to run parts of the control plane in
terms of containers does not necessarily
imply that your end user your customer
VMs are packaged in containers they are
VMs consumed from OpenStack scheduled
with OpenStack but running on high on
top of the on top of the hypervisor at
least in being virtual machines yes so
is that a better answer and then that
gets more than no yeah buts
because no no I think that doesn't
relate if you want to use the concept of
tenants for VMs like in OpenStack you
can run open stuck on the kubernetes and
just provides the OpenStack control
plane to the end user and thread the
whole kubernetes stack running this
thing on for your internal operators so
that's why I wanted to put the things
neutral if someone needs OpenStack I
think they should be free to use almost
like if not then not different people
have different needs
thank you