[Music]
instead of students and he did do some
of code for Google and at that time he
has the opportunity to dig into
scientific computing and so you see that
he has a quite good understanding of
scientific computing Thanks
hi I am per soon and I'll be talking
about scientific computing on JRuby so
the main objective of this talk is to to
tell you tell you how to create a great
gem or two that uses JRuby and that can
that's really highly efficient and has a
very good speed and this is all because
the scientific library that I worked on
is memory intensive and speed counts so
I'd like to share my experiences with
that next I will be introducing
introducing you to the general-purpose
GPU liability that I worked on and this
this was after my G sock and this
library can be used for industry in
production and academia for research and
yes it can be integrated with rails so
side Ruby is also called as Ruby Science
Foundation and it has been trying to
push Ruby for scientific computing some
of the popular side Ruby gems that we
have currently are n matrix taru mixed
models may applaud ipython notebook and
many more
so these are the most commonly used ones
so what n matrix is and matrix is a side
obols numerical matrix code it helps you
to perform linear algebra calculations
on your CPU and it has support for both
dense matrices and sparse matrices
basically it helps you to analyze
matrices which you might have studied in
your high school where you used to solve
linear equations using matrices and n
matrix later for MRI relies on Atlas C
plus C lapak and standard lapak
libraries for its core linear algebra
operations this libraries are
state-of-the-art libraries because they
are written in Fortran and are highly
efficient and are used for number
crunching so this is how you use an n
matrix gem you just require it and in
the first one second line of code I
create an n matrix this you can see that
it's a two dimensional matrix of three
rows and three columns followed by the
element it contents and the type of the
matrix is float64 which is actually
double so double is used for scientific
computing because it has the high
precision and you can't use simply float
32 or float so I created a matrix of
three by three you can see that it's a
row major format one two three four five
six and eight nine I and in the next
line of code I just add these two
matrices and in the third line of code I
calculate the determinant of this matrix
next daaru daaru is what pointer is for
a scifi it helps you to load data into a
data into a data frames from say X excel
file or CSV files or PSD files and then
you can analyze this data so in this
code what I've done is that I simply
require daaru in the second line I just
load this data from alien space is dot
CSV and next I do is that I create a
vector and I just I just show this data
frame now next is mixed models so after
you have loaded that data maybe you want
to perform some computations like model
this data so this can be done by mixed
models m and in this code i ice weekly
we try to calculate the fixed effects
and random effects of this model and
this we can also use this to predict for
some random data next is an a float any
scientific library is not successful
unless we have some great visualization
tools nap plots fix this gap for side
ooby it's used for 2d and 3d wave
plotting and it's compared on the top of
d3 next why you should use side would be
instead of SCI pipe simply because we
love Ruby we loved aids and
expressiveness of Ruby you can use when
you collect large amount of data from a
rails app you can just feed this data
into our into a guru data frame and then
you can perform computations and you can
use this that was an analytics tool next
is JRuby my project was to offer jisuk
was to put and matrix to JRuby and
basically sigh ruby was trying to push
push it's gem towards JRuby runtime
because of the speed it's actually 10
times faster than 0 beyond certain
aspects and with truffled ruby it's
around 40 times faster and right now we
just heard that it's gonna be around 26
times faster for just JRuby classic so
this bird I like to call it as the
roadrunner because I'm just dealing with
speed and I want to make this road and I
go beep beep so n matrix for JRuby so n
matrix for y I will build the n matrix
for JRuby because it has no global
interpreter lock as in the case of MRI
so it's a very good team player when you
have a large processor with multi-core
so you can utilize them you can
can the probe the program you developed
can be easily deployed you with the help
of Warbler Jim so you can use you can
develop any gem on JRuby or any program
in JRuby and just deploy it to a
supercomputers or cluster whatever you
have and then JRuby has Auto garbage
collection for whenever you develop a
see extension for C Ruby you have to
take care for garbage collection because
you are dealing with large data and in C
when C Ruby does the mark and sweep
model as we have heard in the previous
talk that this Markin sweep is not
really good to handle and when you have
a very large matrix say 2.5 million
elements in a matrix you can't really
mean speed is a had not good in such
cases
next is the n matrix for JRuby that I
worked on it relies on Apache Commons
map which is a Java library and it has
very high good developer activity around
this library so am da-rae
before we I built and matrix for JRuby
we had MD array that does the this is an
MD array gem that was just like what n
matrix was for C Ruby it was a the n
matrix for a JRuby so when we try to
create a unified interface for n matrix
for Ruby as well as JRuby just like
local nokogiri does it that you have a
simple gem and you can run it on both
instance tanks instances so we could
have used MD array and just built a
wrapper around it for n mate and matrix
but indeed this was this was not going
to be a good idea because it was a it
used parallel called as a dependency
just like I use Apache Commons map and
it was depreciated at the moment and
next is that every gem when you create
with the n matrix you had to replay n--
implement it using MD array if I didn't
build that apparent on MD array so you
have to put in more effort for
optimization for example you have to
check whether the data is not getting
copied
that so how n matrix works basically n
matrix can be divided into categorize
into two parts and dimensional and two
dimensional two dimensional so this is
how you an n matrix object looks like
you have it's a shape that is for
example I created a 3 by 3 matrix it
since she shape is 3 comma 3 it's D type
is float or it can be anything like int
complex like that as type is like
whether you want you want to store it as
a dense made matrix or a sparse matrix
at S is basically the storage the
elements that go into a matrix now you
have that demon atom this means that how
many dimensions you have for example 3
comma 3 is our two-dimensional matrix
next is n matrix architecture basically
we have a ruby front ender then we have
for MRI we have a shared object
extension dot s o which is built using C
and C++
now this integrates with n matrix C C
library ok sorry
native C library which are C blast OC
lapak and this C this C legacy libraries
could address connected to the Fortran
library that's blasts and lapak so
basically you have three layers and this
one the Fortran library makes is what
mixes computation go fast for JRuby we
have just extends in Georgia it it's
built upon the top of Apache Commons map
so for n dimensional matrix the major
thing operator we had to build on it was
element wise operation for example add
subtract sine or gamma and the first
slide where we added two matrixes this
was just going an element-wise operation
we iterate through the elements we
access the element do the operation and
return it so the major thing that counts
there is you have your loops should be
efficient means you can iterate through
throughout the array and whichever is
the first means whether C Ruby
so here in this slide I show you that
when I created a matrix n1 and I just
add them so n1 plus n1 you get this
matrix for example one plus one gets 2 2
plus 2 4 next what were the challenges
that we faced
first is autoboxing and multiple data
and handling multiple data types
second is minimizing the copying of data
so in JRuby we had this that when when
we tried no strict typing basically die
to die locating a data using JRuby code
we got this error for example in this
case we have an error two arrays we just
add it and if this array is smaller than
one you start getting the values as 0 so
I think Charles will answering can
answer me this question after this talk
and and if I just simply add this any
number greater than 1 to both of them
and I subtract minus 10 so I get the
correct result a next is autoboxing
so what we did was a weekly I in the as
this project was in initial stage I just
did with the float64 that is doubles
only because we had to deal with
reflection and and that's what then
forced it there we created datatypes
using Java and we couldn't rely on
reflection for large data for example if
you create storage as a de dot new and
storage a Java double with rows and
columns or new second one it will be
definitely faster because you know the
size of the array and you can move
faster through through this the second
area
so now we have auto boxing and
enumerators this is a classic case
because when we tried using an matrix
for JRuby for real data for example we
have a 5 point 5 GB 5 GB of data which
we get from a blob and when we try to
run it we get an error here you can see
this highlighted code I just created
this array as array dot new so what
happens is that you start losing
precision so if you just implement this
in using Java in Java code so here you
don't lose precision next is minimizing
the copying of data as we had heard in
the previous charger previous talk some
charge that JRuby takes more memory yeah
so basically what we are trying to do is
we take the storage we are trying to
build an enumerated enumerated that each
within deck we have to get elements by
defined by indices and if there are
blocks pass I just want to do some
computation with it so I just convert
this storage to an array and then I take
the slice index and I try to push it in
this array and here we start losing
values for example if we had the we were
trying to kill to factorize a matrix so
every time you do it if the value is
0.02 or 0.03 this gets to zero and when
when this when you are trying to
optimize something and you have to
iterate through this matrix you have to
perform the same computation through
this matrix it won't get optimized ever
because you can't just go to a silk a
convex point where the data where this
value converges so you can't reach a
minima
so next is minimizing the copying of
data so whenever you build a JRuby
application you make sure that you don't
make copies of data because already it
it consumes twice the memory than C Ruby
so if you start the making more copies
and you have a larger matrix It's Made
totally make destroy your GGC for
example there was a computation where
see Ruby takes around 50 seconds and
when I was just building n matrix for
JRuby it took me around 1.5 hours so so
after I made sure that I am not making
copies of data I took down this time to
40 seconds which was better than C Ruby
so you just pass by your friends you
just create a static method as helpers
for happy to see this example example
later so next is 2-dimensional matrix
now you have an end M dimensional matrix
and you want to perform certain
computations like you need to multiply
two matrices or you need to factorize it
then we use two we need to just cast
this one dimensional n dimensional
matrix into a two dimension matrix so
the basic operations here are dot which
is matrix multiplication our date for
the calculating determinant and
factorize Lu means lower upper
factorization so in n matrix MRI we have
Blast 3 and lapak routines that are
built in Fortran but n matrix JRuby was
the means it depends on Java functions
from Apache Commons Matz so the
challenges were as follows
you convert an N dimensional matrix into
a two dimensional matrix so actually n
dimensional matrix is stored as a 1d
array because you can't just simply
store create a multi-dimensional array
because you can't just lay down them in
the RAM properly now you have the array
size matters and you have to access the
elements with speed and you have to also
take memory in consideration so we have
an n matrix I have to I need to get a 2d
matrix from
so I used this helper functions these
are static methods for from a matrix in
little class called get matrix double
and the original class has a get era
double so in this code I'm trying to
iterate over a matrix means basically a
two-dimensional array so I just
benchmark this Ruby code you can see
that idea in the the first line of code
sorry
we have we created Java basically a two
dimensional matrix of size 15,000 15,000
so basically and I just benchmark this
code where I place I initialize the
value of this matrix as the index so
this takes me around 39 seconds and then
next I get read over two arrays where I
just copy the elements of one one array
into another so this takes me around
sixty five point one one two seconds and
five point four GB of RAM so maybe so
when you have such large matrix your Ram
your CPA your Ram will be a basic
quantity consumed by that time and you
can't do it for any number crunching to
sort program so yes so and I do this
similar thing in Java and I get for this
again that time requires 0.03 one
seconds and for the when we have two
arrays I it takes zero point zero zero
three zero three three seconds and that
I am consumed is 300 MB hence speed is
include thousand times and memories
improved ten times and this is actually
speed y is better than C Ruby but memory
Y is not as good as C Ruby its 0 C ruby
has better takes less memory but speed
is slower next
yeah fifteen thousand into fifteen
thousand which is 225 million elements
so there's another gem mixed murders
that relied on n matrix and simply by
putting n matrix I just putted this
library to JRuby to and so you can model
your data in the JRuby now well now
we've benchmark n matrix functionalities
how these are the system is
specifications we I I had an octa-core
CPU and a 16gb ram next forum in this
club you can see that the number of
elements in a matrix this is for example
fifty-five thousand by five thousand
elements we have 25 million elements in
a matrix and then the on the y-axis you
can see the computation time so let's
say the computer computation time the
better the speed so this is a
logarithmic scale so in this case n
matrix JRuby is faster than n matrix MRI
it is around sixteen forty times faster
next for subtraction we have the same
case it's a forty times faster next for
gamma we have this we compare three n
matrix MRI then n matrix JRuby and n
matrix MRI lapack you can see that on n
matrix J rube it's even faster than the
Fortran code and it's a lot faster means
it's ten times faster than n matrix MRI
and MRI lapak and for four hundred times
fast faster than this n matrix MRIs for
n matrix for matrix multiplication n
matrix JRuby losses to n matrix C Ruby
or MRI because we definitely don't have
Fortran libraries for this and so any
code any Java code can never build a
Fortran code even though we have jetting
and this code will will get improved
after running a lot of loops but still
not get better than Fortran
similarly for determinants it's again 20
times fluid for factorization it's same
20 times sewer so these are the
benchmark conclusions and matrix JRuby
is definitely faster for n dimensional
matrices and 2 dimensional matrices when
element wise operations are concerned
but n matrix MRI is faster for 2
dimensional matrices when you need to
calculate the dot or determinant or you
need to factorize it so how can we
improve this so the solution is that we
also implement the back end of n matrix
jruby with Fortran and this time it will
rely on rely on Java netic in native
interfaces and there was an option to
use another library called J blast which
has which is a j'ni for blast libraries
and lapak libraries but when I try to
use them it was it had a lot of bugs and
it was not it was not efficient enough
so this would be the final arguing
architecture of n matrix JRuby so we
took this left side of this diagram to
this right side and overall when we do
this when I try to do a sample bench map
for this it was actually faster than n
matrix MRI so maybe in two months
n matrix JRuby would be faster on all
aspects than n matrix MRI when I
implement this part of the code
so also the future work includes
implementing n matrix of complex data
type and adding space support and
convert n matrix J to be enumerators to
Java code for better speed so over all
whenever you try to do n make any n
matrix any computation using n matrix
JRuby it would be currently as far as n
matrix a see Ruby or even some times
faster because the overall calculations
that rely on
it's not a single dimension that would
be faster in case of JRuby and obviously
JIT so am I done
nope inter GPU so the google Summer of
Code I wanted to the to go even faster
for number crunching and that's why I
thought of implementing GPGPU library a
general-purpose library for GP
computations and the aim of this project
was to combine the beauty of ruby with
transparent GPU processing and yes this
will be tested on both client computers
and on servers that make use of tesla's
and Intel Xeon Phi solutions before this
and there was no Ruby project that used
AG that was good for GPU computation
maximum you could do was add two
matrices using GPU and that also
personal 4000-5000 matrix but yes the
area fire liability that RB library that
I develop can handle around fifteen
thousand to fifteen thousand elements
matrix easily and we are they get to
test it on supercomputers so what is
edified actually so era fire is an open
source GPGPU library that is written in
c++ and usage it so you using a jet
makes it even faster than CUDA and
OpenCL so yes the competitors PI CUDA
and PI opencl would be slower than a
defier RB era fire era fire has also
bindings to Python but era fire fire
python is built using sia siphon so
whenever you try to do this this code is
really not tested and try to do some
computations using adapt fire Python on
my system and actually most of the times
the program hang so and when I did the
same thing with era fire Ruby when I
built it for MRI it was it was it was
working properly and and the speed was
awesome
next is a defier Ruby can also help you
to just go and go computing without
writing kernels so whenever you try to
do GPU computing most other times you
end up writing kernels and this is a
this is where most people just lay GPU
computing but in era file you you just
have a ready-made formulas and it can
handle matrices of any size it
automatically scales so how do you use a
defier Ruby
so you just in the first line of code I
just created a and verified matrix it's
a two dimensional and two rows and two
columns I just add these two and in the
next hash I show you the how Wade
implemented Blas routine where I
multiply two matrices and then the third
the third part of the code shows how to
get the determinant of a matrix for so
let's see how the it's a fire Ruby's
built for MRI it's a C extension and it
on the architecture is inspired by n
matrix in an array basically basically a
defier is written in c plus fist so when
we try to build this library we need to
handle C++ code so for that the recent
instructions help you out you can do it
and the most point the important point
to note here is that you just get rid of
this mangling errors in C++ for example
this is how I implemented matrix
multiplication I just included Ruby dot
H and I created that data structure for
a verifier esterified object then I then
I just bind it to Ruby fronting in Anita
River I create a function called a RF
madman so this is being casted here
because this is being this code is in is
in is actually in a CPP file and what
Ruby front-end expects it is to be a
nurse C 5 so and next I do do an ER of
mad Mel so this this finally goes to
this line of code
I just multiply it here you can see that
I this line this line is for when
whenever a GP computation is done is
done on a GPU Ram so you need to get
this memory into the CPU Ram so the this
line helps you to do this so when when
we try to integrate arrow fire with rays
this line would be very helpful and you
may be wondering that why jeep the GPU
computing on Rails because you have data
means you collect data through active
records and now you can just analyze it
fudge it would be the app and that which
is same as n matrix JRuby we had the a
Java native interface for arif I'd
already built and I'm even I implemented
some of the blast and lapak routines
these this works on a defier Java what
your father for example the last example
we saw we saw where they did matrix
multiplication is C code this can be
easily implemented in JRuby just using
this part of code so here you can see
that or some jail rubies
now we benchmark array fire the system
is specifications are as follows we have
same octa-core processor with first 60
GB of RAM and GPU was JT and VTR gtx
750ti
and ram is 4 gb dereference so for in
this you can i think you can see it here
and this is around 10 days to power five
times faster than n matrix Ruby and ten
use to power four times faster than n
matrix JRuby and again Arif I this
faster even here it's around 10 days to
power 6 times faster
one matrix determinant it's around 100
times faster even for factorization its
era 500 times faster so transparency
after actually the current here when you
find we try to find era fire on guitar
you will care you can see the code for
actual written only for MRI for JRuby I
I have already done the groundwork it
just needs to be in the wraparound upon
oh okay maybe thousand times faster so
transparency we need to integrate it
with an array and n matrix and with
rails so the where I showed you that
just you just copied us ran from GPU to
CPU you can just create some function
methods for that and we and yes rails is
now on GPGPU and similarly as any array
and n matrix so what are the
applications actually a defier has
endless applications you can use it for
bioinformatics you can integrate it with
tensor flow when it's ready so you can
just create a GPU cluster using air
afire and integrate it with tensor flow
you can use it for image processing you
can use it for computational food than a
few dynamics so hence baby these are the
useful links you can go to for n matrix
infinity and a defier RBZ and the latest
code can be found on arafat temp temp
ranch i would like to acknowledge my
mentor George Evans and Charles Nutter
and John woods for who have been very
helpful to me in creating this these
libraries both era fire and n matrix
next is Alexson Gossman who's who
developed the mixed model gen some Mead
he's the developer he developed Darwin
and
we have got agita tea from the era
fireteam
he's also mentoring me with this project
so also I'd like I would like to thank
emerging technology trust that is the
organized organizer of rubyconf india
and currently they have sponsored my
travel for what n matrix odd
see your question is basically that I
need to send the values to more than one
course for processing right so basically
this firm where for n matrix it is done
by Fortran and Fortran is already
optimized for this it lays down membrane
certain way that it uses parallelism for
that so yes it's done by that way and a
Java code can't beat that qu processor
instructions created by that after the
was defined the first run by bizarre
video for that usually you have no true
libraries in C++ that are able to do
them because the amount of the processor
was built the name of those lighters are
VC and most simply okay you should want
to take a look on them later okay
and there is also one library that I
helped to write for matrix processing
may be an eigen tree that's really fast
you've seen this for hard I can reach
for a higher rate sorry I can 3 is for
our card language right okay but are
using it mostly RC ppin are eigen so
yeah I think that slower than Lopakhin
blasts okay next question
Oh so a great work on the stuff I just
did for a quest
okay so basically the problem is that
even I don't understand whether the
problem is with JRuby or a JVM no I
didn't concatenate those I just add
these two elements means to - for
example there is 2 comma 2 another has 2
comma 3 so we get the final areas for
commas 5 means 1 and actually this can't
be reproduced here sometimes you get
annoyed foot four out of ten times you
get a zero or else it works fine
yeah what do you see is the the
integration of this with rails yeah well
like what what kind of integration do
you
so basically if you have some maybe you
can try it with active record basically
I'm not consulted as I consulted some
double root race developers at rubyconf
india and the ad inputs like we can do
it with race and so it would be widely
used
Thank You person very
[Applause]