good afternoon everybody welcome our
next speaker is Hugo talbo to talk about
simulation open framework architecture
give them a big hand please thank you
very much for for the introduction so
yeah I'm gonna talk about sofa so so far
it's for yeah first first originally
from research and then you'll see it
became a bit wider than a research
suffice so multiphysics
and gene basically that we are that we
are using with emphasis for medical
application we will see that it can be
use for actually any kind of physics
simulation but that's the main purposes
it's open source so that like many
things here at first M and I'll tell you
a little bit about the story of sofa so
it started about 2000 in 2006 in Boston
MIT where a French researcher I had this
idea of creating a platform open source
platform for global globally physics
simulation he came back to France and
then at INRIA which is a Research
Institute for computer science it came
and start started developing this
platform in collaboration with four
different inner teams that was so they
worked about five during five years
together all those five those four teams
and then more and more companies and
startups studies looking at sofa and
having interest to that so now there is
a quite big community made from research
institution universities and also
companies so what is sofa so it's it's
making physics we'll see that just right
now what kind of physics it's doing but
how it is organized so there there is a
main core open source that anyone can
download use with the LGPL license so
it's quite permissive and then all
around it's why I wrote modular what you
are because you can build then your own
plugins and any kind of you know your
own module in which you're gonna develop
new classes new models to create your
own application and what is it that
useful because you know you can put any
kind of license you want on your own
code so basically you can do
a product or make your own research
private or open-source based on so far
using the that kind of plug-in
architecture it's multiphysics that's
what we're going to see just right now
and we are always targeting an
interactive simulation so pretty fast
simulation of physics and you can see
that at our booth in the building in
building K we have a haptic interface
showing a small demo with sofa so what
what what so if I said it's our DPL you
have displayed this plug in the system
so although although I mean usual stuff
so building with CMake we are and github
as well and so just like we has been
discussed previously and and two
dependencies which are a cutie and boost
we are cross-platform so you can use it
on any kind of platform you want what it
is doing for physics so for physics
there is usually I mean from from the
origin we were really focusing on
mechanical simulation so medical
simulation mechanical simulation in
medicine it was mainly you know how does
an organ behave or if you push on the on
the liver or on the brain how does this
organ is gonna respond so it's a bit of
battery but basically it was what it was
made for at the beginning and then we
started looking at more than just
mechanics but we looked at fluid
dynamics and also some kind of other
field simulation which is here
electrical field could be also
temperature field so thermal
thermodynamics um and all those stuff
are available then in sofa to make your
own simulation I mentioned you know it's
C++ classes but if you want to build
your own simulation you can use either
XML or Python scripts to script to then
describe and run your own simulation so
yeah some kind of battery that's the
kind of example we are doing what what
is the use of all that we are using
usually you know medical simulation so
physics simulation in medicine for
making training simulators or helping at
least surgeons you know during the
operation bringing new tools based on
simulation again you can you can join us
at at the building ki you'll see a lot
of different videos and so on
so uh does it work to build a simulation
all these each C++ class build what we
call the component here each one here is
a C++ class and then each component has
a role of course you're gonna have a
solver you're gonna have if you want a
mechanical simulation you will have a
mechanical low describing how does these
are this object deforms a mass and so on
basically all the physics and this is
described as a graph so a direct as you
click graph as we sell each node as I
mean each component in in this node will
have no parameters if you take the mass
for example the mass you need to define
the mass density or at least the total
mass of your object so that's that's how
it works
and this of this sin graph will be
described using the using XML scripts or
Python scripts Morris and here I've been
introduced so one one thing which is
very powerful about so far is that it's
not only you know not only physics you
have also visualization you have some
algorithms for a collision detection but
others that you know out of all those
different models you know you can have
one model for the visualization one
model for the physics one model for the
collision detection so let's do you see
now we see nothing ok and we see even
less nothing here no nothing ok so the
idea is that if you wanna I will
summarize basically all those different
sub here here you see a little bit
that's that's a liver a human liver
so the idea is the the power of this
multi multi model representation what it
is you can have different topology for
representing the same organ one will be
here it's small cubes which on which is
going to be computed the mechanics so
the mechanical simulation will be
computed on X I'd run and here you can
have for for example collision detection
you can use instead of cubes to be more
realistic you maybe you want to use a
triangulated surface but then you have
different objects one for the collision
one for the mechanics you can up here
for the visualization you see nothing so
it's really very nice for visualization
but so you how the question is then okay
you can have all those different models
that's cool but how do you relate them
that's what we call a mapping we have
mapping and making the correspondence
between the mechanics the physics
between the visualization that can be
different or the collision globally what
you need to watch is which is what is
needed here to ascend it's just that
what it allows to do is to set exactly
the power of computation where you want
if you want to have a very accurate
mechanical simulation and a crappy
visualization it's possible if you want
to have the inverse you know a crappy
mechanical system mechanical simulation
because you don't want to be accurate
and very very nice with the super nice
textures simulation it's also possible
because the two model are completely
independent to each other but then the
mechanics is gonna you know manage its
the master and the visualization just
grabs the slave and then you will have a
very nice simulation with a nice
visualization even if the mechanical
simulation is very simple behind so you
have you have some other features in
sofa just like you know GPU computing
which is possible there is a plugin
allowing for using the using the GPU of
your view of your computers you can have
and you can couple any kind of physics
simulation with optic device that's what
we have at the booth that's what you can
see here at the video you have a physics
simulation ok cool it's running it's
running in real time but on top of that
you can directly interact with the
simulation so here the tools are I mean
there is an interface between the optic
devices and the simulation and therefore
the user can directly you know use I
mean use the tool and God exactly a
feedback he's interacting with real
objects everything is virtual but he's
gonna have some optic feedback so you
can also couple
virtual with virtual simulation with
with some optic and interface interface
device ISM many other stuff so there is
you know I said you can create new
plugins adding new features to sofa
for example you have something which is
dealing with medical images you have
something about registration changes of
topologies for example if you are
cutting an objector you have to update
the topology so update what the geometry
basically of your of your objects that's
available also in so far so now there is
a concise I mean you know I told you it
started in 2006 there was researchers
and so on now there is that there have
been some companies startups that has
been created as well so we built a
consortium so that also single
developers companies researchers are
basically happy with what is with what
is going on and we are providing regular
releases of sofa that's what we are
doing and we are taking care of you know
promoting sofa and basically for example
if there is any single developer using
sofa making his own application we are
also here to promote his or her work
around sofa find partnership and and and
talk to to the open source community so
yeah there is a website on this website
a forum to ask questions to start with
so far there is also tutorials videos
and so far where you can see the
different kind of application examples
that you could that you can achieve with
the platform and so that's the different
members that are joining us for the last
form of four months so it's a pretty
young consortium but it's it's still
growing and here are all the stuff that
you can you should remember is that's
it's on github so if you want to see and
discuss about the code it's on github so
so far framework there is a YouTube
channels of a framework as well we can
find all the videos and achievement of
researchers and companies and and and so
Twitter of course but and and then the
forum where you can ask questions and
really get started with so far so
whatever just what I can tell is so as
it's you know open source as many things
in the info stem you can basically
download so far get give it a try make
your own experience with it give us
feedback about that and also create then
your own application we will I mean my
job is also to make so that any kind of
application created we serve
get a get a get an end user and get
promoted so do not hesitate to use it
ask question of the forum you can also
contact me directly for email and do not
is that you come at our booth so we are
at keh keh keh - and booth number 1517
sorry 15 is maybe cool as well I don't
know and and yeah - there is a small
live demos oh and other videos to show
what kind of achievement you can do this
so far so do the latest day to join us I
would be happy to talk with you so thank
you very much thank you very much you go
and we still have a couple of minutes
left so if there are any questions just
raise your hand and I'll get the mic to
you yeah there I see one
I have a question you used a finite
element formulation or another type or
do you have many different types yeah
for for the approach that it's chosen
its many finite element method there is
also some SPH approach MLS approach that
has been implemented in so far but very
few and grids grid simulation has been
very naturally considered you know you
know but that could be interesting for
only thermal thermal simulation but
mainly FM FM simulation so any other
questions well then I suggest we wrap up
Europe thank you very much thank you
[Applause]