so hi I will plant you spine annex VI
which is an alternative hardware
description language for digital adware
so during this presentation I will first
give you a little introduction about
spending idea how it come how we can use
how we can use it and then I will give
some different ways we actually land
very dog and then I will give you many
little example to show you the
invitation of spaniel HDL and how it is
different what give you by using some
abstraction and by using some software
engineering approach to do hardware
design so this position we okay this
penetration will only be about since it
is about hardware it's really not about
simulation thing you can simulate the
output netlist so yeah to simulate
generated the hardware you can use
regular tools because output netlist of
Spain an Excel is reacted and very large
so you can do the simulation of those
octave netlist so yeah this is the
context I don't have many time to give
you my opinion on that but basically
what I think is vehicle chosen to and
very luck 2005 are really bottleneck in
terms of engineering by many aspect and
vex dealt with an atan system very large
will not save all of us because of idiot
support because even of features that
they bring that are not so good finale
so I don't really have many times talk
about that sorry but so finally clear it
is an open source project which start in
December 2014 it focus exclusively an
aerial description and as you can see
here there is the flow so you can
describe your hardware by using some
Scala files then you ask it's a Spanish
the compiler to translate it into a
regular of the HDL and very lot that you
can sensitize or similar
and so chief mates
spinergy directly compatible with all
idea tools because its regular vehicle
and very dark and you can also integrate
some legacy IP like block from fog from
hiding some from material you know are
some more complicated things inside the
Spinelli the spine and exterior key by
using a black boxing system so it's
quite compatible with existing flow and
existing IPS then about the abstraction
level it it starts at the same levels
and we examine very dog a little bit
different but the thing is then on the
top of that you can build a new
abstraction another you can go away from
this mess of for your kids hardware
design to really say what she wants so
yeah just before example some last
points so there is no logic of ahead in
the chromatic cut because financially L
is not a ETLs approach it's really much
more like an LTL approach as we acted in
paraguay you have to design gates what
you have to design registers in six like
that there is no other it you will not
lose performance by using it all names
and all your co-parent iake is pretty
bad
during the translation from spain lyrics
they are two very long and via so you
can simulate it by using your favorite
simulator you can look at the wave and
then very easily understand by
understanding the wave catch-up where is
back in Spain Yahoo f1 and basically
expand a girl is not ready a language
and this is the main point about
venereal Spanish there is a language if
it's a color library so scale is a gonna
hurt purpose programming language and
Spain Eric DL is a library implemented
on the top of it to allow you to
describe being new hardware and it could
seem strange to have a language into
another one but it is probably one of
the one of the best point of Spain in a
clear so I will come and touch later so
yeah this is a simple example a very
random one which has no interest in
practically but imagine you want to
design this
little piece of hardware with a single
condition to derive some comment or
logic some register without reset summer
Easter with roulette in VHDL and in
regular because you have to use
assimilation constructs to build
hardware to interface a hardware because
the Eglinton Parag were initially made
for simulation purpose not for inferring
Hardware so you'll have to write three
different process you have a lot of
redundancies because for example this
condition is duplicated three times
which is not very clean which is not
really safe because you can create bugs
by hitting duplications at many place so
this is how you said to do and this is
how you can do with an odd ready ticket
at syntax and this is some finally clear
example so first difference you can
define things explicitly as signals like
my register is a register not because
you are as I need it in two o'clock at
process but because you define it
directly at the definition I want a reg
of tip data type
I want a reg of this data type with a
reset value to zero so because things
are explicit now you do not have to
write process and these kind of things
and you can write for example that you
want nice enough to be forced by default
and then when the call is true then you
can assign all of those guys in the same
conditional statement so another little
example different is to compare and is
to understand subtract another finish
their rights that though if you want to
define a simple timer component as you
can do in VHDL and Verilog it's very
similar like you can define yeah it's
based on scales oh it's much closer
though to software design in terms of
syntax can define at time a class with
some construction parameters this is
like a generic or a parameter in very
large then this class will extend
component to say this class is a
component so it's a logical element of
my design
then can you find IO into input/output
into a bundle
bender is a concept of hardware data
structure and spinal area then can
define inputs and output of your
components
it's very easy then can you find a
counter into ensign your timer which is
a register of this data type then you
can write conditions as I need all the
conditions reassign it so last
assignment wind the last a figment win
like in Vienna very large sign can do
assignment so if you know how to do the
again very long it's not so far you can
use it by the same way excuse to not
have to care about process and things
like that but then I would start with
the fun stuff so imagine you want to
have a inject bits of color so behind
chick bits of color I mean a stream of
data which carry color of like a valid
an already flag as a patrician and
payload as an idli be data structure and
okay you have a source and check this of
color you want to cue it inside the FIFO
and then you want to connect it to the
sink and check this of color so in the
air 2002 it is really kind of boring
because you have to define Exynos one by
one in many cases you can not really use
recorder because you want to have them
permit rised by verax so you can't
really use records there in all cases
then the most boring part is probably
about instituting the component itself
where you have to paint evening nails
one by one which is very error-prone
which is very copy past work which is I
don't keep work maybe so in Spain like
the sinks are much more object oriented
which mean so yeah for example if you
want in Spain out there the concept of
handshake
this is named stream so if you want to
define a source stream and a sink stream
you say I want a source and a sink which
have stream of RGB color with this
parameter addition so you can already
much more use that a stricter with which
have privatization we have in a
parametrization you don't have you are
not bound at this level and assistance
to entry twin so it is 5 for you you say
I want a 5 for a stream FIFO with this
has element which are very faithful you
don't have to be in all signals of you
that has tricked you into a single se
the basic vector anymore then you say
the depth that you want and then this is
the thing if you want to access the
first part of the FIFO you say five for
that I owe that pash you don't have to
be in sync you directly have access to
them by using lit kind of
object-oriented way like a FIFO is an
object you can say I want to access this
attribute of the FIFO then here for
example it's written that you take the
source stream then you connect it to the
back part of the FIFO and here it you
take the top part of the 5:1 you connect
it to the sink so it is better than this
already but it could be better and I
will command better way to do it
so basically stream is not something
that come magically from Spain excel
compare oh it's something which is
implemented and the top of it by using
regular syntax of it as painting a clear
so it is a class with a type parameter
here which extend bundle because this
class represent and have a data
structure so a collection vendor then
you can define element into your data
structure has a valid and ready
flag a payload instance of this permit
feasible type so you can use this data
structure has a slave input of you
component or as master output of your
component it's not like records where
you have all signals that can only be in
one direction it's not explain how to do
that but it is very useful and easy to
do and then there is this thing this
data structure you can add functions in
functions in it like the operator that
we have seen there to connect
you
trained in in vehicle and very dug
function tasks in procedure are not that
much useful because inside them you
can't define what you want you have to
define rare relationship between outputs
and inputs of the function but you can
define inside them register you can
insulate a component you can do all the
tricky stuff that you want you already
limited with them but here you can
really do what you want like can define
a cue function we take as parameter how
many big you want the cube to be and
then this function we create for example
a new FIFO internally and you cop an
answer and then it will connect as a
stream on the one who you are cutting it
to the perfect part of this five four
and this one can read wrote on the
output part of this FIFO so it is really
simple but in fact there you go in place
of writing or T stuff is already better
than regular VHDL you are just writing
tips like you want a source and a sink
stream of RGB colors and then you'd say
you take your source you want to cue it
we are 5'4 of sixteen element and then
you connect it to the sink and there you
are starting to going away of the mass
of fire of other word design you are
saying what you want and this is working
you can you can write a blog like in
that you can do mistake in your wiring
you can do these kind of things so it's
it's not only you can go further then
like imagine you want to do this ad
where like you have a saw stream of
color this is our random example but it
gives an example imagine you have soup
handshake
I saw stream of Korea you want to draw a
section of this stream when they are
black so you need to add these
arbitration gates and this check then
from this point you want to add a
pipelining stage to have better maximal
frequency or 12:1 depth
five four three eight I don't know so
you need to add that so anywhere
probably if you have to do that we do it
by hand and it's really our province
it's if you do arrow inside bit pressure
and it's always a lot of time to find
out where is a bug in your arbitration
but here there is how you can do it in
Spain HDL I mean how you can do it by
using the library which is intimate on
the top of Spain in exile like you can
define a so stream of every bit color
then you can say I take my school stream
i want to throat election when the sauce
payload is black and then with this
function through and we do it on t stage
till this point and then you say i want
to stage it and t stage function we
create this ad where for you and then it
returned t's just not and then you name
it sink so really you are you are saying
what you want and not how really it work
signals by signals and this is not magic
here you can do you can navigate this to
the implementation of this function and
this is pure RTL and limitation it's not
from this panel compiler so another
example thick machine so you can design
sick machine as you do in reactant and
very large by using switch statements
and things like that but you can either
use the state machine tool so state
machine tool is one time again limited
on the top of spinner deal it's not
something integrated in it and if you
want to do two state machine though you
can say I want a new state machine
I want state ABC which are States state
a is my entry point then you can define
some signals inside it and then you can
say state B on entry I want to set my
contour to zero state B when it is
active
I want to contact when my container is
for I want to go to state C and then
instead be when it exits I want to put
my eye or vessel to true so it's just an
exam that's Spanish they'll allow you to
rise your level abstraction but it's not
because it's implemented in it it's
because it's syntax is flexible enough
to allowing you to build this
abstraction state machine is not magic
really it's just software engineering
with how do I design combined together
so another example imagine you want to
do that you have apples like a Naxalite
or
pb-1 I don't know then you want from T's
boobs be able to drive a signal a and B
which are inside of 32 bits so you want
to have some register here which right
only from T's B's then you do some
calculation like multiplication between
both and then you want to be able to
read the result from this booth so if
you want to do that in via control log
we have to let to manage the these
timings by hand to do some switch cases
so it could be a right but it's not the
only solutions so here is an example if
you want to create a next slide for this
you can write it like that and then you
can use an next slide slave factory tool
the TSP is one time again content at the
top of spin excels not integrated inside
it and this tool will allow you to
specify you register mapping by by in an
abstract way without having any an
acknowledge of the boost timing then
like you can say a is something created
from the factory as a right only
register of T's data type mapped at this
address and the same for B and then you
can do some calculation here with result
and then you can say I want my factory
to make the result readable at the
address 8 and this specification here is
completely abstract from the fact that
it is a Naxalite one you can replace it
here by a PV one and it will work
directly so and behind that there is a
lot of software entering like there is
ash map that you can use to elaborate
your design and this is used behind the
center there is abstract classes there
is abstract functions there is irritancy
ever eaten see ya every new in every
tense exactly yes there is many things
that you can do so a last example this
is list at the most Russian project that
has made fully in Spain there used to
check that each worker Ecklie and it's
not too much buggy and this is a kind of
little SOC which work on SPD a with an
risk 5 CPU with instruction cache avatar
chained to debug it some as their arm
controller
from a pity bridge for low performance
peripherals GPIO timer you at Nvidia
this is an acci for interconnect is in a
PB interconnect and there is some simple
card which are interesting inside it
like for example to implement to fun / -
instance here it is a PB bridge from AK
see like from occifer it's just writing
that you say I want my bridge with this
parameter section and T's it's done
and to instantiate or this decoding
stuff for a PB with all those
connections between components if you're
saying I want an APB 3d color my master
is a people bridge IU a PB and there you
can give a list of safe like timer
controller I / PB is mapped at this
address with this address range and you
know it's in fact that it's in very dark
is it so boring to do that so here it is
saying what you want and you get it then
there is another pattern though it is
for the exit for outside and this one
use a data model pattern like you can
create an acci for crossbar factory then
you can fit it with some data model by
saying I've this list of slaves on up
there
you have T's lift this list of master
and they can access to slave and then
you say I tell you everything please
build yourself so you can really do
software engineering to design your
hardware with this approach and yeah
since this is all for this presentation
about spinning idea you can find
everything open source in this
repository there is unlike the combat we
can't start with a good I think there is
I'm ready to use project to help you if
you want to try it and some
communication channels or do not
hesitate to to comment them if you have
some issue to start up with tools or
anything so this is all thank you
[Applause]
sorry to compare it with chisel so
basically I stopped to work with hazel
I was happy some months with it that
plus two years ago and or two years ago
but basically it appeared that there was
a lot of issue with it and like for
example clog the main support which was
very badly done and there was regularly
some issue about it but no no but there
was no move on the kaiser stuff so you
can also find a list of things that I
don't agree with hazel in the design on
the FAQ section of the an idea comment
section and yeah maybe hazel is much
more about a very large implementation
of the idea has been like that it's much
more about a V actually an intimate
action of the idea which is with check
more things and more stuff but really it
look like interface is the same but
really there is many differents behind
the same like I have to check the FAQ
so basically yeah how to to map some
puce color into hardware it's your
question like using hash map and things
like that so you if you can writing
software and make it able to work in
hardware and software no it's not the
case so spinach Dell is not an actually
as approach it's really an ethyl
approach where you use color as an
elaboration tool to design what she want
by saying among this register Monte's
register i want to do the separation but
Spinelli is not about translating and
algorithms into other it's much more
about saying what you want explicitly
and you get it but you can use a sh map
to do the version of your hardware you
can use all these kind of things like
dynamic list and but has an elaboration
tool like a for generating vehicle or if
the generate in VHDL this kind of things
yeah so how I specify a clock for a
flip-flop though manically it's much
better than uvx debt because it is
implicit so you can define area of your
design which window the effect of a
given clock and reset configuration and
then everything inside it all sub
components will automatically get it so
yeah I had a slide but haven't the time
to talk about it so whichever message
you get when it doesn't work so
medically you have much more confidence
when you hear it spinning like the not
least you have much more confidence than
it's working
physically in for real than handwritten
VHDL one because finally I do a lot more
check by default than seen we do a lot
of check druggies and like for you don't
believe check that you don't have come
into a loop see we check that you don't
have with mismatch these kind of things
and if you have an error it will print
you wherein you're spinning the
description there is something wrong it
will give you the name of the sinner so
really it's maybe even less Easy's and
the idea to remove bugs from a spanish
their description because yeah i made so
it check a lot of much more things and i
put a lot of intention to have nice
pretty
aramis edge with the print stack of the
execution of spain a little description
and these kind of things so it's not
really messy it all right
have to try to give like to get a good
idea of it
I can some of the questions be put in
these discussion session uh you know try
to be quick question
so there will be three process limited
from it exactly like they're exactly the
same
yeah sorry Oh spending like that all is
how did this thing is in between
blocking and not blocking so yeah in
Spain like there by default it is I
don't know which is one but it is like
the default but like this one here yeah
you can do the other one by using
another syntax - so how the mission is
translating to react they're exactly the
same sign in VHDL so then if you want to
use I speak here dedicated blocks and
things like that you can associate a
black box or you can try to write it by
the way that the synthesis tool we in
the stand it's that but there is no
magic between in the translations oh
it's one to one
so if you to about from a rebuking
between the input spiny tail and outputs
there is no formal verification about it
because basically it's not work yet
because you are verifying the outputs at
least you are not doing your
verification stuff on this binary the
description you are verifying the exams
related files so it's why I don't really
care about it being formal but I have a
good confidence in the translation
process