hi so this will be the continuation of
the what we started and it's about in
general community and I'm going to show
some stats because the topic of the talk
was success stories and this is the
first year we'll start to gather some
stats in order to compile to see if we
are successful or we've not so we
already presented very quickly what are
our main web sites and this is where we
are gathered and for example these are
some stats about this track and we had
much more submission than last year and
if any one of you have organizations
that you want to present opposite design
just contact us because we want to grow
the community and would be grateful to
have some much more speakers this is the
and members will see you next year how
much we grow and what are the
repositories we have our most successful
people is the job one in the double pole
you can make requests for designers to
help you with your project and sixty two
contributors already fix things on their
on the website or submitted requests for
us to help them in some way with
interface design or with logos we use
our C for communication so because we
want to be able to communicate with
open-source we're not using slack or and
we're trying to use open and on average
there are 60 users again questions
though you can reach us and maybe this
will be more finished channel two
together and not just once a year at
fordham and almost channel then in the
last year we tripled our tweets and we
usually tweet about episodes in design
and we have lots of photos and this is
how we keep track you can use it as the
hand said it's RSC because of the length
constraint so isn't you need to know
exactly where you can find this and then
let them collect them
it's very new and we try to find ways to
gather some money in order stupid
stickers and this is something that
happens for all the open source
communities finding a bit hard to reach
funding and we have to have backwards we
don't have any expenses currently but
it's very cool that if we have some
needs we can try to fill them with that
[Music]
more and our website this is the only
negative thing we have for the start
this year and that is the number of
articles so we could write more and try
to share more about designers that work
there and about communities in the
gather of events we also have monthly
meetings so you can also find their find
us its first Tuesday of every month if
you're interested and on the jobs so for
the whole period we receive 61 jobs
request and they're still active 45 so
we managed to close the difference and
Philips represent some of the other
things there this means that we are not
that successful in fixing every request
from every open source organization
comes to us but at least we are trying
and we have some some progress to show
you in that direction ok so I'm going to
let Felix to show you a bit of examples
of what we did in the past year
yeah so um where's the presenter so yeah
we had to open source design we love you
like if you're not just open source
coder or even just like managing open
source software we we all love you and
we love onions and peas I know it's not
an onion but you're gonna get it when I
come to this slide so one success story
was the Torah style guide I mean was
it's it's still ongoing so simply secure
posted it on on chalkboard that they
need someone for the for the store first
a guide and picked it up and it was
eager to doing it so he even send them
an email and what happened is that they
didn't reply like for some time when he
said like hey I want to do this project
so he pinked him again and when they
replied they said it's a perfect match
[Music]
what happened is actually that of course
he did the standard thing right he
cleaned up the design into the awesome
job cleaning it out looking for a nice
font phase and really doing doing
awesome work but it's an iterative
process so they have P weekly meetings
and they found out it's a huge project
this huge community so it's not just
about some logo it's about getting all
this together and and therefore it's
it's nice to see that it's not just
another logo but a bigger process
involved and speaking about it it's like
it was a paid job and they even now
started up a UX team for four tours so
actually there is coming design into
another open source project business art
which is awesome and alien now will
continue to work with the guys over
there so this is a very nice success I
would say a different kind of success
would be the open forum mascot so open
farms a project also in github and they
started about thinking hey we
you might need a mascot for a project
and there were some proposals but yeah
it didn't come very far so Simon is also
a part of our community said like I'm
gonna post a job on an open source
design and then this guy found it on our
job board
Sam done and he is not part of
our community so he just found it on our
website and this was his second proposal
and it stuck pun intended so so what
happened then is amazing because you can
see now in really an iterative and open
process over there because they said hey
we need some legs right it should so
next but then they don't look that nice
so do other legs con let's do this and
then they said like ok we have to work
on the eye so what kind of rice do we
want to meet or use and then still it
was thinking like ok but what's missing
someone that something's missing anyone
has an idea what's missing there's no
transparency in the wings so they made
transparent wings and you see the
difference is changed quite much and but
the big thing is the the community
working on this this was all in one
issue this one guy doing most of the
work but he he really appreciated all
these people coming together and helping
him doing this great thing and that's OB
the fine final product and we have a new
member in our community now like he's
now part of open source design and
that's that's great so now this word
like two very visual things and I really
advise you to check out vellum socks you
give this morning but because it's not
just about the fancy logo it's not just
about the digital stuff like we have so
many many experts here that can help
your open source project for example
like doing new complete new widgets or
software structures there or they are
there was this proposal for at least
four redesign of the whole web page so
the architecture behind it and you x and
y a visual of course as well so I would
say that that open source design our
success is really that we connect
Jesus like with the open-source coders
and community and and that's what it's
all about like we are lively community
this was just this Friday when we come
came together to have a nice fun event
yeah and I hope you give us some
feedback and I think we have a little
bit I would say of course we like most
of the designers here try to do work on
open source like so they try to use open
source I must admit I don't use open
source for all of my work but I try to -
especially the stuff where it's about
data right so that's why I'm also part
of the design team at next cloud so I
really believe open source is an
important step and there are options
that's the that's the thing there are so
many open source projects even for
visual design or UX design or else for
example I think we should do we have a
list for tools I think we have a list
for tools right yeah so maybe we have to
put this out more so people find it you
can have a look there can also be inside
the feed bag just like puppet oh yeah
so finding this we have three and it's
called the resources and the question
was how to get design out there I think
[Music]
questions no thank you thank you so much
we hope we contribute
[Applause]