[Music]
yeah I do it to sex it up walking
no tons of data better better better
better
okay
[Applause]
it looks like fill up again this time so
if there are any seats in the middle
please
[Music]
[Applause]
good morning to that so that's an
Ethernet switch basically initially
which was no more than what was called a
something to for friends between
Leslie to wires
you can't just connect two wires
together so you had something like
there's something called a bridge which
was initiated you still feel like I
weigh Peter something like that to
stretch the length of any to run but of
course that was very limited you can you
know you can only connect to two lines
to a page
so therefore multiple bridges I have
started coming in that's we're talking
about like thirty four years ago by the
way so multiple bridge formerly known as
you get a packet in a whimper and it
just gives it up to all the other parts
so and I just became very very fast
because obviously they tended to just
generate a lot of traffic we didn't need
to go so in Kim switches but our
switches for me as different as
[Music]
essentially they haven't actually be
affording database it does learning and
aging of max that means it's either
pocket come in on one port and you
thought packet a frame so it remembers
that the source McIver's came on that
put and therefore if it ever gets that
thing destined for that MAC address we
will send that out to that portal yeah
it'll do that by showing that entry and
fdv just MAC address port that's best of
the essentials investor the least of LF
DVD and keep a timer and if if it hasn't
seen a packet from two five minutes or
okay you said like five minutes left
you see a packet come in but generate
any traffic you should age it out
because and therefore you should
[Music]
afterwards was very important it's about
to segment your switches lots of ways to
do VLANs
that you can you can do the v/line
priority tagging as verified in a or 201
queue the standard or you can just do a
partition switch where you don't have
any extra tags on your ethernet frames
but basically you configure your switch
to be like the two difference which is
three different switches and if you want
to have for a traffic between those
partitions you actually have to connect
the wire so that's the basics of an
Ethernet switch right now a new switch
or an emulation of it you might say and
in the kernel for a long time
the bad was of course a software thing
and you use a bunch of next basically
you put a bunch of cards you put like
four or whatever
cards in your in your server and you can
configure a bridge a software bridge and
then you know it's kind of FTB all and
put mountain in the kernel and you can
you know frames between them things like
that and and wrap them out to a P&O
Ferries systems account as needed
but of course there are some limitations
that first off everything is done by CPU
so you need need the actual general
purpose CPU to do a bunch of comparing
of friends than MAC addresses looking up
in dftb and it's not super efficient
switches tend to be a lot more
specialized specialized memory typically
for implementing an FTB that just makes
it faster to do lookups another thing of
course is these things tend to be i/o
bound initially in Linux getting a frame
on an hour neck meant getting an
interrupt on your CPU to interact with
them cause the curl to receive the frame
from the neck but of course too many
trucks kind of kind of ruins you
performance anyway that was solved a
long time ago where I forget what that's
called what was that that system called
that's it
they're basically just having more than
one frame per interrupt but of course
you've still got the same problem as
long as the coil is is doing all this
manual work on a you know general
purpose CPU it's not going to be super
super performant right now so then
something interesting started happening
and switches started coming out starting
with the venerable wrt54g and of course
threatened WT project came and now these
really kind of very specialized small
CPUs better have a built-in switch chip
that means typically something like five
Ethernet ports and you can configure
those switch chips to actually do
switching between them in other words
you program their FDB you program the
switches RTB so that if it gets a frame
from one court it could actually no sir
I don't need to send that to the CPU
there's much more much more interesting
where the CPU really isn't that strong
it really you can't really do CPU
switching on last time so there may be a
key project needed a way to configure
those chips in there the problem of
course was that you can't just use
defender
because but it was just you know random
stuff that's supported by chips some
great features sometimes I'm not sure W
config really supports them all but you
know the problem with that was that SW
conflict was never up streamed to the
mainline kernel I'm not entirely sure if
an open WT product tried to upstream it
was refused or if they didn't bother
maybe somebody here knows somebody's on
the
no didn't you tried I said how could
says that it was try to submit upstream
to the mainline kernel but it was my
last refused because there was the car
was starting to get something similar
and that was the DSA subsystem the DSM
system stands for distributed switch
architecture really kind of comes from
future present involve several switch
steps the MV 8 80 series chips which I
think we originally there at L switch
subdivision I think the more tougher
more gorgeous product actually I was
pretty generic you could do lots of
other things with it and welcome drivers
were submitted for p53 series and the
Starfighter to which I've many of these
small chips we found several others I
see there's a clock and address switch
supporters well eight five five three a
believe they present series anyway so
there's two sorts of Aryan
this is it that means if you have to
[Applause]
that's really important switching if you
can fix in your system and just behind
the scenes actual switching happens in
hardware that's really important but
there's lots of other ways to connect
you know if they'll switch is to your
system as many as there are message that
and there's enough presses so don't to
switch to a system kimmm
the system is a process to subsystem
that means if you can invoke it from any
present on a PC I bus PCI Express bus
that makes it of course more interesting
to the higher end type of switch ships
that need the kind of bandwidth that PCI
Express uses it's a very generic system
right it's more generic than ESA that
means that DSA was essentially changed
to DSA substance and essentially changed
in the car to be a switch deaf driver
right to DSS so there there are still
BSA drivers could BSA the framework
itself is essentially a switch that
driver if you want to do support
switching support for supported switch
switch side and the correct now right
that's kind of its kind of emulate or
switched up you might see it that way
right now it's kind of the easiest way
right but switch Levin general is super
generic it's got standard operations to
work on your f DB so odd entries each
entry set aging time and value several
parameters
as well support so mid to cast caching
caching and things like that announces
well
setting up VLANs let's switch that and
this happened last year is that switch
I've got merged before anything DSA was
supported but at some point last year a
Mellanox vendor very high-end Swift
ships submitted Jarvis further switch x2
and then their spectrum switch chips IV
they're super super high-end right the
spectrum has 48 of 6.4 terabit per
second to give you some idea that's
that's basically you can have a 32 perks
which report 100 gigabit doing full
duplex on every port constantly and this
thing can handle it right you can use a
switch
with the spectrum chip in it or the
switch excuse chip in it right now in
the mainland corner doing a just on the
main line curl standard driver using the
standard tools up here to bridge all
that stuff that's magic right so with
more likes that is very much it's very
much a pioneering thing I think you nice
if code would follow take a small
miracle but sort of on the fence about
this you might say between somewhere in
the spectrum between Mellanox are
welcome there are a lot of elements
caveum seems kind of interesting include
net switch technology that's the entire
API it's super simple
because just so generic I encourage you
to take a look at it so that's all about
any questions
that's just a treble switching capacity
of the spectrum chip the Mohawks
spectrum chopper system for turbot I
don't know from bowel marks or anything
I don't mean to have you know but I'm
just saying that's a real hardship it
has a total switching capacity of 16
footer better marketing literature I
assume it's correct any other questions
[Music]
there's an exam after this if you don't
have questions okay thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
chickens no battery
yes
maybe it's the simplest blinking that's
my battery
yeah keep it sir
my sense
Aradia endorphin switching in the past
we were starting
for Intel so they decided to do
something like Search tab
the cream stuff so you're using your own
now this is a little bit there probably
might think I'd ever make
they are left to cure the LinkedIn
profiles talking as I went to DC you so
I kind of I kind of assumed
ucg assumptions make an assay to you
this is ice who's this in laser-cut box
[Music]
as we ran under the moon cost them know
there are these prints
you know it's nothing
I know but that's not picking a flower
it's not extending to explode
yeah
oh just with the
[Music]
with strangers
also exposure that's PDF
that some of your speaking 53 money
[Music]
so next up is great pizza I am again
going to ask people please we can't have
anybody in the stairwells so if there's
fair seats to the inside of you please
move in so that we get as many people in
the room as possible if you can do that
before he starts that will be great come
choose one particularly I see five seats
in the middle and they're set that would
be really nice if you could block those
up
so excuse me
you've got me thank you
thank you very much next up breaking a
tcp/ip switch me put you up