all right so the last conference of
rosacea never met yes so we all want the
centralization this is uh this has been
this has been relatively clear the last
this day and so yeah let's talk about
the centralization so this is you right
now and this will be you after this
conference obviously well you sure do
yeah I mean do I have to to present no
it's like no is I'm here to present in
objects and not not really myself
so everyone wants a server there is a
problem with technical I mean there are
technical issues in getting servers to
everyone is literally like the I mean
the technical part it's really hard so
we need something for everyone to use we
need something that is also like oh no
that's not the the right the right thing
so we need something yeah we need
something that is able to be used by
anyone and that's that's a very very
tough point to to address and we also
quite want when we have servers at home
we also quite want natural networks so
that's why this slide but it's just
because it's Switzerland so we also need
need a server to be hackable because we
don't want to I mean as developers we
don't want to close like by with
interfaces like we don't want to close
users into some interfaces that they
won't be able to hack and modify and
extend we need to document our things
and we need a good community support as
well so in this to address this issue we
with the way most development in and the
fare fdn Federation we've created we've
created the Internet cube so this work
this thing and it's actually a a server
that you plug at home so it has like one
Ethernet spot that you you plug so on
your current Rooter you plug you forget
it to a power source that there can be a
battery as well and then it runs a
server at your place it's supposed to be
used friendly as well we'll see we see
how it goes and and it hosts so we are
basically if you've been there for the
when you noticed part since it's it's
winos running on it
you can host like pretty much everything
you emails your files instant messaging
web sites blogs forums it's it's yeah it
tell those it enables you to sync it
synchronize your calendars contacts even
like code repositories I mean it's set
right software and you can plug it
everywhere so at home it works it should
be working on any kind of network
actually and it's broadcasts network
network from your your natural internet
supply provider service provider so how
does it work a bit more technical part
so basically it runs a you yeah you plug
it and you have you plug it and you just
have like when you know is popping out
on a domain name that you've been chosen
and it's magic
so it works with tubes so it works with
a VPN actually there is starting
automatically on the on the device so
that's why this cat is getting out of
the tube because it's basically how you
get out of private networks government
stuff it means you cannot really ask
everyone to open ports on the router
days often very very yeah very hard to
manipulate into cough year so we're
using VPN to to get out and to to put an
IP and domain name on the on the on the
box itself and so yeah p.m. and this is
also why we are broadcasting it
broadcasts as well with the Wi-Fi
antenna broadcast the neutral network
because because the the VPN connects
automatically to to another ISP that is
local and and friendly so it's it
bypasses your local ISP and in bypasses
your commercial ISP and gets to some
some ISP that you can trust who is
providing you with the VPN connection so
why is this a good idea to actually get
a server plus a localized speeds because
you want to have your data at home and
you also want you also want to avoid
being shackled by your ISP you also want
to be to be able to I mean to trust the
the your network providers so that's why
the internet cube is is interesting is
because it gives you free and natural
network I mean it gives you natural
networks and and an open AdWords server
that is running with free software's at
home with your data in a place you
control so yeah that's about it I don't
remember my slides there oh yeah how to
get it
so in order to
in 10 a cube you need to you need to ask
one of your one of your one of your
local internet service provider and they
are located I mean not all of them are
actually providing internet cubes but
this is this is a map of like friendly
Internet service providers that you may
ask like if they can provide you with
those boxes
and and the reason why you need to the
reason why you need to to ask a provider
is because it's a self it's a self
configured thing so the the provider
will configure it for you
and then you will just have to plug it
at home and then it were it runs
automatically but if you want since all
the all the components are free and open
so you can build it by yourself yeah
this is just like latest news and so
yeah you can also build it by yourself
the only thing is we wanted to achieve
the point where the user I just had just
needs to plug it and then it works so
that's why we're we are dealing with
local organizations are providing you
with this but of course so it's an
Olympics Hardware board it burns when
you know us on it so if you know how to
install a Debian way you know hosts on
on a hardware like this you may you
might as well get yourself one just just
by buying it directly on their websites
so that's about it actually so those are
the yeah all the links you might want to
see so DBF fdn was the map this map is
something you can find on DBF fdn the
org and it's the the map with all the
local local organizations are
distributing that might distribute
in ten cube of course I forgot to say
that level you can tell it is the the
French name of the internet cube so you
can get a lot of references of level
internet which is exactly the same thing
winos dog of you of course this is the
bug tracker that you you want if you
want to report a bug on how it works it
has a part for like the specific the
things specific specific to the antenna
cube you have all the like the way we
are generating images for the board and
everything is located on github as well
there is a mailing list and an IRC
channel as well and I think that's about
it yes do you have some questions it's
been very clear the ISP was sorry yeah
so should you trust should one trust the
ISP or more than the box itself or who
should we twist well it depends on your
ISP like if it's like we are working
exclusively with like nonprofit
nonprofit organizations I mean these are
like associations so it's like it's
those are persons that you can trust but
the the the email server is real is
running literally that like on this so
now how trustable is it it's just like
it's a free software made by volunteers
and we try to like ensure that the
security is always like a
stream related length always always a on
top so it's your call but it's free
software
kunzite is yes yeah yes yeah so can one
see the configurations made on the box
by the ISP yes everything is configured
like the standard way why you know hosts
is configuring so it's a it's really
like this the exact same thing and
things available in the way you know
host github and like all the
configurations templates and stuff they
are all located there so is there a
version with tours that of the VPN
there's not but you can you can hack it
to install like yeah you can do it by
yourself but there is no pre-configured
to work
you mean is it plan to as sorry oh yeah
it's a ploy
so is it plan to have an automated tour
also tour services running on this I I
remember someone having done a tour
application on the for why you know host
so you can that you can install on this
for example so that would that will host
like onion services but yeah I'm not I'm
not sure if this implication is still is
still very maintained so yeah no it's it
has to be done manually and it's not
planned for us to do so yeah it has a
lot of other concerns as as well so yeah
it's not fun
yet so can one plug an external hard
drive yes you can plug like in SATA you
can plug a set a standard hard drive on
it and yeah and it's there is no
interface that just boots on the SATA
disk instead of the the SD card which is
the the one containing the system by
default but it's pretty much is fairly
easy to you to do so and oh sorry
yeah so where can one choose where the
VPN is getting out in the unit this so
it's related to your friendly ISP that
you will get to so one of those guys on
the map I mean one of those points on
the map
so there are ISPs organizations they own
servers somewhere example a in the tree
net which is like the the local Belgian
ISP we own a server in the Netherlands
so we will assign you an IP and you will
get out on the Netherlands then you will
have to find another ISP to to get out
from another point yeah you can you can
choose and you can change the
configuration of the pin quite easily
[Music]
risk I have no clue when it is okay okay
down to chip level okay so like like
yeah so is it is would it be compatible
with chip five hardware or is it okay so
is it a certification or is it like a
chip a special specific so as long as
Debian can run on it why you know host
and you can base this on it as well
because this runs literally on Debian
it's a very thin layer that you just add
most of the
the applications they are just like
web-based so you don't you don't need
much more than Debian and nginx and all
the things to to run on it so yes so is
it dangerous to store the data on insta
code it is fairly dangerous yes it's
much much more dangerous for your dad
and then Google servers that's for sure
that's also why we're trying to improve
the backup system because you might want
to back up here and there like to your
friends or other internet cubes but also
you can plug a hard drive on it so if
you don't trust your SD card if it's not
that reliable then sorry what rates oh
yeah yeah I read read discs yeah but
this could be a good good thing you
cannot plug two discs on this one
sorry you can okay so we confirmed it
works you have like multiple discs on
the on it
yeah alright I think this is it Oh
what kind of Wi-Fi version are we
supporting uh I guess like everything
that runs on the on this one which would
should be n yeah there's written n so
it's n B G I guess alright thank you
very much
[Applause]