who's going to talk about
process tags welcome hello thank you to
the organizer of the security room first
because the the except my talk thank you
to you to be here so I will speak about
PTX
that this process tag so it's a good
name process tax it's currently
implemented as module in the kernel but
it's not in the corner because it's not
on the tree of the kernel so it's a
Linux security module based system it
benefits from the stacking facility that
is implemented in Colonel since Linux
4.1 and cents to Casa flow that is the
route or of smack security module it
allows to stack several Linux security
module and it's an ongoing effort that
is still continuing to the the idea is
just a dream as to be able to allow at
the same time sa Linux upon or tomorrow
and smack so we'll see now why to tag
that's the question
but I think that you'll see at the top
the devices here are not tagged so it's
a shame because you can not say if it's
the fish soup that you like or this
bloody comp if that you dislike
ok currently kernel processor attacked
any any processes tact that's the way
that works as a Linux smack and some
other so currently it already exists but
you cannot do it by your home for you
user space use so that's the idea
how it works currently there is two
fights by task this one that is in the
proc PID of the main process and at its
here it's at for the attribute that's
where we you will find security
attribute but be aware it will challenge
soon and error is obscene of Phi P tax
that allows you to converse with the
module so you can read it you can write
it and it responds to I know defeat that
is a very cool thing
so our p tax P tags are just strings you
know so no the string cannot contain a
newline character so this are just
strings without control character you
can insert spaces but no tabs so no
confusion if you see a space it's a
space not at that and it's a field
structured separated by colons okay then
how to use it for example you can here
just use your share to show the content
of the P tags so it just shows you the
tax of the process one the line you can
rip it there is also a kind of query
language so you can write to this same
file you can write this it means do you
have this and the answer is yes and do
this and the answer is no that's really
simple okay
it provides also a kind of white car
query so this is structured as a Yoshi
currently you can add tags using this
kind of query language so just a plus
plus this tag okay
plus this tag and at the end you get the
process tag okay oh yes a sign not
attacks are returned at Saatchi such
cool thank you
okay another aspect is tags can have
value so here you say give the value
simple to the test
thanks but the the tag have to exist
before okay you can remove the value of
attack that is not exactly the same that
setting the value equal nothing because
the value equal nothing is the value
nothing but not having a value is not
having the value nothing okay it seems
reasonable and you can also remove tags
that's cool this kind of query language
is very easy to learn so remove test
then remove at the end it's removed
okay now forking executing will fork you
the process keeps its tag so the child
process has the same tiles did the
parent process when you exactly the tax
that are not having the Kipp flag it is
shown here as hat sign the tags that are
not true they do not have the Cape like
are removed and only the tax that must
be kept our kids that's cool
and efficient so now let's go in how it
works when you have to do something with
Kip flags so here is nothing here is
attack and the tag with the Cape flags
so the Guru's error are not so
complicated but I will not enter in that
so what is important is to know that you
can set the keep the flag remove the Kip
flag create the tag it's it's logic ok
nothing really
extraordinaire it works now about the
star that is the pattern you are
matching something it also works for
removing but also yeah that is special
for adding keep flag
okay we are in the room of security and
we have not talked about security
currently so why why is it here in the
room of security it's because this is
related to process it so you you want to
take the process for what reason I don't
know
but if anyone can do that it's just a
nightmare so there are rules that tell
you what you can do so the rules are
very easy if you are a colonel process
or can I thread you can do anyone
anything that you want but it's not
intended to be used by Konnor process or
canals right
it's a finality there is no internal API
it's only user space taking so you
should have the capability of
administrating one that ori access
control its i maybe someone will say
okay can we create a new capability no I
used what existed so there is a way of
dealing with IOT capabilities is to use
the prefix ptex contacts so if a process
has special tagging that means starting
with P tags it can had it can serve it
can set it can also manage others
processes so this are the basic actions
that you can perform adding a tag
removing attack setting the value of
attack changing the tags of another
process so here are some examples it
means
okay this one can remove any tag of
itself and
it can not remove the tags starting with
P tags
that's another security aspect is that
to remove tags with P tax you must have
this oh no it's not here it's here
because here I also explained it it you
you must have this kind of tag telling
that you can add P tags that's it's a
security it's a kind of traffic language
not so hard to understand but efficient
so here are example of use case the
launcher use case ok the launcher here
has some tags that allows him to create
new text for the luncheon process then
it drops its privilege and at the end it
exacts for the processes it has to
launch and process is now tagged with
what the launcher expect to give errors
to pass because in the fact you know
it's not mandatory to use this to remove
the privilege but you have to to have
privilege before so it's the issue with
the launcher launcher has to be
privileged and to remove and dropped its
privilege so that's that's an issue with
launcher use case it was designed at
first to give permissions to client so
the client as attacked the tag is a kind
of permission the server can query what
permission does this process as this tag
yes okay I will process there is for
example the identity use case this
client query an identity to a server
this server gives their identity to the
client the client do something Forks
exacts etc any process is created as the
identity
negotiated here the monitor use cases
can be to to tag process or this winter
and also a are assertive 4% it's not
good but a good value I have to monitor
it okay and many more use case that's
happened to your imagination
okay it endures name space because I had
a discussion with surgeon about it and
it seems to be a very good idea to have
name space so it's already in when you
create a user name space you get the
user ID 0 and all the capabilities and
you can redesign all your system but at
the ground it's managed ok some issues
so latest version of V of the camera do
not more allows to write these kind of
files so there was a very interesting
debate on the mailing list also the
files in this episode of file system are
restricted and a news case so you cannot
write so many things it's limited in
size extra so another critic is that PID
can be faked
ok and currently the thread are like
process so they receive and a new
identity and they will be they can have
different tags it's not a good idea I
think we have to manage process threads
of the same process to a same space of
tags
and there is also we have to shift from
a crate structure to the tasks structure
but it's an ongoing effort inside the
kennel and the security module that's
also carried by the writer of tomorrow I
don't remember its name Nikki okay so
the next version will use something that
I'm developing that is the process
unique identifier with its file system
that will not be restricted there will
be a new get capabilities and we will
share the same tags for all threads of
our process so it's available currently
there is user libera re that you can
find here that integrates query language
etcetera you it's a facility the the H
file is here so it's easy to read and
description is here you can see hit if
you want to check it and use it in your
project there exists layers for Yocto
already existing and if you have
question you can ask me that's all i
already uploaded
slides and it's up to you thank you
thank you who say and we have time for
questions and one raise your hand
Thanks
you said that you can't fake a PID how
do you do that I never did that and
people say me and not not the first time
that you can fake it and it's true
because you can make sleep a process
create process until you get the right P
I D and wake up the process and the
process just awake and say okay hey
that's you know no it's not him okay so
you're talking about the kernel space
when you deck here your process from the
PID list but not from the shuttle Q
right can you repeat because I have do
you talk about Q's in the kernel when
you can remove the process from the
process list but not from the kernel Q
where the process are shuttled it's
about removing some of the process
structure it's I didn't check this this
part okay you for pointing me this out
okay okay thanks more questions so would
there be an automated way to notify me
if if my Firefox of my Mayer's our
sponsor shell or something like that
yeah say okay this tax and then some
process pops up which shouldn't have
attack were from a privileged process
would this be possible with this
framework I really don't understand the
question sorry let's say someone
exploited my server and then he says
okay I'm a
open net cat reversal and I want to see
this automatically automatically so
could I see a okay there's a new Pro net
cut process any other binary and makes a
internet connection and I see okay this
shouldn't be open by my postfix
currently it has to be implemented I
don't know if it is the good framework
for doing this thing but if it is a good
framework you know it's a mediation so
the tag is a kind of telling to the
process that will allow or not the
connection if the client has a right or
not maybe but I don't think it's really
the good framework okay thanks we have
another question up here so can you talk
about some interesting use case that
they that you do have in mind so what's
some real-world application that you
have okay for me I I came here that's
that's not the first time that I'm here
in security room - two years ago I spoke
about launch or a secure launcher so the
secure answer was the my primary concern
bit was a student research so it has
yeah there is the the process of the
launcher okay you give some permission
you to a process and the it will follows
the process and its child's and they
there is I I don't see another way to
doing that so I what I presented two
years ago was a use of
fuse I used fuse fight system to mimic
prop PID file system to do that thing it
was a little bit different because I use
it file names and directory entries okay
so air is currently in what I the user I
had and it's and I'm still thinking
about that will it be used this way or
not
but in fact for me it was more
interesting to have such framework such
tool because it's more than just that it
can be more and on the Linux mailing
list cache of Lapras proposed to to use
it for example to store do so we spoke
about the monitoring use case very very
easy monetary use case where some
processes are still monitoring system
and get advertising from Allah etc and
so checks this one maybe he this one no
etc and at the end can give values it
has it may have values long term system
No thank you thank you
more questions
raise your hands okay so this might be a
no question but I know systemd and
selinux uses tagging basically tags the
process what I don't understand is is
this the same system or it's built it's
basically a set of a language on top of
it like I don't understand the
difference between the tagging and
system d-ends SELinux and this Thank You
SELinux use a tag it's tag that's the
process tag that you can read at duty to
protect okay
here you have for a process you replace
your P tags with current and you get the
the identity of the process from selinux
point of view okay it may change in
function but that currently is current
okay
that's the same for smack so it's a tag
that is attached to processes and tests
structure by the Linux security module
framework so it's attached to the
credential and it's dedicated to as
Linux so it's in kernel it's made inside
and used inside it check any file access
any IPC anything is checked against this
tag that is the security tag okay here
we are speaking of something that you
can use as at the user level it's not
dedicated to s