if you hold them until the end going
into the project in the storage
architecture it's been mentioned before
just to give you a little bit of context
into what we'll be talking about in the
rest of the presentation then we get
into the mayhem that's happening in
everyday deployments of over it happens
all the time and so we'll talk about the
kinds of things that happen and then
we're going to talk about what we can do
to remedy that and to kind of restore
order into the system from a storage
perspective and then I'm going to try to
bring it all together with some
step-by-step examples to kind of go
through the algorithms that we employ
and how they're going to help solve the
problem
so this is just a really quick overview
of it basically over it is enterprise
virtualization management it is
orchestrated by a management application
that we call the overt engine and it is
connecting out to hundreds of hosts on
top of which we can run thousands of
virtual machines engine is kind of the
brain behind the entire operation which
just dispatches commands out to the
hosts to achieve the results that we're
needing in our system and it provides
the interfaces to end users the REST API
in a web interface now connecting out to
shared storage we support lots of
different types there from NFS to Guster
I scuzzy fibre channel seven others as
well so that's a really brief
introduction let's just go down one
level into the chain here so basically
each storage endpoint its main function
is to store virtual machine discs and we
call those images we're using the Q mu Q
Cal - image format so in our case a
virtual machine disk can actually be a
sequence of underlying volumes organized
into a chain so for the purposes of
today's presentation we'll really be
working at the volume level so it's
important to understand what it thinks a
volume is in this case the obvious
component which is the data area and
this is the block device or the file out
on the storage that were actually
initializing as the data area
be a raw volume or a qko volume okay so
that one's pretty easy the next one is
the metadata area and this is stored
somewhere next to roughly the volume out
on the storage domain and that's a it's
a very small area where we have key
value pairs the stores properties of the
volume such as does it have a parent
does the system regard the contents of
the data area is legal these type of
things and then one thing that I'll talk
about today which is the volume
generation we have is the lease area
I'll get into this one in more detail
but it's a shared storage lease and a
host is able to utilize this to gain
exclusive access to the volume storage
operations occurring which can be
classified into two main groups the
first one our metadata operations these
really change the shape of the storage I
like to think of so adding and removing
volumes from the system if you were here
last year in this room I gave a
presentation on how we could manage in a
resilient manner these type of
operations by using garbage collection
and storage transactions today I'm going
to focus on the data path operations
which are the other type these are kind
of the main operations that are
occurring in a steady state over
environment the main one being the
obvious one being a virtual machine
accessing its disk while it runs on a
host but other examples are the
hypervisor copying one volume from a
source volume to a destination volume
for example so these ones requiring a
little bit of different kind of
protection since garbage collection
really
can't handle the job so we can take all
of our data path operations and
encapsulate them into something called a
storage job so let's say we're taking a
high-level operation such as cloning a
virtual machine disk from one storage
type to another
this may comprise multiple sub
operations for example if we have a
volume chain we have to copy each volume
in the chain over to the destination so
a storage job is going to be one copy
from one volume to another so the kind
of the most granular form of operation
that we can can provide
okay so engine is going to package these
into a storage job and schedule it for
execution on a host of its choosing at
some point that host is going to begin
to run the job when it has resources and
it's going to basically run that job in
an asynchronous fashion allowing engine
to query the progress during the
operation okay basically when the
operation is completed
it goes in a persistent manner so it's
sort of maps to the process of actually
copying the data so that's a little bit
about the storage jobs so this all works
really great
designed for reason because of the chaos
that happens in everyday words so we can
have power outages network service
interruptions hard work those of all
different stripes which are affecting
the operation of the system in
unexpected ways and we can have software
bugs even over the queue and of course
our stuff too so you know we can have
redundant power supplies redundant
networks we can have maintained we can
have better software development
processes but how does we try we can't
eliminate these so if you want to have
reliable storage you're gonna have to
design it from the ground up with some
algorithms that are going to do that and
so this graphic presentation of what I
said the interesting thing is there are
a lot of different ways that failures
can happen with different effects so the
host can lose its connection to storage
engine can lose its connection to the
host and then there could be internal
problems with the host itself and the
main thing is a lot of these are going
to look exactly the same to the engine
so we can't say if it was a power outage
do this we have what happens we have no
idea so how do we restore order when we
don't even know what went wrong but
basically where we can disturb us down
to is figure out all of the outstanding
jobs that were running across the
affected hosts in the system and we need
to figure out what's happened to them
and you have to use storage to do this
storage is really the point of record it
is as I like to just say if it's not on
storage it never happened regardless of
what you tell me so this is our end
point we'll use the storage to tell us
what happened so the first thing we need
to do is determine if there are any
running jobs and decide if we want to
wait for those or kill them and then
with any jobs that are ending we need to
decide if they succeeded or failed so
that we can report back to engen and we
can correlate all of the outstanding
jobs into resolving the end user command
whether whatever it was that they
requested in order to do these things
and again having a storage based
approach we have a couple of tools the
first one is volume leases and I touched
on these these are implemented with a
technology called sand lock which we
discussed last year as well sand lock
runs a daemon on every single house
that's connected to overt storage and it
allows the host to join a lock space on
each storage domain so the storage just
a lock is maintained out on storage once
you're a member of that lock space is a
host you can request volume releases
which allows you to gain exclusive
access to the volumes the basically says
you have to abide by the Paxos lease
algorithm which means that you are
occasion
and renewing your lease on storage and
also you know making sure that you're
passing the liveliness checks and if as
a host you're failing to operate
correctly then sandlot can fence you and
this is really a two-phase thing so the
first thing sound lock will try to do is
kill any outstanding processes that are
associated with volume leases if that
fails it can use the kernel watchdog
device to force a hard reset of the
system so with this in place we now have
a guarantee of exclusive access to
volumes but also importantly we have a
guarantee that those leases won't become
stale or stuck in the case of failing
hosts they'll always be released so that
we can use another host to satisfy the
request the second tool that we're going
to use and talk about today is volume
generations volume generations are
simply monotonically increasing value
within the volume metadata that can only
be changed during holding the volume and
which allow us to sequence the jobs
together so that we can guarantee that
only one storage job per volume
generation is able to run all these
things and put them together in a rough
storage job structure so no matter what
the job is
we always acquire the volume beliefs we
compare a requested generation which is
supplied by the engine when scheduling
the job with the actual generation that
as it appears on storage if they match
we do whatever work the job prescribes
when we're done
we increment the volume generation to
the next integer and then we release the
volume lease so let's take a look at how
this works in a normal flow first thing
engine chooses a host and schedules a
job job whatever it may be onto it and
it gets a response from from the host
saying that the scheduling was
successful so now we can begin
monitoring the job at some point the
host is going to run the job and the
first thing is to require the volume
lease next we validate the generation
against the storage and find it to match
the job and get periodic updates back to
the engine when we're done we increment
the generation and release the volume
lease resolve the situation
so that's all fine and good but let's
see what happens when a problem begin
again with a job that's scheduled on the
host and we are using just noting here
we're using generation 1 for the volume
this is the expected generation then
during monitoring something bad happens
we're no longer able to talk to the host
at this point we have no idea talking to
the storage still and continuing to
write to the volume no idea whatsoever
what's going on so we have to figure out
what's going on we're going to use
something I'm calling volume
reconnaissance and this is actually just
a storage job like any other storage job
except it's point is to resolve what's
happening with the affected volume so
basically we schedule it onto the onto a
house that we're able to talk to and
it's going to check if the job is
running by way of trying to acquire the
volume lease so that's going to give us
that piece of information and if it is
able to acquire the lease then it's
going to be able to determine success or
failure based on the value of volume
generation so let's take a look at how
this works in practice so here we go
we're gonna select host B which is still
responding to us and we are going to
schedule a reconnaissance job with the
last known generation of the volume
which is still 1 at this point and now
it's time to check on that lease and so
there's two potential situations we can
find ourselves in in the first case we
fail to acquire the volume lease so it's
worth noting here that volume leases are
a Trilok semantics so you're going to
try the lease if you if you can't get it
you get an error immediately so if you
fail to acquire the lease we know that
the job is running or has been running
recently on the host and we can choose
whether we want to wait for a while or
if we want to use a feature from sanh
lock which says I'm repealing the host
rock and I'm going to request it for
myself and that's a way of forcing the
job to end and fencing it so that's a
decision we can make in the alternate
scenario we acquire the lease
successfully and now we know there's
nothing running
and we move on to the next step to
resolve the situation and here again we
have two possible paths we can take in
the first case the volume generation
matches and that is actually going to
tell us that one of two situations has
happened either the job was still
scheduled and never ran or the job
failed because the last thing a
successful job does is increment the
volume generation so the other other
chance the other option is the volume
generation comparison fails and in this
case it's counterintuitive but that
actually teaches us that the previous
job was successful okay now it's
important to note that in the previous
slide when we acquired the volume race
in both of those cases we incremented
the generation to two okay and that's
important to note because it has a
really good function if for example host
a comes back to life and reconnects to
storage tries to execute that job we
don't want to stomping on what we may
have done since the you know since we
did our reconnaissance so this is a way
of pre-empting those old jobs we don't
care about that we've resolved so this
one is going to acquire the volume lease
it's going to compare the generation
find it doesn't match it's not going to
be able to proceed any further
so a couple of things we want to do in
the future so really talk about copying
volumes from a source to a destination I
always talked about the destination
lease which is the most important
arguably because it it's right access
the source volume we want to acquire a
shared lease for that as well now today
engine protects against performing a
volume operation on a volume that's
shared through orchestration level
locking but we'd like to be further
safer to have it down in the storage
subsystem itself the next one is job
execution so obviously the design is set
up so that we can if we have four
volumes to copy at once we can do them
all on different hosts at the same time
there's a bit of scheduling logic that
goes into dispatching all the operations
monitoring all the status and then
combining it into the final result so
we're working on that and then finally
we have something called VM leases which
is a way of actually using a storage
leased to represent a VM so at the
storage level preventing two VMs from
running on multiple hosts which would
obviously be a bad idea so that's great
in storage we we prevent storage
operations from conflicting with running
VMs again by orchestration level locking
but we want to in the end in the storage
level prevent that as well for extra
safety so I hope you found this
walkthrough interesting here's some
links to the over at project we're
always welcoming more multi users and
more developers so I'd love to have to
see everyone over
and at this time if there's any
questions about anything I'm not seeing
you just yell out or something Thanks
because it's supported in hosted engine
yeah it should be working everywhere it
should be agnostic of that in terms of a
VM lease integration will have to be
extra careful about that of course but
for typical storage operations it will
work seamlessly
[Applause]