so no yes or no sorry Jorge it's a
letter now assisting
he likes monitoring things including the
cloud including stacks of raspberry pies
with sensors everything on and he is
going to tell us how to troubleshoot
kubernetes okay welcome okay thank you
okay
so today it's been high intensive day
for me this is my third talk it
has anyone seen one of the previous ones
can you raise hands oh cool so he knows
a snake I've shown this slide before if
you're here is probably because you're
running vanities or you're applying to
do so and until we got things like
containers burn it is when we have to
troubleshoot and find out what was wrong
was break a broken on our servers we use
the years tools like that but then when
containers came around things stopped
working basically those tools they were
not aware of namespaces of T groups we
have to treat them the were not working
as good as they were working before and
actually this is a real problem or I
have included here in issue on cornetist
github project and someone trying to
troubleshoot and the answer of the
developer says well you know like try to
run Bosch loop over there do some prints
see if somehow you can get visibility of
what's going on inside of the containers
we have containers for multiple reasons
probably for ones to dimension is that
they are simple they are small most of
the time still always they are isolated
from security point of view that's
that's nice they have less dependencies
we ship everything with
have to deal with messing things around
put the block boxes we cannot see what's
happening inside as we used to do before
or we have to break these things and
install the troubleshooting tools inside
which is not the desire or the best
option that's why we are trying to fix
with Cizek Cystic it's like a
combination of all those tools you were
using before to troubleshoot your
servers each top BM style has thought
all of them all together in one single
tool available opens first we also have
a commercial product but that's not for
today and what we do differently is she
thinks it's cheerful on one side we are
able to keep complete visibility of
everything that's happening inside of
the containers we have managed to did
instrument in or the kernel we install a
kernel module that basically it does
capture all the system calls we copy
them into ring buffer and then we let
user space process to pick the data from
the buffer and suddenly we have more
everything to a user space where we are
more comfortable monkeying things around
grouping and segmenting and everything
so yeah it's all the kernel module the
agent or the kernel module captures
everything we move down into the user
space can either be a diamond or we can
even run inside of a privilege container
because we need to do it in small to
install that kernel module but kernel
module builds dynamically using the KMS
if we don't have Winery
so they get included in the distribution
that you are probably using if your is
not cool we can still open the capture
files but we can't capture
nabu yeah and we dump everything into a
file and this approach basically
some benefits have some advantages we
discover since that process the the
Cystic can see everything happening your
host we can automatically discover every
container you run so there is no need to
instrument to configure the Oh have a
scale up replica or something and then
there is new container or there are less
containers and I need to reconfigure
things around now forget about that no
instrumentation so there is no need to
install an agent in every container or
funky things like that and full
visibility the corn or the thing that
you have to pay the trade-off is that
you need to store the kernel module if
you haven't been into my previous talks
or have mentioned this the reason I'm
going to answer this because probably
otherwise will be a question that you
will be making me at the end is when we
started says they EBP F didn't exist or
didn't exist as it is today so we have
no chance to use that has been involved
in and for a period of time it has some
limitations so for example we have to
copy everything on the buffers and EVP F
has some limitation on the amount of
data you could copy out from system
calls there there are some limitations
those they have been solve so maybe in
the future we change then the other
problem with kubernetes were we
containers and microservices is that we
don't have like single house and one two
three and number of services running
inside now like we have a scheduler and
it's moving things around all the time
so when we need to filter we need to
organize things we would like to get the
be like as close as this as possible
where we can say ok so I have I have my
Cassandra service or I have my radius or
and I want to filter things by that well
the other very cool thing we did stake
is we talk to your container
Orchestrator
so either it's been docker or corn it is
open share TCOs messes
I even a bunch of other platforms we can
talk to them understand how you are
deploying our containers how do you
schedule them how they are related to
each other and use that information to
venture because at the end of the day
what says they can do is cup is
capturing all these events that they are
the system goals with some context as we
can understand better what they are
doing
filter them and run scripts to change
generate reports and find out what these
things are doing we can do this life or
we can dump things into a file which is
similar to TCP dump pickup files we have
container support I have mentioned this
before and we have common line interface
but also we have courses interface
something similar to HD and this is
basically everything I have 4 slots now
we are moving into the dangerous part of
this presentation which is the demo I
have a very cool use case how he can or
of the story that happened to us when
running kubernetes I wanted to fully
share it life but there was some
last-minute problem with the network
because it depends on something external
but no worries because I have a system
capture and I'm going to able to show
you exactly the same thing but first of
all we are brave and we are going to
show you something life let me move this
this terminal background you can forget
about it
it's Molly notes so I don't forget the
things so basically I have here a
kubernetes instance it's run in
different containers you stole
everything just pull in the different
docker containers and first of all I
want to show you how we can leverage how
we can use Cystic to understand how
cover needs work and I'm going to
illustrate this with an example a very
simple example of a service so I'm going
to first thing I'm going to do I'm going
to create namespace which is a pretty
cool app very very very critical that's
why I'm for need on kubernetes then
inside of this namespace I have a
service with the deployment and I'll be
deploying three replicas of on nginx
container simples up so let me deploy
that and let's see okay it was catch so
that's running already cool so one of
the things it's very interested in order
kubernetes does for us is managing the
load balancer you probably if I'm not
going to discover anything me for you so
we deploy with deploy a service govern a
displace load balancer in front and
distributes the traffic between the
number of containers we have there there
are multiple or different strategies in
this case just choosing a load balancer
on on one fix IP address we can do this
with DNS from robben but in this case we
keep it simple so we know that our
back-end service gets that IP address
the chief for one and I got these three
different end points my index pots
what I'm going to do now is to lunch one
client just with curl
and leave that on the background and
I'll open a new shell so we can follow
up
okay perfect so this is my client so now
if I do curl buckin this works so
basically returns the default homepage
for nginx cool now that surprised but do
we really know what's happening behind
the scenes here we can imagine if we
read the documentation but the first
step to get familiar and to use properly
a troubleshooting tool is to understand
how the infrastructure really works so
what I'm going to do is to leverage
Cystic for that I told you already
so one of the things very interested in
things of cystic is that we can use some
kubernetes entities or objects to filter
out things showing here the different
labels we understand from kubernetes if
you are using custom ones we can also
filter them but these are the difference
so of namespaces like the usual stuff
what I want to do now is show you the
course interface so I'll be using cystic
actually I wanted to show you this
basically what we do here and she turns
a snake to connect to cover needs API so
we know how things work inside so these
are all the processes running in my
machine this is could be H sub well it's
not because if we see here this is
probably one of the most interesting
sections they are different beers that
we have pre-built for you I'll show some
of them before you know talks like using
tracers or using this for security but
if you have a look at it here we have
purple beads for different orchestration
tools in this case we will focus on
communities so if I click here I'm going
to be able to see the
different namespaces I got so I have my
critical up and also cube system which
is the internal namespace well let me
stop here did close this I could get
this with with gives in keep CTR what
it's interesting here is that I'm able
to show you some metrics CPA memory for
Network aggregated all that information
so I could see what was the memory usage
for the namespace or the network users
in the same way I do this for namespaces
I can do for deployments with my back
and deployment or for services and
what's interesting is that is that this
is like a tree there is a hierarchy here
so if I go into my button and I hit
enter automatically I go to the level
underneath on I see or the poll all the
pots that they are running inside of a
service all the time I'm showing the
metrics and if you pay attention here on
filter I can see the filter the seasons
diggy supply and so this this very same
filter can be applied on the command
line
[Music]
so one of the things I want to show now
is as I mentioned before I want to
understand what really happens behind
the scenes when I do curl back in and
how all that correction is handled all
the load balancing and everything so
what I'm going to do is she open seasick
with a few filters in this case I'm
using the command line interface so
minus K for the kubernetes api then I'm
giving Evan type open to see opened
opens is called some foils and then I
want to see every file that it's in /e
DC and also I want to see everything
that in the client pot so if I go back
here and I do curl back on automatically
I see all the files that they were open
in my client container under is las et
Cie remember I'm able to see this from
outside okay since as they go says they
gets running on my hosts in this case
okay that's cool I can see yeah the
different open parameters and everything
but I'm curious and I would like to know
what it's actually that I'm reading for
those files I mean this case where I can
do is to leverage on cystic chisels
cystic chisels are some lower scripts we
got that we feed all the system calls or
the events and all the related
information and with those Lua scripts
we can reform and information aggregated
manipulated and for example generator
report or format the output so I'm going
to do see a comb fds is all right come
on let me know check
now I was doing spy firewall would be
the same thing okay so if I run this
command again
mmm nothing happens probably I'm doing
something wrong spy filed it in yeah I
will be his neck oh I don't know why I
have on my notes
what's wrong
[Music]
hmmm this is the first episode of the
demo there we go now this is what I show
you before well otherwise I will move
into the next come on I wanted to show
you
what anyway I'm not messing this with
this the other thing you wanted to show
you boy that's working if I use this
other chisel and I was working I can see
exactly what I was waiting ok
it was it's very similar to the echo fds
so when I did open and a switch so I did
curl so call let's try to resolve that
name so open NS which I with a Revit
file then I open hofstadt Kampf then I
open resolve Kampf then I read the hosts
and with all of the information I didn't
read anything else under a slash et Cie
so this is a nice way to see where my
application is actually reading from
those files because they could be
changing automatically or things like
that another use case of tittles another
example I wanted to show you is by users
spy users is a chisel that will print
everything I execute so simple is that
come here I execute again and I can see
how the rogue user executed that comma
so these are the kind of things are
going to be very convenient to
troubleshoot your kubernetes when you
have an issue that last example before
we move to someone else I'm using HTTP
lock so guess what it's going to decode
system calls writing into sockets will
decode the HTTP protocol and will show
me here the request including HTTP
method or return response called latency
things like that
ttttt so this is very interesting but
still I would like to know everything
that's happening so and I mentioned
before I'm not copping everything
and I mentioned before says they can see
everything so okay let's see everything
going to explain you here
this come on so again I'm collecting to
cover needs API using PK that's printing
from which container is that even coming
from in a form of the output asthey and
then I'm applying some filters and I can
already foresee this is going to fail
but and then I'm applying some filters
that my notes they were not as good as I
thought I'm filtering all the traffic
that's network traffic with FD type so
for the Scriptures that they are
actually ipv4 or ipv6 and then I'm using
some kubernetes filter saying okay
everything on the namespace critical up
or that it's Skye DNS which is the
resolver I'm using so if I run my
command I can see everything that works
executed so let me show you from the
beginning this is a bit complicated but
we'll go through so I hope I'm just
going to highlight the most important
parts okay
so we get the socket first of the thing
we know we see that this is going to
port 53 so it's the DNS resolution and
the dns resolution goes into my DNS
server which is we can see the IP there
but then and we see that it's coming
from curl then we see that the next
message is actually coming from Sky DNS
we read from the socket but we open
a new connection to this guy on port
4001 so we know that vodka is etcd and
what we do there is etcd press requests
with this URL trying to find out what's
the IP address associated with the
domain name we do that we get their
reply over here I'm not going to get
into the details digitate let me find
there we go you see their JSON reply
with the IP address tur then that goes
back to Sky DNS sky DNS sends a DNS
response and then we see curl here that
it got it got the IP address then where
we need to connect it one very
interesting thing are actually I don't
want to miss is what is this 241 so if
we go back to mark over Nittis keep city
notice not here
Kiev City I'll inspect
describe we see that 241 is the IP
address of the load balancer okay so
what etc' replied was the IP address of
the load balancer let's go back here we
see curl connecting to that IP address
to digital let's find it out fifty three
to two Tin Tin Tin there we go
so or should we even so it's connecting
to this API address 241 port 80 but then
suddenly when we keep reading and we see
the nginx port on this line we already
see that this reply it's not coming from
the same ip address so this is different
172 1705 which is the IP address of the
pole this is three key this is fake so
we see the reply back or we see the get
how in Enochs
gets the real they get request we do the
right mark which arrives to curl and
curl print is okay so we see how the
system calls yes we got the question we
don't have a way to export yes the
question was is there is any way to
export to pick up we didn't have a way
now because probably if not all both of
the filters that we can be using on TCP
dump can be used here already
okay so we did this there was we saw the
system called
like all the sockets and everything
writes with files been read to
understand the DNS resolution but we
found out that there were some changes
on the IP address and actually if we do
EP tables we'll see how kubernetes has
one I am in the right place
this is fake here we have one place tube
services where all the traffic that goes
into the bakken service because the
screen is so small cannot be seen
properly but we will if we read this
carefully we will see how kubernetes
creates a chain in on ebay tables at all
the traffic that goes into the IEP that
IP address is split in three different
chains with some probability
deterministic module to load balance
between the different containers
different pods and the traffic goes to a
different IP address okay that's more or
less how it works so think it's very
useful for this and if we have some more
time I got something else prepare which
is one issue I experimented and we have
45 minutes right so we have 10 mins more
ok perfect so this is life this is very
helpful to understand what kubernetes is
doing behind the scenes but actually the
title of this talk was how we control
the kubernetes and as I said before
I wanted to have do this life but there
are some network external dependencies
so instead of bringing a capture file of
an issue that happened to us and we were
running exactly the same scenario but
girl instead of returning immediately it
was taking close to 10 seconds waiting
there hang in and then it was working so
what is the worst thing that can happen
to us
as operators of an infrastructure the
things fails now that's great because we
can fix it worst thing of the harbor can
is that things work very slowly and we
don't know why so I took a capture of
the other scenario and I'm going to show
you how we found the problem using
system so I'm moving back
hopefully this is big enough what I'm
going to do here is again open I think
you're going to hate this cos of your
destroyed open a captured foil and again
include our PV for an eye PVC sockets
filter boy again my critical up on the
sky DNS and what it's very interesting
here and as you see this is going can
you still see this this is very slow
it's very interesting here I'm going to
go quickly it's similar to what we saw
before we are going to see curl are
trying to resolve a house name will go
to a etcd ABCD will try sorry will go to
sky DNS Kai DNS will try to resolve
through etcd and if the entry is not
foreign Anisa t it's going to try with
different search domains and at the end
we'll see that something unexpected
happens so actually let me go through
directly to the points I want to show
you so we can see that first my request
or the request that goes through ET city
it's very very long what I'm sorry I
forgot since the beginning now what we
are doing differently is instead of
using curl button I'm using a fully
qualified domain name because it works
or at least according to the
documentation if I give curl or any DNS
which my service SVC then my name space
dot cluster dot local cover net lease
offer the DNS entry by default so by
some reason I see on the Siskel's and
all this tracing that we are profiting a
very funny search or we are searching
for a very funny domain name so it's
probably search doing funky stuff we'll
see here we do this request that
obviously
it's not going to be fun we'll do the
request again removing some parts of it
sir the search domain it's removing
different parts again not phone he does
it one more time with less it's not
found so we might think that we are
losing time
so the original problem was this was
taken to execute around 8 to 10 seconds
but if we if we look at the time stamps
from the beginning this was 41 minutes
39 seconds and I'm here I'm still 41
minutes 39 seconds so what's the problem
here why this is not working if we see
already here let me find it I did it in
if we see already here we start to see a
DNS request that they are having oh they
are appending at the end something we
are not expecting local domain raising
so let me keep searching because I want
to find and actually I will I want to
find the last request we do here you see
where I'm trying to do a local domain
I'm already at the end and this is not
working so that's that's crazy so what
happen what it's happening here is that
let's start to look at the timestamp on
the left so we go faster 41:47 41 43 so
what happened in between
oh I love that so what's happening in
here look look what we can see here so
what's happening is that the sky DNS is
going to etcd it's trying to forty to
get sorry the DNS request is going to
sky DNS sky DNS identifies this request
with a local domain appended at the end
and sky DNS s whoa this is a domain i
don't have in kubernetes so this must be
some external annoying so let's send
this out to my upstream DNS server and
because my upper string DNS server it's
not answering so it's answering very
slowly is not even available we wait for
a full dns timeout almost four seconds
so this will happen one time will happen
two times and will happen three times
until Lipsy decides it's enough stop it
trying to remove
pieces of my of my full search domain
and we will just try to resolve the
fully qualified domain vanilla as I gave
it to my curl and then obviously will
work so this is what happens at the end
so this is a very good way to when we
have different services talking to each
other how we can get visibility of
things one one side the other side says
Lake and the filters are very convenient
and you will say well but this was
everything Network I could have done
this with PCP done and with more patient
using my filters I said okay yes but you
want to be completely sure that what was
happening on your client so as I show
you before since they thus allow not
only to filter on your network traffic
but on any file descriptor so if I'm
using the echo FDS as I show you before
and now I'm going to repeat it because
now will make more sense to you if I
don't have the same problem I had before
so I can see that the was something
appended at the end which was local
domain that it KN we found out it
because it was being executed in a
developer machine and the developer had
a local domain added by probably some
network manager crap or who knows and
that was going or was being transmitted
into kubernetes and kubernetes was
creating the docker containers with the
search domain appended to it and how you
can be sure that this is happening well
again we know that we can use Cystic to
understand how kubernetes is instructing
docker to create the containers so I'm
not going to use local domain here
because this is not life on my example
what I'm going to use just search so if
I run singular comment to the one before
but this time I'm filtering on unique
sockets and if I try to launch a new
container I'll see how cover knit is
using the docker API on a UNIX socket to
tell docker how you need to create this
container according to the description
so I'm going to run this now I'm going
to create a different container
different name there we go
super container
and teach it in tune something is
failing here again having buffer
contains search well you will have to
believe me
well probably there is something wrong
on my filtering I want to keep the last
five minutes for questions but yeah this
is the idea if or when you leave this
talk now in five minutes what I would
like you to remember or to keep for how
much that you can use Cystic to
troubleshoot anywhere you can hold
anywhere on your hosts if we compare
this to order a BPF based tools this is
way more simple to use you don't need to
know exactly what kind of system called
you want to hurt you need to code any
script just using something similar to
what could be TCP dump both or nest
roids and system cooler where you can
very quickly see a lot of things
obviously it's not as complete as it has
different use cases but you can see
Network you can see file descriptors you
can see everything that has us is called
a touch and this is everything I have
for today I'm living here three links
this very same talk it's fully explained
in the last link so if you're very tired
and you want to look at this is call
these calls more carefully maybe with a
beer in your hand more relaxed go three
you have the same capture so you can
play with filters yourself and
everything totally recommended I hope
you like it we have five minutes for
questions
[Applause]
the question was how can I run this on
any system like the eCos well in this
case it was a command-line tool that it
was installed through a package but
since they can be installed just pulling
the container for docker from docker huh
any place where you can run a docker
container
he can run Cystic the requirement is
that needs to be a privileged container
because we need to pin the kernel module
insert it and we need to execute in
small so that happens
what's the best part of a
there is a question was when I have a
multiple machines scenario how can I
correlate the events or the system calls
between all of them at the moment there
is no tool to merge the different
capture files
yes we have the commercial tool that
does something similar to run on
multiple hosts shouldn't be very
difficult in the same way we have tools
to merge chippie copper or files
together we could write a very simple
tool to merge this and then open the
only thing to take into account is that
these files they tend to grow very very
quickly
remember that they store all the system
calls with all the i/o buffers
everything being executed on your
machine so just a few seconds on a
production server can be a fee gigabytes
so you need to be careful with filters
to keep only the information you are
interested in well if you have no
questions send me a tweet message or
anything be happy to answer thank you
[Applause]