so
it is a tutorial for hardware design
very basic stuff but it can be it can
give you guidelines about things you can
do so it's forcing like that that for
software and most particularly okay and
Wapiti Curie
it's for designing Mouse this kind of
circuit of chip and two kind of cheetah
some data analog so they under value
signals at some data digital and so it's
only it's a talk about digital design
digital chip okay so the first thing to
know is that designing a chip is very
complex requires a lot of knowledge a
lot of tools and it's also very very
very expensive but only big company can
afford to design a very complex and very
very big chip
hopefully there are some kind of chips
like this one that can be programmable
by user so the features of the chips are
completely defined by the user usually
it's complete its defined by the Builder
of the board but if you can get you can
buy board with this kind of chips and
program it by yourself it's because it
has a very particular architecture which
is composed of logical block so where
you can define the logical function that
would be done and a network of
connection that is also programmable and
the user will also define how the signal
are rooted within this network
and they're also bad so what our
available on the connector off and they
are also programmable at least to set
direction of the part and other features
well I talk about digital circuit so we
are only speaking about zero and one
it's very simple it's a well it's about
binary logic so the way to do
computation on binary logic is using
gates there are I would say three basic
gates which is not yet
so it just invest the signal if you add
0 at the input to get one if you have
the one you get to 0 it corresponds to
the teeth in the C language you have or
gate so as you as soon as one of the
input is 1 the output is 1 if both
inputs are 0 they'll put in 0 this
correspond to the pipe up to the logical
pipe operator in C and there is an gate
which is output is 1 only if and only if
both the inputs are set to 1 and this
corresponds to the ampersand operator
and the proto of see where this was
liked very simple maybe too simple you
can say okay what can we do with only 3
operators sweet logical operators but
you get a lot of power by combining them
so for example usually the eggs are so
exclusive or operator which is expressed
with carrot in C can be created by all
the paiute gate so here
if boss what is which should know if
both if both output a 1 and not those
input are 0 so put is 1 this is the user
symbol for zone and with the XOR gate
you can also do computation with
mathematical computation like for
starting another so another one bit
adder is in fact exhort gate
so another is little bit simple and we
can complete it by designing what we
call a full adder so I would say half
adder is a simple adder and the career
so the curry is one only if both inputs
are one and if you want to be a little
bit more couplet you can design a full
adder with an input carry and output
carry so it becomes it a bit complex it
handles all the values cases of the
possible inputs value of the inputs and
generate the Sun and the output curry
and usually it's too complex to be
written like like this so on scheme you
abstract with a box saying okay so it's
another and with this full adder you can
do 6 little bit more complex because you
can group them together and here you
have a 4-bit other and if you want to
set it to bit other you can just
replicate this scheme several times so
you have inputs a and input B the Sun
and at the end a carry that you can
ignore this is how you do a summation
an edition in hardware and if you can
add what you cannot so multiply so you
replicate there are several times and
you either it's like a multiplication on
the bench paper and pencil you add only
if the bit is said to one and each time
you shift this is how you can do
multiplayer in hardware starting from
other starting from simple gates so as
you may as you have seen just using
simple logical gate you can do I would
say almost any mathematical function
well almost any simple mathematical
function in hardware so from it you get
you have inputs and you compute outputs
that's nice but in fact that's not that
powerful because very quickly your
design becomes very very big we have
seen how big is a multiplier if you do a
lot of multiplication in your
computation it will be very very large
and one way to short
shorten the computation is to use the
right person you want to reuse the
output in as inputs and fortunately or
as a matter of fact you can't do that
easily the reason is because hardware is
not about only logical concept it's also
about physical concept like time
propagation if you if you come back to
the full adder there are three inputs
and in fact the times
it's times there is a gate it takes time
to compute the output because some
capacity capacity in the in the design
star Eden it's not it's not lightning
fast it takes time to compute the output
and as a consequence the output are not
ready at the same time so you may expect
a perfect output like in this diagram
but in fact for example the output of a
zero comes just before but before the
output of a one and if you observe a
loop it will drift more and more and for
example the output of a two will be
available much later and because of that
you will add wrong outputs at many times
so you don't know where is the correct
output so you can try to avoid this
nastiest fact by for example balancing
the circuit but it's very very very hard
so the main word and when you do digital
design is never have direct feedback and
the way to solve that is to use what we
call a register memorizing element which
need a clock and this particular gate
what we well we call it a flip-flop will
only win drive we memorize the input and
we reflect the input only at some times
when the clock is active so here for
example the clock is active so the the
input of the flip-flop here will be
reflected to the output just when the
clock is active here
again here's a clock he cast is active
the input is here and will be reflected
on the output here and with this kind of
circuit you have a perfect
well perfectly clean output that reason
why we always use much almost always use
clocks in digital circuit and I'm the
reason why any digital circuit as a
maximum clock weight due to the time it
takes for the loop and that's a
performance attached to any digital
circuit so most of the digital circuit
are composed of logic gates that do
computation and phipps herbs or register
that are used to synchronize the circuit
the computation so that the base of how
to design a circuit computation
segmentation it's possible to design a
real circuit using schematic editor but
it works well for very simple circuit
but as soon as it becomes a bit complex
people prefer to use an HDL which is
hardware description language it's like
along with a salon weed or general in
which but the target specific
specifically hardware there are two
mains hardware language very log and
VHDL and here we use VHDL
so we have this kind of board with a
programmable secrete FPGA and since
about two years we have complete open
source software tools to program this
kind of circuit so there is a scent it
is named uses there is a pleasant note I
will explain that later
that is named eric lee hazlewood and
there is ice term which is used to
create the the binary binary stream to
program this circuit so this body is
about 20 euros so very affordable and it
is supported by open source tools so
it's very nice for for beginners so the
first one the only example using the HDL
this described is when an entity
describes the interface of the sorry
which means how it will communicate with
the environment so there is one input
which is the clock and on this board
the clock is generated by your circuit
on the board and five outputs which are
routed on this circuit on the 5 LEDs but
they are not very easy to see it
mattered I will show so just described
with no TT the interface inputs and
outputs
and in vhdl you have the architectures
which describe the internal of the
circuit so i havenít immediate wire
which is which which is a internal clock
because extra clock is three McGirt and
if I try to blink the LED after swimming
guards you will see the sink so I use a
divider to go to divide to four Hertz
which is visible at this point so all
the LEDs will be being together at four
else and how I convert from three three
minutes to four heads I just use a
controller that is incremented each time
the clock as a rising edge from zero to
one so each time the clock is rising
either I average the top of my filter
which is three million minus one and so
I reset the contour to 0 and then I
switch the clock oh if I if I even reach
the maximum of my cooter I just element
it so the guitar will increment it until
300 and then I turn that it will revert
to zero and switch the for McGurk's
clock you have to know that in any
hardware description language everything
is parallel
so this executes at the same time as
this one this one this one this one and
the process is liquid at the same time
at this one everything is parallel
except that within the process execution
is second sure so this is not a tutorial
computer toriel about VHDL just a view
of how it's done so once you have
written the entity and the structure we
will go to synthesis which will come at
it
- binary code used to program the
programs FPGA and using the GS dead
front-end you first analyze the the file
so you let the compiler know about these
files and then you did the Santa teasers
you say ok I want to generate - sorry
for lead which is known here and I want
to target this FPGA so if this FPGA is a
IC e-40 and you specify the output file
so you guys a lot of processing that is
done on the input file and it generate
what we call an at least which is a net
of gates and off registers and then you
can use a rack the P&L - + to place all
these gates so it will try to assign
each gate to the logical blocks of the
FPGA and to route all the nets what's
very to be technical it pretty
automatically and if it works you you're
okay and with when usual it was usually
it works it works it falls apart you are
using too many gates and there's not
enough gates of the the FPGA or if you
are just at the limit the person who
talk and say no I cannot find all I
cannot find all those routes and when
you pass on what you so specify which
pads is assigned to all the input and
then you have to program the FPGA so in
fact on this board you have a USB
connector and the USB connector is
connected to to a flash so you write a
binary to the flash and the FPGA when it
is started it
with binary from the flash and program
all this all the route network and and
the logical block and once once you once
you flashed you have rhythms of your
binary stream in the flash it's ok so
it's not exactly the one I have program
but you could see LED blinking in fact
it's what I think it's a different it's
a thirty more elaborately designed it's
rotating but almost the same so this is
all the open-source tools i abused okay
i am the developer of jl so that's why i
have used it
your sis is a synthetic server but it
also that's also gone up front end which
is normal when it is almost pizza food
why the VHL front-end is just when still
work-in-progress
what's at so you have a really touched
an open-source option for this kind of
SPG
[Applause]
it's ladies semiconductor but if you
look on Google for ICU for tea you will
find it
the Bing
good question minion sir
first if you don't do back you don't get
to debug second what you can do with
once you have written your design you
can simulate it so it's completely
software approach and you can see you
can try to feed inputs and you can see
what has outputs or you can write test
bench to be sure that your design
behaves correctly and sometimes it bears
correctly on the paper and we say and
when you program in network and then
it's not easy
usually you have to you can you can you
have to add some circuit to try to
understand what happens and was in the
stress Cup but that is kind of difficult
[Music]
know unless you want to other on
circuits that try to read values net and
outputs on the external part but no
[Music]
yeah yes there does simulation for VHDL
and I carries very not does simulation
for very long so it's complete
[Applause]