hi everyone
so I'm Mike Simonson on Twitter I'm a
web developer I am one of the maintainer
of doctrine for those who know the tool
I'm also the organizer of bristle PHP if
there are people from Brussels that are
interested or if there are people that
know any company that is willing to host
us I'd be very happy to talk with you
after the talk and I also worked at cube
solution whenever I'm not behind my
computer you can probably find me hiking
somewhere outdoor now that that part is
done
would you mean why screen no it's
apparently wait sorry
nope oh I can
no it's apparently the best I can do
so I suppose everyone here is a PHP
developer but who here is used to doing
TDD at work ok quite a few people who is
doing TDD like for more than five years
I mean that is quite experienced ok
I hope I'm still gonna give you a few
tricks but this talk is basically
everything that I've learned along the
way going to conferences and meeting
people from very different backgrounds
for instance maybe some of you know
drawer helper I'm probably butchering
his name but it's a c-sharp developer
that gives a very similar talk in
c-sharp but most of what he learned me
is applicable in any language and if you
want to learn stuff about unit testing
he has definitely very interesting stuff
to say who here works agile at work also
pretty much everyone who here works I
mean the boss their boss says that they
work agile but in fact they just do
waterfall ok
so as I said that that talk is going to
be mostly about my experience but I
think it's a lot of you will based on
your answer a lot of you can relate to
that experience my first experience with
unit testing whether at school
we're basically we were more learn we
were more teach how to delete the test
that just failed because we changed some
piece of code and just do something else
like test another part of the code than
anything else in a way I could see that
it might be useful but it was
very frustrating after school I went to
British company for my internship and
there they really practiced the right
way I would say or at least the first
useful way that I had seen it was a very
interesting experience for me because
that was the first time that I could see
someone developing new code using TDD in
a way that wasn't cumbersome and wasn't
just making me waste tons of time not
doing what uh not knowing what where I
was gonna go then I I went to my first
bake job
it was a very big company with lots of
that whopper and apparently no one was
interested in to building code that
actually worked so I was I was mostly
trying to do tests myself but I was the
only one to run them I was also the only
one to write them and the only one to
fix them because I was the only one to
notice when they break that was also
very frustrating but yeah life goes on
and I changed job to go in a much
smaller company where I was heavily
encouraged going to conference like
first M and it's basically at those
conference that I learned most of what I
know now
I'm mostly going to speak here about
unit testing but that's just one part of
all the tests that you can do on your
application but before to speak about
the different kind of test to see where
the unit test stands there is also the
pretty obvious question like when should
we test it's always a cost-benefit
question at some point like the project
has to shape and you have to get paid so
you have to know when to test and when
not to test most of the time I'd say
that it's rather a question like is that
project going to live on after I
finished working on it like am I going
to give that project who this project
responsibility to someone else is
someone going to maintain have to
maintain it if the answer is yes then
it's probably a bit I mean it would be
nicer for him to test it it's gonna
simplify the job of the person that
comes after you a lot especially because
we live in an industry where we are
asked to build prototype and all those
prototype end up in production so if you
wanna know when to test basically ask
yourself the question if you want your
project to succeed or not the unit tests
in the wall test scene is basically the
one that is at the bottom it's the test
that is the closest to the logic of the
code the one that is the fastest to run
because it has the least dependency if
your unit tests as well of the balance
it's not a unit test anymore it's
basically a functional test or an
integration test and the fact that it's
fast to run because it
no dependency make it cheap to run and
make it interesting in the sense that if
you run those tests a lot then they are
gonna be useful the only good reason to
write a test is for the test to fail if
the test never failed this is just
useless it's just wasting time and space
I suppose everyone has seen a unit test
here the example is in Java but it's
pretty much the same in any language you
just have a method in some random class
that is marked one way or another either
way with the annotation of whatever else
exists in your language that is similar
to annotation and that's the same job -
to mark that that method is a test
whether give you is effectively the fact
that you can have a piece of code that
can detect that automatically and you
don't need to program that part of the
work it's just gonna pick up whichever
test you have anywhere in your in your
code and run them automatically it's a
contract between between you and your
unit testing framework the first issue
that I had when I was in that big
company trying to implement or and run
the test myself was that I didn't really
knew a lot of tools that could help me
and now it's really easy to use any one
of them I mean they're all over the
place any unit testing framework has its
own test runner you also have a build
server that you can install to run your
tests on a separate machine and you can
even implement in really simple fashion
a script that picks up every time you
change your code and run the test that
way you don't even need to away go out
of your IDE if you use one and run the
test it's just going to happen
automatically you can have on one screen
your test
instantly running and working the other
without any issue the build server is
also important because as opposed to
what I was doing it gives a way to show
the test result to the other person in
the team I was the only one to run them
so I was the only one to notice when
they failed it's like if someone cannot
see the result of the test in the team
obviously it's not that person is going
to forget to run them at some points and
then forget to use them completely so
installing a build server if you're more
than one person in the team feels like a
necessity to me it became really easy
now
there are templates for PHP projects in
Jenkins I suppose everyone knows Jenkins
it's really easy to set up now you
should definitely do it
there are also IDE runner for whichever
IDE that you use there is probably a
test runner that's already integrated in
it and can provide additional
functionality like just run the tests
that cover that piece of code yeah now
writing those tests you can basically be
in two different situation you are
either wave writing test for a brand new
project or you're writing test for
existing code that you have to maintain
let's face it there is way more projects
to maintain than new project to do even
though there is a lot of new project to
do but like I suppose every one of you
has had to maintain a project at some
point and it's the bulk of the work if
you have
new code it's obviously going to be
easier to start - in TDD on that code
and in that is I would encourage you to
take a look at BDD tools behavior driven
development tools there are basically a
little bit the same the same kind of
tool that we have for unit testing for
the code they have the same behavior but
for the person that actually asked you
the feature of that code so by writing
scenario and behavior different
development it's gonna guide you on what
unit tests you should write so that you
can write the code that fulfills those
unit tests and fulfill two scenario I'm
not going to talk about those tools
there is a lot of documentation
available pretty much everywhere if
you're looking for one in PHP there is B
hats for instance but there are other
it's just the most well-known Oh sadly
if you are not in that case most
probably your code will have
dependencies like often when you look at
blog posts that describe how to do TDD
they use a calculator example it's
really nice because it's really concise
but none of the code that I wrote is
actually so dependency less than a
calculator and as I said previously if
you have dependencies and you use them
in your unit tests it's gonna make the
tests slow it's also going to be really
hard to set up across the machine of all
I mean reliably set up across the
machine of everyone that's on a team
especially if you have people that are
Windows others that are on Mac and Linux
and it's also going to be a pain to set
up on the CI server if you have one
some of those dependencies are a little
bit more subtle than others often people
don't realize that the time is really
annoying dependency and I remember that
when I was in London one of the tests
that I fixed was a test that failed six
months on the year and it was basically
just an issue in a data calculation that
wasn't taking into account the yeah the
daylight saving time it's really hard to
figure out that is the issue if you
don't see the time as a dependency of
your code and try to extract the
dependency in a very explicit way one of
the way that I've seen people deal with
those dependencies is creating what's
called fake object it's really simple to
do here you have an example with the
migration class of doctrine migration it
has a bunch of methods and if you need
to create a fake object for that you
just extend migration and override all
the function that all the public
function of that of that object without
putting anything in the body of the
function and you have just an object
that is really similar but doesn't do
anything it's really easy to do that
like if you start testing but it's going
to be obtained really really fast
because every time you will change
something in the object that you extend
you're gonna have to change it also in
the fake object that's a lot of code
that you have to maintain yourself every
code that you write yourself you have to
maintain yourself and and that's it
now there is also who heard already
about mocking frameworks most of you so
I can probably go a little bit faster
there but it's basically a piece of code
that will do that work for you
automatically so every time that you
change something in your object it can
regenerate that fake object
automatically it can also provide a lot
of additional functionality on top of
that for instance you can verify that
certain methods of your object have been
called or have not been called which is
much harder to do if you implement the
fake object yourself here you have an
example of one of the mocking library
that exists in PHP it's called mercury
there is also a lot of father there is
prophecy and even PHP unit has its own
mocking library but mercury has very
interesting feature like for instance
one of the thing that's annoying when
you have a lot of stuff to mark in your
code is that sometimes you have to
create a lot of mock object that's
returned each other until you have
actually marked the dependency that you
want it to mark and you can do that at
once with Mal free which is nice
although it might mean in the first
place that your code has a problem of
structure if you have so much to mark
but if it's just good that you have to
maintain it's a really quick fix before
you can refactor that piece of code any
questions yet nope
now I don't know if anyone heard about
Oh - mocking container do okay I'm gonna
do something sadly that's not something
that exists in PHP yet at least III
couldn't find any implementation but
it's that idea that in most framework
now they have a dependency injection
container that you configure so they can
create the object that you need in your
application and they reuse that
container to automatically generate
mocks
so because that dependency injection
container already knows how to build the
actual object it can really easily
create that object only passing its
mocks
so you have actually the real object it
just cannot do anything on its own now
the the time dependency the solution to
fix the time dependency is basically to
pass the time every time you need to use
it if you have the time now anywhere or
date time without any parameter and you
were in your code I just gonna make that
piece of code really hard to test and
you should probably buy that information
at at at creation time so
it looks like that piece of example is
okay sorry this is actually showing how
you can you can do that pass the time
without having to change too much if you
do it at first you can implement an
interface a clock interface that just
returned the current time and then you
can implement to class a system clock
that just do that returned a time now
and a mock clock
that's an about clock that is going to
return the time that you decide in your
test okay I'm sorry for the order of the
slide here but yeah the first one was
showing the problem but here bypassing
the clock and asking the clock the
current time we have actually fixed or
dependency issue to the time if we have
any test that needs it you we can just
replace the system clock by the Mach one
and passive the time that we want to use
in our test it's mostly useful if you
are making calculation but it doesn't
take a lot of time to implement so I
would recommend to take a look at that
solution now
it's all good but we also have a big
problem in the documentation of this of
the the unit testing framework in
general because they never really
explain you how you should structure
your tests or how you should write them
because you have that freedom in that
method of your unit test where you can
do anything you want yeah it's maybe a
little bit hurtful in that sense and
often the the the information that you
can find at least in my opinion makes
you end up in with tests that are really
hard to maintain maybe we can come back
to the definition of the of a unit test
it's an automated piece of code that's a
really important one because at the the
company where my girlfriend worked
they had unit testing that they told her
while they hired hired her it was just
some person with an excel sheet file
that was just running the test by
clicking on the button in the interface
that's not a unit test it's a unit of
work of the system that one is really
hard to define I've not seen anyone yet
that could give me a proper definition
of that the only thing that I can tell
you is that to me a unit test it's a
test that tests the smallest possible
blocks of code and you can check that if
you use code coverage often you will see
people that use code coverage as a sort
of vanity vanity thing on their read me
on github yeah yeah I have a hundred
person code coverage but that doesn't
give you an indication
on the quality of those tests if they
are easy to understand what they are
actually testing and if you're if it's
going to be possible to modify them or
not
that's test should check one and only
one assumption about the code that one
is a really important one as a doctrine
maintainer I sometimes read pull
requests where we have tests there are
like 200 lines of code and you will see
someone that do something then assert
something then do something else then
assert something else and it's actually
impossible to understand what he's
trying to test or what he's trying to do
in that test test one thing put what
you're testing in the name of the method
and the person that comes after you is
going to love you it doesn't actually
still if you allowed an information of
the structure of the test yeah
as I said one of the important stuff to
test the quality of a test is to make it
fail first if the test didn't fail your
can never be sure that it actually
tested what you expected it to test
that's something that happened to me
countless time writing tests thinking
that they work and never see them
failing because they were actually not
testing what I taught at all as I told
you the code coverage which is the
really way better use trying to
determine what you are testing than
trying to give you a good feeling by
showing a high percentage that the best
way you can use the code coverage is
trying to cover only one test you run
one test and you see how much code it's
covering if it's covering hundreds of
line it's not a unit test anymore it's
probably going to be slow and it's going
to be much harder to understand what
it's trying to test
okay what is that example I'm sorry yeah
that's the test that he's trying to test
no that's another problem of the code
coverage often you can end up with a
hundred person car coverage and you
think you are safe except that in that
case you can write three tests that will
come will give you a hundred person code
coverage but they are not giving you
they are not testing all the possible
scenario that that code can be in
because actually maybe it's better ask
like how many tests do you think you
have to write to cover all the scenario
of that example so who says free who
says four five six twenty seven how do
you reach that number three power three
I think it's three factorial but I would
say it's three factorial three to be
sure that you pass in all the if and
then one more because you could pass in
none of them but anyway it's that that
piece of code could give you the
impression that your code is tested and
can still end up in a situation that you
did not expect how can you detect that
it like it's really hard to know if your
test is good and the only tool that can
help you do that is mutation testing any
any one of you heard about mutation
testing ok quite a few people for those
who don't know again it's the ID to try
to use the code coverage in a slightly
different way we have a PHP tool to do
that
it's called Hamburg
it's actually going to run your test
using code coverage so it can map each
test with a piece of code that is
covering and based on that it's going to
change logic in your actual code it's
going to randomly change greater than
into lower or equal and that kind of
change that are actually syntax lis
correct but will change the behavior of
your test and then it runs the test that
covered that piece of code and there can
be only three solution either way the
code blow up the test catch the failure
or the test doesn't see anything and
it's actually that part that interests
us if your tests did not catch a change
of behavior of your code
I mean it probably means that the test
is not that good the the problem of that
kind of tool is that because the change
are randomly generated over your code
you have to inspect the change that it
did because it could have no actual
change in behavior it's just the syntax
that change in PHP but that's something
that you have to go through manually so
it's quite slow but it's still very
useful to to determine if your tests are
good as I said because it's going to try
to map your code to the piece of code
that is covered by that test if each of
your tests cover hundreds of line it's
gonna take forever to run that kind of
tool and it's gonna be even harder to
try to interpret the result of that tool
so for instance on doctrine we cannot
run it because it would actually take
pretty much amount on my machine so we
have a lot of work to improve the test
now on the actual structure of the test
the best advice I've got this discounts
from drawer actually it's I don't know a
bit weird that I've could never read
about that anywhere but I hope that
you're gonna find it interesting you can
read about that everywhere
what is AAA anyone does anyone know what
a triple-a is sorry yeah also batteries
in the field of unit testing a is that
idea that you should have three part in
your unit test the arrange act and a
third part of your test I basically mean
that in the arrange part you set up
something then you act on it you call a
method on that piece of code and then
you assert a certain result on it so
here we are building interest collection
adding an element to it and then
checking that the element is effectively
in the collection object or not the
problem is that there is no way to
enforce that kind of stuff like you
really have to read your test and see if
they are actually following that
guidance or not it's just the guidance
so it might not work everywhere so far
for me
it has always worked but maybe someone
has an example where it might be not so
useful
the arranged part of the test here you
can see an example where in your range
part someone is actually creating two
automobiles then painting one of them
and no sorry yeah
and asserting weight so someone is
creating two cars with two different
colors then painting one window with the
color or the other and checking that in
the end that the color was effectively
painted on that second car can anyone
see any problem that could arise if you
write the test like that like it's
respecting the arranger act assert if
you have that kind of test over time
it's probably going to be an issue you
can scan someone cy yeah sorry
yeah so your object is probably going to
evolve and you might decide at some
point that having the color as a string
might be not the best idea and you
change your automobile to pass an object
as we present the color for instance or
change anything else in the constructor
of the automobile and you need to change
all your tests you need to adapt that
everywhere in all your tests so fix that
the advice that you will see everywhere
is oh but it's easy just use the setup
method every unit framework every unit
testing framework provide that kind of
facilities one method that will get cold
every time just before running your
tests it works
but it has two issues first it means
that now all your tests have a
dependency on that setup method and if
at some point one of the tests make a
change to the object it's gonna its
might affect the following tests that
can run we have things for that now in
PHP unit and most of the time it
shouldn't be an issue because it's
actually PHP unit that's gonna make a
new instance of the unit testing class
and call the setup and called the next
test in a computer completely separate
fashion but still you could end up in
situation especially when you're trying
to mark databases and stuff where one of
the tests do a change that gets
persisted and then the next tests are
affected by it and now you're in
situation where the order in which the
test run is actually important so that
they don't fail and when they fail you
have to start like binary you testing
all your tests to find which one is
causing the issue in your test face I've
had to do that
in times it's really painful so I would
advise against against using that the
other issue is that although here it
might seems like your code is dry
because you are only creating the
automobile at one place in the setup
method and then it magically gets called
everywhere if you have a few hundred
tests and you just treat the test you
just see object that you don't know
where they come from that they get that
get calls and then the natural version
is made and it becomes that much more
easy harder to reason about the test dry
in so dry is a for those who don't know
dry is a technique which means don't
repeat yourself it tries to make sure
that you refactor your tests in a way
that you don't try twice the same piece
of code in the same class for instance
or at least that's the way a lot of
people understand it that can be a whole
other discussion but that's one of the
reason people use the setup method
because then they don't have to write
new automobiles everywhere in their
tests if you have that test in the
middle of a file and you need to scroll
at the top to find the setup method if
it's at the top and not at the bottom or
somewhere in the middle it's just a pain
to understand how your tests behave so
the next solution that I've also seen
maybe I removed that example yeah
extracting to a method to the extreme is
also hurtful for your completion of the
test because we've had client that ended
up in situation where there are D all
their unit tests basically looks like
that initialize do and then assert again
having that test or not having it is
pretty much the same now the solution to
that problem that you might maybe a know
the Builder pattern who knows the who
heard about the Builder pattern okay I
don't know why I've never seen anyone
use it in unit tests but it actually
make the unit test that much more
readable and you still get the benefit
that if your code change you have to
change it only in one place for those
who don't know the Builder pattern is
just an object that will create your
object for you so here the automobile
builder just has a build method that
will return your zoom appeal on its own
it might not seems very interesting but
if you use that with a fluent interface
so that you have methods everywhere in
your builder to change how you can or
change the parameter that you can build
your automobile with then you end up
with tests that are much more readable
you actually have
an arranged part of your test where you
can limit yourself to only specify the
stuff that are important for your test
it's not done here but you could totally
imagine that you have a create builder
method but also a create builder with
default values that I don't care about
and then on top of that you just change
the part that is important for your
current test the third part of the test
[Music]
again can anyone see a problem in the
third part of that test yeah
exactly
so maybe you might have heard that that
your test should only have one assertion
it might be not always the case in the
sense that there's some good reason to
break that rules but there are no good
reason to put an assertion in a 4h if
you start putting logic like that in
your code at some point you're just
going to need to unit test your unit
test to understand to make sure that
they're actually doing what you think
they are doing so as as a Bayes rule
it's recommended to only assert one
thing the other reason to only assert
one thing is that all the unit testing
framework true exception when the
assertion fails which means that all the
following ones won't you run and you
won't get a complete picture of what's
wrong in your code
now one of the good reason that I've
seen to actually have more than one
assertion is for instance testing an
exception if you need to test the code
of the exception but also the message it
makes sense to do that in one test but
if you write it like that again if it
fails at the error code exception code
you don't know if the the message is
still the right one or if the message is
also in a weird state it's just an
example there might be better but it get
the job done to fix that issue there is
the concept of assert all it also exists
in pretty much any unit testing
framework and it's just that idea that
you can write yourself an assertion that
you pass assertion to it and it's gonna
run all of them even if one of them
throw an exception and just read through
the exception that were that we're
thrown in the first place
at the end of your list of assertion
yeah
for some reason I see also a lot of
people that want to religiously stick
with one assertion type in all their
tests and they have a sir - everywhere
although that completely works it makes
the default error message completely
useless when you end up in test suite
that breaks a few hundred tests and the
only thing that you can find out of
those tests is a serve true but what's
false yeah I mean if the tests were in
there it was to me it's pretty much the
same so picking the right assertion for
the thing that you are trying to test
means a better error message and that's
what is going to help you fixing here in
the first place we are only writing
tests so that they fail so when they
fail it would be nice if we could get
really fast a good idea of what's the
actual problem in the test and also
people get the parameter order often
wrong so supposedly most of the unit
test run testing framework I've seen the
first parameter is what you expect and
then you pass the actual value that you
are testing if you get that in the wrong
order it's also going to make the error
message really confusing
[Music]
now another way to have better assertion
I've it's also something that I've not
seen implemented in PHP but there is no
reason why it couldn't be done and maybe
it exists and I've just not find it it's
a library that exists in c-sharp and
Java and it's called sugar and what
should we allows you it basically will
change your assertion from the one
that's on the top assert same red and
then get color to something like color
should be red when you read the test all
the time
that you don't spend doing that whole
gymnastic in your head like oh the first
parameter is what I should have and then
the second one is what I'm testing it's
a lot of time that you are not wasting
by just having it's spelling spelled out
directly in front of you it's pretty
much English yeah to me it makes the
code to test much more readable they
also they also have a very interesting
concept of equivalence where you can say
that two objects should be equivalent
but you can exclude some of the property
of the object so here in the example you
for instance use a UUID in the
constructor of your object if you try to
assert that those object are the same in
your unit test unless you have a setter
to set that ID - no it's just never it's
just going to fail all the time on the
UUID in that case
it also made the test to me super
readable it's very clear that the
customer should be equivalent but the ID
does anyone has any question yes
so what is your question exactly how to
write code that use dependency injection
or
yeah so your question is where is
dependency injection or
no I I should probably have asked the
question but yeah who doesn't know
whether than the C injection is okay
maybe people are high but dirt
no it's okay the idea of dependency
injection is just that ID that instead
of doing stuff like that where the UUID
for instance is just created using a
static method which make it impossible
for the person that looks at your code
to know that it's actually past
dependency on a UUID library instead of
doing that you make sure that everything
that is used in your code is either way
passed to the constructor if it's
necessary at construct time or it's
passed to the method that using in any
case using dependency injection in my
opinion is going to make the code more
readable because just by looking at the
constructor you directly know what is
necessary for that class were actually
doing its job but it's also going to be
easier to test because in your test you
can override all those dependencies
easily whereas it's much harder if it's
a static call or impossible any other
question yeah
to be fair it's just an example maybe
it's not the best but to answer a part
of your question that is about the fact
that it's testing at the same time the
paint method in the get method I would
not expect a get method to have any
logic in it so it would be weird that it
fails it's totally something that could
happen especially if it's good that you
didn't try it yourself and code that's
existing and that you are trying to unit
test but there it's just an example you
know it's maybe not the best yeah
maybe I did not insisted on the port
enough but mark is a fix for a code that
is already problematic if you have to
use marks too much and everywhere
it basically means that your code is
structured in a way that everything is
dependent on everything and that makes
it super hard to test that's exactly
what's going to happen something is
going to change somewhere and all the
tests are going to break mark is only
there because you have already existing
code and you're trying to test a small
part of it it cannot fix all your code
at once
yeah maybe I should use an example where
it's actually useful but in the case
that you are showing it could actually
be a problem I have a hard time finding
a good reason to use verify just like on
the spot now but I've seen example where
it was partly justified I just cannot
find a good one
just now we're all the time sorry
thank you very much
[Applause]