40:17 distribution several thank you
very much and I would like to introduce
Peter Robinson talking to us about using
fedora or IOT hello everyone I'm sorry
for stopping you from your beer so I'm
going to talk about architecting
a secure IOT platform using a generic
distribution such as Fedora so the
Internet of Things has the potential to
change the world not necessarily in a
good way and Linux distributions have
been around for some time and have a lot
of the dealing with security and CVS and
updates and distribution mechanisms and
all that sort of fun stuff for long
solved and relatively straightforward
and so why can't we use the current
knowledge to continue to evolve and
improve the IOT to make it a little bit
friendlier place for for the world as a
whole this is a general overview of an
IOT stack one of these days I'll
actually get around to doing this
graphic myself because as someone
pointed out it has a cortex M series
which you can't exactly run Fedora on so
what would you use as a base platform
for IOT if you were to use it for fedora
well the first technology there is a
tech called atomic or OS 3 it enables a
single snapshot upgrade snapshot
rollback of a distribution in an atomic
state so if you boot a device with an
update and it doesn't boot or it doesn't
have network connectivity you can run a
series of
health checks and reset back to the old
version so you should never get into a
situation where you have a brick device
or an uncontacted ball device or a
device that doesn't have access to all
its senses
you obviously need a very good focus on
security and multiple architectures
obviously x86 is a fairly wide spread
with a bunch of IOT but obviously arm
and more so these days arm 64 you
certainly a series of well known
architectures that are deep into the IOT
space
so and that's basically my role is to
build a IOT platform using fedora as a
base as part of my job at Red Hat to
help define we're going to initially
focus on a gateway platform both
industrial and home and various other
use cases and focus on a handful of
devices although it will work on pretty
much any device that support is
supported by fedora but yeah so we like
in the arm space we probably support to
300 different arm devices these days but
it's a lot of work to be able to polish
each and every one of them so we'll
focus on the Raspberry Pi 2 & 3 because
obviously they're very popular the solid
run humming board edge devices which are
the first version of the Lennar o light
reference platform the Beagle bone
variants because they're quite good for
IOT Intel dual platform from an x86
point of view and a pion 64 from a
height of 64 point of view but it's sort
of still a bit up in the air and will
evolve it as things happen
yes so this is basically an overview of
what the Gateway will be based on a
minimal atomic base image with
containers to add functionality and in
the f26 cycle we'll focus on some
example containers like an MQTT
container and and also various different
networking technologies both wireless
and wired such as 802 15 for Bluetooth
le and various other open standards
obviously security is a very important
and poignant point when it comes to IOT
and there'll be a focus on things like
UEFI or opti as part of a secure boot
and verification so from the moment the
processor boots
whether it's using TPMS on x86 or arm
trusted firmware and various other
technologies like that from the arm
platforms to give us the ability to
verify the entire OS through the boot
process to make sure it hasn't been
compromised dependency minimization
there's not generally no real need to
ship 3 or 4 TLS stacks for example if
you can ship less you've got less sort
of coverage and less chance of major CVS
and compromise and things like set comp
and SELinux toolchain related
functionality sandboxing various systemd
functionalities and the kernel self
protection project there's a bunch of
different sort of initiatives there that
are helping secure and reduce so and
even eliminate entire types of sort of
compromised
and then obviously with containers you
can namespace them and isolate them
which means each sort of individual
security service that's running is in an
isolated context with either access
control or proxy or what-have-you to be
able to access different parts of the
network or different components
different network isolation technologies
device isolation and policy routing on
the Gateway level to ensure that if
you've got an entire class of device
that you don't want to connect to the
internet that you can identify whether
it be via MAC address or OS
fingerprinting and things like that you
can set up policy routes to either not
route them or isolate them to ensure
that you know if your acting is the
gateway that these devices can't become
part of a botnet or other such Network
support focus on open standards so
things like 802 15 4 rather than
proprietary technology such as ZigBee
and other sort of locking technologies
where you've got a license or patent or
what-have-you
6lowpan as a protocol and and various
other and things like older technology
such as rs-485 and someone was asking me
about Modbus the other day can support
for controller area networks etc so this
is a sort of general typical wireless
iot topology
as a sort of just a general overview and
so this will be the sort of initial
focus point from my point of view with
fedora IOT and some sample containers
open thread and other networking
services MQTT and various other
messaging stacks caching modules and
various middleware and then a selection
of possible IOT specific stacks there's
been a couple of people that have been
slowly packaging up node-red and each
time a new release comes out they add a
few hundred extra dependencies I'm
fairly certain they now depend on over
50% of the the nodejs sort of repository
stack which is I believe one of the
largest repositories in terms of pure
numbers of libraries on the Internet
so it's it's a very interesting project
but it's vast in terms of I think
they've already packaged up something
like 500 different no js' dependencies
and they're still only a smaller way
there so we may look and see if we can
just pull that in and run a container
style in the short term while we get all
of that done plus there's some
interesting IOT projects coming out of
the Apache project such as current hanno
and similarly related projects Sawada is
an IO Intel IOT project which is already
packaged up in fedora and and there's a
number of other ones that people have
shown interest in
so we're just doing a gateway initially
yes but it's just a starting point as a
means of doing a proof-of-concept and
driving focus I have a tendency that if
I'm not focused on something in
particular I have lots and lots of ideas
and I'll deliver little bits of lots and
lots of ideas and we won't end up with
something that's particularly useful it
gives us a good starting base to build
both the put the different options but
also the community around and it'll be a
combination of industrial IOT and home
because there's a lot of people
interested in the home side of things
but obviously RedHat from a commercial
point of view it's more focused on
industrial and medical and other such
sort of industry gateways and it'll be
initially a proof-of-concept
as a testing platform nothing set in
stone it will evolve and change as
necessary and as you know people
discover things what are the options
imaging stacks I've had a bunch of
interest around different sort of
embedded devices with cameras used for
whether it be security and detection of
like movement or other sort of OCR style
wrecking like recognition or image
recognition and various other stacks
like that and there's some other
interesting projects where we're having
some discussions with there's an AI
platform called Mycroft which is open
source
and they're very interested in working
with us to do some IOT related stuff and
numerous most many ideas to mention like
I come up with a different idea every
other day so so yes in summary I feel
atomic is the right way to go in terms
of updatable secure devices multiple
texture support from the outset initial
reference devices with focus and based
platform in gateway functionality to
start with any questions
so you talk about dependency reduction
so you wouldn't have very many libraries
so that involves not using the standard
fedora bills no no weirdness is like a
different way to get a minimised kind of
so to repeat the question for those that
might be watching online does the
dependency minimization result in
different Fedora packages or Forks of
the package and no it doesn't we'll be
working with the maintainer of those
packages to ensure that that's the case
and there's already other initiatives as
part of yet the intention is to be a
hundred percent within fedora we're
still in the fedora twenty six timeframe
it'll probably be part of the fedora
playground branding but the intention is
to have it eventually as a fully
accepted similar to works workstation
and server and cloud and atomic the
different projects there the intention
or hope from the discussions that I've
had with the FPL is basically to sort of
have it a fully core part of fedora or
at least potentially
[Music]
so the question is around the reference
device support and specific hardware
support within those devices so by
default I think all of those reference
well most of those reference devices
either have wireless and Bluetooth or
options of so like the Raspberry Pi 3
has both wireless and Bluetooth and the
humming board has options of wireless
and Bluetooth the Beagle bone now has a
couple of different models that come
with both wireless and Bluetooth the
vast majority of them already have can
support actual onboard kin controllers
except for maybe the Intel dual but at
least Soviet so the imx6 has can the
Raspberry Pi doesn't have can out so it
will depend a little bit on the device
and depend a little bit on the matrix of
what we decide to support initially and
we'll adjust devices and support matrix
as we go
yeah correct yeah so in the case of like
802 15 4 there's two or three devices
that come with it on board but some of
the different controllers are better or
worse supported upstream and there's a
couple of USB ones that are very well
supported which is what so yeah so
minissha Lee it will probably be like I
personally have interests in the 802 802
15 for stuff and I have a bunch of
different devices at home with it on
board and then but we will probably say
that like initially until there's more
Hardware shipping that will you know
recommend the USB
10 the security stuff one thing was
missing was the any connection any
communications over then and that
so the question is around securing SSL
or TLS based services outbound to the
Internet it's not explicitly mentioned
on the slide deck but it's essentially
service by service so in the case of
mqtt it supports that out of the box
depending on which broker you're using
the underlying base platform other than
pulling down like the updates won't have
any outbound services to note and then
each one will depend on the container
that it's running on does that answer
your question Dennis so the question is
about the management of vast amounts of
devices at the moment atomic doesn't
have a general story there but it is
also being worked on as part of that
team so the intention is there to
consume their standard mechanisms of
dealing with it as it's developed it's
certainly something that's on my roadmap
management of devices managers of
devices connected to the Gateway control
of those devices centralized policies
centralized updates and yeah it's
probably something that I should put on
the slide deck but it's certainly
something that's like in the future
or so the question is looking at
projects like lady open wrt whether
there's intention to do lessons learn
from most sort of projects possibly on
some some of this is still research some
of this is this is the way we're doing
it in fedora there's certainly different
approaches that we can look at there are
I mean projects like open wrt have been
sometimes effective at dealing with
things like security updates and
sometimes not so effective due to
political and social issues within the
project like they're quite often a long
way between releases so there's
absolutely things to learn and there's
absolutely ways we can change things to
make it better and the intention sort of
there is to get something working and
then evolve as we go
[Music]
that's part of the functionality enough
time to do that but the update is like a
delta between the two and you yeah and I
mean that's not that's not up here
specific there are projects that are
using it so like endless mobile is using
it on a Debian based distribution for
their OS as well
the question is could you use OpenShift
to manage that some of that stuff
potentially
I mean OpenShift is based on kubernetes
and kubernetes is sort of like cluster
technology so you could probably use
applications running on an open shift
platform as a management thing but open
shift itself I'm not sure would be at
least out of the box as it stands now
necessarily useful but certainly like
for IOT back-end platforms openshift is
like the perfect candidate for running
those side of things but not on not so
much on the actual device any more
questions
excellent I'll let you all go and get
beer