I just want to introduce samba to
[Applause]
[Music]
that's why I had to find a solution it's
a decentralized solution or it was a
decentralized solution or federated
solution which has a central fallback to
you could use multiple identities that
means you could have some different
identities stored in the system and you
could log into websites using those
different identities as identities we
used email address
simples email the persona service
verified that the email belongs to you
and then it sends this email as
identification to the protocol refused
was easy to implement for website
providers and it was permission less so
websites implementing it did not need to
actually ask for permission to use it in
the slides off the slides in the
beginning it's on slide start Cairo with
a K dot 80 just the first entry there
for stem 2017 so you can actually find
that and click all the links afterwards
as well so persona the scale you weighed
small website if it needs some
administration was some dynamic
component dependent on users which I I
was writing a content management system
or I'm operating a content management
system and some other websites that have
state that needs to be edited and so you
need to login for that what do you need
as a small website needs to be easy to
implement as a website operator you need
to have to trust the identification that
you get from those logins you want to
avoid dealing with storing passwords
because everything can go on there my
old system storage passwords basically
as plain text and sent them as plain
text via email to users so basically
mistakes you should never do you really
don't want to care about how to sort
passwords yourself you want to have some
solution that's proven to to work and
that's upgradable by the way if newer
standards come out for that you don't
want to be locked in that's so if one
authentication or identification
provider goes away you want to be able
to still communicate with your users and
switch to something else the good thing
with persona was as it used email for
for identification to the websites you
still had this email that you can use to
communicate to users and a lot of other
blogging systems use emails as well so
you can actually identify the same user
by coming to you with the same email
even through a different login system
and I do you want privacy ideally you
don't want to to tell some third party
who is logging into your web sites when
because they're then they can watch
basically everything that's happening on
your website so so what what solutions
do we have I started to think what can I
do for my websites basically to two
things I can do everything locally
inside my website system or I can have
it done externally locally it sounds
easy to implement but as I said you want
to avoid storing passwords you you need
to find out how to communicate some
verification codes to users and things
like that it sounds easy to just have a
password and username that the devil
comes in the details
must be trusted as a website operator
you probably have to trust yourself
anyhow it needs to secure passwords you
need to care about that yourself write
code for that yourself and that's
error-prone and potentially hyperbole if
you don't care what you're doing what
you're doing the extremely providers
have the potential for walking as I said
you may need to use that provider for
the rest of the life of your website if
you don't don't have anything cater of
your users that you can use to
communicate directly with them there's
potential policy issues as I said here
you're telling these external providers
when people are logging in and the
implementation difficulties is different
depending on what you use it could be
very easy if they provide even some code
it could be very difficult if the if the
API to use it it's very difficult so
which external providers do we have
local is pretty easy I have to write the
code myself weak stone once do we have a
person that has gone away
Firefox account sounds nice that is not
usable for anyone outside of Mozilla so
it falls out of that after players you
probably know from some websites like
Facebook you see a collection of icons
out there a lot of people call that the
nascar login because it looks like the
nascar logo you see that solution
to providers open ID connect providers
open ID connect these are standard for
for logins that spaced on earth 2 which
is an authentication protocol that's
pretty common now and this like a wealth
bond like a number of smaller ones that
didn't take off that much but mainly you
nowadays you see us too and and open ID
connect and of course there's the
potential of intermediates and just
mentioning those because Mozilla is
using of Syria for some things it's
that's an intermediate it provides you
in the code for for handling the login
from your sites to them and then they
are talking to actually to the actual
authentication providers and you can
pretty easily configure that runs on
proprietary Sorell Affairs so it's not
really the thing I want to to advertise
on an open source conference but it's
it's something you can use website you
may be able to use something different
and I didn't want to use a proprietary
middleman external system that does not
exist yet but is in the works so it's a
future alternative it may deactivates
the other district of persona it uses
email authentication it's decentralized
that's not centralized uses password
bless you know login it's speaking open
maybe connect to both the client side
and the what they call brokers the
identity providers on the different
domains out there and because the
spiritual successor to Mozilla persona
there's a number
people who actually worked on persona
working on party a as well and in
development you can find more
information at party that gets up the
dial we will be an interesting
alternative once they are in the stable
note that they we're not there yet and I
needed something for my websites right
now so I figured in the website is maybe
not the best solution I don't trust
those external providers too much and I
want privacy from them so what can I do
there well I may be able to just
implement the same thing is for an
external provider on my website and then
basically with the same protocols talk
to something that I still host locally
but at least I have everything
encapsulated there and I call that local
external or self hosted external stack
it all runs on my machines the password
security I still need to care about is
at least isolated from the website cold
and it's cold it's hopefully reusable
and that other people can look look into
if it's an open source thing and we can
guarantee that it's a good solution
management of multiple identities is
possible if if a privacy interests are
new issues because I don't leave privacy
for myself I already know who locks into
my websites so I'm not telling that to
anyone else and I hopefully as I said
before I can trust myself and when I'm
using a standard API like f2 or Open ID
Connect there's a good possibility if I
find out that's not the solution I
wanted
I can switch it out to some other
solution that uses the same protocols
because I already have to call for that
in the in the website the downside is I
still need to secure the whole system
and the passwords properly documentation
how you should do that I can probably
look into that so I I know PHP I thought
well that is paris' for os/2 let's let's
do something with this and I created the
PHP off server it's using us gos to API
viable a be a while or to server PHP it
can be extended to open a B connect I
didn't do that yet the password storage
right now happens with the PHP standard
password hash function which uses bcrypt
which is good enough if used within the
federation's but better algorithms out
there there's a bug report out there on
the PHP pack bug tracker to actually use
something better I try to use a script
but now if there's even better algorithm
that that they propose to use the good
thing is once we have a better algorithm
in PHP the code is in there to
automatically update the security for
everyone on blogging because unlike
the password you can rien Kripa the
better function I'm also using unions
there that's stored on disk and the
extends the password of the user so if
someone gets the database they can not
do put voice hacking off of those
passwords easily enough because the
nonce on this is needed as well it's
relatively easy to install system as the
codes with Apache MySQL PHP up to PHP
seven which I'm losing using on my local
systems when testing it my service law
runs it on PHP five there it breaks both
I'm using for the database extraction
not all of doctoring but just a database
extraction layer so it should be pretty
easily extendable to other databases the
PHP utility classes are something I did
myself and putting kids have some time
ago that I'm just using that for email
and document abstractions because I'm
HTML document I'm putting out there as a
Dom document and only serializing it
then which makes it much easier to not
forget and text and stuff like that it's
capable to branch the installation for
the operator
- branded like like you see in the
picture up there with with my logo but
it comes with a neutral one by default
and my information at author care
ability scores pretty well in the
security tests I could run on most of
the Observatory on SSL labs some of that
is because of the code some of that is
because of the PHP configuration the
Apache configuration which I have
examples in the in the repository for so
you can just copy from that if you want
to use it so current status
oh that runs off the screen because I
thought it would be three per for and
it's it's not only support the up in
this variation code flow of of two right
now which means the website sends a
request for for authentication then you
log in there and for for no me login it
implicitly the hence it if your login
since back reply with a nexus codes to
the website on the server side you you
request the token for for that access
code and with that token you can then do
something most importantly get the email
of the user so you have a user and
identification interest for which is a
bit less secure doesn't have to this
flow over the server in there but that
makes it less secure because it only
works between browser and in the
authentication server that is not
supported yet but the library can do it
so it should be easy to add the Open ID
Connect staff is also supported by the
library so it's just a question of
adding it apache mysql or actually maria
vp for now it should be easy to extend
that for other web servers and databases
as long as they're supported by the
doctoring abstraction layer and you can
run PHP on them those remain technical
communication in the main repiy it
supports us english and german as
defined by your browser because that's
the two languages i know of or if there
how to to write in testing is is right
now very rudimentary it's just I'm
trying it with my own document
management system and I'm trying it with
a secondary system I'm I'm running that
has an independent implementation I want
to give special thanks to Crystal Shana
who did review for security issues and
he didn't find at any real security
issues he had a few minor comments that
few of them still need to address but
most of them was nothing special and the
thing that's cut off here it's probably
the most important thing of this whole
slide it's open source it's available
since today since a few hours ago at
speeds up that kind of keio 8000 there
it's under Mozilla Public License two I
care to put a license on my projects
unlike many others on github and yeah
it's it's out there right now if if you
want to use something like that it's an
open source project so it is helped by
the way this right there is the
unbounded version you see by default
it's the log in piece of it the my logo
is not in there it's somewhere in the
repository because I started it without
being able to scan it that needs help
there is implementation of especially
Open ID Connect maybe the time
credential flow as well a test suite and
infrastructure to run the tests more
complete documentation no UI languages
would be nice but there's other three
are probably more important than that
but there's still a good thing it's
standard
files so it's easy easy to do the
translations more installations out
there that actually try it and see how
things are liking and of course any of
your ideas and pull requests for it
would be very very appreciated that's it
I think we should have time for some
questions
the table is here again and if you want
to contact me that's my email address
and my muscle in CLL that actually has
the few social networks I'm on it has
the links for that and with that are
there any questions
[Music]
the question was to provide you with
that yes this this is an implementation
of in the earth to provide some
incomplete because it doesn't have the
client credentials flow it only has the
authorization code flow but yes it is
one you say the hello Cheers
[Music]
okay so it's something that provides
this this role
you can provide it it's a provider of
all those two providers for four
websites I didn't do anything like that
right now the thought behind this is for
people to set up their own tea so I
don't want my provider to be one that's
a lot of other people are using
I prefer other people actually using the
same module inventing their own for for
their purposes and not telling anyone
else who's logging in on their website
that's using some common code that can
be made secure enough so the question is
if there's any change for Mozilla to use
port a I'm not sure you will need to ask
those people at my server who are
implementing sites that are using logins
likes the idea of 48 or a lot of people
that doesn't have one opinion usually
it's a lot of people I think a lot of
people like the idea but we will see
those when it matures more right now
it's it's in a very early testing mode
but I like the idea as well of course
any other questions
oh sure one of the advantages of persona
was that you could log in once and then
be logged into a number of websites
federated login right it's single
sign-on do you think that that goal
today is incompatible with the other
requirement that you had for not telling
some big company whenever you log in
somewhere do you think at the moment you
can't have both of those things
so the question is persona
basically acted as a single sign-on
solution you could log in to persona
once and then I looked into a number of
other websites and if I think that
approach does not work right now without
telling with that concern of privacy
against those big companies I think with
the current protocols it doesn't work
because you're telling them the earth to
protocol and open IP connect protocol
require you to send a request on every
login so you basically have this central
as knowledge of where you log in anytime
there's a potential that we find a
protocol where that that's not the case
with the current protocols we're not
there and so if you don't want that you
probably need to look at something on
your own site unfortunately I already
have some of some ideas or the protocol
that that persona used had some some
chance to not tell someone every time
you log in but unfortunately it didn't
get enough usage thank you time for
questions please give a big round of
thank you
you