so for next speaker is right hard words
I want to say welcome to all of you and
my short lecture I will show the basics
of WPI a which spells to world privacy
and identity Association okay so my name
is volatile
he taught me given into the introduce my
name is hi not moods I worked in the IT
since 1985 and I've been selected as
president of WPI a at the first general
meeting I want to give a short overview
what we need a legal framework to
operate the trusted service provider
successfully and I will show you the
reasons why we do it and I will show you
the way we will do it when we started
and you know this it's some kind of good
practice you start with a kind of
[Music]
brainstorming
and what you do is just number all the
issues you have to deal with and I give
just a few examples what we have to
consider for example finance finance
will include the management of
membership fees donations payments and
of course tax because the takes office
always one gets its part of your money
and you have to organize it very well
you can organize it if you have not a
community but an association the
association is represented by a
management power and this management
board acts on behalf of the association
the same thing is in regards to contract
management's if you see what you have to
do well here how many contracts you have
to sign then you see you need a data
center to operate something you need
contracts to manage the relations
between your trusted service provider
and your customers and you need
contracts for example for insurances
next item is Human Resources without a
personal staff who is doing the things
there is no progress so you have to
organize it in a way that it will manage
or match your targets though to
infrastructure you know the tasks you
have you will run a website for example
you will run some software so that you
can communicate in the teams you will do
and write software and manage it and so
on see the item risk management risk
management is a hottub to do because
you have to write down any possibility
which may crash you down and the next is
you must write it's really a clear
formula clear way to see and then to
have an overview about this and then
when you see risks which may happen then
go and try to minimize it at least you
need a documentation of all of our
business processes and all actions in
the meanings of keeping an archive and
keeping it up to date and these issues
are not all there are many many more
issues you have to consider and please
keep this in mind as a trusted service
provider you are working in a market the
market of PKI is complex and the AI
environment is a little bit more complex
so if you see the PKI description which
is made by internet and during on task
force called RFC 5280 there are laid out
and written in details the requirements
how PKI will work
the browsers like for example Mozilla
Microsoft edge maybe Google Chrome or
whatsoever will follow this requirement
is oft 5280 and sometimes it happens and
that is what we would see that they have
different views about the same thing
which happens and that we'll need for
example to the fact that their trust
rows are filled with the names of CA
companies but they are not identical
everyone who wants to surf the Internet
in the way of let's fake trust and build
up a trust so has its old view whom he
will trust in 2005 the CA the part of
the CL market and the B which stands for
the browsers organized a forum the forum
is nothing else as a discussion forum
and what they try is to unify the views
and the interpretations of RFC 5280 this
part has well-known to many many people
in the community but there is a new
player coming which is not yet very
recognized in the community and this new
player is that project in the a you
called a EDA's and AE das has a target
which has described test as the internal
market in the you will be unified and
this will be done latest in 2020 so
there are only a few years left what
they do in regards to certificate
authorities is that they created a new
level of trusted
which they call cube TSP Accu TSP is not
only a trusted service provider it's a
qualified trusted service provider and
the hope is that they can man make much
more money than before you may see this
attempt of installation qts piece like
for example building a digital ball
around the Schengen space so that they
keep Europe as a single market and
others say and will tell you it will
help the world to communicate better and
more safe and so on that's the one side
of the world of PK ice the other side is
that the same document the RFC 5280
distinguishes between Internet and
internal internal means that you use the
paper I system in your own networks and
these networks have no connection to the
internet so the roots are not strong you
the roots may be not abate and the
reason why you do it is very simple you
can keep your internal network in turn
this is used by almost always all
national governments in the world the
biggest internal peiki is run in the US
administration in Europe it's run by the
government of the German Republic and
you will see the internals if you visit
the website of BSI where you can see the
complete structure of the internal PPI
of the German administration
there is another player in the market
that is Taylor trust Taylor trust is
some nonprofit association and the
members are big business when they
started the members who are for example
the company's immense telecom and so on
and what they do is they run a project
called EBC a that's European rich CA
this project is run to make the internal
paper is to the partners and
participates of this model known and
integrate it into their browsers they
run an LDAP server and if you know the
exact email address of one of the
employees you can write and use an S
mime email signed and encrypted and you
do not need to come in touch before you
just ask that an observer and that will
serve you the appropriate certificate so
the question is what parts will WPI a
serve and the answer is simple both
sides we want to operate in the market
as the trusted service provider and will
deploy certificates for free and our
software is open to all will be under an
open license for your private
convenience you may download it and use
it
well the solution in the this area must
be based on trust
privacy is a right and privacy and
that's written by v1 privacy is not a
commodity that can be sold its utility
and various cultural and social settings
can defer but privacy is a human right
and that was written in the UN world
public sector report in the year 20 and
3 last week we saw in Brussels
an event from data protection officers
and security interests and so on
and this guy and mr. Carbone lugar wrote
a tweet I catch that by some coincidence
and what he wrote is the you cannot
monetize fundamental rights to make it
subject to commercial transaction and
there are words written in the year 2017
fourteen years ago the UN world public
sector report said the difficult is that
a protection of privacy is not higher on
the global or even national political
agendas yet and that yet is still hope
so as I said the solution must be based
on trust next item is a very important
item is identity and the Australian
atmosphere Austrian administration
brought a strategy paper and they said
the citizens must have confidence that
their data will be received by the
addresses fast and reliably an open and
free internet the protection of personal
data as well as the integrity of
interconnected networks are the basis
for global prosperity security and the
promotion of human rights so what we can
see as human rights is always mentioned
and human rights can not be divided they
cannot be sold or made subject to a
market human rights should be accepted
to its full extent
if you need privacy if you accept
identity confidentiality and ignore the
rest then you don't accept human rights
because it's undividable and
cherry-picking not allowed see if you
see the environment and remember my
words then the next is very simple how
to manage this solution you all know and
we are in Brussels the center of former
Galia an old make seem called Caesar
schmuck symbols
Davida at Emperor and if you work as
project manager or manager of a company
or something you know that principle
divide and conquer what we have to obey
is we have to organize users and
customers they will have roles as
members as fellows as customers maybe as
employees on the other side we want to
operate a service which delivers or
deploys certificates and this will be
done for free and this CR will take part
in the market and based on all is our
association which is the charitable
nonprofit association and our members we
are looking for now is make propaganda
tell the world what we are doing tell it
your people tell your neighbor and
getting friends
the solution more detail is shown on
this page so what private identity and
Association is a charitable nonprofit
Association will be owner of brands
logos software and companies is open for
all human entities and by this required
the acceptance of the Universal
Declaration of Human Rights to its full
extent members will pay a membership fee
because you need some money to make
propaganda pay Flyers and burned and
there are many costs and enviar every
individual may get certificates for free
solution part 2 is to set up an
operating center set up and create a
certificate authority that's an
incorporated company of our association
will be owner of brands and logos
operating all tasks which data center
must provide and running on behalf of
WPI a only solution part 3 is a very
very old form of organization it's a
cooperative this cooperative is open for
associations and entities and our
requirement is the acceptance of the
Universal Declaration of Human Rights as
before members will pay a yearly
membership fee and that fee is used to
pay all costs of the operating CA
the important thing that is in this is
that you always remember we do not pay
certificates we pay and we organize an
environment to get the costs and that's
all we do the rest depends on the
participants so the nexus some
milestones as I said today we are
looking for new members I welcome every
one of you to share and join our
association the incorporation of the CR
is in phase let's call this in it the
same as in the incorporation of the
co-operative when we will have our
software tested and the CAS set up we
will go life and going life as meaning
that we will start without it from the
very first day we will never deploy to
the public certificates for the purpose
of testing or trying something like this
no we are finished with this book and
we'll start with an audit the audit will
need about one year and after we passed
it successfully and with flying colors
then we apply for membership and this
year Bay for this membership is required
to get the inclusion status of all
browsers and they cannot deny it if you
are in the same organization as they are
now so I think I have to say thanks
you've been grateful audience and I
would say visit our website and join the
world privacy and identity association
today if possible thank you
[Applause]
hi I just have a few points of sort of
clarification and a question so it is
not true that if you join the see a
browser forum all of the browser members
have to let you into their root stores
that there's not true but it is also not
required to be a member in order to
apply for root store admission so you
can apply whenever you like and you can
become a member of this year browser
forum at a later point the membership
requirements for the forum are that you
are in at least one root store so in
fact it's the other way around you have
to get into root store before you can
become a full member the question how
would you compare two questions then how
do you compare your service with
existing things like let's encrypt and
see a cert and secondly how do you go in
to solve the problem of ubiquity that is
to say making sure that everyone trusts
your certificates as quickly as possible
in order that anyone would want to use
them easily answered let's encrypt just
not they do not a reliable work the
certificates are generated by a machine
used for another machine and what they
are doing is not accountable in the
meanings of legal fluids may read and I
give you the advice to do so the UN the
Committee for international trade laws
has published two big documents and both
about the commercial market and the use
of digital certificates and they say
that the certificates generated from a
machine to use to secure the
communication between two machines are
not reliable so it's out of scope
want to have a reliable certificate the
one part must be a human a human on the
side of the CA and a human on the side
of the the the interest party which
wants to see us or Robyn's they have a
certificate that's about let's encrypt
and the other one my question to you is
are you a member of mozzarella or
Firefox or something like yeah yes so
will I take your words and I promise you
that I will when we start with the audit
I will give you a contract that we will
and to be integrated in mozzarellas
Firefox and then we will talk about it
okay and then we will see and check who
does the right things so afraid that
that's all the time we have for
questions okay thank you very much right
hard nuts yes
[Applause]
[Music]