good evening everyone can you hear me
it's okay can you hear me
I appreciate that indeed that you stay
tuned to the light presentation and
higher do realize that I'm the last
person standing between you and
reception I guess beer so now try to
keep it short I work at people time is
near there there were a focus on big
data distributed systems I'm privileged
to spend enough time on working on open
source project I am a geometer and peace
PMC member for a particular project
today I'm going to talk about two
interesting trends one is has happened
in the last decade the last 10 years
this is the no Seco in big data the
other one is the implementation of sicko
interfaces for various notes no secure
data systems which seem to be happening
it's a big team in the last year in year
and a half and this is a quote I found
from Martin for work from 2012 where he
predicts that if it's ever if ever
sequel gets implemented on top of
establishing no sequel this at least
would generate plenty of arguments and I
believe this talk is one of those going
to be one of those arguments so a little
bit of context the big data and no
secure and non-secure big bank we've
been so this is a landscape of Big Data
technologies for the last year you see
actually from according to some sources
we have over 350 commercially supported
mochiko and big data systems out there
so what actually explains this explosion
considering that for decades we've been
happy or some people have been happy
with relational databases it's difficult
to judge by it by by the name of those
projects no sequel and actually the
strange no sequel big data they really
don't write any prescriptive definitions
but if you think of them more like a
movement and try to understand what are
the driving forces behind them
I think this helps to position them and
to understand why they're so vibrant and
what makes them makes them think tick on
the first place I think there's some
concession about this one of the main
driving forces behind those technologies
and the boom of those technologies is
the boom of Internet itself the fact
that explosion of what mobile
technologies Internet of Things
practically any device now even smaller
one is the source of information and
generate information and the this in
turn generates a cause three main
challenges this is how to handle the
volume of data the velocity of data and
the variety of all these data sources so
and Internet is the cause for these
technologies or to fulfill the demand
for those challenges the other hand it
is actually the solution as well in
order to handle to scale to provide
technologies that can handle and address
those challenges you are going to use
again distributed systems and in turn
using distributed system for dos for
resolving those challenges means that
some of the already presumed
technologies and a guarantee is that
relational databases provide like asset
or - two-phase commit would be
challenged and has to be addressed in
different way it's known for example
that the two-phase commit would Hank in
- in certain cases in failure
distributed system so all new class of
approaches not for example the
consistency and availability in case of
partitioning of distributed system this
is the cap or theorem is are meant to do
and this is part of this tributed system
and many of the technologies that that
that implements this Paxos on the other
hand and as I mentioned the two-phase
commit is not really reliable approach -
to ensure consistency within the
distributed environment so a class of
consist consensus based quorum based
systems like taxes heavy merchants and
many of the NAS ecosystems actually are
based on those type of technologies
another not that popular but I think
very important driving forces the
so-called
relational or object-relational
impedance mismatch
which a relational database I'm not sure
many of you maybe have done some
application development they know that
for some class of applications you just
need to persist your application state
which mark is it very often is a object
based state into relational database for
this you would need some sort of ORM
technologies which is unnecessary for
many use cases as I mentioned and this
gave birth to technologies like or
document based datastore this actually
is a huge group of technologies out
there
driven by by this mismatch furthermore
different type of stores and demands
like graph based databases or full-text
search where the traditional
representation of database models in
strict very often the raw base the
relational model is not very very
appropriate to to do it and there many
other factors but I think those three
kind of are powerful enough to to
explain why there is such a search of
technologies out there last one I want
to talk is the cloud computing race and
wife itself the possibilities to program
the infrastructure actually talk to make
this infrastructure to have
infrastructure on demand is a main
driver for eliminating the operational
complexity and the cost and there is
another side effect of this and this
market textural there is this sub sub
sub movement I would say which is shift
from integration to application type of
databases this is very popular into the
micro services type of data applications
so the idea is that if you have your
application instead of having a single
data store as the application state for
your distributed application you rather
have a dedicated application store for
each application and have a well defined
protocol application level means between
this application so the database is not
shared among them I think I hope those
those those forces explain the reason
why there is such a multitude of
technologies out there and I don't want
to justify this orto to dive further the
point is that there are out there there
lot and as I said over 450 commercially
supported one and one of the interesting
consequences of this is that almost any
organization
that would have a list here of those
technologies deployed in in their data
store data in the infrastructure so
interesting question race how they're
going to integrate those technologies
this multitude of database that would
usually don't have at least few data
storage technologies dedicated a
particularly good for particular type of
use cases and it was discussed today
I've observed I have observed so far too
many trains that trying to provide this
type of integration and by the way the
integration of technologies is very big
deal to do usually did standard ETL
technologies and systems are trying to
cope with this that's not I'm going to
talk today I'm really trying to talk
about how organization can provide a
single holistic view over the data that
is spread across different data stores
which might be useful for certain use
cases very often those are the
analytical or maybe some data science
type of use cases to train their data
set so two main trends are emerging that
are aiming to - in my opinion - to
converging to provide more unified view
on the data system and data processing
system one is more functional based its
unified programming model and you can
today it was mentioned there was a very
nice presentation comparing the
interfaces of spark and fling you have
noticed that they're very close and
actually they're not the only two that
are very similar
apex Apache currents cascading Apache
beam Deo actually inspired by a common
one paper bought from 2010 I think is
from Java Google paper as a type of API
and there is a trend now at least that
spark link and epics are implementing
and converging at certain level under
Apache beam in the project so this is
and this is example snippet of how
Apache beam looks as a notation the
second trend and that's what I'm going
to focus now today is apparently a lot
of the Gnostic vendors and big data
vendors are starting to implement sequel
interfaces for their data stores or some
sort sequel like interfaces for for
diabetics data stores and
some statistics from the last couple of
years or Hadoop so shows that apparently
majority of the tasks that are run on
Hadoop nowadays are either high base or
sequel some sort of seek on Hadoop type
of solutions out there also for spark
and there is a report from last year
states that the most used production
component is the spark sequel within
their system so there is this and I
stated Google F one paper actually has a
quote there that any data system has to
provide sequel interface and I found
this particularly important because a
lot of the Big Data technologies are now
in the open space are influencing from
the Google papers so there is this shift
and ideas and it's interesting movement
to and trend to observe apparently a lot
of company I think it it's worthy to to
try to reason what are the reason what
what is the main driver for this
movement for this converging it seems
like the desire there is a lot of tools
that know how toxic well out there with
within the organization so it seems like
Sukhoi pretty easy way to integrate with
with with those existing tools of this
more like legacy legacy reason secondary
and I think this is a more important one
is the relational model that stays under
usually sequel engines and this is the
the hot pits that we can talk about we
should talk about today and I think this
is important slide although it doesn't
seems very very bright I can argue that
practically any useful data system out
there in one another form provides
implements the set or back semantics so
operators like projection filtering if
the system is more advanced that some
sort of join or group by would be
present so in order to to provide some
usefulness for the users the system have
to implement explicitly or implicitly
dissipate those operators so having this
and acknowledging that this exists and
very often in order to implement a
pipeline or or query execution
statement you have to chain multiple
operators like this and when you start
to play with this concept you realize
it's practically this is the same
relational algebra concept that are very
common in the relational space and there
is a tools that are very good in
optimizing subtype of change and those
are the planners and
indeed the relational expression
optimizers are very desirable feature
for many of the technologies Big Data
technologies simply they're very
difficult to implement now and that's at
least that word very difficult to
implement until recently now there's at
least couple of open-source technologies
out there that provide some some some
some help and are useful to to consider
and try to use and leverage in order to
provide this type of relational
expressions relational cumulation within
the existing big data systems I'm
proposing here I mean this is again just
simple subset of it's possible way how
you can integrate how organization are
I'm dealing with a lot of customers out
there so I have some first-hand
experience with some big players in the
field and see and experience how they
preserve and Pacey them the usefulness
of the data how they're trying to
integrate that their data and it seems
like the most common approaches this one
so this any standard for the writer
database system approach so you pick one
database that allows you to implement
the connectors to external databases or
the external data systems no sequel and
then you can provide kind of single
review on your system just via external
tables which representation sorry which
representation of the external logical
data systems in this case I have
experienced with Patrick Hope which is
yet another to derive from the green
plan that we discussed today again which
was derived from Postgres it's MPP
shared nothing solution which has very
powered actually share very similar
optimizer or its orc optimizer inside
right what's more important provides a
pxf framework this is a Java extension
framework which allows you to actually
implement a plug-ins for external system
so this is I call it an 1/n model
because the organization would use a
single sequel usually post grad G DBC
connector or DB seat to talk with one
MPP database and where the extension
mechanism would be able to see some
portions of them and the Gnostic code
system itself outside
second approach is far more interesting
in my opinion because it provide more
autonomous autonomous e4 for them nós
ecosystem themselves is to implement a
Sequoia doctor for each system in
isolation and for this purpose there is
a frame or very powerful framework out
there called Apache calcite and as you
can see in this case each of the NOS
ecosystem would actually have its own
sequel representation interface its own
optimization the advantage of this is
that you might be able to tuned
optimizers 4cq optimizers and the
relational algebra expression optimizers
better to the particulars Pacific's of
the nas ecosystem and there is an
interesting gyre ticket the Jireh issued
that recently popped up which is
exploring the possibilities to bridge
those two approaches just one slide
about the first the federated database
approach how it looks like so on the
sequel standpoint you're creating a
table that looks like this standard type
the interesting bit is that here you're
providing location to your nas record
data system where you want to wrap and
you have to implement three classes
which is the fragmented accessor and
there is over the the purpose of the
experimenter is that if the dating the
Gnostic or data store allows you to
partition the data in streams that you
can process in parallel the row of the
fermentor is indeed to establish this
partition for each of the streams or
separate streams in parallel the
accessor actually breaks them into a
collection of rows key value rows and
for each of the this value rows there is
over the last component you have to
implement would convert it into a column
a column list which would match this
interfaces there is much more internals
you can pass analytics and stuff to to
configure the statistics in order to
optimize the help the optimizer to
adjust according this particular data
store and this is very powerful approach
if you for example already have Hadoop
and Hokie
like system in your infrastructure and
you can just implement this such type of
plugins and wrap and provide holistic
view on your back-end system
the second approach for direct one is to
implement a sequel interface or
you're an leverage tikka optimizer
around your nasi code database and for
this the Apache frame magic outside
framework provides you query parser this
is sequel query parts the validator
optimizer I think this is the most
important bit here as the bones you get
the G DBC driver which you can talk with
the system and one very important to
design decision about the calcite is to
stay out of the business of how data is
stored and processed which in turn makes
is very useful to implement and grab
almost any existing data store out there
I think this is by design and it's very
powerful decision and if you take a look
about the various technologies out there
that use in one another way Apache
calcite you would see that most of the
big play already using it inside what I
did I'm working on a patchy geode
adapter the Apache geo TC memory data
grid yet another key value store
distributed hash and I'm going to use in
some of the example just as a reference
to illustrate how it looks like so this
assuming that you decide to implement a
sequel adapter using a particle size
drone back-end data store no sequel data
store their cup of decision you have to
make and they're very important
regarding the from one side to how much
sequel completed you are going to expose
and compliant with the sequel standard
and other hand how much you're going to
to leverage the power of the nice
agnostic or not no sequel system you
have so the first thing is you have to
decide how we're going to convert your
data type from the existing nas
ecosystem let's say this is key value
store or it could be even like some sort
of graph representation into a tabular
format that is expect bike outside and
cow side has the standard metadata
expected is the catalog schema which is
collection of tables table which is
collection of rows and row is just a
list of columns represent to the
relational data type so this is
important decision because let's say
that you want to express as some sort of
a JSON or Java object which has
hierarchy and you have to flatter in
some tabular format you have to decide
whether you we are going to spend
computation and a lot of civilization
and to achieve this or you just can't
afford to implement only top-level
fields or some smartness in stuff so
it's up to you to decide what is the
it's a trade-off so how much you're
going to expose from your model as a as
an opposite of the performance that
you're going to gain or lose and the
second more important thing that this is
general principle for any data
distributed data system is move the
computation next to the data not other
way around particular that means that if
you in case of in the context of the
sequel query you would like to run the
executions of this query next to the
node to where data is stored rather than
actually moving the data to some central
node where this processing is happening
and then moving it back and forth in the
context of Apache prowl site you have
two approaches to to achieve this the
first one is simple I call it simple it
just allows you to to implement a very
simple simple inter type of interface
with ability to push down the predicates
predicates
operators relation imperative like
filters and projections that means that
if you have select some fields where
from some table where something it makes
any sense this fuse and there were
clouds at the conditions to be pushed
down to your not equal solution and you
pre-filter and reprocess and return back
only the amount of data that is
necessary for okay for for then for the
system to process I'm going to hurry up
here's this is an example how it looks
the simple scenario you're connecting to
an orifice visa what is JDBC adopt this
is the logical side JDBC protocol so
when you connect to JDBC by the particle
size gdb seed driver to your back-end
system you have to provide a model in
JSON format the only thing that model
contains is your entry point
implementation of the schema factory
with some appearance that are relevant
for your back-end systems the role of
this schema is usually one liner of
implementation is to create a schema
based on those operators that appearance
that you have provided the schema in
turn depends of the mappings that you
have decided to implement for your
back-end system Nestico system and the
relational staff would create a list of
tables and the important things is that
you have to implement a column types
in these tables then when a query comes
it would be passed to the scan parameter
so that from this book order usually
what means that it was going to collect
try to extract this data set from your
logical database and convert it in the
convert method convert it into type that
is compliant with the table definitions
that you hear is that in this simple
implementation you could get all date so
there is not any moving of the
computation code into the data
everything goes to the central processor
and get process they're led to version
that you can optimize this computation
it's called that instead of scannable
table you can experiment filter
scannable table projected future
scannable table which allows you to push
down the filters and projectors but
that's everything that you can do as an
optimization if you have a joint
operators or group by operators
everything would happen central place on
the client side and the second approach
that the calcite allow provides you with
is to implement your own relational
rules and in relation operators that
would allow you to improvise
implementation much closer to the to the
native noshiko system in this case this
is a apache geode and this is very fast
going so how it looks like gdb see this
is everything Hebrew is the standard
Apache calcite framework this is the
beads that you have to implement in
order to to provide the adapter and this
is code generated by the outside so
sequel query comes it is passed to the
parcel sequence converted into a
relational expression and 3 it goes
through the planner which performs some
optimizations actually while performing
these optimizations optimize tree is
passed to the innumerable component
which is responsible to convert this
logical plan into physical plan and this
is already the tricky part in this
process actually if you have implemented
your own rules and operators the
enumerable components would consult
those and would provide a wealth I word
implementation actually chooses the
expression tree this is concept from
League for link 4j I think this is
something that come from from from
Microsoft and this interpreter actually
generate Java code that's optimized for
this implement a
compiled and the JDBC query is
executed so that's the whole 400
complete line and I'm going to skip this
those are the internals of the if you're
going to implement your own rules and
operators in the outside you would have
to get acquainted with this and this is
the generic pattern if you see any of
the implementations of the calcite
adapter out there more or less
implemented for these these steps here
and just I would finish with the example
let's say that you have this relation of
expressions this is the relation of
operators that you would see now we have
a join of two tables filter and project
two of the fields so the optimizer throw
would be to convert and to push some of
the operators closer to the date so you
see the project's so to reduce the
amount of data that moves a port so this
is usually the logical part of the
parcel of the optimizer and this is the
real example with the Apache geode
adapter that I work on if you have this
query this is the logical plan you see
that you have no any optimization the
scan on the tables
then join perform then filter on the
this see one of the field and projection
extract two of the fields if you use the
simple scannable approach which doesn't
implement any rules you would have some
advantage so that the planner would
already reorder the sword or this this
operator in a way that would mean they'd
be executed much more efficiently but
still most of the computation would
happen on the client side where the did
the visual dock the sequel part is
performed if you move one step and you
implement your own rules and have
something that's much more tailored to
your nest nautical data system in this
case I have implemented geo project
filter but there's also group by you see
that actually it uses those operators
and it leverages practically a lot of
dos operators now executed on the nos
ecosystem itself still you see that
joint is not implemented there I'm
working on this that means that now this
query practice could be converted into
two sub queries run on the nas ecosystem
and the result would be returned and be
performed on the client side but this is
something that you can
progress on typical gdb see how we are
going to use this boom stand Java
standpoint and I'm frightened over time
so I'm sorry for this try to to run for
it
[Applause]