yeah
that's a lot for showing up sorry I'm I
have a slight cold so I'm highly doped
but yeah please bear with me I totally
want to give this talk and I'm really
happy that so many of you are coming for
such a boring topic documentation is
boring right no okay okay
you're always already one step ahead of
me so quick survey how many of you are
involved in open source projects okay
how many of you are open so involved in
open source projects that don't have any
documentation how many of you are trying
to change that and how many of you have
actually written documentation before
well well
didn't expect that okay so this talk is
titled writing open source documentation
for open source project it's based on
our experiences at Sousa but we can
apply the lessons that we have learned
to as a project as well and I will tell
you how to do so first something about
me my name is Krista Beckett as you have
already heard I'm the Linux user since
1999 in 2005 I became a contributor to
various projects such as the Fedora
project where I've been very active if
people know me they probably know me
from fedora also I've been involved with
xfce in the LXDE and the One Laptop Per
child initiative in 2010 I was hired by
coop systems the nice guys downstairs
with the co-op Cooper server and yeah
early last year I joined Sousa as a
technical documentation writer and as
you can see here I'm not sure if you can
read it this is the invoice from the
first ever Linux distribution I bought
soozee Linux 6.1 student version 479
darks in 1999 one of the reasons why I
purchased Sousa Wars well everybody was
using it at the time if people were
using Linux they were using or in
Germany in particular they were using
Sousa and one of the reasons for that is
it was a German distribution and it was
always very strong when it comes to
documentation so documentation this big
handbook was a great benefit I still use
this even when I no longer used to
openSUSE I've been using other
distributions I've been using debian
fedora whatnot but still documentation
was the key so that's me
who are we that's the openSUSE
documentation team at the writer doc
Doc's conference in Prague in fall last
year I think there you can see me down
there yeah in the back you can see our
team eat markers fine are probably some
of him norman from linux magazine and
yeah that's not even all of us there's
more because we have been growing
rapidly
suza has been growing the documentation
team has been growing and also the
numbers of the number of products that
we are to document is also steadily
increasing so who are we so the next
question obviously is what do we want
and we want to document all the things
so much for the laughter that's that's
the only picture I suck at slides so the
rest of this presentation will be boring
yeah what are you what do you mean with
document all the things he's yeah you
probably cannot read it I can't read it
either it's too small here you have an
overview of the Sousa documentation
website as you can see it's quite a lot
if you go that's only by products if you
go further down into one of the products
you see different kinds of guides like
get it started or quick install guides
deployment guides user guides
administrator guides then certain topic
oriented guy
like tuning guides virtualization guides
and of course with every new release we
have release notes all of that sums up
to I think at the moment it's 14,000
pages if I'm not mistaken with Susan
Linux into our enterprise 12 so that's
quite a lot of documentation and the
question becomes how do we handle that
how do we write it and how do we handle
it so we are talking about the tool
chain Sousa has basically written a tool
chain of its own because we figured at
the time we started I mean that predates
me joining Sousa but at the time they
started they couldn't find any decent
tools if you go to if some of you are in
documentation and they go to special
documentation conference it's not like
right the docs which is focusing on free
software but to like take on the German
document foundation for technical
documentation you will see all of that
is proprietary and of course Sousa
didn't want to go that way so we did
everything on our own and we wrote a
fully compliant open-source tool chain
we start off with docbook xml for us
it's the language of our choice I know
there are others I know that that
actually we are like the dinosaur
everybody has moved on to something more
modern like like just markup or yeah
there's there's plenty of stuff but I'd
write the docs I figured that we are one
of the few to use doc book but on the
other hand I very much like the
semantics well there's there's a lot of
advantages too much to explain it now I
could go on but we really figured it was
the only language that catered all our
use cases whatever other language came
up there was always some feature missing
it's docbook as its xml it's as people
say right only language you can write it
but you cannot read it right the the
upside is many people are familiar with
HTML or xml in general and many of them
can you can learn it pretty quickly if
you just do a short if you want to
submit a short patch or something like
that you can gee if you see para parar
okay that's probably means paragraph i
should put my text into inside a
paragraph and you're done so that's
pretty pretty trivial and you can see
all about doc doc doc dr. dark next when
you have the language you need an editor
you know probably know this from
classical programmer paintings on tumblr
that is the everlasting battle of MX
versus vim so yes you can use any editor
you want I'm favoring them most of the
others in the team are using Emacs their
proprietary editors there are you can
use G edit J edit whatever atomic no it
Adam yeah Adam so many of them once
you've created your quote in or your doc
book files in the editor you need to
somehow publish it and this is where our
tool chain kicks in we wrote a tool that
is called DAPs the dock boat dock book
authoring and publishing suit this is on
github it's open source you can use it
so some people say well what is that
it's basically a wrapper around make and
I hear some of you complaining oh are
you really talking about new make I hate
new make they're actually new makers the
I mean it's the dependency-based build
tool and that's exactly what you need if
you want to generate output files when
people say they don't like make it turns
out they most of the time is they are
using they're talking about how to make
so they are in fact referring to the
outer tools which I don't like either
but anyway can you make is the tool of
our choice it's running in the
background and you have one front end
which you can use to do all kinds of
commands the simplest thing is depths
validate you want to know if your output
is valid if you want to generate a PDF
file you just type the app's PDF you can
see that make is running in the back
because the that's actually like the
targets for mayic PDF HTML then you can
also pass options like grayscale PDF or
HTML single otherwise you get a chunk of
files we have lots of formats you can
generate man pages plain text files
plain text files are not that easy we
are using we we 3m the browser when it
comes to tables you want to have a clear
output so that's why we first render it
into HTML then use the browser to
display it and save it to a text file
you can do EEP up with Calibra and from
that you can also generate mobi files
for your Kindle and you can generate the
web help that's a special format of HTML
it comes with a with a table of contents
at the side and with a search bar that
is using some sava script so if you are
using for some standalone for your
product and your you only want this one
single help piece on the internet you
probably go for web help but you cannot
only generate output formats you can
also do lots of interesting stuff with
it ok here I need to explain something
there's a call the - D parameter refers
to the configuration file every document
has a configuration file where you
specify the document route the starting
point
every XML element has an XML ID so you
start a say from here on I started so
you give it the configuration file and
then you can say
list files I'm looking for the in I have
a ton of files in my repository and I'm
looking for the file that contains the
route ID art for articled apps quick and
I can get that without I mean I could
get vectors with grep probably but that
would also list a lot of false positives
so we have a command for that or you can
give say generate me a list of all
images with the modification date and
also show these images in a viewer so
it's bright quite a comprehensive tool
then we have some Sousa specific
commands that's not proper
so the translation we do we are it's
written in English even though most of
our team is German which sometimes you
can really see it was written by Germans
because Germans have a special way of
writing or speaking English especially
when it comes to the to the words like
have to mass need their use differently
in German and yeah so we write in
English and it's then generally
translated by translation agency by an
external a translation agency that's
focused on technical documentation in
order to have them translate our
software we give them basically a big
table all in a clearly defined format
with all the images and so on so that's
generated with lock drop and after the
translated documents come back we can do
unpack lock drop or we can just do the
online Target dubs online to generate
online doc to generate the online
documentation that you see on the pseudo
website so that's actually a quite
powerful tool we are still improving it
and we are meanwhile not the only ones
that are using it while back we received
our first patch by somebody from solando
you probably know them so they are
obviously using a two
next in the tool chain we have the style
sheets you have the XML and you need a
style sheet to generate different output
formats for example we have standalone
books or bigger like the manuals to the
guides we have single articles which are
just a few pages we have just just the
HTML and we have different I mean it's
the difference if you will have a PDF or
if you have a website for example on the
in the PDF file you want URLs in links
to be written out because on paper you
cannot click I mean you need to have
them written out so this is stand with
the XSLT stylesheets yeah the next we
have a style guide that reminds us how
to phrase it's not only about phrasing
it's well how to spell certain terms
recurring terms what tone to use how do
you address the reader what's the target
audience and all of that so you want to
have a consistent voice throughout all
your document we want to have consistent
namings
consistent use of terms and all that's
and also the structure and markup needs
to be consistently all that's in our
style guide we then have the style
checker which is a tool that you can
manually run on the on an XML file it
will output a HTML file which you can
then view in the browser and if you view
it in the browser
you get this nice these are actually
little plus signs where you can just
fold the the paragraphs and then you get
a list of well notes and warnings of
things you should probably fix
so much for this style checker we have
yet more tools all of them are on github
in the openSUSE organization that's and
is something that we just finished
recently or it's well it's not finished
but we brought it into production this
week it's continuous integration with
docker
we have dbx included for well in any of
you know stock book you can have
includes but you have the problem that
if you have XML IDs they need to be
unique and if you use and include
various time and doctor documentary the
IDS are no longer unique that's
something that we solved with dbx
included we have the dock manager that
manages meet our tags for example is
this document going to be translated or
not that's something or what path is
once it's published on the website
what's the URL these are custom tags
that we added and they are managed
through the dock manager we have a doc
stats tool Kiko doc is our doc books
subset we don't use the full set of doc
book because it's just way too big we
want to actually limit the documentation
writer to a certain subset of elements
that they can use and also that that
allows you to enforce guidelines like
you must not use nested lists with X
level of nesting or you must not use
this element inside the other element
and all that's in the Kiko doc of course
you need an editor that can read the
schema files and that I mean that not
only just syntax like syntax
highlighting or autocomplete but that
also like the the structure of the
semantics is interesting and also xml
diff ng next angie is next generation
there was already in xml diff out there
if you compare xml files
the classical way as you do with get for
example I mean even though we try to
have very strict with with the
dimensioned ups out all format that
earlier so we have common formatting
like like indentions and and no white
spaces at the end of the line and all
that even though sometimes patches look
messy and that's why you can use docked
up the XML DIF ng to really compare the
content of the file it's not the XML
syntax okay so much for the tool chain
you can ask questions later now I'm
going to talk about the process as I say
it's all open
everything is on github here you see the
docs lis repository so that's the it's
no longer the open through the
organization it's the souza organization
on github you have Doc's Lee and other
repositories all prefixed with Doc
that's us Lee is su the Linux Enterprise
Server and related products here you can
see the DC files for the admin guide or
for the everything guide and so on yeah
it's on github you can submit pull
requests you can you can take it as you
need it and from the slave documentation
we also built the openSUSE documentation
it's basically the same thing except
that phrases like SUSE Linux Enterprise
are replaced with oh the time is
actually getting longer oh I was
hurrying up and and so now I have 30
minutes left okay I slowed down a bit
Thanks yeah it's on github you can use
it you can fork it you can do whatever
you want with it you can even some
people even we were surprised a while
ago when we saw our documentation on
Amazon somebody is obviously generating
books from it printing it and selling it
we have no idea who it is we have
nothing to do with it but it's our
documentation it's
it's really ours we verified it so you
can do that it's open it's all GFDL
licensed use it as you like so when we
are talking about git I need to explain
the branching model a bit maybe some of
you have read this article the
successful get branching model by
Vincent Driessen well the schema it's
not the diagram it's not necessarily the
most it looks a bit messy but it's be
compared it's because it's so small so
basically we are using the developed
branch for development the master branch
is the blue one over here it's only used
for releases there you have the text for
every release and then we have different
branches for features bug fixes and
maintenance and there also they all
follow a consistent naming like feature
slash fade one two three four fate is
the feature and enhancement tracker that
Sousa is using it's also open source you
can find it as open fate it's also used
in openSUSE for suggesting new features
and discussing feature implementation or
bug fix BSC is back till Azusa comm and
then the back number so we are trying to
have a very consistent branch naming
people work on their own branches and
when they are done with it they submit
merge request through github and we are
using which recently started using the
new review feature from github maybe I
can show it later if people don't know
it yet that's actually something very
nice yeah and we are using this tool
called git flow well oh there's a typo
it's it's not F but it's V get flow AVH
that's a fork from the original git flow
too so git flow is an extension
if you have a good repository you type
get flow in it in it once add some
values to the configuration file that
you can for example the naming of these
branches the prefix feature back fix
maintenance yeah it's a helper to
implement this branching model and you
can modify the configuration as you like
but it makes sure that you have
consistent naming when you want to open
a new feature so you start working on
something you type good flow feature BSC
one two three four
start when you're done you would use git
flow feature finish but we no longer
uses this but use github reviews merges
instead yeah and github things get
reviewed thing and then we we try to
squash squash all the commits into one
so that and they have a meaningful
commit message that you can later
cherry-pick the whole feature of the
whole bug fix without having to
cherry-pick twenty individual fixes but
one one commit only yeah so much for the
branching mode of model now the bigger
picture so we have three main sources
for input either through fate which I
already mentioned through Bugzilla
partners or employees file box because
they found found it back in the
documentation or through a system that
is called doc comments I'll get to that
later after that we do evaluation and
planning to be honest that's why I don't
write it out there we are using Trello
for the organization a lot of you are
probably using it personally I don't
like it I don't like it because it's not
open source obviously we are or I'm
trying to push people to use fabricator
instead or something else but yeah
there's plenty of tools I mean you can
use when it comes to tracking there's
there's
many open-source tools out there but
nowadays I mean I'm old-school I use
Bugzilla or something like that or it in
fedora we use spatula a lot but nowadays
people want to have these work BOTS and
I want to have nice drag-and-drop in the
browser and whatnot so we use Trello
that's important when it comes to
planning we assign resources we have we
have this team of like 13 and we have
these tasks to do and we have an
estimation of how much every task is so
you pick your Trello cards this is what
I'm working on yeah that's really so the
resource planning is actually something
I forgot here we have Gantt charts as
well but I don't do them and I don't
know what the software is called for
doing it yeah after the planning comes
the research usually when there's
something new you need to research at
first you cannot just start documenting
it's right right I mean if I knew
everything I wouldn't be yeah I well
there's nobody who knows everything
actually we do have some documentation
writers who know more about certain
things they're focused on storage for
example and they know they have so much
they have accumulated so much knowledge
over the time but usually when there's
something new you first sit down with
the developer for like two hours and he
explains this new feature yeah then
comes the documentation this is where
all the the unicorns are born and and
everything yeah it's it's sometimes it's
hard work but it's just writing the easy
stuff and I think I've explained the
tool chain already so let's just say
it's magic
after that we send it to the developers
for feedback it's not yet published some
of the documents are then translated and
then they are published on the website
later
so one thing but that's actually we are
not done once it's published I mean it's
it's a constant iteration not only with
every new Sousa release but with every
release of the documentation sometimes
we do publish doc updates after the
release and also with every feedback we
get and the feedback is something that
many people forget when they write
documentation so we have two main
methods for feedback one is you can
report a box so as you can see these are
two screenshots from the Sousa
documentation from the online
documentation and there's actually a
report back at the bottom at the top for
every paragraph which automatically
opens bugzilla it fills in all the forms
which book is at which chapter which
everything and then people just need to
fill out their feedback or their
criticism or whatever they have in the
comment field of bugzilla the other
system I quickly briefly mentioned it
earlier it's called doc comments this is
the system that you see here once again
in the background we have the XSLT
stylesheets working the XSLT stylesheets
again doc book they allow you to for
example only we have the we have a
nightly version of the documentation
that's generated every night if you
click the back the feedback back
feedback button there you're directed to
bugzilla but on the documentation that
is that goes live you're directed to the
doc comment system which is yeah more
intuitive you just need to fill out your
email and your name and can provide
feedback so for technical people of
Zilla is probably the way to submit
feedback for less tech-savvy people it's
probably documents or other people just
send us emails - doc - team at Sousa
calm so that works as well but really
don't forget the feedback
and don't rely on people I mean make it
easy for people to give feedback don't
rely on if the hurdle is so hard
hi that you require them to submit pull
requests on github you probably won't
get a lot of feedback so there needs to
be a low entry barrier for feedback and
the more feedback you have the easier it
is the more feedback you get the more
feedback you get the better your
documentation gets and in the end
ideally all questions are answered and
yeah no more feedback needed which never
happens but all right but so far that
works out pretty well and I think
compared to other documentation teams we
are doing pretty fine we've seen that at
the right calm the conference last year
where people were telling us what they
are planning to do and we figured like
oh we are already doing that we are
already doing this so but of course we
do have some problems as well
well continuous integration that problem
was just solved last week but the
biggest problem that I see is we are
still doing the traditional waterfall
thing we have tried to become more agile
or more continuous but that doesn't
necessarily work there's always a very
short timeframe between when a feature
becomes ready for testing and for
documenting and between the release so
after the the beta from beta to release
of Susan or opens to the product we are
very very very busy and don't have time
for anything else
[Music]
sometimes we even have to wait all
features we can do that if the doc if
there's no documentation and the feature
is useless it probably gets delayed or
we need to provide a documentation
update later so again the workload
throughout the year is not constant
and yeah that's definitely something
that we need to address are weird but
it's always a question of I mean of
course you can do the whole agile thing
and document every single feature and
every line of code that the developer
does but then I'll get to that just a
moment but then yeah while you're in
this in this never-ending loop you
document something if you have a scrum
cycle a sprint and after two weeks you
figure out oh our developers went into
the wrong direction and let's do it from
scratch you have documented something
well that isn't there or you have
documented it for yeah no it doesn't
work out so you start all over again
for example screenshots our typical
example right before the release we have
to go through all these screenshots in
the in the documentation again
to make sure they are up to date even if
only a tiny thing in the in the
interface has changed you definitely
want the latest screenshot or the
checkbox or developers keep renaming
options or something like that and you
are referring to this option not only in
the screenshot but in the text so this
can become very cumbersome and if you do
this last minute yeah also we are
decoupled from development that's both
the back or can we just address your
question later after the
okay I already addressed it thank you we
are decoupled from development that
spoke both a feature and back well
people think the developer is the best
person to write documentation but he
actually isn't I mean he knows the inner
workings of his application but he
doesn't know the users expectations for
him everything is so obvious why would
people even ask questions right so you
always need or in a perfect world if
your organization is big enough you do
have a dedicated documentation team or
in your community you have some
volunteers who do the documentation and
ideally they are not the same ones that
are also working on the code we inside
Sousa can bridge this gap by sitting
down with the developers but on the
other hand sometimes it's I mean sitting
down is always very nice but sometimes
it's also emails back and forth back and
forth 20 times that is cumbersome as
well so the coordination effort is very
big and the last problem that I see is
so the first two problems can probably
be addressed with a more continuous and
agile approach we do have for example
the cloud guys in the in Sousa are
working with the agile approach they
have a dedicated documentation writer in
their team who works with the developers
every day who follows their Sprint's so
we will probably switch to to a model
like that but on the other hand you
still need we have this big big big
monolithic as I call it documentation
like the reference guide or something
that's not something that you write on
the drive by while you're developing
that's a huge effort and that's where
you need the team of documentation
writer so we will try something in the
in in between between an agile and a
waterfall approach let's see where we
end up with this and to address this
monolithic issue the issue of what this
big monolithic thing we would probably
switch to
more topic oriented documentation topic
oriented is the new buzzword when it
comes to documentation that's like you
have a single task you have a user story
you want to go from A to B want to
achieve this or that yeah that should be
that should lower or should solve some
of the problems but on the other hand in
traditional documentation the admin
guide or the reference guide is not
going away anytime soon because people
customers want it they want to have one
point of contact where they have like
all the options of this program or so D
so the new topic oriented formats we are
using are more like in addition we
recently started a series called Susan
best practices which will do ya the best
practices for virtualization the best
practices for this or that purpose so
that's more topic oriented now let's go
to the lessons we've learned
docks or it didn't happen I mean you all
know picsArt didn't happen for us that
docks are didn't have him if there's no
documentation for you for your app for I
mean even if it's just a tiny app I had
an app on my mobile I had a problem with
it it turned out to be a back there was
a button missing on a certain screen but
how was I supposed to know there was no
documentation there was a reference his
design should there be a button or not
so you totally need documentation even
if some Mac guys tell you that programs
should be so intuitive that they don't
require documentation you will need
documentation period and don't consider
your work done until unless you're done
with the documentation if feature is not
implemented if there's no documentation
for it really that's that's things that
that also product managers need to
understand of course they want
everything and they want everything now
or they want everything last week but if
there's no QA and if there's no
documentation then it's not done period
yeah as I already mentioned developers
short not write docs we are doing it for
a good reason don't write about the
stuff you know by heart
done
you know somebody's taking taking photos
of these slides yeah you need feedback
channels without feedback it's all
useless you're running in circles you
have no idea what the users expectations
are actually are you can do the you can
do the long reference guide maybe it
doesn't help maybe you use us and expect
something completely different so if you
don't have feedback channels yeah then
it's it's not really worth the effort so
think about the feedback before you
start writing and try to make the
feedback as easy as possible yeah you
need tools
don't try to spend too much time on
tooling I mean we didn't write all these
tools because we felt oh we need to
write yet another tool when we started
out there they were just not there
meanwhile there there are other tools
for example fedora has at least has had
a public publican which is something
similar to Dobbs but it's meanwhile
orphaned I think it's no no longer used
Fedora recently switched away from doc
book the - for example pan doc that's
something similar to what what we do
with dubs that can strands light between
different documentation format and
output PDF or HTML and so on so there
are already plenty of tools out there if
you have any question about a tool or so
you can ask me but make sure you have
the right tools for the job to get the
job done yeah don't spend too much time
on tooling but on the other hand don't
try to no don't you have to spend some
time on the tooling other right
otherwise the writing becomes too
cumbersome but on the other hand don't
reinvent the wheel by by writing yet
another oh this is solving our all our
documentation problems there are some
proprietary solutions out there which
really awesome but totally useless
well for our use case for your skates
useless detail or something like this I
mean there's company making big money
with it but it doesn't cater our use
case and when we then I mean we had
sales agents who were trying to convince
us and we tell them we've written our
own and we publish it for free they were
like what okay
that's small don't start with a
reference guide I mean that's basically
at the very top of the of the
documentation you start small start with
a certain use case try I mean at the
very beginning you probably don't have a
community of documentation writers or
your company doesn't have anyone
employed for writing documentation so at
the beginning at least at the beginning
it will probably be the developer try to
see something from the users perspective
and try to try to think of the typical
user tasks but a user that the user is
trying to achieve and and this
particular topic write it down like how
do I connect to the mail server or
something like that but don't do the I'm
covering all menu options of my program
and then our command line options or
something like that that's at the very
very end of the documentation if you're
done with everything else you can do
this and last but not least
documentation should be open if you're
doing open source your documentation
should be open and by open I not only
mean have your sources somewhere on
github I mean we we do have our sources
on github you can do that whatever you
want as I told you before but also try
to have an open process that allows the
community and allows other people to
give feedback to participate yeah
personally we found it it's difficult to
encourage the community to to start
working on documentation documentation
is something that many people take for
granted and you only use it when you
have a problem as long as everything is
fine you don't need it so that's why
probably not a lot of people want to
work on it but
within the community you can do
something I mean start with something
small like a wiki yeah be open and
that's the message I wanted to bring to
all of you if there are any questions we
have like eight minutes left or
something okay first question so the
question was how do we manage the
localization of our documentation
I mentioned the dock manager earlier the
dock manager has so at the head of the
document you have some some Meetup texts
some some additional dock book elements
the custom elements and they define
whether or not this documentation is
translated so for example the install
guide is translated into these 20
languages the quick install while the
reference guide is only available in
English or the tuning guard or the
virtualization guide so I think we have
like around 20 20 different languages
it's like what we have like some stuff
is not translated at all others is
translated into six languages and and if
when you do the full languages that's
around 20 and that's all defined by
these meta text within the dock manager
we then give it to the translation
agency and from there they they go on to
to do the actual translations
the transition to be honest so the
question was how do they do the actual
management to be honest I don't know
because I don't do the translation
myself that's something that we have out
sourced you can do this for example this
is what we did at caught up at the coop
coop where server with tools like
transifex this online translation tool
this is also good because it gives
people small chunks
I mean it's broken down to strings or
paragraphs and people can start working
on it
so that's something that I would suggest
but yeah I can imagine that if you say I
have this file in English and I now I'm
doing it in German or something that is
difficult but sorry I cannot really give
you the answer I don't know what they're
the translators workflow is I don't
think they start from scratch that but
they will probably really take our files
and overwrite the text but that's just a
wild guess and if you're looking for
something for a community I would
recommend tools like transifex
to try and so the quit the question was
if I make it short why we are using
github if it's if it's closed source
well on github you have a large user
base personally I would like to use get
lab or something well that's not
actually the question the question is
what do you think of the state of tools
for documentation on services like
github and get map and would you be
willing to share some of your
I don't think that integration of
documented I mean they're focusing on
code not on documentation for example
they can if you're using mark-up that
works markup can be displayed directly
in line in github of course it's well
the output depends on the browser or so
but you get an idea if you look at an
XML file and github it's just XML I
would laughs github to have an XML
preview but that's obviously not not
trivial because then it needs to know
the style sheets and whatnot so yeah but
really they don't care about the
documentation much they care about code
but the answer to this is treat
documentation like your treat code apply
continuous integration apply release
engineering tactics that you would use
for code as well but certainly the tools
could be all the services could be
improved you had a question as well we
cannot so the question was how do we
guarantee that the documentation is
up-to-date and I'm sorry I hate to admit
it we can't of course we go through it
like when it when it comes to say the
screenshots that's a pretty trivial
thing you go over the documentation and
make sure the screenshots are still up
to date but we don't really rework every
guide for every release we implement the
new features we implement changes but of
course there sometimes is outdated
information still in there that's where
we rely on feedback where we rely on
users to file box well in a perfect
world you would have quality assurance
not only for code but also for
documentation that somebody really goes
through it and make sure it's still up
to date but that's something that you
cannot really do because of the effort
the second one is a very broad question
but okay the second question first
why not have technical writers as QA for
documentation I'm not saying that I'm
against that but it's it's the question
whether or not if you can't afford it
if you have somebody only working on QA
of Docs and also I think that people who
do QA I've been doing QA before they
should be see things just like the
documentation writer needs to see things
from a different perspective as the
developer somebody in QA needs to see it
from a different perspective so actually
maybe it a technical documentation
writer wouldn't be the best for the
person for QA on Docs
I would rather have real-world user
testing of dogs
there's have grabbed people from the
street and and tell them to perform this
or that if you have topic oriented
documentation it should be easy to give
people tasks that they fulfill and then
you see if it really works or not that's
more interesting than QA so I think we
are running out of time for questions
okay final questions for those of you
who don't have a chance I will be around
on the hallway you can grab me there
okay you got the house
reach out stream sure sure we reach out
for ups so the question was if we reach
out for upstream yes we try to but
sometimes it's it I mean if I find
something that we work with upstream but
sometimes getting stuff back into
upstream is very difficult
like I recently had something that I
needed to document which was some weird
behavior of the Linux kernel when it
comes to epic routing and so the only
documentation out there was a five five
lines of text in a plain text file in
the kernel source tree and some comments
in the kernel code itself I would love
to fix that of course then I can say oh
I feel committed in the Linux kernel but
as you can imagine the process of
getting something accepted is quite
cumbersome and at this point in time I'm
not doing it but other we usually try to
upstream everything all of our work and
souza is actually contributing upstream
like we are doing the OpenStack
documentation for upstream open
OpenStack all right
I think that's all thanks very much for
your
yeah so use our tools breaks them
provide feedbacks and fetches thanks a
lot