all right everybody thanks very much for
coming on up in here welcome so you keep
coming in uh welcome to my talk this is
the premiere of app security does not
need to be fun ignoring no wash but have
a terrible time as I explained to Tommy
here I thought of the title first and I
wrote this talk in the last two weeks
when I got accepted to this conference
uh if you want to get these slides
that's the tiny URL is the bottom uh
Dwayne Dash secured WB I love tiny URL
for that makes it easy so I'm Dwayne I
live in Chicago flew down for this I've
been a developer Advocate since about
2016. and you find me on Twitter and M.C
Dwayne hit me up about anything related
to uh Tech what I'm talking about today
also Rock and Roll I Love Rock and Roll
um improv shows uh do improv in Chicago
um karaoke anything hit me up I'm always
happy to talk to you so quick plug I
work for a company called git Guardian
I'll start out just saying I'll mention
them later as well because we're a gold
sponsor of owasp so you'll see that come
up again later but
um get Guardian is a company that
focuses on secret uh secret leakage
detection and mitigation if you're
hardcoding your secrets or someone's
heart code and secrets somewhere in your
org and they're pushing that somewhere
you should probably be aware of that and
that's what we help people do very
recently we've introduced um internet uh
infrastructure as code scanning scanning
for most common vulnerabilities and we
have awesome open source Tools around
that so check it out I also have
stickers for these uh for this company
if you want stickers
come up and get them afterward and
screen covers so if you want to webcam
cover I got a few of them left
all right so
who here is a security professional that
who here consider themselves a developer
awesome that's who I wrote The Talk for
uh who here is actually a member oh wasp
already
what's that
was my next question but first was
member who's a member of owasp all right
nowhere hands went up for those of you
watching home and uh who uses the oasp
tools in some capacity
a few hands went up
so
what does good security actually look
like I think it looks like this
pager's not going off
you're very confident that nothing's bad
is going to happen by the morning unless
you know something does but you're
confident that you can sleep through the
night and going away on a camping trip
that was the keynote this morning said
they went camping right before came to
this event
you got time to do that you got time to
go to concerts and not worry like I'm
gonna have to leave in the middle before
the headliner actually comes on because
we're gonna have an incident
what really comes down I think to this
that you have that personal time to
spend with the people you love
that's what good security looks like in
my opinion in my world view I come from
the devops space and Drupal and
WordPress
everything we do has a human cost to it
not just a financial cost not just a
technical cost
but it comes down to a human cost
and that's the underlying message I'm
not going to talk about that a whole lot
but that's the underlying message of the
rest of this talk
of like how to not have a terrible time
because what does bad security look like
well unfortunately I don't have like
three pictures that paint that just as
well as those first few did because all
unhappy families are a little bit
different but let's talk about if you
want happy families out there uh who
heard about this Toyota
I'm proud to say I got a top of Hacker
News for about eight hours because I
wrote a piece on this
um they had a subcontractor push part of
their t-connect repo
to a public repo uh and it contained a
key to a data server that had 2000 296
0019 customers data in it
not a good day I did not sleep through
the night on that one oh yeah it was it
was exposed for five years before they
figured it out they have no idea who has
this
uh cash app who's heard of this one
it was a fun one Discerning employee
they forgot to turn on and forget they
didn't have policy to turn off their
rights came back later stole all the
data for all their users
Uber this one probably everybody's heard
of
yes uh lapsis uh a teenager broke this
to the New York Times said hey I pwned
uh opponed Uber
and that's how it broke he said look at
all this data I have look at all these
systems I came into look at I got in
through everything because they hard
coded into Powershell scripts all the
credentials I needed
didn't do anything with it other than
embarrass them that we know of we don't
know what lapses actually did with it
unlike Samsung where lapse has dumped it
all said here's 160 gigs of Samsung's
data including the source code for
Galaxies
and six over six thousand secrets to get
into the rest of their systems
after them not attributed lapses
uh they realized hey someone's stolen
all of our customer data I think it's
directly related to this but they've
never confirmed that it is
they're not even saying what exactly
they stole they just say something got
stolen but maybe one of the biggest
unhappy families out there is Apache
users unfortunately uh thanks to log for
shell
I don't think we need to say a lot about
that but that affected so much of the
internet
everybody involved in that then had to
scramble and have some sleepless nights
and couldn't go camping and couldn't go
to concerts because they had to fix this
they had to figure out how to mitigate
the problems from that
threats are only increasing out there
day to day that's what one thing you've
heard repeatedly here at securewb
and security teams are outnumbered but
maybe not in the way you're thinking
I don't think there are more hackers
than there are are any more black hat
hackers than there are uh people on Red
teams and blue teams and you know people
trying to do good
what where security people are
outnumbered is inside their own
organizations uh security at security at
conference on to Al Trace recently said
um in the best organizations it's 101 of
developers two security people
so what do we do
this is shift left make everybody on the
security team then this fixes that
problem doesn't it
that'd be great that's what shifting
left can mean I think shifting left is a
bad term personally because I see it so
poorly abused
smearing left or um uh
what's it spreading left is spreading
left is the word that I heard that I
kind of like that one because it spread
the knowledge around and that's what it
was supposed to do because if we keep
sliding everything left like everything
left eventually the developer is the
only people doing anything and they
already have a lot to do they got
deliverables they're fighting bugs they
have to figure out devops now they're
fighting kubernetes day in day out
that's a whole industry if you ask most
devops people what they do like
kubernetes is somewhere in their
description of what they do day to day
nobody understands it how many people
write it I think
it's not so much time
unfortunately as well from the business
perspective a lot of business people
I've talked to in my life kind of have
this view of security
it's like yeah we gotta fix the last
thing that broke
oh wait a minute let's slowed everything
down we gotta speed back up again wait a
minute that caused an incident
and we're in this endless loop
but you can just throw a tool at it if
you figure out which tool to throw at it
uh again this is a developers who were
kind of on their own like hey you you
were gonna worry about security now you
build that into your deliverables
we're done no no if I as a somebody that
used to be ex sales I could tell you
that my tool will always be the thing
that solves most of your problems
but in reality there's so many tools and
so many sales people yell on that you
don't know what to do
so I think
this is what a lot of people have talked
to a lot of people in the last few weeks
last few months of my life I've talked
to feel like this or feel like the Red
Queen
you got to run as fast as you can just
to stay where you are
to get ahead you got to run at least
twice that fast
if you're not ever read through looking
glass and what Alice found there it's
the second book in the Alice series uh
uh probably you're familiar with the
first one in Alice Wonderland uh those
are two of my favorite books ever
written it's a bunch of wonderful
nonsense pull them out
um
so right now if you're a developer and
you're just reminding your I've reminded
you like yes this is the world I live in
you might be thinking yeah I wish there
was just a benevolent group of
superheroes that could just help me with
this stuff
turns out there is called a wasp uh the
largest non-profit focused on security
in the world uh
stands for open web application security
project
mission is very simple
no more insecure software
in a perfect world that's what they
would actually accomplish this is
actually their full mission statement
it's kind of long I'll let you read it
but really it boils down to of just a
few things that they do
and there's these things they got
projects they focus on communities
events education training publication
resources
projects is the heart of everything this
is the main thing I think owass is known
for they make all these awesome projects
that do a bunch of things we'll break
down a little bit more in the next
slides but uh every one of them has a
repo attached
volunteers and experts are contributing
their own time and resources to make
these happen
uh there are 242 at current count but
that number keeps going up and they're
149 in usable States when I say usable
States they're in one of these four
categories uh Flagship which is well the
best biggest most supported best
documented
production is a new category as of
October uh nothing's in it yet because
it's a brand new category and there's a
process to get into it that means it's
production ready and you should feel
confident running in production of
course to say that with confidence you
got to go through a process and no one's
done it yet it's too new lab projects
they're not Flagship projects but
they're still pretty good in computer
projects are on their way to lab
um
flagships though are a designation to
give projects that have demonstrated
strategic value
labs are on their way there
oh yeah those numbers that's why I made
these slides uh 18 uh flagships right
now
uh 34 lab projects
and 97 incubators everything else is on
its way there it needs documentation
you're looking to get involved in open
source
here are over 100 projects that would
love your help
and as we get further down on that stack
flagships are very general very big very
Broad
Labs a little more specific a little
more like OAS podcast project for
instance they make a podcast that's what
they do
um
uh the incubators are very specific and
they start getting into the weeds of
what you want to get done with security
and that's a lot so they mapped it out
they said Hey how do you know which one
you need to use when
so they built a map for you it's
literally a map of the software
development life cycle
and says all right if you're in the
requirements phase we got a tool for
that if you're in uh
culture
building and process maturing we got
stuff for that
and there's some overlap there and
they're all arranged around this idea of
cre that fairly recent
um only about a year and a half old I
think Sierra common requirement
enumeration
because there are so many standards out
there there are so many numbers to know
they said what if we just made a metal
layer that combined all the numbers and
linked everything together in a logical
way and that's what they did it's open
cre opencra.org you can jump there on
your computer right now
look up any security topic you want and
it's fully like linked this is what an
IST is these are cves for these are
everything you need to know about it
Community it is people
that's why we're here in the first place
if it was just us doing security out
there in the dark by ourselves
we wouldn't have awesome events like
this
that's why I love Drupal that's why I
love WordPress is the communities code
yeah it's PHP but people are amazing and
you have the best times chapters all
over the world I've been to 200 OAS
meetups in the last week because they're
online and they could do it that's how I
found out about the git vulnerability
there's two cves open for git right now
if you have not updated to the latest do
it immediately and you'll be safe but
that's literally news from last week
GitHub does a really good article on it
get has a poor boundary anyway Sidetrack
many events all over the world uh in
fact I mentioned it earlier get Guardian
actually hosts the in-person one in uh
Paris get Guardian is based to Paris
so that's what I mean Meetup looks like
we almost look like
but you can get together with your
friends talk shop you want to go to a
larger event something like secure WV
they have those too I'm really bummed I
can't go to the one in in November in uh
San Francisco the app SEC days because
of other prior engagements but uh they
have big events
you all know what events are so don't
harp on that educational training those
are my favorite things about OAS who
here oh none of you are all members if
you remember OAS you have complete
access to a secure flag
it's a training platform
that's always up to date with the latest
standards because it's written by the
teams at OAS who are responsible for
this stuff
in any area you want free unlimited
training you can go for search with it
I'm not here to sell you on o wasp but
this blew my mind when I first started
digging through it uh you get a
freeos.org email account but uh that
gets you secure flag for as much
training as you want
truthfully I've not had enough time
since I started writing this talk to
start going through this stuff but
um there's a lot there there's also a
ton of trainings based on olasp I just
Googled literally Google to send the
speaker notes uh the Google search
um
uh OAS trainings or oauth Education and
Training and this is one of the articles
that came up there are hundreds of pages
of results
they also make a lot of Publications a
lot of white papers you'll read will
cite oasp or will come from OAS uh and
they have a book if you want to spend
the book money on a book
a lot of that crosses over the plot
projects so
okay I just told you a lot of
information about an organization that
no one's a member of and only a few
people have started touching the tools
of
how to use this stuff well
we'll break it down into these four
takeaways if you walk away with nothing
else from this talk these are the four
things you should remember about a wasp
top 10.
they make a top 10 list every single
year they're the top 10 type of tax
that's actually what it says it's
updated yearly
um
but it's kind of the 80 20 rule if you
are guarding against the most
active attacks out there that the script
kitties are throwing at anything they
can find an IP for
this is this year this is 21 21 they
haven't come out 2022 yet because well
we're still in 2022.
um but it's based on research and then
two of them are from Community surveys
like what do you think are the biggest
issues
so if you're gonna think hey is my app
secure as a developer this is your
starting point
hey have I actually fixed access control
the
do I guard it against injections
if you can go down this list because all
of these
it's not just a list
all of these have in-depth articles
about what they are
and very importantly how to prevent
so if you're starting your ciso says hey
now you Dev you are responsible for
security for your own apps you're not
alone
you have a whole world like telling you
how to prevent it
cheat sheets that cmciso comes in and
says what do you know about X
if you got time to Google
and read
then you got time to jump over the cheat
sheets and quickly find what you're
looking for the cheat sheets was an
awesome series that will go in depth
about any I think it's 100 some topics I
don't actually know the number off top
my head uh but there's a bunch of cheat
sheets into cheat sheets.oos.org
um that break down any general topic so
next time someone a director level or
somebody says hey what do you know about
kubernetes security
uh do two minutes of reading and you
will have a quick brain dump of what the
experts think about this including
architecture general terms definitions
and like how to prevent the worst
attacks based on the top 10 again
a wash goats not the greatest of all
time well maybe they are maybe they are
uh they are specifically designed
insecure applications
you want to see an example of how not to
write an app
there you go uh web code is the oldest
node.js codes pretty good wrong Secrets
is awesome you want to see how not to do
password management
they wrote a whole app for that you can
go and tear apart and see if this is how
not to do it
uh pie goat all the other incubator ones
are still need help if you want a web go
PHP they need help
but the greatest of all
isn't a goat the greatest of all
is Juice Shop
who's ever runs you shop
awesome well a few hands went up uh
Juice Shop is a awesome application with
a bunch of really fun cookies in it uh
Cookie's been the fact that you click on
it takes you to a YouTube video you
basically Rick rolls you without Rick
Rolling you
um without Rick
uh but it's very in depth uh you could
tactically run this in production you
shouldn't but you could it's that well
made and it's really well documented
there's tons of articles
that will go into details about how to
use it effectively and why you can use
it effectively and how to tear it apart
and tons of documentation on this thing
so maybe it is the greatest of all time
for insecure apps that you shouldn't run
in production
and zap
these are like the top four if you take
away if you take away nothing else
download zap and use this you will be
horrified and shocked
uh maybe not in that order
um so is that attacks proxy
uh they actually have a conference about
this these days uh stackhawk throws it
it's called zapcon
and there's a whole conference about zap
like it's a growing Community into
itself outside of you know outside of
the larger oops communities it's awesome
um so zap is an attack tool
and this is what it looks like
not not impressive but you throw the URL
you want to attack
make sure it's something you actually
have permission to attack and they're
expecting it so that we can be all um at
the whole good side of things
um a really good thing to test this with
is
you shop
uh and it will show you an extreme
example of what it can do
because you throw it and it takes a
while to run it's literally attacking
the app as hard as it can
and it throws up alerts so
I don't know the exact number on that if
you did the math
um but this is what it thinks is wrong
with Juice Shop
so if you're like well how do I even
start with making my app secure I read
all these things I got these checklists
I got these
spreadsheets I've got these white papers
oh wait a minute I can run zap actually
run down the list of alerts and start
tackling it from there
which ones that I should attack first oh
let's go cross-reference this with the
top ten which is the most likely
scenario for me
well they protect you in every situation
no that's a tool like any other tool
it's got limitations it's got uh
drawbacks one of the big problems with
it is false positives
they admit that they're working on that
again it's open source if you want to
help with that they'd love some help
um but it's a starting point
I actually don't know how long I've been
talking
22 minutes wow this faster than I
thought it was
um so in conclusion
you don't have to be alone out there
you don't have to
just wish that someone was helping you
because there's a whole Community people
to help you it's called OAS do you have
to join them to leverage them absolutely
not can you go use all of our tools
right now for free yes absolutely
because the other day security should
look like this not
panic and tickets and people yelling at
you and going looking for another job
because you got tired of it
start with top 10.
just reading that is super Illuminating
about Security in general
you got a specific question about a
specific area they made a cheat sheet
for you already guarantee it if they
didn't it's open source you could
probably contribute one it's something
you know about
play with the goats I'll show you what
not to do
and finally uh zap
download it you'll be horrified
I'm doing hello in Chicago
a little bit faster than I expected
because I had 70 slides but I got
through them somehow
so with that I'll open up for any
questions you all got
I was really hoping to have an OS member
in here that could tell me about hey
forgot to talk about that particular
part of it that I really like but uh but
since y'all are using tools if there's
uh well first if there's any questions
happy to try to answer those
then I got a question for you
foreign
fall okay
I'm in the same boat as you on that one
all I know is what in the in the on the
public conversation on it and it is that
exact sentiment that's what they said at
um zapcon uh this year
um zapcon is completely available online
so you can watch it all for free that's
what the lead dubs were saying is like
there's a cue we're working on itself as
fast as we can the false positive they
see is the bigger problem
um I forget that I could look it up but
I'm not going to
um
but that's the biggest issue people
because that kind of is intended to like
run locally
to test these things not
in production
though it is a flagship and you should
be able to do that that I think this is
me speculating is part of how they came
up with the production ready
category uh because zap will not qualify
for that because of that because you
can't run an Enterprise
um
I don't think that's like the motivator
is like that's make that fix this by not
letting them into a category but that
category should preclude them if it's
doing what they say it's going to just
let you run at a scale
optimism
well
um
but next question which is not a great
question is like do you know if there's
an open PR that someone's trying to fix
this yet that just needs upvotes
[Music]
help
I mean that's it's a I mean that PRS are
open is like the worst response in the
world
just make sure I'm on the right one
I mean 700 issues open so there's quite
the queue
uh let's see
as no PR is currently open
yeah yeah it's still open are the issues
still open so
it's been home for a while too 2018.
so everybody get online upvote this
immediately we'll get this fixed That's
The Power of uh Power that I'm serious
like I just had a ticket close
uh finally get fixed after like six
months for a uh extension on
a vs code extension
um
but it took six months during that time
they gained like six million users and
it's a UI problems like there's an extra
six million people that ran into
something that it could have fixed
earlier
um but what finally got is enough people
upvoted it they're like hey we'll fix it
yeah okay enough people have complained
now it's the loudest uh the um
squeakiest wheel gets the grease
unfortunately
but it's also just us so
that's the that's the plus and the minus
of any open source community
is it's us doing it like we're the ones
building there's no finger you can
really point that doesn't also
eventually point back to us as
individuals saying well why don't I fix
this
but at the same time
you got a family you got other
responsibilities like it's it's a
it's a balancing act but that's all open
source good and bad
and I'm just rambling any other thoughts
any other questions
over there
the short answer is no uh the only thing
I know about stackhawk that I am very
comfortable saying is that they are the
main sponsor behind zapcon
beyond that I don't have a firm opinion
anybody did anybody have an opinion on
this open Forum anybody you stack hawk
in here
there you go
ahead and tell you I've talked to their
sales reps at a booth once but that's a
sales rep at a booth so I don't know
any other
thoughts questions
all right well thank you very much for
coming out and uh check out OAS
thank you
this talk was a part of our 2022 secure
West Virginia Lucky 13 conference if you
would like more information about this
talk or our speaker check the
description below and if you enjoyed the
content consider liking and sharing this
video for more information on secure
West Virginia or you want to stay
updated with the latest upcoming events
follow us on Twitter at securewbcon or
visit our website securedwb.org
we would like also like to thank our
2022 sponsors for being a huge part of
Lucky 13 success