reported
good afternoon everyone I realize I am
the guy after lunch so I'm going to try
to keep things moving
I will try to be entertaining I didn't
bring my dad jokes
but I'll try to keep things entertaining
anyway
uh I do like to I do encourage people to
try the things uh like Hands-On I think
that's the best way to learn so if any
of you brought your laptops I was
mentioning earlier fire them up if you
have Windows I know sometimes I'm amazed
to be here I know sometimes they don't
like Windows people here but I work with
Windows I work with Linux I works on the
Mac
um
written code in lots of different
languages and works a lot of different
interfaces through the years more people
excellent we're just starting
wow I realize I guess I thought it might
be an introduction so my name is Eric
Schultz and I've been working in the
industry for a number of years now
I've done some software developments and
some systems engineering assistant
Administration and the last 10 15 years
working in the cyber security field in a
number of different roles such as red
teams and penetration testing blue
teaming even a touch reverse engineering
but not as much as I would have liked
anyway let's get started here
what I'd like to do today is give you a
really brief history of Powershell I
don't think that's all that important I
highlight a few uh specific things along
the way
and then get started by
um giving you a quick view of the
integrated scripting environment and the
command line shell those are the two
main ways of working with Powershell
we'll talk briefly again about
differences and then I'll just make
mention in some cases depending on where
you are what you're doing you may need
administrator level access for example
then we'll get into what you probably
want to know about things like aliases
and commands and functions and modules
and Scripts
but this was supposed to be an entry
level beginning level so it won't get
too deep into these areas
can everybody hear me over there you
guys can hear me okay uh sorry that's
not much I can do about the screen I
don't know if you guys want to move in a
little closer up to you
you folks are in good shape I think
all right so the real brief history it
started way back in 2006 for anybody who
didn't know that uh it was November
something like that version one very
basic it's it's grown it's evolved
I don't really think the versions are
all that important except they will note
version six uh is when they introduce
their Powershell core idea across
platform open source I think the ideas
they they offer updates releases like
every six months
and we are now currently at Powershell
version seven 7.2 I think is the latest
release and there is a 7.3 pre-release
[Music]
all right for those in the back I could
launch it but uh the ISE if you're new
to software development you might like
the ISE
integrated scripting environment
and I spelled that out and it's gone now
okay the integrated scripting
environment gives you a window with a
nice blue window that's where you're
dealing with your code and then the
window to the side gives you help right
then and there you're looking at a list
of functions and commandlets that are
available to you
it is a nice way to begin programming
begin Powershell programming
I personally I'm old school I personally
prefer the uh other way the command
shell it is
any uh old dos command show or it's
similar to any of your Linux or Unix
type of shell
pretty straightforward everything is
text based you can have fun with the
colors as I like to do there that those
are my color settings
and let's see the nice things about the
command shell
it offers help and help can be very
beneficial and it can be very helpful
but
it depends on the author you do not have
to write any help for the scripts that
you write
I can write a script I can share with
the world and it doesn't have to provide
any help at all there are a lot of good
examples of helping a lot of the scripts
being written and that's how I base my
work
but you don't have to and you may run
into scripts that don't offer any help
the other thing you will like you will
want to get used to is what they call
tab complete tap completion
if you can't quite remember the command
start typing it start pressing the tab
and it'll cycle you through it if
there's only one possible I'm going to
bring that one up if you uh if there are
a couple different possibilities you can
get a kind of a cycle through the list
of that and you can also do shifts to go
backwards if you think the command might
have been down the bottom of the list
you can press shift tab
feel free if you have any other
questions let's see
now
part of the reason I like to work with
the command shell as opposed to the ISE
is it does a few things differently
and if you're going to turn your work
into a script and let other people run
it or run it yourself you will probably
want to run it in the command shell
memory management is different
and there are some features that are not
available in the ISE like this idea of
the transcripts you can have Powershell
record everything you're doing and
everything is getting back just like the
log of any other thing your SSH can log
output rule Powershell can log the
output as well but that's not available
in the ISE version
and once again administrator level
access will pop up on you every now and
then depending on what you're trying to
do depending on the execution policies
depending on the profiles uh if you're
at work you may not be able to do what
you'd like to do without permissions and
if you're at home on your own laptop
you can do anything you want
I mentioned the profiles there are at
least six profiles
they cover different combinations all
users all hosts all users on the current
host
current user and you want to view on all
hosts or the current user current host
these are just different ways of
controlling Powershell in an
environments if you're on your own it's
really your choice what you do how you
configure your profiles if you are in a
corporate environment you may find
certain things are allowed and certain
things are restricted
if you'd like more information there are
a lot of good Pages out there here is
one in particular
uh it is Microsoft's own
it'll give you more details on the
different profiles where you can find
them what they might do for you how they
all interact
any questions feel free there will be
some Show and Tell in a few moments
[Music]
now we get into the most beneficial
Powershell supports this idea of an
alias I imagine you all have heard that
term before it's just one name for
something else a different name for
something else
so for example those of you who are
familiar with the Linux or Unix World
you've probably heard the uh command cat
I was always told that stupid catalog
but anyway on the old DOS commands type
in Powershell that would be the
equivalent of get contents
CD or change directory chdir is set
location
if you want to delete or erase
that's the equivalent of removing an
item and all these things there are many
more all these things can be listed
anytime from the command line or from
the ISE and we'll do that in a moments
a larger list are the get command
function
it will show you all the functions all
the commandlets there is a bit of a
difference there
and it will also again list the aliases
just like a moment ago when you get your
list
[Music]
lots of things scrolling by
they are organized first by the type
like commandlet
function alias
gives you the name of the commandlet or
function or Alias and the versions and
where it came from the module or the bit
of Microsoft code that gives you that
ability
thank you
so an example I have here on the screen
was simply the clear host you all have
heard CLS or clear command these
different commands on different
platforms
that would be clear screen or clear host
but you can type in any of those
the functions generally are meant to be
uh probably part of a script more than
anything else not necessarily a command
line whereas what they call a commandlet
is its own little utility if you will
so it's more something more likely to be
used from the command line but I'm not
aware of any restrictions I'm not aware
of anything that limits you
one thing I really like about Powershell
and why I would recommend learning it
it gives you access to just about
everything on box it is almost visual C
plus plus a command line as opposed to
having the script entire programs you
can do a lot of things right at the
command line
you can look at the settings of the
environments uh here's the dir command
or LS command or get child item command
[Music]
people familiar with command line or
shell might be familiar with some of
these different settings
[Music]
you can find out different paths where
things can be stored where things will
be stored like your temp folders
if you want to make use of the temp or
TMP variable that's where it points
the user domain user domain roaming
profile you can see what kind of network
you're on
the windows directory
and the hive the registry
's hives are accessible right there on
the command line again
[Music]
hkcu stands for the current user
you can
work your way down
[Music]
and it will keep on going if you have
permissions
because there's a lot in this life if
you have permissions you can change
these things if you have permissions you
can
delete the settings you can create new
settings if they have not been created
already
right there on the command line it just
depends on your permissions your
authorization level
okay
my apologies I am kind of zooming
through some of this stuff um
I'll show again the uh tab you do want
to get used to the tab itself
if I bring up the hkcu
it will start to list
the areas below that I can work my way
into
I can shift and tab backwards
I believe
if you're not sure where you're going if
you're not sure exactly how to spell it
try the tab command
another area this is confusing sometimes
um
the good old execution policy
there are various different levels I'll
get to in just a moment right now it
says for example I am restricted
this is the default policy for the
windows clients
I'm allowed individual commands but I'm
not allowed to run scripts at this uh at
this time which is rather surprising to
me considering it's my own laptop but
I have not gotten in here to mess with
these various settings
there are different execution policy
types there's machine policy user policy
process policy
all of these will have an impact on
your ability to get your job done
to run things you want to run
if as you see here
four of them are undefined
it will default down into whichever one
isn't and it will work off of that
policy which is why I'm restricted
back to the different policy values I
mentioned the restricted all signed
you can run scripts but every script
must be signed even scripts you write
yourself they must be digitally signed
with an accepted certificate
remote signs a little bit different it's
the default policy for Windows servers
only the scripts from remote systems
would have to be signed scripts that you
brought down to the box would have to be
signed
others do not need to be
a few more possibilities unrestricted
default for most non-windows computers
if you're running Powershell on Linux
which you can do nowadays
you're going to get an unrestricted
which lets you do pretty much everything
if you have the ability you can set the
execution policy temporarily to
something like bypass it will let you do
what you want to do nothing but blocked
but you won't get any warnings either
if you run a script and it hoses up your
system
start rebuilding
and undefined means exactly that no
policy has been defined if things are
undefined then it will ignore those and
look at the other policies in
an order until it finds one that is
applicable
I like to point out these are not really
security they're not going to stop
everybody
they'll slow down the honest computer
user but there are ways of getting
around them
um
that's part of what red teaming and blue
team is about finding the waves around
uh I mentioned with the restricted I
believe it was you can't run a script
it's awkward but you could take each
command one at a time and type it in the
command line
and probably still get the results you
want
depending on the detail of the script
[Music]
there are also
was it was like not Powershell I'm
trying to think of the things people had
put together basically another
executable which gave you all the
ability of Powershell but it wasn't
recognized as Powershell
and so if you could bring that onto the
Box during your penetration test or your
hack you could still run your scripts
because
Windows didn't understand that it was
Powershell
so as I said here these are really much
more idiot-proofing than anything else
though they'll slow down the honest
folks
but there is usually a way to get around
it if you really want to
now we're going to talk a little bit
about modules
how do you find out what's on your
system
get module or GMO
we'll list out the modules that came
right here that's pretty much out of the
box I haven't modified this one
starts to give you a list of the
exported commands which means the
functions and the Commandments
yeah it's going to scroll off the screen
verbose will give you more detail but I
think in this case it's scrolling off to
the right side of the screen so you
still can't see it
thank you
if you have a module somebody else is
written and you want to import it there
you go
if you want to remove modules from
memory
pretty obvious
and one nice thing about the get command
and you can ask it what module gave me
this
the PS Reliant module gives me one
function in those five Commandments
wow
if you are bringing down some module
somebody else has written you might want
to take a look before running it to see
what it offers you and we're familiar
with it
Now we move on to help as I mentioned
previously though it is up to the author
of the code how much help they've
provided you
a lot of the professionally written ones
will give you some
syntax
not always the most clear in my opinion
by better than nothing you see the Alias
is listed down there in this case
there's only the one really GCM kit
command
if offered
yeah
no uh no examples are given you can
ask it to give you examples you can ask
it to give you the full list
explains the parameters a little bit
more
the all parameter what type it is
position
argument list
[Music]
I'm throwing a lot at you I realize
that's
um
if you have any questions you want to
see anything again let me know
question
okay I don't think I don't know if I
remember that one
I don't think I remember that one very
good all right
okay
and you know here's another good example
tab complete
you want to know what parameters are
available to you start pressing the tab
I guess had I gone through
yeah there it was
I did not remember that one
there's your post I'll work with that
one a lot
shift tab will work your way back
through
that was the examples I mentioned full
so we're looking at right here on the
screen right now
yeah okay that's right it's trying to
remember uh you can
get it to explain what happens when an
error happens
you're trying to remember this one I
have not worked with very much
[Music]
as you can see there is a lot GCM can do
for you
thank you
so ran you through you do help in the
command and ex for example sort of help
command and the full which will give you
every Last Detail that it has available
to you
but it will depend on the code AS
written by the person if they provided
you help you're you're fortunate if you
provided you a lot of help
but they don't have to
the command scripts can be very sweet
very short
so how do you run your script so there
are two main ways
if the script is basically designed
Standalone just to do its thing all you
have to do is name the script
and it will start with whatever module
whatever function in the code has been
designated as the starting points
and it provides you with a menu or
provides you with output right away
if it is a more involved module and it
might have several functions several
commandlets built into it
Imports of the module
and from that point forward you can now
use any of those commands until you
remove that module
all right I mentioned I thought it was
funny I mentioned in the uh
opening talk
there are a lot of good scripts out
there I guess I say be careful some of
the other scripts as well but there are
a lot of good ones the Power view is one
I first remembered power scan I think I
noticed on his presentation
and there are a few others was there
even a power sploit I think don't know
if that one's still being maintained or
not
but the power of you gave you a lot of
net commands written in Powershell
someone else had put together the power
can't script you can probably get your
hands on anyone here familiar with
netcat or NC
I would imagine a lot of you have heard
it's been around for a couple decades
now well someone wrote power account
which is netcat in Powershell
and quite handy
on one
one role I was in where I was basically
the outside red team member uh I just
opened up connections between boxes to
see when the Cyber defense guys finally
noticed that these two boxes are talking
on a database support and they shouldn't
be because of both workstations
and we did also relay some data through
with two uh tunnels from A to B to C
using power cat since we had access to
windows boxes
and where I'm at now
um
I often have written tools where I've
needed them
previous roles I've been in I wrote a
script I just called Wander you start it
at a share on a network drive for
example and it will work its way into
every folder okay let's keep trying and
until it can't go any further was
designed so that it would look for files
perhaps by the name or by the extension
and it has a basic searching ability in
it
so that I could look for certain
keywords and I did find documents and I
did find spreadsheets that had accounts
and passwords and they did not always
work but a lot of them did
and let's see this was a simple web
server here on the screen that I was
showing you
uh it's not much more than what you're
looking at right there
but it simply listens on a ports I think
I picked 8080 in this case
because it's basically running on my
workstation work
and I use this for some of my what I
like to call my cheat sheets uh as I'm
working in Linux or Powershell or
whatever you've got commands you use
again and again again
but you may not remember all the
parameters you may not remember how you
like to use it so I put together a cheat
sheet and I put together the simple web
server they're static but it's good
enough for me that's all I need I don't
need to have a complete web server
I did some passwords spraying on one job
that was a lot of fun if you're not
familiar with that term you take one
password and you throw it against maybe
100 different counts to see if anything
matched then you maybe wait a couple
hours
I had a lot of fun that was that was
quite quite the adventure I can tell you
a lot about passwords that organizations
use and the tendency of people to use
the same password
across different networks or let's see
if you um
if you know the idea of the keyboard War
anybody familiar with that it's not so
much a word or phrase you just go up and
down the rows or maybe go across those
keyboard blocks you just kind of follow
pattern
well just imagine basically one down as
I call it although you actually yeah you
start with the number and then maybe two
up and three down and four yeah I found
those
and I found the inverse of that people
being clever they start at the bottom
and I also found that when people were
done with using one down two and the
expired they just moved over
so
we had a lot of fun and our ciso was
getting tired of reading how we easily
cracked passwords
so but yeah we often started an
assessment we already had accounts to
try so that was a script written in
Powershell
had to leave that one behind though
and I do apologize boy I guess I um I
thought there might be a little more
questions a little more interaction
I guess I've kind of gone fast but we're
basically down to the Q a I'm sorry
about that people but you can take a
walk before your next
your next uh talk whichever attack you
want to go to I uh I'm back but I guess
not till two o'clock this was supposed
to be again a little more Hands-On I was
going to take you through there are some
sites you go to online which lets you
try your Powershell skills uh that was
the idea of the two o'clock
if anyone's heard of under the wire that
was what we were going to be looking at
okay
well you can stay and watch if you want
or you know but the idea was these will
get you to try your Powershell to do
some research and to see if you can get
your way through the levels
thank you
my human's falling flat huh
nothing nothing there okay no that's not
really Me No I gave it away at the
beginning
and social media influencer right didn't
I put that in there
yeah that's uh I I don't know sometimes
I just build those people really
and who would trust them what some guy
recently confessed that
China I think was was trying to reach
out to him to get him to
that they were really paying money to
say certain things like really we trust
these folks anymore
okay sorry I'm getting political I'll
stop now
but if you want the real information
come on back uh I do apologize this is
my first time being up in a conference
like this I have generally
but thank you
I have generally given presentations you
know co-workers or maybe to customers
like I did I did have a lot of fun with
the password one I mentioned earlier
everybody was just kind of sitting there
quietly because I think people were
nodding their heads and shaking their
heads you know
I I could say like the top of my past
which we found and how frequently they
were and I the ciso he enjoyed the
presentation but like I said he was
getting tired of hearing how we were
starting some of our assessments and we
already had accounts and passwords
because my boss would let me go I like a
couple days a week before the assessment
he'd let me start running the script
again to see if I could find any
accounts and passwords
and at least one time uh
the password had timed out you know it
expired and so I thought okay this is a
great account if we could get it I tried
again I tried like shifting over one
didn't work it started shifting over
again we're in so
he was really getting tired of hearing
about that stuff but it was a lot of fun
so
like I said any questions or anything
else if not I guess
I'll try to be a little more
entertaining next time
and I'll try not to go through I really
thought there'd be a few more questions
and stuff so I thought I'd take a little
more time so
yes
like
a small turkey might
virtually oh sorry do you have any
prescriptions those groups have you ran
outside of here
okay if you didn't hear what scripts
have I written outside of work
well I guess none
I don't do a lot of programming at home
anymore
but I've perhaps made use of the scripts
like I am running my personal web server
at home on my laptop I didn't pull that
into this one like I said this is fairly
new and I haven't set it up yet
uh but I do have my personal web server
at home I don't buy the cracking my own
passwords I I leave my wife alone I
don't try to break into her accounts so
um
do I have something like GitHub that I
can share in my description no I don't
but I'd be more than happy to share any
of the scripts
um I'll talk to you when we're done here
on our break
[Music]
what did they call them I I tend to work
in environments where I can't
necessarily bring things in which is why
I tend to write them more myself
you all can probably start to guess what
I'm talking about were you kind of
restricted you can't bring things in
like computers and phones Okay so
uh so we tend to write our own stuff
there but uh what was Empire
uh well that was the name of I think one
of their um
because I haven't been doing that role
for a couple years now but Empire was a
uh I think the name of a Powershell
you started
oh
I still think I was trying to think of
you know a whole package uh Empire is
where a power view I think was a part of
uh Empire and and like power scan or
something like that
yeah I thought there was a power sport I
thought there was and I and like five or
six years ago I was using those more
often and I'll be honest I I would
probably say that's a good place to
start I found his code good I found
their code sorry that was a little slip
I actually like 10 years ago I worked
with one of the guys who ended up in
that effort he was one of their names
you recognized I won't try to you know
what is it when I when you try to grab
somebody else's I won't mention his name
but uh yeah I worked with that guy way
back when before he knew a Powershell so
uh he was he was a bit smarter than I
was he um realize way back in version
one version two that there was some
potential for Powershell because it is
on all these computers
and so somebody came in late I was
saying I'm actually surprised to be here
talking about our show because I know in
some of these conferences people don't
like Windows they they don't
I work with Windows and I work with
Linux I've worked with computer and
flavors of Unix I have some Mac at home
but Windows is out there so I would
encourage people learn it
uh you have access to Powershell if you
have a Windows computer Windows Server
Windows laptop or desktop you have
Powershell
figure out what it can do for you right
now figure out how to bring the modules
down
sorry did I see something or is it
inside job okay
am I am I becoming too much of the uh
Advocate okay I was gonna say my in my
advocating because I really have no
stock in Microsoft I have no stocking
into this stuff
okay yeah okay so yeah I'll work with
whatever I'm doing
um and I'm I'm actually one of those
who leans a little more toward the
they're called living off the land or I
call living off the OS if you will uh I
think we there's a lot here already and
we don't know what's out there
and I I that's why I do try to
familiarize myself with what is out
there because I love it if you've been
in the corporate environment you may not
be able to shut down or reboot
and I've been doing this stuff for years
you open things up you close things out
opening I just like to reboot if it's
windows I admit I still reboot fairly
frequently but it's down to maybe once
or twice a week if we're forced to or
something
but I found out a while ago where you
can't select shutdown or reboot from the
menu but there's a nice little EXE
and they don't stop that
foreign
yeah they won't stop there
so slash R for reboot or slash g is kind
of fun it doesn't always work slash g
will
um try to restart any apps that have
been up and running sometimes they do
come back if you had a couple browser
windows uh the shutdown with slash g
when you log back in it'll bring up your
browser
anime he's right back where you were
I've actually found out surprisingly
okay who here knows notepad plus plus
Windows World notepad it's nice nice app
right
I still do bring up notepad every now
and then because it's just easy
it doesn't bring any of the formatting I
don't know about you all but if you get
a corporate document or something I I
usually bring it out of word or out of
excel into notepad and then into
whatever because it leaves all the
formatting behind it just brings the
text
and maybe it's it's from word to notepad
to another word that I'm doing but it
leaves all the formatting behind
so I found actually
using the G option when you log back in
notepad is right there again
I'm surprised notepad plus plus saves
all your temporary files you may not
saved but notepad you close notepad it's
gone
but you run the slash g after you reboot
it'll actually be there is it's worked
for me a few times so
okay I'm rambled on and on what time we
got here well still only 140 any other
questions any comments I got lots of fun
stories I mean I can I'm not dad jokes
but their their stories so
anything else
foreign
I can't think of anything offhand I do
not have that on the box here too bad
I can't think of anything offhand I
don't know I suppose maybe you might say
the ability to
handle multiple sessions
um something like that what do you work
with you you're one of the Developers
oh oh well I got to talk to you online
then oh okay oh well okay I didn't know
I honestly didn't know I'm not trying to
plug his stuff there but but power cat
was it was a fun one I I found a few
years ago it was quite handy so
attitude
well yeah I got to get your contact
information and I will uh you know I'll
keep you in mind
right now I'm doing more cyber defense
type work and I'm just supporting some
hardware and software I've gotten away
from Red teaming but I Tell You Folks if
that's your interest if you like the
geeky you want to learn some tools you
want to learn some languages and then
you want to do things yeah get into red
team
oh that can be a lot of fun a lot of uh
a lot of things you find out there a lot
of things that are leave a shaking your
head and and even some of the uh perhaps
more of the social engineering type
stuff my previous job I was able to walk
around the building every now and then
just try my badge trying to get into
doors and
they they didn't lock that place down I
was getting into all sorts of doors
I was telling that my team leader at one
time I came back from meeting and I said
dude do we have access to these rooms
and he said no and I said well I got
into this power room right out here so
we walked out to the room and walked in
and I just kind of jokingly said to him
hey you want to send everybody home for
the day
you know uh yeah we're walking right
into one of the sections I'm sure we
wouldn't shut down everything you know
we could have shut down some of the
power
and we've walked into wiring rooms
we walked into the room with the fire
control system which was by the way an
older version of Windows like 95 or
maybe 2000 no password protecting it
at least it wasn't on the Internet or
anything like that but yeah you could
walk up and move the mouse and you got
access to
[Music]
so
and uh yeah my boss that was that was
quite entertaining my boss I say you use
governments okay I let it slipper we
walked into one wiring room and man you
could just watch his face just went from
normal to Red to bright red to like I
thought he was going to pass out or
something
because we were looking various racks
and various different network components
and there were cables connecting
components that shouldn't be connected
view was Joseph
really thought he was going to have a
heart attack or something so
but yeah three guys though sorry you
question
yes
foreign
yes not not a lot but yes I have done
that it's it's been a little while since
I've worked out as well yeah that's
another way to get to boxes here
you talk about a feature that will let
you basically get to the remote box and
run Powershell there
all right
any last questions let's take a break
thank you
foreign
this talk was a part of our 2022 secure
West Virginia Lucky 13 conference if you
would like more information about this
talk or our speaker check the
description below and if you enjoyed the
content consider liking and sharing this
video for more information on secure
West Virginia or you want to stay
updated with the latest upcoming events
follow us on Twitter at secured wvcon or
visit our website securedwv.org
we would like also like to thank our
2022 sponsors for being a huge part of
Lucky 13 success