all right so I am really excited to be
here
um got in uh got in last night and and
just got over here the first thing this
morning and excited to see so many faces
and these kind of events I always enjoy
presenting at uh myself
um I'm also a college professor uh or
adjunct part-time faculty but the
students call me professors so I tell my
parents I'm a professor at a college uh
and uh my mother loves that so she goes
around and tells all of her friends my
son the professor but I'm also the uh
IAC squared Central Florida Chapter
president so I run a chapter in Central
Florida which is where I live down in
Orlando about 30 minutes from the mouse
house so I know what it takes to put on
one of these events so um I got to say
it but a big round of applause for Nick
for uh Bill and everybody
that was a small round but we'll save
the big round for when when I'm done
talking and then you guys can do the big
round that'll be cool uh so I spent uh
18 years working for a little German
company called Siemens I did a lot of
things everything from database
Administration to programming to
networking to network security building
vpns built up our whole infrastructure
for remote access for monitoring our
power plants we're kind of like the
OnStar for power plants back then
and uh got into security and somebody
goes you know you should get your cissp
I went my CI what and that was 14 years
ago and so now I've been working in
security ever since and about three
years ago actually three years ago today
I started at no before so today's my
three year anniversary and I'm hanging
out with all of you so this is great I
this is thank you
[Applause]
let's hope that doesn't keep doing that
um
so yeah with being a no before pretty
well I get to talk about cyber security
all the time every day everywhere I do
it at college with the students kind of
helping that next generation of uh
professionals who in here is a student
not a student alike but a college
student Okay cool so those of you that
had their hand up everybody else make
sure you connect with them because one
of the things that I strive with my
chapter and one of the things we always
talk about is getting connected getting
connected with the people in your
community because you never know who
you're going to meet one day that's
going to help you get that job down the
road because my job at no before is a
result of Eric Crone and Javad Malik
both are other Advocates both came to me
and I've known them for years meeting at
conferences became good friends and they
said hey we have this opening for an
evangelist you want to come and do this
I'm like heck yeah let's go and lo and
behold but because of networking and
getting to know folks and meeting the
people in your community and in this
industry uh it certainly goes a long way
so I encourage all the students in here
get to know the other folks and meant
whether through mentoring or whatever
else so
um I also run a podcast I'm I produce
our security masterminds podcast to know
before lots of fun with that uh our new
episode came out today but I'll talk
about that later on
um of the working Professionals in here
anybody have no before you or use no
before for security awareness training
cool all right
so most or some of you so the rest of
you potential customers great now
um my job is in sales and that's one of
the reasons I love this job is I'm not
here to sell you anything my job here is
to light the firing and what we're
talking about today with regard to
ransomware and Conti but with being at
no before the big thing for me is
enabling people to make smarter security
decisions every day bottom line plain
and simple that's what I want to do
whether it's working professionals
whether it's students whether it's kids
whether it's
we say senior citizens but I like to say
the life experienced because they don't
like being called senior citizens I
guess
but getting them to make smarter
security decisions and so it starts with
all of us and helping educate uh you
know we hear the phrase
humans are the weakest are the weakest
link you know they're always clicking on
links opening up attachments and for me
and I throw this back at it and infosec
folks when they say that is like they're
the biggest attack Vector if you think
they're the weakest link then we're not
educating them enough so
um that's certainly what I try to do
when I'm uh out and about and visiting
so today the the presentation and I've
been told I've got like two and a half
hours which is great because I've got
400 slides to get through no
no
um I've got another 50 minutes to go so
um what we're going to go through and
talk about today is ransomware and
specifically looking at the ransomware
uh that the Conti group we're doing
earlier this year based off of the chat
information that got released and other
information that's been made available
um over the last couple years
and just to give you some insight with
regards to how they do their attacks how
they operate uh Society likes to think
that the hackers and I like to say cyber
criminals because hackers are good
people too
hackers are people that like to take
things apart figure out how they work
and put them back together again
so Society has the stigma of the hackers
or the people sitting in their basement
their parents basements with the hoodies
on and that's certainly not the case
that we've found with regards to conti
and the other cyber criminal groups that
are out there
so when we look at you know kind of The
New Normal when like I said I joined no
before three years ago and it was in
November of 2019 where we started seeing
a shift with regards to ransomware
ransomware has been around since 1989 Dr
Joseph Papp did one where he put out a
um he had a floppy disk those of you I
see some people in here know what a
floppy disk and I think some other
people in here probably were born after
floppy disks uh were stopped being used
but he had a floppy disk and he was
going to a conference it was back then
in the late 80s age was a huge epidemic
going on and he showed up to one of
these conferences he had 50 of these
floppy disks and he showed up to this uh
age conference and he had a document on
there at that point I think it was um it
wasn't word it was Word Perfect doc but
he had written some code that was behind
it that if somebody put the floppy disk
in their computer it would run a program
and it would keep track of how many
times that program ran when the program
got up to about where the application
had been opened the word doc had been
opened about 50 times it he then went
through and encrypted and I do that in
air quotes for a particular reason
because what he did is he just changed
the extensions on all the files so all
the doc or or
WPF files PDF whatever it was it just
changed the extension back in 89 a lot
of people that were just starting to use
computers didn't really have a good
understanding of the extensions and so
they thought their files were encrypted
and he gave you he left you a little
note that said hey if you want your
files decrypted send 400 or 500 to this
PO Box in Panama
and so the first time he went to go
collect his money from the PO Box in
Panama the FBI were waiting for him
uh interestingly enough he got off on an
insanity plea I I'm not he ends up uh he
ended up dying I think about 10 years
ago but he uh ended up doing a whole
study on butterflies after that how he
goes from one to the other but that's
kind of that first case of ransomware
and it's come a long way once we had the
change with
cryptocurrency coming out once Bitcoin
starts coming on the scene cyber
criminals are realizing hey we instead
of using asking for gift cards or asking
for Western Union wire transfers we can
get them to do Bitcoin because at least
then it's not very easily uh can be
traced we can have a certain an amenity
with it and then once we get it in we
can then start moving the money around
between all the different exchanges so
Bitcoin comes in they're using
cryptocurrency now for the ransoms but
even then early 2010s teens they are
encrypting the systems and they're
getting but they're doing it very
quickly they're getting in
they uh they get into the system whether
through RDP whether exposed systems that
are unpatched whether phishing social
engineering
and they get in uh find the data drop
the malware and off they go
some of them were doing it as quick as
30 minutes from time of getting into
dropping the malware the ransomware and
getting out after a while everyone's so
everyone's talking oh my gosh you know
make sure you get your backups make sure
you got your backups have backups and
you'll be all right from ransomware oh
yeah don't forget to test the backups
because a lot of times people would go
and recover from their backups and they
would be missing six months or it would
it would fail on them
so now you've got them coming in it's
more of a nuisance attack with
ransomware because it's it's it you lose
one system or a couple systems then we
get wannacryan 20 2017 and then it
escalates with worms and so they're
getting they're evolving the ransomware
game as they go along
then we get to November of 2019 and we
start seeing a lot of changes there with
Maize with klopp
um Revel was on this was coming on the
scene as well and what ended up
happening was is they were getting into
your system and now they start
exfiltrating your data now they start
looking at okay let's take your data and
hold that for ransom and this evolves
and starts changing the game completely
now we're to the point where they're
doing multiple types of extortions
they're coming in they're stealing the
databases they're stealing client lists
employee information they're going after
c-suite they're actually contacting the
c-suite they're contacting employees
that work for the organization saying
hey we've got your data if you give us
300 bucks we will uh we'll delete the
information
because if the organization's not going
to pay you even had some doctors uh
medical practices it was in South
Florida a plastic surgeon where the uh
the ransomware group got in stole all
the patient information they got like
X-rays and all kinds of sensitive
information and they went to the doctor
and said all right hey you're gonna you
know it's you know three thousand ten
thousand fifty thousand whatever the
ransom was and they didn't want to pay
so then the the Cyber criminal said okay
so then they went after the patients and
they said to the patients we've got all
this data on you and this guy was a
plastic surgeon so no doubt they've got
before and after pictures
and they basically said pay us give us
300 bucks and we'll delete your data and
that's kind of the extent of where they
are now now as we got at the end of last
year with Q4 we saw we started seeing a
decline and everyone's thinking all
right we gotta ransomware beat you know
we'd start to decline and then in the
new year it ran back up again I think
they were just taken off for Christmas
but they they were the increase comes up
but while we're not seeing as many we're
seeing more targeted types of attacks
we're seeing Target specific to
organizations going after supply chain
going after organizations that provide a
lot of services you know we think back
to solarwinds a couple you know right in
the middle of the pandemic uh but the
solar winds with attacking the supply
chain and being able to get into so many
organizations cyber criminals are
starting to do that
as well but what ends up cropping out of
that is what we have is ransomware as a
service you know you've got a lot of a
lot of these different groups that have
the expertise but now you get to the
point where it's like okay I don't need
to know how to you know launch the
ransomware malware I don't need all I
need to do is provide a list of names or
email addresses and they can have the
whole application that can do it so now
it makes it even easier for me to launch
a ransomware attack against an
organization where you've got like menus
and then you've got different tiers that
are set up for those you can sit there
and you know depending on how much money
or how much how much of the program
you're going to use will depend on how
much you get
and you know to the point where it's
like all right we'll get you get 70 of
the money but we're keeping 30 for you
to use the tool
so it makes it a lot easier for the
Cyber criminals out there that don't
need a lot of technical experience a lot
of technical expertise
um and they've even got some of them
even have YouTube videos uh Philadelphia
one of the groups has their own YouTube
video that you can find it was out in
2017 that demoed how to actually use the
program so these groups actually even
have their own marketing folks as well
has anybody experienced the ransomware
attack
that wants to admit it got a couple okay
cool thank you for being honest so what
I'm going to show you here real quick
it's playing good
um this is a video that I recorded it
with my class that I teach and every
semester I do a uh section on ransomware
and I decided one year what happens if I
could you know if I could actually
launch a ransomware attack on my own
virtual machine and show them what it's
like and so that's what I'm doing here
and what you see here in the the folder
in the front is the ransomware samples
that I downloaded out of the through
torrent and I love it I launched the
application and then it goes are you
sure you want to run this because this
doesn't look like it's safe
so I launched the program here at this
point and I've got about 40 gigabytes
worth of data on this hard drive and you
can see the icons and they just changed
so pretty well less than 10 seconds it
took to encrypt the data on this virtual
machine about like I said 40 gigabytes
of data and it goes through
and I actually had a I don't do it in
this video but I actually had a text
file on the desktop that got encrypted I
opened it up and the students could see
yep all the data inside is actually
encrypted you can access it I show them
you get the little ransomware note
because cyber criminals want to get paid
and so there they end up they give you
the note they give you the instructions
they give you the key you got to go get
the tour browser
you got to go get some Bitcoin uh or
ethereum or however they want to get
paid they give you the address and they
give you all that to you I mean it's
more customer service than you get with
some other organizations that are legit
I mean some ransomware groups even have
a online Call Center that you can chat
with people online to get
um to get whatever it is pay up
negotiate or do whatever so pretty well
within about a minute my whole system
has now been infected uh hit with the
ransomware so it moves pretty quick and
when we have dwell times and systems
that are you know 80 days and this gets
done in a matter of minutes so
just wanted to give everybody an Insight
on how quick it actually happens
um there is technology out there you
know the big I know we got sofos here
you know that they can stop a lot of
this you know they see the files
changing so they can stop it on one
system before it spreads and gets around
to other systems so that just to kind of
Baseline everybody there with regards to
ransomware now the title of the
presentation you saw is called uh
ransomware Ransom war and ransomware so
what I'm really curious is does anybody
know how the hackers got away from the
FBI
yeah they ran somewhere
thank you thank you thank you very much
I'll be here all week
um
I'm not going to confirm or deny there's
more of those in this presentation so
you just kind of have to wait and see
all right
and I have plenty more that's inside
this deck I have a whole YouTube channel
of me telling dad jokes so I'll share
that with you at the end as well
um I have a sign in my office at home
that says dad jokes told here and my
daughters gave it to me so it's it's a
you know you know you're doing right
when the kids give you things to support
your crazy habit so anyway so we're
gonna go through we're gonna talk about
Conti kind of they're overviewing their
organization how they uh how they get
things their tactics uh in techniques
and and procedures how they were doing
their ttps and then we'll talk about
some defensive things and also some of
the reasoning behind uh why they did
what they did with regards to
the ransomware attacks so let's look at
Conti overall
Conti is a russian-based
um
cyber criminal group essentially bottom
line plain and simple
um they were making well over a hundred
million dollars a year in the years that
they were operating uh
their biggest Heist I think was 180
million they got out of one organization
with regards to that uh with a lot of
the Cyber criminal groups that are out
there especially in ransomware they all
have particular sectors they like to
Target
when you look at crowdstrike's got a
great map that they have available you
can Google it and go check it out where
it shows all the different groups and
what they like to Target whether it's
energy whether it's in critical
infrastructure whether it's Healthcare
education government systems
each of these different groups have
their own particular sector they like to
Target we'll hit anybody but usually
they find that they will go after a
certain sector to get what they want
with regards to it
what we have here is kind of a breakdown
of how the different groups were doing
monetary wise
Conti basically had over a thousand had
hit over a thousand different
organizations by January of this year
and the payouts were always in the
millions and millions of dollars
um I'm going to talk about a little bit
later on but Costa Rica was one of the
last big ones that they hit
the actual country
uh the government of Costa Rica when we
look at who they were targeting a lot of
the times it was the U.S 50 percent of
the attacks here are looking at U.S
Canada the UK European basically the
West uh there's a statement I'm going to
show you here in a second from them
which kind of explains what they were
doing but when we look at the industry
they were going after manufacturing
legal retail
construction and finance now when we
look at
how organizations do based on a sector
Finance does really really well because
they've been trying to keep the bad guys
cyber criminals out for years because
cyber criminals are in it for one thing
and one thing only and that's to make
money
and so you know why do bank robbers rob
banks because that's where the money is
and so cyber criminals like to go after
the finance that's why we've seen so
many attacks recently on crypto change
extern
crypto exchange uh organizations because
that's where the money is and they can
go in and you know gain access steal
credentials and and look at stealing the
money but for Conti they were going
after the manufacturing organizations
um Law Offices you know a lot of these
these particular sectors don't have
a lot a a deep
um set of Information Security
Professionals in the organization RIT
they might be using an MSP or a managed
service providers
to handle all the I.T and security stuff
uh and so for them they they found that
they were able to get get access into
those particular organizations and so
continue to Target them manufacturing
being the big one so
uh
then on February 24th that's when things
changed as we know that's when we had
the the beginning of the the Ukraine and
or when Russia marched into Ukraine uh
and the start of the
Ukraine Russia War that's going on
the next day we get Conti coming out and
defending Russia and basically saying we
we fully support the Russian government
and what they're doing if anyone attacks
Russia we will strike back
um and
I think there's some people in their
organization weren't too keen on that
but essentially they ended up coming out
the next day and going okay well we're
not allying with any particular
government per se but we are going
against all the Western War mongers
because of what America stands for
later on I'm going to show you a uh an
interview uh with one of with a one of
the ransomware operators
and they have a comment in there which
is hysterical and but I don't want to
spoil the surprise
um so basically they're going through
and they're saying that you know we're
not allying with Russia but we are
against you know anything that goes on
in the west because they don't like it
uh what ends up happening after this
the next day on February 27th is we have
this Twitter account that pops up called
Conti leaks and they basically released
000 uh entries with regards to uh their
chat program their internal chat program
that they used in Conti which was called
Jabber
they released all of it
um and then they started posting all the
files and having links using an
anonymous file service they started
posting all of the the data that was out
there and from that we got a an
excellent glimpse into the world of the
Cyber criminal ransomware operators how
they were operating what they were doing
how they were set up
uh and essentially
um with these 160 000 internal messages
they went all the way back to January of
21 all the way through to pretty well
that day they were able to uh release
all that information along with data
relating to the source code for their
malware uh videos
um pretty well everything that they were
using to operate with regards to their
their environment
so when we look at Conti they were
essentially a ransomware as a service
group they were providing the tools and
capabilities for cyber criminals to
provide the email addresses or the
access into an organization and then
these guys would take over they would or
and they would have their software that
would be able to go in so they were
always managing the malware they had
their ransomware malicious software that
would be in there they were always
updating it because uh as we've seen
pretty well over the years when you've
got cyber criminals coming in with their
antivirus then the patterns get updated
by the antivirus providers the EDR
providers so then they've got to update
so they were it's constantly a cat and
mouse game and so they had people that
were going through and updating that
maintaining the onion website so they
could post all the information that they
had stolen
uh they had their Affiliates you know
you think of this like a business
because that's one of the things that
came out of this was this group operated
like a small to medium business and they
had an HR they had marketing
uh they even had like a partner program
where they'd have a folks affiliated
with them that would go out and get that
access for them
but when we look at a breakdown of the
of the chats and this is kind of like a
mind map of all the different uh
Communications of everybody and what we
had here you have a variety of different
folks you've got Stern
who's doing a lot of the talking in here
and pretty well he was the leader of the
organization and you've got Defender one
of the tech administrators you got
Berkeley who's the developer doing r d
work you had mango who was kind of like
a team lead and then you had Boz who uh
another lead
one of the things that when I first got
into
uh into I.T many many years ago back in
the 90s one of the first jobs I had was
working at a tech call center I worked
for an outsourcer we did tech support
for Dell
and the turnover rate in that place was
quite high but I managed to stay there
for about three years because the
building was only 10 minutes from my
house and any other job I was getting
was always on the other side of town and
not for any more money so I ended up
staying with this organization for about
three years and worked my way up and as
I look at the the business model for
this I see a lot of similarities to what
my time was like working at this call
center working at the Dell tech support
call center
and you know you have these different
groups you have just like any
organization you got an HR you've got
your coders your testers you got your
sys admins you know people that are
maintaining the systems overall with
regards to the web servers and and their
other and their where they're storing
their data
um you get your code reversers you've
got your researchers pen testers you've
got folks that are doing is doing ocean
work and then of course you have your
third party so even these organizations
have third party uh groups they're
working with that handle the spamming
the different uh Bots that we're using
whether it was trickbot arima Tech so
they're collaborating just like a
smaller medium business that we would
have in the everyday world
for me looking at this
when it came to you know these different
groups and looking at it with my
experience at a call center you know you
had people that your level one tax and
then you had your level two text and
then you'd have your level three and the
same thing applies within these
organizations within Conti they had 60
to 100 people
and essentially you would have them
going through and you'd have your one
folks that would get you access into the
organization then you'd have the other
people that would come along and they
would be doing the level one uh
exploitation doing the lateral moves
throughout the network then they would
be doing other you'd have your level
three ones if they ran into a brick wall
and so on and so forth so you've got all
these different levels of expertise uh
as well as recruiting you've got an HR
department going out looking for people
to come and work
and we would always think that oh my
gosh the level of sophistication that
must be on this with regards to these
folks
um isn't as quite as high as we might
think that it is
um this is all information that we're
finding out based within the chats the
communications between the different
groups
and essentially realizing that holy cow
this is just like any other type of
business yeah I apologize the lights
kind of make it difficult to see on the
dark but basically this is a chat one of
the snapshots of the chat but this is
focusing more on where they want to
harvest the data this is early days for
them where they're they just want to get
out there get as much data as they can
rather than targeting specific
organizations
um and their look and basically this was
a conversation with regards to a
particular organization the the name was
mask this came from Orange defense when
they went through and did their analysis
and basically coming back and saying
that
um this particular organization they're
looking just to get as much data as they
can maybe we can get it and then they
decide to move on
it's not all virtual so with this
particular conversation you know
they had offices they're not just all
working from home and sitting in their
parents basements no there were actual
buildings that they had that they would
go to work over the time it was
discovered there were like three or four
different offices and here you have a
conversation by somebody who's texting
in going hey can somebody open the door
hit the door hard
just be careful it's painted don't get
dirty that's the conversation now
granted that's been translated from
Russian but you know trying to get into
the office and you know experience you
know we go up and we badge in and we our
badge doesn't work well they were trying
to open the door and they just have to
bang it hard
um the other one is uh like talking to
your mom she's a big romantic uh big
smiley face in general we were impressed
by the meeting so you know everyday
conversations that we would see even in
our own work environment are certainly
happening uh within the the group as
well
here we have another conversation
um
since you didn't know about the band
they didn't issue a fine next time I
will issue okay but it's not a hospital
so here we have them targeting
particular hospitals and I remember in
Coven I think folks may remember as well
you had certain cyber criminal groups
that were saying okay we're not going
after the healthcare organizations
because they're making the working on
the vaccine for us so that we don't get
sick
but then you still had other cyber
criminal groups that didn't care because
they they enjoyed that was their sector
that they went after they went after the
health care and
um this one within this conversation
we're seeing that well they're not
really resuscitation it's a sports
hospital so it's not you know working on
the vaccine kind of thing
um but we studied them you know when
they go through and they end up figuring
out which group that they've got in so
if they find out an organization that
they've gained access into they have a
whole other department that does all the
oceans the open source intelligence form
and basically what they're doing is
looking at that organization looking at
who works there they're looking at what
their profit loss is or looking you know
looking up information on Google using
all the open uh information that's
available online and figuring out about
as much information about the
organization so they know how much they
can charge them when they hit them with
the ransomware
down in Broward county in Florida
uh I I don't think it was Conti but
there was another ransomware group that
hit him up and wanted to charge them I
think it was four million dollars and
this was a school system and they had
seen that the budget for the school was
about 400 million and so I'm sorry it
was 40 million because it was 10 percent
they were hitting them up for 40 million
so when they bring in the lawyers and
the third party organizations they're
negotiating with the Cyber with the
Cyber criminal group and they're saying
look we can't pay you 40 million dollars
we don't have it and they came back and
said look here's all your information we
have about you we know you have a 400
million dollar budget that you work from
every year
you can pay us the 40 million they ended
up negotiating it down believe it or not
down to about four hundred thousand
dollars
because they had to show and work they
had their lawyers they had uh some other
Security Professionals in there
negotiating with the the Cyber criminal
group again they're just wanting to get
paid but they were able to negotiate
because pretty well yeah they may have a
400 000 budget but they don't have a
surplus they're not a profit making
organizations so granted while the Cyber
criminal group knew it was a school they
they were hoping to you know get as much
as they could out of them
now with regards to Conti one of the fun
one of my favorite quotes that came out
was our good friend Brian Krebs
um Conti is a highly effective if also
remarkably ineffect inefficient cyber
criminal organization so you've got this
organization that is sophisticated
they're getting in they're encrypting
data they're making all this money but
their back office wasn't as good
they had systems that were expiring
hello we're out of Bitcoins four new
servers three VPN subscriptions and 22
renewals are out please send some
Bitcoins to this wallet you have that
coming from Carter they didn't have a
lot of workflow management you know they
had all these systems that were standing
up they were probably spending a lot
more money than they needed to because
they weren't really aware that they were
past due on some of the servers on the
domain registrations uh because a lot of
the time they would create fake domains
for the fishing campaigns for the
different organizations and so what
we're seeing here is
and there's it was the uh the other one
that's on there as well the another
server you left up it effed me up you
know 100 fine
within the within the kanji group you
would be fined if you did something
wrong you know we do something wrong in
our organization okay our manager might
pull us in give us a talking to and send
us on don't do it again you might get
something written in your permanent
record
they were finding their employees
imagine what if we find our employees
you know how much more productivity
might happen but
they're going through and finding the
employees this one was a hundred dollar
fine for that and those fines would all
get put into for bonuses
which is what we see here them talking
about the
um
you know this month three people were
fined for absenteeism and various
mistakes that led to losses these fines
will go to the bonus fund for employees
at the end of the month so the employees
that are doing the work right the the 60
to 100 people they're doing the work
right they're going to get the bonus
whereas you've got other people that are
slacking off they're not coming into
work you know kind of like the same
problems that we have in our
environments here I know working at the
call center uh my last year that I
worked there I worked my way up to
management I think because I was the
only one that was still around after
three years
and I just remember the hiring and
firing process of that you would have
people that just didn't care it was a
job it wasn't a career for them and so
they essentially were you know didn't
want to come into work but they would be
uh fined on a regular basis so
we see that morale is off within these
organizations we've got people that that
you know like to work you got people
that don't like to work you know
Saturday will be a day off same as
Sunday woohoo hooray you know we and
then they've got you know all the
exclamation marks
the the interesting thing that came out
of Bentley Bentley's one of the coders
that's in this group and he said our
work is you know generally not difficult
but it's monotonous so it's very tedious
so doing the same thing over and over
and over every day and that certainly
gets to be
um draining on them
as you know they're making all this
money but the work is tedious it takes a
lot out of them and uh certainly get a
level of frustration that comes from
them from everybody that's in there
with regards to Bentley you know he was
always the one that was making sure that
the code was up to date making sure that
they were using the latest malware
making sure they were evading the
systems because one of the things when
you when you first get into one of these
environments one of the and I realized
this when I was doing my own experiment
with ransomware
especially on the older malware samples
they automatically get detected by
Microsoft Defender did on my Windows
machine and it basically quarantined all
my ransomware samples so then I had to
go back out and re-download them so then
before I realized I wanted to launch the
ransomware I had to figure out okay how
do I disable the antivirus so then I
went out and Googled disabled Microsoft
Defender code and I found a Powershell
script that I was able to run and it
disabled it and even on a reboot it
disabled it again so
that's what they were doing and you know
having to constantly evolve and keep up
with uh between the you know the the
technology that was going on and be able
to keep their systems running
so basically you know Conti in here you
know 2.7 billion dollars is what they
accrued over the uh 2017. the biggest
one they got the biggest Heist that they
got was 180 million dollars from one
particular organization they had about
60 to 100 employees working there uh
they were paid anywhere between a
thousand to two thousand in Bitcoin
deposits a month
so but over in Russia a thousand two
thousand dollars is probably a lot of
money because the folks that were
working there were working making more
money uh as workers than they would
working anywhere else
I have to imagine the the upper folks
Bentley Stern mango and all them they
were bringing in the millions
um but they were had a tight
collaboration with the imitet folks they
were using their uh criminal platforms
as well they were constantly having to
maintain and update their infrastructure
and they were using a lot of commercial
tools and I'm going to go into those
here in just a minute but they were
using services and a variety of
different tools throughout
um the whole time they were running now
with all of this cyber crime one of the
things that's always kind of uh
perplexed me is the fact that why hasn't
Superman helped us fight any of this
cyber crime
because he's afraid of crypto currency
I warned you
okay so let's talk about tactics
techniques and procedures
let's see where is it here it is so I
have one of these cool little SanDisk
one terabyte hard drives and on this is
about 50 gigs worth of all the Conti
data
when I got my hands on the Conti data I
got my the first thing I got my hands on
last year was their playbook it was
posted on the dark web I
came across it and downloaded it
and I'm going to show you some of the
pages from that but when they had the
massive once you had all the files come
out with debris with their breach along
with the chats there was also this
directory that had a whole bunch of you
had cracked 2019 crack in Russian the
adminasplate for U.S in English
Metasploit and Russian you had Network
pen testing Cobalt strike uh Windows red
teaming wmi attacks attacking SQL
servers going after active directory and
then there was a arrange program
this these were training videos that
were on their servers that were from the
pen testing Academy you can actually go
out and see them the interesting thing
that they'd done here was
they had overdubbed it in Russian so
they're bringing in people that have I
have to imagine a limited commute amount
of computer experience they may be just
everyday folks that know how to use a
computer and they're bringing them in
and they're training them these are
those entry level uh cyber criminals
essentially uh that they are
um targeting one of the they've even got
a whole thing on Cobalt strike how to
use Cobalt strike they have that
training video that's in there
um interesting thing about Cobalt strike
it's not cheap and they invested through
the chats it was discovered that Conti
invested about sixty thousand dollars in
Cobalt strike which when they're
bringing in 108 100 million on average
with these organizations it's a drop in
the bucket
but the licenses they got uh they ended
up spending 30 000 on the licenses they
gave another thirty thousand to the
organization to front them to get the
licenses so they're using the same tools
that pen testers are using uh and going
through and then when they're bringing
in their new recruits they're getting
they're putting them in front of the
training videos and watching hours and
hours and hours of training videos from
the pen testing Academy
now when we look at how they did their
attacks you know we can always look at
the Lockheed Martin cyber kill chain you
know and they do the reconnaissance so
they go through and do their initial
investigations they're going through and
looking at you know how are they getting
in the number one way and like you know
even from our own experience social
engineering is kind of the common way
that they get in or they're going into
remote desktop because of covid you had
so and I think a lot of us are going to
probably be able to relate when covet
hit and everybody had to start working
from home we needed to be able to access
the system so they put a whole lot of
RDP on the internet
uh one of the other fun things I like
doing with my students is showing them
show Dan and we do uh when we talk about
ocean and I bring up Showdown every
semester and we do a search for TCP 3389
RDP the remote desktop protocol and it's
always interesting to see how many
connections there are online last check
there was about 4.6 million RDP sessions
connected uh on the internet
one and a half of those belonged here in
the U.S and of those a bunch of them are
Google sorry Amazon
and so they they love going so right out
of the gate you've got a million and a
half servers four and a half globally
that cyber criminals can go after uh
password guessing they're doing you know
password credential stuffing or they're
exploiting uh systems overall once they
get in now they've turned it over to
their next level of text they're looking
at maintaining persistence they're using
other tools to keep that access and be
able to go back in and then start
looking at exfiltrating the data once
and usually they're in there for about
80 Days
afterward they run their ransomware
their exploit and then hit them with the
note and wait for payment
now this is out of the hackers quick
start guide that they had in part of
their documentation and the Highlight
that I'm showing here yeah good it says
I.T professionals with no such
experience
so they're pretty well got folks that
you know aren't familiar with using it
almost any network can be hacked
and if there are no known
vulnerabilities in the entry points
found then you got to look for other
ways so you're going through social
engineering but they would always be
trying the vulnerabilities first that
was their first part so once they get
access they're looking at initial access
with phishing you know compromised o365
accounts we have the comb that has also
been discovered at this time your uh
your collection of massive breaches
where it's 8 billion passwords over four
billion usernames accounts passwords
driver's license and so forth they're
using those to try and gain access which
is what happened with the colonial
ransomware attack last year as well as
the city of Oldsmar those were done with
credential stuffing they might be doing
fishing the voicemail phishing um or
they're using software
um to get promotion through SEO and then
looking at other common vulnerabilities
when they go through and execute they're
basically looking for domain admins
they're looking for the active directory
systems they're disabling Windows
Defender and any other EDR software they
can get they'll even use Kerberos so
that's targeting the Kerberos
authentication system uh bypassing that
using other you know living off the land
they're using other proper services and
applications that are out there system
journals mini cats but the the three
exploits listed here you've got the SMB
print Nightmare and xero logon those
were their favorite exploits to go after
when they were getting in organizations
to take advantage of
because a lot of times folks hadn't had
those patched yet so here's one of the
pages out of the Conte Playbook and the
first thing up at the top is talking
about doing that research then doing a
dump of the shares what kind of what
once they're in on that one system what
are they connected to going from there
and then further pursuing Kerberos
attacks getting to the ad running
getting the password hashes doing
mimikats
um and then just it's literally step by
step of what they need to do to gain
access into the environment then they're
looking at destroying the backups
because we always said from the FBI all
the way to every other cyber security
professional make sure you got backups
make sure you test them well then they
were going through and looking for those
backups and and essentially deleting
them and getting rid of them uh and that
would all happen just before the
encryption part would happen
so other tools uh Cobalt strike was the
big one they even had their own scripts
that they had written uh you had active
directory find ad find Power view router
scan looking for routers and trying to
log in on there use they've got their
own SQL injection tools ngrok is a
reverse proxy for remote desktop
connections any desk which is a remote
control software of course they're using
Tor and they're using Metasploit they
even wrote their own Metasploit scripts
as well uh the Alias RC basically
allowed them to generate other
exploitation tools to run all at once so
they had the sophistication of the tools
and the technology as well as using
Cobalt strike
it got to the point where they were
generating all kinds of money that you
had the developers they wanted to train
their own Forum environment they wanted
to create in their own Dark Net maybe
even consider doing their own crypto
overall and so with all the money
they've been making that was kind of
their where their next step where they
had planned on going
uh but by
early 20 once the uh they came out in
2022 uh and with some of the other
attacks they ended up um having to put
all that uh to the side
but with all these you know they're
doing all these attacks and you've got
all these against
um the websites you know trying to
create their own form and everything
else in the website
um I I'm just I've always wondered does
anybody know where you take a web page
when it's sick
the urologist
I heard one clap that's good that was
good
they clapped and went uh no no that
wasn't funny no no
okay so I got about 10 minutes left
let's talk about some of the defensive
techniques and some of the other things
going on
so towards the uh this well it was this
year in April you have Conti you know
they've come out in
um they come out in February and say hey
we're you know we're against the West
we're you know don't we're kind of
allying with Russia or not but in April
they target the con the Costa Rican
government 30 different systems 30
different institutions they targeted
they got access into their systems their
web pages their social media uh they
ended up having to pretty well shut down
all their computer systems in the
government
and uh they even had a change in
presidents and he comes out after uh a
month of dealing with this and trying to
recover and basically declares war on
Conti
fast forward another month and the Biden
Administration comes out and offers 10
million dollars for information leading
to these to people that are involved
with Conti with the different groups
um key positions with Conte hey we want
you to you know five million dollars for
those
so and what we've seen in the past with
other cyber criminal groups is they
disbanded and that's what ended up
happening to Conti in May of this year
but it's kind of interesting because now
you've got all these people that have
worked underneath Stern and mango and
and Bentley and now they're all working
at all these other cyber criminal groups
like avos Locker Hive black cat so it's
taking that knowledge and expanding it
and passing it on so while Conti the
name itself is gone because now the
kanji doesn't exist you can't go after
Conti people because they're not with
Conti they're with these other groups
um and then you get all these other
groups that are uh growing as well and
essentially we're dealing with a crime
of extortion and it's the how is
secondary how they're doing it it's the
fact that they want to continue to
evolve and grow
because essentially I already said it is
the fact that they do this for one thing
and one thing only that's to make money
granted it's Bitcoin a lot of the time
but they're going through making money
but when we look at kind of a psychology
of them
while they're targeting the West for
them they feel like they're doing right
I don't condone it but they're they've
got they've got a business they're
running they are you know the the intent
that they have is hey if those
organizations in the west aren't
securing their networks and we can get
in well that's on them that's not us
also their charitable giving hey we're
taking the money that we're stealing
from them and we're giving it to people
that need it
um and we look at the distance
innovation
factor it's their war against the West
they're targeting it they feel like
they're unadjusted cause
now there was an interview on VX
underground I don't know if anybody's
ever seen their site but they've got
lots of malware samples and uh cool
stuff but they had an interview with an
actual ransomware operator they verified
it was who they were but they disguised
the name
but this was out of that interview this
was kind of a breakdown of their profile
their assist admin hi Nick
um they're uh they were arrogant to
being captured they weren't worried
about the FBI capturing them they were
more worried about Mandy and finding
them so it goes a lot to say about
mandian they were a pen tester they were
consultant they negotiated they were one
of the negotiators on the other end
um what cracked me up and it was at the
end of the interview throughout the
whole interview they're saying how much
they hate America they hate Americans
we're arrogant and everything else but
at the end the interviewer goes is there
anything you'd wish for wish that your
how your life had been and they go I
wish I was born in America because I
probably would be working at a company
like Google right now
and I I just it just blew me away but
that again it goes to that mentality of
of how they were and what they were
doing
uh over there but you can find that on
vx-underground.org
so we actually got some advice from
conti and this was uh through some of
the conversations uh with regards to one
of the attacks restrict access to
servers for regular users because they
were basically getting in on one person
system and then working their way over
to an actual server that like an active
domain controller or something else
whether you're able to gain access they
talk about use different passwords
because a lot of the times they may have
been using a shared password or a common
password in which case once they figured
out the one they were able to use it for
all the others make sure EDR is
installed on every computer whether you
know pick your flavor set up more of a
complex storage system don't make it all
on one flat Network and protect your
lsas dump on all your computers that's
coming from Conti you know and from
cyber Security Professionals we're going
around and we're talking you know make
sure you got your backups do this do
that they're coming in they're getting
specific because they're getting
specific because this is how they're
getting in every single time
and of course when we end up they even
talk about checking your admins activity
once a week because they're able to
create their own admin account or
they're able to take over one of the
admin accounts and if you're not
checking that activity
um you'd certainly miss something
so in the event that you do get hit with
ransomware you know we always say you
can restore from a backup decrypt your
files using a third party which by the
way the when I encrypted my files I got
my hands on the decrypter just in case I
really screwed something up but I didn't
thank goodness
um it took five hours to decrypt the
encrypted files 10 seconds to a minute
to encrypt it and over five hours to
decrypt that 40 gig
um you can do nothing lose all your data
start all over kind of like what
happened in the LA School District or
you negotiate and pay the ransom
but when we look at the best practices
we always talk about training users and
they even said it as well train you
train the people that work there to be
able to spot those fishing tests
um and if you need a company to do
security awareness and training I know a
really good one
uh backups talked about that segment the
network don't have that flat Network
figure out what your critical assets are
within your organization isolate those
protect that with MFA additional
firewalls reduce the access for your
users you know principal at least
privilege
remove Internet facing RDP put it behind
a firewall use a VPN but having it
sitting right directly on the Internet
is just an invite for them to come in
keep up with patches as we saw you know
you got Conte you like to use those
three particular ones and they were they
were successful for them
and uh incident response and tabletop
exercises this is a great way to be able
to a get everybody on board but get
everybody in the organization that's
going to be involved in that incident
response whether your PR team your CEO
um the CSO I.T managers the business
getting them together making sure that
everybody understands what the plan is
and being able to move forward
I've had Insurance on here for a while
I'm thinking I may have to take it off
again because I know insurance is not as
lucrative as it used to be and it's a
lot harder but
um because I remember in 2020 2021 that
was kind of thing go get insurance and
then they'll pay the ransom and so then
the Cyber criminals said okay let's go
after the insurance companies and then
they got a whole list of new people to
go Target so so as we look at all you
know we deal with these computers on the
systems and the computers on a daily
basis
um anybody know what you call a computer
that sings
Adele
got a couple more laughs on that one all
right so some additional resources as I
wrap up here before we take any
questions so Shameless plug no before
um we have our ransomware hostage rescue
manual so in the event you get hit
hopefully you already have your plan in
place but we do have a hustard rescue
manual kind of take you through the
steps but a good book a great book out
there ransomware uh what do you call it
a protection Playbook written by Roger
Grimes I work with Roger just to be
transparent but it's a great book I got
to Tech edit it uh really great
information in there but as we look at
ransomware and we continue you know with
what we've got in our homes is this
what's next you know are they going to
start targeting all the iot devices in
our home our fridges our stoves the
cameras we've seen attacks on the
cameras already but you know this fun
little comic of um you know if you um
if you don't uh if you don't pay up the
ransom we're going to leave the heat on
in the middle of the summer
so I don't know if anybody heard but
Spider-Man and Wonder Woman are going
into business together
their serve their business
it's called
Amazon web services
so there you go so
um I do have a I produce a podcast with
no before I'm not the host I'm the just
the guy behind the scenes paying no
attention to the man behind the curtain
I have more fun producing it anyway
because I get to work with all these uh
awesome guests that we've had new
episode came out this morning you can
find it on all your favorite podcasting
platforms but we interviewed Tanya Jenka
who is
um she hacks purple
in the community absec we had a guy last
month uh Jean-Michel as a party excuse
me blockchain fantastic uh thing on
blockchain and we've had other folks
stealing and storytelling security
culture so um that's my Shameless plug
to go check it out like I said new
episode dropped today so I want to thank
you all for your attention and uh time
this morning and I again appreciate the
opportunity to come and speak and
um I think do we have time for questions
yeah okay in the back
the problem
basically
yeah no you bring up you bring up a good
point and I think if they hadn't
disbanded and they still may be working
towards doing it
um you know they're always working on
things they've still got all their money
um we could see something like that we
could see some I mean it would be you
know the sheep and the wolf's clothing
of you know hey you know we're launching
the ransomware but we can tell you how
to you know fix it
um but they're like I said they're
constantly evolving their their code as
well and so they may be the ones making
it available for having the other
decrypters because we've seen with other
cyber criminal groups when they've
attacked them or they've broken up that
their decryptors have been posted online
as well but that is certainly uh one
option that may occur we still may see a
different kind of dark net form
um or they come up with their own
cryptocurrency
oh
and that's a possibility as well yeah
yes sir
happens
yeah they're basically helping you cover
the costs
right
um
I'll admit I don't have a strong opinion
on it
um I think you know essentially we're
dealing with organizations that you know
get caught with their pants down so to
speak and nobody wants that I gave a
similar talk at Gartner the other day
and I was chatting with folks afterward
and you know on I generally was asking
what is it that scares you about
ransomware we know what we need to do
but is you know it's a fear of getting
hit even though you've got all this uh
set up and so you have the insurance to
protect you just in case it does happen
because we all know anything in security
is not a hundred percent so you're
always having that risk that's there so
whether using an escrow or you've got
insurance or you've got some other way
to help carry that load
um yeah I have to imagine that the the
fear is certainly around you know
getting hit and then not knowing what to
do well not knowing what to do I think a
lot of us you know
those that are in that position that
they can go through and plan and have
that Playbook and and be prepared and
and go through those exercises that
takes care a lot of that so in the event
it does happen you know do you have the
technology that can help spot it and
stop it you know uh those kind of things
so
I wasn't kidding I do have a YouTube
channel
where I have my dad joke videos so
cool
alrighty well it's 11 o'clock on my
clock I don't know where Nick went I
don't know if he's coming back up or did
he just leave me here
um
let's see what else anybody know why you
can't use the word beef stew as a
password
it's not stroganoff
um who are my windows users in here
handful okay you know what a computer
and an air conditioner both have in
common
they're both useless when you open
windows
so here's one here's here's one for that
uh
anybody know who owned the first
computer
it was Adam and Eve it was an apple
it had one bite low memory and then the
whole thing crashed
yeah that's a good one yeah so cool all
right well thank you very much I'll be
around this weekend
[Applause]
thank you for the big round of applause
this talk was a part of our 2022 secure
West Virginia Lucky 13 conference if you
would like more information about this
talk or our speaker check the
description below and if you enjoyed the
content consider liking and sharing this
video for more information on secure
West Virginia or you want to stay
updated with the latest upcoming events
follow us on Twitter at secured wvcon or
visit our website securedwv.org
we would like also like to thank our
2022 sponsors for being a huge part of
Lucky 13 success