him Kick It Off
well thank you very much once again
thank you to you and your entire staff
for all the work that goes in to running
this great event I only wish I could
have been there in person unfortunately
I caught a con crud and so alas here I
am going through and presenting remotely
So today we're going to start to talk
about uh how the Galactic Empire from
Star Wars was actually destroyed by a
bad data governance program a little bit
about me I met Michael K Brown on
Twitter uh most importantly this
presentation as well as many of my
others are published on my github.com
Micah K Brown GitHub site so please feel
free to reach out I'd love to continue
this conversation here there anywhere
with that being said
whether you're a purist and you go back
to the original Origins and dark Forces
in Kyle katarn or whether you go through
and you follow Rogue one
the reason that the Rebel Alliance was
able to survive the Battle of Yavin IV
was because they had access to stolen
Death
Star plans
where's my proof it's right here in the
episode for opening crawl
right here during the battle the rebel
spies managed to steal a secret plan to
the Empire's Ultimate Weapon the Death
Star an armored space station with
enough power to destroy an entire planet
so if we are going to go through and ask
ourselves
who was this secret Rebel hero
that allowed the Death Star plans to
East Holland I'd uh I'd go through
another start that'd be someone like
this a common everyday I.T security
practitioner data analyst that struggles
to find a work-life bounce this person
probably struggles to get the correct
tools resources and visibility into
their environment so that they can
protect the Galactic Empire and the
citizens they're in so he has challenges
such as separating the signal from the
jam he's responsible for articulating
deeply technical issues such as the
bleeps the sweeps and the creeps to
others and they have challenges
communicating gaps concerns to Imperial
officers or in our world Senior
Management
also besides Chewbacca Michael Winslow
also deserves a medal
so this brings me to what is data
government anyway
these four different definitions one
from Wikipedia one from a group
dgpo.org another one from ibm.com and
another one from
nist.org.gov and if you were to go
through and read and evaluate each one
of these you'll see there's a lot of
similarities and there's also a lot of
differences
so for the purpose of this talk what
does data governance mean to me well
data government means different things
to different people it allows the
business to decide what data government
needs for itself so it generally
involves people processes and
Technologies not necessarily in that
order it allows the business to make
strategic decisions on how data is
stored processed and transmitted within
its environments and it should go
through and optimize the confidentiality
integrity and availability of data
within your organization quite frankly
data governance is how we decide to
decide on data issues
so I love this visualization coming from
nist where it clearly shows that data
governance
is
it's a higher level in terms it's the 10
000 foot view that is meant to help
guide and direct your actions
so putting it together when I think
about my organization I'm a very large
Financial
I go through and I realize that we have
many stakeholders that are motivated by
both external and internal resources so
external things that we might be
motivated are are rules laws regulations
contractual agreements and that might
Force our internal stakeholders business
management I.T security and legal to
create a data governance plan now that
data government plan program bonuses
focuses on topics such as ownership
accessibility security integrity and
self-knowledge of how we
use and work with data in our
environment these are expressed in
policies processes and procedures and
actually manifest in what I call
actionable data governance Technologies
so what are our goals and why would we
spend time money and resources
formalizing a formal data governance
program number one we want to enable
better decision making we want to reduce
operational friction we want to train
managers and staff to adopt common
approaches to Common data issues we want
to build standard and repeatable
processes and procedures that ultimately
are going to reduce cost and increase
efficiency through our coordination of
efforts as well as we want to be open
and transparent we want to make sure
that we are conducting ourselves with a
high level of Integrity both to internal
and external re or stakeholders
so
I've talked a little bit about it active
or an actual data governance tool what
is it well that's any tool that an
organization use to help support a data
governance program and generally these
tools can take some action so they can
just permit an action to go through they
could permission with a special
condition such as requiring a digital
signature or requiring that appearance
of information be strongly encrypted
before say it is sent outside it could
go through and it could allow the user
to put a justification on why they're
taking this action and then allowing it
it could go through and permit and
create an alert or it could deny with an
alert or deny without alert an alert to
you know so based on what tool you're
using different actions are going to be
available I just wanted to give you some
actions
so has anyone played Zelda I loved Zelda
still to this day and when we're talking
about data government the tree the three
triforces are being able to create
policies on how data is stored how data
is processed and how data is transmitted
but there's a fourth hidden Triforce and
that really is identity and access
management to me and why I say that it
is a pillar within data governance is
our tools are going to be making the
fundamental assumption that any action
its species being taken by a specific
user or an entity is that user or entity
actually doing that so we need to be
aware that in order to have a good data
governance program we need to have a
really good identity and access
management program within our
environment
and one thing that if you attend any of
my talks
this is a very common meme there are no
false positives there's only poorly
written rules and this is very well true
in a data governance in a DLP and I'll
show you some examples of that uh here
in a little bit
so
when I was creating this I wanted to be
able to give the guidance I'm from the
Cincinnati area I volunteer with the
Greater Cincinnati Issa and we often
have a lot of smaller or medium sized
businesses you know businesses where
they have a small it program or an I.T
person that facilitates all of it all of
it security and I wanted to be able to
provide them guidance from a from a data
governance perspective and so I adopted
what was done with the old CIF standards
and where I wanted to have basic
controls I.E the do these first the
foundational do these next and then the
organizational which are the really hard
data governance tools to go through into
leverage so we're going to talk about
each of those in a moment
this is another way to go through and to
view it on the top of green
we have what degree of an administrator
rights you need on each type of systems
the type of systems is in the gray box
below and then I've added whether in
general this technology can do a block
alert or an enforce policy depending on
the vendors that you're using they might
be able to do more or less but this is
just basically to give a quick
visualization of where each technology
fits in against different asset types
so let's talk about the basic controls
the first thing that we really need to
get under control is the basics and one
of the the some or one of the hardest
things that I have to do is a very large
organization I have over 40 000 users
I'm trying to protect day in day out
across all seven continents and one of
the hardest things that I have to do is
to do the simple things at scale
so we need to make sure that we're doing
best practices across our traditional
Network we need to find ways to automate
and test basic controls basic
functionality whether that's firewall
rules VLAN restrictions particles
protocols that are known to be abused
often
one thing that I've often found is we
can film a whole lot of time building up
a really good secure environment whether
it's a CDE whether it's a guest wireless
network whether it's our own internal
network but if we don't go through and
we aren't constantly testing and
validating those environments have a
tendency to erode into security and that
can be a huge deal especially as you're
going through and working to establish a
data governance function so this is
where
they will you want to go through and we
want to make sure that we're doing the
basics on our Network and our general
infrastructure make sure that we have a
secure Foundation that we're building
off of
next it comes down to file and disk
encryption as well as Key Management
when it comes to encryption you can only
be as strong as your key management so
we need to make sure especially those
private keys that we're protecting them
that if they are lost we can go revoke
them that we can quickly spin up new
certificates and get back to a good
place now strong encryption of the
client system is definitely best
practice we see now both Microsoft and
Apple have really normalized encryption
across most devices in a very seamless
way
inside work with a global
organization I understand that there are
different rules laws regulations that
are in force in different areas of the
world and we need to be respectful of
those countries and those laws that we
operate Within
another thing that I've noticed is that
it might sound very attractive as to us
as I.T security people to go through and
to turn on Advanced encryption such as
fips 140 however most times I see a
commercial solution allows you to enable
fips 140. it comes to or it comes at a
cost of certain functional capabilities
and it might make some tasks just a
little bit harder I'm not saying it's
not a good thing to turn on fips 140 if
you have to have it you have to have it
but just keep in mind that there might
be a little bit more of an
administrative overhead if it if you
choose to turn it on and you're not
required
now encryption of files written to
portable media is often thought of as a
very popular control after all we don't
want our data leaving our laptops in an
unauthorized fashion however we need to
be very careful on how we do that I have
a friend that they rolled out a rule
that any piece of portable media got
bitlockered
and unfortunately they took out all of
the at the time that organization had a
lot of remote claims work so they would
send people out on site to take pictures
of various insurance claim
and they had to go through after about
200 of these GPS devices were bricked
when people plugged them in to try to go
through and update the maps on them
so just be be aware of those types of
use cases also I do not want to be the
person that uh is responding because a
an employee came back from maternity
paternity leave and they brought a
thumbstick that had you know pictures of
the new baby that they wanted to share
with the rest of the organization and
oops we encrypted that person's personal
drive so we want to be
able to make sure that we are doing
things in accordance
with our strategic views as well as we
are educating our users so that they
know that if they do plug in a personal
device
what exactly is going to happen to try
to minimize loss of personal data
and all encrypting files at the network
or share level might seem attractive
please keep in mind Key Management how
is the keys going to be stored process
transmitted so that we don't have
unintentional
leaks
so finally violent Integrity monitoring
so there's many different way or vendors
that do file an Integrity monitoring and
truth be told this is saved so a lot of
people that I've known a lot of times so
in general these systems will go through
and you'll point them at either various
servers or data repositories and these
systems will
record every user as they make any
changes any additions any ads any
deletes and they'll basically create a
record of who what where when why many
of these systems have the ability either
to Archive Shadow copies to make
restores very easy
but they also have other things where a
lot of them are going through and adding
end user Behavior end user behavioral
analytics so if a user
generally stays in the engineering
folder on the share but they never touch
the HR well it's kind of odd if they
start going through and touching HR and
pulling
up 100 files for example that might be
something that we might find as odd and
we might want to investigate so that's
some pretty cool functionality that you
can get out of here but where I've seen
a lot of use cases
is with ransomware
a an organization gets hit with the
ransomware if they have a file an
Integrity monitor they can go through
and they can see
show me all files that have the dot
encrypted or whatever extension it adds
to the end of the encrypted files and
they can see exactly what computer what
user touched that specific file that
makes it very easy to identify at least
the initial in or one of the initial
encrypting device where we can go
through isolate that get it off the
network start doing a root cause
analysis but we can also go through and
ask these types of systems show me all
of the files that have the dot encrypted
or whatever extension they're using
across your entire environment now that
makes it very easy for us to then go
through
and to take that list and to give that
to the backup team so the backup team
knows exactly what tapes they need to
recall so that we can respond quickly so
this these file and integrity monitors
they're really they've saved many of my
colleagues bacon quite a bit and there
are definitely a good thing to look into
so now let's look at the foundational or
the middle level types of actual data
governance tools the first one is mobile
device management so mobile device
management as I really saw come out of
the bring your own devices movement and
it's great for that whether you're using
a very well known Cloud solution or if
you're running one on your own campus
MDM has definitely made an inroad in
allowing greater flexibility for us as
it Security Professionals and for our
Workforce but lately I've been seeing
MDM move into another section and that's
either non-standard or lightweight
company owned devices where the device
actually owns to the company and whether
it's tablets cell phones or even Ultra
lightweight laptops or mobile systems I
really see the Enterprise adoption of it
MD I'm significantly deep or ticking up
in the case of BYOD and non-trusted
external devices we need to respect
that we are guests on that client system
that the
owner is truly the owner of those
systems we need to go through and make
sure enrollment is just as graceful
as the enrollment we need to make sure
that we are clear and concise
on what we are doing on that environment
and what rights they are giving us
access to
and one thing I'm always hesitant of I
have no problem
wiping the MDM space that we create on a
BYOD but I'm very hesitant even if I
have the user making the request of
going through and wiping the entire
device even if we do have the
capabilities so I would definitely go
through
and talk to legal on that case and make
sure that we have the appropriate ways
in which a user could request a full
Erasure if that's what they truly want
to do
next is identity and access management
and I've had many people rightly Heckle
me that identity and access management
is outside the sphere of data governance
however almost all of the decisions that
are actual data governance tools are
going through and taking are based on
the assumption that the user that that
tool sees is the actual original user
or entity that is making that request
it's not always so I've set in on a
couple red team classes I understand
how people can go through and can move
laterally in the environment I
understand how people can go through it
can impersonate processes and or other
user accounts so having a very strong
identity and access management makes it
so that that our actual data governance
intelligence the signals the alerts that
we're getting out of there are going to
be much more strong have much more
greater integrity
so the risks are not limited to just the
user idea I've seen a lot of compromises
going through and starting to abuse
machine accounts and it's only common to
go through and to see that as well as
there are several different attacks to
try to go through and to
circumvent multi-factor authentication
in fact there's a very well-known attack
where the attacker just spammed a person
50 60 75 different multi-factor
authentication requests until the user
finally got quiet and clicked yes it's
me
about starting about 2018 maybe a little
bit before that a very common thread
came to be that active directory is
insecure by default and I've provided a
couple different uh sites for you that
you can look up and
for what they were going through and
addressing they were right and many of
my colleagues that have gone through and
have
had to remediate the this these types of
insecurities I've had to go through a
full domain Forest migration and team
that's a lot of work to go through and
to do but it's important that you
understand especially from an identity
and access management request what your
domain functionality level what it can
do and what it can't do so that we can
go through and we can make Intelligent
Decisions as we go through and
constantly work to increase the security
of our organizations
so data classifications this is one of
the things that is the hardest for many
organizations to do is to really un be
able to understand
programmatically intelligently what data
they are working with and where it
resides in their environment and so when
you're dealing with data classifications
you have two main types of data
classification so you have traditional
data classification which is based on a
series of data objects such as text
dictionaries regular Expressions pattern
matching and Boolean logic and this can
be challenging why because well there's
many different versions of reg X and so
some tools will use a
very specific version of
my apologies like can you still see my
screen
okay because my screen just went black
so I'll continue on so with
different tools understanding different
regular expression dictionaries that can
make it very difficult for us to
actually go through and to ensure that
our data classifications are very
similar often
it is very difficult to move
data classifications from one system to
another
and have it be one 100 you're going to
get it very close in the ballpark but
it's very hard to keep it 100
another very popular option is something
it's usually called meta tags and that's
where in the Header information of the
file we write a very specific code or a
meta tag into that Header information
and that has several benefits so it is
much more lightweight to go through to
scan for our meta tag data than it is
for another or for a traditional type of
data classification because in a
traditional data classification you have
to scan the entire file or as a meta tag
you're only looking at the top however
since it's usually our users going
through and applying the meta tag for
example Microsoft Office has a component
where you can go through leverage
specific functionality and this is
another office documents uh LibreOffice
open Office have several capabilities
where you add a little Ribbon or when
you save it has a little pop-up and it
says we here at company care about the
Integrity of and security of our data
can you please help us apply the correct
classification and the user can
literally go through and click web
classification and once they click and
they click OK that specific data
classification meta tag is written in
the header of the document and now it's
very easy for us to go through and scan
now the problem with this type of
classification is our users can just lie
to us right
so this is where a combination of
traditional classification plus meta tag
classification works really great for
ourselves
to go to a bit of a deep dive on this
traditional data classifications
can be very challenging so the United
States currently has 50 states each of
these states is able to write their
driver's license in any way that they
want to this results in our current
classification 26 different regular
expressions
many websites to this day go through and
use 15 or 16 digit your numeric codes
when referencing contact y'all
what does that look like to you if you
are a computer it looks like a credit
card information in fact I've even had
these types of alerts I've ran them
through the link check and they came
back as positive even though their
intended use was not to be an actual
credit card it actually passed the love
test
regular expression in word dictionaries
they can be very challenging I'll show
you in the next slide and when you're
building your traditional data
classification rules always follow the
primary rule of improv comedy and pair
them together with yes and I've got
burned in fact my DLP talk that I've
given many places has some of uh the
very comedic ways in which I wrote when
I deviated from this Rule and finally
proximity rules when you're dealing with
traditional data classifications where
you're looking for condition a and
condition B within x amount of
characters from each other those are
very powerful but they are also very
costly in terms of compute cost
so right here is on the left is our
driver's license positive ID match the
challenge was is that we were hitting a
bunch of other types of
data that were not driver's license but
they're being flagged so things like our
incident tickets things like our change
tickets things like our problem tickets
things like year year year month month
day day or day day month month year year
year
notes were being tagged even things such
as our
our user IDs our admin IDs our
contractor IDs they were all going
through and they were all being flagged
as credit cards so our eyes driver's
license so what I had to do is on the
right I went through and I created an
exception a negative exception path the
problem is is whenever I create an
exception regular expression
I'm introducing a big door for false
negatives to go through so this is where
you need to make sure that the juice is
worth the squeeze when you're going
through and you're adding negative
exceptions or else you're going to
introduce false negatives potentially
into your environment
all right uh we're at the bottom of the
hour and it's time to start talking
about the organizational controls
so as I alluded to before I've got an
entire another talk that goes into Data
loss prevention and so I'm not going to
go super deep on this however
when I was a little baby I.T security
practitioner I used to think that a
effective data loss prevention strategy
would be from a single vendor with a
single management station that control
multiple different tools that would all
work together to deliver
an effective data loss prevention
it's no longer that anymore what I see
is a lot of different vendors are adding
DLP like functionality into your already
existing environments for example your
web proxy probably has a component that
does what DLP web does if you're using
Office 365 or another emailing provider
they either have partners that integrate
and do DLP on the mail server or it's a
feature that you can enable in the
various mail Cloud that you have
uh so any more
it's
it's the exception that I see a single
what I term a scan engine or vendor when
it comes to a full stack DLP
implementation and this brings up some
challenges this brings up some problems
because
as you fragment and bring in more and
more vendors
each vendor is going to have their own
default set of information when it comes
to
the actual data classifications and the
challenge is is that if you go through
in the moment that you customize
something
a library a regular expression
dictionary
then you've lifted the responsibility
for maintaining that off of the vendor
shoulders and now it's directly on your
shoulders
and this manifests itself in a couple
issues
in that
when you go through and you have
multiple DLP vendors coming in you could
have the situation where let's say you
have HIPAA data where HIPAA data on your
network DLP is going to be looking for a
completely different set
of rules then hit the information on
your DLP web or a different set on DLP
email and that can make jobs for your
for the people that are going through
and getting the results very complicated
so
when it comes to various DLP compliance
you know the DLP client that's just
something that generally sits on a
client system and looks at how your
users are interacting with data I have
seen some places that have put the DLP
client on servers but that's really the
exception rather than rather than the
norm the DLP Network I like to think of
this as a DLP or as a IPS that instead
of looking for potentially malicious
attack traffic instead what we're going
through and what we're looking for is
that potentially sensitive information
crossing a segment of our Network the
repository scanner
this is something where you can go
through and you can point this
repository scanner to any type of data
store it could be a file share it could
be a SharePoint it could be databases
depending on the repository scanner you
might have more or less different
targets that it supports but it goes
through crawl through that entire
environment and returns where you it
thinks you have potentially sensitive
information
DLP email you know that's just DLP
inspection on incoming and outgoing
email personally I like to scan incoming
email for DLP not because I'm
necessarily responsible for the security
of data
before I receive it but I want to see if
I see a repeated pattern of data coming
in in a sub-optimal manner I want to be
able to proactively reach out and have a
conversation to correct that DLP web if
you're lucky enough to use a web proxy
you can pair something like a DLP web up
with that through generates through
icaps so that you can do on top of Av
inspection for incoming and outgoing
traffic also DLP inspection and then you
have the Management console and this
Management console really it's per DLP
vendor that you have in the environment
and I have to go through and caution you
one of the biggest
concerns that I see with many DLP setups
is where the DLP Management console sits
so we have to acknowledge that data loss
prevention
designed to find where our most
sensitive data is going through and from
a programmatic perspective where it's
being used in violation of that policy
and at that time we create an incident
now those incidents usually have the who
what where when why the rule was tripped
but they also usually have a summary of
the offending data as well as many of
the popular
DLP environments that I've
sat down with they actually include as
long as the file is not too large the
entire file or the entire pcap of what
that data actually was so you can go
through and you can validate that so if
you are say a PCI DSS customer
[Music]
ought to be treating your Management
console as having the potential to have
the most sensitive information in your
environment so that means that you
should place your Management console as
if it's going to hold PCI DSS HIPAA glpa
gdpr whatever those most critical types
of rules laws regulations contractual
agreements you should place your DLP
within your environment as if it is
going to contain that type of data
let's put our let's put our red hats on
here
an offensive person and I go through and
I land and I get shell onto a system
if I'm looking to steal sensitive data
to encrypt sensitive data and I see that
they're running a DLP environment
because all you have to do is list the
services most of the DLP agents that
I've actually come across report their
exact name when you take a look at what
processes are running up this system
this is not rocket Sciences for an
offensive personality
if I know that there's a DLP environment
it and I can escalate my credentials my
privileges so that I can get into that
DLP Management console that's going to
make automating where I want to Target
my attack really freaking simple so we
need to make sure that we're putting the
appropriate controls around the DLP
console to prevent people especially
malicious people from abusing it
so
some other concerns that we ran into is
that the DLP client can have a lot of a
lot of overlap with a lot of
functionality with the rest of the
environment for example
many DLP clients can look at the network
traffic going in and out of the client
it can do repository scanning it can do
email scanning it can do web scanning
my personal view is I want to keep the
client as lightweight as possible and
move as much off of the client as
possible
because of that what we did is we went
through and we installed a and there are
many different agents that do this so
the particular name isn't critical but
it was a little application that it
would every five seconds and take a
compute cost so CPU memory disk IO
Network i o per process and dump that to
the database and so we had about five
systems within security as we were
building our process that was running
this especially monitoring so that as we
make move Edge changes we have actual
systems in the hands of power users so
that we can understand did the rules
that we go through and added did they
add a significant burden on the actual
performance of the end user machine
because trust me once you turn DLP on on
a client system
everyone is going to assume that the
Slowdown is because of that however in
many cases we did find significant
incompatibilities say for example I love
Google Chrome they're doing a lot of
good however one of the flaws at least
from a DLP perspective was the very
first time my users got an update to
Chrome was the very first time that my
DLP vendor got an update to Chrome and
there was a conflict Google changed
their backing code and our DLP the way
that they're hooking into Chrome to do
DLP inspection it completely broke it
such that Chrome would just refuse to
Launch
so I walked in on a Tuesday and I have
150 different incidents in my inbox and
it's before 8 A.M I'm like what the heck
is going on I go to log into my help
desk ticketing system Chrome comes up
Chrome's Clash I try to watch it again
uh I think I know what's going on here
so
to resolve this my end or my vendor had
to take three weeks to really reverse
engineer the changes that were made and
rewrite
how they did Chrome inspection
that was not popular with our user base
so this gave us the ability the
justification to move off of local
inspection on the machine and move it to
inspection that is done with the DLP web
we also had other incompatibilities
primarily and this was interestingly
enough a lot of devsecops tools code
tools
compilers those seem to have a lot of
issues so we had to bypass them from
inspection and
finally how do we make sure that the
client gets deployed in a consistent
fashion as systems are added and removed
from our environment so we had to do
some interesting
reports and some interesting things with
our client teams to make sure that we
were getting the proper deployment
also we found various areas of the DLP
what I call DLP Enterprise can overlap
with other parts for example
we were getting duplicative alerts out
of our DLP Network for both email and
web now when I looked into the quality
of the alerts the alerts that I was
actually getting were much higher
quality in the email in the web portion
so basically I tuned out any traffic
tour from the email and the web server
or the DLP web system from actually
being inspected by the DLP Network once
again trying to make sure that we were
getting the most appropriate of hits
next casbian
so
many people have rightly gone through
and mocked me just a little bit in that
casby is just the LP for the cloud I
said you kind of have a point there but
it does some other stuff as well now in
general I see two different ways that
casby's are
are set up these days the first one is
in line so you put an inline of your
production traffic going out to the
internet say from your offices out and
then you can do inspection and you can
see everything that is going from your
office out the this has some advantages
but it does not go through and it does
not it cannot see
how your cloud is being accessed outside
of those few network connections that
you are going through and inspecting
that you're tapping
so another option is you give the casby
basically an access token to your
authorized cloud and then it can go
through and simply tap in and do all of
its functionality that way the challenge
there is is it is those types of fun or
of casby's they're going through and
they're seeing everything that you're
doing to your authorized clouds but
they're not able to see what's going on
with your Shadow clouds which is what
the first type the inline methodology
will look so whether you're going when
you're going to look at casby make sure
that you clearly Define what your use
cases are what you're looking to do and
that you choose the appropriate model I
know that a couple of my friends
especially at larger organizations they
have a mixture of casby's or even within
the same casbian mixture of solutions to
do scanning on both sets
so finally digital Rights Management so
this isn't something that I really have
a whole lot of professional experience
with and I included it in this because I
want to kind of disprove that this is
a golden ticket
trm has matured over the years it's
behind the scenes whenever we're we're
working with many of our content
delivery services for example apple and
it's fair play uses a lot of DRM to make
sure that only authorized people are
viewing their movies their audiobooks
their textbooks
and I just want to acknowledge
that in especially in the hacker
communities that
the process of DRM cracking has been
something that has been celebrated since
before the DVD key got leaked so there
are many tools techniques tactics that
have been rallied well defined and well
communicated on how to go through and
how to try to start to crack various DRM
processes
another thing I want to warn you about
is always bring legal counsel when
you're building in your DRM solution and
what you want the DRM to do especially
if you're going to do honey pop files
based on talks that I've had with
various lawyers something as simple as a
ping home embedded into a Honeypot
document could introduce legal liability
to either yourself or to the
organization trust me I want to stay on
the correct side of prison the outside
so always bring legal in when you're
designing those types of Honey Pop files
and what actions you're going to have
those honey pot files perform
and with that I want to thank you I'm
sorry I'm not a hundred percent but uh
thank you for your time thank you for
everyone that is working with the
conference
any questions
do you have any questions
yes
now what was that
yeah well the slide he wants to know um
will the slides be available for review
they're already on github.com Micah K
Brown
is anybody else
think that's it Micah
so once again thank you very much
have a great day
[Applause]
this talk was a part of our 2022 secure
West Virginia Lucky 13 conference if you
would like more information about this
talk or our speaker check the
description below and if you enjoyed the
content consider liking and sharing this
video for more information on secure
West Virginia or you want to stay
updated with the latest upcoming events
follow us on Twitter at secured wbcon or
visit our website securewv.org
we would like also like to thank our
2022 sponsors for being a huge part of
Lucky 13 success