so welcome guys this very large crowd
that we have in here I appreciate you uh
you coming so I'm uh Emily wall I uh run
Global Ethics and compliance and
governance risk compliance option tech
for Live Nation entertainment
um which is a big title it's a lot of
different things I'll throw ins pepper
in some of my stuff as we're going that
I'm facilitating today
um we uh our presentation is about women
in technology and we have four
distinguished women here joining us on
the panel so I'll give a quick
introduction to them and let them give
you their backgrounds
um we're basically following in the
footsteps of Ada Lovelace she was the
daughter of a romantic poet Lord Byron
and his wife Anna Isabel Byron she uh
she lived in the early 1800s her
mathematical Talent shown through in her
early life and her skills and interests
in machines led to a working
relationship with Charles Babbage
Babbage was the inventor of the
analytical engine
it's it was a complicated device that
never actually got built but um it
resembled the elements of a modern
computer and as a result of her work on
the project Ada is often referred to as
the world's first computer programmer
it was her notes when the analytical
engine that Alan turning Turing used as
a form of inspiration for his work on
the first modern computer in the 40s
so um we're gonna chat a little bit
about women in technology get to know
these ladies here and why they they
decided to go into a career in
technology and then maybe go into
um
like what advice they would give to
somebody starting off
so um we'll get going with some
introductions first so you'll get to
know our panelists so I'm going to start
with you
um Alicia Joseph if you can give them a
little bit of a background
um what you do now and um maybe what got
you interested in technology and then we
can introduce Hannah
hey guys so my name is Alicia Joseph I'm
a senior at Marshall University majoring
in cyber forensics and security I
graduate this fall
um
so what got me interested in Tech I
honestly
had done like a career exploration thing
for college and
I had walked past the Cyber well it was
digital forensics at the time but I
walked past that table and I thought it
sounded really cool and the major did at
least because I really loved true crime
documentaries and
I kind of got into it based off of that
because I was like well I can look
through phones and recover deleted
messages or contacts and I thought that
would be a really cool thing to learn
and then I also thought it would be cool
to learn how to do penetration testing
all right Hannah yeah um my name is
Hannah Carroll I'm a student at Marshall
I'm a senior for not graduating this
semester unfortunately
um I'm an open source analyst for our 06
program on campus and then also I'm an
intern for zero trafficking also doing
open source
ful yeah yeah very cool
um I'm also the president of women's
cyber or Marshall's chapter of goodness
cyber reviews
yeah
hi Jim clap rounds of Applause gotta
hold this real close uh my name is Jimmy
I'm on the board for securewb here um
you've probably seen me run around like
crazy sorry
um I what was the question
interested in technology
yep uh
I worked for a DSL tech support company
that was on the job training and it was
way better pay than the previous job I
had and I was like we'll just give this
a go and it turns out I was actually
pretty decent at it
um I really like the problem-solving
aspect of it and that's what kind of
kept me in and that was probably
the 10-ish 12-ish 13-ish years ago and
event ever since currently I am a
systems administrator for the federal
government and
um I've been doing that for the past
couple years I've been in and out of
government contracts also that kind of
got my foot in the door here I my
undergrad is actually in Business
Administration through West Virginia
State University and Institute
um nobody in my family prior to me had
gone to college we didn't have a clue
um my poor mom bless her heart uh she
was like here just go get a paper and
like do a thing and I was like um
but that actually kind of served me well
worked my way up
um
and then I received my master's degree
in what is that called technology
management for Marshall a couple years
ago that's super great program and uh uh
yeah so I guess what got me interested
in it was just it was a better pay uh
frankly and I I just enjoyed it it kind
of worked out and that's uh that's where
I'm at now
Francie hi guys I'm Francine Hammond
I come with three degrees and basically
in electronics business and education my
current role right now is a systems uh
instructional design
is instructional systems designer for
Live Nation uh entertainment I support
the Global Ethics and compliance group
under Emily's purview
and I
um some of the other roles that I've had
that really stand out in my memory uh is
a cyber manager at uh at the FBI Academy
at Quantico Virginia at the Hogan Sally
I don't know if you've ever heard of
that but it's a very exciting place it's
something that J Edgar Hoover had built
as the training grounds for all their
special AIDS special special agents and
during the day when we were working we
could see the helicopter store with body
parts in it and somebody knocking on
they had I like a little town built with
facades on the buildings and like the
post office a movie theater and some of
the guys that were in training were
pounding on the doors open up FBI all
that kind of thing it's very exciting
and then the other one that was most
exciting for me in all my years
uh this this industry was working for uh
as like Jimmy I did a lot of federal
federal government contracts in the BC
metro area and one this means that the
most is working for the Pentagon Forest
Protection Agency we serviced uh we made
sure that the all of the police officers
and all the other personnel there were
600 of them at the Pentagon had all of
their security awareness training on
time and making sure that you know they
got the correct training where they
needed it
um so that I'll tell you why I really
got into this a little bit later in
another questions would think I have a
better story to tell you about going in
time so thank you very much
yep so feel free if you guys have
questions oh I guess I don't need that
um if you guys have questions for our
panelists as we're going through the
conversation please toss them out
um you see we have a lot of different
backgrounds and experience which is what
we tried to do so that we could um give
you guys a prep or a right of of women
in technology
so
um I'll throw this out to anybody that
kind of wants to take it um what's the
importance of more women joining uh the
field of Technology
thank you
diversity and I know we all hear that a
lot these days but it offers I think
people as individuals and then also
different genders offer different
perspectives
um there's a lot of ways
my brain is
uh
everybody's brain works differently I do
think
um I think women offer so much more
perspective because
I don't know we can just think think
about things differently and there's a
funny little annotation that I have with
some family members and it's like my
brain I have 900 tabs in 14 different
browsers open at any given moment and
her husband he um my cousin says he has
like one at a time
not to say like he's slower or worse or
Dumber by any means he's a very
intelligent man but just I think there's
a multitasking element I've seen that
with women I've worked with that's the
different I've worked with a lot more
men than I have women frankly in this
business
um but that's one of the more notable
differences
um
yeah I think that's a big that's a huge
because and I'm I'm thinking like four
14 days down the road and they're like
on day negative two and I'm like hey
hold on I see where this is going
um I think that's an advantage and I
think
um
nope that's it I'll stop talking
anything
so one thing that I thought was
important about more women being in the
tech industry is just this feeling of
belonging in general whenever you see
other women in the tech industry because
it's really hard to feel like you belong
whenever you don't see other women in
the field
I feel like that's something that I've
noticed even like coming to conferences
and stuff like most of it's a majority
men
so it's just hard it's hard if you don't
see other women doing the same thing
that you are
yeah but it's nice when there's not a
line for the bathroom as well right
yeah I think it's really empowering to
have more women because like I probably
wouldn't be as far as I am right now if
I didn't have another woman in this
field would really push me farther so
yep
yeah I think it's interesting because
I'm I do a few different things I run
different teams for Live Nation and on
some of the teams I'm the only woman
right I'll get on on conference calls
with people around the world and I'm the
only woman and then on on other
conference calls like environmental
social governance ESG related calls it
it's all women right and it's it's
completely different Dynamic
um but I I agree with you Jimmy that um
just diversification overall not just in
gender right but just backgrounds
cultures all of that
experiences
um because if you get a room full of
people that have the same background the
same culture the same you're only going
to get so many solutions to problems
right they're going to come about it in
the same way but if you have people that
have different experiences and cultures
and backgrounds and and whatever then
then you're going to come up with some
unique
um
bring something to don't ever think for
two seconds that yours doesn't like you
can't do that
somebody tells you otherwise they are
wrong absolutely
all right anybody have any questions I
will move to my next one if not
sure
email
s
let me tell you that's pretty hard I
feel like especially being a black
female it's like you fit two you fit
like two little check boxes they're like
they're like
yeah you give us two boxes that's how it
feels sometimes it's really hard for me
sometimes to sit and reflect and be like
oh I actually do belong that's something
that's been very very hard
because in a lot of ways I feel like
they're it's something that people jump
to just because they're fitting A
diversity box
but then I sit down at the end of the
day and look at my qualifications and
realize that I'm just as qualified to be
there as anybody else heck yeah yeah
[Applause]
I'm just super honest about if I don't
know something or if I know something
I'm like listen
I know this like you have to have like I
don't know some confidence with that
right like if I know for sure that I
know something like I won't back down
from it if I think for a split second
that I don't know what I'm doing I'll be
the first person to tell you it's my
understanding that I start so many
sentences out with that and I'm like if
you want to teach me a different way
great love that
um
wait there was more of that
you've been up since what you had to be
here at six yeah forgive her
I just I think
well that and you're talking about the
Merit thing like I'm a more action speak
louder than words too and I'm like all
right well watch me do this like go
ahead and underestimate me and see how
that works out for you
that kind of thing
yeah I just and don't like put me into
like a project manager box because
um
I've had that happen several times
actually when you and I work together
um we're in the same building uh
oh that's where you were
did you get pushed into the boxes out
yeah okay yeah I went to yeah
um
if that's what you want to do great go
ahead it's just not my jam
um
foreign
problem solving and
the people the people also go in
sometimes my least favorite part also
but
yes right that's yeah that's fair very
fair
yeah
I do I just I really like at the end of
the day doing a really bang-up job doing
an awesome job and just knowing that
like man I fixed it like and I fixed it
well and things are running great like
that's like that gives me a lot of
satisfaction
yeah yeah anybody else want to answer
that I'd like to go ahead and go to the
next question because it's going to tie
in a lot of the things that we've been
discussing here if you don't mind Emily
yeah and that was the the strongest
biases for women
sorry why did you go into Brazil I'm
actually promised you that I would give
you that information right yeah so let
me tell you
my reason for going in going into
technology or Electronics or whatever it
was at the time was really strictly
survival
and a really great stroke of good luck
at 35 it was a single mom trying to
raise the kids still uh and no no
college degree not even a high school
diploma because I dropped out because my
parents like rent my stepfather
basically said you can't go to college
our neighbors wanted to support it and
pay for it and he said no so I dropped
out and got a job you know and got
married the whole thing you heard the
story before I'm sure
um but then one day I got a I got a
letter from Department of Labor
giving me this great opportunity to to
go and to matriculate in a program at
Ohio Institute of Technology it was
electric Electronics program for women
and that was something that I couldn't
refuse
so I
out of the blue it seemed like some just
somewhere out of the blue or got that
opportunity so I went ahead and started
the program and there were what 35 of us
I think in one class at a time and one
or two of us were females right so this
goes along with what you guys are saying
I didn't feel like I checked the box I
was still in survival mode trying to
learn new new subjects physics and
electron electricity and all of that the
main focus was was studying transistors
how they're made and that's really the
basics basis of how electronics are put
together to make a computer and make
these devices that we use so freely
today
and while this very interesting to me
and still is is the fact that it all
starts with a green off desert sand
and that's when I started and then from
that degree program I went ahead and
took a job with IBM and semiconductor
manufacturing where I actually learned a
lot more about how these computer chips
are made then
uh six years later I migrated West to
Silicon Valley to Intel on the biggest
one the biggest of all so I really got a
good education so strictly survival and
the need to have
some education was why I got into this
field I mean nothing about it so let me
tell you why kept me in the field that
was the two companies that I worked for
in Houston conductor area uh and at
Intel I worked in the factories making
the chips and finally migrated over to
HR in the training department and that's
when it became the systems administrator
for their
training and education database and it
was the Mainframe at the time think
about that so everybody was asking me
give me some reports I need data I need
to report a new report so I tell myself
how to write SQL to get data out on the
database I mean then we didn't have it
but then Along Came the bank on data
warehousing so we put all of our data
there right now we can buy tools to help
us get those data out and get into a
real pretty report so by virtue of me
taking the
incentive to teach myself that this new
program or this new skill I was I had
the opportunity to travel worldwide
sorry I haven't been using that have I
driving traveling worldwide teaching
Intel employees how to use these new
tools and I was on my own so it's
basically could have my own schedule my
own itinerary uh you know coming from
the hills of West Virginia in their
background at all in anything except for
raising kids and trying to make a make a
living uh then now I'm here I'm
traveling to Asia and getting you know
first class uh I hotels and fun trips
everything and as as I saw in foreign
countries probably more so the fact that
a woman was at their teaching especially
Electronics or anything to do with
technology was like mind-blowing to them
but fortunately for me they worked for
Intel Corporation things so they were
required to speak English and that was
the only thing that kept me going but uh
you know that was what really kept me in
going into business was not only
the the subject matter that I was
learning and could you actually use
but just being able to have the
opportunity to travel and all those
things too that's what grew up to liked
for me
thank you yeah
next question yeah so do you want to
repeat what you said before
sorry because I don't think the other
panelists got to answer that one yeah
what are you enjoy
ing here
what made you what made you want to be
and what you've enjoy you know if it was
a little bit different than why you went
in and why you liked it now but why you
said
um I think I say because I really like
to make a difference I don't really like
working with people who I like making a
difference for them
that's fair yeah yeah basically
so I kind of have a similar thing like
Hannah and I basically do like a lot of
the same things
like we're in the same internship and
same outside program so we both kind of
have like the same end goals I guess in
a lot of ways but I really do like
helping people I really do enjoy seeing
I feel like I like seeing the ending
product
of what I've learned like I love seeing
what I can do with my knowledge in
technology I feel like whenever like I
also have a love for the pen testing
side of
of our major and I love seeing Oh I can
hack this that that part is just really
cool to me
so yeah there's a whole career set in
ethical hacking you're in the right spot
yes absolutely absolutely so
um
so especially for you you students right
what trends do you see emerging in the
tech field or the the next five years
because it's I mean as Francine said
right she's seen where it kind of How
It's grown over her career from
mainframes and data warehouses and all
that
what do you guys think is that you know
is going to be the next tech in 10 years
15 years that was a question I looked at
I was like
no yeah
yeah we're kind of talking a little bit
about this you make it oh that's exactly
right
Hannah and I were talking about this
before you came in here because
my mind immediately came to iot
forensics and how that's evolved and how
it's being more and more used in
forensic investigations so if you think
about it in Old forensic investigations
you only use like phones mostly or
laptops but now we're starting to see
watches being used where and
um also things like smart fridges Amazon
Alexa's and things like that being used
in investigations which is crazy if you
think about it just because that's
something we probably never thought was
going to be possible your refrigerator
is a rat
right like you never thought that your
refrigerator was going to be a snitch
exactly
but now it is and it's just it's crazy
thinking about how that's going to
evolve like how smart devices are going
to be more and more used
but I think right now there isn't too
much information on how to gain forensic
images from these like iot devices just
because it's so new like some stuff you
can some stuff you can't but I have a
feeling that they're going to be able to
get clear forensic images on those
I think uh with covid coming into play
I think a lot of people on it already
knew like remote work was fully a thing
um but I think everybody else in other
Industries have really kind of it's kind
of opened their eyes to be like oh wait
a minute we don't necessarily have to
have space and Facilities costs like we
can cut down on that or whatever
um so I think some of the Technologies
to make that remote telework kind of
life easier will develop further
um
oh there's something else I have to do
and I just forgot it
um well speaking of the the coveted bit
right so there was a lot of Health Care
related technology that had to Spur up
because of the pandemic as an example I
was in Mexico City in March right and it
was still locked down kind of semi right
you had to have vaccinations to go to a
show that kind of thing and um we
actually had
um cameras that measured temperature as
the crowd came in
because it's crowd control right and you
don't want to stop and do the little
thing and wait for it and all that so it
measures as it goes and it spots out and
it it like notifies folks well that
technology
it wasn't even there was it wasn't
needed yeah right it wasn't needed so it
could be that technology grows from
necessity which happens a lot sometimes
it's Innovative right and sometimes it's
necessity because the whole world shut
down we need to figure out how to be
able to do things again safely it's kind
of an adapt and overcome kind of thing
yeah exactly and that's the same thing
with the working at home model
we had to adapt to that every company in
the world had to figure out how to keep
going but without putting people in a an
office building anymore like we used to
safely keep going yeah yeah and that's
and that's actually a good
segue to a question that's not on our
list but
um what do you guys think the future of
work is going to look like because
coming out of the pandemic right there's
a lot of hybrid some people some
companies are putting people back in the
offices some companies are saying you
know what we're just going to stay with
the work at home model and some are a
little Blended what do you guys think
like five years from now workforces like
what's that going to look like I think a
lot of it depends on what industry
they're in um which is fair like me you
know I face the public so like we have
to be open to accept no clients
um but we also like we offer like two
telework days a month now first and that
wasn't even a thing like
this might shock some people anyway uh
years and years and years ago
they still had uh desktops with Windows
7 on it and I was like bruh what are we
doing yeah so I had to do a lot of
updating there
um so I think it's that kind of stuff
that people
it's like a user adaptation essentially
anybody can get used to anything frankly
um people are going to hate it or love
it but usually hate it
um but I think it depends on I think it
depends on the industry and like what
your you know your mission and all that
jazz is
um but I think we I think it could go
anywhere honestly yeah I do think it's
going to open up a lot of opportunity in
the technology field uh because I I work
in Los Angeles but I live here as an
example right Francine it doesn't matter
where you live in the world right you
can do your job yeah so you can move to
Cancun if you want to and she can still
do her job so I think there's going to
be more and more of that right right a
little Francine oh yeah
the the ethics of the person the work
ethic I mean you can tell very true the
person's been working at the company a
while they are always you can see what
their work ethic is like and uh you know
they take that home with them too
because when I first started working
from home uh any few years ago because
my role could could handle it
um I I would get up in the morning just
early just it's just you know ready for
work and just think what if the boss
stops by I want to make sure I'm working
you know if that was in my mindset no
matter where I am I'm going to be
feeling that way and and putting my best
foot forward I still get up I will work
from home for Emily Emily's in West
Virginia as well but we have colleagues
and clients all over well all over the
world and we support them uh and so it
really doesn't but I I think the
technology is going to change the way
that we do meetings and things like that
the way we meet face to face
be doing more training each other
through
different mediums online and I don't
know what it's going to be but I think
it's going to there's got to be better
ways than Zoom I think
yeah it's definitely a zoom exhaustion
right but that that could also be
additional Tech that comes out is
productivity software and or monitoring
for remote workers right
um and it yeah
um
oh yeah go for it sorry
you may want to take the question was
very softly spoken yes repeat the
question for the room what uh what are
our concerns with privacy issues
um in regards to productivity software
Etc et cetera tracking us and like our
logs and like daily tasks getting
monitored and that kind of thing
um
my thought kind of on that is if you're
just doing what you're supposed to do it
shouldn't be a big deal uh conversely
I don't like people helping my business
so it's kind of a double-edged sword
um I think
because there's bad apples that ruin the
whole bunch we have to kind of have that
thing
um and I hate that but
um my advice on that is honestly just
voice your opinion in like a respectful
way and you know if you're like hey me
and my team like we'll take care of our
stuff
um
maybe can we can slack off on the like
on this maybe it'll take you longer to
track what you're doing than do the
thing you're actually trying to do so I
just be honest about your opinions on
that and um yeah it's a concern like
bring it up
yeah so there there are a lot of um so
this is a field that is growing right
privacy and Technology right so if if
anybody has interests in that that
actually is a subset field right of
those uh making sure that the privacy
laws
are
followed in regard to technology the
internet of things all all the stuff you
just talked about
Alicia with the um your your TV and your
all that kind of stuff and what what's
it listening and what's it recording and
how long is it recording it where is it
going to and who's it being shared with
so um there there are several privacy
laws around the world there's a new one
rolling out in California that's going
to be across the U.S and there's a whole
Technology field behind that making it
run so information security and cyber
security intersect with privacy quite
heavily and that's a whole
specialization field that you could get
into if you're interested in that kind
of thing and I even it could be sorry
one second it could even be something
webcam covers like I have all my people
all my stuff I'm like I'm not spying on
you I don't want to frankly
um but cover it up when you're on a
meeting like it makes me feel better
makes them feel better like even if
something simple as that like it's you
know
um okay sorry that's all I just want to
add that yes sir you had a question
Market comments
Arizona you know you can't do forensics
yeah well it definitely has to be a
balance right because
um as she said there's always going to
be bad apples so you're always going to
have to investigate the law yeah and
that kind of breaches that contract a
little bit
well but there's
um
anything electronic right is gonna have
logs it's gonna have tracking it's gonna
have that so it's a matter of doing it
within the law but then also having the
ability to dig in if need to and
investigate when it's warranted so not
just open source you can go and look at
anybody's data at any time but if it's
if there is uh just cause to go in and
look at it and you follow the right
procedure then you can go in and do it
so there's there's
there has to be constraints right and
then there has to be a way because that
data is there to secure and encrypt and
protect that data so not anybody can get
to it right so it's it's nuanced but
you're you're right that if it was
completely locked down then there
wouldn't be a need for some forensics
but there's always going to be a need
because there's always going to be
somebody that's breaking the law or
doing bad things you're going to have to
investigate
so but if your business is doing certain
things if you're in finance or you're
processing credit card data you have to
log right so
um and that's why those mandates are
there yeah
all right yes
yeah let's go for it
well it's um that's the way the
technology world's going just in general
right is it's
um what are you collecting from who for
what purpose where is it stored where is
it transferred is it transferred
securely right who has access who's it
passed Downstream third parties fourth
parties so
um those things were already built into
privacy laws before right and now it's
just getting added to it's getting
tacked on to some stuff that it really
should have been tacked on to to begin
with so it's it's really the Journey of
the data right because it's it's your
personal data right the company that
you're transacting with don't own that
you own it but they uh uh monetize it on
your behalf right and they sell it to
third parties and whatever so it's
really just balancing that so that you
become the steward of your data again
oh yeah because most companies aren't
set up to do that so you have to
re-engineer you have to restock you have
to
reduce servers or switch to the cloud if
you're you know your data centers
couldn't handle
you know the the load that's needed to
to Really track the data you have to do
data mapping which a lot of companies
didn't build in from the beginning
yeah it's quite complicated sorry did
you have a question
before
great question yeah
you're gonna think about it yeah yeah
one thing that I realized whenever I go
back and speak to like my old high
school I kind of like to break the
stigma of Tech because I feel like the
reason why a lot of people don't get
into it is because they think that they
have to be for one really good at coding
and you don't have to be very good at
coding to do Tech I don't know like
honestly I know how to do it well enough
to do my job
but I'm not like super great at it and
that's one of the stigmas that I usually
try to break right away like you do not
have to and you also don't have to come
in knowing anything about technology
because I feel like a lot of people in
our field don't know anything coming
into their to the intro class and
there's nothing wrong with that like you
don't have to be a tech wizard in order
to start the field and you don't have to
be somebody that was super good with
tech growing up or anything like that
and you don't have to be good at coding
because I'm kind of I'm kind of average
at it if I'm being honest but I
but honestly it is a useful skill to
help I'm not going to say that you're
never going to have to do it because you
will but that's one thing that I always
tell them like hey if you can be a
beginner and come into this and then I
kind of discuss things like the cool
stuff that we get to do that's the
flashy part that gets to high schoolers
I don't want to tell people oh oh I code
all day tell them the end result of the
code tell them what you did like what
you did
in order like what you did with the code
I guess
because I
yeah because I feel like once they see
what they can do with the code I feel
like that's what makes code a little bit
more interesting for me like seeing what
I can do with it more so than the
process of doing it
[Music]
have any experience
a first generation student
life until I went to Marshall and like I
didn't know anything about any of it um
and I feel like I'm pretty successful
and I think it's really important to
share like success stories and
everything like that so and just Empower
them definitely reach out to them and
everything because they might not want
to do it
yeah I really like that you said you
were um going and speaking to your high
school I think that's
yeah exactly
um
kind of on her note of like you don't
have to really know anything like ask
all the questions like I still ask all
the questions every day
um like encourage them to do that and
just
um kind of like don't put anybody up
it's really hard to teach Society to not
do that so I think the more we
conversate about it and just keep having
that conversation over and over again
until it happens
um
give them my email I'll chat with him
all day I don't care
um I it yeah
talking to hospitals is great
um having I try to get a bunch of 12
year olds to come to this I was like God
I know it's like super nerdy but like it
could be fun I was like their stickers
um it didn't go well and plus they have
like school but whatever
um yeah just uh and I'm a big fan of
like they'll ask me something if I don't
know I'm like hang on I don't know but
let me research that or reach out to
somebody I know and let them like I'ma
send them her way 110 now
um now that we've met so yeah
to that I'll just add a couple of notes
um I I'm living proof that you don't
need to be knowledgeable in anything to
start out in this field and you learn as
you go but I think the main thing is to
be yourself don't try to be one of the
boys or one of the girls just be
yourself make sure you network with
those who do know things
stay in touch with them share ideas
whether it's in forums or 101s whatever
the case may be but stay in touch
also remain knowledgeable not not that
you need to do anything about them it's
just you know the latest buzzwords the
things that are going on in the world
just so you can you know answer a
question or two just so you're seen that
way so you're perceived as knowledgeable
uh remain marketable keep yourself
always this was a some good advice that
Andy Grove from Intel Corporation gave
me personally and I was in a training
room with them
we always make yourself marketable make
sure you know you know your resume is up
to date you use the right jargon the
right current information on it stay
current and everything even your looks
the way you dress all those things just
don't act or be seen as a person who is
uh
uncaring or unkempt just keep yourself
you know up to date and document all
your ideas if you've got an idea don't
just tell everybody document this person
then let's say let's try it out let's
see you know share it with others
trademark trademark yes sir
[Music]
so because most of the time when I ask a
question
is
happening to play games and stuff but I
don't know
[Music]
what is your perspective
to talk to the high school students
I think one thing in middle school I had
someone and I know this is more of an
open source thing but they had a
presentation where they showed like how
much information they can pull from
social media which is a really big deal
for all of us so that's a good
suggestion yeah it definitely caught my
attention
yeah that's a very yeah make it so that
it it impacts them directly
all right we are right at time any
Shazam so any closing remarks or
anything that you would like to leave
the audience with as a
um like advice that you would give
yourself if you were just starting out
in in technology let's wrap with that
okay so the first thing that I would say
to myself is to not be intimidated
whenever you're the only girl in the
room like I feel like it's just weird
whenever you walk into the room
sometimes and you're the only girl and
then I'm the only black girl so you kind
of start to question your sense of
belonging sometimes but like I said
before now it's not as big of a deal for
me I know that I belong in the room with
everybody else don't feel like I would
also tell myself to not feel like I
don't belong because I feel like a lot
of times too when you're women in
technology people don't really think
that you know as much as a man that is
the biggest pet peeve for me like
whenever they think that you can't do
your job or you're not as qualified as
somebody who ran through the same major
same qualifications you're just a fan
and they talk to you as if you know
nothing
so
yes don't do that
and try be
showing them that you do know it's
unfortunate that we have to do that but
showing them that you do know what
you're talking about that you do belong
that you do know just as much or more
than your male counterpart and honestly
just staying confident whenever you know
that like this is a male dominated field
and it has been for a while just know
that like we're trying to break the
barrier and everything right now but
to stay confident
thank you Felicia for saying that how
you feel as a black woman and or any
woman in the tech field uh I have some
of the same
um kind of
feelings about ageism
as an older
white or older woman in the field I
sometimes feel as the same feelings only
different you know just account
different bias if you will
so it's there folks it's uh the gendered
ageism is relevant in today's world in
fact it's the biggest bias in the tech
field right now that that there is
including the the salary uh the salary
gap between the females and the male
that still exists too but just you know
when we're we're all together in this
room today and saying you know telling
us telling you some of the things that
we went through and some things we've
learned and the good things and some of
the other things too let's all remember
you know we're all humans first of all
and we look at each other you bring this
you we're a team we're really a team to
say well your strength is this and yours
is that look at somebody and say well
the color of your skin are their ages is
that's not an issue that's not an
important thing and I've learned through
the years to just you know step up to
the plate do the work forget about
everything else and just love what you
do and do what you love that's it all
right yeah and with that I'm going to
wrap thanks to 304 Geeks appreciate it
this talk was a part of our 2022 secure
West Virginia Lucky 13 conference if you
would like more information about this
talk or our speaker check the
description below and if you enjoyed the
content consider liking and sharing this
video for more information on secure
West Virginia or you want to stay
updated with the latest upcoming events
follow us on Twitter at securewbcon or
visit our website securewv.org
we would like also like to thank our
2022 sponsors for being a huge part of
Lucky 13 success