okay good morning ladies and gentlemen
how are you out there
uh are you having fun yet
oh you are oh I'll go away then
um
it is a pleasure and a privilege to be
standing in front of you once again uh
at security
some of you will know if you are kind of
old security hands that what happens is
about two weeks before security
some speaker drops out
the committee go panic and I get an
email saying would you mind just
presenting something for an hour all
right okay so so I I'm Chief Deputy
Underdog Reserve emergency speaker I
think it's my official title as far as
uh security goals so so here I am to uh
to try and entertain you I have to say
this is a completely novel experience
standing here at 11 o'clock in the
morning because I always get put on the
four o'clock slot in the afternoon
because I'm the emergency Reserve guy
and everybody just wants to go to a pub
so I've actually got a genuine chance to
pull the ass off you for an hour this
morning while while there's some intense
some some attention why not
um for those of you who don't know me my
name is Ian Ferguson I'm actually one of
the staffers here at Abate uh
or a life
resident or a life sentence or something
I've been here for nearly 13 years now
would you believe uh I've also been
teaching digital forensics since I think
about 2004 and had the awful experience
in the digital forensics class this year
of realizing that some of the slides in
my deck were older than the people I was
talking to uh which kind of terrified me
but there we go
shall we do some technical stuff shall
we talk uh technology and some
interesting things I would like to talk
to you
um
essentially about a real digital
forensics case that they got involved in
a couple of years ago I teach digital
forensics here for folks who don't know
me uh I occasionally get to do real
casework both on the defense side and
occasionally
um police Scotland come along and knock
on the door and say could you help out
with something this was one of those
occasions it's never made it into any of
my official teachings I thought yeah why
not why not talk about it today and see
if we can interest people in this so the
title is Samsung Plus regex
what you're about to see is the story
Samsung mobile phone
so if you wanted something to take away
from here uh yeah we'll do the takeaway
we'll do the summary right at the
beginning
um what we did was we managed to
identify a new source of interesting
information
interesting on on Android mobile phones
in particular a file called ssrm
underscoreheating.log which doesn't
sound terribly exciting when you say it
like that but you'll see it actually had
quite profound consequences for the case
that I was involved with
basically what we're going to talk about
is the fact that I needed to search
a great big
forensic image from a mobile phone for
timestamps
sounds good
routine mundane the kind of thing that I
do teach in cmp209
um Turned out it wasn't quite as easy as
you might have thought and we had to do
some jiggering pokery to make it work in
particular
no that's that's clay post uh let's get
this technology here
um I had to develop a new version of
grep
to even heard of uh called by grab
to work with this ordinary wouldn't cut
it it's quite I think it's quite
interesting why that had to be done and
how it was done
um we then looked at turning a one-off
investigation and a one-off find of
something into a proper digital
forensics methodology and to see why
that might be an interesting task
um one of the things we were concerned
with is how widely it was applicable and
we'll talk a little bit about that as
well so that's that's the road map for
the next
hour or so
um some kudos to other people I'm glad
to say that Ethan is back with us this
morning he's my partner in crime
literally uh
that's a good joke I remember to put
that one in again
was a student that he had working for us
over the summer on this one plane and
also Lindsay without who's valuable
input and knowledge we wouldn't have got
as far as we did so well done to them
thank you
okay motivation Story Time two thousand
notes yes 20 2019 is it really that long
ago
uh Ordinary Day in the office sitting
upstairs get a phone call from reception
at the front desk
um police Scotland are here to see you
damn they finally caught me
um
went down
uh a fella
that I know DCI Martin do we have any
police Scotland folk in this morning
no say what I like about it good
so basically
um we've got this case that we're
working on it's a rape case and
the defendants defense effectively is
that you couldn't have been raping
somebody of that time because that
somebody was actually playing a game on
their mobile phone that was the defense
all right so it will actually boiled
down to was could we establish
whether this particular game thing
called toy blast
um or announcement called Peak games had
it been played on a particular mobile
phone I absolute period
if it had been you had an alibi if it
hadn't been then it wasn't looking too
good for it
now interestingly the victim
actually volunteered a mobile phone
so you may examine that and they're
given it to this was the folks alone
here is Dundee along Bell Street police
station just along the street there uh
they've taken the phone and they've done
a kind of full forensic number on it so
that they'd imaged it of course they had
the passcode so there was nothing
particularly exciting about the Imaging
bit of this of you know being encrypted
or any of that kind of just so there's
no there's no interesting stories about
cracking encryption with PlayStation
threes or anything like that this one
um
they've got a hold of an image of this
thing and they'd run it through all of
the current generation of digital
forensics tools if you're in this game
you will know x-ray you'll know
celebrate you may have heard a gray key
in this kind of thing uh they'd run it
through that and it could produce
absolutely nothing about said mobile
phone about this particular game or
about this particular time
so they sent it down to the folks in
Edinburgh uh the top secret digital
forensics facility just outside the
airport
um
with a burger van outside
we see all the coppers queuing up at
lunchtime so you know exactly which
building is the top secret facility uh
they couldn't do anything on it they
sent it down to the Metropolitan Police
in London could they dig any evidence
out of this phone that game had been
played during the actual 20 minutes that
were relevant to the case
and it came back nothing can't do it
[Music]
um
I think I'm pleased to be kind of the
Third
person in the queue what they call so
your person of Last Resort
they can't do anything they give it to
Fergie see if he can have a go at it
right okay
so they gave us a 32 gigabyte forensic
image of the phone an entire storage of
the phone they gave us some details of
the time period of Interest
I gave us
this shot
your phone is absolutely full of
screenshots where I've accidentally
pulled out of my pocket and gone click
and screenshot the damn thing they found
an accidental screenshot of round about
the right period showing a picture of
this game all right okay that's that's
something to go on
so there's quite a lot riding on this
um but it was very much well if you can
find something you can if you can't
don't worry too much about it you know
we tried and you are the last
result so I had a go and we tried
various things we thought well there's
be some Network logs on the device it's
a game it's bound to be shipping high
scores back to the Mothership somewhere
can we see any evidence that it's done
that is there a log file somewhere which
tells us this phone's been communicating
nope
um all right let's get
the boys at Bell Street to get in touch
with the ISP and I can't honestly
remember whether it was O2 who the hell
it was virgin
have you got the logs for that film is
there any evidence of you know what was
being sent over the network on that
phone at that particular time
came back black can't remember whether
it was we didn't we don't have any logs
or there was nothing for that time but
we came back
all right getting a bit desperate we
know who the game maker is let's
footprint them so we did the full
footprinting number trying to find a
little bit about them who they are where
they are turns out they're in Turkey I
think uh let's get in touch with them
have you got anything is there anything
in your system logs which will tell us
what that phone was doing at that time
no reply nothing said no
I think somebody did try and get Turkish
police to go and knock on their door I
don't think that ever happened whatever
um
all right we know the name of the game
we know a little bit about making games
around here at upper teeth
allegedly
incidentally we're all in the wrong game
by the way we shouldn't be we should
have all gone
on computer games instead of computer
security when we looked into this bloody
game
saw what people were paying for for a
few fancy graphics and some crap code
you know people are being paid good
money to churn this stuff up
awful uh basically we tried to reverse
engineer the game could we figure out
anything going on that this stage was
starting getting suspicious this game
actually isn't communicating with
anything at all it's a standalone game
on a phone there is no communication
there's nothing in the log there's
nothing
perfect
assumption
thing connected back to the Mothership
and we could find something that way
false as far as I know I didn't kind of
go ahead and prove that but uh
but without working the Assumption
disprove what else are we going to do
all right
and this is kind of the point of the
talk
digital forensics isn't just about you
use pressing the buttons and seeing the
pretty stuff that comes back if you
can't find was the game being played at
that time
try asking a different question
at time was the game being played now
that sounds silly and trite I know but I
can actually remember sitting there and
kind of the moment that my thought
flipped over
right stop looking at it that way look
at it the other way
can you find anything at all on the
phone which tells you what was going on
at that time period
oh
how would I do that well we've got all
of this stuff back from
the other forensic tools in Dunham
they're finding nothing relevant
what would happen
if I search the entire binary image for
timestamps relevant to the 20 minutes
where this crime is alleged to have
taken place one point how can I do that
well we could we can come up with time
pretty easy we know what it looks like
how do you actually search for that one
of these forensic tools have pulled it
out what are we going to do
in other words how do you search for
time steps at this point
again this is kind of one of the point
of the talks
you know you really do need to know the
fundamentals of what's going on in a
system
what do time stamps look like well
actually there's lots of different
possible formats of time stamps and we
looked at several
um SQL light as I'm sure you know is a
database which is widely used by Android
and in fact by Apple iOS as well
what would a time stamp in those periods
look like in SQL live format text it's
actually moderately easy to search for
not all programs
in fact
someone is breaking it why is it always
me whenever I stand
I'm not actually I don't I don't think
I've actually spoken in this lecture set
for about three years because
uh so it's a bit weird being back every
time I'm in
um
you will know that time steps are often
stored just as a great big integer and
that integer is often the number of
seconds since the 1st of January 1970 or
the number of milliseconds since the
first of January 1970
so the Unix epoch oh my God I'm older
than the unixie park
you can't measure me with use
um
there are some variations to that you
don't know whether the time stamp is
going to represent
UTC universal time code Greenwich Mean
Time
um
could have been British summer time was
it well not in December so that made
that one a little bit easier uh
was it actually even in local time was
it some other time zone
all right so this is starting to get a
little bit complicated what might that
time stamp actually look like
well I'm going to search using grip if I
want to specify how to find anything on
the computer I'm probably going to use a
regular expression
all right what does 10 am on a
particular day in question look like
well if it was a local time then it
looks a lot like that in milliseconds if
it's GMT it's an hour earlier it looks a
lot it's a number
okay
uh
all right well that's just an integer
remember CMP 101 some of you from years
ago uh data representation and all of
that jazz well let's try and represent
that as hex
turns out that it comes out like that
it's a hexadecimal
okay
um we knew that the incident I think it
was 10 40. let's call it 10 40 between
10 14 11 percent of argument we thought
we'd kind of
change the range a bit so we went for
anything between 10 a.m and 1 p.m and we
worked out what the
hex representation of those integers was
for those two times so we have bounds
that we're looking for right
hang on time steps
long
in C yes right so 64-bit integer
I mean had these things and actually
what I need to do is to ignore the least
significant Bank
and that's going to give me a time range
corresponding to
the start and the end so we're just
ignoring I can't remember how much of it
we ignored but depending on how many
bits you ignore you're kind of giving
yourself a different range of times that
you're looking for uh needs to be
encoded and escaped for the shell and
for the big rep
turns out we were searching for that as
our regular expression I think that's I
think that's 10 o'clock
well actually 10 o'clock and if you
remember your regular Expressions on the
end
dot means I don't care what's in there
so it's 10 o'clock and a bit
so I'm searching this whole
binary image for things representing the
time 10 o'clock in a bit to one o'clock
with a bit less
just say we're going to search 32
gigabyte image we've got a copy of the
entire memory of the phone
there's a problem with that and I don't
think I'd ever worked it out until I
came to this case
great
a friendly command line graph that we've
all used it was used every day is
profoundly
meant for searching things in text files
in other words it's meant for searching
for printable characters it's meant for
searching with things which have a
return on the end which say that's the
end of the line
hang on that 32 gigabyte file is
profoundly its binary data it doesn't
correspond to that
grip has a 2K line length limit
2048 a big surprise
I can't use gret to do this all right
okay that's a bit of a problem
also turns out there's no way of having
non-printable characters in The regex
actually I've since found out there are
some flames of grep do that the time
that we profoundly believe that we could
not use regex
with uh with non printable jars
and then the real big one is the grip
has been compiled this is true for
almost all of the versions see out there
with 32-bit file points in other words
the maximum size file you can search
with grep is four and a bit gigabytes
right that's just blown our approach out
the water we can't go grabbing for
timestamps
what do we do do we run away and cry
quietly in the corner
admit failure walk along the Bell Street
police station say
I'll ask I can do nothing
no
we are software Engineers we are hackers
we are head bangers we rewrote grip
this is the best this is the best book
coming to the best bit when you see how
long it takes to rewrite grep
you're either going to call me a
charlatan of God
right
um
we wrote A Thing Called well I call it
buy grab could be big could be biograph
who cares
um
I use Python I use the library called M
map memory management Library uh memory
mapping Library I'm going to tell you
how marvelous that is in a second uh and
good old regex library the standard
regex line python python is more modern
job python has 64-bit file pointers so
we've just blown that objection to Java
straight out of the water
we want to allow the specification of a
pattern as hex so I need some way of
processing the command line to do that
big deal we could write command line
processes
um it's available there if you wait till
the last slide there's a nice QR code
and you can go straight to the page if
you wish to download this pile of useful
code
um and actually
this is where you're going to cry
that's it give you four lines
seriously you can Implement grip in four
lines
yeah you can python
actually it's not okay there's about 12
lines before that just take the
parameters from the command line and
process them so that they're in a nice
form to use it those four lines
are the only four lines you do anything
useful in that program
what does it do
it takes the name of the file
that you've typed in one that you want
to search
it memory Maps it so there's a kind of a
virtual memory thing going on here
basically what it means is you can treat
the entire file as one big string python
thinks it's a string and M map is hiding
the fact that it isn't even in Ram the
fact that it's on disk it doesn't try
and load it all at once so it doesn't
matter if you haven't got 32 gigs of RAM
on your machine M map handles it kudos
to the designers of M map this is one of
the nicest most powerful
obstructions I have ever used in my
career it is genius
um okay so we now have the data sitting
variable
we take the pattern what we want to
search for well all that's doing is
grabbing it from the args array from the
command line Arguments for the program
we're then going to say I want an
iterator which looks for that pattern in
that data and then for every match that
it finds printing out the match
that's it grep re-implemented four lines
of python brewed
not my brilliance
pythons
okay back to the story
what did it do when we ran this thing
well it actually produced exactly
that output there so we're searching 32
gigabyte file and it gave me
a dozen lines
all right A lot of them
text files well yes I have an advanced
forensic tool called Notepad which we
use to have a quick look at the text
files nothing very interesting
there's a whole load of DB files SQL
light DB all over Android yeah
look at those SQL light nothing terribly
interesting
the hell is this one ssrm heating.log
never heard of that before
so what we did we actually
gripped through all of these this was
kind of before I even went to sqlite
um for a looked for a bunch of words
that might be associated with the
particular game so we looked for heat
Gates which was the name of the
manufacturer so the name of the game we
looked for one or other two things
what did it turn out now I apologize
that this is
um
we found that as a log entry so 1149
timing
what's the biggest asset of a comedian
um
no you didn't get that one
right uh
timestamp it matches remember we were
thinking about it being an hour out
because of
BST and GMT
top peak games all right well top hang
on top that's a Unix command this is
Android all right so ah actually this
thing or something called net.peak games
dot Amy
was using 12.8 percent of something
surface Slinger 2.82 audio server 2.2
the game's running
at that time it's doing something we've
found that it's using resources okay
at that moment we now know we're on to
something there is something being
logged here
we're about to have a bit deeper look at
this ssrm heating box so it's the only
one that matches the time Stone and the
strings connected to the game and we
came up with a whole bunch of log
entries PMP entries commentaries net
entries
top entries
no idea what they are I've never seen
this before in my life either this is
completely new to me
we've got some stuff which appears to
say
games is actually doing something
at the appropriate time
now none of this is proving the game is
being played yet but we're starting to
get there
so we'd better do some digging what the
hell is this ssro and heating.log Google
ssrm underscoreheating.log
zero matches
was it zero maybe not quite zero it
wasn't many
relatively few
um okay this is part of a thing called
the Samsung system health manager system
this has nothing to do with health apps
this is about the health of the device
turns out that what it actually is is
Samsung's monitor safety system
we think it's original purpose was to
stop devices overheating when they were
being gamed too hard
uh in particular that the GPU was being
given too hard and it logs things like
memory usage Network usage temperature
all of the kind of resource things that
you might come across in an operating
system
this thing was logging every now and
then all right
possibly it was to do with preventing
overheating possibly it was to do with
actually tuning for games performance
you're not quite sure uh what we did
find out was that it received little or
no attention from the academic Community
certainly from digital academic digital
forensics people nobody heard of it very
very little documentation about it the
only place Ethan queued us to this one
um
XDA Dev Community had heard of this that
was about all we got the rest of it we
had to work out ourselves
so what does it do why is it interesting
um
it basically logs things things stuff
starting on the phones activation and it
obviously has cleared the last factory
reset other than that we couldn't
actually find out when the log was
cleared it makes a note when the device
is being rebooted so it assists across
sessions
but it doesn't exclusively log games
it's just logging what's going on and
the system effectively it's kind of
running top every now and then and just
recording stuff about it
format looks a lot like that a time
stamp uh followed by some kind of code
and a message
is it a circular buffer does it have a
capacity limit does it overwrite don't
know I can't tell you those that's the
future work inevitably it'll be a
circular buffer so stuff will persist in
there sometime I'm going to virtually
guarantee one day it'll it'll overwrite
so we managed to do some work and we
found out that it logged all of these
different kinds of entries and we did
some some readings and looking through
and tried to figure off figure out
things like uh when the LCD screen had
been manipulated by set commands uh
logging network connections
handles the charging screen so all kinds
of interesting bits and places that was
the one we liked
very similar to the the Unix top logs
graphic activity basically what's the
GPU doing how busy is it
okay
so after all of that we were able to say
we can prove
that something written by Peak games by
the way there's only one app on that
phone IP games
was actually active and was using the
screen the screen was on the GPU was
busy actually processing graphics for
round about the 20 minutes in question
oh dear
so this is actually corroborating the
accused defense
the victim had been playing again at the
time of the incident and actually
kind of round off that bit of the story
the police went back to the complaint
eventually she admitted the thing had
been completely fabricated she had a big
round with the boyfriend
and tried to frame him for rape
um they didn't do that at the end they
were talking about possibly Prosecuting
her for wasting police time they didn't
in the end
as with many of these things she
probably needed mental health support
rather than being arrested so I think it
kind of had a happy ending but um
I think it's always interesting to
remember
when we do this stuff yeah we love the
bits and bites we love the technology
there are human beings on the other end
of everything we do I think it's
for those of you who are considering a
career in digital forensics it's
possibly worthwhile just you know
bearing that particular one
okay
so that was kind of the end of the
immediate uh involvement with the police
down Bell Street but we now have this uh
unheard all sorts of evidence the
current J generation of digital
forensics tools know nothing about this
file we thought well this is that's a
bit sad this is quite interesting
there's useful stuffing
how could we actually turn this into
some kind of evidence-grade procedure
some kind of methodology which we could
use for this
um we were fortunate in the ncsc gchq
that year were lashing money about and
we managed to employ an intern for the
summer to actually work on this and do
some background to work on it which uh
turned into a rather a useful thing I'd
like to just talk about that for a few
minutes now
so in terms of turning it into a DF
digital forensics technique what do we
need to do
um again those of you who've been in my
classroom know that we bang on about a
digital forensics life cycle digital
forensics process consisting roughly of
acquisition extraction evaluation
applicability
visualization I may not have used
exactly those words the last time you
sat in CMP 209 it's
that's the flavor of it
first of all can we image the device in
this case we could yes we're doing
nothing about decrypting phones wrong
talk uh extraction can you find the file
yes we now know where to look at it what
causes events to be logged no idea
oh right that's not really what you call
forensically sound we need to understand
better what makes it actually right a
log entry
how many phones actually use this
Samsung system Health monitoring
software
well this one does
that's all we do at that point
can we make the evidence easy to
comprehend actually I'm going to say we
failed on that one but we can judge that
later
Ethan in his infinite wisdom and this is
pure coincidence I assure you've
actually handed me the phone this
morning uh is returning it after having
or have you been doing with it for the
past three years I don't know I don't
want to know I don't know
factory reset um
[Music]
we don't have access to any 30k plus
forensics Tools around here I wish we
did anybody is now a rich alumni of this
University and wishes to buy Ian a
couple of copies of n case
I'll be good
um but we you know me we like open
source we like the command line what
we're going to do well we'll root the
damn thing and run DD on it okay right
we've got that we can we can we
rooted image so now now we've got spare
form actually identical to the one in
the case same model same we're playing
with this one instead of somebody's
other phone now so that got rooted and
we started seeing what you could do to
the phone which would make it create uh
a log entry
so
once again we were searching for
Relevant strings in particular the
strings that we now knew appeared in the
log
um with big rep and we were able to
access the file system raw using debug
FS if you've never used debug FS as a
way of accessing stuff on ext4 file
systems and things fun stuff
um so that was kind of the before by now
we were confident yeah okay we could
just Mount the damn thing up and find it
a meaningless bit of Linux down the
bottom you can just grab the file off
there and we could achieve it
so key question what causes events now
to be written to the log of this phone
well
you get money from gchq
what do you spend it on you obviously
spend it on hiring intern to walk around
Dundee with a mobile phone in their
pocket for a few days
which is basically what Michael did and
we gave him what we called uh some
structured walks we came up with a you
know we wanted to go here we wanted to
spend so long there we wanted to go
within range of that Wi-Fi we wanted to
take it out we want to access a web page
we wanted to do and we came up with
something that we thought kind of
properly exercised all of the things
that the mobile phone could do but the
point was that we needed them doing
repeatedly and exactly the same time so
if you saw this guy kind of Behaving
really strangely around Dundee and some
of the cafes in 2019 2020 it was it was
us
uh so we used a whole variety of these
things followed it and then basically
what we did was match the log entries
against what we told him to do
what hey Presto of surprise surprise
every time you go past a Wi-Fi place it
logs something and says you're his wife
oh that's quite interesting so the phone
itself is maintaining a list of which
Wi-Fi access points you've been arranged
with
do our privacy researchers know anything
about that one so I thought that was
quite interesting the way back to what
Apple were doing in 2012. that was a
good one
uh okay so we established fairly easily
yeah there's a pretty straightforward
correspondence between Common Sense
everyday life events with the phone and
the log file
has that been tested in court no
would it stand up
I don't see why not but you know maybe
we need to try that one
okay applicability
I didn't do this I'm making no claims
uh how many phones actually have this
file uh what Ethan did was he grabbed
the firmware some firmware from there a
variety of phone models probably reverse
engineered them and confirmed indeed the
executables necessary to run the health
monitoring thing uh were there as was
the actual log file uh S6 to S9 Plus
android 10 7 to 10.
we're guessing it's still there
so you
it's 20 also there you are
okay it doesn't guarantee that it's
running on any given phone I think
Chance is pretty good uh your mileage
may vary if you get to try this kind of
stuff
does that help anybody understand what
was going on the phone
no I don't I I I came to this on my
slides and thought right what shall I
say about this slide and try and explain
it when
um actually actually I could just about
try I think we could say that somehow
we got from the log file that
the Play Store had been accessed
whatever there's a red piece it would
probably be an accessed twice why it's a
peak rather than bar chart I don't know
but the physicist in the is revolting
deeply against this diagram okay
non-labeled axes don't anybody ever
submit the graph to me without the axes
properly labeled or you'll get a bit of
1980s Sunderland University Physics
person down your neck
um no uh I didn't yeah we tried we ran
out of time and money
nearly as early as well I hope you've
got some good questions
um
some conclusions three pages of
conclusions first of all this thing we
think this Samsung system health monitor
manager provides an interesting source
of digital forensic evidence which
people don't seem to know about I really
should write this up as an academic
paper and publish it
so this is this is it being presented to
the world I hope it's in use to you
um
we've pretty much got a validated
methodology something which has got a
little bit of substance to it which
actually lets us prove that it really
does what we're claiming what it says on
the tin uh it's been tested to some
degree at least it hasn't been stood up
in court
is Big rep
a production digital forensics too no
absolutely isn't it's a nasty little
four-line script uh
goodbye
oh no it's worse than that actually oh
it's locked
go or get back you little salty oh no
that's interesting I can't go back any
further who's fiddling who's fiddling
with minor ship you remember the last
time I was here and I was talking about
all of the Bluetooth snarfing stuff I
was doing there's a bunch of fortios up
there at the back when I'm doing the
live demo suddenly start creating
Bluetooth devices with rude names
much appreciated guys
[Music]
um
why is that oh
sorry about that uh is it is it
production standard two no it's not it's
a script it's kind of Handy
um if you're in the game of deriving new
right I now know why that's doing that
and that's entirely my fault guess who's
say who's copied the slide from
presentation with some timing
information on it whatever whatever
um
take regret use it it's released under a
do what you like with it license
um
have fun with it
you can't remember what else I was going
to say about it can't be but I can't be
bothered to go through all of that
living room to go back to the past slide
um
I suppose the point I wanted to make was
how long have I been in this game how
long have I been doing Computing for
longer than
Millennials aren't you
no not quite not quite
let's call it 30 years it's actually
more that I've been creating software
and doing doing stuff with computers
I think those four lines are code
possibly the best four lines of code
that I've ever written
I I'm actually being deadly serious
about this I mean I've written huge
systems but I've written stuff from my
PhD with you know 200 000 lines of code
actually I think those four are best I
got more satisfaction from those four
and any of the other stuff I've done the
sheer power of being able to say just
treat that file as a string Now search
it
I think if you realize what you would
have to go through to do that manually
not money to even wipe the code to do
that without that in math thing I'm just
you know on an nmap Fanboy yeah
okay
um
third thing is the importance of kind of
fundamentals
in in digital forensics uh you know we
all get excited by the latest greatest
shiny tools
we love you know the Deep technical
stuff that you're going to hear a whole
load more about today
don't forget your fundamentals don't
forget that it's actually quite
important that you
you somebody somebody in your
organization
has that ability to go
right time step it's a number how's it
represented it's represented like this
it'll be searched for like this the
regex was that
it's all first year stuff
second year stuff there's nothing that
difficult in anything I did here and yet
I hope it's proved that it was something
that was of you know genuine real world
actual actual value uh and you know I I
encourage you
shouldn't throw the pointer away uh
you'll have heard me bang on about this
before somebody beats his knowledge you
know that's what this game is really
about about understanding what the
number of silicon in front of you
is doing how it does it and all that
kind of thing so just to encourage you
to keep on going with that sense
uh the future things we should do
um is there equivalent functionality in
other phones uh I strongly suspect that
Apple has something very similar to that
in iOS somewhere is there equivalent
functionality into the Samsung devices
we've got Samsung smart TV at home
it's sneakily monitoring when I turn it
on I don't know anybody wants to find me
another big Samsung I'll quite happily
take it apart and have a look
um
just simply trying that technique on
other devices on iot forensics a couple
of PhD Folks at the moment working on
doing forensic investigation of iot
devices may be actually going into that
low level and looking for stuff like
that might be an interesting thing for
us to try so some future work to have a
go at that uh very finely a couple of
thanks really first of all to DCI mark
lorente from tayside police sorry police
Scotland
for having the faith in us to just walk
along the road bang on the door and say
can you do anything with this without
that none of this would have happened it
doesn't happen often that somebody just
lands on the door and says here's an
interesting problem but when it does uh
it's kind of one of those really nice
moments of your career and also a big
thanks to Michael our summer intern who
did a lot of the Harvard graft of
actually turning some fairly nebulous
ideas and some hucking around with
python into a properly validated
methodology
if you want big red it's there
uh
promise I'm not rickrolling you much
with that uh
[Music]
good there you go right that's the end
any any questions
I think I think we tried I think we've
got absolutely nowhere
um I think that that mind you
I certainly don't have the contacts in
Samsung
um I think we you know we were at the
stage of digging a couple of email
addresses off the Samsung website and
just emailing them speculatively I don't
actually know anybody who works do we
have anybody from Samsung in this
morning
and if they do they're not admitting to
it they're furiously ringing what the
hell is this system monitoring thing
um no uh so the short answer we tried
but no
foreign
will be limited by a 64-bit pointer so 2
to the power 64 bytes
if anybody wants to work that out
Nick wants to know over there I don't
hold the number in my mind it's big
computer
I think if you deleted one line out of
it the chances are you're not going to
notice
I think if you delete 20 minutes worth
out of it you're going to spot it
because the phone's actually
sorry I should be up here for the
microphones uh
the phone is constantly logging things
and doing things even when it's sitting
by your bedside at night and you're not
touching it it's automatic updates and
God knows what else it's doing and that
kind of thing is loads I mean I think
you would notice it in those
circumstances
foreign
how did we come up with the structured
walk that we started doing basically we
cheated so you know we we we we did a
couple of rough ones
and just looked to see what was in there
and we started seeing things like you
know Wi-Fi equals Starbucks
okay
um URL
this at this time and you kind of
figured well okay
what we need to do is to do all of the
kind of systemy things which are kind of
built into raw brings so like networking
things like doing an update that kind of
thing so they all got Incorporated
and then it was a question of looking at
well let's let's consider the kind of
apps that somebody has a foot on their
phone is there a typical app Well
everybody's got a browser
everybody's got Facebook
don't they
so you know we just picked a few on
you know I think I'm going to stand up
and say that's that's the limit of the
rigor of the
thing really what else can you do it's
got to be your imagination about what
can this phone do if you do it to the
phone does anything appear in the log
and you know some some things did some
things didn't but by and large the kind
of things that you might expect it to
log yeah there was an entry there
sometimes even sometimes it's just okay
how busy is the processing you know
particular Point there's a spike in
there
in the
[Music]
uh you know stuff top returns and you
say okay busy at that point
screen on screen off
backlight on backlight off
see other bits of hardware on the phone
I think
we can't honestly remember did we did we
check for the Bluetooth it's been turned
on and off
it's okay it was looking what is the
hardware capable of what might it be
used for is there an entry for it
make it up on the spur of the moment
oh
foreign
question how do you keep a forensic
methodology up to date okay
the answer is that you write it in
suitably abstract level if you're if
your methodology is you know press this
button enter the number two scroll down
twice
you know that's going to be out of date
six months if it is point one understand
the hardware of the device from whatever
Source Point two understand the inputs
and outputs to this system 0.3 find a
way of capturing those inputs but if you
write a suitably abstract level then it
you know it's survivability is longer I
reckon you can write the digital
forensics methodology
okay one of one of the points that I
bang on continually about to the
students here is you know
what's that
see if any of them have been listening
what is it
yeah somebody said it's a computer okay
so all of the stuff that we've been
doing with computer forensics and
digital forensics for the past 20 years
is precisely applicable to this it's got
input devices it's got storage it's got
all of the things that you know your
desktop computer has got don't treat it
any differently and if your methodology
is written sufficient should be
abstractly to cope with that level
I've got one of the one of the guys from
a PhD guys at the moment that's doing
stuff on iot forensics and you know I've
said it needs to come up with a
methodology what I'm looking for in that
methodology
is not you know connect the USB
connected to that it's
one go away and understand the hardware
on the device you're doing it from
whether that's from the manual whether
it's via internet search
try and find out about the device first
second stage okay now you can take it
apart and have a look and see what's in
there can you identify the storage
device that black thing there that looks
like a chip all right
processor chip is it a non-flash chip is
it storage chip is there one option all
right and you know you can you can write
your methodology such that it can cope
with that kind of thing that I think
stands a chance of surviving for a while
admittedly yeah there is there is a
problem technology changes we've got it
how am I doing
I've another 10 minutes oh my God
some of you may remember that we used to
do lectures in room 3006 which has the
piano up front
that was always good for a giggle when
we ran out of material uh right sorry
there was another yes
[Music]
that's a very good question I can't give
you a straight answer to that one I
think the answer is probably quite a lot
but it was just the one that really
caught our eye was this top thing
I'm a that identified how much
The Source certain processes we're using
and that as far as we know so even when
you've got an app like this game which
frankly doesn't do very much
it's still appearing in the log it never
logs anything explicitly itself
but because this is being monitored it
appeared there and that that seemed like
a useful source of information so I I
can't give you a percentage it's
probably something that should be done
anybody wants to find me a project you
know
cross check the heat log against some of
the other sources that would be an
interesting thing to validate
[Music]
it was it was within it was within a
couple of days but what we did observe
was the log went back a months
so it obviously been quite a while since
the log has cycled over
it but certainly persistently as far as
we can tell the only thing that it
doesn't persist through is a factory
reset
any more for any more oh
that's a good question how long
real time probably about six weeks from
first getting the phone to actually
being able to go back to the police with
some confidence and say yeah we know
that that phone was that game was being
played at that time uh
that wasn't six weeks me working on it
full-time University don't work like
that kind of thing but I of that order
[Music]
is
it together
we certainly did but that was kind of
more in the kind of deeper understanding
methodological stage when we were
actually still talking to the police
live you know I was very conscious that
this was a a live investigation
basically as soon as we had a couple of
entries in the log said look this phone
has been busy with this game in this
period
um they were they were very keen on
hearing that early
um
conclusions for example
the absence
[Music]
it's probably a generic for it
right it's no it's a reasonable question
well it's a philosophical question can
you prove an absence of evidence what is
it what does it say
um in the end not a lot all you can do
sometimes is say look we have
indications something was going on here
and that feeds back into the real life
investigation
I mean what happened here was you know
as soon as as soon as we had some
indication something was going on
they went back to the person so young
hang on your story doesn't quite stuck
up here and actually it was admitted
relatively easily in terms of the kind
of rigor that you're talking about yes
there is more work to be done I'm not
going to hide that
oh
in a sense this is it you know what what
I should do is write paper and publish
it in digital investigations
started I've sat down and started to
write that paper about three times you
think you students are good at avoiding
deadlines and procrastination master
um something yeah the proper thing to do
I now that I've actually
you may find that you folks are being
very useful in that you've forced me to
think about this again maybe I should
now sit down and actually write that
paper that would go into digital
forensics that is red in the labs and
that's certainly read by the people who
make the software so that that's kind of
the way of feeding back into it
um so yeah that's that'll be how it goes
anybody got anything else or are you all
running away go on yes sir
uh I think they're actually there are
actually multiple entries in one line
and I think it's a lot of them
um
you've got me can't remember off the top
of my head but there was multiple things
processor core GPU and a couple of other
bits and pieces as well
right I am actually going to showed up
at that point and uh let you get off to
the next tour thank you