okay so hi everyone first of all my name
is
okay so as far as my profession is
concerned I am currently a technical
cyber security analyst working at a
company called techforce it's based in
Aberdeen and other than that I'm also
doing my masters and I think I'm hacking
in cyber security from Aberdeen and
first of all I would like to really
appreciate you guys that you have
specifically taken out your time to be
on this track you could be anywhere and
you give me that well thank you so much
for that and I'll make sure that you get
to do do get the value so today the
topic of uh which are which I'm going to
this doesn't share my insights that is
actually dumb ways to cryptographic
failures in this what I'm gonna do is
that I'm going to explain some of the
really dumb ways that we do in real life
and that actually causes different types
of cryptographic failures so let's just
get right into it I'm assuming we have a
different set of audience everybody
would have different cells of expertise
and stuff so for those who don't know
cryptography is basically just a simple
science mathematical science that we use
in our daily life to achieve security
principles these principles include
confidentiality Integrity authentication
I will ability up to some extent and
authorizational identity access
management so I am speaking so much
so much so yeah we have very different
techniques through which we Implement
that we have encryption you have hashing
you have digital signatures and not only
these there are so many processes that
we have the key exchange session
maintenance identity management access
control then even talk about the
protocols that yeah TLS transport layer
security ipsec talk about emails we have
pgp pretty good privacy so lots of
things we use cryptography in our daily
life so what is basically a
cryptographic failure then so
cryptography failure is basically a
situation that occurs that when you are
trying to achieve a security principle
you don't achieve that let's just say
you were trying to achieve
confidentiality and you couldn't because
you are using an outdated algorithm or
someone like that so in that case
basically it's basically a photography
failure so why cryptographic failures
are important there are two things first
of all the impact obviously let's just
say we are trying to achieve
confidentiality and if in case we are
not able to achieve it you can possibly
imagine the impact it's not only
informational loss not only financial
loss but reputational loss as well and
right now as we speak like you won't be
able to feel it unless it happens to you
for any other person you'll be like okay
it isn't it isn't that much but when it
happens with you that's when you realize
and the second thing is frequency these
attacks are really common right now in
2017 it was on third position with the
name I guess sensitive data exporter and
the 2021 report it was escalated to the
second position named aspartame failures
so why do these cryptographic failures
occur so there there's one perspective
to this one is that as you can see
there's a little Miss in here in this
new one this demon is basically like you
can say the chat landscape it's huge you
talk about there are so many different
companies working in different sectors
you have energy you have Finance you
have sales like so on and so forth
everyone is using it and everyone has
different expertise level in technology
some might be using the latest one some
might be not some might not be using the
latest one and then this one there are
hackers and there are securities users
this is the term that I have made myself
so Security Solutions are basically
those people who are not so good with
security these are the people like who
are likely to click on a phishing email
I'm not trying to still attack people
here but
but generally these two will go hand in
hand and this little thing would simply
can't do much much about it so
there's another approach let's say you
are trying to achieve confidentiality
and then again you chose the wrong
weapon you chose an encryption algorithm
that was updated problem second one is a
little bit more which I really want to
emphasize in this complete project or
whatever this presentation is about as
you can see that you there are some
equations right if you see them on an
individual level you will see that the
steps that we have calculated they are
exactly right but we have missed one
thing that is basically the guideline
that you have to follow the board Mass
role basically and just because we
didn't follow that rule we are facing an
anomaly exactly that's what happens in
real life cases
okay so now let's just see what are some
of the ways downgrades through which we
achieve those cryptographic figures so
day one that's weak encoding all of the
vulnerabilities that I'm listening I
research them through cwe which is a
common weakness and enumeration Library
you can go search on that everyone has a
number associated with that so as you
can see this one is a code basically
what it does is let's just say you want
to store a password in a configuration
file
so what you're doing is that it's
getting the password value from the DB
and it's recording it via base64. so we
know that it was encoded in base64. that
actually is not that good because as a
security researcher I know it's just a
matter of like seconds to convert that
back and if you have something like this
at your back end you are doing wrong so
yeah it provides that security it's
simply like this as much as security
this Grill is providing to this side of
the road it's providing that much so if
you are deciding to achieve
confidentiality what you will do is uh
encoding in base64 is probably not the
best option to do so
okay the second one is clear text
transmission of sensitive information
again uh we are getting a connection
with the website and we are doing it
through HTTP and you most probably know
that when we are using HTTP all of the
data that we are trying to send or even
receive that goes in clear text and for
anyone who is on that virtual side of
the things can actually shift that um
now you would be saying to me yeah it's
just so easy like it's like normal thing
we know that actually DP does this
what's the catch in it the catch is that
most of the people actually don't know
we are from the technical background
that's why we are saying it if you just
go and these are Google dots so if you
just put this command on Google you'll
find out the results that are HTTP
websites excluding someone that are
https you'll see this much results
around
I don't know what's that number 223
million maybe yeah this much websites
are there that are using HTTP secondly
there's a tool called curl we as
developers use it much because we have
to integrate data between web apis and
Sun data API sometimes and what it does
is it has this option called hsts which
is HTTP script a strict Transport
Security what it does is that it
enforces even if you type HTTP in the
URL what it does is that it will make
the data go and follow https but there's
a problem in this what's that this was
the vulnerability that was published in
October 26 2022 that was exploited just
because of a single problem what was
that the thing is that when you are
trying to pass it a link let's say HTTP
any website and you you can see this dot
right here right it's an IDM collector
idn stands for internationalized domain
name these are basically uh you can say
non-ascii connectors or non-latin
connectors that are not ASCII characters
so one hacker just find out that if you
can do this you can bypass this HTS STS
option so the main point was trying to
tell you that it not obvious always that
if you are using https
in reality https is being used no it
doesn't really you have to make sure
that you are using https
so yeah exactly that's what our friends
say then hard-coded Keys again so you
see that uh the hash is given here and
the configuration actually checks it
against and if it's right you are good
to go out if it's not then you are not
good to go
again a simple thing to do you can find
reversible hashes online just go paste
it and you will find it and it's gone
down so don't compare credentials with
hard-coded hashes always
reusing launch value okay so this is
kind of an interesting one because uh
nonce basically we use in Security in
order to get the identity so let's just
say
anything any particular thing you like
let's just say Donuts you like donuts
and I want to be at a family of donuts
and I said that okay if you like donuts
be the member of my club what I do is
that I give you a secret number and
since whenever you want to connect with
me just add this number so I will know
that you are a part of my donut club or
whatsoever so the bad thing in this is
that you are not changing the smaller so
let's just say once you have given this
secret value to a customer or whatever
your client any attacker if he has that
he can use it because you're not
changing them so he can impersonate as
that person another example that I can
give is that these lanyards security
just gave you these and they said that
we want you to wear them if you want to
come to the after party there's no photo
in here so anybody outside who wants to
go there can take my lanyard if he wants
the main thing is that security is not
changing these I know this is just for
one time it's not a good example though
but then again if you are not changing
balance that's a problem again
anyone can impersonate that and for a
fun fact non-stand for number used only
once so that doesn't really make us if
I'm using it again and again but then
again I said these are dumb ways and
these are actually followed in real life
that's why I'm talking much about it
so using key post expired again if you
are checking the validity of SSL
certificates so let's just say
um
I met with a
I met with a student he's from Aberdeen
and I want to validate that if he's
really a graduate student so what he's
going to do is he's going to give me his
ID card now because he's a genuine
student his ID card is valid but let's
just say it was expired two years ago
like he graduated two years ago this
does not give me you see there's a gap
in this I need to check validity as as
far as the expiry date as well
so yeah exactly that's what happens if
an SSL certificate is expired an
attacker can interlude in basically this
attack is called SSL streaming so what
it does is that the attacker basically
intercepts the SSL TLS handshake process
and then presents a fake SSL certificate
and then creates an established
Collective victim basically
so yeah
so always check the validity plus the
expiry date of the certificate if you
are doing that
each encryption I think I've talked
about it much so yeah basically the same
idea don't use anything that's outdated
such as classical ciphers low key size
using tests or encryption don't just do
that
because Brute Force attacks are common
confidentiality is reached and this is
one key takeaway that always use those
that has good Randomness first of all
and this is a Content a big concept I'm
going to explain it a little further as
well and then we have the key size as
well that the key size should be strong
enough so and then this one is strong
non-linearity so non-linearity is in
terms of s boxes as box as you know
stands for substitution boxes we see
those in Block ciphers let's just say a
yes that's in that we use these and
there's a proper concept it's not just
like you are making randomized desk
boxes it's not it doesn't really happen
that way
okay so key exchange without
Authentication
so this one is just a normal example
that I have created let's say there are
two parties A and B they want to
exchange a key a share key how they
actually do that they do it by this way
they have a generator called G and they
have B what they do is that they'll con
uh they'll calculate these values let's
say this B is a random number chosen by
P and this a is basically a random
number chosen by a what they do is that
they'll calculate these publics and then
they will share it with each other and
then again they'll do the same step and
they will reach a share key
let's discuss it in terms of an attacker
again if you can see here the attacker
because it's not being authenticated
what we'll do is that you will generate
a fake key or fly from y side I'm sorry
I label this error x f y this doesn't
really like sounds good because in maths
it boggles my mind also but yeah the
same concept what he will do is that he
will just distribute these values and
maintain two different connections with
A and B considering and making them feel
like they are talking to each other well
in reality they are actually not
so yeah exactly the same thing
so always when you are exchanging in key
it's a key element that you need to
authenticate the other party
incorrect usage of seeds and pseudo
random number generator so you can sing
it you can see this is a piece of code
and I have used this function called
Rand
so what this does is that it produces
random numbers according to a initial
generator which is here as strand one so
when this is fixed what it will do is
that it will always generate the same
like same random values so just like
this so if I have this piece of code
right here no many times no matter how
many times I run this I'll always get
these values so obviously these are not
random there's a pattern to it and when
there's a pattern to it obviously that
doesn't provides good security
so for security are two random number
generator should be used
and then we have use of RSA without oeb
so RSA as you know is an asymmetric
algorithm basically that you use here is
just a normal exercise that I have made
for you people so you can see there is a
modulus content then there is a public
key and then there are two messages M
and M1 and I have encrypted them using
the harnessing so Cipher is equals to
message raised to the power public key
and modulus yep so we have these two
ciphers can you actually tell
any different identify any pattern
between these
similar
the first one tells me that that
actually that these two ciphers contains
the exactly the same word that's one of
the details that I can identify from
this and then there's another one as
well what's the other one the other one
is oh sorry the other one is that the
same word is being encrypted twice in
the same sentence how do I find this
so here if you can see these were two
parts hello world and hello hello so I
encrypted them yeah I know some of you
might be thinking you didn't encrypted
them what you did was this public key is
one
when this is one obviously the message
is going to be less than modulus
but this was just to kind of give you a
context that happens in this way
obviously if I used large values for RSL
let's just say 1024 bits obviously it
would be it would take a little more
time but then again the idea is that RSA
is deterministic so you need to have a
way to figure it out so yeah those folks
that were giving your looks and he
doesn't do that I didn't do that what
he's trying to say so yeah so use a
optical asymmetric encryption padding
always say if you are using RSA though
what I recommend but I'm not a security
um
but generally for encryption asymmetric
ciphers are not that good they are used
for digital signatures or authentication
kind of stuff if you want
confidentiality you can use AES or ECC
uh elliptical curve cryptography for
this and these are just general RSA
issue like there's a common modulus
attack and what you need is that
sometimes you don't even need the
private key in order to get the main
message out of it and then this one is
chosen ciphertext this one is kind of my
favorite because you see let's say
you're an attacker and you get a cipher
text what you do with it is you multiply
it with a number I call let's say three
and you send that to the receiver now
obviously when the receiver will try to
decrypt that number you will not get the
right number because you fabricated it
so then you can go to the receiver and
say oh I'm really sorry I didn't know if
you got the wrong number can you send it
back to me and I can have a look I don't
know maybe these guys may what kind of
protocols and once you get that
decrypted number back you just need to
divide that with what you multiplied it
and you will get the original decrypted
number without actually having the
private key of that person then again
the whole security of RSA actually
depends on this modulus
yeah if you are able to break it into
two prime factors e and Q generally you
can make your own public or private keys
and then you can do whatever you need
what
so yeah basically basically this is the
whole summary of it so always choose the
right weapon know how to utilize your
weapon to Max there are problems in
every you need to make sure that you use
the right amount of security required
and have a holistic view of security
because when we are talking about let's
say confidentiality
we are I've only talked about RSA there
are so many other things you can look
forward to but just make sure that you
have in-depth knowledge of it and you
don't do something like I discussed
earlier uh where I said that you need to
follow the board Mass rumor right you
are just missing the bodmaster rule and
for that you found that normally or
whatever so yeah that's it thank you so
much