our joint good morning everyone uh yeah
welcome this talk uh we're going to talk
about spec driven research for Fun and
Profit this is just something an idea I
came up with when I was doing some
research it was based on reading specs
and standards if you've used it systems
you've used standard based systems and
pretty much the entire web runs on
standards so it's kind of an interesting
area and I think one that people can
dive into in terms of you think of it
what research you want to do next uh
probably started very very about me um
I've been in I.T and English security
for a bit over 20 years now
um uh I've been testing grizzla things
these days I am a senior security
advocate for a company called datadog if
you've never heard of us we are a SAS
based provider of monitoring
observability and security so this talk
is not about their job people want to
talk about that sort of thing afterwards
happy to do so I generally focus on
container security I don't see any of my
talks in the past probably realizes this
um Docker kubernetes that kind of thing
and I have had the opportunity to
present at a reasonable number of
Securities uh I looked up by my desk I
bought my lanyards uh I got there left
one of the front Securities one 2011 uh
and then the security two to three and
the 2018 one so I think I'm not quite
spoken the most Securities of anyone but
uh Graham used to beat people here so I
get one up on them so I might get my
title back anyway let's get on with the
top so
why why are we interested in specs and
standards why is this something we want
to know about well pretty much the
entire internet and various other
systems run on standards these things
are decided by
um when a new area of Technology comes
along and vendors are getting involved
in it they start thinking well we want
to our systems both to talk to each
other right we want everyone to be able
to interoperate to do this we need to
agree how we're going to handle data
processes protocols so they come up with
a standard uh the standard bodies
there's lots of them depending on the
area of Technology we'll typically say
okay there's a new area of Technology we
need a standard for this let's get
ongoing the reason why in addition to
like kind of obviously altruistic we
want to work together big companies big
end users of Technology like standards
right this is Dreadful Theory
Enterprises what's called vendor lock-in
so I buy something for one company
they're the only people that make it and
then if I ever want to leave I'm in
trouble I'm the contract negotiations
come around next year they know they've
got you because you can't move so end
user companies like standard based Tech
because they hopefully don't have that
login they can move to anyone else who
implements the same standard so there's
a good reason for this to happen
um the other thing is typically
sometimes when a technology becomes
popular maybe some vendor starts
something right and everything takes off
and everyone's happy they go well after
a while people are going to trust others
it's just our Tech so we'll donate our
technology to a standards body so you'll
see a lot of people when it's their kind
of early adopters they donate their work
to stand with bodies who then carry on
and when you have a standard you need a
specification you need something
detailed low level that everyone can
read and go okay I understand how
Implement worker in here I will be able
to interoperate with everyone else who's
done the same thing
so that's kind of where specs and
standards tend to come from
um so how do these things get written
right how do I get from we have this
idea of a standard to a detailed spec
and typically and I want to generalize a
little bit here
um typically this is done by lots of
people seeing your kind of I.T architect
types for big companies and Academia who
get together into a committee and sit
down for lots of time writing document
and if you think about what their
interests are you start to get an idea
of where we might have some fun from
security perspective all of these
companies want to make sure that in the
standards everything they need for their
software to work so there's lots of
incentives for them to put more things
into the standard more use cases because
they've all got complex big customers
with complex big use cases and they want
the standard to reflect all of the
things that they want to do right so
this tends to lead to standards
everyone's have a red standard you kind
of with the idea there's a lot of kind
of complex stuff in there and that's why
it happens because there's a lot of
interesting people making these things
big and worthy and covering every
possible use case so they tend to be
bigger rather than smaller
so that starts to get the idea might be
interested so I'll give an example just
gonna make this a bit real that was a
little bit abstract
um I'll talk a little bit about a thing
called saml uh if you're in Enterprise
I.T or if you ever use an Enterprise I.T
system you will have come across saml
security assertion markup language the
idea of this is it allows authentication
providers to talk to web applications in
a way say here is the credentials for
this user you can believe them when they
say they are who they say they are and
log them in and the idea is that lots of
different systems can talk to each other
using Samo
it came up in the mid 2000s as a spec
and it's all written in XML because back
in the mid-2000s everyone thought
everything should be XML luckily we
don't do that anymore
um but it's still there right and I use
some other day right uh I I've used
Google as my identity provider every
system I log into tends to be log into
your Samos it's a very heavily used
piece of tech
um and Samuel well this is a spec right
the spec is an 86 pages long uh this is
one section of the specs actually
2.4.1.3 I'm not going to try and go
through this the idea is to give you an
idea that this stuff gets a bit
complicated that's one second now
imagine you're a developer you have been
tasked with writing a saml
implementation and you have to make sure
that it does exactly what spec says you
have created pages of that record code
that works exactly as that spec says it
should work
no one would ever want to do this but
this is interesting from our point of
view because of
there's lots of security truisms out
there I don't actually subscribe to all
of them but I do subscribe to this one
um me I'm also people complexity is the
enemy of security the more complex a
system is the less likely it is to be
secure the reason is imagine I'm
guessing some people have written
programming code before when you write
code you're trying to keep in your head
what are what's my code flow what's all
the data going in and out what are all
the formats the more complex it is the
harder it is for you to keep that in
your head so the more complex you are
you're going to make mistakes things are
going to leave creep leap through the
cracks you're going to end up potential
security problems and then you imagine
being someone implementing this and
going there's absolutely no chance that
any one person is going to keep on their
head all the time so you'd have big
teams doing this and when you're big
teams then you have problems of Oh I
thought this meant that oh I thought
this meant this other thing great as a
researcher I'm going well that's great
because if you make mistakes you don't
understand it there's opportunity for
security people
is very much the enemy of security and
that's why I think specs are interested
in perspects are complex Things based on
specs are inevitably complicated
therefore they're inevitably not secure
as a rule
and I said what is that did that turn
out to be true in this case 247 cves say
yes there are 247 CVS that mention the
word Samo if you look through some of
them they're typically implementation
flows so some provider took us that
tried to write code then limited and
that's something
I'm not surprised but from a research
point of view that meant that 247
researchers got an icv to their names
and did some interesting research just
by reading one specification
um there's two types of flaws you get
typically when you've been through some
of these one is one of the art
implementation mistake right so someone
read this made a mistake fine you get
above it the other ones which are
interesting is think about the standard
writing process a committee of people
all got together and agreed that you
think they got respect 100 right they
didn't leave any edge cases that weren't
accounted for they didn't leave any
undecided variable bits the answer is no
of course they did spec issues are even
better but you get all the
implementations at once so if there's
something wrong with the spec I can go
around and get bugs in every single
um any implementation software his
example 247 Series so it's fair to say
this does happen
um so that was kind of like the theory
right the theory is are my idea of
hypothesis is that specs lead to
security flaws so let's look at a worked
example of this uh and this is a really
simplified kind of process that I went
through when I was doing some research
so
I'm not a full-time researcher by the
way this is more something I kind of do
in my weekends I know
um read investigation right first thing
gotta read the spec work out what's
going on find something interesting
looking and I'll talk about how I find
something interesting looking getting
implementation so get software which
implements the specification because
that's kind of stuff that'll have the
bugs in it run the experiment design it
run it successfully you're back to the
star
pretty simple sub restart process so the
way I did this the one I want to talk
about is they call the open container
initiative OCR so if you've used Docker
you've used kubernetes you've used
Codman use containers I guess most
people at least use some level of
containers they implement this thing uh
you the specs written by oci these were
one of the donated types so Docker wrote
These specs in the early days of
containers they then said well people
won't adopt this stuff if it's just us
because they'll be worried about vendor
locking so they donated them to a body
called the open container initiative
agenda Linux foundation and they now
manage develop and run these specs this
three there's the image spec so when you
pull a container image it's an OC part
of the OCR image spec that's the format
when you run it with Docker podman
containerdy
um that is runtime spec so anything
which runs containers and then you pull
it from Registries that are the oci
registry square right so three specs
I would look at the image spec right the
image spec was first one I looked at
um because well that's kind of easy I
use a lot of container images let's have
a look and see what the spec says so the
first thing to do is read this effect
luckily for me it's not 90 second pages
long I'll be honest with you if it was I
wouldn't have read it um it's more like
a 15 20 pages so this one wasn't
horrifically you know hard to look at
um if you're starting doing this yeah
simple specification don't do something
with XML stuff because your head will
explode
um the modern stuff is a bit kind of
nicer uh so I read the OCR image
specification it's a fillable like
pretty much all specs are available
online because obviously you can't write
implementations if you don't be
respectively available so the
information is always there for you to
read
is visualize what you're doing or I like
to try and visualize what I'm
researching I've read along document
let's try and reach like this percentage
all the different parts of container
image and how the specification says
they work right so it says an index
contains one or more manifests which is
obtained image manifest which contains
config image layer of subjects
where is something that could be
interesting where do I think there's
something which might be a bug or might
have something interesting to play with
from a security standpoint and I so I
went to look for an interesting part
I think before I came on was this
scripture so I noticed there were lots
of arrows all pointing at this one thing
so I thought okay that's interesting
because it's a used throughout image
spec so let's hone in on that and I said
what is a descriptor and it turns out
when you're describing a container image
that's oci format you everything is of
type descriptor right so you can put
anything which is part of the descriptor
type into any part of the spec okay cool
let's have a look at that so I looked
through all the different things I can
have in a descriptor and I said well
what could I play with iPhone URLs now
as soon as I saw URLs I then hit ah this
is potentially very interesting one I'd
never seen a URL in the container
um I've looked at ever so that's weird
uh two if I see URLs I think of a couple
of things
if it's a URL that means the systems
might make net requests right because
what are URLs there are things you
request online so this thing can have
URLs in it does that mean it will make
Network requests as soon as I put one of
these in that's an interesting one to
look at also URL parsing is a common
core source of security vulnerabilities
URLs are actually surprisingly complex
if you ever want to dig into quite how
weird URLs can be going with the kernel
the guy rights Carl has written some
blogs about exactly how weird URLs can
be if you think they're just HTTP called
way more complicated than that so this
potential parsing box as well and then
there's potential for things like server
side request portrait so that's a bug
where I can make some system make
Network requests on my behalf in a way
that's more trusted than I would be so
there's lots of things as soon as I see
URL I mention they go okay that's fun
let's go and play with URLs and see what
happens
um so I thought okay URLs let's let's
look at that and so the spec describes
it and this is what the spec says about
the URL field because you can find out
and see what it's meant to do so this is
kind of really simple it says this
optional property specifies a list of
your iPhone which is what you've maybe
downloaded each entry must conform to an
RFC entries should right
the interesting thing for me where
optional should be made and you'll
notice they're all caps if you're
wondering why they're all caps there is
a spec which describes how you write
specs unless there's several there's a
spec RFC 2119 which says what these
words in caps mean and the in the case
of optional should me it says this if
you're implementing this you don't have
to do this bit but you can right so they
don't have to put this in
as a researcher I like optional men
should for a couple of reasons it means
that different interpretations might
handle it differently so I might get
bugs where one implementation does it
this way one in police does it
differently because it should and
optional it's also code that won't be
heavily tested right
as a researcher you're looking for stuff
or people missed and look at things that
people didn't look for things that are
optional tend not to be truly test
Suites because why would I test that as
optional I never do it okay cool I'm
gonna look for anything which is
optional in a spec so now I've got a URL
and I've got the fact that it's optional
cool this sounds like at least worth
looking at it's at least we're playing
on but in general if you're looking
through specs look for those words and
you'll find them lots of places specs
are amazing for like conditional weird
things that no one ever uses but
typically when developers are writing
implementations they'll just put
everything in there because like hey at
some point if you're someone might want
this I might as well write the code
while I'm writing it
so what can we do with this so that's
like well what can I what would this
mean say I I do this and it would
actually does something what are the
security vulnerabilities I might find
well one I might be able to create
tracking right if I'm successful in
embedding a URL that is is then pulled
every single time someone gets this
image I can track their use of the image
so I can start I mean people and people
don't expect that they don't expect that
image to track you and create Telemetry
so that's interesting maybe I can do
that I might get ssrf right what can I
do if I can make a cool URL under the
control of the container engine that's
running this container potentially that
I might also get I didn't actually put
up here I should have done URL parsing
box so I may get an actual vulnerability
and an implementation where it powers of
the URL I give it some weird URL with
lots of different parameters in it and
it complains crashes or maybe actually
does something like you know gives me
access to the system so this is
impossible that's it
um get implementations right I need
software to actually import this to work
out whether this is really a problem or
just something in the spec that's kind
of interesting so in the case of oci um
this this is quite a few different
implementations you can get your hands
on
first one's container runtimes right
container runtimes are the things that
run containers so when they go they're
going to pull my images they're going to
run them these are the things I want to
actually get down and play with luckily
it's all open source super easy if
you're doing some specs you have to
watch because a lot is implemented
property software can be harder to get
implementations but pretty much
everything container land is free Docker
is the original uh OG software that
everyone has used
um containerd is actually used by Docker
but also works Standalone with a program
called nerd metal for reasons I don't
know why they call that and Portman is
Red Hats Red Hat doing everything in
containers their own way because they're
red hat
um and they have their own tools forever
I can then get container Builders things
which can build images so if my research
is around container images I need to
have tools to drilled images Docker
build exit build up again build eyes red
has one doctor bill Lexus the uh it's
the new version of Doctor's Notebook
tools Scorpio crane there's some tools
that muck around with images they move
them they translate them they upload
them download them inspect them so
they're interested as well
and container Registries I need to put
my images up somewhere and have them
retrieved there's loads of these and
they all pretty much Implement these OCS
specs so Docker Hub ghcr key there's
also the cloud providers about their own
registers too so there's lots of
opportunities here and these are the
ones I looked at there's probably more
but those are the ones that kind of good
starting point
so design experiment right I now have a
thesis I have this idea URLs could be
interesting I have some software let's
go things to play with once I played
them so how do I actually get the point
of designing an Instagram
so this is what a container image
actually is if you've ever done Docker
run something and you've actually run it
if you actually container images are
actually just turbos which is kind of
nice if you want to play around with
them because you literally just save
them out of Docker and untour them it's
literally just tart so it's nice and
easy to do and this is what they
actually look like when you're getting
them index and manifest Json and oci
layer are just this is how this can turn
laid out everything is in these blobs
um the blobs are all identified as sharp
2500 caches it can either be a manifest
at this created the image it can be the
configuration of the container image or
all the files but everything just lives
as these blobs with the kind of shower
hatches and the show hash is interesting
because that's how it verifies you
haven't mocked with it if you mess with
these things it should have changes as
soon as you change one character that
shot has completely changes so that's
what you end up having to kind of like
where all your information ends up being
so I got one of these this is a really
simple I also recommend when you're
doing something like this start with the
simplest possible version of the
software you don't want to make it more
complex if you're doing experiments this
is as simple as possible image this is
just busy box literally very simple
image and I got the first file which was
the index manifest and it looks a bit
like this
you see it describes the compact there
and it describes the layer of the
container image but that's the pressure
the Magnificent what you will notice is
there's no URLs and I looked quite a few
images I got from various Registries
none of them use this URL field it's
totally unused
um but it's available so what I did was
work out where I put a URL
and I ended up working out you put it
there it's a Json file
um so it's if you know Json format it's
pretty easy I basically added a URL to
that config section
um and what I did was I got a domain
name
UK actually using one of the many
dominions I bought which is nice to do
rather just leave them waiting there to
get renewed in two years time
um but yeah I actually use this once I
use and I basically put a file that had
the Shah name of the same as the compact
right so these things match up
um so that was the exact same content as
they are so that it doesn't complain
when it actually pulls it and I said
okay that's was a good day and then I
bundle that back up and copied it back
up to container Registries so I modified
it got my experiment got my my uh URL in
there and I send up to container
Registries and then see what happens
um a little quicker say if you're doing
any testing around web stuff so around
ssrf you want like test something where
you want a reliable URL that you control
it's great if the best way of doing srf
testing or any other kind of HTTP test
is get a URL you control and you will
log because then when you're you can
tell your thing your experiment is
working because you're using blind
experiments it's really hard to tell
it's actually working or not get a URL
you control the way I do this I've got a
little very cheap EPS running caddy
caddy is a reverse proxy software and
web server software it's very very
flexible this is the config section I
use for this experiment I would
recommend if you're looking into that
thing look into caddy one of its best
tricks is if you give it a valid domain
name you can just say in the config file
PLS and it'll go with less encrypt and
it'll get a valid certificate and it'll
bring it down so it'll get TLS errors
because a lot of software users will
birth out because of TLS error how does
it all for you you don't worry about how
certificates work really really handy so
I've got a link at the end for some more
info and but definitely just doesn't say
we'd recommend
run experiment okay we've now got our
experiment we've got our our image that
we bundled up with a URL in it we have
got
um our implementation software my
importance
so what happened uh well what happened
was I this is my candy Loper and um what
I found was that when I was calling him
just about you running them you just
pull it down to a horse with some of
these container tools I would get a pain
and the bits I've highlighted are very
handily what the what this software does
is it tends to tell you in this user
agent exactly what it was to pull it so
it tells you the software name so I know
exactly which tool it was that triggered
it and tells me the software version
which is kind of interesting because if
there's ever a vulnerabilities in that
software I get kind of told in advance
which is nice because I get to know what
versions are running
so I got lots of different uh things
depending on the tools I was using but
that was useful because then right you
could prove this is working right I know
this isn't they've done this stuff
because like television is random people
believe I did publish a vlog about this
I started getting weird like hits from
various people girls and clicking links
in my or copying the URL but thanks for
that but you can tell the difference
because it's the ones that actually have
good user agents on them
so success or failure well in this case
I got my pings this is kind of what I
was going for this is this is the the
outcome I looked for when I did this
it looked a bit like this
um and there was a couple of interesting
things Docker never ever picked so
despite Docker supporting oci images and
being the tool most people use it would
never pull the URL
my theory is there that what Docker is
doing is it's converting it to us it had
its own proprietary format that existed
before oci I think what it's doing when
it's loading an image it's converting it
back to its proprietary format and just
ditching the URL which is interesting
continuity pod and Scorpio they all ping
quite happily and all of them support
oci even Docker Hub which is again kind
of built on the older Tech it supports
ocean averages so it worked this image
worked in every one
um
in terms of the outcome uh I did
whatever hopefully good ethical security
researcher would do at this point and I
reported it so I said this is something
which is in your spec but it has some
unintended side effects right
essentially I can now build an image
that will track any user of that image
people who run containers probably don't
think that's something that can happen
so it's unintended functionality it also
has the risk of blinding ssra so if I
give you a crafted URL and you run my
image I can make a request anywhere in
your infrastructure
is that a security problem well it's not
right it it's pretty digital I'll be
honest and say I don't think that's
something everyone's got to worry about
but it's definitely not intended it's
not something that should be happening
basically they said yep we recognize
that is his security issue it's not
something that's ideal however it's in
the spec and it's not that high risk so
fundamentally we're probably not going
to change it so you have to help list
all works if you want to believe this I
don't think they'll ever fix this
because it is part of the spec so to fix
it they would have to remove that from
the spec and whilst I don't think and
this is what the other thing about specs
is once it's in the spec it never goes
people never remove things from spec
they add new things to Specs but they
almost never remove things from respect
so that will that behavior will work
forever so if you're ever in a
circumstance where you need to track
someone using container image I pretty
much guarantee this will always work if
they're not using go
I learned a lot about the OCR spec this
is probably the best reason to do
research I'm honest
um it forces you to learn the low level
details of how stuff works I now know
exactly pretty much how to build
container images from scratch with text
editors and tar which I did not know
before so I learned it which is always a
great way I also had some fun side
effects
um I was playing around like tarring up
my image and then like trying out
various tools and I found that if I used
to talk man basically a little bit
differently
um some vulnerability scanners stopped
recognizing the image so Docker would
still run the image quite happily but
vulnerability scares would that's not a
valid image I'm just not going to do
anything with it so again that's another
potential security side effect
um I could bypass phone scanners
depending on how I construct my image in
time I reported that one turns out it's
a some sort of weirdness in the
underlying Library so it will get fixed
but probably no time soon
um I also think that image that some
container tools will run While others
can just ditch it so I've got an image
that Docker will run by Apple because it
doesn't do anything about URLs if I put
an invalid URL there also view that URL
and you basically make it an invalid URL
cordman and container they always go
that's invalid I'm just going to ditch
it I'm not going to run
so again you can imagine a circumstance
where maybe for example a security check
is done by something running continuity
and then the container itself runs using
Docker it will bypass a security check
because the security says that's not
invalid that's not a valid image that's
not where to run the doctor says yes it
is I'm quite happily going to run that
so this is where implementations and
differences in implementations can be
kinda interesting
um not gonna happen every time but I can
imagine that being something that that
apparently foreign
I'm far from finished on this one and
other things I always think you're doing
or anyone else is thinking wow we'll see
how it looks super fun I wanted to do
research on that things you could look
at
um weight at all ci2 and things get and
parse and look at container images there
are websites you can get that will do
things like inspect images well I'm
embedding URLs potentially what do
things that cause them to get it this
scope there
um however they handle URLs the other
another element in that descriptor thing
is data and it basically just says this
can contain data a64 coded data but it's
not super well specified how container
runtime should actually do handle that
so what happens if I put a huge data
section if I put gigs of data into
complex action will it crash obviously
when you get into crash bugs be a bit
more careful with third-party systems I
wouldn't go uploading gigs of data in a
complex section to a public registry
because you break it whilst technically
you'll be okay I wouldn't want to be
receiving end of that call
um so there are attention to look there
there's other elements there's related
specs so the runtime spec and
distribution spec they just take how you
run containers and how you store
containers so you can look there as well
and also specs as a big change suspect
new versions of specifications will come
out all the time OCR currently writing
version 1.1 it's got some new features
to handle things like container signing
the way container signing is yep is
handled the moment is pretty hacky if
I'm honest so this will actually improve
that as well so there's universities
spec which obviously new potential
problems
more information I'll put these slides
online on Twitter afterwards and
Mastodon but just some other ones I
would recommend that post there
um de-essified security researchers by
research from NCC it's a really great
post on the process of research and like
like how it works
um well recommend that I've written up
this if you want more on this particular
vulnerability I've written up that
vulnerability uh and how you do it and
then also if you want some more stuff
about caddy and how to use caddy for
testing I've upload there for that as
well it's an easy to read development
questions
we've got a couple of questions now or
otherwise email Mastered on Twitter
while it's still up
um it's available as well
any questions
feel please contact later
yep
yeah I think I think it's a great way of
doing it because as I said there's
it it benefits for as an approach
because you can do it in a kind of
really structured way you can take a
spec especially in your specs because
the older ones like the 2000s ones
they've been pretty heavily you know
like attacked but there's always new
specifications coming out in the weary
I'm in Cloud native people are like
specifying Cloud native there's a lot of
stuff around there
um so yeah as I kind of approach to
research just going through it looking
for every measured optional must
and then just trying out that process
right just run through the process of
getting implementations what happens if
I do something weird to X put lots of
data images format of data
um one thing that
kind of it well the other thing is that
you can find internally in
implementations is
um some languages where you get code
written in different languages
containers almost always go on but some
people write things in other languages
as well like rust C whatever
um you find weirdnesses in things like
how they handle fundamental data so
golang is very very strict on IP
addresses if you give it one of those
weird formatted Optical or hex IP
addresses it just goes no that's not
valid rust and c will go oh that's
completely valid IP address I lacked on
it so there's lots of fun there to be
had as well and just like looking at an
implementation written in one language
implementation written another language
these languages do things differently
that's going to introduce potential for
bugs so yeah I think for students is a
great idea to like um pick a spare and
dive in and even if you find no fun bugs
you'll still learn something about how
that technology works
any other questions