yeah so hi everyone
um as the title suggests
um the question that's on my mind as
well even as real media in the present
day
um and to get into that I'm going to
cover in Broad Strokes
um where we sort of started with media
how we got to what we have today
um what
what is wrong with it from obviously the
security side of it I mean we're all
security people here
um
what are the sort of
policies and procedures in place that
keeps this information and
misinformation at bait and then what we
need to do to solve all these problems
that we're seeing in the present day
um
so I'm an Alum here ever take
um so I thought might as well give a
talk at security because I didn't manage
to do it in my 10 year
um I used to be a consumer security
consultant so for a few years I was
doing the the app and network pen testy
stuff
um and then I moved into becoming a
developer just creating things
is no better feeling to be honest so
I'm currently working on a provenance
focused social media it's called frankly
and I will be talking about it later but
right at the end because I'm not trying
to make a sales pitch
um so we'll start off then with like the
background of media
um
so a little disclaimer as well that a
lot of what I'm going to be talking
about and focused on is images
I'm not trying to belittle the world of
those with vision issues
um but it's just that there's so much
content
um in this world and are in this space
rather in images are the easiest way to
get the sort of ideas across
um
so
the
the way that we would capture a lot of
ideas and events in the past was very uh
was based on these two mediums like
painting and drawing what we saw and
writing
um the tales of what happened
um very opinion based written commentary
and
then when it comes to Art and the actual
drawing process it takes a lot of time
to like capture that into a medium and
you're not exactly in a position where
you can simply draw up something that
you've even never seen as well yourself
so you need to have also been present
and there's elements of word of mouth
and so on that really plays into all
this
um
so yeah they're not exactly the perfect
mediums for capturing things exactly how
they occurred
um
and this led to some interesting results
and this is the first part of audience
participation if it decides to go for it
okay it's already given you the answer
but let's pretend that we didn't see
that and guess what all these different
animals are
um if anyone actually wants to give a
guess or we're just gonna skip
feel free
because I mean that one's an absolute
State on the top left there
um
yeah
and then
yeah so obviously different stages of
its life cycle is what you're trying to
say in those captions here yeah
um a lot of this misinformation around I
mean spoiler obviously came up
hippopotamuses
um a lot of it came around the the
actual name of a hippo it translated to
like War Horse so obviously you know you
you look you hear War Horse and you draw
like the
the swan thing or some fish with extra
legs like
you needed to sort of
again this clickers shape yeah
you needed to be there see it
um you needed to
you know be present and obviously that's
not possible like these things live in
very specific climates and here in
Scotland that's quite pilgrimage just to
see a hippo
um
so the gossip the rumors that the spoken
word around these things would conjure
images that obviously didn't
reflects what was real and again these
mediums are slow people aren't going to
stop in the middle of pillaging a
village so that the picture can be or
the painting can be drawn
um and
the written word about what happened
if everyone in said Village was taken
out who's actually going to write about
it from the point of view of the
defender so
thankfully when Tech Advanced it took
away a lot of the limitations
um in terms of capturing what was real
and what happened
um
sound waves uh light photons they
weren't just a transient thing they just
flew by never to really occur again in
the same fashion and it was something
that was captured then into medium
in terms of chemical film uh obviously
it was quite a
specific set of events needed to happen
in order to capture it
um appropriately so
there is an element of trust and the the
science behind it
um
and yeah of course the point that I I'm
trying to place here with the um the
dates is that What mattered most is when
the majority of people started to have
the opportunity to access this Tech
commercial cameras and Commercial record
players uh gramophones Etc capturing it
in the house
um and then the combination of these two
to
result in video as well
so
in terms of audio music took on a whole
new depth of appreciation and we're able
to play it in the homes
um science uh didn't uh used to be in
fact like a audience style thing where
some guy would be up down here at the
front performing a science experiment
and it was down to all the people who
witnessed it to spread the news of what
the the experiment yielded
um
and then journalism as well in the form
of the newspaper
um
it took a long time for photos to
actually be incorporated in there but of
course seeing those things
provides a bit more assurance that it
happened there's an element of feeling
present
um and you wouldn't think anyone would
abuse it
[Music]
um
but of course that happens this is one
of the more lighthearted first examples
of abuse with photography
um
these are uh two of the five photos
referred to as the cartingly fairies
which are quite a fun example of what
amateur photographers in 1917 were able
to come up with
um trying to replicate Slice of Life
Life imagery where they were interacting
with fairies and gnomes
and um
none other than the scientific main
behind Sherlock Holmes Arthur Conan
Doyle who was a massive spiritualist
I saw these photos and was like
I saw the proof I need
I'm gonna spread the good word
and at the time I believe he was working
a newspaper company so it was like I
want to get it printed I want to tell
the world I want everyone to know and
they were like they're obviously fake
and he's like I'll prove it it went to
three different validators for this
imagery
um one of them being Kodak
um two of those companies then agreed
the photos aren't tampered with like
these are real photos because yeah the
photos weren't edited and post it was a
staged event
um the guys at Kodak specifically said
like
this obviously isn't real but like the
photo itself wasn't doctored he's like
good enough for me getting it printed
yeah
so that's like an idea of what an
individual was capable of uh even quite
early on in the commercial photography
times
um and then you go into nation states as
well and the both of these of course
being
thought was of the same man different
times of his life Joseph Stalin
um
a lot of people see this one on the left
of him when he was quite a young man
um and it's quite funny because I
recently realized that this even was
slightly doctored
this was after he'd already died some
Museum was setting up an exhibit of like
look at all our sexy leaders I guess and
they put the Vaseline filter on them and
when he was younger he had like acne
scarring obviously it's quite a minor
minor thing but like they edited the
photo to make them look a lot more
younger and
have more attractive leader I guess it's
a bit weird
um
but then separately as well
um those of you might be familiar with
the new Google product Magic Eraser and
Stalin was really good at that and
cutting out a young lad there called
Nikolai
um who was just kicked out of the
Communist Party
um and obviously wanted to change what
actually happened and say well I was
never associated with this man
um
yeah
so
like I said earlier as well it used to
be that the the systems to capture this
imagery was quite a straightforward
process it was the laws of physics and
chemistry and uh the light was in itself
painting the scene onto the film
and there was no middlemen no gadgetry
um no SD cards you know there's no
interpretation for how it happened
there's no way to manipulate that
particularly easy easily especially when
you've got this Source you can always
point to the film and say well this is
the original like this is how it happens
but nowadays we have a lot more CCD
sensors there's still some die hards
um film photography sort of people out
there but
um when these
started to become particularly
affordable in the mid 80s
um
the photography Community are the people
who are really uh passionate about
film-based photography we're sort of
sounding the alarm like this is it truth
is truth is going away but we largely
ignored them because like you know
what's the worst that can happen
um
and then we spread run even further
um all those scientific advancements we
know just carry them about in our
pockets
um
we're able to consume all the cat dog
media uh that we like
um so yeah no one uses it for anything
that important so we're all fine I guess
well
yeah of course
it isn't all cat and dog foods
um there's a whole rabbit hole again
going on with Animal Club
um that we can go down
um of all the different facets of
society that really rely on media in
order to convey a sense of trust
um
I don't want a cherry pick
all right I don't wanna
try and cover the whole Spectrum there
um so I will cherry pick rather citizen
journalism
um as a good example of what we need to
be
focusing some of the effort on at the
moment
we used to consume our news through an
AM PM paper
um again like media started to build
itself into there to make you feel
present with the media make you feel
like a witness to the events um that
occurred in the present as well
um but with the modern world and these
modern devices comes a modern
consumption habit
um
some people
myself included rely on Independent
reviewers on YouTube to say is this
technology actually going to be you know
the one that I want uh to bring
something into the house or even
quite a few steps further their Facebook
groups that circulate their politically
charged content amongst themselves
slightly Echo team very fashion but
regardless a lot of that in order to
convey points is through media
um
and when you combine Facebook and
Instagram under the metasphere that's
like
1.65 billion images being uploaded daily
um according to one source and then
um on YouTube there was another source
that said in June of 2022
um for every minute it was 500 hours of
content being uploaded
um
and then there's uh crazy Elon buying
Twitter and you know making truth and
like authenticity eight dollars a month
so
um
from the citizen journalism space and
especially when a lot of these pieces of
media get circulated up to the bigger
organizations
um we're relying on fact checking
mechanisms
um to validate each individual piece of
media before it gets published in a more
official manner
um and relying on forensics
investigations uh methods just to ensure
that there hasn't been any tampering
with a lot of these pieces of media
um
and then of course the grease the wheel
there's obviously elements of automation
for both
um to ensure that there's no mess or
disinformation being brought into the
modern news cycle
um those things do happen of course
there's examples that I'll go into later
um that
I mean a good one I actually don't have
in the slides later that I'll go into is
um game footage from ARMA 2
um a military simulator getting put on
the BBC News is a headline story because
they thought it was captured in the
field like
so
yeah I mentioned messing this
information and if there's subtle
differences between these two that I
just wanted to quickly address
um mess information
is the less serious one
um it's more or there's less harm and
misinformation life's importance and
typically the information being
misconstrued
um it's more like rumors insults and
pranks
um but then you go into this information
and that's
media content that's out there to
deliberately deceive people into a false
narrative
propaganda
um fishing
and just general hoaxes
um would fall more under that category
um
like I said that's the two main axis is
that Define the to or where it fits
between the two different terms of
course I'll use it synonymously but
things like
Fades are evidence of fairies that lives
in the middle like is it that important
that it's this information
um I don't know that's why it falls
within the
start space but I'll use them
interchangeably
um
and it's all personal opinion as well I
mean I personally would think that
cosmetic brands touching up The Afters
on a before and after for their new
products that falls into mess
information
see with it
Kylie Jenner and stuff are doing or
they're like photoshopping their thumb
out of like these Instagram photos that
they're putting up as part of their ad
campaigns yeah but the importance there
isn't too high as the consumer you can
obviously just not buy that product but
then things like War propaganda and
showing upholstered interpretation of
troops or equipment
um that's life's at stake the importance
shoots up
um even if it's only one extra tank for
example
um that's that's quite firmly in
disinformation
oh I don't know how that go in there
but yeah so
the big issues then that really we see
um
from a societal perspective like the
idea of these filters coming in
um is obviously body image issues you
see a lot of that but generally like
just having those little subtle edits is
the default mode and it makes it hard to
obviously guess like what's actually
real and what's not
um
I have a few images or videos that I
might show at the end and that really
put the point across here but I'm scared
keynote will crash on me or something
um
so
yeah and because of the accessibility of
these things it's trivial why wouldn't
you do it is almost becoming the
narrative which is uh a little bit
disappointing
um
and then we don't even need to have like
someone stood in front of the camera and
the photo being taken to manipulate it
we can simply stage the event like I
mentioned with ARMA 2 and what BBC News
decided was headline content
um
there's
cases where you can just simply you know
spawn a tank in one of those things and
take a video of that or you know
taking photos of people that don't
generally or they don't actually exist
and again the main stress and the
importance here is that this has become
so trivial
um
there's yeah there's no need for the
real camera to be there you feed your
photo into
a system enough times and it can maybe
even generate photos of you on the beach
for example
um
especially through systems like
generative AI which are really taking
the scene things like chat GPT and all
of the different image based models
um
it's one of the greatest disinformation
machines that I've kicked out recently
um it's not all the silly that deep
faked audios of trump and Biden on the
headsets that I'm sure everyone else has
been seeing on Twitter recently which
honestly cracked me up but
um there is the greater impact
um things like at its worst revenge porn
people's faces being put onto the
actresses and particular scenes or even
again coming back to fishing
um using someone's
real face gives an opportunity for you
to reverse and find whether or not that
person actually sent you a message
um
and then the consequences for a lot of
this stuff hasn't been
um nation state levels yet
but for example
um one maliciously generated political
speech May
like the Pakistan and India situation
into further disarray
um America and China
uh Russia NATO so there is obviously
some real impacts that can be seen that
could potentially be Targets in the
future but
uh I'll bring it back a bit we'll have a
little fun game of audience
participation that will hopefully work
this time
um
I'm gonna show four photos
these first two
um here that I'll just keep on screen
whilst I explain
um basically
I've generated some AI faces and it's a
matter of what do you believe are the
real humans and which do you believe are
the AI faces here
um here's the last two
I'll give you another moment here
I'm obviously using the contrast of this
monitor or projector to my advantage
um but
yeah
if anyone wants to have a guess at who
is real who is not
um feel free yep
you think image one is fake do you have
any idea why
this is
okay
yeah the the light Reflections yeah
um
no that's fair I mean that's obviously a
major part of it and the sense of
uncanny valley that you might be
experiencing through that uh yeah
oh the shoulder on the right hand side
or just the lack of shoulder in the left
yeah
um
any other guesses
uh sure sure
yeah
I'll take the last two that I saw here
starting with you
yep that's a good show you're getting to
what I'm about to go into in a minute
and last one up there
yeah I mean all the features are
Telltale sounds but yeah the ears are
certainly one that especially in most
headshots that these things will be
taking in like it may not have like a
lot of side profiles to train on the
ears too well
um
and these photos all look a lot more
human than some of the ones from liquid
but I'll assure you that none of these
are actually real
um
someone and besage Basingstoke actually
caught on that quite quickly I was
impressed but yeah none of these
um are real here
um I'm trusting the clicker again for a
while but uh we made this thing
um in order to spot the Deep fakes
um
I'm just borrowing it because I was a
bit lazy to write my own so this is
quite focused on video but things like
asymmetric jewelry can be a really big
giveaway because that's not typically
the focus of someone who's declaring a
success case to these algorithms
um so especially when it comes to
glasses noticing little bumps
um can really help
um obviously yes you mentioned earlier I
think in the middle about the teeth
um sometimes it doesn't understand how
many incisors a person should have for
example so noticing three or one or one
and a half
um is quite useful
um I'll go into a few extra examples
here as well so
this is what I was saying about the
asymmetric jewelry where on the I'll
just do this instead on the left ear is
some weird like drippy metal jewelry
thing and then on the right there's
nothing and it's like
yeah okay the asymmetric jewelry
obviously does exist but this does not
look intentional in any form
um
and again I'm I use the projector to my
advantage but the hairs on the one on
the right start to get a bit wispy and
like the transparency just completely
glues to shot
um if you're looking at it on the screen
that I've got down here you can see a
little bit of like rainbow colors just
like clipping through as a result
the final one in terms of like uh
glasses here and it just straight up
clips into the cheekbone
um and then there's whatever the
that demon thing is in her shoulder
um like especially again when you're
looking at it on my screen down here and
it looks like they've rendered like
forearm style skin so you have like
really hairy like shoulder thing going
on
um
and it's pretty cracks and that thing's
in my dreams uh so yeah
and this is the the halfway point recap
for anyone who's nursing the security
hangover
um so I talked about the hippo drawings
all quite quickly as a result of my
slides coming up
um so describe why we needed the cameras
obviously in the first place they solved
the misinformation of just Word of Mouth
um
I then went into the cases of some of
the early edits to show that this isn't
a new problem it's just getting easier
um
and the cats out of the bag in terms of
these tools already we can't exactly run
backwards and yeah the potential
societal harm is obviously real uh
equally to individuals and again I
quickly brushed on it but like
self-image is obviously one that's
getting quite uh hit quite hard
um with these sort of tools and these
sort of filters
um
so what can we do to fix these problems
if you think about it from the
perspective of like every edit it's a
bad edit it just makes this a bit more
of a binary question for now
um so we could train the user to just
find all bad or all edits all the time
um this is an example here of uh North
Korea in 2013 sending out some
propaganda about how they ordered in
some new hovercraft
um obviously they didn't all arrive so
they ended up having to fake a little
bit of it
um
so these two hovercraft here are very or
the angle of attack they're coming into
on the beach is the exact same the
lighting is the exact same and where the
people are even standing on it or the
exact same Beyond you considering the
fact that they are perhaps the same
hovercraft it's just a bit too
coincidental you run it through some
forensic Stills as well and it just
straight up shows it's a copy paste job
and the same with those two boats at the
back
um and the boxes there represent zooming
these things to the exact same size and
it really just Paints the picture and
that yeah that's it's just a really bad
copy paste job
um obviously they've had 10 years to
improve on it uh this is 2013.
um
but yeah we could teach the user with
examples like this how to detect these
things right we could uh teach them the
same way that I did earlier with the AI
tools so what does everyone think is
that going to work
uh
rhetorical question no I don't think so
I mean fishing emails
um that's that's a solved problem right
uh you know no one's clicking on them
anymore
um
yeah the the skillshit or skill set
shouldn't be a prerequisite and we
shouldn't have to do a Pearson view exam
to make a Facebook account for example
right
um and the tools I mentioned obviously
that was 2013. and they're just the
tools and the methods are only going to
get more sophisticated
um so training is going to fall behind
uh no shot so you know let's maybe leave
it to the professionals the people that
have gone through this training and who
do it as a job right they both jump on
the keyboard and smash through all the
content that's coming in
um
again just assuming all edits are bad
edits just for the sake of getting that
sort of warning almost that this may
contain an edit or this does contain
that just to make the user a bit more
informed that might be the way to do it
uh not really
um
we can't expect people to pull the
all-nighters to get through the what was
it 500 hours of content per minute on
YouTube
um and we certainly
aren't going to see someone volunteer
pay for it YouTube is already making
profit and they claim and that sort of
they're just making profit and they're
not gonna then sacrifice a whole bunch
of their own profits to make
misinformation and disinformation and
solve the problem
um and the users as well they're gonna
hit the delays that are incurred through
this review process it's just not gonna
really work and there's not always
videos being uploaded publicly there's
the unlisted for example on YouTube and
there's the groups the private groups
and Facebook
um and even in Twitter spaces
um people aren't going to just be happy
that one extra human from outside is
looking into it
um
so
we maybe roll back how we're training
people
uh we incur a bit more of a journalistic
perspective on it just focusing on the
content that's trying to be portrayed
and did that happen is that really or is
that an unedited photo not looking too
far into it just like a do you see a
flying Peg or anything crazy like that
um understanding who was the uh author
of the piece of media who was captured
in it uh getting some context clues of
when where and why they were there
um you can then start to narrow down
contextually as well like was this real
based on you know if they said they were
in
like Dundee at this time of year well
the sun wouldn't have been out
um so why is that a sunny image or it
was raining that day there's historic
records to prove that
um or that's straight up for Eiffel
Tower in the background that's that's
not quite right
um
again you know
not all cases are equal as well when it
comes to this sort of stuff so you would
end up sacrificing
some of the Lesser scene content you're
just relying on people to talk about the
most important stuff
um
that sometimes works like
Twitter birdwatch
[Music]
um
not too bad it's sort of confirming that
the content and claims being made
um on your behalf
um
but it relies on like a stack Overflow
style contribution manner uh compared to
stack Overflow because I'm a developer
it's just the easiest way to compare it
for myself
um
yeah it does an okay job but again as
mentioned it relies on
um focusing on a subset of the overall
content and
then as well you need to consider who
are these Anonymous people who are
contributing the answers and why are we
meant to trust them uh you go back to
even
uh stack Overflow and chat gpt's
emergence
um and they got inundated with answers
so stack Overflow questions that were
generated from chat GPT
um so
um the
bit of a big block of text I'll tell
they are
um they basically put in a policy to say
don't do it even if the answer is right
because it's just too much
and we we need to just sort of
chill out with it so
what if we get something else in you
know an AI is generating all this
content so let's get an AI to capture it
and then declare whether or not it's
real right
um so
it's an okay idea at the start but then
when that Tool's out there someone else
who's making even if the tool comes out
and it's perfectly able to capture every
single bad piece of content
some point new content will be made that
then can bypass it and the bad guys then
have leveraged to Now train their
generator to be better and we get stuck
in this order Boris
which reminds me as well of antivirus
you know problem solved in the 90s when
we came out with the first one right
um
you go beyond even the check some
methodology that original antiviruses
would have been based on and you talk
about modern day heuristics and
pattern-based checks
um it's still obviously a little bit of
a losing battle when everyone's able to
generate the stuff themselves
um
so
this is the final quarter of the sites
um
maybe we should go from a reactive
analysis from all these all this content
that's been generated to a proactive
validation that what you're generating
um Is Real at the time it was captured
um
this is similar to an existing system
called provenance
um
there's the three examples here of
paintings diamonds and airplane Parts
where as soon as possible a record of
its in its creation and its life cycle
is established
um
as soon as diamonds are maimed they're
sent up um an illegal uh and our legal
main it's sent up to be laser engraved
in order to establish a
removal from the ground and it's
entering into the market
and and that's to
remove the possibility of malicious
diamonds making it in from who are refer
to his blood means
um or blood diamonds sorry they're
referred to us
um additionally in terms of paintings
I'm not always as on the exact moment of
creation uh Records being generated but
maybe a few months or years after and
someone comes in and validates that the
materials that were in use and the
methods that were in use
um and carbon dating all of that like
the time that they expect it to be have
created
um states that there should be made by
the person who they say it was made from
um and again similar to diamonds at the
moment of creation airplane Parts they
get the ID on them as well so
if you compare this into digital media
there's a seamless duplication
from every single file as you copy and
paste it across your hard disk but
and there's a lot of
media that is being generated all the
time and the obviously I mentioned
earlier but computers are really good at
the boarding stuff and just doing this
really rope fashion of like
following along with that massive volume
of content in the first place so
could we take some of the qualities from
a system of provenance like this and
replicate that into a digital system
so
that's a bit of what I've been working
on recently
um and the ideas that I think should
take place going forward to help
curb this information
um
there's already some Solutions on the
Shelf as well that can contribute to
a ledger of all of these actions being
or all of these images taking being
taken and where they came from
um
systems I'm referring to are called
distributed ledgers
um
and I'll elaborate on what that is for
those of you that don't know
in a timely fashion of course
um
so ledgers are like a database where you
record every single transaction that
happens
um so every single time something is
added or removed and it's just something
that's added to the overall structure
um and it's not
a point in time capture like databases
are so distributed letters then takes
this technology or takes these captures
and spreads them across multiple systems
um the network between each other using
a system called consensus
um so that they speak to one another in
order to confirm the state that they're
at what has been added who added it and
is it okay to come into the Ledger
um
so
they reach this state of consensus
between themselves that's cool
um
yeah blockchain's evolved from that
system and proof of Base trust or yeah
they brought in an element of an element
of proof-based trust
um to address some concerns they had
with too many people trying to be
involved in individual transactions
um
I'm not trying to buy into all the
racist nft hype I'm just talking about
it as if it's a tool so don't worry
um and yeah there's obviously points to
be made in regards to power consumption
of running a system like this
but the spoiler alert is there's not an
excuse anymore to buy all those fantasy
Nvidia graphics cards and calling it
work
um so at one level below blockchains as
well as a permissioned version of
blockchains
you get to keep all the security goodies
from the level above but you get to
close the doors a little bit on who can
actually contribute to a network like
this
so
just a bit of an elaboration as well of
what that tool actually brings us
um hopefully most of the people in here
will know of the data structure of
singling linked list where each item
refers to the previous one or the next
one
um in this case it's it's referring
backwards instead of forwards
um
each entry into the Ledger
um has a hash associated with it for
those that don't know what hashes that's
a one-way function that takes in any
level of input and gives a fixed length
of output
um that's consistent so the same garbage
data coming in or which results in the
same hash coming out
um
just to touch some power draw as well
um as a bit of an elaboration before we
completely swap off of blockchains
um this is the power draw of the
ethereum network
[Music]
and then at one point it completely
bottomed out
and that's from like just going back
a year from a couple of days ago so
the amount or the analogy they use
um is the difference between the Eiffel
Tower
um and a Lego figurine and that's how
far the the power draw dropped where uh
in terms of terrible hours
um that the overall Network consumes but
if we're deploying our own one
um in order to establish where all these
pieces of media came from what
specifically would we want to store on
it
um
the the best ideas here would be a hash
of the sensor input
um just because again a hash is a
consistent length of output that's quite
easy to store in a ledger like this as
opposed to the whole media item itself
um some information as well on who the
Creator is
um the device that it was created from
uh going back to my phone as an example
the device information might be the the
phone's model but then specifically
which camera on the phone and the
settings of which that camera
um was at at the same with capture as
well
um and the more of this information that
you sort of try and Pile in the harder
it will get to fake of course when you
go back to the idea of degenerative AI
stuff yes they can generate a face now
but then
you're you're adding more information
and that they need to very specifically
replicate
um it's just it's adding to the
complexity
um and the whole system that you would
want and a digital provenance sale
fashion would be you're tracking the
light photons coming in to the camera at
the very start and you're wanting to
track it all the way to the end consumer
um
so
the main points are that you're wanting
to secure that capture device as much as
possible and as soon as the image is
captured you want it to be fingerprinted
and securely held within the device
um
you'd want to store it in a distributed
Ledger
um in order to keep it public for
everyone to see that record of creation
um and understands
and knowing that the technology there
doesn't allow for malicious edits and
without it being transparent due to The
Ledger section of that technology
um
of course for people to use the system
it needs to be transparent clear what's
happening and clearly describing to the
end user what
um is actually the assurances the system
provides so ensuring that the the user
interface makes that clear and it
it explains everything to the best of
disability
um
and of course you need the assurances
that the systems underlying Technologies
are all
um all the information is held securely
every step
um
the devices May initially be served
pre-service Secrets
um
this will just ensure that we know who
it was that actually took the photo and
how it got to us for example
we ensure that the hashing algorithms at
plate are going to not result in
collisions uh or duplicate outputs
effectively
from unique inputs
we need to also ensure that all of the
data is held securely both in transit
and at rest
and there's plenty of practical issues
that could come from a system like this
and that would need to be addressed but
um
this is all part of you know claiming
that it's not the the magic answer for
all the problems we are seeing but it's
something that would also get worked on
and very similar to the systems of
pre-saned executables for things like
installing
your
software on a home computer
and you want to just ensure that this
information there is keeping you as safe
as possible as far as possible
um
so anchoring
as we refer to when you put it on the
distributed Ledger
um should happen as soon as possible as
close to the sensor where possible
um so in the case of slightly Dumber
cameras as opposed to fill on
smartphones you may want to just
information say even via like the SMS
Network as soon as possible just to get
those assurances in as fast as possible
um
the consumer again needs to be able to
verify this at the end result and
validating that no edits have taken
place and again will are
being able to interpret the assurances
that come with a system like this
um of course even going back to the
newspaper example as well
not all images will fit in the newspaper
column
and there is legitimate cases of editing
like cropping and that needs to be
considered so that the images will fit
in an appropriate space or have been
slightly rotated to ensure that the
person is standing straight for example
um
we then would of course need to rely on
secure input devices
um so ensuring that the system is secure
as a whole and that the individual
devices are tamper resistant or tamper
evident
um and then again coming back to that
transparent UI you must work on
a system that's clear and easy to use so
that trust can be formed between you and
the user and working on all of this Tech
in the open as well will provide provide
a lot of that trust so
yeah
um an example here of a system that
would be
relating to this would be one of the
ones that I've been working on with my
team at open Origins
um it's a IOS app
um where you're able to just capture
images within the app and we build up as
much metadata as possible around the
image from the sensors data available as
early as possible uh we get it fired
into
a DLT
um so that from the point that it's been
captured in there you can assure that no
edits have taken place
um on by the time you consume that piece
of information
um authenticity information on what
device it was captured on
when it was captured when we got in our
system at the location these things are
captured in as well
in this case it was a teacher's strike
in London
um so then of course at the end
um you
fill in that
accepted edits scenario you've got
things like the QR code to link back to
the original asset on our site so that
you can for example if you have trust in
this system you can fall back
from perhaps another site where the
image may have been pressed or
manipulated in some fashion through the
upload process there
um
so yeah we
we see that the generative AI sort of
offensive tool set is quite heavy and
there's a lot going on they've had a lot
more time to get up to Pace
um so it's a bit of a David and Goliath
trying to catch up to a system like that
and build up a system of transparency
and security and what's been quite uh
security Lacks
uh
system in general photography as a whole
um
yeah I'm gonna skip this slide here but
that's uh the main that's a long shot of
it I'd love to hear questions I've got
cadburys cream eggs I'll happily throw
it people if you ask a really good
question or if you're being really
annoying or aiming your head and
but I've I've been told off for through
or the idea of throwing them so uh yeah
you'll just need to come down at the end
to collect them
um
the
final point I just wanted to make before
going on to questions is that frankly
the app it was an it's a bit of a closed
Source State at the moment or closed
Source uh closed entry State and we've
got envelope Code system if you're
interested in having a look at the app
um you can scan the QR code it's taking
you to my link tree but I've got links
from there and to the appropriate page
in the App Store
and separately
um for the students and first second
third year we're looking for brand
ambassadors again the link will be part
of there I'll leave this slide up
um now as we go to questions so yeah
thank you
very much
yeah so the question was am I not
or the example I gave earlier in regard
to Kodak and the staged imagery and
that's a fair point that a system like
this could give and false
assurances in a staged environment but
all of that extra metadata as well
that's being provided through the
transparent UI would hopefully help
and reduce cases of for example stage
content getting through the net
um arming the user with as much
information as possible is kind of key
um which I might not have made clear
through the metadata and transparent UI
part but yeah the hope is that the more
information you have the better informed
you can be and the better choices you
can make
and you can rely a lot more in the
system than doing all of the information
and time protecting yourself
so yeah good question thank you
yep
[Music]
so the question was if you were to
upload it through a separate device onto
your phone and then try and get it into
the app so the main point of what we're
trying to do with frankly is sort of
restricting the capture in the first
place so you can only use it through the
in-app camera very similar to how
Snapchat was quite early on before it
had the gallery access
um so the idea is yeah the the content
is assured because we were there at the
point of capture to almost say like yeah
perhaps so good good question thank you
interrupts
yep
yeah so the question again just to recap
was
um how do you handle low no signal
situations where someone captures it
um initially and trying to get that to
the DLT as fast as possible
um so especially for the low signal
um the idea of getting that fingerprint
up as quickly as possible is super
important because from that you can
assure no edits have taken place because
the way the hashing algorithm
fundamentally works is any edits would
immediately change that fingerprint
um no signal you're then also relying on
strong on device security and signing it
on the hardware level as fast as
possible and height of yeah hiding that
information into the hardware
um until such a time you can upload the
full uh or even that initial fingerprint
and then the film wanted further on
um the example might a good example
might be Google photos you take a photo
on your device uh you take 10 more it
doesn't necessarily upload them all
until you're on for example Wi-Fi
connection because it doesn't want to
absolutely check your data so yeah
good question though thank you yep
yeah so the question was in regards to
the centralization of the diagram I give
um for the distributed Ledger um
yeah we obviously aim to work with for
example uh BBC on major news
organizations so that we are not the
source of truth because we are
fundamentally are building this system
so that we wouldn't be the source of
truth that will be shared amongst
multiple organizations ideally with
different views so for example in the US
you have your major news organizations
on each side of the debate uh having
both of them contributing to the upkeep
of a system like this would ensure no
biased content really getting in as well
um so yeah the aim is using dlts and
this uh
specifically permissioned blockchains as
an example of have invading trusted
sources to help maintain the system and
not just bearing the way of all
ourselves so yeah it's a good question
thank you
um Danny stop now yes kill no worries
well thank you
um it's good Chan
[Music]
foreign