unit doctor dre and got it down
you
switched on
does not want them
stimulant
i mean i really like and what happened
when it looks ridiculous
about instead
alright alright well still here
welcomed and i got your material used to
be
abroad a last year really desire
reaction without addressing my sandbox
and c_n_n_ party as she's
deliveries
john holliman kiss and hug them
and soft
say hello
harvard we had talked about all kind of
uh... breezy hester we've got a lot
being hurt
this sunday for the usually as late as
though i'm a finding of the israeli
salad party
but actually what we're gonna talk about
tonight
and sometimes i'm really really cool law
enforcement provisions the second half
of it all
but the first ask you to be a just a
little balls out
pa starting with something that i have
created wasn't and apparently a frequent
well that this is something i understand
disneyland but you always is that you
have reviewed the top
i came up with a new protocol
for uh... interpersonal reaction if
you've ever been to make contracts has
defeated but all the fun your neighbor
if you'd like to ask a question about
your back is the response
well not this is the injury protocol
and i'd like to get your sharing
dreams sharethis a lot of celebrities
you haven't really really like
you make it
right on stage of the start of your talk
extracted up
for u and your fellow speeders
because i'd like you know when you
snowballs at icici shout as the leaders
of the wrong word on
we have to direct
it works right and i want to be like
that but after talking it over
and respond distilling things to be
happy 'cause we will draft more abuse
and if you ask us principally questions
or you know if after you do you want us
to be involved in something thank god
associate telling the jury that's nice
of you to please the anchorage this
uh... you have these graphics for you
talk to kill actually dreams on stage
and i share your local something with
other people and it began with a little
bit short of talking had to happen three
minutes minutes
not so what is this right i wish i was
used to this treaty all still that's is
one of my favorite favorite cocktails
the never get anymore
because it features applejack
apple jacks in the oldest american
leaders of the favorite george
washington's mother four
but still that's that is one heart
attack
which is essentially an ample whiskey
it's kinda like another one operandi now
streetfire starsight introduced three dr
about that
anytime did you want in the little with
their students and the cocktail
nationalistic
there is the latest version of your
breasts credit last fall equal parts
apple jacks
and uh... downside i taught us the law
the
people are really trying to
bt towards me
but these are the beneficiaries should
we have glasses at the ready as we look
like falls believes
locally trained for it
but i did not follow this is where
you're really beautiful makeup stuff
and we have a lot of these stories tell
starting with dave who's gonna fill us
in claim
want to know this time of year
stories about some of our friends in
europe that if you haven't heard in
should you be stories they're great
all the letters to the settlers were
related
any other times he calls the from you
little says those
wishes encounter in germany
are you really really actually bar
eleven constant the standards of the
last
when you get there
with his views of the issues involved
whilst uh... down bill clinton and the
like this
let me know
altogether
the symbol of selection
uh... with car with a over little is
accurate and reliable especially trying
to make it any time received
correspondent
nevertheless here
this is a really tough
on that
is usually these
and is normal
the something a little surprised you
on
uses the words of wisdom
on ready was able to use these days is
that more noble isn't it
wrenching this november
and then repudiation because no
independent uh...
busy on won't but student at the
in tryout with wonderful is that they're
a bunch of social engineering violated
by instructors and uh... the
and i'm
this is the
and as though you're not moral that's
and that's all the reforms melinda
literally
limit
that's it for us the religion people
armor
word for good
disillusion
this is
is thirteen u_p_s_ lauren
this is another thing photography
about optus
there
major greasy somebody pompoms
there's at least favorite
uh... song
incidents this week on an
denies that it's not really frees me
attack smile really weird thing
and he split big all he had any thoughts
they're not design
t_v_ permission renounces for financing
designed to keep the people
from stopping them
overrule runs they're almost like kind
of your ladakh to make it the tory
acting they're not designed to be
intricate
so that kind of attack
he's reluctant
five dash away it your way out of my
head for the past
released
the german company please do so he's got
model thirteenth this is one of the
biggest cuts ever made made you've
actually seen these props if you're a
sci-fi fan
uh... when you reverse and that is
really more commercial and had not run
walk around serenity
that's the cops but not right outside of
abuses on local stations to keep her
locked in
the use of the reasons we have some
began with the people in the region
incidence of skin usually really clear
exams but
place against the state and the like
piggy you know just getting out of tax
cuts
not that hard
and he can be seen to be killed all of
us as holding
is just a little none of that is still
barely bigger that cokie
so pick-ups just because they will be
entertained is not you know really hard
to get out
that people treat you just saw
you can do that these two undecided at
right now hopefully were really foolish
or any of the jury
for upgrading xcode
i will just be bridges being dismissed
taxi
we're gonna try a lot of different wants
the extremists on
someone cameras and just from the air
once in a disability
the citizens but
it's obviously no doubt that he has just
wheeled ourself sexy contacts that we
have for you is going to be called
castle ones
workplan music player music tracks comes
not like modern you know i mean there's
thirty seven is offering to help no last
night is that people eighty-four late
seventies early eighties porn
but you have
two guests at the white house for a
before we actually succeeding in what
we're doing
and i think as a friend address where
you got cokie's you know a lot of free
shit but i just saw a few and noted dot
on the songs he sang exactly three
legged abortion
one morning
grass
outside
may thirtieth in china and added
indulgent registration handle just
reading too much
if you think you know it
may he can try to guess at what some of
the city's before you know what movies
from
beforehand and stuff so you ready
all right miss india
i wanted to be on camera that
drive-by listed
passing
instead
brings
and other government
how old is the
the
that
classless out for a couple of
as the
kiit
has
that's not good
exit
what was the reality guessing precinct
level
but it may be heading into us and i was
on the spot that does not need to try
this please write later
indicating and as part that good
one of the smaller and have preferred
wire they how they work with the
engineering behind
well doctrines that you can look at
what's actually going on inside of most
handcuffs maybe food using
and i've learned a lot to do
so continental court
such a personal there's not much going
on
you have this tragedy hot here
any helpful here with also rations
and his friend
and a lot more
soon because i did not
is matched by a dozen including one way
not another direction
so europe arrests in there
clampdown but can't get out
now and you don't want to hang tough
you helped me gain tighter either
these these require
it's pretty anywhere
interferes with the ball so that you
helped candidates higher
freedoms
and he keeps on m_t_v_
you know what
that's pretty much power and how it
works it's pretty simple
here's a video demonstration d_c_
depression are going in
upon clinton
you can
because india t
all he does
that is the
paul
admissions and when
so julia
there are not complicated what's going
on it's not hard
c hollywood gets a lot lot became really
braun
you know what people are coming out with
or ccr
like tv shows the substance of the hair
he cracks brite
there's also a real quick and you've got
a c on it
dcr
suggest in is using it
he's a battle
ends with the point where the you are
and police
mizrachi indeed dan
begins in the middle of a long
the forces and our way
and julia dharma
really quickly shipped a lot
using video of
in helping
done a lot
as easy to really done a lot more about
the way you works perfectly fine
but you don't want it
universes
malabar the way
it's you know what works
nothing shouldn't work became
what does work you about c
covering the either way
kick it back
jim questions here haha three
and see how the actual oval office
didn't have joined models have different
methods of doing it some more about her
some are just a little all
magazines will circle here
would depend on the end of the keys
but as for instigated malabar across
yes you're right mysterious
procedures little dot
actually ground here's the that's off
if you're really acts
or really there
the
doctrine
batteries in the final demand would you
agree
candidate
daily basis
cajun along side by side as all eat
is reminiscent of us here and that i
really a
represents the
initiating this instead of learning how
to manipulate outstanding outside on the
top and inspire backing he said you
pushed all his wrists
annual
citizenship
odd steve at my anyway
two years the
cell
justin arrives here
we're going to uh... granted their
sovereignty as a consequence she has in
house
and gets more potent right
they may still be excellent
these are big milestone
a alright appreciating his accident
there you get there
there
take months mohammed
expressed
so you're getting a hole inside these
all three of us like the shootout
before you can actually
gas though the ford mustang sorted out
just to start asap
councils
out some
israel's concept that subsequent
respectable
to shoot cataract
the status of the today
will direct online topped the pop
hip-hop
protects prepare for us so it's really d
blazes decline
results there
my radar screens these days brightness
an actor
no matter you know i don't know how much
more than seven hundred
garnier
stored in the same is activated
desire
from one hundred
mentor
say you're sixty-odd consecrated
warranties
what's the context of that stuff on
fellow courses
along the matching santana
so yes
shipping incredibly incredibly easy
actually see though is that ok tak
just taking something
it became right
and check out the policies together to
have a copy
as i'm talking about the records of it
andre
cast
trustees not copy of it just a little
bit
little belief
and get a lot of things stuff in became
with cops
and chandana all
composite off
i think it out
rebellious after
now
political issue
adult
manager response
justin that allergies so don't be
adjusted native plants
its ups and downs problems aren't at
home because it's not that i a
so doctors also one of our killer of
hitting about that seasons and more
companies as well start superfluous
but so we're looking at our last few
weeks once thought he testing as he sat
there let us
yet another song
online gets you in this age levels
classical secondstorey
candy yes as working
behind
bhai
azmaria crackers
after with my return at one thirty
pacific
crap
carlisle five separate parts the dallas
building on the grand prize money we've
got out of atlanta really archives their
allocated awesome yes we should be later
if you look at the mall smug it to you
my pocket
wiretapping
mom but
another what some two hundred landscape
are you single and double lock is good
alliances fraser jump ahead louis is
actually going to talk about uh... a lot
handcuffs
or
you just this time
is a whole new instruments delay
devender
yes came from la jolla
released home
disagreed on
blinding
okay i was then this
farrakhan
bayview
gone off their essayist unique event is
idle outstanding year free trade
agreement copy as well
excellent job
actually has a swedish police of the
catherine
x_-rays gonna get it right out we're
going to be done
the money is there
you had just witnessed us like blasting
through all these cops
and you might want to know what you did
a lot of people and how does cover costs
these files are all cops is lousy
if there is no not all custom is that
there are better quality tops are
covered in really well
the most common thing
e_v_a_ copy really tight tolerances
if you make a handcuff if you can't
sleep shoes
visited schools into very easily
to be completely frustrated most of
these attacks
we try to get out of them on trying to
pick my way out of smith and wesson
acetic acid acid peerless doesn't seem
really nice france
unlike some other kind of that you don't
ask him about it
there much later that much harder to
only really getting their not mission
then you can probably count
incompetently u_n_h_c_r_'s all you need
to do
so one more guests one more films
i know it has a few people it is taking
a wallet gold is like uh... of teleport
for knowledge penicillin condition
sorry guesses well i think you will try
to get out of these it was nuts
trusts u
carriers travis
so contacts
no
things
planning
ranging from abortion handing credit
expected the senate people don't look at
for example for the
uh... huh
so i can't wait out some of us
as the world's contact
stubble on the
you know i just got back from one side
philadelphia like this specialists
the
uh... unit
regular style cops can still be great if
their quote high-quality hymie psycho
high-quality cups there are few
manufacturers
making really pretty badass cops
of sweet athlete in
there are so many factions that need
really interesting things that are hard
not to shoot with tight tolerances
really liked it too
the most commonly happens
is vice listening depaul
involved with that
so mad little paper clip or something
going in there
you're not in a trip the entire paul
might catch part of it
but not all of it
the highest cops that are popular sees
through the u_s_ sometimes used to a
seasonal chicago cops as well
they all have to split paul
i have some cops from korea tom chang
gentler form of id reversed needs him
that's the company
occupied triples football
so it's a really why
really hard to depress all of the of the
planes at once
my favorite pastimes david cuts there's
concern always got the mail there's room
by another group com on walls holding
corinne answering
lonely and properly appreciated the love
that i have for the three docks
not only as a slip
loopholes for therein down his little
she notes
that you really can't get to from either
angle
is incredibly targeting their running
between them izzy blocking slowly it now
as actually critics of the scientist and
on the front seat can slip she visited
the press demolition
is really really nice
uh... there's even you know alleged on
the back into the bodies you can sleep
in the other way the new version has
something you can even see is
interesting little when the front pages
g_m_'s
anything he strategy into their
is really sick whereas at lapd blames
edwin
we want
so hit me up
was demoted from
there's actually revenues
and it's just for justice
i worked as a legal seventy-three she
asks so there is really really beautiful
cuts they're really will be
the products for the memorial stutterer
that constant using them
and these are the only cops action on
this year
completely agree with frustrate the d_c_
nine four nine a smirk beings and
pocketing like this after you know i
don't know i don't know how to get out
of them
ncd political for not getting s no way
to get you with us
they are really really sweet
so that's my little steel dot if your
actually want course but there are
really cool cuffs modified overseas
if you're a law enforcement or just a
inventions usana
there's something different comes into
play when you get all these
re-engineered variations in the design
house
you run into some trouble
the war we start tinkering with the
basic
cuff style
these are two incompatibilities
especially sports users
for example
one of the customer intermediary
suspicion i'll back you were going to
get people was that while we were
happier costco about
energy upstairs admission are around
brand
but the cop bomb is really thin
there's no standard standard sheet
for every kentucky
but there's not one standard size
perset
so that's why has this been most hancock
believes the belatedly y
so you can see that huge and so he was
not gonna turn
as part of late
is hitting
the bonds that make sense
so some companies actually manufactured
the calling of universal keys hightower
scheme very hot alan keyes
you can buy support universal ki
it usually copies of it that way
cut down a little bit or believes that
we're just so smaller manufacturing and
ask for quality control
and so it was all over cheap involve
universal
that works really well on those basic
cuts including the house including
milligrams that don't have the right
size
where you start run into trouble
remember those multiple
paul and high security guards if you
have a lady
that is too small
any state in the cop of multiple faults
in might not trigger
all of the polls
candy is kind of learned
behind-the-scenes at what some of them
are going down
cellmark
especially strong chances are so why
i've got blood to bleed champion between
two different paul horowitz went down
wants to admit it but the sponsor of
this
three different strengths
request is under three different springs
they are not
that's how people's
they might attack mts if you can get one
of the damn conflict visit when she
humans in the position
there are no holes prints is that was
the complete documents
unless they extend that walker twenty
only through everything spring and home
wholesome maybe you will do that
rules are coming on line in the
marketplace because they what content is
the awesome always find the product
misunderstand
winners and contacting running into
trouble
certainly just making up he believes to
small that will not solve all your
problems
so to all
and for the president would have
happened
he's already i'd be curious about this
for a while
i want to ask you guys informs exit
levees and also one of us problems
so start category
for the christmas meeting for the last
meeting here iran over and over your
house
who need it as locks shop he has an
awesome collection
everyone raw all their collections
we don't everything comfortable which
was a lot more detail
but a lot of abu ali and she said no i
did some things for manufacturers that
they could use it was not there really
needs to
but i was interested
involved
involving a standard
handcuff keys can
i said there's gotta be variation you've
got the every manufacturers will be
different
and why don't you know contract out to
treat you have additional help
which is wrong with me right
said eugenia solitude is bring this
design
something that unfair
and i sat there just measurement sheets
just measuring all the copies of every
dimension i can't conceive cokie
basically
as you know she had been inner and outer
dimension
and then lady
dudley has been added overall
rise instead has served with
as a i wonder exactly across the
industry cross the world
what kind of irritation we're talking
about
some of those pretty much split all
letters that have walking piece is this
something that's flutes experiment
at least slot
all the data
which is a part of what is the biggest
was paul is what smallest was the
standard deviation was the acting
strange
who's that we're going out with your
whose typical
has really fascinating things the
sixteen million dollars data
i wonder
if they are
possibly even anytime
on ideals he didn't respond
in everything
as far as we can tell
behave thank you liane
knowing that it
but yeah interviews yes
so now total of one of the most part of
the like this but save your clothes for
after this video because this
is what we ended up made
at the end of the
so challenging terrible
heroes but
it was a lot
with congress
with gestures
that all of us
these days
uh...
artist and i think
yourself
so i think the public office
can you tell us the any other way
interest
ascii
we've just witnessed
i speak yes sure applejack yes let me
ask you kath
involved
through the food right down the law
animals not art it's just a matter of
you know measuring
and i think the press release
really blew me away things so impressive
uh... we were hesitant referendum was
the last minute shoppers
the sweetest guy ever
eight image for a for effort not just as
he's good at it as a basketball's locks
eve must-see artistry penthouse
and all this stuff
well let me get keys
neela do math
measuring
the same time feedback that was just
looking and at simpson's home idols of
aids as betty filing
he tries to give us a little jenny's
within his own left a mark on the
website
indians
just ivone using his scale
as a locksmith lovecraft
nate he has with you
tens of millions
of what i've produced
just by popular
and
upon finding i see if someone's really
really committed to doing the job right
so i'm very proud of him we're very
pleased to call
so the issue he
allow delegates
in europe because we're litigating just
mentioned to you later
but elections are really simple
the dimensions art museum previous uh...
wheatland tribe election translator
as as an organization does actually
after delivery since we don't have all
the patton boggs
meert
to dance in the world like that
acutely testing the waters
uh... but yes i will be uh... we will
need license this certain organizations
who organizes a one e keys
i know what needed for a living he's
really sweet guy for on com units like
stuff there
mean-spirited cops he's interested
families analysts are orson
realizes it
uh... for people who've been responsible
beyond the licensing commercial side do
you really believe they release as a
nonprofit group tools has no problem
with you guys making santoro
uh... if you want to make them please do
and use them we'll show you some really
good tips about it
because it's so funny
if you want me is thought to sell
if you want to make this comes as cokie
design and don't like obviously
owner foundry in fact reinforcing you
know you don't have access to free
speech
industrial processes
is actually really trivial to do this
while i said well let's take a look at
using
handcuffed he has a piece
as a starting point right
the ultimate ki
as of late wife clara's two point nine
builders
so that he did not sound of valor and
some of those building brands that are
too skinny
certainly not been able to use as
cheekbones
it also has of late to reach deep enough
into cash for paul's some international
cops
interested parties halt lady
five point five millimeters hall
utilities european-style many styles
popular american handguns
in fact you want aside from some korean
cuts overseas businessman unless
does she have to also can be quite big
you hold a meeting goes out to be chefs
you know
use that one
into the hands of
lesbians the little pain in the middle
of a kentucky waits never acted we fall
into the eighty-nine doesn't matter much
but hopefully left looking at either
jumptags or smith and wesson
nato expansion says and i see a pic of
warehouse in those guys uh... at boxset
industries fellowship international stud
spokesman massie you're much more likely
that
and between the two of these
much mental illnesses initiate off
accounts
it would not be down seriously missing
lesson is right there is ready for you
afew greedy passes for the fireworks
rebel
chopped a split right there on the way
you will have
tina smith and wesson ki
which may be doing and if you have law
enforcement either of your you're
actually at the house floor officer who
knows
you can do this
is it wasn't he cap
and bought and rocks
a whole talking back
now
however as a trainer traveler probably
needs
premises of the bill is next war again
tomorrow and as i have a yahoo com if
you want a lot of on realities
please write
we've tried to do testing on every cop
we brought new work ice where you work
condo how do you think that's right
hair
the inside patterson you know
this background that he had every
opportunity
i send paul
and
trying it is is very extreme
thank you so much