[Music]
Suzanne wolf has the distinction of
being the second longest-serving ICANN
board member after Steve Crocker
Suzanne's experience stretches from
policy to the highly technical
please welcome Suzanne wolf I want to
say thank you Brad and thank you
everyone for being here for this
wonderful moment I think Brad did ask me
to speak as the other longest-serving
board member Steve started as the SFA's
on a few months before I came on as the
our sac liaison and he has now outlasted
me by a year I left the board a year ago
I've really enjoyed the reminiscences
the reminders of the history we've
shared this so far this week but when
I'm asked for an observation about being
an X board member I'm always reminded of
the joke about I think retired
politicians you can say whatever you
want and the good news is no one cares
the good news and the bad news but as
much fun as that can be I don't think
it'll be true for Steve he's always done
me and the community the honor of
honesty and commitment and people have
listened as much because they find what
he says useful and insightful is because
of his role on the board and in the
community the difference I think in
being a retired board member is actually
that you no longer have to speak it if
you don't want to but I do hope that he
will the other board experienced Steve
and I have shared has been in providing
a particular type of diversity as
techies the ITM community requires a
balancing act of its techies as it does
of all of us techies don't run I can and
probably shouldn't but their input is
important to have and needs to be
available as part of the process at any
time at any stage this means the ability
to listen to others views and to make
our own views accessible and persuasive
these are skills the techies are not
always expected to have
but I think Steve has played that part
with commitment and with grace and with
deep deep fervour
someone Steve and I both held in very
high regard Jon Postel used to tell me
that you should always be trying to work
your way out of your current job because
it's the only way to get to do something
new so thanks Steve
congratulations on working your way out
of this job and I can't wait to see
what's next
[Applause]
[Music]