[Music]
Thank You Larry 48 years ago when Steve
was a UCLA graduate student he was
recruited by a renowned computer
scientist named Leonard Kleinrock to be
part of a very special team a group that
successfully transmitted the very first
message across the ARPANET which as we
all know was the precursor to the
Internet mr. Kline rock-like vent wanted
to be here tonight couldn't make that
happen but he also sent us a video
message Steve I couldn't be more pleased
to reach out to you over this Internet
textiles we have andreat you today in
absentia I'd rather be there but
otherwise coming out over this internet
capability is special I want to
basically express my congratulations to
you for a wonderful job and I can and it
reminds me of the history you and I have
together I've known you since the late
1960s working on the fledgling opponet
which evolved into the Internet
I remember how well you put together a
group of software team okay you put
together a software team there was
amazing Vint Cerf Jon Postel
yourself and some others and you led
that team and you brought about the
early host host protocol and you created
a group of graduate students around the
country on your behest to form a group
that worked together and develop the
technology it was an amazing time a
golden era a time I'll never forget I
knew a lot of fun to work with
I remember how often you come into my
office and sucked flame to me you needed
some travel money to here there in the
other place convincing argument and
every time you managed to get it out of
me and I'm happy we did that but you had
always had a good argument your
personality was charming and basically
very effective
the the work that you did was
unmatchable the work that I can you've
done here is is to be honored and
strongly effective and what you've had
to do if I can tell a story about you do
you remember the time that we want a
sailboat
one that you invented a big son of a gun
and you got a lot of your friends
including myself on that boat and put us
all at peril we started sailing in Santa
Monica Bay the wind picked up we weren't
quite sure how to handle this big rig so
we decided we better get off the water
onto the sand so we headed straight for
the shore racing not sure how to slow
this thing down and went crashing onto
the sand well done we lied on the sand
laughing crying wondering what happened
and you said that's what theater is you
were always a fun-loving guy and I've
known you all these years I wish you
Godspeed in your next endeavor and
congratulations on this wonderful job
you've done
I have I have to tell you a funny story
about the sailing story that he just
mentioned I did a video interview with
Steve and I asked him about the story
that Kleinrock just related about
sailing Steve goes you know we did go
sailing and I did crack up a boat maybe
two but I don't think he was on it and
I'm thinking my god how many crashes and
the boat is this guy had and then the
other day the board his board colleagues
gave him a very nice gift of a glass
boat and I thought god I hope he doesn't
drop that I hope he doesn't drop that
[Music]