[Music]
we're here today with former Board Chair
Stephen Crocker and current board chair
Shireen Shalaby Steve let's start with
you you're leaving behind a substantial
legacy but you're also leaving behind
some important issues that Shireen must
now undertake what are some of the most
important ones well one that's very much
on my mind is the who is Registration
Data Services that's been outstanding or
long-standing a problem five years ago
the board took strong action to try to
set that on a new course and it has not
yet gelled we have not yet gotten to the
place where we need now there's
pressures with the GD P R so that's a
that's a whole collection of issues
around who is that
needs to be taken care of and it's going
to take even more work is there one
issue that in your mind you're going I
wish we could have reached a resolution
on that one before
well that's the that's the one that I
you know feel I thought we had enough
time to get that under control and I'm
sort of disappointed that it's still
hanging out there Shireen let me ask you
this you're a new chair but you're
certainly not new to the ICANN board
having served there for a number of
years what are your priorities as you
assume the new role as chair okay so
Steve has mentioned the business
priority I'd like to commit come at it
from a different angle and to be the
most important thing is that the board
should become a reliable partner of the
community and that's how our
stakeholders should see us what do I
mean by reliable partner means that
we're good listeners we understand their
issues meaning that our priorities are
aligned with their priorities meaning
that we make thoughtful decisions on on
their behalf it also means that we have
to be transparent and they have to trust
us and finally I think it means that we
have to act in the collective interests
of all the stakeholders and not the
single interest
stakeholder but partnership goes both
ways
so we will do our our effort to become
the reliable partner but I think the
community also need to act as our
partners and help us in achieving our
objectives and that sounds like a
process that's not gonna just have you
you don't snap your fingers and that
happens overnight that's a process
correct there is a process especially
that if you think go back before the
transition the trust between the
community and the board was not at its
highest but the the transition process
have actually caused the trust to
improve and I think as we go forward the
number one thing really that will make
it work is that we trust each other and
when we make mistakes we collaborate and
operate in a collaborative manner to fix
those mistakes and you mentioned
accountability has been being a major
foundation to achieve that absolutely an
accountability works both ways we are
accountable to the community they are
accountable to themselves but I think at
the end we're all accountable to each
other we're all together we have a lot
of challenges ahead and as long as we
work together in a clear transparent and
trusting way I am confident that we will
make progress and rise to the challenges
Steve in your opening speech you talked
about I can no longer being considered
an experiment elaborate on that
well I'm sure that the people who
orchestrated the creation of I can fully
intended that it was a permanent
operation when it was put together but
with a certain sense of realism that it
was yet to be proven we're now 19 years
19 years into the process and
if you add up any of the statistics
amount of money the number of people the
number of issues number of meetings etc
etc and the awareness we're now very
much a part of the firmament in the
internet ecology and and also if you
look at some of the other things that
are going on around the internet
environment we're even perhaps more
stable and better organized than some of
our counterparts so I think there's no
question at least in my mind that we've
become accepted that the issue of
whether we should exist as way in the
rearview mirror that the function we
perform is pretty well understood that
our role in the world is understood even
by people who are not intimately
involved with us but it's just part of
the overall business and governmental
and academic communities understand with
your departure from the board
you're an Internet pioneer with your
departure are we losing that historical
context are we losing that institutional
memory yeah and that's a good thing it
gets replaced by myths which then
persist forever
Shareen at the end of the day how are
you gonna gauge your success is true
well I think it isn't just about my
success let me start by telling you what
I how I see the role of the chair all of
the chair is a very pivotal role for the
board it's a role that has to harness
all the talent of the board and also
create an environment for effectiveness
and collegiality but I don't want to
gauge my success I think the community
will gauge my success and the board
success if we at the end meet the
challenges some of them Steve have
described and also if they if they trust
us and end up really feeling that we are
the reliable partners so that's the and
I've explained what it means I don't
want to go through it again but that is
a good measure it's the community to
assess our success so much of what you
seem to be saying what I'm hearing you
say is it's really about the
organization the board the community
working together and in a sort of mutual
trust indeed absolutely I mean we have
to follow on from the transition the
transition gave us an independence which
is priceless it is up to us now
how to take this to the next level it is
up to us to implement the bylaws which
are the new ones are have to say our
complex there are 250 pages long
compared to the old ones with 450 and we
haven't tested the implementation of
those plus there are also some changes
coming along as a result of works to do
in the accountability how do we
implement those is going to be crucial
there will be differences of opinion
there will be
opposing groups but to deal with them in
a collaborative way that doesn't break
the trust is essential we have to
preserve that and we have to make sure
that we and the community are on the
same side and deal with these issues as
if we are truly partners rather than two
opposite sides final question for you
Steve came to the role with a highly
technical background you're coming to
the role with a very successful business
background what does that bring to the
table for on-camera I have to start with
the joke that Steve brought in in one of
the speeches where he said he's trying
to teach me to count in binary and I'm
trying to teach him some Arabic words so
that was that was a very very nice joke
but I have to say something about that
when I became vice chair he gave me a
test seven question to answer in binary
I haven't answered until today and I
don't think he's happy about that let me
say on a more serious note I never match
Steve's technical skills that is
impossible right he's a giant of the
internet is a pioneer I am NOT I do have
a technical background I have a an
engineering background and also a
computing Sciences degree and I worked
in the field of systems and software and
hardware for a good part of 20 years so
I do have an appreciation of the
technical side but what I do bring I
think is a lot of experience of
governance and strategic thinking
because that's what I've been doing for
the last number of years and I think
like Steve said I can has not no longer
a start-up we are an organization which
is 19 years old we have 400 people 150
million in expenses we have location in
13 countries around the world we have
major issues forward and now it's time
to evolve a little bit and take it
further in terms of management
governance and structure so that when
all of those are in place and they are
in place well it frees the mind it
allows us to focus on the business
issues rather than waste
Taman processes and organization so
often people ask me said what will you
do differently to Steve well I say the
answer is simple is evolution and not
revolution I mean we we have understood
stewardship really advance the board
really advance the way we do things
we've restructured our workshop with
restructure our thinking of course we
can do more it's a continuous
improvement but I want to take away all
the sort of administrative and
organizational structures things away
from day to day decision so that we
focus almost entirely 100% on what the
community needs and on the issues at
hand
excellent Shireen Shalaby thank you very
much best of luck in your new role Steve
Crocker best of luck in your new
endeavors thank you gentlemen thank you
very much
[Music]