Oh
[Music]
areas yeah I think I'll do all the
talking this one floods yeah does
anybody want to be the jabber scribe
thank you yo anybody want to take
minutes it's really easy really really
really easy I'll give you a cough drop
I'll give you to cough drops seriously
we can't proceed DJ all right Melinda
thank you anyone who goes to certificate
transparency now as to volunteer to take
minutes that's you know there are the
stickers this time do they need to lose
you yes I mean it one hour what take all
my cough drops it like to be kinda easy
if you just download the PDF or
something and add annotations to it
because we are going to we're going to
try to go really quickly so that
everyone can get to the github off which
I think it really doesn't alright the
blue sheets are going around there on
that side of the room that's them over
by now you have all seen the note well
at least three times oh my now yeah okay
there we go now i'm using the mic i am
rich this is daniel 60 so you've all
seen to know well basically it says if
you've got any IP r you must have
disclosed that you've got the IPR
otherwise please leave the link
okay all right Daniel did this bang-up
job of coming up with a slide template
to discuss all of the drafts so without
further ado most of this meeting is
probably going to be asking for people
to commit to reading the drafts there in
a couple cases help Shepherd a document
through their short they're very
straightforward they're easily separable
there's not a lot of relationships among
all of them it's not like you have to
send in understand all of HTTP before
you can understand h2 so okay so um this
drop I think this dress is one of our
priority we have discussions about
assigning your IDs so we took a decision
which is requesting the ini ark and
putting this whole idea to under this
arc there has been some discussions
about pre hash this is non pre ash
signature I think the consensus is that
we should use we are only defining the
draft for non pre hash version variant
so I guess want to comment that I think
that that also should be said for all
the drive if we should say that clearly
it's it's a basically a design choice
and yeah there is a awesome identifier
for the pre hash variant so well if we
are only focused on the non pre hash
then probably we should remove this next
like I think there are two slides on
this dress okay so the next step
alrighty values update diversion and we
need some reviewers so that this week or
next week we can
send that to the iesg so I never
launched here no you care about Sam ok
we'll take me to the list I don't want
to do it without at least one up from
first have you read it I guess what so
it's it's really good shape ok Tammy
yeah
all right girl CMS yes do you want to go
to this one or yeah this is any
discussion no no no no you're changing
the oids to the I a narc on republish I
think we will maybe remove everything
about the pre hash variant other there
are the Oh IDs the algorithm identifier
in the beginning and should we have some
comment about the CR else also to some
of the discussions we had that Sam the
three think I see God now you have you a
question have we decided that we're
replacing the IEDs that are in the
current draft with other royalties they
so that we'll have to go into the
eyepiece like a need for after about Ed
BSA because it references this one okay
yeah yeah what's on the story summer
here with you okay so the reason we
asked for is that CMS was needed needed
to register so mo IDs and we couldn't
get the contact information from the
current ID used by curdle so we did not
receive answers we move to an INR we had
a short arc donated by symantec in the
contact person Oh otherwise I can find
okay so all right um should we post a
draft probably pretty quickly and then
we are ok and then we'll forward it out
though yo yo yo just sync up with the
ipsec box
okay okay so um edss signatures so
nothing really much to say we one person
is we only had one reviewer so it's
pretty shaped but a well if possible we
would like to have another reviewer so
anyone volunteering how could somebody
devil for this is open yeah I'll get
someone okay so next slide um this one
is well has more reviews I don't think
we need really another reviewer any
questions regarding this draft next
draft yeah they're all in Lascaux so all
those um so this draft yeah it's about
to use of share too um yeah I think we
it's it's almost the same we well we
would need more reviews especially I
think it's more the way to graph is
written but it's pretty good it's pretty
well shaped and almost ready it's a very
short drat i think less than 10 pages so
people coming later are going to be a
sinus reviewers wow yeah so again if you
can't could provide some feedback
Saunders I mean review choose one or two
drafts review them and then we can look
forward why don't you get no cookies at
the next idea
oh come on yeah yeah this drafty well is
also pretty much ready some changes have
been submitted to the least he has been
considering various implementations so I
don't think it's very clear but it would
be better to have some other feedbacks
other reviews it's mostly to see if the
text is clear rather than a contact I
mean so that's pretty easy to go yeah it
is already widely deployed discussion
bullet says and it points up
um yeah this one's so okay yeah I get
very confused with the name of the draft
so this one is adding a new gfield new
key exchange algorithms based on the new
other kernels the curves yeah it's only
adding a one point or two so please say
you agree with a draft and so we can
move that forward next slide and if you
have any questions on each of these
dress or issues you want to give you
read it right and this is you want to
bring up step up to the mic and we will
back up no problem just trying to set a
speed record here we'll look the curb
don't just one question about SSH in
general what happens if you put with the
existing applications or app that are
out there if you have nests SH key for
an algorithm that isn't understood did
the widely used versions of ssh do
something sensible or do they fall over
and die has anybody looked into it I use
a key or a host key usually as so I
think like the widely used in Satan
plantations we'll look at a whole bunch
of files in your daughter's age
directory to try and find something that
they can they can use no they're just
carry on for the next thing yeah until
it hits the air account it says too many
failures but yes it does a reasonable
thing okay well this one is also adding
two point codes so smart on this one too
no 20 okay it's a good les hommes this
one named adding named eh groups
specific ones I'm curious I'm curious
what TLS folks think about it since we
sort of have kind of dropped those I
mean sorry this is microphone hi and
we're kind of like moving towards the
different set of groups in this some
little surprised you're not adding the
ones that we spent the trouble
standardizing but you know not for us to
tell you what to do rather than you
should do what we did so I think this is
more about capturing what's in the
deployed base then moving forward I
think that's a valid concern though and
should probably be reflected in security
considerations section this is dkg sorry
I actually haven't read this at all but
I'm assuming these are finite field
routes that here that's fine I actually
don't think that you should say use the
same groups that we specified for 40 of
us although I do think we should have
specific specified groups so i'm not
sure why ecker recommended that you use
the exact same groups that we did it's
fine to have two different protocols use
different sets of groups as long as
they're strong primes usual usual
constraints out of 90 google so if this
is just documenting existing reality
than that that's great and should be
done oh why wouldn't you just want to
use the same groups just less text just
to to provide mean the rules for
generating groups that are strong are
not complicated like we understand those
and so you might want to not use them
across domains if there's some weird
something gets cross domain that we
don't understand there's a bunch of
situation with cross domain attacks
because you're using a similar protocol
and things hook together
it turns out that something TLS looks
like something an association can be
reused I don't see that here but I don't
know and if you avoid using the same
groups you can avoid that problem if
Greta these are the same groups as I
them then now you die you're just the
question is I vs SSH so I'm totally fine
with using one set of groups for one
protocol to avoid any possible cross
protocol condemning a condition that I
don't understand I'm not going to have a
specific answer oh I don't know I I
didn't find that hugely convincing but
the my organ was purely like it's less
typing and that's not great either sir
all right we'll try to encourage
discussion on the list and maybe pollute
I can TLS also I don't think I those
groups has any equities here like you
know we may have some overall ITF
question what we should do but it's not
like jealous cares what I mean other
than as a general matter of principle
cares what I safe does um anything that
me adam says these are just this is just
you know this is just endorsing stuff
however pure to do that great if we're
on acceptable at least if I if if we're
picking new groups that we nobody use it
we want them to use weepers I ask why
but second I would say like there are
these other group structure we that we
were happy about there are q9 sunseeker
and these are the groups that are
usually naik and IP second they have
been there for all time over and they
are venerated in same way that the one
certainty Eleazar created except they
are using pi and the Taylor's using me
yata care but ever they're getting ready
I have the same base so actually either
one is fine it's just you know which you
think is both of them are used already
all the donors that we know best right
already so it's just picky one so the
second half of the phrases and running
code so that would argue for the ike
okay I it might be a little premature
for last call who solicit some
discussion on the list it might be a
bike shed anybody else anybody else have
any other issues drafts potential work
they want to discuss well we we have um
well when the CMS draft and the peak
eggs draft will be sent will we have a
receipt of requests to for a GSS update
and so that's going to be the next
coming draft before we close yeah that's
right so that was off mic there before
we close Russ so I'm sorry I was late
did we talk about draft p kicks and did
we settle on absent null or both um if
not I'd like the darker added since
we're all here so nope rehash all that I
understood that was better than that
yeah no let's explain the issue we did
not talk about it we did not talk well
it's Jim here yeah yeah so the asn.1
structure allowed the when you're the
parameters field in 1997 when they
converted from the 1988 syntax to the
newer asn.1 syntax some editor dropped
the word optional in algorithm
identifier and as a result a bunch of
people were forced to specify null as a
parameter when none was needed and then
they had it optional back in the next
release and so there is some some code
that doesn't remember that or does not
yet know hear that optional is there and
they insist on
some parameter and so I prefer to not do
that but get people update their code
and the bottom line is that we have one
place in that document where there's a
discussion on the list about whether
it's optional order null and the big
point that i have dated benjamin made
and I agree with him was pick one don't
make it you know accept either one
because then you end up that's where the
interoperability promos come am i right
Jim mirrors did I okay thanks but I'm
that would be easier if other people can
support that view yes underneath that's
why i love stark warrior I don't 90
google I strongly support that for you I
don't give a hoot what which one it is
if this group doesn't pick one then we
will pick one and we will break everyone
else who picks every anything else and
and therefore i will pick it so i
suggest you pick it so on the one hand
you'd be like well the existing deployed
base expect something on the other hand
the existing deployed base is going to
need changes to support these curves
anyway so let's just do the clean right
thing Jim the document right now has
picked one which is dark yes it matters
because Java the standard Java provider
can't deal with it a pamphlet and okay
right I think they're so document okay I
think you're also a lot of other
algorithms that are actually using
saying that you must not have you know
you first let's have now they're so if
they don't support that they don't to
portos sequence all girls either so I
think the chiverses need to fix it their
stuff fun
I'm not sure how to phrase the question
without annoying people but um then yeah
well okay so yeah absent break some Java
in both so how many want to support
those hum absence or brick city okay all
right so it's absent simplest cleanest
break some java none no no i hated this
one s when sequel had the problem too
right no you carry an explicit I'm not
here and then both so how many people
are in favor of supporting both how many
people are in favor having no there's an
explicit I'm not here how many people
are in favor of having no indicator when
there is no option that's a pretty clear
consensus will confirm it on the list
yeah right yes I got to know not and Jim
do you have to make any doc changes to
do that I yeah that's called a straight
line yeah all right great okay I think
yes right surprise okay anybody else
anybody else have any other business
they want to bring up yes okay all right
there is a last question about the use
of PSS and/or PKS s 11.5 so for I think
it's a RSA it is sh yeah
so I can find the draft name some crew
the colonel Arthur you get shot good one
yeah yeah so one question is do we have
a we would like storing to move to PSS
given that well PK CSS is kind of we
can't avoid that one so do we want to
add a PSS or is it a bad idea to have
these two variants personal preference
shoot 1.5 in the head just like what
like TLS 13 did jump um try you have
mirror hitter Goodman on the list said
that there's actually no weakness that
we know of with PK SI s 1 point 5 so it
might as well stay with that it's true
that it's that it's easier to make
proofs about PSS but there's no weakness
why I add some new stuff when we already
have because he s 1 point 5 not my
arguments pretty good yeah there are
given I think they were soon attack but
if you have a very short you know expert
if you enjoy whispering tree or
something like that there was some type
of 1.5 that was more vulnerable to
something than PSS yeah but I mean I
mean if you are saying that there's
nothing for 1.5 there dearies yeah yeah
but I mean I mean yeah then I'd
basically also actually just moved a
basic was using 1.5 old also and now in
the bin which defied the Liberator to
sleep in search we actually only
departed you know to say that the PSS
system under the soup to speak on which
of course causes you know issues because
people actually have to implement it
when take them into signature algorithm
they can't just make a very simple you
know oh we have the same or sequences up
tickle giggle sickness algorithms and we
just change the format they actually
have to implement VSS also but I think
it actually would be better to move the
PSS
Adam Langley Google PSS would be nice
but isn't the world moving away from RSA
as a whole and so is it really worth the
time to worry about this steaming pile
and sorry make up the context wrong but
we're talking about this for Shi yeah
you have anybody implementing in the
room but then we shouldn't decide um you
know I've near jenin opposing you then
because of TLS 1.2 me epigraphic
librarian the world is going to
implement PSS now so might as well use
it wherever we have where we have a need
for signature algorithms does anybody
have any strong feelings one way or the
other yeah okay well we'll take it to
the list and the inclinations to say
let's not add something that may not be
widely used right as okay thank any
questions all right yeah thanks for
coming um we'll probably wrap up at the
next IETF everything will just be in the
last call next class next idea for
probably that's certainly the last face
to face unless somebody comes up with a
whole bunch of new drafts and mechanisms
thank you all for your participation see
you later alligator all right so with
two follow-ups on the list well free p p
pcs versus already a PSS what do we do
exactly because it's already on the list
yeah some people if you haven't signed
the blue shade
yeah well we'll just call consensus
again obviously yeah no no no they just
a chorus decided that you can gas
injection okay all right i'll say what
is the book about you hey so they they
will do physics i guess was a dds a sign
optigan second one is probably not a
tasty tape hair pills I need to give an
ash politics in DNS big or JP eventual
did you use to the man that's chair
right that's what's male takes us yeah I
don't think it right that's fine happen
okay sorry it's right on hey sir maybe
you can ask our breasts yeah what about
exercise yeah as long as little yeah it
rasta yeah oh sorry so do you want to
send email sure the actual parameters
and signature oh yeah so do we send an
email alert unless you subsequent sort
of in there with ya sayin you know from
the consistency so you read it yeah
I think Jim should be so anti guard
because otherwise we will have to the
various people will the visual of it
around the problem was I needed three
more right and they were silent so I am