let's give it 30 seconds to give 12 to
the dangerous and if applicable to the
topic okay we could swap at any time
good afternoon everyone this is dots I'm
glad you're here to join us my name is
remington a do I not co-chairing with to
buy his gun room so let's get started so
you've seen this I'm sure in previous
previous sessions the note well of
course applies to this meeting we have
the blue sheets passed around please
please do make sure that you sign it so
we can provision the room in future
meetings and wanted to thank our jabber
scribes in turn takers Frank and Bob
very much appreciated agenda wise we
have a full deck ahead of us what you
see there is not that different that
what was on the mailing list I think
only one implementation report was added
would anyone like to bash this agenda ok
I take that as no let's proceed forward
before we do that just wanted to give
you a quick status update on where we
stand in the working group since we got
together last in IDF 97 we had a virtual
interim in February we also had a design
team meeting earlier this week on Monday
to working group documents have been
updated and earlier this week we started
a pole for adoption on the gated channel
document there's been some traffic on
that please do respond and we have at
some time on the agenda to talk about
that later there are also a couple
updates in the individual drafts we're
going to get into a lot of these
documents during our time
here we have an updated use case a show
for new movement since we last got
together in terms of published documents
on the IM DM with regards to the status
of the solutions it's actually hard to
see there in the graphic but we've we've
had a couple of updates that you see
reflected there in green but in the case
of the bottom three documents the
authors on that draft have said for the
time being they're going to pause
progress on these drafts and put their
energy into those top two drafts and we
can further this conversation when we
talk about the solutions we'll talk a
little bit more about milestones after
we wrap up on the drafts but I throw
this up to point out that we are behind
we need to revise those milestones to
reflect reality and we need to start
really pressing forward with ours with
our solutions kind of drafts and we can
talk about how to do that specifically
again after we hear the presentations so
to the agenda first up for us is Roland
who's going to be talking about our use
cases so we have a clicking in one
moment hi I'm Roland Evans over networks
okay the cliff he is not working I'm not
smart enough to unit here we go okay
here we go so um first of all thanks
very much to Daniel will go on in Frank
John who pushed this update out with the
04 draft of use cases the structure has
been simplified so a lot of the stuff
that was in the appendices um leading
unnecessary and has been dropped we've
added an orchestration section not
because dots is vital to the operation
of orchestrators but to provide use
cases a use case at least one escapes
that shows how a denouncement agaciro
frustration system would interact with
external entities via dots and what
effect different dots messages you would
have on the the actions of your
frustration system takes
in order to successfully mitigate DDoS
attacks so that's actually a pretty
lengthy section that is an added there's
also a new intra-organizational use case
this is actually I'm having to do with a
broadband access ISP who are protecting
their customers against ddos attack
scene and and how the use of dots would
take place between their customers in
their actual orchestration system and
detox communication systems even though
the end customers themselves are
actually you know what are there
individuals their small home offices
what have you there different entities
this is actually considered an intra
organizational use case because the
broadband access ISP operate the entire
network infrastructure here it's not as
if this is in like an enterprise who
operate their own network infrastructure
and have their own distinct transit edge
or their purchasing transit from one or
more multiple providers so it's a little
different that's pretty intense extent
exhibit a pretty extensive section and
the pro style is a bit more accessible
as well so that's really Oh war in a
nutshell 405 we have eight or nine
proposed additional use cases that we
want to put before the group to take a
look at these are dealing with issues
like multihoming in a scenario where all
the different upstream transit providers
support dots but they don't speak to one
another or situation in which they do
speak to another or a situation in which
an endpoint network has multiple
upstream providers but only one of them
actually supports Dawson has yes
mitigation service capability we also
have provider requesting assistance from
a provider so an overload senere an
overflow scenario where where a DDoS
mitigation service provider is actively
mitigating attacks and they're reaching
of their capacity in terms of transit
and mitigation faster so they signal to
other operators for assistance using
dots and then we also have another use
case in that group which is where
there's a federation
of networks who have joined together for
mutual DDoS mitigation assistance and in
this particular case and a hosting
colocation operator are getting pummeled
by a lot of traffic coming originating
from a broadband access provider network
and so they actually signal the
broadband access provider network to
suppress the outbound you ask traffic in
donating clear network so those kinds of
use cases will be in 05 there's a
grammatical things and stylistic things
that we want to improve from from 04 and
they're the same thing in the
orchestration section it's not really
changing the meaning of the content in a
significant way it should stylistic with
anything else we want to continue to
harmonize our terminology look at their
graphs we have two additional terms and
acronyms that we need to define as well
and one of our authors has changed
affiliation so we need to update the
document vo5 to reflect his new village
so that's all I have questions comments
so rolling win when when money you
expect that though 5 i'm relatively soon
um seven of the nine additional use
cases argue written have to get the
additional ones out there and then get
them out you know for comments before we
look at incorporating so not long can I
quantify this with the date okay I
expected date because not long its
relative term let let's say roughly
three weeks we can we can try to target
that but it's going to be dependent on
how much feedback you know we get right
back thunderbolts and half the clue get
we can get you for that kind of time
frame but not not very long ok can I
suggest with working group hit first you
can actually if you have already seven
you can close to seven and second a
feedback that comes I actually want to
encourage that this feedback is given up
on the mailing oh we love young not off
channel and then it will be again
helpful if you just make an update and
you know don't don't be shy version
numbers are cheap we have plenty of them
so
thank you okay I Andrew Mortensen arbor
networks you have the multihoming use
case there with some dot servers that
were not capable or was that where we
have an ongoing area where they're all
dots capable and I'm a looming area
where there's multiples but only one of
them is dots capable can we talk about
the operational impact that will have on
the organization that is request you
know the things they need to take into
account when they have to under it when
you're under do not stab and then they
end up going from you know three
upstream providers want right what kinds
of things they have to take into account
that's actually a big part of dots that
I think a lot of folks don't realize is
that the technology itself is not magic
great oh it's simply a lingua franca and
in the use cases we hope to give the
flavor of the other out-of-band things
that have to be done in order to make
dots work good because one of the
outstanding issues on the architecture
draft is the multi-homing case so
hopefully the use cases yes we also on
to our last architecture call in in one
of the use cases its broadband access
network where there are multiple dots
clients that are all signaling for
mitigation systems because it's a very
broad-based hat and we talked about on
whether or not it should be considered
in scope for dots the dots servers
themselves to try to consolidate
alerting or whether that should be a
meal up to the orchestration system what
have you so we then that the three cases
included thanks so what did I ask if
there are new additional questions I
don't see how I come in Mike are there
more use cases out there that you don't
see documented in any of the existing
individual drafts or in the current
working group document well when we can
get a discussion going I'll go ahead
this evening and send out the seven that
are already written down written out now
to help facilitate to get people comment
on them hopefully we'll disruption
humans
I'm wondering whether we should probe
the room for who has read 04 because
that is just recently released so did
who has read 04 yet okay well that's 76
a few people a handful yeah potentially
was too short notice before the meeting
so okay then I think we need some more
review and well if you can shoot out
some parts early then maybe the
reviewers will be more motivated it's
always a little bit people would be
hesitated to review a draft if they know
all the next one is coming in a week
yeah okay cool then yeah I encourage
that actually I think from a chair
perspective in a couple of weeks or
months we need to go to last call so I
think this is the right time to start to
do reviews more thank you Thanks a room
thanks Roland next up is a discussion
about requirements Andrew
it also occurred to me yesterday we
discussed getting the use cases draft up
into the dots wgf depository so you can
track the shoes there as well so
hopefully we want an update on that soon
all right so this is an update on the
dots requirements largely this is going
to cover the issues that we've been
going through and our tracking on github
so let's start with the status we do
have a lot of issues a lot but we have
the via known issues on github in the
github Tretton issue tracker the open
issues right now are the blockers to
work in your glass call so you can
actually monitor our progress toward
working group last call by tracking the
open issues just because that's the case
doesn't mean we're not accepting new
issues if you have concerns about the
existing draft please feel free to add
issues you can do this on the github
site or if you don't feel comfortable
that bring them up on the mailing list
and we can make sure that they get
tracked on github and pull requests are
welcome to so if you have changes
suggested changes you don't need to wait
you can go ahead and forth the
repository right now make changes to the
markdown and then set up a pull request
and we can just pull it right in so
we've closed about half of the known
issues since the interim meeting any
feedback that we get on the pull request
has been very helpful there hasn't been
a whole lot of interaction there but
what we've gotten so far has been very
good and you should look for an 05
update very short they probably this
week I've got another poll request or
two and we'll continue working toward
the work of your last call I'm not going
to go into too much detail here on the
recently closed issues you can you can
find them on the issue tracker and I've
also sent out I think a couple updates
to the working for failing list on this
but I will touch on a couple of the more
significant ones issue number nine
pulled in some language from tears
signal channel draft about the path MTU
where the dots agents themselves are
asked to try to discover the path MTU if
they can't they fall back to some
reasonable defaults I think it's 1284
default case and if legacy ipv4 networks
are a consideration to fall back to 576
really necessary issue 11 covers what
sort of security state that dots client
can assume on redirection we currently
have some language there that says the
dots client cannot assume that the
security state is going to be the same
on the redirection target but it's free
to try to do a session presumption using
something like you do a session
presumption I think probably of the
other coast issues number 12 is the most
significant this is trying to establish
the responsibilities of both parties
when it comes to mitigation requests and
the status feedback you get from the
server this goes into some details as
well about the details that you're going
to come back so packets per second
dropped on behalf of the client at twice
per second total total ice drop total
package dropped there's some additional
things there but they're less less
important I think one of the major
concerns that that big Dolson whose
feedback kind of drove a bunch of these
issues had was about some of the
indistinct language for things like
mitigation termination headline so we've
tried to clarify that and the
responsibilities of both parties when
mitigation is actually considered to be
totally terminated this has an aspect
where to try to prevent route or DNS
flapping dots client is it can make a
request terminate mitigation but the
server has a small window to leave the
mitigation running so if the client
decides to reenable mitigation rapidly
the dots client the dot server is not
announcing routes again rapidly I don't
know if this is actually concerned for
people a sort of an informal survey that
I've done with some operators it seems
to be this is relatively important but
others and also said we can just do
Ralph lap dampening so I would be
interested in some feedback if anybody
hasn't well
our networks so um yes I mean you don't
in general it want to have to be
changing your network network state
constantly on however you know from my
perspective and maybe this is how it's
been discuss I don't know this is not
really something that should be built
into dots itself necessarily but it's an
implementation not you know some of some
kind of timer and I think we actually
talked about that in the 00 use cases
draft and you know when we're talking
about the very basic case um we're not
ems requests negation and then turnings
terminates in mitigation that term is an
optional you know there could be an
optional timer where the mitigator keep
some negation active so I don't think
that that's necessarily something that
should be built into dots itself but it
is certainly something that I would
believe an implementer would maybe want
to put that knob on here so one of the
considerations here is we're trying not
to encode financial relationships right
but one of the considerations here is to
try to figure out at what point the dots
clients responsibility and ownership of
the mitigation is actually over while
retaining that flexibility that you're
talking about so the dots server
operators can leave the mitigation for
some small period but at some point the
dots client knows that after that timer
expires it's no longer responsible for
the mitigation can just assume that
since it's asking the mitigation
determinated the dot server operators
are free to let that continue running
maybe they've got the attack has
continued to impact the Oscar server
operators network but not the clients
and the dots client wants it over for
the responsibility yeah roll it over to
our networks um so in that scenario yeah
we probably engineer this in the meeting
but you know the idea is you have the
dots client makes mitigation request dot
server accepts that mitigation started
mitigation status messages are exchanged
then the dots clients is ok I'm going to
issue a negation termination request
great and then you know my assumption
would be that the dot server would
basically say no and then sighting in
litigation is still running and continue
to provide status updates you know until
it based on whatever timers are
configured it decides that that will
indeed close the negation down yeah so I
hear I mean this could be a
configuration thing I think I want to
make sure that the dots
I operators retain the operational
control but I hear what you're saying
yeah is it control control is wrong word
because this is a communications medium
rain and as you said we're not trying to
enforce you know the contractual
relationship which are trying to
facilitate the communication so you know
whatever on you know timers or whatever
you know special rules that allow for
you know a force mitigation termination
from a doc's client to a got server
that's almost really almost outside the
scope of dots oh my thanks so I guess
the the last one that's really worthy of
discussion here on this this slide is
the required an optional mitigation
scope types so previous revisions had
listed some example scope tights but
they were examples they were not
required or optional so the required
scope types now are the obvious ones
ipv4 got a quad ipv4 prefixes ipv6
addresses and prefixes and fully
qualified domain names the optional type
right now there's only one of them so
feel free to suggest others is a URI and
we previously also had listed in the
examples e 1 64 telephone numbers but
you can actually encode those as a URI
so that's I think that covers it and you
are I covers lots of different schemes
as well so we have I think eight or nine
remaining open issues one of them that
we discussed a bit yesterday during
design team meetings is the definition
of what a session is if you look through
previous revisions of the signal channel
if I of the requirements draft there's
this kind of loose use of the term
session more or less interchangeable
with this the channel itself so I've
just gone through I have a quarter quest
now that replaces session the channel
and that made us revolve both of these
things getting Dave's input on this
would probably let us know if we're
moving the right direction the issue
number six is something I think is
probably just a deletion we already have
in front of the security requirements a
requirement from usual off I think this
is just left over I'm going to skip 16
for the moment and then we have some not
considerations right now but they are
implicitly client only
so we need to have some serving that
considerations and whether upnp is
something we need to to add to the
requirements or after a reference to
anyway um so issue 16 is how overlapping
requests should be should be handled
let's say you have multiple dots clients
they detect the same tack separately
there's no acquittal coordination
between them they both asked for
mitigation for the same attack how does
the dot server resolve that I've become
less enamored of the idea that the dot
start would be responsible for resolving
that I feel like this might have to be
an implementation specific thing the dot
server turns a mitigator or whatever is
responsible for installing filters were
doing the putting the appropriate
countermeasures in place and depending
on what a mitigator says is okay the dot
server either rejects or adds the
mitigation it's about a quote on azure
networks as far as I know there's no
concept of mitigation scope within Don's
right again as you indicate that's
something that is really outside I mean
outside the boundaries of the DA system
now you know that the client say okay I
I'm requesting negation you know for
this particular slide your block right
or for this particular you know you are
I or what have you but in the actual
configuration of the mitigation scope
within the dr orchestration system
that's operated by the des integration
service provider is we need we don't
want to get into that because then we're
going to start constricting guys to a
particular paradigm of des mitigation
that relies on a specific technology
path we don't want to do that um could
you go back one slide please or more one
where's the part about the fqdn it's
under the issue phenomenal okay sorry it
was in this light so do you really mean
fqdn or do you mean like the zone cut
because fqdn has a very specific meaning
it is it is a very specific meaning and
the I initially just had domain names as
the initial language yeah and some add
some input from another one of the
editors who suggested replacing with
fully qualified domain have so that's
what's there yeah i think we probably
replace fqdn with something else because
I'd always that implies that we're only
able to put a an fqdn na dots mitigation
request in April client reality we might
want to say like
you know star dot you know example that
a tu been something like that every
subdomain addressed okay sorry Nikki
Fleming and raising the overlapping
request handling I understand why you
know you prefer on a service I'm not
having to deal with it I'm not convinced
that's right answer my concern is that I
don't want to get into a scenario where
requests are essentially client
specifics right and a giving client that
asks something would have to be the one
that gets rid of it as well and if there
are any kind of conflicts right somehow
the clients have to coordinate amongst
themselves right I I don't think that's
going to be workable so I totally agree
on that yeah that's soap so I think
there's an issue in terms of when you
specify a neat mitigation for a certain
scope right how does that get reconciled
between multiple clients that are not
necessarily coordinated and I don't know
how you would do that without having the
servers and she'd be dealing with that
overlapped and you're solving it on the
back end so the one thing that that's
been in the back of my mind right is
this is might be an appropriate place
for the relay where we have that that
the aggregation of the signaling and the
relay is responsible for doing that I
don't know that that's any different
than just having a serger do it I'm
figuring out where the overlap is and
merging them what what really did I say
oh yes what wait way what gateway so
what I'm saying is no I'm being serious
right because when I understand yeah the
in one of our in the architecture we
have this diagram right where there's
this aggregated signal i'm right at
multiple downstream then the gateway is
responsible for a sort of merging into a
single channel up to a dot server and
that that aggregation sort of implies
the merging of these signal channels and
the scopes but that's since a gateway is
just a back-to-back server and client I
don't think that's only different than
having a server do it let me rephrase my
question okay I you suggesting that we
formally define what a gateway is and
the responsibilities that it has because
currently we don't open spot with that
one
I'm not not right now yeah I would agree
with them oh I think we got a chip away
at this one you know I agree all right i
think the remaining open issues none of
these are particularly contentious in a
way that the overlapping one is i think
there is some ambiguity about what
ownership and protected resources are so
we need to tighten the language there
and get some consensus on that and
adding a couple requirements for
authentication and authorization this
can just be put into the security
requirements section there's a lot of
implicit understanding of what
authentication and authorization is
required we just need to make that
explicit and finally did brought this up
before the last in your meeting about
the need for replay protection my sense
is that we need to be very careful here
because any ability to replay might have
an impact on the server operators
network so we should be we should have
full of retha protections in place there
aren't too many other upcoming changes I
think the the one notable one is that
the operational requirements section has
really evolved into the signal channel
requirements I believe there's one
remaining operational requirement in
there that we can just go to the general
requirements that's relating to the not
finding stuff and then the remaining
requirements under the current
operational requirements section will
just be retitled signal channel
requirements any corporation of any
minor Corrections typos and so on please
submit new issues as soon as you can we
are working toward working group last
call as I mentioned at the beginning of
this is the queue of issues open issues
are the obstacle that is the obstacle to
work your glass call so this we know we
can get through that the sooner we get
to upper he professed call thanks
I economy car without to the heartbeat
discussion do you think there could be a
zero heartbeat mode that'd be difficult
there could be your fabulous of any
caste equal game of Tata Tata ah could
be easy could exist that so in the
architecture draft we have the anycast
consideration section where I think
maybe we should make this clear we
talked mostly about using it as a method
for service discovery right it's a way
to this you use a any cast at service
address and then you get directed to the
unicast server that you should be using
I i think i think the yeah okay papi do
you think that uh math regular i said
how to eat though yeah right in that
case with any cashier you can send a
number change in there yeah yeah I think
we should discuss that offline i'm not
sure that i have a good answer for you
right off the top of my head okay
amite eek i'm just a economies point
they're only a zero heartbeat idea i
think that might have value i mean
that's the odd implement eight implement
potential implementer go spoken to who
wants to spin things up on an ad hoc
basis you know because they don't want
to be maintained multiple sessions from
multiple customers potentially tomorrow
and so that that could have some value
their initiative with that could be
handled maybe via the data channel i
guess which could be just navigating
across sensational but if the signal
channel had a zero hardly function right
and so then they figure just set it up
sells out of the channel user palace or
event ID yeah buying such an exit area
down do the same thing reason the
session use get ego sessions yes okay
okay other questions and comments okay
in that case we'll move on to the next
draft which is the architecture and
andrew you still have the floor
alright so this is this is going to be
quite brief and we have a lot of other
things to discuss a while keep us moving
like the dots requirements we are
tracking open issues long if you could
have issue tracker under the dots WG
group we only have a couple remaining
issues right now the document itself is
kind of paused while we're waiting on
changes to the use cases and
requirements I think the the recent
movement on both of those graphs is is
getting us into position where we can
make the tweaks that are necessary and
we can get ourselves working group last
call soon the issues that we have closed
recently do cover things like service
discovery anycast and the the need for
redirection in the dots of architecture
these have been closed for quite a while
but and all of those changes are in the
existing drafts so if you have issues or
concerns about the the current
discussion of any of these topics please
take another look and bring it up on the
work of your mailing list of or simply
open an issue we only have a couple
remaining issues as I mentioned in the
question for the use cases multihomed
dots clients are still something that we
need to sort out I would like to talk
more with the use cases offers on this
so we can try to coordinate come to
something that's mutually agreeable and
then finally things like privacy and
visibility for a Christmas signaling
this has been a concern about the if you
need to have let's say a mitigator wants
TP I into encrypted traffic are there
concerns about sharing private keys and
if you're using this sort of backstock
recursive signaling but that really
covers it on the architecture draft
right now largely it's going to be some
coordination with the requirements and
use cases drafts and then if we can
knock out the remaining two issues I
think we're ready for working group last
call again submit any issues you have
with the current draft as soon as you
can so we can keep track of what
actually is remaining before last call
I kaplan-meier DAV um sorry I hadn't
read that part and just hearing you say
DPI mandame el traffic that's gonna hit
a bleep storm yeah and I'm not
advocating for it it's just a concern
about do we need to mention the perfect
concern about privacy and security if
somebody is advocating for this in the
architecture draft we're not necessarily
advocating for the sharing of these
might accuse why wouldn't you just have
a requirement that are that's it I'm
sorry I think a requirement that
prohibits it we want to impose that on
somebody that you can what are you
wrapping this in what I'm using TLS
that's that's likely yeah so when you
had a 1.3 that's already done that the
there's the other static if you hum and
stuff that's going on as well right so I
mean there's yes I agree with you ah
yeah not an ietf um you're not in a
working group right not in a working
group um it might go through the
independent stream editor I haven't
agreed to 80 sponsor it and I'll meet
Becker would okay so we'll have to see
what happens but um right yeah i don't
know i think it's i'm proud no i think
getting for this right this was an issue
brought up by one of the other editors
and we've been trying to figure out is
this something we need to treat the
architecture draft all right i'll well
when at least by the time against to my
review i'll look at it and see if it
needs to be in the strap that all um if
you're doing a negative statement
against it that would probably be fine
maybe dropping it completely might be
your best bet yeah okay thank you
roland ovens are renette works a couple
of the issues that are still outstanding
for architecture as well as for
requirements they require some fairly
dense discussions that might I mean we
want to keep things on the list as much
as possible but that doesn't preclude
having interactive discussions and then
summarizing providing the list so maybe
we can think about having a actual
meaning you know a con call for
interested parties to discuss these
issues sometime relatively quickly
because I think with some interactive
discussions we can kind of go through
and not some more things down more
quickly than we could trying to trade
messages on the list I agree I mean I
would even settle for any discussion on
the mailing list at this point on those
issues with their be interest for us to
do virtual item around virtual number
around this or sorry just one question a
timeline for this when do you need it
next week two weeks two weeks from you
ok so you you come to us and tell us
your gonna be doing ok thank you other
things related to the architecture
documents comments concerns feedback all
right thank you and so next up on the
agenda we're gonna pivot to talk about
different protocol and solution-oriented
drafts first up is draft ready dots data
channel that Nick is going to be talking
about and for those that did not see the
announcement on man was this is the
draft we're talking about to pull for
adoption hey i'm nikki i'm here to
present on this one Terry could make it
and it's really this is this is really
more of a recap of the discussions we've
had over the last couple of months and
also the bits and pieces from the
interim meeting the main reason why I
want to recap it is because after the
last meeting we had a bit number
discussions between myself and root area
and a couple of others and we decided
that the as far as the data trial goes
the a lot of the efforts were converging
anyway so we decided to just converge
onto this one draft so to that end the
data challenge using rest conf there
were young models in there they're
cooler yang they're funky the updated
draft meets all the requirements as as
it has been have been pretty much in
line this draft being pretty much in
line with the requirements all the way
along still sitting on top of the stack
that's very very familiar at the
restaurant TLS tcp/ip with dot sitting
on top of it um the rest Kong for
suggested and if you seem to make some
sense it's obviously a subset of net
can't it's not a heavy use net com so we
feel that might provide less overhead as
far as like implementation goes but then
kind of in it allows us to basically use
some common app commonality across other
efforts were it addresses the needs of
what we need as far as like
configuration so on you've got the
general kind of what you would expect
post put delete guess to retrieve config
data and non config there was a tea
lights are people liveliness it's
generally speaking the data channels
reasonably connection-oriented anyway so
it will be maintaining that it goes
along we've got a number of young models
in there already and then we've got the
people it exists and the convert as well
as we go a couple of our options a
couple of examples as identify a model
filter model you identify one is it was
discussed earlier regarding things like
fqdn and this question on that it'd be a
the idea is to basically assign an alias
at the time with the actual mitigation
that instead of having to kind of define
every single individual element you just
say Oh use alias one and that
preferences IP address this work this
service of this so it kind of ties in a
few of those together and then it can be
expanded as we go along maybe we've got
fqdn I you are IE wants it or in there
and stuff so they can just as we as we
wish and as we as we see fit weekly pad
that out
and that's pretty much it i mean it's
just it i think we've we've all come
along same path of them the type of
things you want in this particular draft
and how it's been going in if we've all
been kind of getting there so that's me
done any questions comments sweet so
just agenda wise we built some time here
to talk about are we ready for adoption
of this as a working group kind of
artifact we're not going to decide today
we have a poll out on the mailing list
because we travel and everything there's
two more weeks to provide your your
thinking on this after ietf finishes but
again we have time in the agenda if you
like to share your feelings endorsing
this or you have some concerns and you'd
like them voiced Fleming andreasen I'm
supportive as I said on the mailing list
I think makes a lot of sense I think the
direction that is going as well makes a
lot of sense which to me is more of a
separation of theta channel NBC Hong
satellite is really is operational stuff
I mean configuration related data and a
signal channel can then leverage that
data later on so I like it by the way
it's not to say that they're on any it's
that it's still not being worked on them
Dave race and some comments before
regarding the eye again comments around
the idea session but also the comments
around hit the ideas of cuddling and so
on that we need to look at absolutely
nikka me just to clarify adopting just
as a working group document is not
accept and and it all suggests that what
is in that draft is is concrete it is
completely valuable it's just that we're
accepting the existing text as a working
for artifact I mascis HD consulting I'm
all for this being a working group
document it keeps one aspect simple so
we can keep our focus on the the really
driving part which is the signal channel
OOP okay thank you then that moves us to
the next part I'm unhook this one as
well yes the signal channel which is
more entry more challenging than any of
the swings okay so um one of the reasons
why I want to present this one in the
absence of thiru is because I wanted to
get some color around why why would sort
of converging around this one the shell
even open so there was a protocol
document the week before which sported
protobuf zamora beaconing type of
singling there was this one which was
using co-opting see bore and there was
some other variations on there again
what we had a discussion after the last
meeting and we we came to the conclusion
that we would like to again try and
converge on a single path just to reduce
the amount of duplication and so on to
that end we've kind of decided that in
the absence of being able to kind of
standardized on protocols at this
particular time then what we thought we
could do is at a later date may be used
as a content type we were using credit
buffs in our original draft as an IDL
and leveraging that in the new a draft
that down in new revision satiric put
together and stuff it moved more towards
that some boards a similar apps ybor
having a similar aspects as its protocol
things like the mapping and so on the
element mapping be in addition to that
also having discussions with Fleming and
so on what we saw was we didn't really
want to go through the rigmarole of
reinventing tcp or UDP and congestion
control and all these type of day to the
coop we can handle that for a soak so
with this one the highlights is again we
have the young in there it's a
mitigation request model configuration
model and so on including rules defined
in the core young cyborg and it compiles
nicely
see poor again is being used or
prominent of signal map to see more
types we're using particular types and
nothings to ensure that we can just
again make it a bit more efficient
rather than kind of complete that
constantly reiterating through the
schemer every time you send a message
which was a big big issue I had kind of
between Jason and coding versus say
something like protocols the mitigation
response and the requests are now marked
as non confirmable the non confirm will
requests ascent at regular intervals
until response received that was
something else that we kind of were that
was that was the way we thought needs
shaping in this one and two good job
getting it in there channel
configuration star flag does confirm
also we have sort of have the best of
both worlds and we have printable
messages when we need them non
confirmable than we don't and we go from
there what we've decided to do I think
as well as tranki so that we have static
types we kind of tried to remove some
the ambiguity of 0 in peacetime we could
have confirmable you know and so on so
we're bhutan is like these ones will
always be at this particular
characteristic these of 14 bills of that
characteristics there's no ambiguity in
figuring out what you know kind of
various aspects of what peacetime is
versus you know what you know what time
is the heartbeat mat mechanism is using
the car ping we're looking TTL is 1.3
their sport never event specific
parameters which we feel is important
and for extensibility and so on added
new mutations those parameters which are
somewhat useful for the endpoint to be
able to figure out what's going on it's
like a very basic basic level of
telemetry for the the originator to be
able to figure out you know what as far
as like if the attack on going as you
tackle on going what it's saying it can
then try a degree of status yes Larry so
with regard to sorry Andrew Mortensen
the TLS versions do you think that we
are going to be blocked waiting for
detail s 1 point 3 this morning I mean
it's there are no competing DTLS drafts
right but it's still individual draft
yeah I'm not asking you to choose but
none
we we need to decide if we're waiting on
it yeah overall detail s has been a bit
of it well the dtls has been a bit of a
pain in this um not so much because DC
less itself but the available libraries
out there are painful say the least to
try and get to do what we wanted to do
there's either you know they're just
either lacking or they're just so hard
to work with this isn't that so but
that's pretty much it so deal with this
weekend which we're trying to move
towards this to consult wars
consolidation I'm not sure whether we're
completely ready to to say that this
one's ready for adoption yet but that
doesn't mean we couldn't ask the
question again comments or questions
welcome maybe it's a chair quick
question why do you say you think it's
not ready yet my personal opinion is we
just need to refine it a bit more and
that's maybe just being a bit precious
it's it's more it's probably it's I'll
guess I guess it's more cosmetic than
anything else my opinion is to that but
my opinion is that I just feel we need
to kind of like maybe just refine it and
just have it flow a little better and I
think that's something that's actually
been working to in the most in the most
recent variation most recent version and
I think it'll be out in the next version
as well and I think we're very close to
it but I just think there's a few tweaks
and everything that just you know just
before we go with it having said that
like I said let's not say we could
master coach slamming andrea's so I've
ever support the notion of trying to
converge on a single value yeah I think
I mean what this group needs to produce
right our protocol specifications in the
end um well one of each one for today I
don't yes you're right not multiple of
them and the sooner we can get to that
point like the better in terms of you
know where do we focus our energy right
i mean we had the information model as
well the reason that we have that my
friend is because we have had competing
protocol suggestions in there like the
data model is in here already like same
thing for the data channel so if we
could find a way of converging on a
single protocol
of a signal channel I think that would
be very helpful to the group overall so
I would certainly support it from that
point of you cook and you know i think
it was reasonable right as a starting
point oh yeah i mean i mean what's in
there at the minute i don't really have
any issues with the content for this we
just need to it's just flowing likes it
cause my dear I mean a plenty of details
still right but you don't get you want
to change yes not my skirts I do have
two concerns from what you said Nick
actually one that the am Angie said TLS
dtls 1.3 blocking what's the
consequences of that that no what no
what is it that why do we want 1.3 and
thus the blocking we may need to call
that out the other thing is the comment
you mentioned about detail are actual
detail ice implementations and issues
regard to that is so is their experience
which is showing us something that week
that will be need to be concerned with
or any gave maybe some implementation
recommendations which we may need we
need to stay say in the as as
informational information but something
they had to put in the document with
regard to actual experience no I think
those are both great comments and as far
as our invitation goes implementation
attempts of gun I think what we found
and where we have heartaches is because
we've been trying to get this working
for a little while and now very in our
various efforts and it's like just
trying to get the one that's you know
the ticks all the boxes that we feel we
need having said that I think if we if
we do start to consolidate on single
draught and we're starting to kind of
say well now we can start to talk about
the stuff then we can start to them dig
deeper figure out what is what we need
what's lacking what we can tolerate you
know even yes and so on and then we can
figure out well is it is this a blocker
or can we go do something else you know
is it is the for example I think Andrew
used the tiniest cell which had an
implementation that might not be great
but would it be sufficient you know so
there's those questions to come up but
yes I think your comments or well noted
thank you
I Andrew ones and I think I'm kind of
responsible for the question about
whether we should adopt now but that was
on revision 09 revision 10 has
incorporated a bunch of stuff and I
would be okay talking about adoption in
spike maybe maybe that is indeed than a
question to ask maybe before I ask that
we should ask who has read documents
okay so okay who has read draft ready
dot signal channel version eight nine or
ten because that makes it cos hid it
okay so that's a couple of roughly 10 12
keep your hands roughly okay just okay
that I think that's a sizable amount of
people so um master so actually show me
off now okay let's be let's be let's be
aggressive and that's awesome so who
would be I'm gonna ask the question who
would be comfortable know who's in favor
of adding adopting this is a working
draft the answer would be yes no or
don't know so who's in favor yes crazy
or shelby hand hum i think this hummus
probably more adequate sorry soham now
or the ad has something to say cafe get
new book yeah whatever your location oh
alright so if you're in favor of
adopting hum now please okay who is
against that I'm now please okay i think
that is reasonably good abstains you can
hum ok i think that is quite good
consensus to adopt thank you cool
okay so this brings us to to an exciting
part of the agenda from a working groups
perspective to actually talk about
implementations of some of these
protocols so we have two up so economy
is first talking about the entity
implementation hi i'm thomas newcomen
EDT communication they I'd like to show
you the demesne tation experience behind
in the field short presentation okay now
we are developing those diet top of rare
fish a domestication from the these
drugs which with us nah I just hate
working well although if he is not free
romantic it will be open sourced with
psv see clouds lightning it is re
implementation of a very able to invent
through those protocol specification he
accordance with the curing of da
stressful fair and we can show you a
table to any time so please contact us
I'm available after this meeting us any
time in the rest of ikea meeting she's
makin a Meccano stop you which versions
of those drafts did you implement okay
it is not written very are pitiful this
date each other in the video lady trust
our signature honor is based on part of
city hey thank you
okay this figure shows the outline of
our application the core of application
is the thoughts communications channel
between those client and server the
thoughts Gaia since those message is not
service in court over de ellas as dots
sugar the dot server receives the signal
and then he validates it to forget a
message format as the content itself of
the posterior and then determine whether
the students should be handed over to
further process then adult sabah start
mediation by handing over the signal too
lovable broadcast a mitigator the chose
go bdp are the first the plague of
locusts which enables our deviate law
stick or Die version in any digital
network so we will expand a capable in
Tahiti to utilize other devices which
really over ssh or other protocols
finally the third server will be able to
send out message to other dots enabled
devices as adults gateway functionality
the software is implemented in colon
Adam implementation experience I can
assure you that the cost education
experience is venture to be implemented
however finding good libraries such as
God restaurant especially DTLS is rather
yada because we are trying federal
detest library however we haven't found
any good he can get get it library we
work with the specification of God cigna
father anam grab it yeah entrance
regarding the details libraries are you
if there is no native
golang dtls library right now right
there's some that implements the go lang
dtls which is rapping openssl as i
corrected that what you're using oh yeah
yeah no Mickey Cola like I so I you see
that I am calling it okay yeah yeah yeah
yeah did the one that I have been trying
to use is a tiny detail s which
implements the sort of their
requirements for co-op I don't know if
you take a look at that but it's it is
the best electron hey I use the loose if
it's here how about which is only using
a gated 1.2 okay I'd like to show you
two issues family if you need to
experience but one is about the coupling
of data channel on the student other the
student center of state deviated what
year is this land package gates must be
used for mutual authentication under the
boat summer couples that dot signal on
the data channel system using dust those
trans identities so two drafts require
that same common name for playa cited in
DTLA of signal channel on the theory of
each other I think this is strong
restrictions for implementation and
deployment so if Todd is going to use
other beauty authenticity Brody's it
needs generalized conflict of C energy
we are we I mothering for the customer
organization education ID tip actually
included integral data makes it okay oh
hi Jeff Hodges if you don't need to
really be using the seein as the subject
name you should probably be looking at
using the subject alternative name
extension and mapping to DNS in that and
you don't need to use a distinguish a
next 500 distinguished name in in the
subject you can put
whatever you want and there but you
really should be leveraging subject
alternative name okay Fleming andreasen
I agree completely with your observation
this is you know what we were alluding
to I think before as well with your
authentication and authorization model
and also the separation of the signal
I'm data channel the way it is right now
is not right i mean the signal channel
and data channel I independent right
it's the data that's being conveyed over
them that you have to reconcile in the
back end and we have to have an occasion
or authorization model that works for
that I think right now it says it's
based on the dots you know client ID or
something like that I agree i think is
too narrow I think that's your fear more
flexible with me mad so what extent we
need to specify that versus that becomes
you know a back-end operator issue I'm
not sure yeah but separation updates
turn around a single time I don't pick
on the issues so I gratitude change the
point ok infinity experience we
thought we realized that the Italian Air
Force Hospital on see that the only post
going to because it is used to sometimes
so they are each so the they are
separated ok totally obscure channel are
separating the thoughts cry out for this
channel can be placed in different
location there will be less probability
of suffering from attacks than the place
optional channel only devices so in
order to cover those channels from
combat grant or then this world and 450
ed hardy however if that is really
beautiful I'd like to add some use case
to our use extra typing at least one by
me and raise nyan absolutely i think
there is such a use case good
thank you sorry just a just 2 plus 1
Fleming and I graders in this case I can
see many occasions when that might be
useful for whatever reason I need to
have I don't have separation in the
domain or to have clients are again like
we said before either single signal only
or Dave channel or combined but spread
out yeah yeah thank you is that that's
not captured right now in the current
text I'm confirming I don't think it's
captured in that I don't think some text
yeah I think it I think you could imply
it but so she touch you I think you can
find out by I I apologize just to make
it explicit so it's not in the use case
draft clearly enough then that means it
needs to be clarified there yeah so
thank you yeah sorry for interrupting I
enjoy mortensen I was wondering if you
had any if you've done anything toward
client provisioning at all my
bootstrapping or if that's still coming
down the road although yeah their client
provisioning yeah so so getting the
keying material ok now I'm death using
that I am software page only reading
that typifies fighting about that equate
of the mitigation who hey I'm Amy I'm
kind of bomb a squid some this last
slide where you had the one data channel
with multiple armed signal channels
pretty much flies in the face of your
previous comment about how to connect
the two authentications together to pair
them up because you basically have
almost like a reverse multicast sort of
a situation here or how they didn't ease
are going to done this is going to take
some real serious of thought
about how to do the the identity control
such that you have what linkage you want
it's an interesting use case but it's
going to take some real serious arm
thought of how to do it and feel
uncomfortable with it hey we can live
our party Jefferson organisms you
mention I thinking the first or second
slide that you're open source the code
right so my question is you have a
timeline for that or whenever you play
into the never the code to release the
code okay uh now I'm trying to talk to
our raviga Department oh I don't know
world how I don't really date so I
cannot promise you however it will be
between these a big meeting on the next
time clementa isn't just responding to
Bob's comments before I actually don't
see them at us with each other at all i
think they're very well aligned to use
case in areas that get there i think
it's very common I it's not the channels
that are being bound together right it's
the data that they're operating on and
controlling access to that data that
needs to be sorted out I don't see
anything at all consider
okay i love rifle of the last word from
me that i read at least that we made a
heartbeat but it is not even eight yet
so i will get hot hot with our dogs you
know Charlie are falling through the
operatives with each other drop and then
i will make a father feedback to this
body would wake up dead a tragedy not
thank you comment as a chair this is
awesome so i've been long hoping to see
the first implementations being
presented and this is really very very
good thank you very much very yeah thank
you Kaname thank you administrative
liebe for you to the next presentation
where is the blue sheet who needs the
blue sheet okay if we could just pass
the blue sheets up to whoever needs the
blue sheet thank you Fleming Europe if
you could tell us about your
implementation so uh mm-hmm I can tell
you about series implementation it's uh
it's not mine i will do my best you know
all right so if you recall the
presentation that we did at the last I
ETF there was actually a couple of
slides in there about the proof of
concept that was done back then and it's
pretty similar actually in terms of the
information that's in here the major
difference is that the proof of concept
implementation has been updated to
reflect the latest draft so in terms of
the overall framework here californium
especially on the server side that's the
same as for the last time you go online
of course and not download yourself if
you want to play around with it there
are various api's in here isaac was
mentioning right there is these related
to congestion control our than I
important message transmission
parameters heartbeat timeouts which we
specifying as part of your ball toss
protocol operation and then the new part
here about messages being confirmable or
non confirmable also that's being
leveraged
well now in the end of a concept that's
here has done the client side is
browser-based so there is a plug-in
copper again there's a URL here where
you can go fits that that will enable
you to essentially come up with your own
messages and then you can send those to
the server and you can play around with
those and that's a sense of what's been
done here is an example of those again
you see we have an example here non
confirmable message seaboards what we're
using and this is another there is a way
of actually decoding some of these
messages back and forth if you wanted to
see there's a URL for that as well so
this is just basically illustrating you
an example message here how it's been
actually encoded and what's be sent
across so that is it for the proof of
concept from terror any questions or
comments on that okay thank you for
making so we just had two
implementations are there is there a
third one lurking that anyone wants to
bring up or aspiration for
implementation
Barry green for akamai I think um in
hallway conversations leading up to this
and and I did last week a read-through
of all our docs from the point of view
of implement as Russ white and I were
talking we don't want this to go down
the path of cider alright so I think we
need to instigate implementations all
right so I think we're in a phase where
it's not just asking who's implementing
I think it's dumb there are there's um
efforts where you can have several
companies get the governesses ok we're
going to instigate we're going to pay
some University go do it or you can you
got governments who throw money at
projects like this you know it's I think
um now's the time to start you know in
several people you know involve of the
drafts or say like oh we're not ready
yet this is okay no now's the time to
start to instigate the implementation
our roadmap of deployment right because
we will we want to make sure that we
come to fruition for this work we got to
get our roadmap of deployment I mean to
get a the co we have a prototype or the
ballot make sure it's done you start
that now get the funda now right like I
don't know you know on the you know like
for instance of you guys see see if you
know right right if if we don't we don't
if we don't have vendors starting ACC
process it concept commit process these
are the sort of things we need to start
getting going with it because as you
start it now you know we get to more I
ETS you know we're making some good
progress on the specifications things
will get closed out and as we get more
people using the docks you know what
we'll find and discover things in tune
the work so if there's I think if
there's anybody interested in this I
think we can get a side little
instigation sort of of discussions going
on and start rolling this out and then
in the next idea report out for the
working group is to have a sections of
saying okay what's the result of our
efforts of getting things moving on more
implementation operational deployment by
two cents
thank you completely agree any other
vendors researchers want to speak up
about their plant implementations yeah
it so two things that your bison I've
been talked about it our first now that
we're talking about individual
specifications do we want to start doing
this as part of the hackathon that's
held saturday before ITF perhaps in
Prague we're Singapore and given that we
have two implementations at one point we
start talking about interop between them
so things on our minds if you're
interested please do let us know okay so
the last item on our agenda is not
directly related to some of the specific
architectures we've been kind of talking
about so next up is talking about IP fix
usage so Marvin all right this is Marvin
don't play from Huawei and I'm gonna
give you a brief update on the interrupt
ok this is countin I would go through
the background the changes from the last
iteration ideas issues in this step the
main main purpose of these presentations
to do some clarifications so the
background as you'll see why would I be
fixed draft appear in adults looking
group the first thing is um actually our
draft targus same problem space that we
want to solve that dots attacks but the
approaches we approaches we are taken by
taking are given differently as you have
learned that dots is more about
signaling building the signaling
mechanism but our job is more about
building a data analysis platform so so
that's the difference
and so this is yes as the working group
chairs just this is a little bit of the
the scope of dots so this the reason why
we submit this revised the draft is
because it's a little bit about the
history the original draft was here so
we want to present the new a PT job here
maybe we can hear some opinions from the
floor about security issues alright so
the nest like ah what we propose in this
trap is actually a collection of IP fix
information elements as you can see on
the left best the original setup I've
been fixed elements in the last
iteration so it is in the new trap that
we have armed with in the IP fixed
elements and we have actually removed a
lot of IP fix Edmonds because the
removed I be fixed elements they can be
implemented using the existing animals
through some combination or complex
structures so this is a maybe a lesson
learned for you that if you want to add
some new IP fix information elements you
should really look at the unique 16 ones
alright and so what's left in the new
trap is it's all about TCP connection
tracking that's a the concept would like
to promote so as I said before we like
to butte a data analysis platform so uh
so we want to collect a certain
information from TCP connections and it
is
is by a by using big data technologies I
am using this password because because
the information we collected from the
typical anxious don't have to be very
accurate actually we just want to
monitor the changes that behavioral
changes of those characteristics in
those TSP connections so so i chose on
IP fix because we need some mechanism to
export those information from kiss p TCB
traffics and as you know that I Vivek
see small standard and is widely bought
it so we just need to add some new
information elements so this is the main
idea okay if you look at the diagram
what slack what's what's lacking the idx
information elements is the sum of the
some of the information related to TCP
that set up all the timing information
for example the timing information that
is related to this participe three-way
handshake which is used to set up a TCP
connection some attacks may our result
in a very abnormal that changes in those
times so we believe collecting of
clicking these kind of information is
and processes it in arm in a statistical
way can help us detect anomaly in TCP
traffic's what so what do you mean by
TCP connection tracking as you know that
TCP has certain secondly in flex so we
want to have some flax set for all those
that is basically in flex if we
observe a sink then we observed a sink
ACK that's normal but we said that flex
only if those blacks occur in the
connection in a normal sequence if it's
not in the normal sequence then we will
not set those information we will not
not set those flags so by clicking this
information we were it would be easier
for us to tell apart what the TCP
traffic is doing all right we also want
to incorporate some of the informations
about the the packet and the time
intervals between different TCP segments
because that might be armed exploited by
the attackers so this these are a basic
set of information would like to collect
around his feet connections and nest
which will realize there are certain
issues regarding our solution the first
one is a sim message asymmetric traffic
as we know their internet is more and
more is becoming more and more
asymmetric so this will limit the
applicability of our solution because we
need to collect the information from a
conversion point that can observe both
the uplink and downlink TCP traffic they
also they also some concerns about the
performance yes um if the traffic is
really a stream the bottom of the
traffic is really a large that might
require a super power device deployed on
the conversion point to collect such
kind of information so these are major
two issues that we we are now are facing
and basically so as I said this is just
some clarification from the front for
this working group so I we appreciate
that way to some discussions in the
email list and we appreciate the old
comments you have given to us thank you
very much and so the next step we are
we're going to take might be when I
submit our IP fix information elements
directory to iono the ANA but the reason
we are doing another reason we're doing
this presentation is because we want to
solicit comments for you as much as
possible so thank you adding questions
or comments no thanks very common um so
what I would suggest because this it's
ok that the Vettes to having users as of
that mechanism as a working group but
this would be an individual submission
document correct it currently is non in
the working group right so so then you
would do an individual submission
documents submitted to I Anna diana is
going to have a question who's going to
be the technical reviewers right so the
question to the working group is we'd be
appropriate technical reviews sorted to
clarify the IP fix registry is expert
review expert review it's expert review
right specification right and and there
is a list of names for expert visual
voice for IP fixes sensors so I think
you just submit and see what they start
to getting the feedback from them
directly alright thanks yeah Julie egli
you're just going to submit it in there
gonna say yay or nay and it'll be super
simple though it should be no big deal
right
well what can we use the mic if we want
to follow up on that Kathleen Moriarty
Adia I'll follow up with Joel I had some
thoughts while you're presenting as well
and thinking you know see if the what
the chairs had suggestin seeing at the
the I can fix doctors they were okay
with it another thing and just looking
at the what you're proposing it looks
like a lot of the types of things we see
that come from the opt area in terms of
the types of measurements and you know
when we look at scree considerations for
them we just couch it and in frame it
down to its minimally necessary and and
try to do the best we can to protect the
data so there's ways to look at it and
there's probably a way to get the Sun
either here or an OP yeah I mean I think
those are Jolie egli again I think those
are surmountable obstacles right I mean
when you're dealing with proprietary
data in a management system obviously
you have to protect it in certain ways
and you know in security sensitive
environments that requires that you put
bumpers around the description in your
document but that is actually the normal
operational paradigm for this kind of
information because you wouldn't
wouldn't want to leak it even if it
didn't have this stuff on there all
right thank you for that perfect thank
you
so yes so on the agenda we actually have
time for open mic so if anyone has any
thoughts comments or concerns to share
with the working group please please in
the queue so with regard to DTLS and the
version whether we're going to be
blocked on 13 if you look at the
individual submission of the dtls 13
draft right now it says that DTLS one
two and three are interoperable and are
operable you can clients as long as
support both it's fine I think we just
proceed with details 12 for now and when
detail s13 is available we can we can
deal with it to be as Cano muah be a non
working group chahat yes big plus one go
for detail s 1 point 2 i'm a i'm robi
hamilton I'm with chemical abstracts
can't see but it actually is remember so
i have no idea for sure what mitigation
means here and if there's of the
implementations that i've seen so far is
there anything specific in those as far
as mitigation goes reason I'm asking is
were a DDoS attack target on a regular
basis now and every IP address that
tries to connect to us is different and
so as far as I can tell there could be
500 billion people trying to connect us
so I don't know necessarily even how to
tell other than the fact that suddenly
we're out of sockets on a server so
anyway that's question angel roll under
you answering this question that
question yeah Andrew Mortensen over
networks so mitigation is we are
attempting to define what mitigation
means in the requirements draft there's
some terminology there so please take a
look at that specific definition and see
if it covers what you're talking about I
don't think the specific form of
mitigation whether using something
in a firewall or a DDoS mitigation
device or just trying to put out flows
back rolls to block is within the scope
of dots itself Roland Evans or networks
so if you look at previous iterations in
the use cases draft there are some
examples that do talk about some
mitigation technologies but the purpose
of one of the purposes of dots is the
big technology independent in terms of
the negation technology so we're not
locked into a given paradigm rate on
some of the you heard earlier in a
meeting we're talking about some the
initial proposed use cases will be
coming coming out and those feature
different technologies and so forth to
provide some I guess color commentary
great the help hey just a or color to
the discussion as far as the way i see
it i think the simplest way it
power-crazed andrew in the pastas mean
the world idea of dots is to basically
say help it hurts here and then as far
as the mitigation goes that could be
anything I mean it could be unplug it
you know it could be anything at the end
could too is in scope as far as well I
could be but that we don't want to
prescribe that because that people's
ideas are different you know as a
people's definitions are different and
it's that's just a whole world of pain
okay so i think we're skirting around
the questions very green outcome I um
because you're talking about you're in
serious pain right now so here's my
suggestion because the work that we're
going on here in ittf as a you decide
this is two years out this is a lot of
we're trying to make ourselves better
but what you can do is I'll point you to
a little guy I get people say here's how
you can bring your vendors in to figure
out what is right for you but you add
one new question all right based off of
this with implementations every vendor
you pull in to say how can you help me
Yusei what's your deployment planning
your roadmap for dots all right these
are asking what's your dutch rome at
then you pull all like the vendors in
here pull annoyances what's your dots
rome at because you're in pain now and
so the offline i'll help you out in that
part but at the
question what do you got is it dots and
they'll look at you go like what's dots
this is don't get a clue get on board
with the future thank you for the
question because this is an excellent
example about how people read things
into our documents or look for things
and we need to ensure that the
architecture doc which is over people go
to first all there's a dots architecture
clearly calls out how know where
mitigation fits into this and that week
I believe we do we're mainly to
strengthen just a little bit more to
clearly point out that this is how we
signal for call for help mitigation is
over there so that that so people coming
to hear saying i'm in pain will know
that they have to go over there for that
pain addressing for right now that
that's all I've been through many of
these before where the documents did not
clearly call out what's in scopus out of
scope and where else to look yeah I
would plus one that not comment that
nabob just made fresh eyes on the
document are wonderful and if you don't
feel like you see yourself reflected in
the use case please let us know because
we want to update the text to do that
okay other topics to bring up to the mic
okay so catching actions from the
discussion so we agree that we're going
to accept the decidua as a working group
document so if the authors can resubmit
that as a working group document will
will will get that approved I would also
remind everyone we're still pulling for
adoption on the data channel documents
since we started that before the working
group so again if you have feelings
either way please do drop that on the
mailing list there's time and then with
the time we have remaining not that I'll
take that long just wanted to review the
proposed milestones and I would
reiterate what you're about to see here
only Tobias and I have seen and we'd
like to discuss these with you so we of
course are behind on everything we have
the use case requirements and
architecture documents as a straw man to
say working group last call after prague
in September what is the reaction of the
working group to that and all the
authors on this draft I enter Mortensen
speaking for myself and not necessarily
for my co-authors I think we this is
even conservative for the requirements
in architecture so you mean you could do
earlier cool what should we write there
sorry for being so specific Saturday ok
ok so meaning to its two weeks or
something sorry anyone saying not to be
clip I think probably buy buy a product
ok ok fleming andreas i think you do
need to stagger the requirements and the
architecture document a little based on
the discussion at use cases while i use
case and requirements yeah hopefully we
can do that a little bit sooner but you
need a little space for the architecture
to reflect whatever changes go in there
and also hopefully reflect that you
working with last call comets that come
in so if I internalize what you just
said use case requirements july ish so
august/september architecture so i'm
only altered on the architecture
document so you know i'm quite happy
with September I'm not as ambitious as
my co-author but that I will let the
authors of the use case and requirements
documents for themselves Daniel yeah i
think the use case should be addressed
by two month ok
so what I'm hearing from the the authors
is July use case use case in
requirements I'm sorry we're not editing
this live and then architecture document
staggered later for September further
from the rest of the working group
because Kathleen's not officially
listening to any of us yet because will
submit this what's the reaction I mean
any comments is everyone comfortable
with that okay and then then it comes to
the actual protocols and so here we got
to do a couple of things so first our
official milestones actually say we're
making a data model document and a
transport document uh my counterproposal
to that is it looks like we're
converging towards a data Channel
document and a single channel document
so first I would argue that we want to
change the nature of the milestone
itself and then tossing out a gauge of
I'm sorry of December on both votes so
does anyone have any feelings on first
rebranding what the milestone itself is
and then the timing of it um hi nicht
ich um no I'm for it I think that um
that's let me mentioned before as far as
data model information little goes they
were probably more necessary when there
was a number of dates I think now
there's a degree of conversions then it
can be just those particular task me
just converged into that that function
so yeah other reactions from from the
working group on those okay well
Kathleen we're gonna submit mr. you
officially for your review so you can
stare at them just as we described okay
so this actually brings us to the end of
the agenda we have time so if anyone
wants to come up to the mic going once
going twice okay well thank you everyone
for participating thank you very much
and we will send out the invite for the
upcoming virtual interim discussion in a
few days and yeah if I close
and if I could have the blue sheets
whoever has them if you could run them
up to the front who has not signed the
blue sheets yet and where are the blue
sheets good Oh meet you