we are here at the ITF 98 in Chicago and
with me is a Lisa Cooper new share of
the ITF taking over after after me how
did the meeting go for your relative I
thought we had a great meeting have
really good energy a lot of work got
done here in Chicago a couple of the
highlights for me you know we've had a
lot of interest in the internet of
things lately and at this meeting we had
a new piece of work around a data
definition language for the Internet of
Things last month implementers in the
room contributing to the discussion
trying to shape the work going forward
initial stages so I thought that was
pretty great also we had a pretty
important milestone in the RTC web
working group which is so good that
standardizing of real-time protocol
stack for doing voice and video
communication over the web ton of
industry interest and input into that
group over the years and working group
is actually concluded its work at this
meeting documents are going to go out
for you can't community to review but
they're very very stable in really great
shape so I was happy to see that that's
great and the web marketing team was
also a packet and we always have before
that I hear click otherwise begins and
100 plus people in the in the room it
was very active one team in particular I
paid attention to it was the TLS 1.3
team we're working on 18 different
implementations of TLS that I think is a
great sign of how much danger she's
paying attention to this particular
piece of technology coming out of the
idea another thing that's kind of
related to TLS and a few other working
groups is that we're using more and more
open source technology and repositories
and github in as part of our work with
the specifications and not just the
software's themselves and so we had a
great discussion of that how how the
different working groups are are doing
that and what
learn from them and hopefully be able to
do that also a mock a bit more working
groups in the future a list of what's
gonna happen next so as usual the IETF
work will march on on the mailing list
and design teams and would improve
internal meetings and also on gets out
now that you have is expanding as a tool
being used across what's my purpose be
ITF sao work will charge on our next
in-person meeting will be in prague in
july so that's one will gather again
this group and looking forward to all
the progress of any time