yesterday a cisco has all these behind
is trying to be some kind of the cargo
like birds much let's get real like big
moments talking everything I submitted
my version to affect Little Snitch
reports will get it violation maybe
something else I'm so super cool I just
come to edit your dr kunitake negative
ever get like that sex think is
incorporate yes yes any poison second
now negative 36 seconds good afternoon
welcome to the RTC web meeting this is
our last meeting in North America for
those of you who were not expecting that
announcement we're hoping to close this
working group in Prague so please get
ready for the ride between now and
Prague to involve you reviewing some
documents you applauding our document
authors and editors and you're generally
speaking being ready to finish this up
so you're in chicago that's Chicago so
are you if you're not meaning to be in
Chicago or in the RTC web meeting now
would be a moment to head to the exits
[Music]
this is the note well if you don't
understand the note well please find
your friendly neighborhood lawyer or
your corporate lawyer your choice and
have them explain it to you basically if
you don't understand it getting up at
the microphone likely not a good idea
you may also find getting up at the
microphone not a good idea in other
circumstances that's not the problem of
the note well the working group status
update look two thumbs up on draft RTC
web overview going to the iesg boo and
we've had two working group last call
versions of RTC web GF which is our
major topic for today
two thumbs up for the two new versions
as well here's our agenda administrivia
you are here before we move on from here
guess what we're going to need no takers
jabber relays possibly someone to meme
the meeting if you'd like to volunteer
for any of these roles please raise your
hand now thank you very much Jonathan
has and I'm carefully repeating his name
into the recording jonathan is doing the
jabber note taker come on who wants to
be the last note taker for RTC web in
North America last one you too can have
a place in history Ted if you can
guarantee that this truly is the last
time I will do it I'm not allowed to
speak for the iesg but i believe i can
say with some certainty that if we're
still going the next time we meet in
north america will be yeah well none of
these chairs will be present and i doubt
any of you will be either all right so
we have a jabber scribe we have a note
taker and we have a plan to close the
working group by prod now review
dependencies Colin you want to get into
the pink box please so the good news of
our dependencies is uh that list is
about half the length that we were lost
the time okay and so most of the
documents so that we actually you know
normatively depend on across several
groups have moved to the state of you
know up requested or are further along
which is really good
let's see most of these are actually
moving along quite well I think the
actual stuff in this working group I
fecund the IP handling stuff will be
discussing later hour but tomorrow
friday i guess and the other stuffs
looking close to done so next slide
that's the status of other things that
we depend on that are not yet rfcs but
you'll notice that a crapload of those
are in the RFC editor queue in the sense
that they are approved and just
basically blocked waiting for references
so once the rest of the stuff approves
you know the the the cluster from area
41 will Buster 238 the I the RFC editor
carefully gives these numbers so if
you're ever asked what's what's are
blocking number its cluster 238
questions it's also worth pointing out
the RSA editor has been warned that this
cluster is coming and they are well
aware they are preparing they've seen my
spelling okay next slide and that's
really that's that's where we are with
dependencies there isn't another slide
there's none others like but there are
thank yous now as you've all known for
this week we've been up you know
collecting various records and stuff for
our exiting area director who we would
like to thank for putting up with us in
this whole working group for so long we
have other things that might arrive
later in the week but in the meantime
but we promise they will come in North
America thought you'd appreciate it's
called the carrots hmm the next one is
the stick that's very true che tu che
yeah I think I really needed actually
the sticks more than I mean big carrots
and the new job thank you i will miss
this working group dearly from the
bottom of my heart and good luck Adam
remember how in this one I turn it into
out of you a slideshow and it's not like
the very bottom alright so this view of
her and tell us will remember how
woefully unprepared I was for that on
imagine home prepared i am for this
given that most of my time doing TLS
slides um one of these slides I fact
only saw about two minutes ago exactly
next slide so we did 19 we're at 19 we
had 18 you see how this works um there
was a bunch of working of us call
comments we made a bunch of changes I'm
here to summarize them um I don't
believe actually any open issues to be
open about so I'm really summarizing on
these things were not some of these
things were numb who could list some
work your job to figure out which ones i
will stop briefly after each thing to
see if anybody is very upset next slide
we will not be discussing appendix B
appendix B has been by consensus of
people who care kicked over to predict
art and music he merges into bundle and
there and wordsmith there uh-huh so if
you're hoping to see me and Magnus argue
about our DP DX muxing you're in the
wrong place that will be somewhat other
time um so next slide ah so there was
some there were some questions about
these only things that said you should
only do x-ray
only do why and whether like that
whether whether it was better to say
them when they were meaningful and then
stop saying them or to say them
constantly for no obvious reason on so
on the on the due to some discuss some
discussion on list in some discussion by
the editors we concluded the right
answer was that for consistency and also
for simplicity that you basically only
said bundle only a MUX only a new em
sections and there's and so however you
do say on weight on in this and the
answer says bundle or box as the case
may be he doesn't say only ever on so on
this was included as best thing to do
and this is what we have done John I
assume that's for the correct definition
of new which is include recycled I yes
okay yes basically if there is a that
the right way to think about this is if
there is actually some question about
whether this thing could be treated
differently we will tell you and if
there's not we will not next slide um
also in the bundle theme I'm not sure if
these are actually sorted by theme or
just happened to be this way but this is
how they are on so there is this
question appeared about whether how I
should handle on our attributes the only
made sense for media sections like RTC
mocks but that appeared in situations
where you're a bundling the thing a
media section onto a data section so one
way that's going to happen is if you
start out by negotiating a data section
as you have the data session could be
negotiating you add say video m line but
you wish to bundle it onto the on you
wish to bundle it onto the datum section
um and I guess by us already box is
irrelevant but others letarte on and so
we say otherwise that these meet
specific these these transferred end of
attributes should only go on the thing
that is being bundled into a nowhere
else but it's just kind of goofy that
there on the data section we concluded
that goofy was better than non goofy and
so we should do that
there's a bit as a discussion on the
music list about this topic we I think
Paul kids of it being the rough but
finally being beaten down and agreeing
that we could do this um uh we will need
to presume text updates in a variety of
documents which will notice the last
call's we go forward noticing that says
things that contradict this arm but that
was the way we did in jsf with the plan
that we do that all right then right so
in this case the editors folded on the
much discussion about how it happened in
cases where on I we're basically say on
the offer had offered ABC and the answer
had picked be on the j suspect
previously said at that point you were
like could only do B and you couldn't
offer see and and and a riad right and
uh this isn't had to be simplicity um
but apparently make people sad day had
situations where they wanted to add them
back it's permitted by 30 days before so
we weren't like you know we weren't
doing anything goofy here by allowing it
on so we changed that back on but the
rule is you have to add them at the end
the reason that i'm at the end is to pro
stability of the negotiated mechanism uh
Jonathan so it says you can who is the
you and is there a if it's the browser
is there a prob for it I there is no
prob for it um I don't believe um huh
are you try Twitter yes so if it um I
believe if you were the person who is
responsible for removing it then set
color preferences might have some effect
on however the other person was that it
will not on so this should have a frog
for it um on you as the person making
the offer at this point no matter who
was the original offer answer okay no
something's not okay so I so I guess
again my question is so what this is
saying is that you can you know even if
the other guy rejected it you can put it
back but I you're saying that since the
since that offer has to come from the
browser I as a JavaScript I've no way of
actually causing that to happen so I'm
not
sure to the other guy rejected but you
might have rejected it right yeah if I
rejected I can put it back the other guy
rejected it then either browser will
will not put it back depending on its
opinions you can control now great if he
put it back you can take it out hahaha
[Music]
and you can stop it what to you so let's
put it this way if the browser does
offer it if the browser the kind of
browser that offers it you can stop that
from happening but you can't do is make
it to it I guess what I would say is if
you wish there were a frog for that you
know where to go and is not here okay I
ain't w3c I didn't mean like like but
down below uh-huh okay this is my last
working for the day and let's just say
this ad thing is tiring um okay right I
think this is the one that actually like
Colin just added exciting to do it um
right on so right we're now allowing you
to on to do credit references and have
them to have them apply in the middle of
a thing as previous my colloquy Bernard
previously indicated um we didn't just
allow that we thought about it for a
while glue to probably work now we allow
it um that's what I like to say about
that right um camera raise this may be
his whore old mate was / nard one of
those junior pickers um that uh that
basically what happens when an API call
fails um and you know what what
guarantees do deliver and let me tell
you as someone who actually wrote these
things the guarantees we really wanted
to liver were none um boys the CC an
undefined behavior but we eventually
after some drinking and coffee included
that really that wasn't very cool and so
it now says something the implementers
are going to hate I'm sure the people
who do hurry this code it was a lot will
come come we later which is that if
these calls fail you have to go back to
the previous tape so it has to be basing
is if the thing never happened um yes
same nose is like a casinos coming
attack me uh yes uh nevertheless we
concluded that you knows what his things
is good for the good for good for the
JavaScript programmers and bad for the
browsers and that's the way should be
right priority of constituencies
Mountain Thompson yes I'm pretty sure
the nails will kill you but this is just
adding to the pile right that may be the
case I I he does know where I sit
unfortunately ok next slide is that
really it well I was like pretty good
huh we're like 16 minutes in so um I
guess the question becomes now are there
any other issues anybody like to worry
about jcf because if not we will have
held that you forfeited the right to
raise those no no wait wait first we're
gonna ask anybody who wants to hold a
hum hum now anybody who does not want to
hold a hum um now we're just now we're
just trying to make sure you're paying
attention here right because in those 16
minutes some of you drifted off i could
see yogurt being consumed we're really
in a serious moment in those people
despite the attitude of all four of us
in front um this was after a working
group last call after the second working
group last call this is the set of
issues that was raised in the second
working group last call the authors and
the chairs believe them to be all
resolved if you do not believe them to
be all resolved get me to a microphone
now or we will be putting this thing in
pub rec very very soon clear I'm not
gonna have to cut my hand off and give
it to Martin thank you so much so Ted I
suggest you make the publication request
now before anyone raises another issue
hahaha
I think in the interest I will make it
during the plenary tomorrow night right
ah nevermind nevermind stop that man
christer you rise in support of your
colleagues from hahaha did we can submit
a new version before wednesday night
without annex without a panic speak
without Appendix B alright so the DQ is
still empty we will get a new version
that does not have appendix B so that it
does not confuse our our colleagues on
the iesg when it appears and other than
that few people in the room realize this
is going to go to pub wreck right I
[Music]
doubt I'll be sober enough to do that
but I'll see what I can do on hand ok ok
let us return to our agenda which sue us
you're gonna have to stall a good bit
I've seen your draft um is this example
yeah yes hey man sure you can we can
read all the examples like huh all right
I don't well that was interesting
discovered but preview closes the wrong
window if you press the button that says
closed window I'll see if we can do open
recent ok this is Easter Mike ok shortly
ok this is for the stp example staffed
and I have this next slide show yeah we
know like this is about trying to come
up with some examples that uses Jessup
and try to be as close to Jessup as
possible in terms of stp construction
and it provides someone who is trying to
read how the stp is used some references
to artificer that they can figure out
how a particular part in sdp is used
next slide ok what happened between 0 to
10 for ocean so 03 was just an update to
the ocean because it was expiring so 04
is the thing where a lot of things went
in so we like Cullen had presented an
idea of 96 cup of open issues on how
some of the identical on category and
transport category attribute should
appear in stp and a gist of 19 and of
clarifies every of those things so
that's good so we closed all those open
issues and then we Jessup 19 also
explains about how we interrupt with
legacy offers like which has RTP AVP but
with a fingerprint how to kind of take
that as a DT less srtp so that's clear
as well and a new edition that had that
was added was to have DTLS ID for the
offers and ancestors added and then one
example has been added to also show how
you use identity attribute in stp apart
from that new edition that happened was
we created in as sdp attributes
checklist appendix that way what it
basically does is it go it went through
J sub section J sub section 5 and
compiled list of requirements that we
feel the stp attributes in the example
should match so this was basically done
so that we can align to Jessup 19 so so
right now the summaries that we are very
close to watches of 19 says
that's it so the question for GF is that
are we ready for working a plastic all
so we got a very extensive review from
Hulk is about a the previous version
sorry did you have a comment yeah just
nine times in question for clarification
you said very close does that mean you
need to do some more work because kind
of very close doesn't help much let me
put it this way for disappointing it's
exactly what just 19 says excellent the
shipper yeah i'm sure i read it some
eight to ten times no it's a convertible
for which week we're very sorry but ok
so before we take this to working group
last call i would like to reviewers to
go through it this is actually pretty
dense stuff and i would like to have
that level of assurance that somebody
outside the author team has actually
gone through these examples and read
them so no two more reviewers paul can
review again if he wants but i want to
reviewers of the current version so we
have like 20 minutes of silence to fill
your chairs will sit here and stare at
each one of you until two hands go up
either electronically or in the room
could could you bring up the jeopardy
theme for us please no i mean if
somebody puts their little hand up we're
willing to press the red button if what
they're gonna say as we volunteer to
review Oh Nils who's already gonna be
choking people to death has volunteer
thank you okay so we need one more you
playing the home game just enter the
queue and we'll press the red button
Justin Justin did review it once before
Paul so probably is a good point % okay
bread around Justin Mozilla I can be
roped into reviewing it I've looked at
it enough or stp enough but let the
note-taker show that two volunteers from
Mozilla have agreed to review this
document and have the thanks of the
working group for same thank you very
much that doesn't mean the rest of you
are going to get off of it because as
soon as they put their review in it's
going to come to working group last call
which means you all get your wack but
this isn't gonna wait till Prague this
one's going to go out for working group
last call as soon as those two reviews
are in and any issues which are raised
by them are resolved so expect this to
be done on the mailing list between now
and then everybody clear Barnard says
yes anyone else hold up your hands to do
this yeah okay okay so we can close now
and return on friday or we can try and
do friday depending on whether or not
our speaker for friday is available the
22 documents we have for friday are
related to feck and IP handling Justin
are you on the call Justin's calling an
old school okay given that we will see
you friday and you have the rest of your
afternoon I couldn't hear you I have at
least three reasons to beat you I will
have my twelve-year-old read it aloud to
you if you're willing to fund one year
of his college education
we'll just read it back into licensing
back you know reader Jonathan didn't
listen to it yeah it will be
automatically captioned from somebody
standing and read aloud and see whether
the resulting captions are it also will
read it also read the ice the ice
packets did initiate the connection in
Haxorus area but you all seem in stunned
anticipation of your email or something
but I'm
[Music]
you