in the plenary we were thinking of
something useful a topic that would be
of the interest of the IPF crowd and I
mean regarding 5g that we are basically
you know as I mentioned getting a lot of
requirements there's going to be a lot
of work actually in the IPF going on in
the next 12 months and we thought that
you know I'm cellular security would be
good but not only basically talking
about what we're doing regarding 5g but
also a bit of historical background you
note of you know how security was in
previous cellular systems so as usual we
try to organize these things with idea
first and and Joan is actually involved
in the security groups here so we
thought it was a basically no good
arrangement so John please yeah thank
you so low that nice introduction so
this will be about sellers security it
will be about network security only not
about the application layer if you think
your Wi-Fi network then you know what
this is about and it will be about 3gpp
cellular systems only used to be a lot
of competing standards but now with LTE
and 5g its GDP only so this presentation
will be in basically into pouch one
historical patch going through how the
security 20 PP seller systems have
evolved from the analog bagni systems to
gsm 2 3g and 4g and the second part will
be quite focused on young quick story of
some of the things that the industry is
driving in 5g so starting from the
beginning and there's basically been one
generation cellular system each ten
years so first one key systems they were
launched in around nineteen eighty will
complete analog and the
basically new security conservation when
they weren't made the analog she could
very easily it's dropped on them just
using a ordinary radio that could turn
in the right frequency and basically the
cha-ching was that patron sent its ID in
clear text in an effort short out to the
right field so anybody picking
eavesdropping on the ID and being able
to reprogram the phone could call for
free on someone else bill and
development of the next to G system
started quite soon after in 82 and as a
comparison I have some Mountain EPP
things here for example here you have
deaths was publicity 77 so 2g completely
digital but still circuit-switched not
packet switched patootie there was a
large security focus but still the main
goals was to fix the problems with
bungee and make it as secure as a fixed
home it was not intended as a
military-grade secure communication and
it was probably the first mass-market
communication system with cryptography
in the word very widely deployed and
this was not appreciated by Intelligence
Agency another thing fun thing jeezum is
still after running and will be for many
years but it was deployed expecting a
tongue 10 years life span and gsm boss
Sanderson 87 deployed in 1990 and you
can see that was way way before SSL or
example Wi-Fi with web which was ten
years later and extremely lesyk
less secure than gsm this is how
authentication in GG gsm looks like the
phone has the phone on a network has a
shared secret they're called k a
symmetric key the phone sense its
identity called MC to network and this
is something clear this is a problem you
can track this identity dsm used on
temporary identity but you can force the
phone to reveal its long-term identity
the whole networks on some random number
and the authentication check any key to
run the numbers down to the phone the
phone calculate this authentication
string and his MSC new compares the
values caught from the film and valued
code from the home network see if the
film is authenticated then the phone
derives this key casey and you have
encryption between the film and the base
station i will point out this was a very
long time ago nobody really knew how to
make secure authentication and
negotiation protocols so one thing is
that the MC something clear text another
is that the negotiation is not
integrated protected they are with
negotiation a third thing is that the
basically the key derivation does not
include the cycler albert and and maybe
the largest weakness is that it's only
the client phone that is authenticated
the network is not authenticated and we
will talk about how what was most of
these things have been fixed to the gsm
was designed in a completely different
hi photography was seeing us for a long
time seeing us classified as wet
tons for export control now they're just
bite us do you use it was also no clear
definitions of what consisted strong
cryptography yes that strong cryptic
cryptography was not allowed to export
there's very different rules for example
in the US and the European Union this
became much clearly in 97 96 with the
decimal agreement but even here around
this time it was basically 56 Orion
proved to be teeth within orb and this
applies for two for example deaths and
also for gsm he some uses late dyeables
are designed for 64 bits but they are
short-term 256 this was in the Western
world for exporting to third countries
development concrete industry was forced
to introduce a weak version of the cyber
called a pipe tube with limited security
and these are words were not publicly
reviewed this was not possible to use
way too slow mobile phones of this time
needed something much much faster and to
my knowledge the reason to have been
secret was that basically they were
deployed so anybody founding weaknesses
on them do not have them positive next
me I'm 10 years into and 3d and base
here a lot of the weaknesses in GSM was
known to the main goal in Trinity
security was to fix weaknesses in GSM
one thing is mutual authentication with
some replay protection the signaling is
integrated protected so that you you
cannot do a bidding download hack on the
ciphers the algorithm's public and what
we give a s is used for Federation
authentication kasumi em snow was used
for encryption in integrity this was
previously published Cyprus yes security
level is 108 hit everywhere and the
wager encryption was extended further
into the network and given guess loans
in 2001 and on the same time as TLS 10
and the same here as AAS and sharp she
was then five years later would we got
hsdpa which was really the sort of
mobile broadband racing the speeds
enormously and 3d is actually two law
checks them still very secure there's no
no serious attacks on PG done 4G he also
called LTE and the goal here was to make
it at least as the u.s. jeje improving
the security here and there for non
security reasons the encryption was
moved about in the access network again
to the base station but that was but
also ipsec was added from the base
station deep into the core network and
yes hepes now is used to large degree on
the
then I / sect is now really getting
deployed into the pp networks and I've
seen figures expecting eighty percent
used in a couple of years thirty use a s
for encryption integrity asn shuffling
5640 derivation and it's come prepared
for 256-bit keys even if that is not
used and this launched 2009 wrong same
time as keyless 131 row 22 and the
Cyprus years are perfectly fine then we
had let's see lte-advanced was a most
higher speed version launched in 2013
and 2014 both dev aslam's want a is
voice services over LTE and LTE is
packet-switched only the circuit
switched options from earlier seller
releases were removed and see our third
of each other and 4G one of the main
additions in 4G was the key hierarchy
and if you won't be we do have time for
short questions during the presentation
also but otherwise we take me questions
after yeah basically one of the main
design goals for LT was to never reuse
the same key twice basically you drive a
new key depending on which I'll go to
use you drive a new key depending on
which node it is and when you do
handshake in the hand Uber's between
inside LT or between MDM and other
systems you also do new key derivation
so basically the way key that lower down
any key is does not allow an attacker to
the rawhide Reiki and also keys at the
same level does not allow you to drive
some other key and in the handovers LTE
provides both forward and backward
secrecy so that then you knew you cannot
derive the keys from the previous
session and the previous new node cannot
derive a kiss for the new session and 4G
and LTE was really the first global
standard 2g GSM was deployed in porch
mainly in Europe and part of asia africa
south america 3d the trinity p 3d system
UMTS was mainly deployed in europe some
of the programs in the US but it had
competition 4G had initially had
competition from wimax but while max did
not fly and for the ended up as the
first really global celery standard
here's an overview of all the different
cyprus and integrity and key derivation
out which in the gpp system I think this
might be their only overview I have ever
seen and I made it myself the Pacific
where the hair means that they are not
secure basically because of key length
earlier al with this appeal or key
derivation Alex these are deployed on
the sim card and his m was really ahead
of its time with hardware based client
authentication in 1990 so these are good
stir in implemented on the sim card in
the phone and also in the home network
in the HSS earlier version Darwin
restrict export control used 56 or
64-bit keys that is of course not
secured by today's standard and the
first version also had a weakness so
that seemed coach could actually be
killed if you did query them if you got
on your hands on them and you could
query them quite many times but
practically in the lab at least Twiggy
introduced the mini nosh key duration
that builds on a s and here we have
128-bit keys and built as both input and
output this is still considered very
well well deployed and still considered
secure to have backup out wit 3gp p.m.
es mi standardized it jack generational
with this pants on Tkachuk which was
also the basis for short tree but it's
irreducible slightly different
parameters than chaudhary that comes
with a minimum length of 128 but also an
option for 256 bit keys them was quite a
lot of average for integrity and
encryption the August once let's see if
I won a fight too they are built on a
lettuce or to be able to run them on
phones in the 1990s and they use 64-bit
keys which make them insecure by today's
standard a 51 is actually there is some
theoretical attacks on a 5-1 but in
practice the best practical attack on a
5 on a steel brute force either by
testing lowly piece or lately by
generating a rainbow table basically if
I one is actually giving you almost as
good security as this as the key length
a PI 2 is the export version it uses a
64 bit keys but it's just not offered
64-bit security and it was never
intended to do rider a 53 is a built on
sex Kasumi this is secure but it uses a
short keys it's you can brute force it
and basically all these called Albert's
and the a5 now a five and I'll with they
were initially secret they have later
been reverse-engineered and leaked
Kasumi is a block cipher that was the
basis for the first cycling in the tree
new system it feels it's an evolution of
this block cipher misty is you for both
encryption and integrated protection
later snow twiggy was added this is a
basically 3 PP and yes ma took snoop 2g
a very well-known stream cipher and then
you've added some extra additions
because there was some theoretical
theoretical speculation that snow could
be suspicious about two algebraic
attacks later versions is a es have
would think that's neutral enas is
probably the most used today five year
will likely reduce the ciphers from
foggy as a stock might add more
specialized faster or 256 bit versions
later so why do people still consider
cellular networks to be insecure I think
if you really media others quite a lot
of negative attention and I think if I
and also here in IETF fighting cellar
security has a very negative people in
general have a negative feeling I think
that is namely because of 2g GSM that is
a 2d esm is not secure it was designed
30 years ago today and it was it was
definitely best practice security when
it was released and was designed for 10
years use opportunity steam used and it
will I think all the GSM systems in you
USA have been closed down but in Europe
they will use very least 10 more years
for our UT purposes unfortunately your
phones will happily connect to a gsm
network and
as the network is not authenticated it
will happily connect to a full space
station as well and to my knowledge
there's no way to disable gsm in in
today's films either iOS or Android I
would like to see that but right now I
don't think you can do that and another
problem with GSM is MC captures which
can track your identity and and track
where York see that you have been in two
places at the same time this has been it
snow let it has been used in for example
trash cans in cities with MC captures
them selling you personals nice
advertisement and immediate ease are
these terms for Space Station in the
capture or stingrays of them mix
together in stingray is can do both of
these things it's a product from a
company in C captured tracks your
identity and the force base station you
can connect to and make calls post base
stations is only possible in 2g MC
captures is possible in all the
generations so what will happen in 5g
and this is ill heavily debated in and
there's ongoing work quite early work in
TPP I think the high level 20 PP work
happens in three stages first as a one
is doing requirements that nuclear
operators then Sh even
satori esta tu is doing the architecture
very high level Vanessa tree is doing
high level security and I'm cg1 the city
groups takes over and make stage three
low level detailed specifications of
everything yeah so one thing that party
definitely needs to take care of is the
enormous growth in mobile traffic and so
LTE was launched I don't know but around
2010 then the data traffic in the
movement networks was quite small and it
was voice was still a large part of the
traffic back then theta from mobiles was
growing and data from smartphones also
but all quite small after that voice is
basically flat data from tablets and PCs
has been increasing steadily but data
from smartphone has formally exploded
and I respect to just keep growing we
are here right now and from here to 2022
the amount of data is expected to
increase 10 times and if you're wired
network that would cause problems as
well but you can always have more wires
and wireless the spectrum is limited by
me 5k will take care of this with adding
new frequencies very high high
frequencies that can be used and also
with beamforming where the radio is
basically a very narrow beam that
doesn't collide with any other beams
leading to less noise but equality then
increasing the overall capacity I think
whoever doctor is our main drivers for
party security and that is mainly iut is
a main driver for 5g in general m45 be
security we have Sam source the
automotive industry census basically IT
sensors put requirements on low energy
they may have very small bait amounts
but it should be very energy efficient
hmm and it might sleep a large part of
the day here this is a very strong
contrast to broadband in media we have
very very high bit rates and then you
have the automotive industry where me
maybe latency is the most important
thing you want latency in the very few
millisecond latency from use under
request you get a response and you also
get normally in cellular networks all
the messages are sent from a user
equipment to a base station and to
another user equipment in the automotive
industry you might want to have culture
car communication and then we have
factories we might want to control
robots for example you're in
infrastructure electric grades etc and
so it's quite large amount of different
use cases that the industry seeds for 5g
it is very different with very different
requirements
and one whose case is to use faggy more
in industry for example in for example
in a factory where the factory might
have its own own 5g network but not
really clear how the responsibility
would be between the factory industry
owner and mobile operator and which
frequencies is for deriving another very
strong trend in 5g is that everything
will be virtualized and this is
something already happening for 4G
networks but gep positions has not
initially been designed to be
virtualized maybe if you consider
virtualization from the start you might
end up with slightly different choices
and divisions and also many are you teen
systems require things to be very very
cheap there's no you don't want a dish
too much harbour cost or cost for manual
deployment and configuration this is a
high level picture of a party system I
do not talk much about this but
everything will be virtualized you will
have sem and then also big careful
parties that fergie will have we have
edge computing and be a much more open
system where other parties can deploy
and run applications inside the network
maybe in the base station to get
extremely low latencies exam
for pro factories or automotive or rail
yeah so what are some of the concrete
problems security problems left so one
of these are MC captures this has been
gotten quite a lot of media attention
last year's those examples of someone
putting a lot of in C captures and or
force base stations around places in us
and also the same thing in Norway
[Music]
uncertain who did this yeah and this is
one of the goal that we would like to
solve em party another thing that is on
a consideration and at least the goal of
Erickson is to have more flexible
identity management in 5g the
requirement group in 3gpp as a one has
already decided that 5g shall support
alternative credentials that means
something else than the you seem
application that today are stored in the
UICC which is commonly known as the sim
card yeah but the requirement does not
say really what these alternative
credentials would be but a good guess is
that it will be a symmetric crypto
public keys and certificates Rose want a
lot lower cost complexity for massive
iut and for
factories and industries wanting to use
5g we want a lot more flexibility so
that the Phi Z system can integrate
integrate a lot easier with existing
triple a service in industries and I
trees and the and to mitigate the
problem with MC captures basically the
problem is that a identity is something
clear text and when it's not you can
force the film to reveal its identity
and if I obvious solution to that is to
encrypt the identity with a public key
in the home network and this is possible
today it would definitely not have been
possible when gsm was standardized the
phones back then could not do public key
crypto in with any good latency it would
have taken to way too much time and then
you would have maybe waited ten seconds
to connect your call that would not be
good the solution would likely see look
like something like this probably the
whole network will see that have it you
will run guetta Hellman but probably not
the ethanol ethanol diffie-hellman
probably a static ephemeral deferment to
reduce latency and bandwidth but I'm
probably not a long time term static
some staticky that you can exchange
replace three the home network would
have a private key why the user
equipment would have the public key key
of the home network g to the power of Y
and then we use the phone would generate
X
some ye to the power of X 2 little
network and then encrypt the identity in
see a with a key divided from the if you
have my secret and today the MC contains
the phone the identity of the sim card
but it does also contain the identity of
whom network for routing purposes that
would be needed to still send in clear
but then the only thing in third-party
attack you would see is which home
network this film is connecting to and
not the identity of the film itself and
this will basically mitigate MC captures
in 5g then you would still have problems
if an attack you can force you to go
down to 4G or 3g another thing that is
under consideration and driven for Phi G
is which kind of protocol should be used
for authentication out today when the
phone connects to 20 PP access string
people radio technology then it uses
what is now known as EPS AK is basically
the 3gpp authentication and key
agreement protocol Sam pin roll it roll
form without any packet layer when the
phone connects to an entree DPP access
but uses the same code to authenticate
them eat aks used today and this mantra
EPP access code for example be a Wi-Fi
network owned by the WHO operator so
today
it is only used for non gpp access and
they're only supported eat algorithmic a
and eat a k prime which is slight
modification and the plan for 5g which
every time is driving is to use the IETF
standard e everywhere so basically you
have the same when you connect to it
really PP access or when you connect
your norm three deep at PP access and
your you use eat irrespectively if you
authenticate with a sim card or if you
authenticate with certificates done 20
people would need to support more than
eat a case tannin which is specified for
sinkage only and where alternatives up
for discussion is today is ctls and eat
t jealous or pap ET les is basically use
the TLS handshake and then when you
authenticate you you don't set up a
record layer eat g TLS is that you set
up TLS and then you authenticated
authenticate over the encrypted pls
connection and here is one place where
IDF work is very likely for example ET
les is quite this specification is quite
outdated i think it uses GLS 10 here as
103 is quite different yeah m 20 PP
would definitely would like to use TLS
103 only i will personally make sure
that 3d PP mandates TLS 103 as soon as
it's published everywhere where TLS is
used in Trinity a third thing that is
under consideration
is its perfect forward secrecy today the
keys for traffic protection for
encryption integrity protection of
traffic the application data entry DPP
networks are derived from the long term
keys symmetric keys stored on the using
and in the HSS and of course they also
generate a random number and then you
derive keys from that and this is secure
as long as the symmetric keys the secret
keys are secret and if the leak of
course you get problems and according to
rumors that is exactly what happened
couple years ago rumors all that several
different intelligence agency hacked sim
card manufacturers and got access to a
large number of secret peace is what
allowed one to passively East drop on
seller radio this is of course only
rumors but at least one sim card
manufacturer have acknowledged that they
had a massive breach even if they did
not acknowledge that any keys were the
attackers got access secret keys and how
do we mitigate this from happening again
an answer is similar to the encrypted MC
we do key exchange with DJ Hellman
basically you do if you have the
ordinary determine some g2x etude y and
then you do DC combination with a
current 3gp PA AKA and of course this
would this will probably be mixed
together to save the number of round
trips it might even be that you have a
static kee on the server side
none both parties derive the keys using
the long term secret and the
diffie-hellman secret and currently trip
is looking at using elliptic curve if
you help me that's a current best
practice but this would need to be
replaced in maybe five ten years from
now when quantum computer starts to be
at rest and the best there's basically
except there's several good candidates
for post quantum security Hellman on
this lattice based which might be the
first alternative for example GLS dtls
but they're the keys are quite large in
wireless network you really want to have
small keys to save bits and here super
single electrical I solidify her month
is a likely a better choice here the
keys are much smaller but on the other
hand the computational cost is much
higher it it will see and basically if
you want more high-level information on
this Ericsson has published three quite
recent whitepapers one on five-year
security giving a high level quite one
technical description on what the
scenarios what the problems and the
solutions are podgy security ericsson
also has a like written by paper on a UT
security illustrating summarizing a lot
of the problems facing our UT security
and privacy and how they can be handled
Todd Erikson white paper is the seller
networks for Mike massive
UT describing the new improvements that
have been made to to LTE to handle IOT
basically three peoples done three
different work items during last year
two different enhancements to LT
specifically targeting IOT and one work
item Tori targeting gsm where gsm has
been or GPRS has been updated with new
algorithm secure long-term at least 10
15 years for iu g yeah and that's it any
questions I you had a article on a
pull-up that DC was littered with empty
catchers in that article it says that MC
catchers can do can can can catch text
sell and install spyware is that just
creative journalism or is that humans to
capture could only see your identity on
track and see that you are it's the same
term you sim sim card that was at this
place at this vacation this place at
this location but the term MC catcher is
open mixed up with false base station a
force base station would 4pm would
believe it's valid to the base station
connect and you would make you call this
force base station and the base station
would be able to eavesdrop on you if of
course if you're using data traffic and
your phone has some vulnerabilities then
the base station might hack you as well
but that might happen if you go to some
web page and your phone has a problem as
well
yeah hi you didn't talk about the
differences in from 40 to 50 spective
from base station to the escape epic a
twat bigotry is there any changes there
like earlier and 4G we have a seagate
when all that stuff right so is there
any you didn't talk about that part
actually you're talking about all this
from you too you know yeah there are
some changes but I don't know what the
latest status on a tee is on a high
level laughing the security is more or
less the security solutions or more or
less the same with some minor additions
but part of the architecture changes
that hi so you talked about the security
improvements of the mobile handset to
the base station covered in a 5g but I
understand it the next generation of
attacks are already happening on the ss7
and interface station communication and
you have anything to say about what's in
the store for projecting base station to
base station or base station to network
yeah ss7 is i am not talked about
application they are not about the
carrier net connecting different porch I
think ss7 is even older protocol than
these there's a large number of
vulnerabilities there's been a lot
several studies looking how you can fix
these perfect the answer is that you
probably count with backward comp
abilities I think you need to replace
them or yeah and that takes time I think
one of the main problem was that you
could access there's a certain network
online on the internet from so yeah it's
on places and that of course made it
very insecure I think these problems are
now mainly them fixed making ss7 it
still has insecurities but at least it's
much harder to access them further body
endings for joining me one question in
terms of kind of a fake base station
problem that as you have roaming on
international roaming in particular how
would a handset know which are good
networks in which a bad networks so I
Roman to country a visit I have no idea
what my mind's not none of my home
network and a rogue Network happily will
offer to serve me and how would I know
that that is how would the device
reasonably know which networks just pour
it come on is there a mechanism intended
that I can discover that right now it
doesn't seem to be the case yeah in a
sense is what if I know Roman 4G if a
network will let me on my device will
happily join it yeah but in port if you
use 4G or 3d then the network is
actually authenticated so well you know
what it is but I mean when I warm to
some country that I don't know yeah mine
I have no idea if he's network names are
meaningless to me know yeah I know
second literally yesterday somebody who
has not my best interest ecology yeah
but if you do that in 30 or 40 then you
can trust that at least your home
operator which you hopefully trust has
trust this operator and allow your phone
to connect to it so Israel currently a
mechanism addressed don't know is there
currently a mechanism in place that the
Houma operate a whitelist sleaze network
stuff on me now because I don't know
what if I my sim college doesn't go I
don't have a channel to ask my home
operator at that moment when I'm
connecting I yeah it's basically when
you are connecting to this network that
you don't know then that network too
babe you're prone to be able to connect
with the roaming network has to talk to
you whom operator and you whom operated
needs to allow your poem to connect to
this
George it is it has to talk to your home
network because otherwise it won't get
your king material otherwise it cannot
authenticate itself to your phone and
your poem would react it so that you
could film connects to trade your gmat
network that means that this network has
been authorized by your home operator 2g
there is no operator so then you don't
know anything you name the young can you
screw up to the place use cases which
was that this ok or yeah yeah yeah so I
see a in 5g the verticals probably a
very important the use cases so is there
any special requirements in the security
for this year's case week you jest a for
example in the tripod transport it yeah
I think one of the the main thing here
is one main requirement is latency but
that's not security-related what the
security related come from that they be
the bus needs the course needs to talk
to other cars directly so then you need
to have a key change your kid duration
in neck in place so that the course can
authenticate themselves to other cars
and be sure that they are talking to who
they are talking to yeah and that they
get command from the right but today all
communication is user click temp base
station yeah and you want to implicate
that so the main security thing here is
that course should be able to
authenticate to each other when they are
using 5g to communicate
in this case easy and you knew mechanism
when you to intrude introduced to to
catch this kind of us at authentication
yeah yeah there's definitely new
protocols and new key derivation but
hopefully they should work with
irrespectively on what kind of
credentials you used to authenticate to
the network so you authenticate and then
you would get keying material to
authenticate to other course yeah but
new protocols definitely needed yeah
Huijin from your presentation you
introduce there'll be some changes
between security design between the ue
and the core network so I wondering is
also is going to be some changes between
in the backhaul network to indo p in the
core network so right now my something
that's for geog using IPSec to increase
traffic is having change to that or I
think one of the Lord changes is that
which is already happening is that
everything is getting virtualized so
actually you before you had you had a
radio encryption and then you have
optionally IPSec when everything stopped
getting virtualized you have you have
the nose divided from hardware even the
base station will be wrong hotly in
Hardware often the access network
importantly in the cloud and then you
would have maybe a GLS Conlogue between
these so you will probably have several
layers of security will probably have
maxik security ipsec NT lesson maybe
application layer security also ok thank
you John um just like three minutes to
the next session so we have to wrap up
thank you very much i hope you guys
found this interesting if you have
follow-up questions please touch base
directly with with john thank you
[Applause]
yeah sure and the next session is ops
AWG circular interested in that just
stay here are the things that verily it
is then large number of messages that
are actually received by the forum free
you