[Music]
again okay well I should probably get
them online but I'm not quite as well
prepared usual I don't have a good money
no mistaking that Island yes either how
much time do you have to go to start we
of hope we have redundant silver
cylinder I think no no something that we
have a lot of line wrapping little
justice kept it cool most of you know
where I'm attitude we already
I guess I should start cuter pregnant I
guess I could suppose it including
visits dishes
[Music]
Oh
some
10 for me features skip this you lifted
online from rolette ND sir it's better
to download ok so it's anything like
women you have needs ethics large one ok
what's the answer sometimes you reward
are you starving down if we need to find
sore at the huge ball japan i think you
should work how does it look good yep
alrighty wider yeah you have to speak
pregnant you're not full screen
give me a lottery photography get you
junkie scream to get oh that's three fun
page next page that's my excuse for the
hero's right here hello there's any
effect we go so Joe I start down at the
one that touching something
yeah yes greetings everyone this is the
beginning of the troll working group
meeting we thank you very much for
coming please note the note well and
after clue she going around please make
sure you sign it my illustrator coach r
su has a pea sized glasses so um one
other thing this is going to be more of
a discussion and friendly talk so it's
always more interesting if you're up
toward the front and we all can talk I
realize you might feel comfortable in
the back but we always like it if you
come to the front if you don't there's
no forcing you but I certainly would
love to have many of you closer her okay
with that will start we and besides if
you if you're using later laptop the
tables are much more effective okay this
is our note well how many people have
never seen a note well good this note
well looks like all the rest of them
please read it it talks about
submissions and I pr's and what your
contribution is you should read and
understand your friendly note well
because it's part of ITF and if you're
working for a company it's part of your
company to have IPR ok so we are
fortunate in that we're getting a lot of
documents toward the end of cycle I've
sent working group last calls for
several we've had some good comments on
them we've refined it but it's always
tough to look at the document one more
time but i'm going to ask several people
to just please read these documents were
we're making the end of the active
activist passed through we're making the
end of some of the directory assistance
pipe drafts and we're going on to the
multi-level and low pay apology please i
think we've got it as I said by George I
think we've got it but
please read okay this is our agenda for
today the agenda is this administrivia
time bashing we sort of started late
it's really hard to get past the the
drinks and the cookies but i'm going to
give you status i'm going to then go
through the yang model mohammad mohammad
fear and purpose and or is that the
remote he's remote somewhere Muhammad's
remote and Donald's here rom kumar and
if I've mispronounced that wrong from
whom are please let me know I think
that's the way if you go by our that
just tell me that Fang Wei would love to
join us but it's in the middle of the
night in china and it's tough so that's
our topics today we'll have five minute
wrap up okay so we've gotten Sutton two
drafts in the RC Ataturk you we've got
two in the publication request and we've
got two graphs that got returned at this
point the ARB optimization is gone
through one revision thank you very much
use out and we are back to just one more
check on it and then it will go back to
Elias kind it'll go through working
group last fire at call and then
aleeah's review again please when we
start these review processes I
appreciate your active looking there are
two past working group last call with
drill over IP and trill resilient trees
I've sent in some comments to the
author's we need to quickly revise these
after ITF so I will actually hang on
several of the authors like Margaret
over here in and try to get some of
these things and I just really
appreciate your help because getting
these through as you will know Margaret
from being chair and other things
getting it through the last toughest fun
is getting it through the last process
is difficult we
have a draft and working group last call
and I've let it sit through this time
period we haven't had many comments on
it but I i think it's there's been some
interest so please comment we have
graphs that have revision and I think
the smart end nodes in a dress flush the
address flush will go back through
working group last call because it
didn't finish the smart end nodes I
think you know what needs to happen
there and we will again go through
working through class call now what does
all this mean what we're doing is we've
done tremendous good work and we're
pressing it all toward RC so help your
fellow authors by pressing it toward RFC
now there are whole bunch of drafts that
we've sort of adopted and I'm going to
go through them and sort of classify
them why am I doing this I see that
we've sort of come to the end of what I
think our operational issues we've gone
through the active active we've gone
through the directory assistance
multi-level multi Nick thing ah thank
you is there is it here oh there it is I
got it nope that didn't work well let me
go back okay one more so for example we
have the trill data center interface and
we have the trill we have some true
trill transport over mpls I will try I
think most of those graphs are fairly
well cooked I will ask you to please
review the yang documents will cover
next what you're hearing me say is I
think we're sort of to the end of
several large pieces of work but the
only thing hanging out is is security
that we've got some individual drafts
and the any urgent thing we hear from
you we're at a place where most working
groups go into a hiatus or
sort of go into a death rebirth thing
this isn't because technology isn't
working it's because in reality you've
done a really really good job with we've
gotten through a whole bunch of stuff I
think we've gotten to all the product
lines what they need for those who are
shipping trill product it would be or
trill sort of product tell us if we've
gotten everything but we've tried to
focus on what we've got if there's
something we needed we're heading toward
that G we've gotten through the first
piece we've defined everything will let
it set if there's some urgent problem
i'm sure the 80s will pick up and move
it out but we're at that you know coming
to one end why is that important i
really want to get all the rfcs through
the process can I probably send it ten
times now hope read the dress okay and
these are the documents we have done you
see this status and these are milestones
and looking with these milestones we're
going to readapt the milestones or out
of faith but we will we've completed a
whole bunch this is a tremendous working
group its technical capabilities have
been a joy to work with but we have a
few overdue mostly because we've
recycled a couple of these in review I'd
like to catch up our interviews and we
were going to recharter or shut down the
working group I'm not sure we're going
to make July we may be november but i
think we're heading toward that hiatus
that's your chair trying to so if you
got some challenge on that that's where
i think we're heading again because i
think we finished let me give you an
example of another working group that
went through this bgp went through a
whole long cycle where we had a whole
lot of work and then we went into hiatus
for a while we sort of say that because
we really didn't have in something
interesting to say but then when we came
back we had a lot of interesting things
to say and we're still finding things
that are changing in the BGP environment
is just for a while
we weren't changing so take this to be
like trill like bgp okay John I think I
need to pick up the next one
okay how many people here have worked
with yang I think he's out okay good now
this is a little bit of talk about a
challenge when we had our yang models
are trilling which is the basic
configuration the p.m. and the OEM the
PM which actually works out the ohm we
did a lot of work ahead of everyone else
and then tisa thought it would be a
really good idea to have lime and to
make the true model go under lime lime
is finishing its work and I don't know
that it got to everything we thought it
would so I'm faced with three options
and I just for those who are working
with gang and drill option one is the
working group last call and send through
the process the modules because it's my
understanding from deepak and maybe
other people who have implementations
that you have implementations of the
existing drill gang models they will not
be exactly up to latest snuff off for
some of the requirements and format so
some stuff is easy for format to change
and some stuff is fairly hard my first
option is we're not going to really
address the hard changes we're going to
say these are adopted and used in that
case I will collect from deepak and any
work view that have drill and figuration
yang models the information and send it
to the isg the second option is to
change the trill p.m. and OEM to be
dependent on line that means you have
the line base and then we have to do new
models for that d fox original comment
to me an email was no I'd rather stay
with the original gang model okay we can
do both but that takes a bit more energy
I'm well
to do that but I'd like to start now
because yang models have taken us a
while any feedback you sound ok I would
like to see we take option one first you
want option one ok that would be and
your implementation wants option one
yeah without ID imitations oh yes I'm
sorry kak task that is chairing know and
know the answer yes ok so i have cisco
and while we wanting that and i will
probably go with option one that was
your answers two implementations we're
going forward ah by the way my
definition of interoperability is two
implementations in the field that is
prejudiced by my work in BGP if anyone
wants both you must tell me within this
week because we'll go on and I will tell
the lime chair that's nice if you get
someone to volunteer go forth but we're
going to stay focused on the first
option ok and if you feel shy about the
mic come and talk to me afterwards but i
will make a fairly call um let me just
give you a little information about some
of the challenges now that I've gone
through the major question which is one
of the challenges that is that in the
future in the sort of lime time frame we
would have to work with the revised
datastore and revised data stores
changed the OP state to be separate than
the rest it also has taken dynamic data
stores such as trill r2s might be into
that ok and I've gone through some of
that already with one I think I've gone
through that let me see if I can get to
the next slide set
it's mohammad so he's remote and I've
never done them on my old wise okay so
i'll just bring up the slides for us so
how do we pumped his voice speaks like
big me Lord Hey look at
we have to write one up in it
thank you go ahead hello everyone hello
we're joining it Hey yes okay click
enjoy okay thank you so in this document
what we are going to discuss hear it I'm
thinking of FGL into the trail headed so
how we are going to do is we're going to
subsequent slice so this presentation
flowers at the orem making FGL Tantalus
against is contagious as in the present
is eliminating 32 digital space
invention for forums for bringing FJ
equal to negative evidence emerging ever
so what exactly all and again inhale was
in the inner head under the original
date our Garrett is so what we have
thought out LG refrigerator and this
document proposes changes in the actual
package structure that is describing the
subsequent section of this document in
the good next leg
okay this is how the present svenska
train so we can see and after in the mac
source address we have ethertype that is
893 be and we have two parts that is in
the label and high pot and in the label
low part and sometimes it is little bit
confusing that why it has been
discontinued so this way we're thinking
of bringing that FGL into trill header
so can we and again another problem here
is the ethertype we have again in four
bytes of ethertype so that is again the
waste of means four bytes can go for
next life
yeah that is what I discussed in the
previous slide that FGL is given to two
pots and 12 bit higher order and to alva
to order part which sometimes is
confusing and it is also if Jill added
or removed in the original frame space
which causes forehead in the processing
on the edge are bitches so what we are
doing now here is that we are adding FGL
and removing edge here in the original
french space that is Wikipedia overhead
on the edge or bridges next slide okay
so what we are doing here is we are
proposing a new frame structure where
FGL header will come maybe side the
trail header so you can see the original
header will be reminding that if someone
wants to be don't want to change
anything this original packet will
impact will remain intact whereas FGL
header will take off take care of the
late FG 11 yeah can you go next slide
this is how it looks like so trill
header is whatever we are using as of
now so FGL header it is having that is
in the town so you can see here we have
some information regarding a chill
headed I beat our with key priority
field and we are bringing entropy labor
also and the entropy label is because
what we now have is that we have to go
all to the deep packet inspection to
find out for doing a load balancing on
course I'd means if in for our bridges
if we have easy empty pots
we have to do a deep packet inspection
for load balancing so I that what we are
thinking is to bring entropy a new
entity called entropy level the HCL
header skin next slide so this this is
how it looks like when we come back add
a strill hider and HCL header you can
see here that FGM rider will come after
English nickname so we will we can go to
next slide where I will discuss each and
every in speed next slide please this is
the trill Heather party same as
described in RFC wh 0 with few changes
in its version field we are going to
change it with a new version means
bringing it when your value right now it
is 0 so it might be one so that
indicates that the trill header has an
axial header so if Jill header is
described as below so I beat is one bit
field when set indicates valid HDL is
presented so Arvid is one bit field
which is a result in next life ok he
field is a two-bit field whose value
provides information on the National
that is priority field so the priority
field incredible value 0 of people
indicates that reality field is offered
from the inner wheel and header which is
a forwarding including DC I means DC the
eligibility drop eligibility indicator
and so for most significant bit will be
in use or priority for least significant
bits should be set to 0 and ignored by
doing packet forwarding position
and so can they go for next level okay
value1 non-people indicates that clarity
Figgis clarity field is offered from
inner mpls headers exp bits which is a
3-bit field and three most significant
bit will be used for priority highly
significant bit should be set to zero
and ignored while doing pack according
decision valued 20 people indicates
reality field is copied from inner IP
for headers tosser dhcp killed and hence
all eight which will be used for taking
forwarding decision and the value three
of a bit field indicates that purity
field is copied from inner eye be a
success traffic plus and hence all 8-bit
will be used by taking for decision so
these are things we are we are trying to
use for doing the qos because whatever
we have this will you an administrator
user a free hand on what basis you want
to do means qos fill our benches yes
next
okay this entropy field entropy label is
a 16-bit field which is calculated based
on has generated by in that package
layer to address means MAC addresses
source or destination Methodist and
layer 3 addresses IP for source of
destination addresses are ipv6 losa
destination addresses are l for
addresses means tcp or UDP port numbers
a combination of all Diego and then you
to use to to load balancing distribution
are low distribution of Dayton ecmp of
core our bridges without doing deep
packet inspection now what we have to do
here is to we have a big deep packet
inspection go all way inner into the
energy packet very if i try to do any
cmp otherwise we'll choose delta field r
l three fields to do easy on you but we
have to go to an inner packet and we
have to do a deep inspection so by
bringing in trophy level what we are
trying to do is again we are giving a
free hand to means unless later or
someone who want like whether he want to
use an inner ear two hitters are in the
l3 headers and you don't do a deep
packet inspection and without that doing
entropy level will help us to do a load
balancing and it's like okay so now FGL
will come here after this entropy level
this fine grind level is a 24-bit level
which is same as whatever it was earlier
so what we have married this as a
contiguous later cuz this contributes so
this indicates the frame belongs to it
which particular broadcast segments so
on top of that we have reserved for
future purpose I think you can go for
next line so what exactly it will
provide us what are the uses that we are
getting from here is that with entropy
label load distribution in the easily
turn on me cmp for our bridges and
achieving of qos until can be done based
on customers requirement and top of that
what we can do here is that there are
some models in mpls for achieving us
like white model short fight model all
those things we can bring into the trail
also alert if really and some customer
wants it could be like that but for
achieving us until what I can see here
is that right now we don't have that
much of free hand provided to the
administrator if he wants to stay
whatever is there in the trail header is
indicating to him or if you want to
change so we can give him a free hand if
you want to take the decision based on
the inner headers which in the hidden
there is a to head up our l3 hidden if
l3 header means again how he want to do
it so by bringing this priority field
into FGL header I think we are giving a
free hand to a customer r2r
administrator how he wanted to take a
decision and another thing that is most
important is that a change of different
mode of services easily like we land
based service instance we learn bundle
service instance
we learn our bundles resistance etc so
it will become very easy when we bring a
team outside the inner header we can go
for next line next like okay so this is
what i have so any comments on the
proposed idea is always welcome so well
Donald's going to the mic let me ask an
operational question this proposal hints
that you've got customers who are
leading these changes can you provide
some more detail on why the original
stuff original fine-grained label wasn't
able to accomplish some of these pieces
and what your customer scenario don't
give enough so we can tell the customer
but if you would just give us a little
background on what customers you're
working with why it's important to them
that would really help me in my
evaluation so all right no we don't have
any customers as of now so what we can
see the different technologies for we
are like what we have right now is tell
always means want to have something like
FGL to be outside the inner packet
headers so what we are doing here we are
putting FGL inside a inner packet header
so they always have means want it will
be outside of it and top of it as I told
that entropy level what we here we are
proposing will have it will give
a very good chance for load distribution
there as the condo in deep packet
inspection that that will bring a lot of
overhead to the for our bridges so it
has to go all the way in split in order
to freeze energy fields so and I also
chillin of us until what will we right
now we are doing is we are using
sometimes we land header outer wheel and
header if the technology is like PPP we
don't have Ellen headers also right so
and also the means a lot of models that
we have in kos like pipe model universal
modern and sharp white model that is in
mpls get some so to bring all these
things i think somewhere we need to make
this FGL means to bring the sexy and
outside the inner header and to put in
the trail header I did it will become
easier so because sometimes it is
confusing when we see the ethertype well
if two times it has been repeated so so
we are wasting you around some two plus
two means four byes where to tell that
this is the a third type so that's where
I think we need I think that will this
will improve some of the things which
right now atl is not having so frankly
speaking there are no customers as of no
vertices as a mincer proposed means IDF
bunny and Donald okay let me summarize
because some of the meat echoes coming
in but it's trimming parts of your words
so I'm going to just summarize what I
think I heard and please correct me and
I'm sorry for the the quality seems to
just put certain things so my
understanding from what you just said
is you have some what I guess would be
data center customers that need a lot of
ecmp you have other customers outside
the data center that are attached to
VPNs who need some of the split out that
the fine-grained labeling has and then
I'm not sure about the third case
whether you have some other QSR
requirements based on a particular
application voice or something else I
again I apologize but I'm just trying to
characterize you know the needs because
data centers our news needs combining
them with exterior some Q s is new needs
if you would just walk through that and
Donald if you heard it better on the
types of users you're welcome to
Commodore John if you if you heard any
more on the user's animals and before
that yeah this answer go ahead and
answer mark did I understand your types
of users correctly and you need and
actually so there is no customer as of
know so this anyone who want this
proposal so this proposal is like after
seeing lot of other technologies so who
has a FGL kind of header which is
outside the means original header so
that's where we are trying to bring it
but we don't have any customers as of
now so if you bring it but Cupid's to
perceive a particular customer market
thank you for confirming that or not do
you perceive a particular market that
this will help you reach I'm just I'm
trying to get a sense of
the push to change a header and you talk
about that justjust for my background I
think those definitely someone will come
back to us means and what I hear is a
lot of customers are like because of FGL
that is inside the original header the
customers is really not understanding
what exactly why exactly it should be
inside it okay thank you um just a
minute down over in drama theme I'm
asking about use cases I mean I won't
along that line I'm I'm just kind of
curious if if you don't know this to the
customers are what the scope of their
problem is you know how tightly bound it
is is what you're looking for I mean you
already have alternatives lined up if
you cannot get this achieved excuse me
it I think they're basically I'm curious
is what is your plan B if you can't get
this to work how you want it to what
what what is your alternative path I
don't have any plan their loneliness
continue answer as if how it is going on
it for example how we are using a chair
as of now continue with it if no one is
ready to accept it and it is better if
we have some kind of new draft in the
drug ship and someone is then ready to
try it out
all right thank you very much more now
on to the rest of the question well is
not least like before way I just wanted
to make a couple comments and think I
believe one of the things is that the
existing FGL standard I have some slides
to go after this mentioned that existing
FGL standard hasn't actually been
implemented in merchants iligan kind of
a problem and this proposal by making
the FGL field contiguous to make it
easier for never processors to handle it
and a number of other aspects of it
they're designed to make the fast path
implementation easier so that it can be
done better with network processors or
you know would be easier to implement in
and so uh burton silicon in the future
and that's a little this little point
these lights here I was thinking they
proposed changing the version number
which is kind of a big deal in the
trouble petrolhead er there's other ways
of doing it which would be are there are
these there's some flag fields in the
trail header which are critical flags
over there said they would cause any
switch that didn't understand it to
reject it which don't require changing
the version at all we have a one bit in
that area is the bit which currently
indicates that the optional flags word
is present so it can use another bid in
that area to indicate that the FGL a
header information was present so I
think that might be a little easier than
trying to change the version of them the
only thing I know that I really creative
mode yes depend on merchants loca
implementations of it there were
customers basic implementation
Margaret Colin from pain land security
um the first question I have I guess is
uh I did we'll go over the drafts for
this meeting but I didn't find this one
so what is the draft that this is
documented in but but these changes is
their draft for this okay so i will not
feel guilty that i'm asking questions
based only on looking at the slides page
eight i think it was slide 8 i have a
question about this it sounded like
we're going to have a new header version
that says that the header that follows
is an FTL header and then we're going to
have a bit in the FGL header that says
it's a valid FGL header now what is it
if that it isn't set an invalid FGL
header I mean I don't I don't understand
what the is that space always going to
be reserved but if that fits one we
should do something with it and if not
it should be all zeros I don't
understand what this needs that I've
seen that I'm not quite as upset with
because this scene there another routing
dress as they try to migrate versions of
header so is this is that what it means
the space will always be reserved it
will be all 0 is that what you're
proposing I'm not sure if your name is
Mohammed or umair and so I'm not sure
what to call you i'm sorry could you let
me know yeah you can probably do a lot
of more models and yeah all you want you
can call it Fortuna okay yeah yeah so
now about that I beta so for example
might be will use FGL for some of the
reservation purpose sometimes the htl
values might be all zeros so then we can
tell that there is a invalid FGL value
which is there in this header and you
can directly drop it
so that is the purpose why we are
linking the I bit so if this is not the
way to commence like to handle it I
think we still have time and we can
think about it but right now the main
intention is if something which is all
the value is zero then implicate the art
bridges to directly drop that frame okay
and then I had a question about a few
slides from now there was if the value
is one of the values to with the values
three there we go um one thing I should
think you should at least consider here
is that deciding what to do by looking
at a value and then a field is
computationally more expensive right
than just deciding what to do based on a
field and I wonder if it's possible um
and I'd have to look and think no to
have a way that we encode one field that
could be as much as 10 bits long because
you're one two and three are going to
take two bits plus you're a bit field
right if we have a way to encode one
field that we could map all these values
to so that there's a consistent set of
fields instead of having three different
types is something I would wonder about
in terms of if there's a meaningful way
to do it i mean if they're completely
disparate information that they're
trying then then we are sort of mapping
to it by having one two three at the
front right but is there a way that we
can actually map these to be meaningful
in some simple way like for instance are
the three bits really indicating
something that could be mapped into the
eight bits i I don't know I know that
the three that toss field has previously
for various things being mapped into
other types of traffic class fields like
the dip surf field and I wonder if we
could get two to one set of information
we have a trill header with map values
from the other fields I don't know okay
and then my only other comment is on the
well why don't you answer that question
i'll give my other comment when you're
done so go ahead and the reason behind
why this these are dope fields because
one it indicates that convey we have
copied is miss Perry liquid then when we
want to copy it back means when it is
going out of 30 campus so if some
customer want in such a way that if you
want to copy the priority bits back to
its original hidden so it will help him
to know which very he has to copy it
back so whether it is n2 header there is
LT hidden so where exactly you want to
copy that that's why we have divided do
you think it might be modified these
fields might be modified in transit yes
correct yes that's why it means we have
I mean different type of models in qos
as what I was discussing like we have
pipe model me hair and universal model
we have short pipe model these models
means means each model is different from
other in the case where sometimes we
don't want to copy it back sometimes we
want to copy it back to the virginal
header so the reason is just to do the
edge carrbridge it will indicate that
where you want to copy it back means
whether to the end to head over a
three-headed the first two bits which is
in the FP field will help to the
averages edge our beaches where you want
to copy Trevor yeah I'm pretty sure it
is it safe to modify all of these are
empaths so but um yeah I Donald wants to
say something about this I I don't want
to margot has another comment but i just
wanted to say that that there seems to
be enough space in this FGL header that
you can preserve these things you know
copy them into their but at some level
the current drill architecture assumes
that there's always a
for bit handling priority for the drill
data packet and basically the grotto
eligibility and the three bits of
priority and the trill switch ports are
Bridgeport's and they could have these 8
q's having additional information around
is fine but it's sort of would be good
if there was a spirit priority and a
wonder crop eligibility field available
and having additional information which
is ok but the exit the trill
architectures would have assumes there's
that for bit summary of the priority for
handling things and then the the third
thing I wanted to ask about let me try
to remember what it was can you just go
forward a little bit on the slides
because I'm maybe it'll come back oh um
go back 10 one of the things that you
can get into with attempts to calculate
entropy is if you have one way to do it
and a good hash algorithm you will get
an even distribution okay but if you
have multiple ways to do it you get a
less even distribution right because you
are hashing on different stuff I think
you want to look into and I need to see
actual text this is it like enough
information for me to make that judgment
but when you do that you want to make
sure that you talk to some people dirty
people or something to make sure that
whatever you're coming up with with we
might use this or we might use that
actually it's going to result in an even
hash distribution because that isn't
always the case if you can use these
fields or those fields or some other
fields and then the hash algorithm also
has to be well well defined in order to
come up with an even distribution so
that was my only other comment that was
just random advice worth what you paid
for it Thank You market is there any
other questions or comments for uma
okay we will take this draft to the list
and have further discussions it's the
first draft well you would do me a favor
if you would think a little bit about
the use case you might deploy in this
and send me a note on that thank you no
i would add were the greatest hopefully
a way of encouraging people to read into
this assuming that this all be written
up is it there are a lot of things we
wanted to do when thinking about Joe
that we didn't do because there was so
much resistance to any sort of hair
change of any sort and the fear was that
it would cause all the ripple effects in
the market I've Donna pointed out there
are no silicon chips supporting it the
custom chips that were designed to do so
I believe we're known for shipping and
so the resistance to doing that isn't
really what it was before and so if
there really is a good reason yeah my
point is is it this might be worth
looking into the situation has changed
right and I should ask the final
question remark are you intending this
for software implementation because at
this time the speeds can do it are you
intending it for some of the trail
labels fine green labels to be put in
hardware if you know at this point and
excuse me Kenyan will feet will be a
hardware implementation that does
hardware forwarding or will it be a
software implementation that does
boarding by the Trillia fine grading
label these are hardware and already
many monitors so just let me repeat that
hardware is your intent and yeah okay
thank you that's also very good
information thank you for putting up
with the remote in speaker you'd be good
to give us feedback to the chairs how
that worked thank you yeah thank you
very much and thank you for giving a bit
very early in the morning if I got it
right here at five thirty in the morning
or is it six o'clock it is dope dude we
on me yeah right it's what we're wearing
I'm 53 am yeah wow you look very fresh
and alert so if they I did
wonderfully for 253 am in 230 wow that's
dedication thank you thank you so much
Donald I believe you have another thing
that goes on the same topic yeah
originally I was going to propose a some
a different way of doing this fine green
label thing but I turned out my look at
it it didn't work so hey then knock that
it's plenty of a few slides on does it
little background and backwards
compatibility stuff next slide I have
approval okay so you know the purpose of
fine-grained labeling is to provide a
24-bit label I got 10 and ID when you
need more than the 4,000 vlans because
you have one that your classes of
traffic to their food separate and the
it's me okay I don't know the all your
chopper to the via the basic the VLAN on
the native traffic if you configured it
this way gets mapped into an FGL at the
ingress our bridge and then the egress
it gets mapped back I guess the mappings
can be different and it's also prides
away where you can have the purdy us set
for the traffic which is different from
that externally and can be restored I
mean don't I push them spoken yeah
bushnell okay yeah priority of yellow
okay so this is what it looks like it's
very similar to the previous diagram and
you might wonder how this strange double
ethertype thing came out it's it sort of
comes from the ethernet from the tag
stacking stuff I mean if you go back far
enough a certain large commercial vendor
started putting to customer VLAN tags in
a row to indicate essentially a 24-bit
label and which that was never approved
as the standard by any standards body
and in fact what I Triple E did is day
later said you need to use a service
VLAN followed by a customer VLAN if you
want to effectively get that because
they thought putting two copies of the
same tag in the row was evil or
pertaining to pick it certainly was it
was never standardized that it never
approved so not certainly wasn't kosher
so anyway uh but so we sort of wanted to
do something like that but I don't
remember if there was a liaison or
anything but basically we were basically
told anything we wanted to do with that
customer or service VLAN tags my tripoli
had to exactly follow I Tripoli rules we
couldn't do anything different so we
said well we'll get our own either type
and then we can say what the rules are
so you've got a roni to type Andrea
simply did what is commonly called tag
stacking but with our own TV but that's
how it ended up that way so one of the
things is let's assume it is a draft ins
the standardization of the proposal that
Goomer has presented
there will be a problem you might have a
link with different ports on it from
different our bridges that use different
FGL encodings and that's not going to
work very well so does the one of the
details that we would need to clean up
to do this is to have a bit in the
capabilities of the either in the port
game abilities or the switch
capabilities indicating which variation
they were using and if you guys are all
the same on the link everything is
wonderful you might it might be better
be purport if there could ever be
something you could convert from one to
the other or you could have it /
switched if you want it to be simpler
and if you ever do get and which is on
the same link then you really can't send
FGL traffic because they will the other
end won't understand it if if the FGL is
you know you could have a court that
understood both the existing format and
acquittals and the new one but if you
have two ones that are fundamentally
incompatible probably the safest thing
to do is just not establish an adjacency
on that link and this should be a very
rare situation would only be case where
the network is perhaps not that well
managed and a well managed network a lot
of these in compatibility problems
should be very rare nevertheless for
safety and make sure you don't send
something to the wrong ten enter the
wrong VLAN and violate security
requirements you do need to indicate the
format you're using and you need to
check for this into that ability so
that's really all I wanted to just add
any questions ok we'll go on to the next
set asides Donald what was your intent
was to just work this out with the
previous one
so yeah I whoever has chuckling before
and Mar both our names on the Venus
draft so Buddhist slides so the next
step would be to produce a draft so I
think it should obviously a first draft
doesn't have to cover everything but
it'll be good for it to at least mention
all the issues and have a sketch of a
solution to any of them Thank You Donald
we're going to go on to the next thing
on our agenda which is the parents
election are you is route from a Kumar
good you're here wonderful in person let
me see if I can get these slides up
please take the once i get your slides
it will be just easily and thank you for
redoing the slides for us he gave me a
moment to get to the right screen does
this look good did I get the right one
yeah ok here we go ahead and just tell
me when you want to change the sides ok
so I'd like to make the case for this
particular draft which solves a known
problem in trouble my name is aunt
Miranda both of the communications so
what is the problem that the draft a
scientist out it's basically that the
parent default pattern selection rules
standardized in the treadle
reconstruction process can lead to
situations where parents for a
particular node in the tree shift
unnecessarily and I'm aware of this
creating problems for customers in the
field and the draft here basically tries
to provides actually two different
solutions which can be used for this and
I will explain what they are and which
one is preferred as I go along so the
crux of it comes down to this basically
the second pilot the lower paragraph on
the page ok so if and I'll skip one
slide mode so it comes down to this so
basically if you are building 3 number J
and you have a situation where a node
can be pulled by three different parents
then the virtual chooses the parent for
that particular tree is it use it orders
all the parents in ascending order of
seven octave is is ID and then in dec
sets them up so that the first one has
an index of 0 the last one has an index
of and not P minus 1 or whatever it is
and then the parent choice is then made
as J minus one more p where j is the
tree number and p is the number of
parents so what does what problem does
this cause so let's take a let's take
the example of this spine lift network
that's shown on the right side here are
basically let's say that this we are
talking about tree number two and that
is the root node for that tree you start
off the SPF at eight and then it tries
to go ahead it tries to pull the nodes
that are optimally reachable from it so
on the very first shot is going to pull
in one two and three because those are
the nearest nodes that are attached to a
so and four one two and three there is
no choice of parent because it is the
tree root is a and only a can be the
parent now as the second step none will
start looking at other nodes which are
reachable through one two and three and
now you will find that you can now reach
B and C now when you try to pull in B
and C into the tree you have a choice
they can be pulling through one through
two or three so that's the rule that the
rule that was on the previous slide is
basically acting as a tiebreaker for
this particular situation so in this
case what you will do is you so let's
say they in ascending order of I sighs
ID there the parents are one two and
three okay so one is considered to be
our index 02 is considered to get index
one and three is considered to be at
index 2 so because this is 32 and you
have three parents potential parents you
will compute the index the preferred
index as 2-1 mod 3 which is equal to 1
mod 3 which is equal to 1 so you will go
with so the node at index 1 will
basically too if you see the list there
right so too will become the parent for
gay and see so the tree looks as it does
on the left side arm so this is fine but
what happens when let
node number one went down so again
you're forced to recalculate the three
at that point at that point what happens
is a pulls in two and three directly now
again when you come when you're pulling
in B and C you have a choice they can be
pulling through two or they can be
pulling through three so again order the
parents in ascending order so they are 2
is at index 0 threes our index 1 you run
through the calculation which is
basically three number minus 1 mod
number of parents which is in this case
2 minus 1 mod two parents now so is
equal to 1 mod 2 which is one however
the node at index 1 is actually is node
3 now so in the updated list so now what
happens is the parents were BNC shift
from two to three ok so this causes a
lot of issues in real in real networks
because basically you have running
traffic that can get disrupted and the
there was a real customer case where
there's some kind of financial / that's
one or somebody was looking for a way to
solve this so that that basically led up
to this and there are that as far as I
can tell there are two ways to solve
this i will talk about the bogie
approaches and why i prefer one of them
so the simplest easiest way to solve
this is using the affinity sub here it's
a sub theory of the router capability
tlv which is already used in many other
scenario culture and it's published by
the so in terms of semantics is
published by the planet identifying
which children it wants to have a parent
relationship with and the specific tree
on which this is to be done it's a it's
quite powerful and needs to be used with
certain caveat so the way the approach
one works is that the operated
configures parent stickiness on a
particular preferred mode so in the
previous example if you go back to this
slide it's on unknown number two he can
he can configure this parents tequila
saying that my preferred parent in all
three situations is to for that
particular level in the tree so once
once he configures this what happens is
that the the two then runs through a
tree calculation again when it runs
through the tree calculation it does not
use the default reviews and at the same
time at that point it has not published
any affinity
but ignores its own any affinity tells
me that it might have generated but it
because it has now a preferred parent
skaters it acquires the so when you're
in the SPF construction you see that you
are in contention to be a parent for
those children and you it asserts that
parent relationship basically so
immediately bill pools DNC in the
previous case through through itself and
and it becomes the parent of BNC now
once it has run through one calculation
and and it through it has waited for
some measure of stability let's say a
few check a certain time interval or
something like that then it goes ahead
and publishes and affinities of jail me
saying that hey i am the preferred
method for children B and C on three
number two so once this goes out in the
network everybody knows that too wants
to assert that current relationship and
they all bind it to two as the parent
okay so subsequently what happens so if
you take the same situation in the
previous the did this approach one
scheme implemented what happens is that
when one goes down you are even before
one went down presumably when two was
configured with the parent stickiness it
went ahead and published an affinity sub
tlv which went to every node in the
network so even when one went down
nobody is using the default trail
calculation anymore they already know
that two wants to be the parent because
it has sent its affinity Kelby and it
which is valid right now so everybody
will pick you as a preferred parent so
the parent will not shift 23 when one
goes down basically which is what you
wanted to achieve so there is a second
way in which you can do this this
approach is a little bit harder to
implement arm and so the way its
proposed is that so the draft presents
are modified form on the Dijkstra
algorithm where basically you are you
are if multiple parents can pull in a
particular child at the same optimal
cost then you can insert a policy filter
in the free construction thing what
which will drive your parents election
basically the policy filter is abstract
you can put whatever you can hold it
however you want
but the what the draft cops about is
that you make it match your previous
stable pre-construction okay so you can
begin with let's say you started off
with till the default rule rules and
your tree look like like it did on the
left side of the slide gear so once you
know that too was the parent in
subsequent recalculations you will
continue to be maintained to as the
parent because you are poly because your
policy is always referencing the
previous table draft reconstruction so
so by doing this you basically preserve
whoever was the parent when the first
drill parents election was applied so
this will also solve the problem but
basically here the difficulty with this
approach is that you have to you have to
kind you're kind of doing the doing a
kind of time synchronization in a
distributed Network basically so this is
harder to do and with some caveats it
might work but it's probably best suited
for like small to mid-size networks but
and this slide indicates how that works
so when one went down because too was
the preferred parent you continue to
latch 22 in your subsequent
recalculations you policy guides that
but still between the two approaches
approach one is substantially better
preferred arm and because it's
guaranteed to work everything that you
need to implement approach a is already
there in trill and no change to the
protocol is needed but I still put
approach be there as a backup just in
case you know something prevents
approach a from they use on no and
there's no there's no I pier on either
of these approaches that okay so
basically I'm requesting that this gear
adopted as a working group document
because it solves a reasonably important
problem in true arm however there are in
the published version there are a few
mistakes and logical inconsistency that
I need to fix I have a private draft
which I will probably upload after the
after I the current idea on one of the
questions I had was you know should we
carry approach be all the way till the
end or just remove it and knew that
approach a arm
the other thing is the policy driven up
mechanism listed in approach be can be
used in some other situations
particularly if you want some there can
be alternative default parents election
groups it so you can probably come up
with other formulas which will try to do
a better job of distributing the links
on between the parents the children
between the parents basically if there
is any approaching interest in pursuing
that maybe we could probably use
approach we as a separate draft and
approach a can be enhanced to add node
redundancy for that sticky for the
preferred parent basically so one one
other question I had was the draft is
currently informational sorry
experimental and can it be should it be
changed or informational so so that's
about it so just because I may be behind
in the draft and the draft changes the
affinity tell me that you're proposing
is that a new version of a penalty kill
me than I missed or is that the original
affinity Fieldy that we've had a mother
okay so the change is really which is
this an application or since we're not
changing bites um or is it just a
mechanism for changing parents election
in other words we're using the same
affinity tale be or type a we're
changing the paragraphs in RFC 7780 is
that what i understand correctly no it's
just a blinding the same affinity
existing offended if it's ain't romantic
in the new situation it's not really
changing it's not what I changing
anything ok ok so it's it sounds like an
informational I'm sorry if it you know
you're not changing anything it's an
informational good idea on how to
prevent your customers from flapping but
if you're not changing anything in the
in the dress
sounds like if you've got customers that
have problems this is a real important
thing to look at and you know i would
state those things to the the list and
indicate the problem you know underline
the problems you're having with
customers so that we can consider that
in the process of adoption it sounds
like the custom are you having lots of
customers a few customers and this is an
edge point can you give me sort of a so
i should like uh there was basically a
presentation in my previous job I'm
other people are looking for it my
current job I'm not available ok anybody
needing do so this is from a previous
set of customers ok other questions on
the technology folks anyone have looked
at it well thank you for the very nice
presentation I think that's an
interesting problem with the parent node
ships I've seen that another protocols
thank you thank you very much ok we're
working down toward the last part of the
agenda I believe we have just one more
thing or am I at with the smart end
nodes Fenway did some revisions to the
smart ed nodes based on comments Don
will will present because it's I guess
very late in China as well ok give me
one moment Donald turn over Great Flood
you won't we just go on the next slide
sure yeah so I guess so family is not
available like if the changes in this
version are mostly due to my comments
that's no anyway so it diff these are
the advantages it saves in the learning
space wicked refresh supports
fine-grained label aware end stations
you should ever want such a
thing which you might I guess I strats
been around for quite a while and by
several times next slide oh no sorry
sorry so uh so changes from the last
version it ends I see it now it only
supports full directory information
because how to do push was unclear and
the this is sade stuff in there which
was pulled visually these are all
results of my comments on the on the
previous version and exactly what
macular as it uses for where's multicast
frames it's been changed to the all our
bridges multicast at us let's see this
is uh this is a more changes in this
version if you get a native
multi-destination frame from a non-smart
n-no then you have to send the krill
data package to the campus and also out
of port to the look that back to that
same length so that the smart end note
on the link will pay attention to it so
easily the questions whether these
fairly extensive changes actually are
put in good enough shape for doing
another working group less hall and I
think they do so we should think about
it and start one shortly I guess it'd
been through one where i can move last
fall modified is result any comments
because this is one of the things i
wanted to try to get result was a smart
endnotes draft going to final working
group last call the real comment was on
the multi cat the native
multi-destination data they were the
previous fundus didn't really cover all
the cases correctly so there is another
graph which is the directory assisted
encapsulation which might be working
with last call at the same time
the topics are similar enough that it
might be convenient to be able to review
them both at the same time and I think
that would be very beneficial because
that finishes some portion of our our
directory assistance or well we've come
to the end of the session and thank you
for your attention we will call it into
the clothes Donald if you will post that
that any questions to the draft and then
i will post later in the week of working
group last call blue sheets please and
who are if you will post a comments
about your your you know general some
general idea of customer needs maybe
that will engage people I don't want you
to break any company confidentiality but
if you just describe it and I think
we're went to sleep so thank you again
oh you know I mean is everything
okay venom but is so pretty soon like
everything you could have done you did
cool he really was acting like this like
this heavy people spent on a 6 18 months
but you're not better luck in it that
long yeah and the answer was kill well
yes I said to someone here today most
opposition to sink nice yeah because go
down to but that's hard i will take
those down to the registration or if
you'd like to the gross the grove or
tainted weird growth growers problems
were throwing the IP address space
mostly it's bgp policy issues is that
mine a classic thing