you
hi everybody thanks for coming along
today I'm gonna be talking about
offensive ansible for red team's people
have asked me one of preparing for this
why have you got it attack they'll learn
fine well let's get to the good stuff
first you know like how come he actually
uses that as a tool to actually attack
infrastructure so that's good so a
little bit about me is that edward has
likely said I'm a Red Team operator for
a fortune 500 company I've been in
intersect for a bit 15 years now and
I've had a different sort of path into
this area I had done everything from the
tech writings security architecture
OPSEC pan testing and everything else in
between
previously bad programmer made every
mistake in the book and developing so
called new media when DVDs were a thing
currently I am in a red team and I love
automation occasional t-shirt winner
doing some stuff for all their
organizations like CERN and this is what
I get in return so good stuff also like
psych one not very fast but I'm there
anyhow okay so I talking about today
DevOps tolling on principles for
offensive purposes so just to break that
down a bit I think that red teams are
changing and if they're not they should
do if there's a lot more development my
it's based on DevOps principles agile
all of that sort of thing we need to
follow suit and I'll be talking about
how those principles and some of the
tooling things such as like ansible how
they can be used for offensive purpose
so as I recall it using it in a
professionally evil manner full
disclosure I used to get automation for
most so some attitudes to it I remember
being challenged one day by an
individual where I work out what
happened we automated you out of a job
this is a miss doing OPSEC pam testing
on the expectation that you could
automate absolutely everything to do
with
good luck with that so join the red team
and I find that I in order to actually
break things and achieve operational
goals I'm obviously having a t-bill
things a lot so that's everything from
small tools to do enumeration right
there up to spinning up some attack
infrastructures so it's pretty good for
that I'm not a programmer as such but we
know enough to get by which is good
enough okay why do I actually like all
things DevOps from an offensive security
perspective Automation is the big thing
for me I have done a lot of stuff where
it's some manual laborious activity
where you're setting something up the
hard way maybe that's good if you're
learning something from scratch for
instances will want to more depth later
about high data set of an Active
Directory in an automated fashion that's
okay if you need to learn at once and
learn the principles behind it but if
you're doing that again again again it
just gets a bit boring and it's not the
best use of your time
so just they prove a point in here take
a look at this one if you want to
actually spin up maybe some stuff in a
virtual box or if you're gonna do it
with terraform and if a lot of mind will
work to do in here potentially if you're
downloading isel's and things like
that's installing prerequisites adding
Active Directory rules all of that
lovely good stuff that's gonna take an
age the stuff I'm gonna be showing you
today is I'll be the slightly best in a
local lab environment with VirtualBox
and vagrants and then been able to
configure up the ansible
it's largely machine time where you just
tell it what you do what you want to do
and offer oh go go grab your lunch
coffee or whatever and come back with in
a bit right under two hours for a
specific setup that I've got for you
here which will be pretty good but
there's also other ways I've been able
to speed that up in the cloud but today
it's just
going to be a local lab that I've got
here and you can probably tell I like
cats so you can okay speed and
consistency I just want the thing done
quick like for instance if you need to
spend up a machine in the cloud with
terraform it's done like that even
better than doing it locally which is
really really nice people are human we
all make mistakes and you've got a long
list of tasks to do to spin up a server
or a series of servers what's the
chances may be overlooking something or
thinking oh I'll do the third that's
when you're going to get problems that
you have the actually sit back just die
debug things if you're doing the
automated way with tooling such as
ansible it's the same thing done over
and over and over again which is nice
and also this raises up to get on with
the business of hacking or as I call it
hacker sysadmin we want to be learning
new things we want to be achieving
operational goals so ansible can help
with all of this can be used for more
exciting things beyond hacker sysadmin
but let's see what we can do with it so
what really is ansible it's the easiest
way of explain it's an IT automation
tool covers configuration provisioning
application deployment etc whereby you
actually have one mean machine that
actually controls a bunch of other
servers etc and I could call out the
ansible controller its job is say right
ok I've got a real estate here of X
number of servers I want you to do these
jobs for me in this order and just go
with it so it's pretty neat for that
sort of thing
Automation how does that differ from
terraform been asked that quite a bit
and there's maybe some crossover in some
small areas but I'll show you more I
think those limitations are later Tara
forms actually to build the actual
infrastructure
that's just basically getting the raw
machines up and running for instance
later in a demo you
be able to see where I've actually taken
a bunch of ISIL files downloaded off the
web and then using tool called vagrant
locally it does that spinning up
terraform sort of similar it will
actually get your machine up and running
but it's not necessarily configured how
you actually wanted to do the tasks you
have in hand whether that's actually a
fishing server record the c2 channel
whatever okay so I would say that the
two tools are actually very very
complementary another question I've been
asked is that ye fixated on ansible leo
there are other tools such as puppet and
chef I'm not gonna disagree with any of
those tools I'll be really honest folks
I haven't used them a whole lot but the
big thing I actually I would say that
about ansible why I actually like in
comparison to those other tools
it's agentless and what that really
means is that if I want to control a
couple of hundred maybe a couple of
thousand servers I don't need to install
anything specific on those boxes if
they're Windows I can communicate over a
Windows RM and then on anything that
takes SSH in the next slash Macworld
that will actually work integration
perspective although it's Navy
independence of tools such as terraform
and vagrant for getting that raw machine
up and running it works very very well
with that I think it's just a great
handover you've built the raw machines
and I actually that's configure them to
go to war everything is defined in
simple text files we call a me llamo yet
another markup language something like a
scummy number some people have actually
said that it's a declarative language
mmm I'm gonna disagree with that I would
say it's procedural well it's largely on
the basis that you tell it what you want
and you don't need to be worried about
what's going on behind the scenes so if
you have issued a command to talk to X
number of servers in the background it's
running maybe a lot of pipe and stuff
after it's made an ssh connection or
it's running powershell if you're in a
Windows world it isolates you from all
of that sort of stuff it's got a series
of module
there's hundreds of them thing is doc
sensible calm it will just mention
hundreds of different modules that you
can actually utilize really really good
source of information so with that out
of the way
what's what is that that makes ansible
work
there's loads of terms and not going to
cover all of them but the basic sort of
building blocks first of all is what we
call rules and that's really like a
collection of tasks that have a common
purpose friends since you may actually
have a rule where you've got a lure the
commands in there that are used to
actually create a domain controller or
you've got another rule that's actually
going to be able to spin up a single
server and installation obviously
there's going to be a lot of individual
tasks associated with that but logically
they're grouped into rules so you can
see on screen here and hope it's
reasonably easy to see if I can remember
to turn this on I've got one idea in
here about a power play but rules common
member server MS sequel that looks
incredibly simple it's not just all of
it that's it that's what they call a
rule and that points to a load of tasks
in the background so you can see where a
given rule has a lot of support files
and default files variables handlers
that will actually trigger specific
actions such as restarting services and
things like that
tasks and variables so there's a lot of
stuff underneath the hood there the
tasks this is the bit right call it
procedural what you've actually got in
here is in this case this is actually
taken from a rule to spin up sequel
server installation it's just telling
you okay well resource name is sequel
set up wearable I find all the files
that I actually need and it's pulling
these from a load of variables so these
can all be customized according whatever
way you want okay so there's loads of
different types of tasks that you're
going to actually have and stunning up
an installation in here so that's just
one of them reel it into sequel server
playbooks is where aim you get to sort
of put things into action all of those
roles and their associated tasks you
grip them together and it's what they
call a playbook and say right I want you
to go off and perform this role or this
series of rules against the series of
machines that I'm actually gonna tell
you about think of it as like a play
because how you would have like a sort
of do is used in sport quite a lot but
highlight them to the key moves to win a
game and done the right way will
actually see in here today a playbook
that can actually be used for offensive
purposes think of them as the links
between us them a list of servers and
all the rules that need to actually get
implemented so moving along making use
of ansible on the red team talking about
it from three perspectives
first of all attacking with ansible sort
of talk about accessing data lateral and
what I would also called vertical
movement as well I'm gonna show you how
to actually spin up an ad lab by the way
the examples in here today are a bit
attacking when those and things like
that
it's not so that's exclusively designed
to be used for Windows is talked about
earlier there but access over as this H
etc you could use this against a Linux
real estate and so it's just a nice
little example today and also we'll be
talking briefly about high ansible can
be used in the cloud as well again I'm
talking my building a local lab but as
red team's we do use ansible quite a bit
to configure a complete attack
infrastructure so let's talk a bit
attack in here so we've got a bit of a
scenario in here where assume that I've
got root access to a Linux server not
picking one or right Retta where I've
got root access to assume that somehow
I've got access to it what I want to do
is can I actually utilize what I've got
in here
take any of these so we've got a domain
controller member servers business
catch-all term for a file server web
server or a bundle of loaded stuff in
here and then obviously at Windows 10
workstation so that's our starting point
so let's take a look what we can
actually do now if I'm on that Windows
are sorry that Linux box I want to find
out what on earth have I got something
we would actually do in a red team is
that one we've got a certain level of
access we want the understand where are
you at what do you have what can you do
with what you have where do you need to
go so like we're doing a bit of a
situation wrapping here in this case I'm
just doing a whit chancel I'm there low
and behold there's user slash bin slash
ansible also interesting some other key
files in here there's a configuration
file I will be talking about that file
later and one of the dangerous defaults
has actually got actually I'll tell you
and I by default when you install
ansible
the configuration file has logging
turned off you have to explicitly turn
it on so if there's any defenders in the
room that's a good thing to actually
take a look at first other bits and
pieces as well I'm looking for a host
file I'm not talking about at C hosts or
anything like that I'm talking about a
list of hosts that are specific to
ansible so this controller is
controlling a bunch of machines
technically it's called an inventory and
that files stored in a file called hosts
not always in at C ansible hosts it
could actually be in any node other
number of locations on the machine so do
take a look for that and I'm gonna hone
in on the host file in here to see what
goodies that it'll actually show me in
here an inventory file is just a list of
boxes that a given controller has
control over and yes you will see them
nicely grouped up together into
different sort of functional areas great
thing about this is that whenever you
want here she attacks something or
indeed use it for so-called legitimate
DevOps purposes you can in your attack
construction at different parts of that
inventory you can do all of them
Red Team scenario not always good but
you can be more specific focusing on
maybe some subgroups or individual
machines within those subgroups so this
is a roadmap to us as it says in here
spoiler alert the very very nature
ansible is they allow it to be doing a
lot of admin configuration deployment
stuff this is actually going to actually
have complete roots life system access
to anything in that real estate so
already alarm bells are ringing in here
at the main controllers mmm interesting
but maybe that's just too obvious I
don't necessarily always want to
actually go ask it to demean controller
maybe I actually want to go after some
dealer because that's more sometimes
rather a lot more relevant to a red team
goal you're after data and so um for
today's purposes in here we are actually
going to show you how we can become a
dummy an administrator on this
thumping some hashes oh but again
there's a load of other things people
have asked me is that okay is it ansible
it's actually vulnerable in here or what
you know what other attacks have you got
but it's not like a Metasploit point
should click go it's not an attack
framework it's a management and
configuration framework for machines and
my view in this one is that if you
actually have a really good handle on
how to actually do stuff at the
command-line antiderivatives together
and shell scripting allosaurus good
stuff
well then ansible is the way to make all
of that actually happening and just a
really interesting talk earlier there
from yo Keem and normally talking about
how they actually had some scripts that
actually pull down additional components
malware all that sort of stuff
this sort of stuff as well is going to
be very very good i will be showing you
a demo of hyatt actually can do a number
of tasks so interesting you can as i
said talk about using play books which
is just what you say right here's a list
of servers
here's a playbook relating to a series
of roles who often do
you can also do ad hoc commands which is
interesting there be fun to do a better
set rep once you're actually on
understate someone liners for instance
then here I'm sure you can see it at the
bottom ansible all now and I'm pointing
it to my hosts file in here - ends for
module and setup this will return
pretty much everything known to man and
woman about this box except the patches
I'll get to that later so it's going to
tell you about everything to do with
processors it's sort of what that
operating systems got installed all
sorts of stuff in here
very very useful if you want to see if
there's any other wider bigger issues as
well and in here system info and there's
nothing really new in here but this is
not an exploit framework it's a way of
actually launched in some specific
commands system info might even if I
actually had the ability maybe just do
sort of Nebat SSH based access or
windows RM access straight into that I
could do a bundle of like PowerShell
commands locally on those machines
that's probably gonna ring anon alarm
bell with that with the defenders what
I'm actually seeing in here is that the
answer the controller it's actually
known to be an administrator it needs to
be able to do these things and perhaps
there's nibby mm-hmm
I sort of there's not going to be as
much stuff raised on on dashboards if it
sees that oh here's a command from the
controller to another machine in here to
do something well yes as expect that
you're gonna be transferring files and
configuring things this looks normal so
I would prefer to do it this way because
we're working off the land and here as
quietly as possible
okay so scenario in here that I want to
show you today is that you want to be
able to create a user with elevated
privileges again here isn't the add-on
here is that you know you're not always
gonna won't be going after to me in
admin but for today I'm interested in it
and a cop we want to move laterally so
we could move to older machines in there
or we could decide you know what we want
to go further up the food chain and go
for Jimmy and admins all of us or stuff
so breaking things dying what do I
actually need to do in here by the way
no surprises I came last in art class
for choice of graphics and things so
bear with me in that what I want to do
in here is a malicious binary night
there are umpteen different c2
frameworks you could utilize for this
and yes meterpreter may actually pop
things and dashboards not really too
concerned about that today it's just
good for a really quick demo use
whatever c2 framework of your choice in
here but the point is we are actually
going to get a malicious binary
transferred on to our Red Hat books and
that can actually be used in a play book
transfer that all the way down onto a
given target machine in that inventory
and then that seems somehow more safe
because it's expected to be doing that
sort of stuff and then it's gonna be
calling back home
I love amateur pad or listener okay okay
so I'm not going to show you all of that
stuff today we're going to focus on
really the stuff a bit ansible itself so
let's get the better but generating the
motors payload so here's an interesting
playbook that can be find on that box
and I can be find white because I put it
there obviously you're just gonna have
to be very very careful you're gonna
need to do some sitrep in there to see
well you know what sort of things are
actually there you don't obviously want
to go in and create a play book with
comments rattled on it pull in this box
that's not very wise so I've used some
bits of obfuscation in here to make this
kind of normal in this case I would have
developed this offline SSH the the file
or secure copied over to the Red Hat
controller box and then we can start
there so I'm I've told that I don't want
to gather all that setup information
takes too long
moving along Leo and I if I want to put
some militia
binary on device such as a Windows box
ideally you want that to be something
that's not going to be monitored for
antivirus or other endpoint protection
controls again you're gonna need to
spend a bit of time investigating that
but for today's purposes created a
folder in here called software packages
slash library mmm maybe there's some
deployment packages in here so hopefully
that looks kind of normal but you know
take a look at your own sort of specific
environments and try and plan then
damage but this one when copping my one
of us creating this demo I actually did
something pretty lame use cert you tell
on the actual victim boxes I'm gonna
know because common files like our
common apps I got probably will ring a
bell on a defense of dashboard somewhere
so I thought right okay when copy and
let it do all the hard work for me its
so-called expected behavior and so we
should be good so I'm picking an Oracle
9 ok so some thing called client setup I
obviously if someone's gonna be that
interest that you're gonna gag grab of
that binary you're gonna strip it die
and see what it is and if this
interpreter sort of axion here you're
gonna find it pretty cool alright quick
nice we are so again there's other
things that were taken into
consideration here nibby of actually
encrypt that that binary you've done a
few other things the obfuscated code
that sort of stuff and then once it's
actually on we want that to be activated
no she activated it I want the actually
get enhanced privileges and I'm gonna go
for the kill in here with Adam Ian admin
a kind night I had actually thought
about specifying a command in here to
actually define the accounts and design
at their relevant group but maybe not
the wisest thing to put it in here
because this is actually going to be put
on that victim
ansible box and if anybody stumbles upon
it and sees creds sitting there that's
really really bad stuff so far right ok
do this with actually an answerable
ad-hoc command
my can there's gonna be partial logging
on your Windows environment hopefully
but again I'm creating them and here the
knowledge that I've gained so far in
here that this is actually expected
behavior you may actually have processes
running on that to mean controller there
may be going to be doing a partial
command to import a bunch of new users
and sign them members of groups
obviously you're gonna be looking ident
here for anything with an enhanced level
of privileges such as to me an admin
again but the point is in here it's
better to do it this way then actually
have something that will actually be
quite visible inside the actual playbook
and also stuff like that can be really
really easy showing up in ansible log
files I will talk about log file stuff
later so well so so those are the two ad
hoc commands to create the demeanor I
started to create the user and then H
they give them the main admin probes so
my I want to take that playbook and let
it go my actually being specific here in
that playbook that I want it to run with
those nice new creds that I've actually
got because that will hopefully return
me a reverse shell in the context of
that user that a special event here
again more obfuscation and here sis DB
utils obviously you should actually have
a really really good handle on what
accounts are actually in your inventory
a your Active Directory and seem like
this should actually be pop monoid
swoosh it but again I'm blending in here
okay so demo time sequence will not be
shortened there's some stuff later
actually show you is that because it
depends and dying loading thousand
things can take a bit of time and they
were speeded up so to speak this one
isn't okay so up at the top we've
actually got our a session on the
console controller down in here I've got
the meterpreter set up it's already
fired off the commands on here to set up
user and sanam sysadmin cribs nice plan
that playbook it's transferring that
file on to the given machine in this
case the domain controller that's
activating it and look see down in here
we've got a meterpreter session okay so
hopefully they'll pop up yeah there we
go you can see it's in the context of
this STD utils let's confirm that yep
that's good and pretty Liam but it'll
work in this kiss get system now I'm
gonna do a hash dump night that's just
for real demonstration purposes you may
want to do that a bit more stealthy I
using volume Shadow Copy or something
like that but in this case that was
quick it was actually easy again it's
all done to what you actually know about
your target environment suitors so
that's just one way of actually how do
you actually use ansible for an
offensive attacking perspective in there
as I said it's really don't see your own
imagination and what you actually need
to achieve your operational goals so
putting that inventory to work for you
there's loads of other things that we
could have done in here we could have
actually set up a cron job on that
ansible controller to pull down key data
from boxes on in the inventory let's say
that parts of that inventory were
maintaining daily sales figures maybe
and you have points that actually opens
credit cards you get the idea if
anything interesting is stored in those
boxes we could actually have something
that will actually pull all that off and
bring it back to me if you want it to be
a bit more stealthy and you can actually
put some of those machines to work for
you potential one on there things such
as a sharp point if you want to use that
to enumerate I'm your Active Directory
installation interesting and again I
hear something out in here none of these
types of things are actually new at all
just think ansible it's just the way I
say automate a lot of this stuff I could
have actually like an we'll see Morgan
a type but all the stuff in manually I
would have to go off to each and every
individual machine I could have watched
something together with Bosch or
something but this is pretty neat allows
me to set up an entire playbook on off
you go
also what I was doing in there
I was issuing those ansible commands
from the ansible controller I it is
possible that you could actually talk to
those victim machines controlled by
ansible
directly from your own tak
infrastructure I would say maybe not the
best operationally but perhaps there are
no firewall rules in place that would
restrict me from doing that I can that's
something you're gonna find out from
your own sort of reconnaissance
activities so and that's obviously
something as well that you'd want to
take a look at if you're actually
examining logs on a box that is
controlled by ansible you want to see
well word that that connection come from
well you take a look at the IP address
of the machine name well that's not the
answer book controller that's the sort
of stuff it should be popping up on
defensive dashboard okay some things in
here probably have already covered again
cats are busy here so they're keeping
under the radar before you do any of
this know exactly what it is in here
that you're looking at have you any
appreciation for the types of activity
conducted on earth it's what's what do
you know about except that so-called
normal behavior I mentioned previously
there but not using a cert util on those
victim boxes get ansible to do the dirty
work for you and use a module called
wind copy it's so called seen as normal
perhaps in that sort of context and a
little bit blending in as well so he's
soft not playback I actually had it was
actually going to have no creds in it
the language is pretty neutral the
functional which was interesting at the
fenders in here I can apologize about
the graphics folks
my god hopefully there's no hoodies in
here okay a few of the things that are
sort of normal like sort of activities
for blue teams in here baseline what a
so-called normal behavior that is a very
sweeping term and I apologies if that's
actually sort of simplified like that
but you really really do need to
understand what is normal behavior if
you've got an inventory that's actually
control with ansible
you know where where is the ounce of a
controller what sort of activities does
it actually do does it normally do
software installations or does it
normally to users on two systems what is
it so just understand what you're
actually doing with it so anything
outside of that should stick I'd file
integrity monitoring so if anybody's
creating accounts or tampering with
files good stuff they actually have on
board their turn on logging on your
ansible controller as I said by default
it's turned off which is pretty bad so
you're gonna want to take a look to see
in there ansible is actually configured
with a log file and then go after those
log files and examine see if there's any
telltale signs in there and obviously in
a Windows environment too
you're going to need to take a look at
your partial tech logs and you're going
to be looking as well for so-called
ansible related traffic which is really
SSH and when RM by the way like was any
of that traffic coming from something
that's not designated as a controller
and again you could maybe restrict that
with some firewall rules so moving on to
learning 9 we're going to set up a local
lab in here
it's all gonna be based in VirtualBox
you could actually use terraform all
that sort of good stuff but again this
is local if you want to be able to maybe
model an environment that's going to be
so-called see if you want the model up
in that attack before you take it into
your real attack environment a maybe you
want to try it some new cool privilege
escalation type stuff all of us or stuff
having built some personal labs and
things at home this is a long
process it's good to learn to do it once
but it really is a waste of my time
doing this sort of thing I will actually
be publishing some stuff up and it get
hub great all my own personal stuff
later stand by for that how they
actually do all of this but you know
this is really cool in the sense that
it's making use of those freely
available windows isel's the trial
versions that allows 480 days it's
technically free so it is instead of
your time so that's an interesting way
to learn some stuff so you can see and
here my lab setup it's just based again
on they surprise surprise those cm3
machines that we were attacking earlier
at the main controller a member server
and a workstation
I'm the really good thing about this is
that if you're dealing with there's a
hundred need a trial version business
with Microsoft so what we can actually
do for instance with vagrant locally and
we can say right hold everything
bring it all down destroy those boxes
and I bring them back up again and off
it'll go and get you fresh installation
and we're all rocking and rolling which
is good okay so building out our boxes
I'm actually gonna skip past the demo of
this one in the interest of time in here
today vagrant is something you would use
locally to spin up a little boxes if
you're doing this in the cloud you would
use terraform good thing a bit vagrant
if anybody's interested in it you can
actually pull down a load of pre-built
boxes from vagrant quite a google lot
and it'll take you to it I've actually
used these in some of the demos today
it's quick and handy soidiers so I'm
just gonna skip past that that's the
vagrant file that this e tells it okay
well what machines do I want built with
whatever networking requirements they've
got so on this kiss sir private network
running inside VirtualBox on machine
which interns at their ten-year-old
Toshiba laptop that still actually works
so demo in here I'll just screwin
through it very very quickly I'm not
going to go through all of it in here I
will show you how will actually check on
that
and said right vagrant up go create me
the raw basic machines in here so it's
I'm gonna focus primarily on DC b-sides
in here obviously it's going to make
sure that there's no port forwarding
conflicts for things such as three three
at nine and stuff like that so it's
literally as good as that now why would
say is that technically after this
actually runs you've actually got a box
you can start to log into but it's
pretty useless to us right now it's
actually not doing very much for us so
this is where I've actually brought in
here ansible yeah thanks very much for
bringing up the boxes vagrant or
terraform but now I want to configure
that this stuff I've actually been
working on for a while I've collected a
lot of stuff from a lot of different
sources actually one of the things
actually delay in me actually published
and there's nothing github I want to
make sure the right people get the right
attribution whenever I actually publish
all of this I saw lots of different
things isolate it and I thought what if
I bring all of this together do this and
hopefully it will work for me so stand
like that so we can see in here
something that's going to actually run
three play books
so that's corresponding to three rules
at the main controller a member server
and a workstation concentrate primarily
on the domain controller stuff in here
it's gonna have three pieces associated
with it some software i've called it
obviously at night didn't DM it
correctly but prerequisites that it
needs for a Windows server some stuff
that's actually common for everything
I'm standing up and then the really good
stuff for domain controller so here's
where I would call it's all procedural
in here so reboots actually in here that
we've actually follow setting up with
the Mian in here this is actually quite
long again when you can read that to
your heart's content
once it's available and I get repo so
this is everything relating to the
establishment of that do me and
controller hide a I want it configured
and in this case that is actually being
communicated over windows RM
which all on that victim box be running
a load of partial commands so this
in there okay so I need to him that add
an inventory which I've already got in
here and no I actually want to say right
go build that for me please while I go
off and do something else more
interesting hopefully this will actually
yep so I'm Gavin that ansible a book
called lab setup which is an
amalgamation of those three other
specific play books off you go and do
this night if you're doing this box
fresh we still have a load of stuff to
download from the web they'll take a bit
of time so this is a shortened sequence
so you can see and hear a lot of things
change this false basically I've already
done that Leo I don't need to reinstall
that but this just to give you an idea
of the steps that it's actually running
through in here to set that all up so
lots of interesting stuff to do with
partial firewall rules all of that
lovely good stuff so reboots all that
sort of thing
ensuring us a domain controller so
always yeah it's just previously gone
from the prerequisites and to everything
else I need now to make that operational
DNS forwarders because I want them to
actually have web access to download
other stuff and then and here's well for
a bit of fun I've actually put in some
stuff to create some groups to play with
and I are really nice sort of
development of this would be to bring in
a complete sort of inventory oh of users
kind groups all that sort of stuff I've
done some in here but that's a work in
progress and you can see that's actually
finished now I'm jumping into my
VirtualBox in here all three servers are
actually running and I'm just going to
just go into recording to login to them
so you can actually see that this is a
workstation vagrants already logged into
it it'll get kicked out in a second and
what I can actually do in here is just
hopefully interact with it we're about
to get the Windows desktop in here and
we'll get a message really soon in here
that it's actually
join the dummy and and all of that
lovely good stuff Rowand but for three
machines in here I was on a 72 megabit
download internet connection
it was taking me roughly about two hours
to configure that three machine setup so
your manage may vary so you can see in
here workstation b-sides hack lab dot
local nice so it's all there so it is so
hopefully now I will be able to see or
demean controller as well and just take
a quick look at our server manager and
then we'll actually take a look just to
make sure that Active Directory has
actually been set up there you have it
it's all there
we can see the two machines server
b-sides
and also the workstations as well and
our users so we're all good there so you
can start using that straightaway under
stead if that x ID on you as in the
trial rip it down obviously snapshot
anything before on if you need any data
off it alot lovely good stuff and you're
ready to go so you can start your hack
and slash research you can use that for
any number of things you sharpen up your
enumeration skills you want to try it
some privilege escalation
it's all there so it is so have a go at
it so onto the last piece in here for
the Clyde everything I've done here so
far has been locally in a nice isolated
lab with ansible I can configure
machines anywhere whether it's on a
local box or something to stop on the
Clyde so I would say that you know this
is gonna be equally useful to swim or
actually building infrastructure up in
the Clyde to attack some systems coming
in from the outside so to speak
terraform I actually love it because you
can actually spin up machines in less
than a minute the raw machines so no
messing around with local ISO files but
obviously if you're going to a clone
environment you're going to have to
start paying for it as well the
terraform good first had basic sort of
deployment of the machines my
terraform if you're spinning machines up
in the Clyde you can see and here this
is actually a digital ocean droplet and
there's full accreditation to this
person in here a really really good
source about doing all of the sort of
stuff it's got a digitalocean droplet in
here and then this section here called
provisional remote exact like this is
where there's a bit of crossover with
ansible you said well why on earth would
you actually need this little I put
everything in here where it's going to
be after you download and cobalt strike
and I'm done I don't need any of that
stuff that you're talking about an ounce
of all at all I would actually argue
once that's good for getting basic stuff
up and running what about the lifetime
of your attack infrastructure you're not
just gonna be spinning up a bunch of
servers you're gonna want to near be
take a look at that box over time to
make sure it's probably patched or if
there's been any intrusions and as well
also if there's going to be any servers
in there that are going to be serving up
malware etc you're gonna want to be able
to pull those log files down and
understand well higher my I've actually
been attacked I've actually had that
doing some stuff prepping for this last
week I'm just saying some stuff attempts
to brute force a web app which was which
is interesting so we want the actually
see those log files as well talked about
earlier if we're actually using that
inventory to go after some really useful
data on that a test it we want to be
able to pull all that back you can't
really do that with terraform and Simba
will be really really cool for that so
when the box is doing its job I need
some stuff brought back to me so that's
where I would say that's you know like
that's where ansible has the edge so you
can take a look in here this one is
something a craft that last night
actually I bite we've got a web server
on our client infrastructure running
nginx I like it because it's nice and
lightweight compared to Apache I want to
actually bring back those log files
maybe I want to type that into an Elk's
stack or if you've got several million
quid to put on Splunk go for it so you
can see in here it's bringing everything
down from data state and I can I just
say well para machine II and store that
off
which is really nice another really
interesting thing I know I'm cutting on
time in here because configuration
templates they're nerdy words further
called ginger - templates and it's
nothing against people with red hair
promise I like this stuff let's say that
you've actually got configuration files
maybe for running an engine X web server
where you need to do a lot of
customization on impera machine bases
you can copy that file over and then you
can be really useful and do some bastard
or sad or whatever it is you want to
customize that if you actually use
ansible templating it will say right I'm
taking that file I'm moving it over and
I will customize it for you at the same
time that's the real time see ever saw
this folks
so in summary ansible is a DevOps tool
red team's if they aren't agile and
utilizing DevOps tooling right now they
should be and the DevOps teams as well
know that or should know that this can
be used for good but if you've got an
answerable controller that's purely
locked though and pretty configured it
can actually be used as a weapon against
an organization it could actually end up
being the weakest link and also as you
saw in there it can be used to automate
some of the more mundane tasks Frias
better you want to spin up at your own
local Learning Labs so with that please
don't shoot me this next slide brilliant
I'm Mia Rizzo
any questions
any questions for Leo over there in the
back I am I just did a good question
cause you mentioned that like the
ansible controller is important for like
blue teams to lock down it was wondering
like as an attacker what's kind of the
most like out of all the ways to
configure sorry can you speak up a bit
oh sorry so I'm out of all the ways to
configure like these kind of keys to the
kingdom bet to them infrastructure sir
like for in regards to access management
whether that's rotating keys or like
provisioning them through like the
service and I what's what do you not
like isn't attacker the most like what
gets in your way the most in terms of
getting access to these not an attacker
it's a double-edged sword of medic we
all like to be able to compromise things
but sometimes when you compromise that's
a bad thing to really if there's maybe
some indications on here that I've been
able to get past things and here maybe
there's no network segmentation maybe
there is no two-factor authentication to
get SSH access to that ansible
controller box those are some things
maybe that we're lacking in there sure
thank you yep any more I mean where we
were back sorry just a question do you
see other products and lower down civil
being as Vaughn will disturb with attack
I'm here see I didn't hear ansible
itself is not a vulnerable product out
of the out of the box it's high it's
actually configured you could say that a
bit any software not specifically for
provisioning automation configuration
etc or what I'm recommending is that
just like any other software when you
actually deploy it do take a look about
how you can actually lock down access to
it's about you know like for instance if
you're dealing with a real estate in
there of God know so many servers do you
have actually firewall rules to say I
would only listen to you and you alone
the logging stuff etc it's really as I
think it was what Brian mentioned in his
keynote speech earlier on there really
should actually be some sort of
pre-flight checklist things that need to
be done before you let the server go
wild it's just that it's nothing really
new in that respect all right it's
lunchtime we are five minutes late so
guys have fun and girls with the lunch
thank you very much leo and give him a
warm man