hello hi thank you everyone for
attending thank you for having me thank
you for not falling asleep after lunch
so good to see you all just to briefly
introduce myself before I start talking
about the talk
my name is Seale I work at the threat
intelligence analysis group at
checkpoint
I've been there for three years and I
mainly well most of my work focuses on
Middle East stuff and this talk is no
different
actually this talk has a lot to do with
Libya and if you don't know where the
country of Libya is it's actually right
in the middle of this math I made it a
bit easy it's North Africa but Libya has
a very interesting history because back
in the day it was ruled by a king and in
1969 that King was abroad in Turkey and
Greece supposedly to receive some
medical treatment and there was a
revolution against him and that
revolution succeeded quite easily there
wasn't a lot of resistance to it and
then someone else rose to power someone
by the name of Qaddafi and Qaddafi
became a bit of an internet celebrity
for the recent years but before that he
was really the voice of change in Libya
he wanted to get rid of the corrupt
Kingdom he wanted to overthrow the
tyrant he turned the country into a
republic and because he was such an
advocate of change he only ruled for 40
years and by the end of that he didn't
even go willingly because in 2011 that
was actually the peak of the Arab Spring
so all over countries in the Middle East
there were protests asking the rulers
and the dictators to step down and to
improve the living circumstances within
those countries and the political chaos
started from Tunisia that's where the
protests first began and then spread
most notably to Egypt and Syria but the
it also reached Libya as well and
eventually Qaddafi was overthrown and
killed and the situation didn't improve
much
after that there was even a council that
was supposed to choose a replacement for
Qaddafi but they failed and they also
failed to prevent a second civil war
that happened in Libya in 2017 and since
that day or nowadays there are two major
people in power in Libya there is a
prime minister which leads the
government that the UN approves of and
there is a general marshal of the Libyan
National Army so he leads the rebel
powers against that prime minister and I
gave you that kind of Borak historic and
boring historic introduction in talib in
Libya because this dude the general
marshal or by his real name
afta appeared in an interesting context
a Facebook page that was using his name
and that page was created I think in
march and it was sharing posts like this
one and there are a lot of things that
we can tell from this post first off we
see that it had 5,000 reactions so a lot
of people were exposed to this post a
lot of people saw it and engaged with it
it was promising mobile applications
that word that could could have been
downloaded by the link that it offers
and they were supposedly providing the
users with the latest news from Libya
but in truth that they of course had
malware and they were malicious so I was
really curious just coming across this
post randomly going through stuff on
Facebook and I wanted to dig a bit
deeper into this and find out more about
this attack and this page all of the
posts that were shared by it were like
this one so they were sharing malicious
links to malicious files and so one of
the first questions I asked myself
coming across this post and trying to
investigate this further was are the
attacker is using other ways to spread
the smell where is this the only page
did the malicious activity start just
now or has this been going on for a
while and to answer that one of the
first ways that I've used was the
Facebook search part so I used that to
look up some of the links that were
downloaded the militia that we're
downloading the malicious files and that
in the posts by this page and doing that
I got back nothing and if you're if
you're familiar with the Facebook search
bar you have extensive stalking
experience you would know that not a lot
of the times it doesn't really give back
the most accurate results even when you
know a post is there you don't always
get it back
and that wasn't probably the most
effective way to check this but then I
realized that the posts included
something else besides the links
downloading the files they included text
and that text was an Arabic and I speak
Arabic and I can tell you that text was
so shitty that I even created a version
of the post with all of the grammatical
mistakes and wrong syntax and weird
phrasing highlighted you can see it's
kind of like very high percentage of the
post and I roughly translated that into
English with the mistakes you can kind
of feel or see how I felt reading this
and seeing this text in the post itself
but this can tell me two things first
off I can tell that whoever wrote this
text is an Arabic speaker because they
didn't really use translating engine or
Google Translate or whatever to generate
this because even though that might
sometimes mess up the message you're
trying to convey Google Translate will
give you back the word army with double
a or two with you etc and second of all
I can use that in my advantage so if I
can find those uniquely wrong mistakes
again being repeated elsewhere I can
probably say that it was the same person
who made that mistake and so I did that
and this time around when I looked up
some of the Arabic phrases that I saw in
the posts I got back results and I
actually got back many many many results
using this technique and you can see
that all of the results here also follow
the same patterns as just a small
caption and then a link leading to a
malicious file and soon enough I
realized that each link was shared by
more than one page
so we can really see the same text here
the same caption of the post and the
same link copied in multiple places on
the same day so I soon realized that
each such link had the potential of
exposing multiple related pages and then
those pages as I was going through them
revealed more links and the links
connected me to more pages and then
those pages connected back to the same
links so again I realize that could kind
of create a network here of URLs and
Facebook pages and I did that and this
is the full version of it all and it's
very ugly it's zoomed out you can't tell
anything about it but this is kind of
the full melty go graph of the graph of
the whole thing connecting all of the
pages and the URLs but we can really see
how interconnected this is and looking
at the connections we can tell that each
link was most of the links were shared
more more than once by the different
pages that were involved in this attack
and again just by mapping the whole
thing I was able to tell that the
activity goes back to at least 2014
that's the earliest instance I have seen
relating to this activity so it has been
going on for quite awhile when I came
across this I was also able to tell that
there are approximately 40 pages that
were involved in this operation and that
were being used to share the malicious
posts and I saw that this had a very
wide outreach because eventually some of
the pages that I came across and I was
able to connect this had tens of
thousands of followers and even two of
them had more than 100,000 followers so
you can imagine that each post that was
prompting victims to download a
malicious file had the potential of
reaching thousands or tens of thousands
of people each time through one
individual page and we can ask ourselves
well who is this after who are the
attackers trying to target using this
and you might have wild guess but we
were able to get more solid evidence
about the victims because actually all
of the posts or most of them were using
link shortening services so a lot of
Google short links and bitly and tiny
URL and what's great about those links
is that they story statistics so I can
see how many times they were clicked
where from and more information about
that so in the link I'm showing here for
example we can see that it was create
around the time it was great it was
clicked around 7,000 times and that was
also around the time it was shared and
that's a very high number as well but we
can also see that most the time the
victims or the people that click this
link were referred to it by Facebook so
we know that this is the major attack
vector for this campaign and out of the
seven thousand clicks five thousand
clicks came from surprise surprise Libya
and there were some victims supposedly
or some other clicks from different
countries but we can really see the
focus on this country by this attack and
again disclaimer a click does not mean
successful infection so these are just
the numbers of clicks we don't know that
they were victims eventually but we can
really see the focus on Libya even in
terms of links here and the same pages
that were involved in the malicious
activity shared other posts as well so
we also saw them sharing updates about
things that were going on in Libya and
news and that kind of followed the same
pattern so that the same post with the
same caption and picture was copied
across multiple pages and seeing this I
was very surprised I first off I thought
it was trying to push kind of hidden
propaganda or agenda and maybe trying to
influence some people but in reality
these were just news updates that were
trying to keep the followers of the
pages engaged and trying to keep them
following the pages themselves and just
to eventually click the malicious links
and increase the pages legitimacy
this wasn't really trying to politically
affect anyone's opinion I would say and
another question I was asking myself and
you might be is why why were the
attacker is using Facebook why this
social network so in Libya but also in
other countries where there is a lot of
political conflict I would say sometimes
your mainstream media or your main media
outlets the official news channels and
the official newspapers are not the best
source to get your news so a lot of the
times you would be thinking you're
seeing what's really going on when in
fact what you're following great the
channel is really giving you kind of a
biased idea of what is going on and
they're taking just one side and because
of that a lot of people in the Middle
East region but also in different places
have turned to other sources for news
and it involves obviously online
websites and online blogs but also
Facebook so Facebook has become kind of
a very reliable way for people to get
their news from and as soon as the
victims realize they're in sins that
people realize that threat actors were
very quick to follow so we also see that
in a lot of the misinformation campaigns
that have been exposed recently Facebook
has played a very major role and
actually such a campaign that was
exposed by Facebook's themselves by the
Facebook company that was affecting
countries such as Sudan and Libya it was
they discovered that the attackers
behind this attack invested nearly one
hundred thousand dollars in advertising
trying to reach the people or the
citizens of Libya and other countries
and affect them we're trying to kind of
humiliate one later and promote another
so again we really see how important
Facebook is in the
landscape in the Middle East also in
terms of misinformation campaigns but
also in terms of malware so we've seen
some of the more advanced players like
if you know of the dark caracal threat
group but also oh no okay sorry if you
know of the dark caracal threat group
and apt c-23 for example so we have also
seen them spreading their malicious
samples using Facebook so these are just
two examples of groups that they have
used or pages that they've used to reach
a wide audience of victims and even in
our case like although the posts or the
news headlines that the pages share it
weren't really trying to do something
like behind the stage or affect people
but we can still see that updating and
sharing those news about Libya and those
pages did keep the users engaged and it
was kind of a nice way to keep them
following the pages and since we've
mentioned malware here and malicious
files you might again also be wondering
what was the malware that was used in
this campaign so it wasn't very very
impressive I would say the attackers in
this case we're using kind of off the
shelf tools so known remote
administration tools for both mobile and
desktop that they were attacking the two
vectors in the case of mobile we saw
that a lot of the times they were using
spine out which again kind of provides
the attacker with with a nice panel that
can let them control basically anything
on the infected device and exfiltrate
all the information like contacts calls
and more sensitive stuff as well and in
terms of desktop so it was a lot of NJ
rat and other things that the attackers
didn't really develop themselves so they
again didn't waste a lot of time on
developing their own malware and in case
of desktop they did add some protective
layers before delivering the payload
eventually so we can see that when the
victims would download the filer when
they would click the link they at first
would be or would receive a VBS file or
at wsf file and you can even see that
the name
the file itself looks like a news
headline so just to keep the theme of
the posts going on and to convince the
victims that oh this is okay you should
click this should run this on your
machine and then opening up the VBS file
again we can see that it has this sort
of random blob it's first but it's not
really you can tell that this is just a
comment it's not really part of the code
and it's just used to hide the beginning
of the VBS code which is down at the
bottom so it's just meant to confuse any
victim who attempts to open this file
and the purpose of the VBS it just
basically take an array of decimal
values and turn it into the
corresponding ASCII characters and
eventually reverse that string and now
we can see that we get a more readable
code in this case and we still have an
encoded bit at the end and that is
basics t4 encoded and which is in this
case the payload the executable fails
the purpose of the VBS is to kind of
prepare for the payload to be executed
on the machine and the payload itself
was a dotnet executable again also
something open-source of the shelf not
something the attacker developed and it
was supposed to gather information from
the infected device so again like the IP
address the installed antivirus products
etc and upload all of that to a C&C
address and that since the address
helped me answer the question of who is
behind this attack because basically the
this website or this CNC used duck DNS
or a dynamic DNS so it resolved to a lot
of IP addresses and then going over the
going over those IP addresses I saw that
one of them was associated with another
domain and that domain was used by this
campaign back in 2017 so it was the C&C
4 other files that were spread by the
Facebook pages
and that other domain unlike the drtc
dns it had Whois information and the
Whois information showed me a name that
I couldn't really get a lot of
information on online but it also had an
email address which again repeated the D
RPC that we see in the hotter website
and looking up this email address I also
saw that it was used to register to
other addresses dexter ly comm and
dexter ly dot space and searching for
dexter ly actually led me to a facebook
profile operated by the attacker
so dexter ly was the current avatar of
the attacker behind this campaign and
the prehistory vs avatar as it turns out
was dr. pc which we've seen in the new
web site address and in the gmail email
that was used for registering them and
this Facebook profile I mean if you've
looked at similar attacks it kind of
follows the pattern of attackers of the
sort
he was basically flexing about all of
the achievements and everything that he
did and all of the systems he managed to
infiltrate and basically sharing panels
of showing successful infections and
victims that he managed to get to run
the application and what was a bit weird
for me at least observing a lot of
similar threats in the regions that
usually those kind of threat actors
would be like oh look look at the credit
cards they managed to steal er look at
the PayPal account and got into and it's
more it's more about bragging in that
sense but this guy was actually sharing
a lot more sensitive information so over
the years I think he managed to infect
thousands of people mostly from Libya
and apparently he also got his hands on
a lot of sensitive information by doing
that so we saw that using this Facebook
profile he also used to share a lot of
financial documents that were shared by
the Libyan embassies and Libyan
government and internal information that
wasn't supposed to reach his hands or
anyone else and he can even see him kind
of getting his hands on communications
between international companies and the
Libyan government as well so this was
really kind of surprising to see that
despite the basic tools he was using
this was very very successful and did a
lot of harm actually and he even shared
some official documents and on his
facebook profile so we can even see that
he got his hands and a couple of copies
of diplomatic passports which is funny
because this the one on the right
actually belongs to the general Marshall
to the guy from the initial Facebook
page
somehow by infecting some guys in device
he got a copy of the diplomatic passport
of this guy and that was crazy and
seeing just the scope of this attack was
again also crazy and we've reported all
of this activity to Facebook so luckily
the dexstar ly profile is down nowadays
all of the pages that were involved are
down and again this guy some of his
activity even back in the day and I
realized since later on was also
uncovered by Trend Micro I think back in
2017 but he that didn't deter him they
still kept at it and this time we took
more strict means in terms of trying to
stop him from doing what he's doing and
they really hope he doesn't go back to
doing that eventually because he he was
also sharing the fact that he received
emails by the FBI letting him know that
they're aware of his malicious activity
but I think as long as he stays within
Libya he's gonna be off the hook but
just hopefully not doing anything
malicious anymore so to conclude this
activity has been going on for years I
think even more than 2004
theme this goes back to way before that
and in the previous profiles that I've
seen also operated by him he was kind of
also active in 2013 and all different in
different hacking activities and he was
using off-the-shelf tools and I think if
you're kind of working in threat
intelligence or in malware analysis and
whatever that makes our job in terms of
attribution a bit harder because if he's
using his own unique code that's kind of
better for us to track his tools and to
know what is going on there and to be
able to tell when he releases new
samples for example but just knowing
that he is using things like spy note or
engineer at mix it makes it a bit harder
and I think looking at the alternative
of identifying this guy simply by his
grammar mistakes and seeing tracking
this activity by his typos was a nice
alternative in this case that would have
been harder if we were just doing this
simply by looking at the malicious
samples so in terms of threat
intelligence techniques this also kind
of provided me at least with a new way
of looking at things and not just
looking at the malicious code but also
sometimes it's more simple than that you
don't only have to rely on the sample
itself and despite the low
sophistication of those things and the
fact that he was using those open-source
tools we can really see the high impact
of these attacks and I think this really
applies to a lot of threats in the
Middle East the fact that they are not a
very sophisticated man there are very
sophisticated ones don't get me wrong
but despite the fact that they're not
very complex we can really still see
them doing very very high like a lot of
damage simply because they know how to
socially engineer their samples they
know how to reach their victims and they
know how to design the bait for the
people that they are targeting so in
this case we really see the investment
of this guy in the usage of those
Facebook pages with thousands of
followers and trying to keep them as
legitimate as possible and succeeding
throughout all of that into reaching
those people and not really by investing
a lot of effort on the technical side so
I would say that and this may be repeats
what Brian said earlier in the day that
you don't really have to have the most
advanced tools for you to have the
severe impact that this campaign had and
that'd be all for me thank you