alright I'm going to talk a little bit
about a side project I've been working
on developing around Dorking mostly you
probably know what it is I'll I'll do a
quick introduction I probably won't use
my entire 30 or 40 minutes that I have
to be for you to drink beer my name is
Philip Breslow i'm currently a security
researcher at recorder future i used to
be a software engineer in linguistics
and then I was a much-hyped data
scientist role for a while so start off
by introducing what dorkiness looking at
a few tools that exist today and the
issues that I see with those then I'll
show door key which is the thing i built
and then i'll discuss some of the future
sort of projects or ways this could
develop Thai food try and cool the
dorking or search engine hacking is
nothing new it's been around for ages it
sort of took off in 2002 when Johnny
long started collecting a little
database of the works as they're called
these clever search terms and we can see
why it's called why it's called a dork
from the original page Google dork an
inept or foolish person has real by
Google and this is what it looked like
way back when this has sort of morphed
into this shiny looking thing exploit DB
I was the google hacking database and
it's it gets new search terms every few
days basically and it's related to
especially when a new vulnerability
comes up people want to find servers
that are vulnerable this is an example
of work so searching for ham dita XL
back door in the title of the page
brings up web shells of a specific kind
and if we click through to these we have
access to that server so since this has
been going on since 2002 why why bother
doing the
I think there's a talk on this every few
years it's still as relevant if not more
relevant we got the internet of things
you know toaster d dos webcams someone
can sneak in and look at your parents
what can I make it everything is online
you get ICS SCADA systems online I'll
show an example this you and then again
nothing has really changed it's still
the same issues people are publicly
posting sites without having login
credentials or the use the default week
credentials so it's still it still
matters so I was looking at trying to
find a good example of this old Dorking
thing a google search technique aided
new york damn hacker in iran you could
think oh that's that's pretty cool or
pretty bad but then again when we look
at when this was published it was a few
months ago so that's that's a bit of a
fail so when most people think dorking
they think google searching or like
normal text search i just wanted to
bring this up just to highlight some of
the issues with these things google has
great advanced search operators most
dorks that you find especially on the
google hacking database as implied by
the name is our game for Google Bing
filters a bunch of dorky results you
can't find SQL files like searching for
the file type extension and as limited
advanced operators on the flip side Bing
has an api google has removed their
search api they only provide one that's
called custom search engine and you can
sort of trick that into searching the
whole web that you get very limited
results i'll talk a little bit more
about what search engines i support here
later some of the existing tools they
all seem to be focused on single-use
there's a lot of pretty you ice and most
projects are dead hopefully this won't
be one of those projects you know
hopefully not and what I wanted for this
is something i did at work which i could
later publish open source and free for
everyone this because i wanted
machine-readable results that i could
set up alerts on for example i want to
be alerted whenever a certain domain is
has popped up in one of these dorks that
means that something is going on for
example for a specific company notable
here search diggity they have a very
nice website with a lot of good
information but the last updates i can
see where from 2013 so I built this
little thing called dorky this it's hard
to read here but it's basically a little
management interface for keeping track
of which dorks you want to run let's
split up into two different components
we have a runner that collects these
dorks from a mongrel database and runs
them and close the results waits a
little bit and then it does it all over
again and then we have the UIL component
that I showed a picture of just now and
in between those two is the mongrel
database that just stores the
information the dorks the results I
built this using Python I like Python I
do it a lot for work I used Mongo
because it's it's free it's he set up
and if you want to do some rapid
development you don't have to specify a
schema or anything you just shove it in
there and Burkes org which is a great
little web application thing for Python
it's what powers flask if you haven't
used it you should really try it
included search engines I i included
google unfortunately since they don't
have an API you will need a thousand
proxies but it works Bing using their
API Google custom search if you have
something specific you want to do as
well as shodhan and if you haven't used
rodin it's it's basically like a
searchable n map that runs across the
web and they collect screenshots and
things from open and rdp port to think
it's very cool you should check it out
if you haven't
so the UI is very simple I didn't I
didn't want to do something very cool
you put in put a query and put a
description you put it in a category you
give it a source you found it somewhere
and then you pick what search and you
wanted to run it from and then it shows
up here at this room a little bit hard
to see here and as soon as you add it
and you have this sort of runner
component going it will pick up that
career next time it runs and it will
execute it and collect the results and
looking at the results this is just in
the UI you just get to see which which
IP in which pork and sort of the header
that came back if you look in the
database it's the whole cached response
from Sheldon and for for example for a
google search it's the URL the sort of
title of the page and then the little
description that comes in your google
search result so for configuration it
talks through a Mongo database that you
need to set up you need you select which
search engines that are active you can
input your API keys for certain sites ok
Google you need to Roxy set up and then
you need some filtering because you
don't get you need to filter out because
a lot of people repost these dorks on
for example blogspot or whatever and
then you'll get noise in your data as I
said some of the issues here our results
are not perfect sometimes there's a lot
of noise there's right limiting you have
to sort of pace yourself and if you use
the api's then there's API costs
involved because if you run all the
dorks from the google hacking database
then you'll run out of money pretty
quickly if you're using baying for
example and one of the biggest issues
and the big reason why i think a lot of
these projects fail is because you need
when the api's are updated or when the
websites are changed you need to update
your approach and I could tell that when
we'll turn off their search api you
could tell a ton of project just
collapsed and then never updated again
so some some of the future things I'd
like to add more search engines github
virustotal hybrid analysis or some ideas
some better logging and error handling I
have been a bit lazy but i'm working on
improving it then adding a pipe to
elasticsearch i think would be cool if
someone wants to set up their own works
the way i'm using this i'm running this
in our production system right now but
I'm piping the results into or or sort
of platform and in there we have
alerting capabilities and stuff like
that so I did not add the output to
elasticsearch myself I figured I'll show
you a little bit of a live demo I'm not
on the on the Wi-Fi so i won't give you
the actual running the dorking but i'll
show you how the UI looks if you want to
if you want to check it out it's I
github.com / recorder future / dorky
it's MIT license and if you have any
questions free salut at gmail com I did
not sign up for this peer list thing I
apologize yes I think I have it running
another real
so this is dorky running on my machine I
have it's not on get up yet but I have a
script that imports the entire google
hacking database into your own local
database so its grapes that website it
puts them in as not enabled to begin
with because you don't want to lose all
your money and in here we can sort of if
we wanted to enable this guy hit it it's
enabled and it will start running next
time it's run the query I showed from
showdown is in here you run some query
sq webcam it gives you a bunch of webcam
results and you can look at the sort of
ugly results in here but it's a ton of
webcams available
and I didn't intend to this to be a long
talk I wanted to keep it very brief
because if you would like to try this
out please go on github start running it
there's no reason for me to stand here
and drone on for 30 minutes about
something quite simple that was it if
anyone has any questions or comments
please yes I they are I mean that's for
for me it's been working out so far it's
I have maybe maybe a gigabyte or
something in the in the production one
and it's working fine yes you mentioned
machine readability towards the
beginning but it's not a command line
tool is the idea that you have that
people would know sir yeah so what would
I use this for is that I have a separate
script that I run the pulse data from
this manga database as soon as new and
then I sort of pushed that into wherever
I want it
no I'm currently pushing it into so what
I'm pushing it into a recorded future
which you guys won't have the option to
do unless you start working at recorded
future you can talk to me afterwards if
you want to work at record a future
anybody else well if not then thank you
quickest talk at bsides what work