so okay next up we have emin rogers from
University of Illinois give him a round
of applause alright so I do
cybersecurity research at the University
of Illinois with a bunch of different
people on this project from Illinois and
Oregon State and Rutgers and power world
and here's some pictures of some of the
key people on the project somehow I got
involved with those guys now Kate was
supposed to be here with me this would
have been her first hacker convention
talk she's done many i triple e type
speaking speaking engagements before she
was really excited about being here her
husband was much more exciting excited
when he crashed his bicycle and he needs
to show the reconstructed or something
so Kate sends her regrets and I'm going
to be responsible for her part 2 which
is all the power stuff so it's going to
be pretty cool but the research project
that we were on it was funded by arpa-e
where at the end of three years and at
the end one of the goals that we had was
we were going to ensure that our
software was going to have impact and in
order to do that I really pushed for
open sourcing the engine that we use for
cyber physical impact analysis and
primarily this was developed for use in
the power grid so the idea being how can
you ensure operational reliability and
understand the impact of you know the
c-word or you know the network attack
surface around a large system that
provides power to many people and you
have more cyber security things than you
have time to take care of it how can you
effectively prioritize those things so
your effort can be directed where it
would have the greatest impact on
reliability of operation because the
problem is very complicated when you
think about you know
there's internet connectivity come into
the corporate network and we've got all
these little field devices and then you
got you know nasty hackers trying to go
into substations and and/or there oh
we're going to come in through the
internet and attack the land so it's
it's a very large complex problem when
you look at how do you put everything
together so that we can look at adding
on to traditional contingency analysis
because planners and electric operations
manually define contingencies like oh
we're going to lose this substation and
we're going to lose this generator and
they're like ecosystems or big things
within the power grid but we want to try
it and then they automatically insert
these things and they sent they simulate
the impact what would happen if you lost
that substation of that generator or
something big but it was always meant to
be this like n minus one criteria where
we lose one substation what's going to
happen and then traditional contingency
analysis has always been that way where
we're going to we're going to plan
everything based around that thing but
the but what happens when you add this
cyber on top where maybe it would be
very you could simultaneously bring down
or provide a denial of service condition
to multiple locations and how would you
plan for that short of yeah we can make
a big giant black out but then there's
like middle ground between that like I
get five things happen at once what is
the contingency for that and previously
we couldn't do any computation with that
but newer more modern hardware has
giving up giving us the capability of
providing for much more fine-grained
infame
about impact and that's what the
research project was all about and
because of the advent of more modern
communications in things like the power
grid you have this idea about the size
of the contingency list can just grow
very large if you look at a thousand a
thousand lines and doing a 10-1 means
you have a thousand different criteria
but you go out to n minus 2 and just
take two things out then you're you're
just getting really big and so what do
you do because when you look at game
theory and there's a lot of game theory
people on our research project they
wanted to compute everything and it got
really really large fast and we're like
what we want to do is come up with a way
to reduce the where we're going to be
calculating and we do that I'm going to
get to it a little bit about which is my
part about we add network attack surface
to reduce the space of computations that
we come up with a ranked list of
contingencies so if you look at like
things like the this is the beginning of
the 2003 black out what the tool can do
is take all of the different physical
components that are inside of a
substation and then we map them map the
cyber and a network of tap surface
around it and we can provide a mapping
so this is like normal and so when
something happens there's a little bit
of a disturbance and then depending on
what the piece of equipment is how long
it takes to clear the fault determines
whether that the thing would cascade
beyond the bound of whatever it might be
and then if something bad happens we all
know that this was probably bad so
modern computing has allowed us instead
of it oh we lose this substation
something bad happens you can actually
go into an industrial facility after
doing some of this inventory working I
will I always
too I want to go in a sense nation and
point at something I go I want to know
you know insisting have an IP address
how is it connected on a network what
would be the impact of this thing work
to be misused and so the project tries
to answer that question and this is kind
of like a preview of what's what you get
ready to see this is what the front end
looks like and what you're able to
download now it was released four hours
ago but sipes of streamlines the
utilities ability to inventory and
analyze cyber physical assets so it
brings out first way if we have to do
work to collect the data from the
individual devices that make the power
grid and then provide a mapping between
the physical device and then its
manifestation in the planning model and
then and it's if it exists its IP
addresses and network attack surface and
as we did the research we came up with
use cases and like the first one a kind
of touched on a little bit with asset
ranking so that is like I've got a
fairly large or a medium sized what
everybody call it I have a sponge of
substations I have ten thousand a
hundred thousand assets do you know
which ones are the top 50 individual
computing devices that are in your
network likely not because planning has
always been I always viewed as being
from the top down so we're going to look
at this substation and we like to say we
do cyber-physical from the bottom up so
we look at all the individual components
in the in the power grid and then rank
those assets and they can actually be
ranked in within like the threshold for
voltage stability which is like 15
minutes because utility will calculate
how they're doing every 15 minutes
typically so your troll federal kind of
looks like this I'll do a demo later I'm
not going to hold on this too long
unless
FML screws up but you can get a lengthy
list of what your top assets are and
then we calculate a cyber cost based on
network availability and vulnerability
scores from the ics-cert database so we
can adjust it and map data to come up
with this score and then there's also
performance index which is related to
what does he what does what's the impact
of the equipment in the on the power
side and then some of the other use
cases that came along as we were doing
this at utilities because we actually
have deployed this software at certain
utilities is this idea about patching so
it attached a lot of things and I want
to know if I only have a limited amount
of time to patch things which things
would get the best benefit of being
patched first so if you're able to
provide a ranked list of all your assets
you know which of the assets you should
patch first and is actually a little box
in the tool it says I just patched this
asset then the tool recalculate the list
of top assets based on the fact that
you've patched certain assets you can
also keep track of which ones are
patched and not patched so hopefully
that will work in the demo not there's a
screenshot of course so the idea is we
have a network attack surface over here
and we can we can map the attacker and I
don't know if I can use the mouse for
the people online but on the left over
here where the attack path and this is
like a standard network attack surface
ton of graph but we also can grab grasp
that into a physical one line diagram so
if the electrical engineer is here
should be able to tell you a lot more
but I know even as a cyber security guy
126 percent is bad so the guy gets in on
that device that line goes to one
hundred twenty six percent and in the
animation that that we actually can run
and I'm probably not going to do it
today it causes a little blackout so the
other thing that's really cool if you
think about it is aggregate exposure so
how many you know Willie's 385
I have in all my stuff because if
there's a vulnerability and a certain
revision level or model has a
vulnerability what happens if the elbow
out at the same time we can actually
model that now so there is a way to just
select or show how many of each
different thing you have and what the
impact would be if those things were to
go down and then this then leads into
another case we got from actually
utility feedback because they wanted to
be able to do cyber incident planning
where they wanted to be able to come up
with more realistic cases of a cyber
incident and then what could they do to
plan to make for a more reliable system
so the idea would be in the blackout you
know there were there were certain this
is the actual 2003 blackout in a power
flow diagram and then if you had a way
to map all the individual components you
could show the where the most important
things were and then the impact of that
event like we should we showed before
and this piece probably have been a lot
better if Kate was here but this is the
transient stability problem where within
five milliseconds if the fault doesn't
clear there's a problem so we want to
take all the individual components and
determine which ones have this 5
millisecond threshold exceeded which
would mean that it would impact devices
around it and that could perhaps get
larger and then and again of course
another this is what you're going to get
in a download and we'll see if the demo
actually works later but so the
aggregate exposure like I said before so
if i wanted to come in and there were
three different things in common so i
can have a multiple pathways coming at
and we can then simulate that no now
again not even being an electrical
engineer 114 142 percent
bad so and then this is a just a power
world flow diagram and an attacker to
threat models an attacker I don't like
the word attack but the academic side
worth I work with love the word attack
so I really tried to remove the word
attack as much as possible hmm what
would I call it instead a day that ends
in Y so the question was how how would I
how would I call the instead of the word
attack what would I use I would say it's
just a day that ends in Y so things
happen and if there's some multiple if
you have something in common amongst
things it's not really a until now that
wasn't really weight effectively model
this and so one of the things that we've
been really working on is how do you
visualize these things because there's a
lot of junk in in this and it's a very
hard problem just in visualization so
actually the first thing is if you go to
this IP address this is actually live
right now you can see what we did was we
took the I Triple E eight bus model and
then modeled all of the protective
relays and everything the distance
relays and you can see a cyber physical
representation of the I Triple E eight
bus model it's actually online this is
using Gabe weaver c PTL and then we did
a talk I did talk with him about this
couple of years ago cpt la cyber
physical topology language and it's in
the plumbing of the engine so it
provides us with ontology so that we can
describe the relationship both from a
cyber perspective and a physical
perspective of individual devices that
make up this system and that kind of
like all works together with with you
have you can use your network software
of your choice because there's a there's
a JSON format
it's a little while and we have planning
software and the engine is what's been
open source today you can put your own
impacts and network attack service and
make your own rank lists and with the
whole idea the goal of the project could
be grid reliability and it's been I
released it I think it was eleven
o'clock this morning after we got the
license attached to the software which I
noticed wasn't there was no license I'm
like on the phone like what wait a
minute maybe we should put a license on
this so it's open source under the ncsa
UIUC licensed license and what we did
was we work to remove the dependency of
any particular piece of commercial
software so I have a slide about that
later the idea is and I think of already
kind of talked about this a little bit
the physical connections and the impact
together are so I've got in the top here
the host may be compromised or line Kate
then line k is at risk and then this is
all manifested back into what is a
protection scheme at the substation and
in which individual device is that risk
and then what would the impact be if
that device were compromised and then
with this critical clearing time we can
determine whether or not it's going to
be an issue because the plan will tell
you if it clears within five
milliseconds I don't care about it so
now let's see what happens and if I
remembered to turn the porn off on nine
because I was it I was waiting in the
speaker room so this is that IP address
thing that I showing that will provide
the slide so that you know what the IP
address was but it's 72 dot whatever
that is it's up and this is actually
hopefully online so this is actually out
on the internet somewhere so you can see
that the visual representations of the
eight bus model you can go online and
look at those by going that IP address
you can get me afterwards and then the
other thing is
is the actual tool which is right here
so when you download sites ax or
armadillo which is what it's called the
release is called armadillo you're going
to get a html5 front-end you need
tornado and Python to run it on your on
your machine and I can go through and
start it but I actually went ahead and
loaded it I could show you later we'll
see how I'm doing on time I think I'm
talking really fast right now so I don't
want to champ starting it right now
because it's all running and it might
screw itself up because it does open up
a port inside your computer because we
connect to like 55 55 so when I click on
sites analysis so if you have multiple
projects you can select those and
there's a folder structure for that and
so I can go in there and select that and
then the little visualization will
appear and I can view the cyber assets
and then we can also view the physical
assets we get to one line diagrams and
then if I start this it kind of looks
like this so now we have a ranked list
of assets in the eight bus model so if i
click on different IP addresses i'll get
the corresponding pass if it's still
working it was working because the
password up there or i can view the
physical that's still working and then
the the cyber connectivity in that
specific location there's also a couple
of other features in the tool that's
been released today and that's let me go
back here
there we go so there's also the other
visualization so we used III for
visualization and that's coming up but
this is the this is going to look really
really small on this video so this is
the eight bus model but if I click on
individual substations I can then get we
have a tree view on the left and then we
can show the both the physical their big
from a planning perspective or one-line
diagram perspective assets and then or
click on individual things and the
network would come up or the network
elements or the cybersecurity the cyber
elements the network attack surface of
individual substations and then there's
also this is another tree view of the
same C PTO based things once we get the
mapping of this relay is this IP address
it serves this function we can tie all
those things together via ontologies and
then look at all of the different
components that make up the different
sub station so i can select any sub
station at random or if you can see that
somebody can pick from the audience and
i can show not if i do that there we go
but same so how about you pick one and
we'll see if it actually works till
somebody how about have a brook okay
there you go so this is a half of rook
substation and then i can look at the
different cyber and physical components
that are in that substation looks better
on a if you have a bigger screen
obviously and then get back here
and then it kind of can get big and
here's where we hit the d3 wall so we
actually have a model that has 300
substations in it and it's about 5,000
devices so this is 5,000 devices and d3
kind of like starts to on itself so
like if you wanted to zoom in it takes
like 30 seconds so I could get all the
way in here but I don't have that much
time even as fast as I'm talking right
now I don't have that much time but so
it's kind of there but going back and
some of the other trees that we used
individualization really helped us put
more information visually on the screen
because one of the things we learned in
the research going into utilities is
that it seemed like we were more
interested in the visualization than the
utility actually is because all they
really wanted was either CSV file or a
list we want the list we want to see a
table and that's really where they
always go back to the you know the home
interface where we just go into not the
right one we go into here and they want
a nice table so they can see their top
assets and this should be working
there we go they want to see their list
of assets and I think if I come down
here and with the video kind of like
maybe see that now I can mark two things
I can do with the engine that are kind
of cool is that you can mark a host is
being patched so that you know which
ones haven't been patched yet just well
utility asked us for this but the other
thing I thought was really cool is I
could actually mark a host is being
compromised and then recalculate the
right path based on that and then you
can also go through and see the
vulnerabilities based on CD score for
each of the individual components that
have IP addresses we tie all that
together and then we can also patch the
mark the vulnerabilities as being
patched in and recalculate the the pass
and then did I forget anything I'll find
out when I go back to this lies I think
there was one more
and yes there's 11 so this is actually
d3 so this is the eighth substation
model and one of the things it's like
okay that looks like some kind of
blended salad so what are you going to
do when you have all of these different
devices and one of the things that we're
working on and we built the trees is
that I could show you all the different
devices but then how does this make
sense you add names do not put names in
these are all traditional visualization
problems which is why we have a blend
between you want a visualization you
have a smaller network that's going to
be fun especially from an open source
perspective because maybe you don't have
5000 devices one of the things that
besides folks as to do is to come up
with a way for I'm not a power guy how
can I use this so the visualizations are
are very mature and stable we've had we
had professional programmers working on
some of this some of the visualizations
and then you can always go back to the
tables because you can get a lot of from
just tables because people understand
either the name of the of the device or
its IP address cyber guys are always
going to look at cyber security people
look at the IP address and know what
we're talking about and then like
operator as long as thats for the name a
little casita name and you can change
these kind of things once you have
everything into a database so i'm going
to go and see if i forgot anything here
i'll need to pick the right slides okay
so here's how you start the tool
so let me see not bad so when you go to
github and download armadillo you're
going to need to be running tornado it's
some guy shaking its head yeah yeah so
then you all you're going to do is and
it's not start tornado it's I think it's
not it doesn't say that it's something
else now so that that's that's wrong it
says start size' it doesn't say start
tornado anymore but then it comes up
just like I showed you in the demo you
click on sipes analysis maybe I should
have looked at these slides before I
tried to demo because I probably would
have done better click select and then a
bus analysis comes up a bunch of stuff
starts to go in the background this is
the engine doing its thing and then you
can go in and look at your ranked list
of contingencies and then here's the the
list of assets and then we have this
like I said the security index is
determined by the cyber cost and the
performance index and you want to
contact any of us will contact
information there's been papers written
on some of the formulas behind the
performance index to decipher costs and
there's more papers being published
towards the end of the year regarding
this research and did that showed you
that there's the tree view maybe it
looks a little bit better in the slide
where you can select out on a different
yard and it shows the connection between
a distance relays this is our attempt it
really better orbiting then we can get
out of d3 because it's so jumbled when
you put a few hundred devices on a small
screen but it's more than just power the
site's the engine and the web front in
there can be used on things other than
the power grid and like I said before it
there is a performance index JSON
template so you can make your own
performance index for
dividual devices and then build your own
network attack surface via that the JSON
provided in the open source and use the
engine and something that's called
offline mode and then you're like well
how do I do that so well The this
is like literally something that was
done last week because I was very
insistent about having a standalone
product that would run without any
proprietary information from commercial
products so Olivier calls it offline
mode so you actually have to type
offline in the command line he wrote
these up we had a Olivier was a he was a
we had him on loan from a Marine
Institute in France he's a Frenchman and
he calls it offline book so now it's
offline mode right now I don't know if
it's going to stay that way but it's
actually in the command line so you
would do run types of that eight bus buh
buh offline and you can also change the
output in CP gen that CSV so that you
can pull your own information in and opa
he's not in America anymore he left last
week and but I thought that I would want
him to be in the talk so that's Olivia
he really induct rated himself into
America while he was here and he was
amazed as of the of the soft drink so
sipes is available github as of 11 this
morning there is the papers involved
with some of them normalization half
analysis that we did at the Illinois
website under iti sites ax and then
codigo is a company that has been formed
to work on servicing the open-source
kind of like with snort or something
like
where you want somebody to come in and
do this and part of the arpa-e project
was path to commercialization they
wanted they want to see the research
have impact so codigo can kind of help
with that and then Kate would have been
happy to be here to talk to you about
this is going to this is her company and
my role at the university is to help
researchers have see their research have
impact and to perhaps have them start
companies and this is the second one
I've done at the University of Illinois
so I think that's it I had plenty of
time for questions who's going to add
chris restaurant I mandiant um so your
model I'm an electrical engineer and I
want a few okay so be gentle I'm a
hacker I'm not a right so I used to work
for aunt Reggie and so I actually know
matt davis that's Kate's we went yeah
he's he's okay yeah but he's not he's
not he's very happy right now yeah yeah
yeah so we went to school together a
tech anyway my question is is I know it
focuses a lot on the relays and things
like that does this project also
included things like rtu substation
artis as a matter of fact it does that
but the idea is you know we can map
impact of anything inside the substation
because with the ontology is that way
the sexy things are the relays and sure
because they have the greatest precision
I need to be I need to understand what's
going to happen five milliseconds within
five milliseconds after something
happens in a relay rtu goes out oh no we
don't have readings from this site the
grids not going to go down his different
different performance index but it can
be included but if you have 10,000
things are going to get towards the
bottom oh yeah we had to do risk ratings
for every type of piece of equipment for
relays I had to do them for Artie use
yeah and I wanted to include cyber at
the time
time but we didn't have very many are to
use on the network so if you have an
older substation with a lot of
electromechanical relays but you have a
modern substation gateway are to you
with IP that would be really good too
yeah well the other thing is is the idea
behind we see this a lot out in the
field too because we've been to a lot of
utilities is that we can model serial or
like non-routable protocols because it's
just a relational map to us a you get to
be to get to see and it's much easier to
model then when we're looking at a
larger utility it has maybe multiple
pathways and you can still map impact on
that but you lose like so I won't have
an nmap there's no IP address so you
have to adjust your cyber score because
it's different like your cyber score
probably the one then because I can get
access for that I own it right exactly
all right thanks good question and would
you be so kind of share with us if you
could the future to write like you know
I guess what's next I mean I see that a
company has been founded I know that I
don't know I there's gonna be a lot you
know you're expecting a lot more paper
to get out and you know that there's a
lot more publication but you know is
this gonna be used I mean is it gonna be
it's just gonna be shopped around to
utilities and power industrial companies
I mean could you share a little bit more
about how you're gonna what the approach
is sure I can do that so I didn't want
this to be a vendor pitch yeah so you
know we are out in wet we've been at
what use the world meeting we're working
closely with planners we're with the big
utility out and what we've actually
modeled the Northwest with this and we
need to transient stability studies and
critical clearing times for some of way
I don't want to miss because I think
this is live but for some of wet but
it's possible to do all of what we just
would need to model it and so we're
actively involved in that kind of thing
on the
side of the fence but this is not a
kadai go talk this is it talking about
the engine we use this engine and and
what other people use it to because some
of the continued research that's going
to be happening is in cyber because we
can formally describe what's going to
happen in physical impact cyber is a
little behind we're about maybe a year
to two years behind inside we can't
formally described cyber the way we can
participa this and there's continued
research on this with some of the folks
that I flash their pictures up earlier
anyway whatever no no but I'm trying to
be very careful about that
right because when we were talking about
what we're going to do with the software
and there was like you know I'd have to
be very careful but when I say now
because this is being recorded but you
know we wanted to be open source because
we wanted to get it out there that makes
it it makes a commercial pathway easier
because anybody else can go out and jump
and grab this software now but we have a
three year head start on you and we know
how to do this and we've broken this
thing a thousand times before the web
front end is very stable you build your
own impact models you can do this stuff
now and what we're really this is also a
call for volunteers this is a new open
source project let's let's make this for
the community the engine is very nice
and I'd like to see people get involved
and so if i can ask a question about how
your cascading impact through the graph
first you maintain two graphs one for
you know reach ability know if you
compromise this to compromise this in
one for something like flowing you know
increases in power as you remove or add
yeah that's like dozen or is it a single
graph structure no it's multiple graphs
so you have the graph for the power
which is very formalized in many
different commercial applications
planning software which ever one you use
and we've built an interface so that if
you don't use power world you use
something else yeah you can write to the
XML and we can take in that impact data
and on the other side like for network
you need to just tell us we need to see
firewall rules or in the format that the
CSV sits in so you can push the two
things together and I've completely
forgotten your question education oh the
graph the graph so so yeah the it's more
than just graphs but the online mode for
example what we do is we can recalculate
what this score is based on both the
power the power grids always changing
what's important in the power grid is
going to change depending on what time
day is yeah because load moves all
around and then your corresponding
whereas the hot spot is going to move on
the cyber side too because these are the
things that are more important okay and
I don't think I answered your question
it explains how you're flowing the
cascading failures through to get impact
by yeah cuz there's a shock towers you
know exceeded if if you had power world
there's a socket that's open in the
engine it talks directly with power
world and then when there's changes
power world does transient stability
analysis and it also does a critical
clearing time on the individual devices
and this is something we literally just
finished two weeks ago so we can we can
provide a critical clearing time in
power world for individual relays now
the attack pass through the are you
modeling attack pass on the attacker
side is it you know they got into this
and with this I can get into this or you
more modeling just if they you know we
know that this is connected to something
an attacker could potentially touch and
therefore if it goes down we see this
and are you modeling failure modes other
than just availability yes so it's a
combination we look at the firewall
configuration so we get a reduced set of
network attack surface from that
availability and then through nmap we
can if you have n map data and we've
done actual and mep scanning and we've
artificially produced in map scanning to
interrogate the us-cert database so
these are the vulnerabilities that might
be on this system so if there is a
vulnerability that matches the software
that's in the system it's going to
percolate up on the list and this is
also something that can be calculated
over a period of time or iteratively is
that iteratively yes and so and then
you're determining when you're
prioritizing assets by likelihood an
impact are you just kind of using some
have 5 by 5 matrix for impact vs
likelihood how are you weighing those
two together to get your single this is
the most important
how do you combine those two orthogonal
vectors in the tool there's a paper you
can read it's it's it's the answer is
longer than I can sure get to right now
but there's and it's also a research
topic you know we make some decisions
about what formulas we use to come up
with these indexes we test them against
the utilities that were going out with
in the real world and we're getting
close and one of the things that I'm
really I'm really happy to release the
software out to the general public is we
want to know how close we are and how we
r how we're calculating both performance
index on the network side and then the
impact and then blending them together
because we started out first using game
theory and that was very empty problem
berryann be problematic and then we went
to depth-first search and we've got a
lot of PhDs on this project lots of
papers were written about this in it but
it all came down to practically how do
you reduce the attack surface so that
it's big enough to calculate but then
it's still interesting because I reduce
the attack surface down to zero then we
can calculate everything season so you
got to find out there's a middle ground
in there somewhere and then the more
people that use this we can find how far
can we take today's electronics because
I think we can get much further now than
we could 20 years ago but no work has
really been done on modernizing this
kind of planning okay thank you that's a
good question thank you so
anybody else so thanks I think that
maybe the electrical engineering part
would have been a little longer if Kate
had actually come and appreciate
everybody's attention and just go out
and get the software and tell us what we
did wrong thank you