good morning everyone happy to see that
at least some of you are here ah so yeah
domains of Grey's just a really bad pun
you don't want to know why so Who am I I
am the complete insane person who came
up with this basic concept Nick here is
the guy who actually made it usable
couldn't it dump with Adam I Nick his in
the program but he didn't submit his bio
until like two weeks after the programs
would printed or something so they can
want to introduce yourself at all no
you're good alright so the basic concept
here that we're working with is your
standard phishing attack so I'm sure if
any one of you opens up your email right
now you'll see something trying this
this is very common you have your basic
idea where someone tries to fish you
they include a link hey you need to
reset your account information or
whatever some pretext in order to get
you to go to their website and fill in
the information that they want to steal
from you this is incredibly incredibly
incredibly common and really it's been
endemic for years and years and years
now I'm sure that everyone knows or
knows of someone who's been victimized
by this particular kind of attack this
is the this is the bog standard vaguely
social engineering vaguely technical
attack and quite frankly it pisses me
off just because there's no reason why
they should still be working it's
incredibly obvious if you take the time
to look but unfortunately most users
don't take the time to look the problem
here is that a training is really
ineffective most of the time I'm sure
that any one of you who have worked in
in military or corporate are very deeply
familiar with the information security
that tells you to evaluate emails and
not just blindly fill things out but
unfortunately well it just doesn't
happen that way now this is your slide
no fine fine he's shy so small and
medium businesses are really heavily
affected by this that the large
enterprises large corpse they tend to
have some resources to at least mitigate
this or people to clean up after it
happens to them small medium businesses
they don't really have the budget for
continual training remedial training
remedial remedial training how many
layers deep do you want to go with that
yeah it's it's just it's horrible it
fishing keeps working and all your red
teamers out there you know this very
well and it seems like nine tenths of
the time when you hear someone who's red
teaming talking about what they did to
get into a given network it starts with
so I fished them and then it's the
Gateway it's it's your gateway hack
except it's not really a hack as it it's
just social engineering obscured
slightly by a little Network happiness
so ultimately fishing keeps working like
I said this pisses me off so let's let's
take a look at some of the existing ways
that we try to counter fishing is that
one's yours
alright some of the usual ways we do it
is male hetero rights we can call out
emails as they come in but yeah we
actually expect people to notice that
and do something about it but often
times they don't we have spam filters
which they partly mitigated but
sometimes especially in SMB if you're
actually running your own spam filter
like it is not the best of situations
you're still getting at these coming
through we have blacklisting which is
for the most part unaffordable for small
businesses it's not the easiest thing to
get running it takes a while yeah and if
you don't really know what's coming
blacklisting doesn't help and then we
have white listing which also hurts it
really hurts because who do you know
you're talking to until you know if if
you ever want to talk to someone other
than your current customers white
listing is really not going to do much
for you yeah so most businesses want to
expand at least a little bit hopefully
so this is one of the common reactions
that we see people get frustrated it's
it's inevitable that people really
really hate how often fishing works and
the time between when you notice even a
good systems administrator when they
notice that fishing is coming in they
end up having to race to block their own
people's access to it and it it's
obvious that this is not just a problem
for your company other people are
getting hurt by this and you know I I'm
dedicated blue team here yes I am the
sworn enemy of all your red team people
even if I do like you socially but
ultimately this there's a very deep
level of frustration on the defensive
side
because it just keeps happening it's
going to keep happening it takes way too
long to get them taken down even if it's
only a couple hours before they're taken
down that's too long people take only a
couple seconds to click and start
entering information that's harm we want
to minimize that so let's let's analyze
how these these fishing campaigns work a
little bit let's take a good solid look
at what kind of system they use what did
they depend on to do their work so we
have logistical requirements a fishing
can't happen without some kind of server
for the victim to get to it's usually a
website it may be co-opted
infrastructure my my three years dead
blog blogspot com or something like that
someone's DC forum or whatever that's
been compromised or they may well just
rent a VPS in Estonia or Latvia or some
other place that doesn't have
extradition with the u.s. bulletproof
hosting in the Netherlands there's a lot
of places you can put this but you need
time and effort to acquire it and you
need some kind of means of running it
because as much as as much as these guys
around the attack this kind of basic
infrastructure makes them kind of
defensive to be well it gives us a way
to attack them you can have them taken
down by legal means or you can have the
AAS blacklisted for routing purposes all
sorts of good things you can do but
ultimately the challenge here is to
figure out there in different they're
not in this just for the lulz usually
they're in this to make money the
credentials they're harvesting gets sold
or used elsewhere and in some fashion
that is profitable to them so if we can
make their expenses go up and if we can
make their profits go down as a result
this harms their business so keep that
in mind a little bit like the drug says
attackers have budgets to that's that's
a real key concept to keep in mind here
so how is it when you get a fish that
your user ends up actually getting to
them so the fish has to hit your mail
server which spam filtering does help
somewhat here ah and the user has to go
and click on the link even though we
tell them not to they still do it so
when the user clicks on the link what
happens here the the browser opens up it
fills in the information from the link
it fetches DNS finds the server goes out
there hey wait a second here it fetches
DNS your users workstation has to
resolve the attackers domain that is
something you control and this is why
password managers for instance password
managers don't get fooled by this
because your typical password manager
here is something that is it's
relatively simple it looks at the
specific page that you're going to and
it looks at its database and says okay I
have this credential entry associated
with this particular page so in this
particular case it's not going to get
fooled now it may look just like your
bank's website it may look exactly pixel
perfect they may even have not put in a
typo but if the domain isn't the same
you're fishing is not going to work on a
password manager
so the problem here though I would love
to have absolutely everyone run password
managers it's a beautiful thing it
solves so many problems but
unfortunately there's a lot of distrust
of them there is a lot of people who are
very very deeply suspicious especially
of the the cloud based ones that they
consider that to be an unacceptable risk
to them now personally I'm of a mind
that the risk that they ameliorate the
risk that they solve is orders of
magnitude larger than the risk from any
individual password manager getting
breached but that's an argument for
another time and what's worse though is
there's a lot of folks out there banks
especially are notorious for this who
make it there that they do their level
best to try and mess with us they they
throw in stupid JavaScript to block
pasting or if you pay something they'll
just immediately delete it and it's if
you if you call them out on this if you
say hey guys you're blocking password
managers they're like yes but it's for
security reasons for security reasons
they they block the thing that keeps
people secure okay so the problem here
is i can't go and control them I can't
control my bank deciding me for security
reasons will just block pasting can't do
that but
what we can control is the DNS on our
end and that's something that that we'll
get into in more depth a little bit
later but the thing to remember is there
are things you can control there are
things you can't and if you really want
to be effective you have to focus on
those that you can now a little
background here I love black lists I
really love black less black lists or my
friend and if you follow me on the
twitters or something you'll see me
talking about this all the time how DNS
blacklisting is a really great adblock
measure just because all these add
domains they're really reasonably well
known and if you want to get rid of
these ads if you want to keep them from
even showing up you can redirect your
local DNS to sinkhole them this gets a
lot of fun it breaks a lot of things and
interestingly enough causes some anti ed
blocking scripts to get upset but
unfortunately blacklisting is reactive
it's expensive to do it's expensive
computationally in some cases but it
just doesn't work until you know that
the threat is there but an interesting
thing about this particular threat early
in the 20th century back around 2002
2003 fishing domains and other related
scam domains they tended to be live for
about a week we've done a lot towards
getting those taken down in the past 15
years and as such these days most of
these fishing domains only live as of
2014 4 24 hours so this gets to the
point where we can practically do
something we've narrowed the window that
there
allowed to operate in and now let's
narrow it a little bit further fishing
is very much a short con they are in it
to win it yes but they only have a
narrow window of opportunity to do so
everyone is trying to get rid of these
guys and they know it and they have
adapted they move faster the whole move
fast and break things thing works really
great for these guys because that that
fits their business model these are not
your your your suave scammers who
infiltrate and and schmooze and
eventually run off with the whole casino
vault these are the hustlers on the
street who are doing more or less a
gentle mugging they are only interested
in interacting with you for as long as
it takes to get your information they're
not invested in this they just want to
grab and dash so keeping that in mind
keeping in mind the very short window of
opportunity that they have to do
anything keeping in mind the pressures
that they're under and keeping in mind
that there are aspects of their workflow
that you control here's the core concept
if you can control your DNS and if you
can keep things that are suspicious from
resolving long enough and fishing stops
working if the if their page gets taken
down or abandoned or otherwise left off
after that 24 hours and you've delayed
resolution on your network for that 24
hours fishing no longer works this is a
way to block their window of opportunity
they can't work with that so and Europe
next year
there are a few prerequisites you're
going to have to actually control your
infrastructure so in your network if
you're loud and dns to resolve just
straight through to the internet it's
probably not the best thing what we did
is we wrote a small program that sits
there in between your actual dns
resolver and looks at the time window
when things were requested basically you
want everything to go through it it's
probably the easiest way just egress
filtering to what's it egress filtering
yeah 53 needs to be filtered out bound
because if you can't let things just
hang out going out to the Internet by
themselves funny little anecdote a
particular client I was working with had
not yet implemented egress filtering
they found out that their sprinkler
controller was requesting DNS from
Russia so that's that's not usually what
you want for a sprinkler controller
unless it's know that really heavy sure
noble water yeah anyway stand on network
controls you want to put the gray Lister
in front of your DNS you really want to
make sure everything resolves through
that
this is definitely a proof of concept
yeah I would not run in production yet
but uh yeah we have a proof concept that
runs great listing with blacklisting
support by listing support basically
what we've done is we you point your dns
resolution to it and if we don't know
what it is we're just going to point
that i guess a predefined 9p yeah you
can configure it we're defaulting to
local house just because that's the
stupidest and laziest way to do it but
if you have for instance some kind of
internal infrastructure that you would
like to use in cases where you'd like
for instance to interface with the help
desk or what have you you could easily
point it to a local server on which you
have some kind of landing page that will
accept whatever and say hey this has
been great listed talk to your help desk
and also let's keep in mind that this
being a proof of concept these things do
evolve and change over time it is
something that needs extensive
baselining in order to work because as
you found out what Google Authenticator
had issues with it because it flips
through a whole bunch of domains during
its request process baselining it is
something that is either you're going to
have to just keep on making requests or
if you wanted you could for instance
throw a spanner a mirror port off of
some local network device or just
iptables with a tee and throw your your
DNS traffic over to it for a day or two
before you actually put this in line and
that would enable it to baseline your
network into its its database further
you're going to want to populate the
whitelist with your local domain because
the nature of this is such that we want
to
resolve any white listed entries
immediately without having to go through
the trouble of evaluating whether we've
seen it before so whitelist blacklist
grey list whitelist your local stuff any
people you know are good blacklist if
you really don't want to see something
will just reject it great listing oh
that's where we're doing other fun
things yep yeah basically if you can
monitor your stuff and put it in their
first kind of pre warmuth then
everything will run a little bit better
we do have drawbacks though as mentioned
earlier you actually have to run
everything through it if everybody is
resolving their own dns who knows what's
going on you have to have one
centralized point for it and yeah as
mentioned some of the single sign-on
stuff sometimes breaks because they push
you through a couple different domains
to get that working but pretty warming
it allows that to be mitigated once up
should fingers crossed once all the
domains are populated into the grey list
and they've aged enough to be allowed it
tends to work out really well and as it
happens we've set a default blackout
date of what was 180 hours sounds about
right it is seven days essentially so if
you've hit it within the last seven days
it continues to persist within the grey
list that's the basic notion so if it is
something you keep using then it will
stay live if you stop using it if for
instance you were associating with a
given company that company goes out of
business then after seven days or so
after you stop going to that company's
website it stopped it falls out of the
grey list which is pretty handy because
there have been instances where
companies have gone out of business and
someone else has grabbed the domain
after it expired use the now-familiar
domain that's probably still
white listed in a lot of places and
proceeded to fish people for all sorts
of gain it's a fun attack also there's
the greatest part that you know we
actually are doing yes after 24 hours i
believe by default is when we actually
resolve things right there's the initial
gray out period of 24 hours we're in the
first 24 hours it's going to resolve
locally or not resolve it all depends on
how you want to set it up and that that
24 hours to seven days window is is
essentially the active window and as
mentioned if you keep going there it's
going to keep essentially sliding that
active window to seven days in the
future yet and then probably the worst
thing we've noticed in testing things
like reddit are just really going to
break because you're just popping up
different domains all the time and most
business users are only going to be
visiting a handful of domains the time
though I mean you're for business for
business yes if they're if they're
surfing reddit on business networks well
maybe they deserve a little pain so as
it happens will expand this a little bit
now because other things break because
of this some of them usefully botnet C&C
is one of those hilarious things I'm
sure you're all familiar at this point
with all those love of lovely domain
generation algorithms all the fancy
botnets use these days I where in order
to keep their CNC agile their command
and control they can't keep their CNC
stain on one domain everyone is
hammering it trying to get rid of them
through legal means or otherwise so they
dodge around a lot but that's an
opportunity for us because since they're
flipping through domain names at a rate
that's entirely too fast for for
blacklisting
this means that their domains don't
persist long enough for a great list to
allow them so botnet C&C is going to
stop being effective if your network is
protected in this fashion I so that it
gives some interesting second order side
effects and there's the type of
squatting is another one I don't know if
you all recall but there's there's that
lovely controversy that came up recently
where someone went and typos squatted a
bunch of code repo domains and proceeded
to the thing that was controversial was
that he went and put a generic script in
there that popped an error when you
downloaded that script so typo squatting
works because people people don't always
enter in the correct domain but as with
the as mentioned earlier with the
password managers the machines a little
bit dumb the machine just gives what
it's supposed to give and we can take
advantage of that so if you fat finger
github or whatever then it's not going
to be effective it will resolve locally
you'll notice your script breaks and
happiness and Sue's I think the best
ones were that you can't actually get
the cryptolocker key because it won't
resolve that one's fun and actually that
fits into the next thing this is a slide
that still garion passed me from a
presentation I think it was trend micro
down in Australia was giving a couple
weeks ago the lines the horrible lines
are mine that's not their fault but
their analysis of ransomware delivery
shows some interesting ways in which you
can control whether or not these things
succeed so obviously
with the malicious URL if you can't
visit the URL immediately generally a
fishing tie back attack then that's
going to stop the lovely downloaders
because you know apparently we need
JavaScript and email these days which i
think is a terrible mistake and should
never have been implemented but then
again I'm a boring person I those lovely
JavaScript downloaders in outlook in the
preview pane and all that kind of other
happiness won't resolve and the attacks
not going to work likewise if someone
does get full on ransomware like you
said it can't communicate back to the
mothership it's not going to be able to
manage the full handshake now there are
a few variants these days that use a
generic key but because these these
ransomware authors are lazy as well they
have shared their generic key for any
system that does not resolve the command
and control system which there's another
weakness there's something for you to
exploit so in a way this this is this is
kind of interesting how many second
order effects were getting out of this
grey listing thing and there's a lot of
other areas that we could work with this
is just a very basic a admittedly the is
simplistic a concept we're working with
but the generalized approach is by
controlling your infrastructure you can
diffuse a lot of attacks you have to
consent to being attacked I mean if you
never hook up your computer to the
network no network based attacks going
to work but you have to do that you have
to cook up the computer to a network to
actually do business so we get
trade-offs so
if you do this kind of control you're
allowing yourself to dictate to the
attacker under what conditions they are
allowed to engage and that there that is
is a very strong defensive measure
because now the attacker has to put a
lot more time and effort into attacking
you than they would otherwise they can't
use the low bars they can't use the
low-hanging fruit they have to put in
extra effort and that alone dissuade
some of them the others who are actually
dedicated to attacking you are forced to
use more sophisticated methods they'll
have to figure out some way to get
around the gray listing on your end
there are a couple of obvious things
some of which we are addressing naked
eye peas for instance you're going to
have to make sure you've got squid or
something filtering those out there's a
fun little regular expression the horror
thing that allows you to do that but
dictating the pace of the attack means
that you have more time to respond to
the attack you can take more measures
and something which I didn't include on
the slides but is definitely in there
logging we have the provision to write
logs that tell you what is going on if
you see in your logs a whole bunch of
initial gray listed attempts by a whole
bunch of computers on your network you
know something's weird if you see that a
whole bunch of computers belonging to
the finance department are suddenly
hitting a great listed entry it is
highly likely they're being fish trying
to get your bank account credentials
that kind of thing likewise spearfishing
of your executives that's going to show
up in the logs so we have the logs
available and it breaks them up as to
whether or not it's a loud grey list of
forbidden grey list blacklist or white
list so you have that
visibility into what's going on in to
your network which is a lovely tool I
don't know if you've ever tried to
analyze dns logs from Active Directory
before but it's not very easy it takes a
lot of time and effort and its really
annoying so and I guess I've been
speaking a little quickly because we're
all ready to the payoff here's a repo
here's a tool for you I it's very
differently proof of concept and we
would like a whole lot of feedback we
want people to try this out on their
networks we want to see how well this
performs in real life and if you want to
give us some contributions to make this
work better please I'm a terrible coder
he's much better than I am definitely I
fix it up as much as I could so he took
my horrible nasty awful frankly awful
proof of concept and and made it into
something vaguely acceptable sorry for
the handicapped and we would really like
to see this go out into the world where
it's open source feel free to take it
and use it as you will I feel free to
adapt it to other things personally I
would like to see integrated into
something like pfsense or other similar
distributions of that sort because it
would work well within that kind of
sweet and if you have any suggestions on
how to improve this how to make it work
better I am all ears I am more than
happy to take your contributions to take
your criticism to take any suggestions
and see what we can do about making this
better I'm actually just curious what
happens when are you running it on a
foal yeah we'd like to see bigger net
when either of us has a real big network
to play with so seeing how well this
scales is going to be an interesting
interesting challenge so there's your
basic concept and if any of you have any
questions we'd love to hear him
latency so that's that's a killer
question right there I met a little bit
and it's pretty much the resolution of
the one machine and then the next one so
if you're doing resolv.conf which is the
default I think it's late it's whatever
pretty much your network latency is
basically doubled because it's going to
go out and try and grab the next next
response so it's more in the order of
milliseconds than minutes yeah well I
mean if it's great list and it's going
to be morally well yes if it's great
list it's going to be a day but ok so
for some networks blocking dns on my
break a lot of stuff so what about the
idea of using dns master so kind of
transparent dms proxy to filter all the
requests through the rails that is so
this is essentially a DNS proxy in and
of itself it's it's a very simplistic
one and it's really more of a filter
than anything else but yeah it's we're
not looking to block all dns outbound
fun waiting to do it in DNS mask so and
Dina's mastin let us do it so yeah
here's how we're doing it leverage
responsible policies own fine so why
if we don't have it in our lists then
we're just going to result in to bind to
pretty much for the first part of that
but you've dug by the weaknesses and
stuff yeah when you talk about volume
and performance and scaling our art RBZ
we seen is a really good crutch to rely
on vc networks that resolved you know
millions of the middle of a shock to you
rpz might take five to ten percent it at
a time but you can have a million
domains in you're blacklisted but if if
I I took a small look at that I kind of
got rid of it afterwards because it
looked like it was just a blacklisting
thing no yeah it didn't look like it fit
the problem when I was doing the
research so I could be wrong this could
be something that a clever bind
configuration could well solve but hey
let's let's try it out anyway any other
questions no well I want to thank you
all for being here thank you for hearing
me lab away for a little shorter than I
was scheduled I guess up go ahead
that was that was not a condemnation of
Estonia I was just looking through
Eastern European countries in my head
and that was one of the ones that came
up my my my apologies if I offended the
Estonian community but I'm sure it's a
lovely country I've just never been
there all right anyway my thanks to all
of you for being here and for listening
to me blab on and on my thanks to all of
you who i harassed into coming here and
who actually did and if you want to find
me on the twitter you can find me at
munim if you want to talk to him you're
probably going to have to find me first
because he doesn't hang out there good
luck good luck I am on the pier list
deal so if you want to go to our lovely
post convention discussion sponsored
person that peer list you'll be able to
find me there and we can continue the
conversation there or you can always
catch me after the talk and I will be
wandering around although if you are not
scared by my horrifying socks then you
probably should be it's great to see you
all and thank you for coming
ok