okay so next up we have Gabriel Bassett
and Anastasia atanasov from verizon
there on the dbi our team so put your
hands together okay so we're not going
to be talking about the DVI our report
in fact we're not even be talking about
the data in the DB I report this is all
going to be about the process it goes in
to the data so that the data janitor
work right it's like eighty percent of
the data scientists work is you know
cleaning and preparing the data and the
other twenty percent is complaining
about how the data isn't clean enough
and so if by the way I'm going to
apologize ahead of time this is a really
high content per minute talk it's very
dense and frankly the slides are not
that good they're kind of boring there's
just a lot of words don't look at them
we're much better to look at like we're
not hard on the eyes so look at us
listen to us it's a lot better and so
the reason we wanted to do this top is
kind of threefold first this is not
something that people normally talk
about like we talked about the models we
created the cool things and how well
they did we don't talk about all the
process we did to get the data where it
needs to be second we wanted to help
happy will understand how we got to the
number so that when you read the DVI are
whatever import you can look at that
number and understand the process that
went into getting to that number and
finally for those people who you know
are new to data science we wanted to
kind of give them an exhibit an idea of
here's what happens in reality with data
sciences here's what they spend all
their time on data wats how they clean
in the entire process behind it and so
this is this is really its agenda but
it's also the data flow it's what the
prop the process our data goes through
and we're not going to really talk about
how we store the data you think we're
not going to talk about how we store the
data but we are we started a git repo
and it just kind of lives there and so
unless we mentioned otherwise that's
where all the stuff is happening
and so like other skip the formula stuff
I'm the mad scientist I'm Anastasia
atanasoff I'm a data scientist I have
background in security and pure and
applied mathematics I one of the
co-authors of the report and then I do
exploratory and statistical analysis on
the data yeah i guess i should point out
i am not at a station of gabriel in case
there was any to us and so talking about
the report if you aren't familiar with
it it's a report on like a hundred
thousand incidents that happen each year
and you know the goal is for it to be
data-driven we want it to be done to
academic rigor but we'd give it a really
cheeky voice so that it's actually fun
to read because it's a report and
reports on a fun to review and try again
that's why okay you know you told me
before it was on so well I guess I would
I wasn't monitor off switches okay
should I go back now I'm not going to go
back I'm not doing it so okay so you
know the first thing we kind of think
about is what's data right and the clear
way to answer that is to google it and
so I think this is kind of what we know
data to be it's it's something that's
solid it's unchanging it looks the same
from every single angle by the way do
you know you can buy a ball of Onyx on
ebay for five bucks and get delivered
from China in like three days like
that's impressive i thought it was i was
like looking for a ball and i thought
was gonna get like some concrete thing
and like I got this ball of Onyx I feel
like I probably stole it from some
ancient uh you know museum or something
and so you know that's kind of what we
we know like that's the definition that
we know but reality is we this is what
we feel data is like is it's a puzzle
piece and when we look at we don't
really know where it fits or you know
what it means but but we're confident
that if we analyze it and figure out its
place in the puzzle we can put this
together and come up with a picture that
really conveys some knowledge now
unfortunately this is what data looks
like
this is the floor of my record I mean
not my rec room it's my kids well no
it's actually both we share the rec room
some of these are my toys and so when we
analyze data its reality is a bunch of
pieces that don't actually fit together
like they're not designed to easily
connect and so part of our job is to
make the pieces fit together also they
can fit together in many ways right with
a puzzle only fits together one way you
only get one picture out of it you know
if you're playing with duplos you can
build anything you want you can build a
car or a boat or car boat you can come
up with a ever picture you want and so
the reason we need to talk about our
methodology talk about our process is so
that when we put the pieces together
into a picture we do it in a repeatable
verifiable maintainable manner and
preferably move from a manual process
where we can introduce heirs to an
automated process and so the first step
is getting in preparing the day I'm
going to hand it over to Anna to do that
section all right so when we get the
data we always look for a very robust
and diverse data set so we make
continuous effort to recruit partners
from all over the world with various
focuses and we also want to maintain a
good working relationship with current
partners from year to year so these
different focuses of course introduce
some sort of bias as bias is inherent in
any kind of research it's not
dichotomous so it could occur in any
phase of research whether it be planning
data collection analysis or reporting
because it's independent of sample size
and variance you do have to care about
random error as well so it's always a
good idea to identify the different
types of bias that you may encounter
during your research such a selection
bias detection exclusion bias or even
observer bias so we consider the
bias-variance trade-off and then with
random error that's when it's a good
idea to start looking into hypothesis
testing and we look into our confidence
intervals so some potential partners may
not meet our data standards so this is
where we will review and assist in their
data collection methods if knee
be also every partner stores that our
data in their own way so what we do is
we provide them with the standard excel
file for them to use or we give them a
web form for them to enter their data
into and then we take the various you
know xls CSV text file or whatever and
we hand convert it into standard excel
in order to maintain consistency so for
those cases when we receive non-standard
source data what we do is we build
mappings / partner so we take their
enumerations and we map them to ours and
we reuse these mappings each year and
then also to complete some of those
mappings we actually have to hand code
various features such as adding an aches
codes for industries and do any kind of
necessary conversion such as timestamps
in order to maintain that consistency so
many times data is missing complimentary
encodings so we either manually edit or
we use heuristic rules using a script
for example if you have an incident or
record that has malware that vector that
web app and the record the rules will
also add an asset assets that web app
into that record in order to help
complete the data if there is missing
data we contact the partner see if they
can provide it if not we automatically
add in the required field as we put
unknown in that required field also
because data is anonymize we do add data
to account for traceability so for
example there are fields that the
partner does not provide but we add in
such as DB ireo source or master ID in
order to help with that traceability
sometimes we have to remove things from
raw data for example we look at the
source data and we have to ensure that
it's actually deemed an incident how we
define an incident is that it is a
security event that compromises the
confidentiality integrity and
availability of an asset so we don't
include things that are not compromised
there's no impact or if it's just
informational we also remove unintended
duplication for those cases where a
where an incident can be represent to
multiple times in the raw data we also
remove already aggregated data for
example we get a text file and it just
has counts by industry or accounts by
attack type or accounts by data type
it's very difficult to make end of
correlations with the aggregated data
because we don't have access to the
individual incidents so we make a habit
of reaching out to our partners and
requesting that they don't provide
aggregated data and the actual
individual records so for storing data
we have three main directories where we
have our source data first best data and
reviewed data for a source data this is
our original unchanged raw data we never
delete it and we always keep copies for
each iteration we have our first past
data which is where we just put the data
into the DB ir format so our collection
well I'll get into that later so the
data is examined and then is prepared
for import and then for review data we
just take that first pass data we review
it for completeness and then it's ready
for import so typically we have a couple
members of the team that look at the
review data to make sure that it's
consistent from this year compared to
previous years and that we're actually
working off the same dataset next we
convert the data into JSON which is what
our schema is built upon so we use CSVs
we don't have to play around with
worksheets we don't have to play around
with programming language parsers or
anything like that we use import scripts
to convert input CSV to JSON so each CSV
is unique and it requires its own import
script overall we have three different
Python conversion scripts to import
those formats the problem with these
scripts is that they've been written by
multiple authors in the past so we have
run into consistency challenges where
it's sometimes hard to maintain so one
solution that we implemented was that we
actually module eyes those import
scripts we remove common portions to
separate modules using heuristic rules
and then we have a single control script
that we where we import all the modules
and then run the actual conversion
process ok I get picturing do you like
the animation it took me a long time to
do that I think it's very good it's the
only one in the chart like I promised I
didn't like animate from here on out
it's all animations so no we don't need
to talk a whole lot about the schema
right because we're not going to be
talking about the data but what we do
need to understand about the schema is
what it
means for the structure of the data and
so we need a schema that could bring in
both structured and unstructured data
right because we have data out of Sims
there's very structured tabular data but
we also have case reports they have to
be coded up and so our schema is a JSON
schema which is actually like a literal
thing you know it's there's a standard
for JSON schemas and what it allows us
to do is get a hierarchical structure
for our data and the problem is this
introduces a couple things that later on
we're going to have to count for the
first is the hierarchical nature so if
in normal we have like an action right
now actually could be hacking but we
have varieties of hacking so action
hacking variety sequel injection action
hacking variety cross-site scripting
action hacking variety use of stolen
credentials and so we need to be able to
capture we're capturing at multiple
levels of the hierarchy and that's going
to cause us parsing problems later on
that we know how to solve because I
wouldn't tell you about it if I
consultant knocking the other problem we
have is that it creates multinomial data
non-exclusive multinomial data in fact
so that normally what you have is you'd
have a feature and that feature would
have a set of values that can take on
well our features can be multiple values
at the same time action hacking variety
can be cross-site scripting at the same
time as its sequel injection at the same
time its use of stolen credentials and
the hierarchy the JSON schema is fine it
knows how to handle that but again as we
get into parsing we'll see how we have
to accommodate that those challenges and
so of word about kind of the schema the
technical realities of it so the scheme
itself it was good but we realized there
was some fields we wanted for debe ir
and then there were other fields that we
wanted for our open dataset vcd be and
then there were some fields that really
you know we're just exclusive to those
two things so the community schema
didn't have that so now we're up to
three schemas and by the way each schema
isn't really represented by a single
file it takes multiple files to
represent it because the parsing scripts
use different
different pieces of the schema and so
now we've got five files / three types
and of course you know it's not a static
thing we change it over time so now
there's iterations of it so now we have
five files by three schemas by multiple
iterations and you know it turns out
that if you take that and you store it
in a single repository under the same
name and just hope that people
understand which directories are which
you don't know what the hell is what and
so instead we say let's go find a better
way to do that and so we've broken it
out by the repositories at the schemas
liban so our DB I our version of the
schema lives in our DB I our repository
various community the sea lives in the
various repository and now we have a
very clearly defined set of files and
what they do and what they're used for
and that's defined in the repository
with them and instead of adding
directories within the repository for
the different iterations we just iterate
the entire repository so we have good
traceability and these are things that
are obvious they're clear no one would
ever make these mistakes right except us
you know last year now the next fun
thing about this is the reality is
there's there's the schema and then
there's like the conversion script and
then there's the input file and the
theory is that the input file will be
perfectly parsed by the conversion
script which will perfectly generate the
schema the reality is that physics does
not require the same fields being each
one of those right it's not like
magically because you said it was that
way that's what happens what happens is
that you have this and it all agrees the
first time someone writes it but then
someone over here on the input file
decides that they want you know a couple
more enumerations and so they put them
in there but they don't tell the guy who
wrote the import script and so now it's
here and maybe they even put it in the
schema so the schema had something but
no one actually bothered to come back
and tell the guys that wrote these two
things to put it in there or they
thought they were partisan it here but
someone commented that line of code out
because it was really weird and they
didn't understand it and all this sudden
over a couple years these things become
inconsistent so we spent a lot of time
the summer going back and making them
consistent and the reality was the the
issues are not in any of the major or
we're not
the major places they remind things that
really had low coverage enumeration wise
but this is one of those challenges we
run into is you have to have a plan for
how you're going to keep all of those
consistent and so the next step once
you've gone through that you've you know
parse the day on the schema net now you
want to validate right because you want
to trust but you want to verify and we
get a different thing anomalies we get
kind of missing values or typos or the
most common sometimes there's always one
file that just that you look at and
you're like how could any of our tools
have outputted that raw data like that
is not physically possible so you end up
like spending hours going to fixing that
one up and like Anna said we have
heuristic rules that were applying we
want to double-check those heuristic
rules and so the validation script
checks the heuristics it also checks the
business logic we use NYX codes for
industries we want to check that even
though that's a six digit or a five
digit number it's one of the valid codes
because not all numbers are valid and so
the mott the validation script does that
and this is another plow place where we
ran into an interesting technical
challenge because it turns out
validating you know 100,000 records
isn't always fast and our Python script
ran really really slow at it and so
we're like you know what we can do this
what will turn it into no jasm will
validate and nodejs and that works it
was fast but at a huge amount of
technical overhead because it added an
entirely new tool chain to a process and
when you add that one it makes scripting
a lot worse because now you're calling
no.js from Python and on top of that you
tell your team members hey you know do
you want install node.js and they go no
you know and so they're like you run it
and so now you're the only person who
gets to run it we fixed that we went
back and looked at the Python code
figured out now the Python is actually
faster than nodejs was but better we
convinced condensed it down to a more
maintainable product and in fact because
it's all Python we can import the
validation script and we can run that
along with the import script so it's a
single step process and so of course if
we're validating that kind of implies
that if we find anything we have to
revalidate re-import
fact we also get a lot of new data you
know partners give us data over time you
know they give us this set and they go
well we got some more and the key Nettie
and it turns out that if you have 40
partners providing an incident data we
had 70 partners for years so of them
provide incident data and you have to do
these iterations multiple times it's a
really great opportunity to look for
speed because I'm the one that has to do
this and you know it turns out we had it
down to four steps last year and but
every hour I had to come back to my
computer type in some line of code it
hit the button and leave for an hour and
it turns out when you do that four times
in an hour each step it takes four hours
to go through each freakin iteration
it's my time no and you can't like have
a beer while you're doing that and so
the team like finishes up the coding it
like five o'clock they're like great
Gabe we're ready for you to start
emporia and like nine o'clock I can
finally have my frickin beer and I don't
want to have my beer earlier than that
and so this year we're bringing into a
more push button style we're keeping
state in the system so that we can just
hit it button it will realize okay these
are the files that change those are the
ones that need to be re-imported
revalidated it will rerun that assuming
it gets no validation errors it will
tell us if it gets them will let us know
and that way we've done in it gives us
speed it gets his consistency gets us
repeatability in fact it lets us we be
parallelized not paralyze us now so that
each individual partner coming in gets
its own process and we're running five
or ten processes at the same time which
makes this so much faster and so now
we've got a hundred thousand JSON
records right and the way we analyze
these as we print everyone out and then
we put them in front of a camera and
then we just flip them really quick and
we look for what we do is we put them in
our that the whole picture thing isn't
happening so who here is used are ya
couples okay so our likes tables right
it likes tabular data does our like JSON
know our doesn't like JSON it will work
with it but it's not what it's designed
for and so now we need to cram a tree a
hierarchical structure into a data frame
and this is where we start to run in
those problems with the hierarchical
nature and the multinomial non-exclusive
multinomial structure the data and so
the way we handle this is we make every
leaf in the JSON schema its own column
so there is a column for action hacking
variety cross-site scripting and it's a
boolean column it's true or false and so
every record that has its true not is
false and we have another column for
action hacking variety sequel injection
another one for lost and stolen assets
and so now we've solved our the problem
of storing our non-exclusive multinomial
data but that doesn't solve the
hierarchical problem and so we're going
to have to add in some surrogate columns
to deal with that so we're going to have
to add in a column for action hacking
and the way we're going to fill that in
is anything that has a variety of action
hacking is going to have action hacking
is true as well and so now we've
accounted for our hierarchical data but
again and that one now is pretty easy to
parse it doesn't have the parsing
problems that the non-exclusive data has
say now a final thing is like this is
all your current data set you like you
did all this process you know you
brought in your hundred thousand records
but we don't want to just know about
what happened today we want to know what
happen last year and what happened the
year before and so it's important to
keep your data in the same format from
prior years and keep it someplace
accessible so that when you import
you're not just importing your current
data set your also importing those
historic ones and you need to be able to
impress oh if i use scheme aversion to
today and last year i use schema version
1 i need some way to take those other
you know 200,000 records and bring them
up to date when this is all
straightforward stuff it's all easy but
it's all things to think about if you
don't think about them you run into them
when you try to do the process and so
once we've got it all into the data
frame and nice into a place to analyze
it it's time to start exploring it i'll
head over to anna to do that so we've
made the exploration process
more explained with the audio I think
I'm louder than you are possibly hello
out there okay so we made the
exploration process more efficient by
actually pre generating a lot of the
more common exploratory analysis we auto
generate three reports where we slice
and dice the data in different ways by
the way we use knitter which is an R
markdown language for reporting so what
how we slice and dice the data is that
we look at the overall summary we look
at trends over time and then also any
significant changes since the previous
year the reason why we look at the very
it look at it from different
perspectives is that we don't always
know if the features value or its trend
over time is actually going to be more
interesting and then also with these
reports we actually run them twice so we
run it for incidents and then breaches
as well we also run these reports for
the overall data set and then also
subsets so this includes patterns
industries or partners so overall we are
working around there's a probably total
around 8,500 figures generated in total
and this is another place by the way
where we paralyze so these reports take
a long time to run because there's so
much data in them and so we end up
running you know five or ten reports at
the same time as well in our core flow
for exploring the data we also don't
wait until the data is complete to start
doing the actual exploratory analysis we
can already gained insight before the
data is complete and then we also start
the exploratory analysis early because
it helps us to find any kind of
anomalies that we may need to go back to
the raw data or the source so we run
these reports early and we run them
often also as a note it's an easy
mistake to only look at your current
version of of your data Gabe and I make
it a habit to actually explore the data
frame manually because sometimes we may
be able to gain insight that the pre
generated pre-generated reports don't
capture and the key thing is to always
go back to your raw data so our main
objective is to make novel findings to
start developing our hypotheses
these hypotheses help us to decide all
right what do we actually need to talk
about in the report we look for things
that are big that have changed
significantly between years things that
are commonly seen together and things
that we've you know we've seen patterns
remember they're almost predictable we
also want to take care to see what's
unexpected and what may cause that so
it's also not enough to actually find
something that's novel we have to answer
the question okay why why is it relevant
so this is where we put the finding into
some sort of context so first we have to
see is the finding actually true or do
we need to fix something in the source
data or the import process we use tools
such as Association rules to help to
answer the question of why a finding is
relevant so these association rules show
us how enumerations relate to other
features and what had occurred most
pertaining to the novel finding so we
use some key attributes for association
rules such as support confidence and
lift and then we also look at the
distribution of a feature with and
without an enumeration for example if we
want to look at action we will look at
the distribution with actor internal
excluded as well as not actor dot
internal so we not we end up looking at
the entire distribution and seeing how
it shifts and we don't look at just one
enumeration but actually is set we not
only do we look at incident data we also
look at non incident data it helps to
answer the question of why key finding
is relevant and it also helps to put our
incident and breach data into some sort
of context so non incident data is not
as refined as incident data we may not
necessarily you know get what we need or
want from the partner there's no
standard schema it takes a lot of time
to do exploratory analysis because
that's all manual for an incident data
and then we make sure to communicate
with a partner to make any kind of
clarifications or maybe they'll be able
to provide some additional data to us
they all the other nice thing about not
incident data is that we can correlate
findings across multiple data sets so
say partner sends us men
we're data where and we maybe find
something that's interesting or our key
finding what we actually do is we
collect multiple data sets and then
we're able to actually increase our
sample size which decreases a random
error and we're able to verify those key
findings and then not incident data
grows quickly and it's quite big so what
we use is 32 or 64 gigs of ram and an
SSD which is very sufficient so we
didn't spin up any spark cluster or
anything and we also spun up an AZ to
share our data files this really helps
to ensure consistency so if Gabe
generates a stat and I validate it we're
actually working off the reclaimed
version which saves a lot of time so
then from exploring we actually have to
start thinking you know go moving into
the writing phase so first we have to
decide what actually constitutes the
data set not all records are made the
same some records have a lot of unknowns
in the required fields so what we do is
we score all the records for complexity
and then we discard all those records
that are below a certain threshold so
today we we have our threshold is set to
7 enumerations and this helps us to
answer ok what actually encompasses the
data set because the goal is that we
want to represent all legitimate data
the data set will end up being a
combination of south of subsets of the
full data corpus so for example in 2016
we had over 300,000 records but the data
set actually ended up being a little
over 230,000 records so after removing
those low complexity records the next
thing is to identify and review all the
major subsets of the data so this is
normally in the several hundred breaches
to several thousand incidents for
example in 2016 our major subsets of the
data was dried X and web app attacks so
we have to understand what causes those
major subsets and the data and we need
to consider several things so first so
the limited number of sources report a
lot of common low fidelity incidents
which was reflected in web app attacks
did a limited number of sources have a
unique view that added a lot of
high-quality incidents and this was
reflected in dry decks and then finally
did something unique happen this year
that made something stand out across
sources and this is where actually
started getting into arm into our
patterns where we see the same types of
attacks happening over and over so then
we have to answer the question okay how
do how do these major subsets affect the
overall data set do does it look like
they don't affect it at all do they skew
it in a way do they eclipse it entirely
so I have to decide on how to handle
these first we analyze the subset as
part of the overall data set and then we
just caveat skew which is what we did
with dried X in our report we could also
analyze the data set separately which is
what we did for web app attacks and then
we could also do both which is where we
start getting into our patterns so
overall before writing we need to work
off a single subset of the data this is
our subset embarrass and by at this
point we've decided what to include and
exclude from the data set we're also
looking at approaches of accommodating
for skewness specifically you can reduce
skewness by applying transformation so
your plates a variable with a function
of that variable so if you want to
reduce right or positive skewness where
extreme data results are larger you'll
have frequent small losses and few
extreme gains and that's where you want
to start taking your roots logs and
reciprocals if you want to reduce left
or negative skewness where extreme data
results are smaller frequent small gains
and few extreme losses that's where you
want to start taking your squares cubes
and higher powers so then the fun begins
when we start actually generating our
stats and developing our hypotheses
first we differentiate between an
incident in a breach and our analysis
and then when we report the stats in the
you want to report on the stats and the
report so i had to find what how we
define an incident and we define a
breach as a security incident that has
confirmed data disclosure of an asset to
an unauthorized party
we also need to be aware of what
constitutes a filter for example if you
take the field year it can be
interpreted three different ways first
incident year that's the year that the
incident occurred second we have debe ir
year this is a debe ir year the data was
assigned to so our collection period is
from november to november and then
finally we can look at it as data set
year and this is the year that the data
was actually imported so for coating up
incidents in vc DB say we code up we
caught up in 2016 the actual incidents
occurred several years ago it would be
inappropriate to include them into this
year as current incidents in the report
because they had occurred prot in prior
years so the key here is that those said
incidents are assigned to the DB I are
here associated to the actual incident
year we also have to be careful when
people request for stats regarding year
so if they ask for a stat across
multiple years we usually assume
calendar year if they ask for this year
we usually assume data since last report
again we always communicate and clarify
that we're talking about the same thing
and also again we exclude those old
incidents that we just happen to code up
this year but that actually had occurred
in previous years then we also have to
be careful of catch-all for example
unknown other nna what's measured what's
not measured do we count it or do we not
for unknown we consider is not measured
it doesn't add any additional knowledge
when we encode the unknowns because it
adds no data we typically exclude it for
others we consider it measured but it's
just not covered in our schema so it
does add data so we do include it
finally with na s it actually depends on
the question so for asking what percent
of breaches involved a financial motive
we would typically include this because
some breeches just have no motive but if
we're asking what percent of motives are
financial we exclude it because na is
not a motive so those questions sound
like they're asking similar things but
they're actually quite different then
comes counting and how do we count n the
normal way to calculate it is
we count how many of each enumeration we
sum up the counts and we get our end
this doesn't work for those records and
incidents that have multiple
enumerations so for example if you have
one incident that is both social and
malware it will be counted more than
once so instead what we do is that we
subset the records that we care about
her that we want to analyze we exclude
our unknowns in any potentially anaise
and then you know then we sum up if we
count the number of records I eat the
number of rows before summing up those
features next we look at confidence this
is very important when we're subsetting
data because our sample sizes decreased
quite quickly this is where you want to
start looking into your random error we
look at confidence intervals I want to
see if they overlap for example for
where you know we're working with
statements like hacking was greater than
malware this year or hacking increase
from last year so just to recall if
there's no overlap and the confidence
intervals this implies that the
difference is statistically significant
if there is overlap it doesn't
necessarily mean that sick that the
difference is not statistically
significant so depending on who you talk
to people define confidence intervals
slightly differently it is correct to
say that there is a ninety-five percent
chance that the confidence interval you
calculated includes the true population
mean some other people define it as
there's a ninety-five percent chance
that the population mean lies within the
interval which is not quite correct also
if you want to be more confident that an
interval contains a true parameter so
for instance we instead of ninety-five
percent we want to look at ninety-nine
percent the interval we become wider if
there's more variance in our data it
also creates wider intervals and as well
as smaller sample sizes that creates
wider intervals and
we know that there's a inverse square
relationship between confidence
intervals and sample sizes so if you
want to decrease your margin of error by
half you'll technically have to
quadruple your sample size so overall we
calculate these confidence intervals we
don't include them in the report because
a majority of our readership could care
less about actual upper and lower limits
we can treat our data in two main ways
so we can we look at it from the
binomial perspective which is what we
have done in previous years and to date
it depends on what question you're
asking for binomial versus multinomial
for binomial we work with primarily
boolean columns so you know is it for an
incident was it you know social a social
incident true or false malware true or
false was their data disclosure true or
false so again this was our primary one
but the problem here is that it doesn't
model interdependencies between features
so that's where it's nice to start
looking at it from a multinomial
perspective especially for those records
that have more than one enumeration
because you're not only looking at a
singular enumeration you're actually
looking at a set we have a crop tena
stats in the dbi are lots of presents we
can't ever say that there was X number
of breaches in you know in the past year
we never know the population size we
always work with sample sizes so I for
our percentages we break it down by
action or by pattern or whatever it may
be the problem is that when it 11
enumeration increases it may look like
another enumeration is decreasing for
example if you have 100 hacking breaches
in 2015 and in 2016 then you look at
malware you have 10 and 2015 and you
have a thousand and twenty sixteen
malware is going to look like it's
increasing but it's going to make
hacking look like it's decreasing when
in fact it was actually consistent per
year so with things like that when we
generate figures and it looks a little
bit misleading we are very careful to
annotate that for a readership to avoid
any kind of confusion so then after we
generate all these stats then we have to
actually validate those hypotheses which
Gabe will get into
so I got to talk about validating the
data now I get to talk about validating
those hypotheses right well we'll start
with the figures so this is one of the
things that in reality when people say
they read the DBR what they really said
was I looked at the figures you know
that's like that's the standard but in
fact it's cool if like when we're
briefing the DB our way I cast that
question and you're like who read the
DBR and there's like a few people it's
like if you ask who read it first like a
bunch of people raise their hand if you
ask who looked at the figures for it so
you get a lot of hands there and then no
one raises their hand for the reading
question because they weren't really
sure where you were going with like when
you asked reading first and like I I
don't like not raise my hand here and
make it sound like I didn't even look at
it but people look at the figures right
that's that's how we communicate and so
we want the figures to communicate our
points clearly right and so we use the
common ones we use bar graphs and we use
line charts you know very standard ways
to go but you can communicate clearly
without necessarily being simple you can
have complex figures that communicate
clearly and we try to put a little bit
of variety in we had a parallel
coordinates tower we actually had an art
plot in there for everyone that red bike
into the appendix but the important
thing is how you track these figures for
validation so we talked about we run the
exploratory reports right every one of
those exploratory reports with every one
of those figures has a unique ID on it
and when they someone from our team goes
okay we're going to put this figure into
the report or into the section i'm
writing we capture that unique ID and
all the code associated with that figure
and it goes into a validation of figure
report for us and that figure report has
the unique ID it has the title which is
effectively the hypothesis for that
figure and then it has the entire code
to generate it that way we can track and
we can track it as things change and if
someone comes and request one of us to
do a figure for them we given the unique
ID that way is the report is being
written and put together we have the
idea of the figures that are in it and
we have a report that can generate them
all and that way we have confidence that
we can repeat those figures and can do
them consistently
and we do this all with knitter the same
thing we do the Explorer turn reports
with and we do it with ggplot has anyone
here use ggplot has anyone written like
a ggplot figure that was really nice and
like under ten lines it's big but you
get really nice layout quality figures
from it it's the way to go and by the
way so we wrote the report and then and
they did this last year we went on a
podcast with a professor who specializes
in data figures and had him critique it
because we want to continuously get
better and you know what he didn't say a
whole lot but you already said it
doesn't count if you actually listen to
the podcast he do you remember like the
flow graphs they're really bright and
they had lines and stuff and he's like
yeah you can't use those ever again
people can't read this and we really we
kind of knew it but we include them for
consistency but next year we're probably
going to replace him with small
multiples charts also a great idea is he
took the figures and he said look you've
got this figure that's got this one
really big bar in these little bars why
don't you put like a big big red letter
a on that bar and then in your in your
text you can put that same big red
letter a that way people that want to
know what that bar is or why it's big
can find the spot easily in your text
it's a great recommendation and it's one
will hopefully see in the DVR next year
and what we do for figures we want to do
for all of our hypotheses right so you
see statements like hacking was greater
than malware or malware increased since
last year or you know fishing was forty
percent of breaches every single one of
those statements in the report this year
was in a validation report and we
probably made a mistake in that this
year last year we waited till the report
was written and we wrote those next year
every single time we give out of stat
we're going to give out a unique ID with
it and we're in our validation report
we're going to put that unique ID we're
going to put the hypothesis so we've got
this report for this year's put the
hypothesis we're going to put the code
to generate it and we're going to put
the outcome that way every single number
every single statement in there can be
tracked back to the law
chick which a riot at and it's so it's
very similar to the figure report and
the important thing or the reason that
you need to do this is because anomalies
creep in but you know there's something
you can do about keeping those anomalies
out the first is start from a single
code base like it's it's just bad juju
if I like I'm running one version of our
and Anna's running another version
because we may come up with the same
numbers we may not it depends what's
changed between the versions in fact
it's really bad if I like actually
change what version of our I'm running
during the process so like we have a cut
off somewhere in like the fall where
it's like we stopped updating our
statistical software until like after
the last version the last iteration of
that dbr is published because we don't
want to break our workflow or change our
workflow midstream the next is you want
a single data starting point so like
Anna said we we have a lot of records
and we have to ultimately choose what
are we going to analyze as the main set
and what's going to be analyzed as
unique subsets separately because we
want to represent all valid data but we
don't want our data to once i have data
to clips others and so it's important to
bury clearly label what that starting
point is all of the analysts at work
with the data know where to start with
their data we all start at the exact
same point and that helps us with
repeatability and additionally we also
have a common analysis process we all
used apply it who uses deep liar for our
people oh come on we have it that's
suede so we had a lot of people he used
our and very few hands went up for deep
liar like if there we go at least one
person because if you're using our and
not using deep liar you're going to be
amazed at how like actually logical are
can be you know as opposed to like
feeding stuff backwards in time you
normally do it you like actually get to
feed things forward and so we use the
standard process for doing it and
because of that it's very easy for us to
all arrive at the same answer every time
and so on the other hand there's places
where we've tried to do things like the
Association rooms we talked about those
so with the Association rules we've had
issues where like we generated stats and
we generate interesting stuff in the
association rules but they're very hard
to replicate you have to
start with the exact same data the exact
same columns we can't run it on all of
our columns so we have to subset same
and then it's like any machine learning
algorithm the arguments you give to it
strongly affect what the actual outcome
is and so unless you got all that
exactly the same as the first time you
ran it you're not going to get the same
answer so instead you know for something
like Association rules we're going to go
back and recreate those stats using our
normal deep liar process that way we
have confidence in the repeatability of
them and so and by the way like we
talked about in this track yesterday it
doesn't matter what your stats are if
there's not a so wat to them and so
you're going to do all these great stats
you're going to do all this analysis for
confidence intervals and when it comes
time to write Oh tons of it's going to
get cut out just like line after line
like you would not believe how much like
it's our favorite it's always the best
analysis isn't it like the stuff that we
love gets cut out and so it's important
to just be prepared for that because if
there's no so what behind your data it
doesn't matter how good the stats where
the analysis was it doesn't go in and so
looking forward we're doing a lot of
work the first on veras we're currently
iterating versions to increase the
enumerations to get a more coverage on
what people want we're also going to fix
some consistency issues in the hierarchy
on the next version and then we're going
to go to sequencing so that you can in
various you can record this action
happened then this one then this one or
this action happened and it compromised
this which led to this you know which
will let us capture some additional
granularity as well as being able to
represent things like pin tests we're
also doing a lot of work on varus r
which is the our package that parses
varus data we're doing some internal
changes to make it easier to work with
for those who have to deal with this
kind of stuff it currently uses data
tables which sound really great until
they break everything you do like once a
month and so we're going to get back off
those it turned out sounded good when we
did it we're also putting an additional
helper code and functions and more
analysis tools within it it's stuff that
currently resides in a separate
repository but we want to make sure it's
available to everyone and we're putting
in more statistical tools and adding in
things so that other people can
on confidence intervals when they're
working with our varus ours by the way
all this stuff is open you can download
off github we're also working on our
workflow and by the way when we're
updating this stuff we're updating a
consistent manner especially like
updating the varus schema you know we
have a huge chart for everything so that
every single thing in the entire
workflow gets updated at the same time
and we don't have half the workflow on
one thing in half on the other and
that's hard to do but it's something you
need to plan for if you're going to
maintain a tool like this add a tool and
so we're updating our workflow making it
easier more repeatable faster and
generally trying to make the whole
system easy to run consistent and
repeatable and before you took the
conclusion there's one thing I want to
talk about here we all generate data
products and we've come to terms with
the data but not everyone in the world
in fact not everyone in information
security has because you know it's hard
when your brain is telling you something
like someone's telling you something
with data and your brain is telling you
something different right and because
you look at the data and it feels a bit
like magic right that analysis process
even when the entire methodology is
disclosed it still feels a little like
magic because your brain is saying I
don't know if I believe that data but
there's a sign in the UK it's like art
on the side of ability ins says your
mind is crazy and tells you lies right
and you know there's a lot of truth to
that because if you kind of contrast
what happens with your brain right
because your brain can organize all this
like it'd be great if you had a process
but you like you can put this all into a
single picture but it'd take a lot of
skill and a lot of thought to turn that
into something interesting all those
disparate parts and that's what your
brain has to do and the downside is
there's there's no documentation of what
your mind did right how those ideas are
forming you don't know what data went
into it you know maybe your mind
excluded all the little cardboard bricks
maybe it brought in a bunch of a Lincoln
Logs and added those because they were
somewhere in your mind and so it decided
include them in your model you know you
have no way of time that you have no way
of
questioning or validating the process
that went into creating the picture and
you have no way of maintaining
consistency so like today I might look
at this and know that looks like a
flamingo you know and you know a few
months down the road I get the same
problem with the same data and like
great that's a Tonka truck you know you
have no way of maintaining consistency
over time your mind is a black box Andy
Ellis the sea so at akamai i think is
planning on giving a presentation that's
called the complexity apocalypse you
know and his base thing is that
information security risks are now too
complex for system 144 gut instinct
analysis and so it's important that us
is you know data-driven people you know
encourage people to build a mental model
that satisfies all the facts right those
that come from their mind and those that
come from the data so in conclusion
though the data is not perfect it never
is it never will be but you're here to
help it tell its story but not torture
it have a consistent process you know
and if possible automate for
repeatability more importantly document
everything you do put a unique ID on
everything you generate question
everything that everything of interest
and communicate because when you
communicate for the people to consume
your report it helps them understand the
process that went into the numbers and
for the peat for you it helps you
understand and learn from the people who
are using your information and so with
that I think I left good for me I left
like five minutes for questions
so you mentioned the fun stuff that
doesn't make the report because it
failed the so much test yeah favorite
serve items it was all the malware
analysis we pretty much a week slice and
dice specific malware names and we
wanted to see what families were very
prominent we did a couple it did a
couple more stuff with malware but it
just didn't make it in yeah there was a
lot around like so we talked about the
subsets of the data right and we talked
about how not incident data its context
well part of the reason we put left the
dried X sub set in the overall data set
as opposed to analyzing it separately
was because when we looked at the
malware data you could see the impact of
dried X in it there was just a
significant amount of a botnet data and
what it really was was it was
executables coming by email or infected
malware infected Word documents or
office documents coming by email and so
you could see how these BOTS were
actually happening significantly and it
helped inform us on in how we handled
the data and we had some really pretty
cool pictures like they were all done we
did him like up to the final quality and
they just didn't make the final cut but
if you ever get a chance to like see
either of our like actual dbr
presentations like it's ours we they
can't tell us not to use those figures
and we got them so like I got them all
on my presentation yes brother two quick
questions somewhat related you mentioned
three different schemas yeah ah that's
the first I've heard of multiple schemas
when it comes to the analysis and the
storage of the data is this something
new to this year's report or it does
know we only operate on a single one of
those schemas we always use the dvir
esquina but there's there's some things
like if you look at the scheming and
notice there's a plus section and that
plus section is marked to allow
additional features in it and the idea
is that if you as an organization have
things that are relevant to you but not
to other people you can put them in
there like we we used to deal with a lot
of pci data and so we have you know
specific pci enumerations that really
aren't part of the overall schema but
that we have and then we use a DVR
r 1 DB our year is actually a plus thing
it's in the DVR schema but it's not in
the standard schema and the reason is
because most people don't care about
what your the data was imported in the
DVR because they're not importing to the
DVR and so it's just like little helper
stuff like that that's specific to us so
we always use the DVR schema and the dbi
our schema is ninety-five percent the
community schema that gets to my other
questions have you published what the
different schemas are and disclosed
within the report a technical reading
lists those differences so that as other
data scientists other analysts are
taking a look at the community schema
what's up on the community site they can
reproduce your results using your
methods well should be they'll be able
to reproduce so this gets back partially
the data on because of the data sources
are agreements or that we are not
allowed to share the day like it if you
create any analysis on vc TB and send it
to us we'll run it on our data set and
give you back the analysis but our
agreements don't allow us to share the
actual data and so ultimately there will
never be kind of the perfect
reproducibility but I've got no problem
sharing the additional features that are
in the DB our stuff we talked about it a
lot you're going to be sorely
disappointed there is nothing exciting
in there all the cool stuff happens in
the community schema like you know
because really what people care about we
call him the forays right action in fact
it was in the scheme of thing like the
on the circles that's where ninety-nine
percent of our parsing comes from and
the stuff that gets in the plus section
in fact unfortunately it's a lot of
stuff that they like kind of tried
they're like let's try to see if this
feature gets coated in or we can fill
stuff into it and it turns out no it
didn't get used at all and so you even
in the plus section for other than like
the metadata ones like dbr year it's
just all columns and knows you don't
it's in the schema but there's no actual
data in it but it's no problem to share
it you know it doesn't really affect
share I don't so I'm trying to think
what the best way to share it would be
because I don't on the various website
but that's this is what I'm worried
about right because if I put that on the
various website now I've put two schemas
two different schemas side by side and I
don't want people looking and going well
which one of these should i be using you
know the cuete answer is you should be
using the community schema that one's
designed to meet the needs of the
community and if you use the additional
features you know potentially we confuse
you and also we're not as good about
keeping those additional ones as clean
as we do the community ones like there's
some there's like some enumerations that
I was cleaning it up this here and I'm
like hey why'd you got like what is this
field why is this in here and they're
like oh yeah we tried that out like
three years ago and it didn't work and
we never took it out of the private the
private schema and so I'd also be
worried about confusing people but you
know it I'd be happy to email your you
know and I we've got a blog but it turns
out that getting stuff on the blog is a
whole a lot of work and so there's got
to be some way maybe in the there's a DB
I or repo that we use to it's got all
the figures in fact if you didn't know
this last year we post all the figures
there this year we posted the figures
plus the data behind the figures in an
RDA file and then next year I'm going to
try to see if I can post the validation
report in there but I could probably
dump it in there I'll need to be
reminded I forget things very quickly
but if you email me a DB are at Bryson
com I'll make sure happens I'm just
thinking this would go a long way
producing some of the criticism that
they're important as continuity is
especially this past year
well but it wouldn't open this about the
sausage I think this presentation is
great I think this should be shared
partly sure if you think it'll help i'd
be happy to do it yeah i think this
would produce a lot of mystical prizes
got some of these reports yeah cool
thank you