hi hello my name is kuba I'm working as
a software engineer in security team at
Yelp and I'm here to tell you today
about how we automated our model
response at Yelp so first couple words
about me i started at Yelp around two
years ago and since then I've been
mostly involved in our malware incident
response process and also in the
meantime automating and basically
working on our security processes before
that I used to work at sa p in
sovereignty policies in France in a
security interest research group and
prior to that I was studying in Krakow
and also doing joint degree with the
university of telecom perry tag this is
your home also in sophia antipolis so
just sort of a quick recap yelped
mission is to connect people with great
local businesses and this led over the
past 12 years since the company started
to over 102 million reviews as you can
see on this slide 19 billion of the
users are coming from the mobile
websites and applications around seventy
percent of the stretches are also from
mobile and web apps mobile apps and
basic our mobile app website and right
now yep Yelp is present 32 countries
worldwide so what I'm trying to say by
showing you all these stats is basically
we have more than 4,000 employees by now
and most of them are actually using
macbooks to do their daily job so sort
of acquainting interaction to our model
or incident response process this sort
of starts when one of our employees gets
an alert either like some detection by
our endpoint monitoring software or some
network monitoring stuff that detect
some suspicious binaries on the user's
machine or some suspicious net worth
dropping coming from from a particular
machine but just let me first introduce
you sort of two people involved in all
this process so fast will have a Yelp
employee
who typically uses macbook to perform
its daily duties and from time to time
they will wonder to some grey sides of
the internet right for instance Gettler
to download latest update to adobe flash
player or some free video converter app
which comes packaged with malware also
for free we have help desk engineers so
they are kind of serving as an interface
between users and ask the security team
how does engineers are the best people
to perform all this task they have best
outreach to the users in terms of both
different time zones and different
locations because Yelp is also present
in various locations around the globe
our offices are in various locations
around ago and we have also secured team
that is also consisting on Morales so
the people who are basically in charge
of analyzing the alerts about malware on
modern infections on someone machines so
job of malware analyst is typically to
answer these three questions how the
malware got there in the first place
well is the Machine even infected or not
and how we can prevent and detect
further infections to sort of stop
spreading malware all over our company
infrastructure so there used to be lots
of false positive in our approach in the
alerts we were receiving so we started
involving malware analysts as early in
the process as possible so we are doing
this initial 38 and this is basically to
establish whether this is real error
alert or a false positive whether it's
something like Windows Fred on Mac OS
machines that we don't really care about
and this is sort of to save us time from
all these other tasks like forensics
collection and 4 x's allottees so we can
weave out as filter out sort of as
quickly as possible whether this is a
real threat or not there's always saving
us some time but our traditional sort of
approach involved later on after this
initial 3h basically collecting
forensics from there from the machine
I'll tell about
this a bit more in the next slides this
task used to be performed by our
helpdesk ninja so they're like as I
mentioned the best people to do it
because they are really living close to
the users they can just go grab
someone's machines take it up the
network run the necessary collection
script get the output back and then the
model analysts can start start analyzing
the output so they can assess the risk
related to the infection so when it
comes to different kind of tools we have
available for digital forensics
collection on Mac OS there is OSX
auditor so this is script that more or
less inactive for the past few few
months it's open source on github it
lets you collect different properties
from the from mac OS machines there is
always square which also is open source
project open source by Facebook it
allows you to query different system
properties like you will beat wiring SQL
database knock knock is also quite
useful tool that lets you figure out
which processes are running on your mac
OS machines so this may give you more
insight into whether there are some
known processes like system processes or
something that was actually installed by
the user potentially packaged with
malware there is Google Rapid Response
framework this is a bit more interested
they let you for instance collect file
samples so it also gives you more
insights into in terms of whether the
machine is infected with something or
not because they give you possibly to
collect the samples of the files from
the machines as well I'd like to also
mention the book that was recently
released is OS stan is in response
scripting analysis by jaron bradley this
book's also comes with kind of ideas for
scripts that you can basically have to
collect various forensics from from mac
OS machines and also gives you some
ideas about how to analyze them at the
yelp we use OS X collector which is a
tool based on OS X editor it's also open
source on the github so this is a
forensic evidence
election analysis toolkit for OS 10 we
open sores it some two years ago it was
actually first project I worked on when
I joined you out so I'm pretty proud of
it that it's love there and still used
by people actually let me get a quick
show of hands how many of you are
familiar with OSX collector in the
audience a couple of hands ok cool so
basically what Isaac selector is is a
simple Python script that Iran on
potentially infected machine it will
collect value system properties you see
it here on this slide and then output
them as a JSON file so that analysts can
take this file and try to figure out all
these properties whether machine is
infected or not so the way OSX collector
runs is it collects gathers all these
different information from plist which
are kind of like you would say windows
registry things on Mac OS machines
various sqlite databases that also mac
OS uses to store system properties as
well as some other a local file system
information for for instance for
applications installed the system or
browser history browser extension things
like that so here is an example of how
such a JSON entry collected by OSX
collector looks like it comes with some
common keys like file paths file hashes
timestamps they're also signature change
for instance for for binaries that might
be useful to figure out whether this is
something we expect on the system or not
so what we used to do later on after
collecting all these files from the
potential infected machine is that
Morales would basically sit down and
with some simple tools like grab or JQ
which is actually quite cool thank for
Jason visualization they will go through
the scripts basically trying to find
some incidents that were happening
around the certain time frame or goals
also allows you to with hub of GQ filter
and show only URLs related to user's
activity around a certain time frame and
basically based on that annals we'll try
to figure
two were for instance the file was
downloaded from or when the file was
installed by the user trying basically
to figure out answers to these questions
I mentioned earlier so this also works
pretty well but if you have thirty
thousand lines of JSON output it may
come as a really job of basically
looking at a lot of Jason and don't get
me wrong like I like Jason Jason is very
pretty this simple but it's also very
easy to read and process by my code from
code so actually why don't we let code
process JSON output and this is what we
started down as the next step so early
on we automated the JSON analysis
process or with what we called OSX
Kaiser output filters and they basically
what they do is they augment the initial
jason with all different properties for
instance the information from our
internal blacklists or information from
some external threat intelligence api's
they will also try to construct the list
of related files to a files that are
potentially infected and then produce
some sort of summary of bindings so this
is a really cool it automates the whole
kind of analysis process but the the
tool itself OSX collector out with
filters it was quite tedious to maintain
because mal Reynolds had to basically
get the installation installation of the
two on their machine when they started
the analysis they had to also basically
sit there watch it one ink they if the
machine went to sleep or if they decided
to like close the machine or for
whatever reason they lost internet
connections all this sort of process
will kind of hold and then they all have
to restart it because it connects to
various external thread until I pis by
HTTP so basically the food was not
written in the way they allowed them to
kind of like post it and resume at
certain point of time also not to
mention that basically whenever there
was like new version of this OS X later
out with filters mal rounds were in
charge of themselves
dating the source code getting all the
dependencies so it was really really
tedious task and not something we were
looking to do with the process that we
were actually trying to automate so we
thought we can do better and we turn the
autistic like throughout the filters
into a service and we call the service
amira automated malware incident
response and analysis so right now with
amira what analysts is doing is just
dropping the OSX character output file
to the s3 bucket and amira will
automatically trigger the annals of the
new object in the bucket this is based
on fenkell s3 even notifications so we
have configured disaster e bucket
basically to send a notification to NS q
SQ whenever there is new object in this
bucket this SQ SQ is called here on the
slide amira s3 even notifications so
whenever there is a new object created a
notification will be sent to this queue
amira periodically check for the new
messages in their sea ice cube and upon
receiving a new one it will fetch the
related OSX collector output file from
the s3 bucket and you can see actually
that output of the OSX character is
packaged in tar.gz file two sections
face because it's like lots of Jason so
we want to compress it as much as
possible so here i will also extract the
first decompress the file and then
extract the proper json file from from
the archive and then it will run execute
all these different analysis filters on
the OSX collector output file
and after all this process it will send
the results of the analysis for instance
to another s3 bucket so the malware
analysts can patch the results from from
the bucket and see whether the machine
was infected basically with the whole
summary of them of the Alice's process
here are the examples of the another
results that amira produces so for
instance we will see some domains and
hashes that we refined from the black on
the blackest that we are curating will
also give you an idea about information
found by conducting the external threat
intelligence AP is another world
surprised you suggestions so basically
for the things that were found on the
external threat intelligence api's but
are not listed on your black place it
will suggest you to you to add them to
the 2d blacklist amira doesn't require
too much configuration to run basically
all you need to do is to figure out on
your own this ester even notification
spank it is well documented on the AWS
documentation so it's not really
something difficult and then just to run
it you basically to specify as qsq name
and AWS region where the queue was
configured to run there is also a
possibility to specify this results of
loaders so there is for instance
possibility to add also some other
results upload their so result of all
there are basically a way for you to
tell Amira what to do with the Alice's
results so you may want to add some
other way of distributing the results
for instance you may think about sending
the results of the answers via email or
some similar or some basic alee attach
them to your incident response platform
if you have some more advanced system
two to three edges alert and so that the
syrup while I was mentioning that kind
of disaster about that there the end
results of the s3 bucket is is uh is
optional step are there any questions so
far related to
amira so the question is whether we are
using it as a lambda function or running
it as our internal instance so we are
running it is our internalized pneus
gather several factors its lambda
factors are really cool but I found them
quite at ease when it comes to importing
some external dependencies like
basically this whole OS X caught up with
filters but our first idea was actually
to think about lambda functions there
were some other questions okay if not
let me continue so actually you can go
even the step ladder with all this for
instance and also to make the forensics
collections tab so basically what you
can do is instead of just getting the
Machine and running the OS X character
script on the machine you could think
about basically having some scripts that
will run OSX collector on the machine
and for instance upload the results to
an extra bucket if you have large
installation in your in your company so
like we all have around for does
employees with with mac OS systems you
probably use something like your
inventory management system you could
think of basically just dropping the
script to run OS X Factor collection and
then uploading the results to s3 bucket
and that will trigger the Amira to to
run their collection to run the analysis
on the on the results here is an example
of sits script it's very basic I
actually stole it from someone else it's
the only thing it does it's just
calculating this signature for AWS s3 so
it can send a file their end and then
trigger the whole analysis process
so the whole annals is sort of saved us
a lot of time in certain cases it served
us up to like hours from several days we
used to be when we were involving also
help desk into the whole collection
process we have to wait for them they
were in different time zones sometimes
they have to chase the user which will
also in the other time zone so the whole
process could easily take up to several
days and then the whole analysis as I
mentioned when it was interrupted
amiright takes basically all this effort
from you you don't have to sit there
watch how it collects all the old
information from various Fred
intelligence api's it also we uses lots
of caching mechanisms so all this OSX
collector output filters it comes
packaged with some basic cash that will
now teach you the same queries for
instance if that user visited the same
websites I mean most of the users are
actually visiting probably like eighteen
ninety percent of the websites they're
visiting are the same so when we're
running the process on each by each
individual modeler analyst basically all
all all of them I had to pretty much get
the same information all over again and
with a mirror which is able to have this
information at once from the AP ice and
cash it so for instance saves us lots of
quota from the external IP eyes and it
basically makes the whole process in the
pasture it also cut all this interaction
between the modeler analysts and help
desk so right now amira is taking care
of forensics collection also the
analysis obviously there is need for
analysts to review the whole results
summary and actually provide
remediations that are done executed by
the IT engineer help us but before we
still like there is less sort of human
interaction less errors possibly that
could all over along the way
also there is no need for this physical
collection so even less problems with
basically a chasing users down the
corridors and taking their machine of
the network we can just remotely run the
script collect all the forensics get the
analysis done and then basically malware
analysts can sit down and look at the
analysis and figure out whether there
are any false positives or we were down
any sort of other problems and it also
allowed us to do more proactive forensic
collection so right now even on the
machines that we are not really sure
that they're in fact there are we we
haven't even received any alerts but
potentially there is some suspicious
networking activity from our DNS
resolvers we could practically run a
mirror and get all the forensics on a
live stem and and figure out whether the
machine is impacted on that and the
whole thing is open sourced so go try it
out I'm really looking forward for any
questions related to the project and the
issues that you've spot if you have any
suggestions also don't be shy create
simple requests and then my way i'll try
to review them and all that doubt i'll
like to thank you for coming and i'm
open to take any questions
what kind of percentage I'd say it's
probably way more than 80 purrs like
around this like eighty twenty percent
all right so I guess some of them will
be clearly false positive some of them
will be like oh it is a threat but it's
not applicable for this particular
machine and ya mero basically helps us
to to figure this out because even for a
certain press that are for instance our
end point or drink say our windows only
will still get the alert and then we'll
have to figure out these seriously
windows only for instance some browser
extensions there don't really are
related to to any systems so that's how
we can also analyze it are you planning
any integrations with like sandboxing
technologies goo goo or anything like
that yeah so regarding sandbox inc so
this is purely sorted for forensics
collection so there is no sample
collection obviously it would be very
interesting to connect it also if
something that could process a sample
but then we are sort of approaching this
problem of how we are transferring the
samples on the way so for instance
Google Rapid Response framework they do
something that allows you to pick a
sample and I guess at the point of time
we would be able so to have some more
reliable Anna's when it comes to the
file so so far we are operating
basically on file hashes I guess file
names things like that I mean URLs are
pretty okay like sometimes we are
basically collecting a sample from the
original URL rather than from the
machine because also maybe sort of to
give you a heads up on all this
remediation process apart from just
getting rid of the threat on particular
instance what we are trying to do as
well as block domains block IP addresses
serving malware so at this point of time
actually it is more important for us
where this Fred got from and if we are
able to pinpoint it to particular domain
URL and get a sample there
we know we have to block it right so
it's it's actually more related to what
we are doing later in the step so now
that you're now that you're able to
collect a lot more and analyze a lot
more at scale is there have you found
particular things that you've particular
indicators or particular types of data
you've collected now that we're not
worth collecting before that we're not
we're collecting weren't worth
collecting terms is really expensive
yeah so there are particular parts of
forensics collection done by OS X
collector it tries to get as much
information as possible that's why this
30k lines for machine that was running I
guess for several months and then the
whole analysis process is also longer
because of that yeah we decided for
instance not to look too much into
cookies collecting a browser there were
several issues actually with that also
that collecting cookies value from
someone's machines is a security issue
in the first place because you're
collecting lots of information that
should not leave machine the reason
sumption is not leaving a machine
sometimes we get some noise related to
to one of the filters so there are
filters that try to extract domains from
particular URLs there are so filters to
try to create kind of a network graph of
related files so for instance if you
have some related files to the one that
is impacted maybe it's potentially
interesting to look at them as well and
these are most of the part too noisy to
be actually taken seriously we very
seldom look at them on the latest mac
hacks that are out there using GPU
graphics attacks are you looking at
those not really I'm not to bother
I was wondering if you keep your OS X
collector files and periodically rerun
them you know as your threat feed
updates and if that's proven any of any
value to you yeah so so far what we are
doing we are keeping the malware
forensics that we collected from the
machines we are not a mirror yet is not
to stifle apart from this cache that
I've mentioned earlier it's not creating
any state there was actually a project
it was presented at signed continue to
last year where people were trying
basically to also put all those
information I think it was MongoDB but
you may think of okay let's put it in
something like elasticsearch clusters
blanc and let's square it so these are
potential next steps for this project
basically apart from just taking as like
one machine individually let's try to
see how this machine differs from all
the other machines in the network this
is actually something that OS querrey is
able to do for instance like having the
whole fleet of machines and trying to
compare one machine against all others
in the in the in the same infrastructure
what's the run time of collection and a
mirror I mean how long it does it take
on each laptop and how long does it take
to process so the whole collection
process so just purely OSX collector
script it does rely on how basically for
how long time the machine was used if
the machine was used for several years
you will for instance like browser
history isn't pure like you have lots of
apps installed it might take quite some
time then the whole I know so like worst
case like you know up to a day let's say
yeah yeah we had the cases when it was
like running for a day like it was still
in the good old days of other skin
janiers trying to get the machine right
now as we were running it by our
inventory management system we to be
honest we don't collect too much insight
about when the collection was started
and then when the collection was
finished we only know this time when the
collection was finished so you don't
know if the collection was
because user for instance was not in the
office for like a day and his machine
didn't mean up to the central inventory
management system in the best case I had
actually on my when I was preparing that
the presentation I had a case when the
whole collection and analysis process
also running and others which can also
may take up to yeah and other several
hours it took eight minutes basically
from collection to to having the results
a available for for the mall or analyst
to look at you mentioned started doing
proactive collection have you looked at
collecting that data and trending on the
data over time in something like elastic
search or cabana yes so this is
something we are not doing yet but
definitely something I'd like to work as
a next steps basically after we
automated older this kind of similar
with respect to active defense do you
guys have a particular threshold that
you have to meet in order before you
deploy the script or do you just kind of
have this script you know already
available to run on machines and you run
across all your machines or do you again
or do you have to reach a threshold so
yes we do have something like a
threshold is basically this alerts we
get from endpoint touring or network
monitoring so this is our initial kind
of trigger for the whole marwa malware
incident response process but then we
had some cases in the past when we were
suspecting part of the fleet to be
infected with something and then with
just one click we were able to deploy
the script like hundreds of machines get
the answers down by the next day and
look at this so it's way more scalable
than our previous approaching this
what kind of file size is this OS X
collector like put out like could be
seen file size in terms of the
collection yeah so the tree was actually
on the slide but the compressed tar.gz
file it's usually several megabytes if
you decompress it's like 60 megabytes 80
megabytes something like that okay any
other questions still okay and no thank
you kuba let's hear it