we have a price and Scott they're going
to be presenting one compromise rule
them all it's going to be a little bit
of an addition to the previous
presentation on Empire so with that I'll
leave it's bryson Scott can you guys
hear that okay now great Scott's going
to show you today a little bit about
dcos and mezzos and why you might want
to check out these technologies for
doing job orchestration across your data
centers and then I'm going to show you
today why you should take just a little
bit extra time to try and secure down
some of the building blocks that DCOs is
built upon so I'm hand it over to Scott
to do get you a little bit up speed is
anybody in the room familiar with DC OS
or mezzos are they using that in their
day job for fun we've got a couple of
people so DCOs stands for data center
operating system it was born out of a
need to efficiently use resource into
your data center a lot of organizations
find that just running jobs on our
servers they're seeing about sixty to
sixty-five percent utilization of their
servers like the hardware that they have
in their data centers meaning they have
millions tens of millions lots of
dollars worth of hardware that's just
sitting in in their rooms that they're
paying for that's not really giving any
use for them so DCOs was born to kind of
solve some of this problem the
philosophy behind dcos is yew tree it
you treat all the resources hardware in
your data center as a single box you
bubble all those resources up into one
place where you can then send jobs to
different places to make sure that
you're running your hardware as
efficiently as you can yeah so at the
bottom of this cluster you need
something that can run it like an
operating system which is a kernel
mezzos is kind of the colonel layer of
this D cos there are two pieces of maize
oh so there's the cluster which is
set of masters that receives offers from
agents or slaves the agents are slaves
you install on hardware or VMs or cloud
instances that make resource offers up
to mezzos so that's this bottom tier on
top of mezzos you have a set of
frameworks those frameworks do job
definitions so if you have like a set of
Apache servers do you want running if
you have batch jobs if you have
scheduled jobs there's different
frameworks that will handle those
different types of jobs on top of that
is where you deploy your applications
usually these are multi-tenant clusters
they can be multi-tenant clusters
meaning you'll have jobs different types
of jobs running for different teams
probably not different companies but
more than likely different types of jobs
running on here these are usually
packaged up in containers handful of
different container using technologies
but typically docker so you write your
job in docker you orchestrate it using a
framework and then mezzos takes those
job definitions and spreads them across
finds places for them to run a little
bit more about the communications
between these the agents are running on
this Hardware at the bottom or VMS or
whatever they communicate with mezzos
using a configuration share called
zookeeper easiest way to think about
zookeeper is basically a network a
network accessible JSON object so key
store I store this value I retrieve this
value somewhere else so the cluster the
slaves will say I have hardware I'm
offering it it'll put a red an entry in
this key store the mezzos will pick that
up match your job with it put it back in
and the slave will pick it back up and
start executing that job between the
kernel and the frameworks which is that
kind of top purpley one those are
typically done either via zookeeper
again or rest api's that are built into
mezzos
some of the common frameworks of a
marathon is probably the most common one
pretty much any deployment of mezzos
that you'll see we'll also have marathon
living next to it marathons for long
running jobs it's also used for scaling
jobs so if I have one docker container i
created job definition put that in
Marathon and then you can say oh I want
ten of these running or 50 of these
running you can drive it using the API
so collect other metrics from the boxes
say as performance goes hits eighty
percent utilization increase more
instances in this pool Chronos is
basically at kron4 dcos so you can give
it a job definition which can be
something as simple as a like just a
normal bash command give it a time frame
and a frequency to execute on and it'll
just whatever that time frame hits ping
it so you can see a lot of the
correlations between dcos and these
services and frameworks as you've seen a
normal operating system yeah so typical
use I have my docker container I create
a job in Marathon hear it mezzos finds a
host to run it on sends the command to
the agent the agent pulls down the
docker container runs it with whatever
environment variables or arguments need
to be passed into it and yeah that's
that's kind of the typical use yeah I'll
handle oh no no quick demo
so this is what D cos looks like as a UI
so it shows what your utilization is
across the host obviously we're not
using our stuff very efficiently right
now you can see what services have been
spun up in D cos Chronos and marathon
are frameworks but they can also be run
inside of mezzo so here there's a little
bit of inception going on but Chronos
and marathon services running inside of
mezzos as well as communicating with
mezzos if we want wanted to set up a
schedule job we would jump into Chronos
come on Chronos and you could create a
job here it's been a little sluggish
come on Chronos
if we didn't do sufficient sacrifices to
our demo gods effectively here to pop up
you give it a command you give it a time
frame in it whenever that time frame
hits that will trigger the job via
marathon
order for having VPN problems
now we're dead
alright
yeah marathon you'd be able to see the
jobs that are already to find how many
instances they're running and you also
be given the option to scale it up or
down so it's is really well built for
scaling and high availability of your
application running in here obviously
this is a pretty small cluster and
conference Wi-Fi isn't awesome but yeah
we'll move forward I don't and take it
back over okay so it's good
thanks God okay so how many of you seen
Lord of the Rings yeah okay so I know we
just went over a lot of stuff right and
for the most part people haven't heard
of these technologies before so these
technologies are being moved towards
high utilization inside of companies
that guys are probably acquainted with
like for example if you go to the maze
oh's website you'll see a list of over
100 companies some of those are like
Airbnb and things like that that are
using the cluster to automatically speed
up processing and and do you kind of cpu
intensive tasks at scale so so alright
so now we're going to talk about initial
access inside the cluster so this talk
is more a post exploitation talk and
we're going to show you some brand new
empire modules that are going to enable
you to talk to these various building
blocks or services that are inside of
the DCOs cluster so that's that's kind
of the crutch of what we're getting too
but before we do that we got to get
initial access into the cluster right so
how many of you have ever hacked a
website before raising hands yeah so you
know there you go right so go over here
on the VPN okay great anco over here so
i have this at this container it's
running inside of our dcos cluster this
is publicly accessible in the internet
so it just has a vulnerable a vulnerable
PHP application so this isn't anything
crazy but if you see here I just wrote
really quickly this eval at PHP and if
you press pass eval and it'll show you
this so you just pass you all parameter
and that parameter just gets eval right
so you get system on it so you know
that's really trivial that's not
anything you know mind-blowing because
what we're trying to do is show what
happens once you
get remote code execution on inside a
web app inside of that cluster container
so coming over to here so I'm going to
ask this H out to my box and pray to
demo God's that this is going to work
all right i'm gonna drop from VPN see if
it works then ok we're on the box sweet
is that text clear big enough for you
guys or you want a bigger bigger all
right bigger it is i give the people
what they want alright is that good ok
alright sweet ok we're up on our box
we're a hacker right we've used this
eval shell to drop down a weave lee
shell on the box a weave Lee's like a
c99 a public shell that I frequently use
when I'm pentesting websites how many of
you raise your hands have heard of
Weasley before ok quite a bit cool so
it's kind of modular like metasploit you
can write additional code and it will
actually eval it on using a PHP email on
the server side and kind of keep it more
in memory so if someone does on file
disk analysis they'll just find the
highway randomized Weasley loader on the
remote side so if you haven't used we
flee before for web shells you should
definitely check it out although that's
not what this talks about so so I got a
bunch of screen sessions running on this
so I got one set up for we've Lee we've
Lee you give it the name of the Python
which is the operator side of weave Lee
then you give it the web address so you
can see here this is our website and
this is a you need a password interact
with it so I'm going to tear this off
the internet hopefully after the demo so
you guys can't hack my box but please
don't screw up my demos in the meantime
alright so when you drop into we've Lee
shell you just get this prompt if you
execute a regular command you can
execute commands just like you were on
the box if you want to execute a weave
Lee specific module you can just do
colon and then the module name or if
you're confused call and help will list
out all the modules so we're not we're
just going to use this to get
interactive
sweet so we got kind of a web shell on
the remote target inside this container
inside the DCOs cluster so we what we
really want to do is we want to get a
full interactive remote access tool
running in that room outside right so we
can you know pivot through the network
redirect things like that so how many of
you raise the hands you have you used
Empire before any any version Empire
okay a couple okay what about
meterpreter you guys use meterpreter
yeah a lot of you okay great so it's
just a post exploitation rot allows you
to interact with the system so there's
two versions of empire there's the
PowerShell version which is for windows
and then there's the Python version
which is more focused on OSX recently
code changes in it have enabled you to
also use that on a set of us and BSD
targets back porting support for 5.25
written in Python so so we want to get
Empire running on this box right so one
thing one catch people they're obsessed
with making their containers as small as
possible right so they want the least
amount of dependencies in the container
because they want them to be able to
easily scale and they want them not to
take up as much resources so what does
that mean for us as an attacker we don't
have as many options for post
exploitation as you might on a normal
next box a normal linux box so so let's
say we're all in this box we really want
to get Empire up and running on it so
normally if there python to be there we
just be able to execute Empire and be
good but if we do which python on the
box it doesn't return back anything
because pythons not installed inside the
container so I docker how many you guys
use docker before his hands yeah some of
you so doctor has a repo that's public
so I pulled down the top five containers
in the docker repo this is the top five
containers that people have downloaded
of the top five only one had Python
installed on it by D
so as a person who's trying to hack into
dcos clusters this poses a problem for
me so i built a stager a new stager for
Empire and I'm going to for all the new
stuff I'm going to push it in to do a
pull request tonight for it so you guys
check back tonight you'll see it's there
well at least in the pull request Intel
well or whoever is upset so alright cool
so we got oh yeah we got actually got to
show you guys that the solution so the
solution that I come up with is that
it's not the perfect solution but it
works is I built a Empire stager that
will actually build an elf binary using
pi installer so it's going to generate
your stage or inside an empire then it's
going to reach out to PI installer and
compile figure out what dependencies
that needs and then compile that all
back to an elf binary that you can just
remote up you can remotely drop that elf
binary in the target those you don't
know elf binaries are like EXT s for
linux systems so all right so here we go
let's go over to empire interact all
right have I lost anybody maybe but if
you guys have questions feel free all
right I get thumbs up so I'm just gonna
keep going so all right so i'm going to
show you guys how to use empire as part
of this i'm sure well did a much better
job the guys before but uh but i'll show
you my way so you just dot slash empire
and then then you need to establish a
listener first so there's a port that
we're going to bind to on the attacker
signed and this is what our Empire rat
it's going to be kin back to and we're
going to use to interact with the remote
container so right here if you copy what
I'm doing in this presentation in a real
pen toast you're gonna have really bad
OPSEC and probably get caught so you
might want to up the game a little bit
but I've just established the default
which is it's going to listen on port
8080 so when we execute the Empire rat
it's going to connect back to this
server on a DAT and then we're going to
be able to issue commands and all that
and I just name the name of the listener
test because trying to get stuff done so
then we do you stager
and then we just do PI installer so this
is a new thing right so but the other
state it works exactly like the other
stagers you just do you use stage you're
planning cellar it shows you all the
options you need to set the only one we
really care about right now is we need
to tell which listener to call back to
we only have one listener the test one
and that's bound to port 8080 TCP so set
listener to 88 or to test right and then
do info and then the only one other
thing you want to note here is it's
going to build the elf binary and chuck
it in temp and call it Empire right not
not too stealthy but nonetheless it's
going to work right so okay here you go
so what it does it's going to reach out
scan through a couple Python files
figure out what dependencies you need
klab those back together into this
Python file right here and then reach
out to PI installer and automatically
use it to and stuff to create the health
binary so elf binary is now made on this
remote system so if we go into / temp we
can see there's now a binary call elf
and if we file it we can see it is in
fact an elf sixty four-bit binary if you
want to do something crazy you're like I
really like where you're going but I
want to go put some crazy code in and
then how they compile it just for
convenience I left the source file here
and i left the spec file which is what
PI installer uses to compile and make
the elf so you can do some easy
customization they're kind of use this
to jump start okay and then just because
I'm just trying to demo things to you
guys today I'm just we're just going to
move these binaries into target by
basically doing a PHP version of WK
right so I started up just like a kind
of a hawk web server on this block and
you see the ad hoc web server is running
here but just in case you don't know
this trick this is a really cool trick
if you're on Python you need a really
quick HTTP webserver just do you pike on
tech em for module and then use simple
HTTP server and actually establish a web
server on the box and it will dish out
any files that are in that direct
so here we're going to dish out files
that are in / 10 so it's just kind of
convenient okay yeah let's push it back
okay here you go so that's just a trick
to because I'm do not like setting up
apache web servers just to pull it on a
file right so Oh shouldn't quit that a
wrong thing all right we're good all
right I just said a lot of words so
hopefully you guys are still tracking
with me here all right I swear once we
get in the network it's going to be like
butter okay so it's just way for it I
know it's a lot of setup for it alright
we're back in weave Lee now so we got a
double you get the binary we've Lee
makes this super easy it actually just
has a function and I'm going to find it
oh let's make sure it's not there from a
previous demo nope we're good now things
in / temp on the remote target now we're
going to use this module we've Lee
module 2 depth to basically w get the
file using PHP yeah we flee makes our
life easy so we just wait a second
because it's downloading a file files
now there we can even command up and we
flee and now we can see the files on the
remote target so we just need to make
sure we schmatte it and then to make
sure it's executable in the remote
target this is a linux box that we're
just going to kick it off using a using
just a straight command so this is the
weave lee the PHP shell is going to kick
off Empire the binary pulled down using
we flee from the simple Python server
okay all right here we go all right now
in an ideal scenario if we come back
around to empire will now see the
glorious text that we've all been
waiting for which
his initial agent from this IP is now
active right this means we got we got a
new agent inside the target Network so
if you tell you agents we can see all
the agents there's only one here and
then we just type interact and then the
name of the agent and then we can one
thing that is really helpful inside an
empire is the rename so we just rename
that to ever we want so I'm just going
to rename this to like a web app or
something so we can we can remember
where we are in the network's because
we're going to get it we're not going to
stop at one agent right we're going to
go through and tear this network up so
all right and I got to get back to the
slides because we're missing out on some
killer memes right so so is the top five
that I analyzed only one head Python and
that's the registry one the other four
top ones did not have Python so if we
use the PI installer trick we can get
around that yeah pack it up boys we're
going on a pony trip so so this is
pretty much us now we are that hacker
dude that's Scott master hacker and then
throwing lightning bolts we get our that
little icon with the Python that's like
the little iPod Empire logo I don't know
maybe you guys got some of the stickers
from before so we got that running
inside a container inside the DCOs
cluster so so what we first got to do
when we get inside ad cos or maize those
cluster is we want to orientate
ourselves by doing a little bit of recon
against some of those systems that hold
ya information about where services are
available in cluster one of the tenants
of the cluster is basically a slave can
die and a new slaves can come up and the
cluster will make sure like always three
of this container or running or always a
hundred of this container or runny and
it will realize how these those dive we
need to spend more up and and you also
do like traffic redirection through eh
eh
boxing all kinds of other stuff so all
right so i'm going to show you now how
to extract information from nasos dns
service so maze owes DNS it provides two
avenues to for you for containers or
services or apps to get information out
of it provides a traditional dns service
i'm not really going to talk about that
today any of your traditional dns
reconnaissance techniques will work
against that what i'm going to show you
is they have a new API that they build
out and that I feel like a lot of
developers are going to use to try and
orientate themselves inside the DCO west
cluster so I'm going to show you how to
extract information out of that and we
need that information to exploit more
stuff could i make an interjection yeah
go stretch it over so the the dns both
the service and the api is pretty
important to the whole ecosphere of
mezzos based on the concept that
basically any service could end up
popping up on any agent so in order to
figure out what like what resources
you're talking to you can't do that by
AP you have to be doing it by by dns
record so this isn't really something
that could easily be stripped out of all
of mezzos because the frameworks
themselves need it to know what end
points to talk to both IP and port
because either one of those could be
could be random well is random in most
cases ok great thanks Scott so
interacting with the web app Empire
agent so I wrote this module for Empire
it's it's really nothing more than it it
allows you to do dns lookups inside the
network i just wanted to show you
something about the DCOs cluster so you
kind of understand the easiest way to
kind of orientate yourself once you get
initial access so there's a there's a
TLD called
call mezzos so and most of the services
will have a name under that so master
mezzos once you get inside the network
will resolve to the master marathon
mezzos will resolve to the marathon box
Kronos dummies those words onto the
Kronos box and then you can also see
what people things are co-hosted because
they're going to give you back the same
IP so if we just do we just said master
may see us and then execute then it just
shows us hey it's on this 10 dot address
inside the internal network so it's
doing a DNS woke up so so go into
something a little bit more I mean
that's really simple right you could do
that using ping or anything on a box I
want to show you a module that I wrote
that a so so the next thing you really
want to do is I wrote this other module
it's mais o Dinah's API and numerate so
when looking through the source code and
i found an api function called enumerate
it is basically the equivalent of a zone
transfer so it will dump all of the data
about everything in the cluster that
maze those dns knows so I don't think
this is undocumented but it's also not
in the documentation so but the
developers do talk about it like in
github issues so i don't think i think
the documentation is just not been
updated yet so but you I mean you can
you can have your own opinion on that so
mais OU SDNS it listens on tcp port 8
123 and we can just determine that where
that is because it's usually coasted on
the master and
and this will just make an a web request
out to it call the HTTP API and then it
will collect the JSON it returns the
results in a JSON format and then Empire
is just going to record those down to
disk so you can see this worked it
recorded it to disk right here and I'm
just going to show you what it looks
like because a couple modules kind of do
the same thing but I just
but I just want you to kind of be able
to visualize more what this looks like
from an attackers perspective
okay so it just returns back this JSON
blob and the first thing is going to
tell us is the frameworks that are in
the cluster and then it's going to say
hey inside this framework there's tasks
and inside here there's this proxy and
this proxy is on this slave like this
physical hardware box that's the IP of
it in the cluster and then the most
important thing that this is going to
give us though is the IP and then the
random high port so one of the things
you're going to find with dcos and maze
OSAS services are come services are
coming ups going up and down and every
time they do on a slave their service is
not going to bind to a normal port so
even though this is probably a proxy for
Apache or another web service it's going
to bind to these random high ports so
querying the dns service and figuring
out what those are it's going to enable
us to further exploit additional
services and what we really want out of
this is want this Chronos because
Chronos is kind of like crontab for the
DCOs data center so if we can interact
with Chronos we can schedule malicious
task and execute them and so here we see
that a Chronos is on dot one sixty and
then the most important thing is Chronos
is random high port is 6 1 2 3 2 so you
could I guess scan the whole cluster to
figure these stuff out but it's just
easier to ask right all right sweet
alright so we know where Chronos is in
the cluster now so now we can do a
little bit more pwnage
what I'm god 35 oh ok cool
so when you set up your cluster inside
your data center yeah most people use
that TLD 40 the question is do most
people use the mezzos domain name is
that it so and the answer is yes like a
lot of people are hard baking that into
their infrastructure I when it's used by
a lot of the frameworks by default and
then to you have to have some way to
discover where the services are so you
can interact with each other the real
problem here is that there's really no
uh there's no are back right so there's
like why does a web app need to be able
to ask where the Chronos cluster is
doesn't right but it can get everything
so which I think they're working on but
it's kind of like a work in progress so
okay cool so we can also interact with
the master via its API and then the one
thing that this is going to give us is
it will give us a complete list of all
the slaves that are there all the IP
addresses are in the cluster that could
be slaves that are in the cluster that
we want to get on but are just like
don't have any docker containers on
currently so we kind of missed those if
we just went after the dns service so
just going to kind of skip over that
because it's the Zack same thing
research it's another module really seen
and then returns back a JSON blob got
recon for sure okay all right so we got
our Empire agent and then we got Chronos
running in a container inside the
cluster we now know where that is by our
reconnaissance modules so now we're
going to interact with that to get
additional empires inside of it all
right so I got really excited because I
was like great we're not going to run
inside a container anymore we're going
to use Chronos to pop out and run as
root on these on these hosts so we
should be able to natively use Empire
without having to comply to the elf
binary
that that premise did not work out so
the core rest is kind of another strip
down OS designed for loading of
containers and the version of Python
that's installed on it by default does
not have URL led to which is a
requirement right now for easy Empire
natively so it's not a big deal we just
use the elf by you again but I was a
little bit disappointed right so all
right come around to here
alright so we can do the Recon the only
thing about the Recon that you really
want to take know is uh against the
mezzos master is it it listens on tcp
for 50 50 and for the most part people
aren't going to change that because all
the slaves or agents are gonna have to
talk back to that okay so here we go is
where it starts to get a little bit
funner so I wrote this module it's
called Chronos API list jobs and what
it's going to do is inside of Corrado's
which is here we can see we can
visualize the list of the jobs right so
this is going to interact with the API
pull back a JSON blob that's going to
have this do the thing Chronos job in
there and all this job is really doing
inside of our cluster right now is it
saying hey execute the sleep command on
the box so this is kind of just a demo
thing but so what I like to do is I list
all the jobs in the Chronos framework
then I can add job that looks really
similar to the other jobs to blend in
and then execute that job and then
delete that job so I'm clean because I
don't want someone to come in and find
my job my malicious job so so so we get
a listing just by interacting with the
Chronos mezzos TLD we just execute on
that and that's going to save back a
list of all the jobs to this JSON blob
just looks pretty identical to the last
two songs that showed you so I'm not
going to that up but and then and then
now let's go out a job right now that we
know what the jobs are let's go out a
job
so Chronos API add job we do info okay
so the couple things we need to do here
like one where's Chronos in the network
we can pretty much use the TLD trick to
do that then to these parameters right
here we mostly just want to blend in
with what we listed out like we probably
don't want to make up an owner that
doesn't exist somebody might get
suspicious if they have logging enabled
about that and then the name of the job
or the description of the job is when
you click on the job and the GUI you can
see the descriptions right here so you
just want to blend that in and then the
name right here we want to blend that
into so I just call mine scheduled jobs
you're 01 description scheduled job 001
and then the main thing that we want to
change here is the the port right so the
mezzos is going to automatically deploy
the container inside the DCOs cluster so
remember we have to use the DNS recall
and to figure out what port it was so if
you guys were I think it was 6 2 3 2
okay great and then by default this is
just executing the ID command so we want
to do something a little bit more
malicious than that so go over here and
we're just going to execute this this
one liner here which is going to set the
command to curl the Empire binary that
is available via our Python simple HTTP
server set it as executable schmatte it
and then execute it on on the witch and
so we're not really specifying if you
notice which slave or agent to execute
this on the framework is going to figure
out what has resources and just randomly
deploy it there so i'm working on a
newer version of the module right now
that actually is going to let you set
that parameter because i found a way to
do that but but that'll take a look
they'll be like a week or two before i
get that out so so we just set that and
then you can type info and then you can
see are malicious command is set up
there
well good and then we type execute so
with Chronos it's kind of a two-step
thing we're going to add it and then
it's kind of like it wants like a cron
schedule so we could set the cron if we
know the remote targets time or assume
the remote targets time is similar to
our own so that it would execute like in
five minutes or something that I don't
know if you guys remember like
scheduling at jobs and Windows domains
and classic stuff like that we could we
could do that same thing here but
there's actually an API call that just
says xq now so so I wrote another module
for that but hopefully this one comes
back it worked one buddy don't do that
go back
let's screw something up it's got hard
to tell what the resolution a
I'll make it big again once I
about just 32 16 32 web a command kronos
try different job name oh you think the
job okay let's just go check agents oh
no okay all right all right oh that's
right we didn't set it to run yeah so
yeah but that sleep so it should so let
me jump in really quickly so in the
kronos job definitions it's not a normal
cron schedule it's not like star 1 star
star whatever you specify a start time
and a period so if you say go 2040 like
a 24 hour time period but start sometime
in the past it'll fire immediately and
then it will fire 24 hours later so it's
not a normal cron schedule it's a start
time and period which is kind of it's a
little bit different no
all right that's okay so
yeah we it should it should show up here
if it was working from a tiny be having
a hard time all right okay just one
minute jump back into we've Lee all
right you still see it's executing
interact again with this session take
off another one thanks
go back around to empire okay agents in
Iraq g7 I ok go here you this module is
the simply too simple Python servers to
ruin oh that's like well it should
fashion a matter for this right but yeah
we should we should check that to set
this set the poor
okay and then do execute in the remote
target Network okay there we go okay all
right so hopefully it shows up now here
I don't know why though their empire
died okay there we go here's our job AAA
you can see it's malicious you can also
see the last time it ran was never so we
haven't started it yet if we actually
set the timings correct on it we could
get it to like schedule out for five
minutes but a it's just easier in my
opinion to use this other API call and
hopefully I'll be able to consolidate
these all into like one module and then
your future then execute okay come on
buddy oh the name is wrong that's
changed it setname to AAA and then
execute
okay great so you should see over here
in a second it's going to refresh and
then it's going to say runny so we got
running now and that's great because
hopefully it pulled back down our Empire
and we got a new empire agent on the
inside the system so so we go to agents
and we can interact with the new one and
uh so cool part about Empire is you can
see who you're running ads over here so
you can see we're running as apache on
the first two ones then this new one
we're running as root so and then we
could just make sure we're running as
root by doing a shell ID execute and you
can see comes back with ID command so so
oh thanks as a long road but but so also
yeah you want to schedule job and it's
executed so so that's that's basically
the diagram we had the agent because we
popped a web server we talked to Kronos
framework after doing recall and you
figure out where it is and now we got
Empire run yazoo inside the cluster
right you could just repeat that until
you get a code execution on every single
slave or agent as root inside the
cluster yeah or working on the new
technique to get you took more targeted
in the network ok cool I'm just going to
check time oh we're pretty high in time
so I'm not going to do this one but
figure it out this how to do the same
thing but instead of interacting with
pronouns we just interact directly with
marathon I've never seen anyone run a
maze O's cluster without marathon you
could technically not have Chronos in
there but uh you pretty much knew the
marathon so if you can talk to marathon
you can do the same thing it's the same
process you need marathon right yeah
yeah yeah you're pretty jacked about it
alright so that was that demo I'm
skipping it your data centers too
pretentious and that would get us a
slate running as root doctor is running
Empire running another slave all right
so all right yeah so once you own the
cluster like you can spin up jobs you
can spin those things out you'll notice
that at no point did we do any kind of
container breakout to go from having
access in this container to having
agents running as root on the other
agents so once you get there where can
you go DCOs is highly automated bull and
most the time when people are using it
they're going to be interested in in
tightening up their release pipeline so
a lot of times you'll see DCOs you also
people see people doing the same kind of
like really high speed releases like
automated everywhere from a push to get
to a new version of your application
coming out and running in production
what that means is you'll often see
these boxes and production with access
back to some point where bill artifacts
live that could be back to get directly
it's almost guaranteed to be back to
some kind of doctor private registry so
by looking at the job definitions that
you'll see in marathon and Chronos
you'll see the credentials and the
locations that you need to go back in
pull more pieces of information out it
could be useful for in your pen test
most of the time these applications
running the docker containers are not
going to be completely self-contained
either like they'll need some kind of
persistent storage out to a database out
to an object store somewhere that they
can maintain state that means that these
configure the credentials that the
application will need needs to get into
that container somehow that's either
going to happen as part of creating the
docker container Jenkins may bake those
in and then ship it off to the doctor
registry or it could be defined in the
job definition as environment variables
there's a couple things you can do there
to try and make it a little bit more
difficult but eventually the application
is going to need those credentials to
remote resources so if you have control
of the cluster you have control of all
the avenues of getting that those
credentials in so recommendations on how
to trim some of this down some of the
components in dcos do have
authentication available most the time
is not set up by default a lot of the
frameworks all
basic authentication some of the
frameworks require zero authentication
and you can't set up any authentication
otherwise it'll break the whole
framework so wherever possible on your
frame works on zookeeper enable
authentication enable it on the UI
enable it on the API try and limit that
down as much as you can one attack
Avenue that we didn't really talk about
was slave authentication if you had
visibility to zookeeper on the mat on
the mezzos master you can spin up a
malicious slave register and start
receiving jobs from the master so make
sure you turn on agent and framework
authentication and yeah hope nothing
breaks definitely test it out first next
is segmentation for the demos Bryce
compromised the container and then was
able to immediately hit the mezzos like
the control plane from there most
situations there's no need for that to
happen there are a handful of
technologies you can use to shove the
whole IP stack into the container you
override the docker bridge with another
way to access the network you can use a
project like calico which then can put
down a BGP overlay allowing the commute
the communications between the
containers on different hosts yeah try
to do everything you can to segment IP
access from the container to only the
resources it needs don't open up the
management plane if you don't need to
next update like this is pretty
cutting-edge stuff mezzos 1 point 0 was
released like five days ago and had some
security features in there that we
haven't really been able to do a
thorough exploration of right now in
versions we did an evaluation of there's
no role based access control meaning if
you get into D cos you're an admin and
you can see your jobs you can see
everybody's jobs with the new version of
mezzos there's some role based access
control in there that's supported at the
mezzo Slayer the frameworks still have
to catch up to that in order to really
make use of it
yeah so a couple companies that are
using mezzos this is typically used by
organizations that need to run products
at scale do your info SEC feud yeah okay
cool infosec feud so I just wanted to
see like what's the most egregious thing
I could find on the internet right so
there we go right so there's really no
reason for any of these services to be
on the internet they should at least be
protected to force you to get a foothold
in the network before you can pivot to
them but I thought let's let's see let's
go to a major cloud provider let's see
how many people have poor 8123 open and
let's see what I can do like just a
little bit of recon nothing too crazy
right so looking at me Bezos DNS how
many servers do you think we're
accessible via the Internet by a quick
scan of a club yeah I said yeah I was
hoping for a lot more but uh I found 54
by scanning one cloud provider so that
were open on the internet so so a little
bit and then should we jump back one so
each one of those represents an entire
cluster which could be two machines it
could be a thousand machines so that's
not 54 boxes that's fifty four clusters
yeah and then how many of them do you
guys think my zone transfer trick worked
against it I thought it was going to be
100 is about fifty percent and that's
because I think it's a newer feature so
only about half of them are up to date
so so that's why that's my theory I
don't know you can go do your own
research yeah yeah okay all right so um
you can also interact directly with the
mezzos master so I just did a quick scan
of that how many do you think we're
directly accessible from the internet
okay I'll tell you so 41 is what I found
so these are things if you just know how
to talk to protocol you could tell them
to execute commands as across their
entire clusters right so it's kind of
kind of a big deal and then the one that
I was really surprised about what
zookeeper so I thought okay there's like
50 boxes for these other two services
probably about the same person keeper
anybody want to take a stab at how many
zookeeper servers i found on the
internet 3,000 and so why this is is
because zookeeper predates dcos and
mezzos and so a lot more services
required a zookeeper but how many of
these do you think enabled
authentication on them under twenty
percent so eighty-two percent have no
authentication on them so this in my
opinion is an entire like Redis like
situation where you just have rightist
databases on the internet with no
authentication with super sensitive data
in them I think you kind of the same
scenario would see Cooper going on right
now on the internet so I mean
technically I didn't release modules for
it but you could get code execution
through zookeeper depending on what its
uses right so but at the bare minimum
it's super easy just to pull up a
zookeeper GUI and browse over and view
sensitive data so that's my last meme
thanks to these dudes for making Empire
because that's where all the modules are
written for then you guys saw him them
talk right before this and that's it if
you guys want to talk
as any questions just weird like I got a
couple of doctors greedy boats to go
away you must feel awesome question oh
yeah great questions the great let's do
it Joey I played for more minutes and
just quick announcement 7 p.m. till we
closing ceremonies the children so any
one question haha i love that question
that's question best question you rockin
the question I don't know alright thanks
guys