hey folks welcome to breaking ground I
hope you guys had a nice lunch
and are not too sleepy because we're
doing six degrees of domain admin we're
going to learn about Active Directory
privilege escalation so I'm pretty
excited before we begin I'd like to
thank our sponsors really quickly
besides is sponsored this time by a very
spry creativity Amazon tenable and
source of knowledge they all are hanging
out in our chill-out lounge so go say hi
get some cool swag if you could please
turn off your cellphone's or turn them
on silent and be respectful that would
be nice and that's all I have for you so
I'll hand it over to the speakers let
them introduce themselves and take it
away yeah all right welcome everybody
the title of our talk is six degrees of
domain admin if you're not familiar with
what this reference is there's this
thing called six degrees of Kevin Bacon
where you can take any actor any movie
and in six degrees of separation you can
more than likely connect that person or
movie or director or whoever to Kevin
Bacon so we've taken that same concept
and we've applied it to Active Directory
privilege escalation and we were super
excited to talk about it so let's go to
the next slide my name is andy robbins
i've been a professional penetration
tester for four years i originally cut
my teeth in the financial services
industry focusing on community and
regional size credit unions and banks if
you're interested in talking about ACH
files i would love to talk to those
about talk about those with you
otherwise you can find me on twitter at
at school or waldo with a zero at the
end
testers in Paris I've been in the doing
countries testing for about two and a
half years now I contribute to a bunch
of open-source projects namely
eyewitness and he's way more than that
so hi my name is wall Schrader my handle
is harm joy I'm one of the big kind of
offensive developers in our team and I
also do offensive red team pen testing
type engagements I'm the co-founder lead
developer or one of the main developers
on the Vale framework Power View power
up Empire all that kind of fun stuff
cool all right so first we're gonna talk
about kind of what the current state of
Active Directory domain privilege
escalation is so by a show of hands can
I ask anybody who was involved in ad
security at all either on offense or
defense cool so most of the room awesome
so you should be pretty familiar with
the concepts that we're going to be
talking about so let's go ahead and go
to the next slide so if you're involved
in Active Directory security you have
more than likely seen this quote it's
probably one of the most overused quotes
in our industry so John Lambert the
general manager at the Microsoft threat
intelligence Center had a blog post with
this title so defenders think enlists
attackers think and graphs as long as
this as long as this is true attackers
will win so why would it would ask
everybody is just keep this thought in
mind during our talk what I'm hoping
that we can show you is that not only
our attackers thinking and graphs but
now we're actually going to be using
them as well all right so Active
Directory as we all know is effectively
ubiquitous across the entire world if
you see Shawn Metcalfe stalk at Def Con
or blackhat one of the points that he
brings up is that 98% of the fortune 500
companies in America use Active
Directory pretty much a given right so
what is that ubiquity mean that ubiquity
means that Active Directory gets a lot
of attention both from the defensive
perspective and also the offensive
perspective there's a lot of time
research money effort blood sweat tears
that goes into understanding how best to
defend and attack Active Directory
environments so as penetration testers
and as red teamers what that means is
that every so often we get these nice
easy buttons that make our jobs super
awesome and we get to look like an elite
hacker because we popped a box with MSO
eight oh six seven or we escalated
rights to da with MS 1468 and like yes I
am an awesome hacker because I used a
certain module to do that right so these
easy buttons as awesome as they are are
also ephemeral they have a tendency to
go away as especially as our client
organizations mature certain practices
so their vulnerability management
practices get better they're actually
starting to pay attention to some of the
things that we've been saying for years
run vulnerability scanners do centralize
patch management audit the results of
those what does that mean that means
that you have a certain window of
opportunity to use those easy buttons on
your assessments unless your client is
really not at that stage yet which is
also a lot of fun so let's go ahead and
go to the next slide so here's a typical
situation that you might find yourself
when you're on a pen test that you are
focusing on Active Directory so you get
your initial foothold into the
environment maybe this is a meterpreter
session that you got from phishing maybe
this is beacon if you use cobalt strike
maybe you started off with lair to
access and you use responder to get your
initial privilege on a machine somewhere
in the in the environment now thanks to
some work by will Schroeder you can use
PowerShell and power of you to collect
information about the environment that
you're in so all of these like dotted
boxes these are gonna represent systems
that we know exists in the environment
but we don't have any kind of privilege
to yet additionally we can find out
where a domain admin user is logged on
you don't need administrative rights to
find this information who like by a show
of hands who does this all the time like
on your assessment you're using like
invoke user
Hunter you're using getting a session
you're finding out where the target is
in the environment what box you need to
land on and run them to cats and steal
their credential all right now in this
kind of like you know maybe a little
less mature type environment let's say
you're able to escalate your rights
locally on the system
you run hash dump you collect the ntlm
hashes for local users including the rid
500 user and maybe they've applied KB to
eight seven one nine nine seven the
passive hash killer but not really pass
the hash killer patch or maybe they
haven't bottom line is you escalate
rights on this one machine and then you
gain kind of notional administrator
privileges to everything in the
environment so did that click work okay
there we go cool so the solid blue lines
on these computers are going to
represent systems that we now have the
ability to pivot to and lo and behold
who should appear but the domain admin
on this system that we can pivot to so
we put it over to that machine we run
them at Katz's we collect that domain
admins password and clear text and we
win we're awesome we're pen testers
really tax ORS we give the report to the
client and they think that were most of
they're the most amazing person on the
planet right who's done an assessment
where the escalation path looked almost
exactly like that a lot of you awesome
so let's take a look at a slightly
different environment so again we get
our initial access through beacon
meterpreter responder whatever you got
your initial access and again you can
figure out where the domain admin is
logged in on the environment
however this environment actually does
have fairly mature patch management
vulnerability management processes so
you can't find NSO eight oh six seven
you can't find Tomcat you can't find
JBoss pitcher pod has been gone for a
decade right so let's hit next let's say
that eventually we do find some kind of
privilege I would say that nine times
out of ten the way that we on our
operations usually get our initial
foothold into an environment are clear
text credentials that are left over in
open file shares and what I mean by open
file
shares our shares that any user who is
authenticated to Active Directory has
the ability to read so what does that
most commonly mean like GPP login
scripts etc we find this all the time so
let's say in this situation we found
that as well at this point we need to
make a choice we need to make our best
educated guess on what system is the
best to pivot to we see these three
users in these systems that we can pivot
to but we know that none of them are a
domain admin and we also known it we
also know that none of them have local
administrator rights on that system that
the GA that the DA was logged on in the
first place so essentially we have to
guess or you can go through the analysis
which is a royal pain so let's say we
make a choice we just said we're gonna
pivot to this guy's box next we find out
what systems does this new user that we
have the ability to impersonate have
access to and we find out that our scope
of administrator privileges in the
environment is starting to grow very
slowly now we needed to make another
choice we can either say all right well
I have these two other boxes in this
first stage that I could pivot to so do
I want to go there or do I want to go to
one of these new boxes that I have
privileged on let's say I choose to go
to this one in the top right I see that
maybe there's something in his user
account properties that indicates like
maybe he has some kind of privilege like
he's a sequel admin or he's a you know
he's a patch management type admin
something like that a wsus admin now we
pivot to that guy system and figure out
what critic what admin rights does this
new user have in the environment when we
find out there's nothing new we are
still where we were and so we're going
through this kind of credential dance
this kind of credential shuffle where we
have to go to this box get the password
find out way of admin rights - and if we
fail like we did just now we have to go
a step back and it sucks and you get
really upset and you reset and you make
another guess and so this time we guess
let's go to this guy over here
and then find out what admin rights this
new user has so lo and behold what
should appear but this new user that we
just popped has admin rights on the
system with where the DA was logged on
awesome so what does that give us that
gives us access to the domain admin
account which now we have access to the
entire environment so this kind of like
credential shuffle or what microsoft for
to refers to as an identity snowball
attack by a show of hands who has
executed an attack path like this most
of you awesome sweet I'm glad you're
here so this concept we refer to as
derivative local admin our co-worker
Justin Warner termed this phrase after
seeing this kind of pattern on our
assessments over and over and over and
over the way that Justin describes this
is the chaining or linking of
administrator rights through
compromising other privileged accounts
makes sense good definition concise so
put another way let's say we have this
user Bob okay now bob has Abin rights to
this computer called PC one on PC one is
this user named Mary Mary has Evan
rights on this system called PC 2 so Bob
derives administrator privileges to PC 2
through compromising Mary as she is
logged on to PC 1 another way that this
can happen is through security group
delegation in Active Directory so let's
say that Bob is a member of a group
called helpdesk let's say that helped us
doesn't have any privileges in the
environment however helpdesk is also a
member of this group called server
admins
which does have privilege in the
environment that delegation that write
that privilege rolls downhill
as you add groups into groups so bob is
a member of that group that group is a
member of that group that group has
admin rice at PC too
Bob has happen rights of PC to every but
that makes sense so far awesome
all right so while the derivative local
admin attack is highly effective and I
would say that on almost a hundred
percent of our engagements if we get any
kind of privilege given enough time we
can turn that privilege into domain
admin or enterprise admin there are some
significant challenges and weaknesses
with this approach as well first of all
this approach is extremely
time-consuming and tedious work every
step of the way you're having to reset
and gain your new situational awareness
you need to find out where does this
user that I now have access to have
privilege that means that you're going
to touch possibly every system in the
environment again which if you're on a
Red Team assessment or you're trying to
evade detection is bad news bears don't
want to do that
we want to hit every system one time and
get all the information that we need so
additionally the information that you're
getting when you're executing this
attack path is not comprehensive so the
biggest weakness I would say is this
right here so you take your report to
your client you say here is this attack
path that attack path you really
couldn't understand or identify until it
was already executed additionally there
are probably other attack paths in the
environment that unfortunately is just
not really possible to know about
without some kind of tool like what we
are talking about today next you have
limited situational awareness during the
entire course of your escalation process
okay finally you may not have even
needed domain admin rights in the first
place to meet your objective if your
objective was to get access to a sequel
server or a web server it makes sense to
go after a DA because that da is gonna
have access to what you need or they're
gonna have access to the workstation who
has a user on it that has the access
that you need cool so we're gonna be
talking about graph theory briefly so go
back in time go back to computer science
102 if you don't have a CS background
don't worry because neither do i but
this is pretty easy to understand we're
all seem to be talking about the design
of our attack path everybody good so far
alternating heads cool so what are the
basic elements of a graph first of all
in a graph you have vertices vertices
represent an individual element of a
represented system so put another way
let's say that we are building a GPS
program right
Google Maps funfact uses graphs for for
navigation purposes let's say this to
Washington is a vertex Portland Oregon
may also be a vertex Walla Walla
Washington could be a vertex Las Vegas
could be a vertex next we have edges
edges generically represent the
relationship that connect these vertices
if Seattle Washington is a vertex and
Portland Oregon is a vertex interstate
five is the edge that connects those two
vertices finally we have paths paths are
a collection of vertices and edges that
connect otherwise disparate or
disconnected nodes so there is not a
highway that directly connects Las Vegas
to Seattle Washington but there is a
collection of interstates state highways
towns that you can go through that will
get you from point A to point B awesome
put in a visual context we have two
vertexes or two vertices in this graph
we have vertex one and vertex two there
is also an edge that connects vertex one
to vertex two it is a directed edge so
it is one way only you cannot go from
vertex 2 to vertex one against the wrong
direction against this edge you can go
from vertex 1 to vertex 2 on this slide
let's talk a little bit about paths as
you can see and like this is this is
fairly like simple to look at and
understand vertex 1 to vertex 4 there is
pretty obviously a path okay from vertex
3 to vertex 4 is there a path there's
not because these edges are one-way make
sense cool so
we have a tool that we are going to be
demoing called bloodhound the design for
the bloodhound graph is as follows the
vertices in the bloodhound graph
represent the basic objects in Active
Directory every user group computer and
domain is a vertex the edges really the
edges represent the relationships
between these different vertices which
I'll talk about in more depth on the
next slide finally the paths the paths
of the most critical part of bloodhound
the paths always point towards
escalating rights or always towards
compromising a system or compromising a
user or a user who's a member of a
specified group so let's take a look at
this visually like I said every vertex
is an active directory object so we have
two users on this graph we have Bob and
Mary we have two groups IT admins and
domain admins and we have a computer
called server one next we determine the
group memberships so we see that Bob is
a member of the group called IT admins
we see that Mary is a member of the
group called domain admins next we
determine privilege we determine what
groups what users have administrator
privileges to what objects so this group
called IT admins has admin rights to
this computer called server one finally
we determine who is logged on where and
we find that Mary is logged on to this
computer so this computer has a session
called Mary can you see the path from
Bob to domain admins awesome so let's
put this really simply first of all all
the information that we're talking about
here you do not need privileged to
gather in Active Directory
thanks to winning t providers API calls
will is going to go into a little more
depth on that so we need three pieces of
information we need to know what users
are logged on to what machines again you
could find that without privilege
secondly we need to find out who has
Evan writes where
you don't need privilege to do and
finally we need to find out what users
belong to what groups and what groups
belong to what groups this is all we
need is all the information we need to
build our graph I'm gonna pass it over
to will cool all right so I'm gonna go
over some stealthy data collection what
Power View so did anyone read the
paceman dump from Tania's Fisher from
the hacking team stuff we obviously do
not condone in any way using our tools
for illicit purposes but uh you know
thanks Phineas for the the publicity I
suppose for calling out Power View so
there's a little bit of a surprise scene
seeing all that in there so what is
Power View Power View is a pure
powershell 2.0 compliant Windows domain
of situational awareness tool it kind of
came about from you know starting to do
these more advanced red team engagements
and starting to do this kind of you know
the the precursor to these types of path
hopping manually when I when I first
started about two and a half years ago
and I took a lot of this tradecraft and
began to automate it using PowerShell
which our favorite term for it is
Microsoft's post exploitation language
so the entire project is one single file
it self-contained you don't have to
install any additional modules you don't
have to you know drop anything to disk
we like to run Power View very
frequently through cobalt straight to
beacon it's also pretty much completely
implemented into the PowerShell Empire
project which I spoke on in this room
last year about so go back real quick
Power View will collect all the data
that bloodhound needs to build as a tech
grass and also has some really nice
export functions and transformation
functions built specifically for
bloodhound which I'll go over and again
if you have elevated rights in a domain
meaning domain Aven or server admin you
can get much more information but you
can get a huge amount of this
information even if you are a basic
unprivileged domain user so I'm gonna go
through the three different areas of
information that Andy said we're
required for this attack rack design and
show you how power View collects that
data under the hood so the first thing
is who's logged in where we turned this
user hunting
so the main function for this and
PowerView is invoked user hunter is one
of the first ones that we ran so there's
a tool net few exe written by Rob fuller
that did something kind of similar at a
more basic level in a compile C++ binary
kind of took that expanded upon it and
ran with it made it a much more flexible
solution so invoked user hunter will use
to power view functions under the hood
it uses getting that session and getting
it logged on and getting it logged on
local so getting that session uses the
net session enum windows api under the
hood and it does some like really nice
fancy trickery and PowerShell to access
that without dropping any files to disk
getting that logged on uses network
station and um and the logged on local
is a new addition that uses remote
registry if it's enabled you can run
these and get this information back
without being without needing
administrative rights and the remote
system your query there's also a stealth
option what this will do is it
enumerates all the users in the entire
domain and it pulls out all like the
file paths profile paths and those
particular type of Active Directory
properties which might indicate a file
server being used so it gets a set of
hot likely highly traffic servers that
most users touch and then it just runs a
git net session against each one and you
can map back what users are logged on
where again with no elevated privileges
alright now who can admin what we have
the first piece on who's located where
now we need to know how to take those
pieces and say who can actually triage
this access so this is one of the
craziest things to me found this about
two and a half years ago I think there
wasn't a huge amount of information
about it publicly but we can enumerate
the members of a local group on a remote
system without needing administrative
privileges on that system I have no idea
why this is allowed we're super happy
it's allowed these otherwise this tool
might not exist but it kind of blows my
mind there's two ways to do this the
first is using Quebec real quick the
first is using something called the win
inti service provider which is a
backwards compatibility type artifact in
Windows so this was a remnant of like
Windows NT domain deployments or the net
local group members windows api call
with both these you can just point them
to a remote server and it'll just
bit back not just what the not just the
user that's a part of the local
administrators or any other local group
you would like like remote desktop you
can also get the SID last logon time
password last change and a huge amount
of information that an unprivileged user
has no right enumerated from these
remote systems but we're allowed to
empower view if you want to execute this
you can do the get net local group one
of the most common functions that will
run you can just do a computer name an
IP NetBIOS name and if you would like to
use the API method instead of winning to
the winning t approach which is the
default you can pass the optional - API
flag this is a bit of a new addition a
few months ago I did a little bit of
work which on Metcalfe and we realized
that you can actually correlate group
policy object information to determine
the same type of data so GPOs
group policy objects are just
collections of settings that are applied
to particular machines one of these
settings is who is the member of the
local administrators group on the
machine it makes sense it lets you do
really easy you know kind of mass
management of this type of data and
enterprise so if we correlate this data
and do a little bit of trickery in the
backend and if you're interested in this
you know talk to me in the hallway I
love this stuff but through just
querying information on a domain
controller so we're not touching every
single system like we did with the
previous approach we're only talking to
a domain controller or pulling group
policy object back information back
we're linking that with where those
policies are applied for sites and OU's
and we can get a really nice mapping of
who can administer what machines with
just communication to a domain
controller which is super normal
there's I can't imagine a way this would
be detected maybe there's some thinner
they can detect anomalous LDAP queries
but I haven't seen it yet and it's much
faster but you don't get quite as much
information it's not quite as accurate
so the Power View command let that does
this is fine GPO location you can
provide a user name or group name if you
want to figure out what a specific
person can administer in the domain by
default it'll just dump all this data
out sweet the last part is who's in what
groups this is the the simplest one of
all
so we want to numerate all the groups
just follow the group names through held
up and then pull out the membership
reach and power view we can do this
pretty easily getting that group pipe it
to get that group member if you're not
familiar your PowerShell this is the
pipeline it passes fully serialize
objects between different commandlets or
functions that you're running so a lot
of times by hand we might do get knit
group of wildcards to say okay who are
what groups I've admin in them and then
let me enumerate all those users and
things like that if you do this by
default it'll just dump out all the
nested group relationships in the entire
domain and that's it pretty simple the
least crazy of all of them so power
views existed for a couple years again
we've been doing a lot of these
approaches manually bloodhound is going
to include a slightly customized version
of Power View that has a couple extra
functions in it what we call the
bloodhound and gesture so there's three
commandlets there are three functions
that are built into the bloodhound
version there's - bloodhound data and
this will automate you know enumerate in
every machine in the domain and either
by default touching every machine and
gathering this information for
completeness there's also the stealth
options you know just hit DC's just do
sessions you know there's tons of
flexibility with how to run it the
second one is export bloodhound data
which will take all these objects that
are returned from get bloodhound data
it'll JSON Oh fie them up and build the
custom cipher queries that are used by
the the backend solution for bloodhound
and it stuffed them into a REST API for
ingestion so the key here is we can do
all this without touching discs if we
want to and we have the ability to bend
our traffic back to the analysis server
that we control and also we have the
option to just export all this stuff to
a custom CSV schema that we developed so
if you can't or if you don't have the
bandwidth through an agent to actually
send all this data back and don't want
to wait you can export it to a CSV
exfill that CSV somehow and bloodhound
will accept CSD ingestion as well
awesome okay we're almost ready to show
it to you but we got a couple of other
housecleaning items to share with you so
bloodhound is the name of the product a
couple of facts about bloodhound let's
go to the next slide and the first item
on here is that bloodhound is a web
application that is built with link
curious Jas Lane curious enabled us to
quickly prototype and get the thing into
a state where it was actually usable
without becoming experts in like d3 or
Sigma which are the most widely used
graph drawing libraries for JavaScript
next we stuff everything into an
electron binary so it is platform
independent
it doesn't require a web server to use
we're trying to make it as operationally
friendly to use as possible next it uses
neo4j as its graph database we decided
to go with neo4j
and we also just got decided to go with
lean curious because they offered free
and open source solutions that we could
use to keep our tool free and open
source
finally the information to go into the
database is fed right now exclusively by
the powershell and gesture that will is
just talking about all right so I
believe we have a video showing a
demonstration of how easy it is to use
this operationally for collecting
information once you have your initial
access into Active Directory
you want talk to this will okay so in
this case we're just showing it from a
Windows system you could do this over a
remote rat if you like we imported the
PowerShell scripts straight off the disk
but we could also do this into memory if
that's what we'd like to do this is a
slightly older versions the syntax has
changed a bit we apologize but the we're
gonna have a ton of documentation of
wiki and stuff that this shows exactly
how to use it in the current state so
we're gonna run give bloodhound data I
know the text is a bit small um just get
bloodhound data and passing the you are
URI for the REST API ingestion and point
it's really nice with neo4j is we also
have a batch congestion and points here
and having to do a call every single
time you can batch up like a go 1,000
queries at once and just stuff it into
the backend database through here we're
doing for both to show kind of like
back-end for both debugging messages
it's doing the enumeration all the
sessions all the computers and kind of
see the whole pieces there yeah so this
very small little lab with seven systems
and you can see that the collection
finished in about seven seconds we did
this on an op where our client had two
hundred thousand workstations and
servers it took approximately 24 hours
to collect the information needed to
populate the graph database Rohan is now
going to show you the front-end
so once you've actually populated the
database with the info you need which
again you can do with the power shell on
gesture
now you're interfacing with the data
through the bloodhound interface which
Rohan will show right now fun little
story about two weeks before this
conference my coworker here told me not
to rewrite into electron and I
completely ignored him and did it anyway
in general I tried to give the advice
that if you have a working product or
POC maybe you might not want to do a
roundup from scratch rewrite a week and
a half before Vegas but I mean I'm happy
with the end result and I'm happy he did
it he put a huge amount of time into it
all right so on the back end here we
actually have a neo4j database running
this is actually data from a live
environment that will very generously
put together for us this is all semi
procedurally generated randomized data
this sample database is going to be
distributed with the code on Saturday
was released so if you guys well you
guys have like a sample data set to play
around with with the tool so when you
initially start up the bloodhound
application the first view you're
presented with is any group that has the
word domain admins in the name as well
as what users are part of that group or
what groups are part of those groups
this is oftentimes one of the first
things we try to enumerate and we look
at this data a lot so it's really great
to have this easily visible so we're
gonna start by showing off some of the
autocomplete here anything that is in
the database whether it's a computer a
user or group you can autocomplete using
the search bar here so just to give you
guys a user we're gonna start with well
take this dude here whose name is a
little weird if you click on any user
you're presented with a good bit of
information over on the side over here
one of the first things you get is
first-degree group membership this is
what groups the users part of directly
you can also query unrolled group
membership we're gonna change this
layout here so it's a little bit nicer
you can see what groups this user is
part of by going through other groups
yeah so what I would what I would add to
this is that the what we're looking at
before where you just see the first
agree group memberships that's what you
would see if you did like net user blah
slash domain that's the only results
that you would see so that's this first
degree of separation those first agree
group memberships and then you can see
what effective group memberships this
user gains through delegated groups
it's actually pretty difficult to
enumerate in meaningful fashion it's a
lot of data that you have to keep track
of where this used to remember of the
first degree local Advent which is
direct admin to computer if you do a net
local group administrator our computer
then they would show up this would show
up here the next evening look at is
route delegated local admin rights so
this is where the user has local admin
and because of it is group membership so
you can see that this map this user is a
member of the domain admins group which
is going to give them access to a lot of
other things
now get the interest of performance we
actually do full nodes with each other
so you'll see that there's an 87 that
next to this one there's actually 87
computers hidden in this graph that you
can't see but you can expand that data
if you would like alright the next thing
we can calculate and this is the really
cool stuff that we really wrote without
for its derivative local admin rights
not derivative local admin rights we'll
show you where a user has local admin to
do to any form of pathing expired
whether it's through a group or if it's
grabbing a user through another system
where that users already locked at so
just as an example this user is a member
of the domain admins group which gives
him local admin to laptop five laptop
five has the user cheese shop and
internal outlook a lot of them and do
you the fact that we can recover the
credentials or steal the token of the
logged in user
we can now impersonate you shop and use
that to move further throughout the
domain or into a different domain now
we're this user logged anywhere in
anywhere you deal with pre-sentence one
of the things that is obvious here is
that these graphs get out of hand pretty
quickly provided from domain is learn
huh so we added a very handy feature for
you
these graphs so in this side graph here
we're going to look for a route called
research and when you click on this
it'll zoom in on the graph and show you
where that that group is clicking on a
group will give you a lot of extra
information on the group as well
you can query who the direct members of
that group are you can query a through
the unrolled members of that group are
once again this book this query usually
takes quite a bit of time to run if
you're trying to reverse through groups
so having it all easily accessible in
this fashion makes it a lot easier to
work with you can also see where this
group is a direct admin to so because
these are all extra nodes they've all
been collapse in here we could
right-click on node and hit expand and
you'll get all these though is very
easily visible for you a group can also
have triple of lab and writes the same
as user so you click on this you'll see
that through all the different sessions
and admins and admin rights we can go
further and further down through our
domain on this graph here we have
another new sequel to sequel to is a
computer computers also have their own
set of data that's associated with them
you can say who's the direct admin to
the system you can say you are the
unrolled adness despite the fact that
there's only six explicit admins to the
system once you unroll group membership
and members of those groups you get 51
administrators these are the kind of
things that clients often don't know
about just because it's a domain
contains expand groups who come nested
and people forget what group does what
it is possible for a computer to be part
of a group this particular computer is
not nor is this computer in the local
admins group of any computer which we
talked about is a very stealthy and
interesting persistence mechanism
however you can still calculate
derivative local
the ranks from a computer LLL use the
exact same methods through sessions
group membership and admin rights to go
further and further throughout the
network it is also possible for you to
enumerate the sessions that are on a
computer same is just about any of the
other two things for Power View however
we're going to look at this one here and
you can see that the tak paths get
increasingly longer as you get more and
more privileges well we're going to go
on to one of the most useful features of
bloodhound which is pathfinding by
clicking on this button here you can ask
bloodhound to generate new paths from
any node to any other node provided the
path exists so just to give you guys the
user here we will go for our favorite
group ever which is domain admins so as
soon as you do this one home will query
the database that try to find any
passing exists between these two nodes
now this is a particularly interesting
one for us the user Jade through it
which is where we started is the member
of the external that local domain as you
move through this chain you'll see that
it's a member of the group which gives
an admin to a system which has a session
for another user who is actually a
member of a group in another domain
so we've now gone from the external of a
local oh man to the internal local
domain
jumping domains trusts hops has always
been a very interesting task they can be
quite tedious bloodhound has absolutely
no issues finding the paths across
domains just through the did data
already has following this path you'll
get a nested group membership here which
will give you admin to another system
which gives you the context of another
user yeah so what I would say is as an
operator when you're looking at this
graph bloodhound is telling you exactly
what you need to do to become a domain
admin so I need to start as this user on
the Left I need to pivot to this
computer here where I need to steal this
users credential and then I can either
take this path or that path pop one of
the three computers that are one degree
away from domain admins steal a user
password
and then because those users are part of
the domain admins group I've arrived the
domain admin and this group has rights
to several other systems now you can
pick any of these systems and the tap
will still be valid different users or a
lot of these systems and each of these
paths takes you through a different
group but still ends up on the same
system which is desktop 11
that's how xi will give you the session
for another user and you can follow this
chain all the way through your more
vested groups or through a youth or
another computer and your vegetable
result is the domain admins now another
thing that we've been working out a lot
is a prebuilt analytics queries one of
the things we like to do is find
shortest paths in da this is a fantastic
capability you can show the client when
you click this button you'll get a list
of every group with domain admins I can
click on one of these and get a graph
that's going to absolutely blow up my
screen so any of these external points
here have to this is the kind of thing
you can show a client let's say this is
how many different paths I could have
taken to get to doing apples group this
is a far more comprehensive solution
than finding a single yeah imagine the
difference between delivering a report
to your client saying this is the one
attack path that we identified and
executed and it took us three weeks to
find versus spending a day ingesting
data and being able to tell them these
are all of the possible attack paths
that exist in your environment during
this period we can identify hotspots in
this graph and we can do analysis saying
these are the reasons why these attack
paths exist and give them very
fine-grained recommendations on what
changes they need to make whether it's
user behavior or privilege that exists
in the in the domain to eliminate most
or eventually all of these attack paths
we do have a few other buildings grace
here user with most sessions computer
those sessions these help you identify
users who are logging in the most or
computers that are being logged into the
most we also do have the ability to map
all the domain trusts in your domain
this is all queried as part of the get
what how data I was talking about
deliverables for clients you can export
a graph to either JSON or an image the
image will something great you can throw
in your out brief or you can give them a
sign they want to look at the raw data
themselves now we do actually have the
ability to collect bloodhound data
function will export to CSV and you can
do all that CSV ingestion directly
through the bloodhound user interface
this is great if you want to take all
the data offline or you can't get away
from the client Network back out to your
database you can just ingest it through
here and it's actually exactly the same
cool that's our demo we're going to plug
back into the deck
awesome so DEFCON Saturday 1:00 p.m.
track 1 is when we will be making
bloodhound free and opensource so we
have a couple of things you need a quick
two week we're not quite ready to
release it right now at that time go to
bitly slash get bloodhound that will
redirect you to the github repository
where you can download bloodhound we're
gonna have a wiki that will show you
usage we'll have the example database
we'll have the source will also have
precompiled binaries for you or we'll
have instructions on how you can build
from source if you would if you would
like to do so that's it thank you very
much
on Twitter you can find me at underscore
Waldo with a zero Rohan you can find him
at Captain Jesus will Schroder you can
find him at at harm joy thank you very
much
I think we have time for questions we
have 15 minutes for questions anybody
have a question yes okay
the question was are there any
commercial tools available already for
clients to do this kind of analysis the
answer to that is yes and no yes
in that Microsoft actually built
something very very similar to this in
2009 which we think they called heat-ray
there is research done by Alice Zhang
and John Dunnigan at Microsoft security
Research Center they built something
called here--a that like I said I did on
identity snowball attacks however it was
never made public and I don't know why
there may be other commercial solutions
if there are I don't know about them
yeah that blog post the you know
attackers thinking graphs defenders
thinking list go to that blog post at
the very bottom go to the resources and
you can find a direct link to the PDF
which is that white paper of that
research I highly recommend reading it
there was a question in the back yeah oh
yeah we also have stickers if you would
like a cool sticker to put on your
laptop thank you thank you the queries
yes yes you can
so Rohan showed the attack pass going
from one user to the domain admins and I
believe your question is if you can
export that graph so you can use it in a
yes so the query language that we're
using in bloodhound is the neo4j query
language which is called cipher we are
doesn't quite answer your question maybe
we can talk offline about it okay
big client waiting 24 hours alright so
his first question was remember your
first question I'm sorry okay path of
least resistance so by default
bloodhound is running a query in cipher
called all shortest paths this is gonna
tip eclis run Dijkstra's algorithm to
identify the shortest path from one node
to the other what we are planning to
implement which we do not have right now
is something called conditional path
finding so say for example I don't want
necessarily the shortest path but I want
a path that meets certain criteria based
on maybe scope or rules of engagement or
I like let's say for example that I
don't want to touch any Windows 2012
systems so show me a path from this node
to the other and don't include any
windows 2012 systems or I can say I
explicitly want to include a certain
system in that attack path your second
question
your second question was updating I'm
gonna let Rohan answer that for or I'm
sorry updating the interface is very
simple through electron it's gonna be
similar to Chrome you close it you open
it but that wasn't your question your
question was updating the information in
the database right okay so that brings
in to the difference between what is
kind of static information and what's
dynamic in active directory privilege
and group membership information it's
gonna be relatively static it's not
gonna change all that much day-to-day
user logon information is going to be
much more dynamic so you can add
information to the database and it won't
currently it will not clobber
information that's currently in there so
you're gonna be adding more user session
information every time you do this
something that we want to add is
temporal information to these edges so
say for example on August 9th I did I
did a collection and I knew this user
was logged on here but then by the time
August 12th rolls around that session
may not be available so something we are
planning on
implementing our is again with
conditional pathfinding show me a path
that doesn't rely on a relationship that
is outdated which I can define myself so
show me a path that is likely to be
still valid by showing me something that
is from today or something that is from
yesterday what that will also do is
it'll equip incident handlers or
forensic staff to you know look at a
system that may have been compromised
and say you know this compromise
happened on March 21st I want to go into
my bloodhound data and I want to say
show me what show me what this database
looked like on March 21st and show me
not only the system that was compromised
show me all of the possible other
systems that the attacker could have
possibly spread to so that I can
increase and hone in on my forensic
scope they're usually going to be lining
back into that box again users tend to
keep reusing the same Active Directory
objects so from our experience the
session data despite the fact that it
can be outdated has never actually
yielded a path that was not valid even a
day maybe two or three later so any
other questions
if you want to chat with us we'll be out
in the main room for a little bit
yeah we've also got little cool stickers
if you would like one come up here and
grab one again thank you very much