ok so again this is Mark Burnett our
last speaker for today he is the author
of the very acclaimed book perfect
passwords I was actually considering to
bring in here to Las Vegas to have it
personally signed I still have it at
home mark and I again mark came with
this talk have you actually been
tormenting your family over this I am ok
yeah time so I think there's gonna be
very interesting to listen what's he
ever actually be done in doing so mark
your free dude kassad all right ok um
I'm Mark Burnett I guess hi MA I I did
stuff and I talk about stuff so but on
my first slide here i'm going to read my
intro ok so this talk is about passwords
and killing passwords and really the
mess we've made with the whole password
thing because although we like to think
that we have played a part in making the
world more secure mostly what we've done
is alienate users we've made them log
into everything over and over and over
and over and over we tell them to make
sure the password is really strong but
don't write it down and of course don't
forget it be sure to add some special
characters or sometimes when it's a bank
don't include special characters banks
we bombarded users with I gotta change
my screen here the NIP bombarded use it
with a never-ending supply of policies
CAPTCHAs remember me boxes on behind now
and of course you don't check the
Remember Me box even though it is
everywhere and of course usually
retaliated how they know best with memes
and you know we can't blame them because
we created them we recreated those
monsters and they are monsters
but I have got this little analogy here
actually I just saw this video has got
to find a way to work it in we are all
losing okay now i don't know i don't
know if you notice it it's kind of quick
but um i watch around this year i'm
going to zoom in and it slowed down but
watch around this area because there was
something just kind of went by real
quick there you probably missed on the
first time so alright so we've been
doing passwords for several decades now
and you think we've pretty much got it
figured out right but but let's let's
look at what we've accomplished and
let's just kind of do a report card here
password policies seemed like a good
idea but you know it turns out we really
don't know what works I mean users have
bad passwords so hey let's force that
bit passwords but that kind of end up
with not enough requirements too many
requirements strange requirements no no
two identical consecutive characters and
I don't know if you know me on twitter i
complained by a lot of stuff short pass
for explanations policies for policies I
mean come on failed user education you
know they're still confused with as much
as we've we've tried there they still
suck at passwords they still hate
passwords they still want to kill
passwords they're always trying to find
some some way to work around their
passwords so we're going to fail on that
too
password manager hey now I know we've
talked a lot about password managers and
it's kind of important thing to a lot of
people here a lot of person here but you
know we've got to face it they're just a
temporary fix they're really not a
long-term solution they kind of tacking
on to tacking on to this problem we have
a password and we're trying to fix
passwords by having password manager but
yeah Hardware tokens hey no talk
Hardware tokens we're doing for decades
now I mean we've been trying to get
right and we've tried a lot of different
things but the thing is I've ever tried
to get someone to use a hardware token
who isn't in the security business or
Leslie you know the company forces them
to you know it just doesn't happen and
there's that now biometrics hey users
like those fingerprints I scanner is
voice matching you know movies have been
doing it for years it looks cool seems
really secure I mean you got it if I
mean if it's something really secure
they're going to voice match right but
you know we still haven't figured out
how to make it we really haven't made
forget make it secure and we haven't
figured out how to make it anonymous and
we haven't figure out how to make it
work everywhere yeah oh I don't have
sound I just realized the house cool pop
pop okay sounded like that kind of
alright so the way the stars is until
this this particular topic stars until
had me write an article a few months ago
and and they've seen they seen a lot of
my tweets and stuff and they thought hey
it wouldn't be cool if we got we wrote
an article about killing passwords and
they thought you know it was gets a
bunch of equipment it's let's let's try
it out on my family you know and kill
password see what really works and yeah
that didn't go so well but I got I got
um some wearables stuff some some you
bikies I'd bunch of those laying around
hi scanner a fingerprint scanner and
password man tried to use intel spooky
and this one mimics parent was really
fun for me but um you know I I did it
for a few weeks I got all my I got all
these things hooked up you know got
everyone in my family I def I got you
know I had this interesting it was
pretty diverse thing in my fam I got my
eye to my wife you know both I that's
another story my three my boys I get for
and my father-in-law oh hi especially my
father-in-law I'll just let you guys
just I don't know if you can see those
big
you got to read some of them my
father-in-law put tape over his webcam
transparent scotch tape I'm amazed at
despite my best efforts my
father-in-law's ability to fill his
computer with every Spy were known to
man my father were locked today told me
he needs to get a copy of Harvard
graphics then I realized you serious I'm
just going to say the world is not
secured till my father-in-law can go 90
days without getting some kind of
infection on his laptop no every hack
today wasn't because of the passwords I
released seriously people like my father
in law okay my SSID used to be not found
my home group blocked and we flexed over
broken my father complains that nothing
works at my house well I have so many
stars what's that hey so anyway I've got
a pretty diverse group to pull from
needless to say my father-in-law got the
cat book which is you know password
manager Kathy password manager disguises
a book about cats anyway that's really
interesting though because I got I got
this stuff I mean I got this you know I
got one of my son's to use you bikies I
was kind of hacked but I got him to you
know use him for all those different
passwords someone were static
ecstatically up hard coded passwords but
you know the whole thing was to kill
passwords at that point my wife got her
this does this fitness tracker and the
thing is though you know once she found
out that it's worth how much was worse
she's going to sell on ebay so that in
last
the it was just like I last about three
weeks and then you know I can see I it
all end up back in on my keychain again
they just kind of they just kind of gave
up on it but why can't we get people to
to use this stuff I mean why is it so
hard I mean I couldn't get my own family
to do a knife would think I like to have
some kind of influence over them what do
we need to do to get user participation
here wait oh hey listen to mall okay so
it's got to be usable I mean it's it's
if it's not usable I mean obviously it's
got usable but you know it's got a its
got to have its going to be easy to
install it's got to be I can't have a
lot of terminology you know crypto
terminology it can be frustrating tudela
yeah it's guess that's thing with my
wife she gets really frustrated with
stuff so if it doesn't work like the
first two times he's ready to give up on
it so it can't be frustrating these be
flexible needs to work across a lot of
different platforms now we get it
there's a lot of cool authentication
stuff but only works on windows or it
only works on your mobile so it's got to
work on different platforms it's got to
be compatible with a lot of different
authentication technologies I mean
windows hellos nice but it lost stuff
you can't use it you can't use a you be
key to log into windows hello it's got a
its got to be invisible it's a user and
you know they just really got to feel
like they're not even using it i mean
that's that's the biggest problem with
passwords aren't they're far from this
invisible they they're struggling with
them all the time i mean just just
monitor the key word password on twitter
and yes silloth it's kind of funny but
you see all kinds of complaints about
passwords and it's got to be ubiquitous
i mean if your bank sent a sends you one
token the only works with their with
their website what's the point of that
it's got to be something that you can
you can use on all the different
websites or all the different systems or
only works on websites but not their
less or vice versa I mean it's gotta be
something that that works across
different systems
so with this in mind you know I decided
to take to the extreme okay didn't work
with my family but I thought I tried
myself I mean I'm pretty brave so I I
got all this stuff to get I had a few
more things my keychain I got this you
know there's that I track her and you
know I installed it all my system I
system really doesn't boot and very well
anymore but but I did I installed it all
you know and I um you know I tried it
off like what you know what are we doing
wrong here I mean what am I why isn't
this so hard to figure out and just to
be clear we're going to killing
passwords anytime soon you guys know I'm
just skip that one so let's talk about
password managers I said there are
temporary fix they're just kind of a
crutch to get us through to make
passwords usable for now I mean it may
be 10 years maybe 20 years but they're
really not going to last it's not a
long-term solution here I mean we don't
know our own secrets i mean we create
these least we don't even create the
secrets that generates a password for us
it manages the the secret for us it
enters the demand for us but it's not
just kind of breaks the whole security
model breaks a little concept of having
a secret because yeah we have this this
master password but it's not really way
this is going to work and we just got to
look at that look at passwords there are
transitions or should be there to get us
to this place where we can we truly have
a seamless system where we're you know
we're doing more than just typing in
static passwords you know tulus type
type in sac passwords for us
sorry but to get that to get to that
place we're going to have to get
operating system support we're gonna
have to get browser support I know that
was my quest now yeah he thinks that
browser shouldn't be involved but you
know you got to have the operating says
you gotta have the OS it's got to be
have a trusted platform to run the
browser and the brothers going to have
that trust authentication platform to
log in to your websites and if we don't
have the browser involved if we don't
have the operating system volved we're
just not going to get that I mean it's
just we have to the only way we're going
to do that is to get every component
integrated and so who's going to do that
not in search who's gonna do that I'm
asking for volunteers no okay okay so
what you have we've been doing this for
a long time we've got we've tried
magnetic stripe cards we've tried smart
cards token generators all kinds of
technologies and that's what users want
they want something it's easy something
is plug in or or you just be near a
computer unlocks it if it if you lose it
you you've got this thing Galaga if you
lose you grab another thing and that's
your thing and you do that to log in and
you lose that thing and you get another
thing so you know that's that seems like
a great solution but you know hard work
the classic trade-off between hard work
the classic trade-off between security
and convenience and you know what seems
great for users really doesn't work well
for security soap and vice versa but you
miss them let me do it again for you so
around 2005 a lot of websites realize
they need to do Lydia thing to make
things more secure so we started like
paypal and ebay and some banks they
started distributing these these vasco
go tokens you know you push the button
it gives a six digit code and actually i
really like these every night I've had
these for 10 years and the battery still
works I still use them on my paypal
account but I guess they really kind of
thought for the for the companies
because they just you know they kind of
it got to where they pay pal just kind
of hit that that feature for a while it
must have been a major sport headache so
we couldn't what's that
exactly nobody use them but me and like
you probably and like some other guy so
Bluetooth now a Bluetooth interesting
because people are always trying to I
mean Luke to seems like the perfect way
to do this you know you don't have to
touch it just go near your computer it
unlocks its but it's not exactly secure
I mean you it's always on you know it's
easily spoof able it's visible I mean
within 30 feet or more if you have a if
you have a I mean sometimes I've seen
people will do up 200 feet this right
antenna vulnerable to man the middle
attack i think there's going to talk at
DEFCON about that but we keep you know
keep put everyone keeps going back to
this these blue to stuff and the
protocol is insecure there's just really
no fixing that unless unless we fix the
protocol but one thing you do is you
treat it like it's an insecure network
and we know how to deal with in secure
networks I mean you you have proper key
exchange you have certificates you can
have pin certificates you you don't just
detect the presence of a Bluetooth
market or as you you exchange you do a
proper challenge response you exchange a
time base or digitally sign time Bates
token but no one does that it's a
problem is this tractor used for my wife
what I just end up using some software
effect I there we go and we used some
software this rojos it's kind of cool
you you have all these different things
you've got USB flash drives well Luke
with Bluetooth key p kc s number 11
security module you back east you can
plug in all these things and they even
laden with windows really nice i did
that with my wife integrate it with a
couple other things tasker and some
stuff on her on her phone and you know i
worked good until like I said ebay you
know my wife sake now
on that you know stories my life anyway
huh that's right I study DEFCON badges
feel like from five and six but you know
let's go for a lot of money on ebay it
turns out so try a these fitness
trackers actually kind of cool because
you think about they've got first of all
it's something you have you know you've
got possession there we also got GPS on
some of them you've got biometric
markers I mean sent this one's got a
heart rate sensor you know that if
there's done authentication through
heart rate it's got microphones on it
you can do voice authentications got
galvanic sensors you know it's basically
got a lie detector test on here not a
watch but I mean there's a lot of
different possibilities I mean you could
you could if you really want to make
that work I mean wearables are really
interesting and it was you know it's
pretty transparent of Microsoft try to
do do it with their bare thing called so
variable called fan yeah they're real
band and either which is basically if
you push a button gatekeeper now this
one's kind of interesting I don't
actually like I like this one so this
little thing right here you get a USB
dongle and then you just put on your
keychain you walk up your commuter
answer it's really accurate like you can
see how far you want to be from a from
your computer you can say like three
feet or five feet or 15 feet it's really
and you get within three feet it you
know locks and when you lock way it
unlock or other way around you can
choose how you want to log in if you
want logging with just the gatekeeper or
with a pin or whatever it is just really
cool I really actually kind of had fun
with that one but then I saw this thing
just enter your winters paso and enter
your windows password below this enables
you to log in to your PA whenever
someone asked your windows password you
know that's bad sign when it went it
went authentication so I saw this and I
saw this and it was just bad
I mean I don't you can see here vice
Mike 10 you know and the encrypted and
there's the call the code for encrypting
it and yeah it was just bad i mean it's
kind of sad because that was kind of
cool I know I've worked with I'm we've
been working with them and they're
they're improving that but it's you know
it's that there's a lot of potential
there are something some way we can go
without you know some bluetooth device
it's pretty seamless for the user you
bikies right I mean we all like leave a
cruise how many people here have you
baqi all ride how many people out for
you bikies one two three what's that on
which one
the 40 well it depends on how I mean
what kind of crypto you're talking about
because there are i mean the yuki is
writable and you can you can put in you
you can write your own java modules in
there so i guess it depends on what
you're using for but you know it depends
on how your how you're using it and i
think i think you big he's probably the
closest to to getting a real hardware
token it's usable it's cheap you too you
too f standard a few of those you to
have tokens this one here it just kind
of folds out and tape Phil ruin I got
four five dollars on amazon widespread
adoption a lot of people well I should
say widespread adoption among us really
easy use you know put in push a button
the it's got the the ue key itself got
the OTP smartcard channel response other
stuff but we still can't get people to
use them I mean I gave my son three you
bikies for all is different you know
that's six different passwords because
you know it's about Ali had I still
couldn't give an use it for that I have
my one of my son's I my tan year old
like he actually still uses his you
Vicki yeah you know logging into here's
the only one of all my family who
actually survived the whole thing uses
you've a key to log into gmail but but
we can't get you be able to use them i
mean that's about this easy as you can
get right in SC rfid got a ring here got
two little NFC tags on it and OA got on
the back of my back when I got a
Hennessy tag back in my wallet I got ya
see tax I can yeah swipe my wallet and
in the bathroom I can swipe and launch
my apps I need on my phone
yeah son someday yeah the Nano I believe
or yeah I think I don't know one of
those RFID is cool that rfid thing you
know I'm yet I mean I got these these
little scanners i put on my computer i
used to seeing my computer with such a
mess you know all the stuff edit a stuff
taped on there because i had a you know
so i got NFC and rfid you know so it's
kind of guy i actually got another one
for my garage so i can open my garage
door with that and i work but great for
that but I don't you know the thing is
you can't change it it's just a code I
mean it's spoof able it's easily copied
you can't turn it off so it's not like
like Bluetooth I may at least blue to it
you can kind of secure it by only turn
on when you need it you need a reader
okay you know those readers but I don't
know what that is oh so I used event
ghosts in Windows i used the realest
thing i use tasker and kind of got all
the stuff integrated it worked out
pretty well and it's really cool but
it's just not secure at all I mean might
work for home users than that I don't
know just don't do this I mean unless
you got some foil gloves or something
because you know once someone I mean
it's spoof legislation sees someone
scans it and you've lost it you gotta
like what do you pull it out and put
anyone in and you can't really change it
and that's worse than your fingerprint
mobile devices some some based on Google
off maybe there's a lot of them some are
proprietary simi's algorithm some these
personal custom algorithms somebody's
push notifications some use a
combination of that those things they're
really contour easy use everyone's got
them some kind of mobile device people
are more willing to protect it and
they're going to notice when it's gone
it's not going to be gone for long the
problem is is they're vulnerable to
remote attacks you could you could have
some bad apt someone installs there's
they're slow to replace and you can't
just go get a new one on the plus side
there is a lot of support for
Google ah i mean i've probably got 30 40
on my google authenticator and it's just
constantly growing so i'm not going
that's you guys get that so oh I forgot
about it yeah that's that's what I call
him what can be chopped off I kind of
ran out of graphics so I started using
some stock photos so i guess thing is
with fingerprints finger I here's my
fingerprint scanner it's a little tiny
one the problem with fingerprints and
this is the authentic they had oh they
had a problem where they were storing
the password encryption what the way
that some of these things work is
another reason why I said that was bad
news when they about a bad sign when
they ask you for your password though
they'll encrypt your password and it has
some logic in the program that indicates
you and if you pass that's dedication
then they decrypt your password and use
that to log into windows and so that
just means your password stored
somewhere and most likely it's got a
hard-coded key somewhere or based on
your PIN and it's really cool it's built
into windows you know but the thing is
you can't login to website your
fingerprint you don't have you know
there's not really much you can do with
it and just log into windows that's why
there may be your M your mobile phone as
well and oh I risk no irises are
interesting I like this one the best
that camera is just kind of weird I
think
and this was my personal favorite
because I just worked really well it was
just really seamless it's almost as when
worked almost as well as the UH the
bluetooth yeah okay so me my kiss it
says looking for you making sure it's
you it logs me in so it's kind of it's
kind of cool I pass pictures I kind of
freaky but yeah it's just I mean if we
could get this something like that to
work I mean like I said we get the OS
support we get the browser support and
then we get the application support but
the thing is we're not going to walk in
not going to log into any websites with
this so it really not much look I
should've got a big pitch i guess but
there's really not much you can do with
it other than just I mean oh you can
play asteroids kind of cool you can you
look at the asteroid in it blows it up
and some games but it's not much you can
do with other than that it's I mean it
would be nice if we could get that more
commonplace but they aren't really cheap
has about one hundred eighty dollars for
this guy's to the cock up so they're all
catering people waiting outside yet take
over the room so I have to ask mark to
speak every five minutes five minutes k
acta de yeah
oh you give it away Hayes voice fix
don't ask for passwords if you ever do
use a i could meet you cut biometric or
alternative indication you ask for your
password there's several of them that
did that it's just that you know they're
storing it somewhere oh and there's this
thing I mean you've got a class pass you
can use you icky but if you lost lost
your Ubik you device click here to
disable you with key and then over here
it says use email verification instead
so it's just kind of I why not just
e-mail verification in the first place I
mean it's you're not any stronger than
that weakest think they're so expanding
modalities well we I go back to fix
fixing it is you start strong work
backwards we allow a lot of different
allow support for a lot of different
types authentication don't I mean these
lot of these like LastPass for example
it lists you know these these certain
two-factor authentication things you can
use you know if they're not I obviously
not gonna be available on every device
for for every person I mean not everyone
has fingerprints I mean you know it's
just you got to have flexibility based
on where the user is what kind of ice
are using where they're logging in from
and other factors that you know that
could make it potentially suspicious so
you kind of take away you know is this
suspicious you try to take the score
away then you add on with this the
stronger authentication factor is
determined to get you back to up to
where you need to be you know to a
certain score to to pass them and here's
some kind of testing things that you
could look at where you where where you
are when are you there where you were
which device you're using who you know
who is with you but I hear something you
probably don't want to use
um something you forgot something you
lost anyway something UAE's how'd you
bleed so I thought you guys might want
to use the hashtag and kind of carry
that on but rules based authentication
of that's one thing I'd like to see I'd
like to see some kind of I mean with uh
with like within the windows hello for
example you can log in with a
fingerprint or with your face or you can
log in with your pin code or password
but would be nice to say you know I want
to log in with three of these three out
of four or I want to say you know these
times I want to log in three or four if
i want to say if there's been more you
know certain conditions i would be nice
to have a rules-based setup that you can
decide either we could decide let us
have five different ways to authenticate
you have to about three of them
artificial intelligence there's there's
a lot of potential there for
understanding when to require multiple
factors or you know three or four
factors for authentication then if you
can't find devices some of the password
managers do that were already smarter
wearables that would be really cool okay
but are you okay and then there's this
that's it I guess they don't have
questions we have questions have time
for questions while they're setting up I
I was told they are really eager
together get in here but again you know
Mark would be around so pleased you ask
him questions outside