hey welcome to my talk today at hardware
I oh I was already here last year so
this is my second talk at hot video
today we will talk about dropping the
make picking up the keystore um to talk
about an access point from a major
network provider now suppliers sorry I
will tell the name later on so let's
start with a presentation so about me
I'm a security analyst and researcher at
Iran w in Heidelberg Germany I worked
there since about two years now I have
background in electronics since many
years um not to play around with
technical staff not only electronics
also mechanical things um yeah few weeks
ago I had a long beard but my girlfriend
didn't like it animals I had to shave
yep so about us we're renda independent
company sat from hard about Germany
established in 2001 by yesterday's
keynote speaker in a row who's also here
in the crowd we have about 60 employees
and yeah we are about continuous growth
in revenue profits and yeah working
latch environments we are also a host of
the troopers conference which is also
based in Heidelberg on our website and
blog yep okay today dropping to make is
usually about this today it's about the
manufacturer installed certificate on
access point and it looks like this if
we go to access to it so um the whole
thing started as a customer pro check
the customer wanted to end on to roll
out and these access points in his
environments for his remote workers
discuss if it is secured to roll him out
if there are any wolves in the access
points so the hardware guys at your NW
got hands-on and finally found some
things the major Network supplier was
big secrets until yesterday because of
the responsible disclosure process we
went to yep the thing is about the
access point you have the same Wi-Fi
profile profile as in your company so
you don't need a VPN software app top so
it's easy for the admins is it's easy
for the users and it uses a GTA last
tunnel between home and company when
there is cisco yeah it's the cisco
aironet 602 office extend access point
long name for small thing and yeah
product is end of sale and end-of-life
time cisco when i disclose the two cisco
they told me this about five six seven
times if i am aware of this i said yep
but there will so doesn't matter for me
if it's another sailor end of life time
and also they want to release a patch
for one of the rooms I don't know they
wanted to give me a test but I didn't
receive any files until today um yeah as
already is that we went to responsible
disclosure process that's the thing we
do got Iran w it was published yesterday
I didn't hear of the guy from the cisco
guy the whole month so yesterday there
was mail in my mailbox and yeah he was
asking if he could already publish it
and I said yep do so fine for me fun for
you timeline will be displayed later and
also white paper
will be issued I think beginning of next
week so let's hack it this is the piece
B of the access point there are some
people connectors like here very very
empty headers so we so let some pin
headers on it so we could easily connect
like here here here under the earth
shields different MC use or socks also
here's a USB port which is behind the
sticker on the back of the access point
because they have no use for it what I
already know is that this access point
is not only used by Cisco it's also used
by I think it's netgear for different
purpose so there is no GTA last tunnel
to company and such things yep there's
also NAND flash and some footprint for
thing spy flash um yep I only worked on
the USB port was also disabled and as I
remove the sticker yeah about your yacht
and check we will talk later also about
an end I think this is also cheytac
header the traces are going to the Wi-Fi
chip so yeah it was not that big
interest for me ok what we think we've
got so far said to use P what's hidden
behind a sticker and disabled we have a
broadcom sock we will MIPS arc problem
is about broadcom you don't get data
sheets in the wild also micronics none
there is it easy to get a data sheet
also you are che attack and another
debug header so step-by-step information
gathering arm data sheet not in a wild
for nand flash
yep pin outs of the headers it's easy to
get them by measuring with multimeter
che check you laters pretty handy to
shine arrow or by use of illogical and
lysis so this wasn't a big deal I'd also
try to interface with the use and with
USB and why he faced answer but it was
disabled and also it was documented
somewhere in cisco judgments that it's
not enabled um he up to you out of the
sex exponent loves to talk a lot so
there are lots of debug output what was
pretty useful started like this told us
emits a cafe running on it and it's
brought come FEMA environment and yep
here's some memory addresses key state
is I think three or four times mentioned
while booting so this was of interest we
tried to boot from the golden image this
was also of interest later on under
linux kernel 2.4 point 20 so this was
with the most useful information for
cheytac we needed later and here again
the key states he stayed lock okay i had
a problem there was lots of information
no login possible it was not interactive
and anything like control c won't work
while booting so he quickly interrupted
to get into some kind of bootloader
asset cafe yep but they are popped up
one message m several times and it was
the key state so this one asked he was
locked in small letters and our device
was really locked and that's what's the
matter why we couldn't interface and why
are you
so what could we do we could dry and
give up what's no option because it's
paid work we could also dump the nand
flash which I hate I really hate it I so
I'm so unsuccessful with damping
manflesh I don't like them okay you
straight hack yeah but why it's not
needed at first okay so let's get our
hands dirty don't know if they're in
English if there's an English
translation for Hector that I talked to
the scalp editor there's the nand flash
i prepared it with some insulation tape
to don't short some pins because i
already lost the device doing this okay
the idea was let me try to boot from the
golden image which is the starting the
OS of this access point yeah the idea
was to interrupt it here while is it
trying to boot so the Ascension by
preventing the device from booting to go
an image it will go into some kind of
recovery mode or a boot later coffee
will pop up so I see as I thought a
system have to be has to be on the nand
flash I try to do it this way so we have
data inputs and outputs in the nand
flash and I just thought okay connect
him to ground in just the right moment
the right moment was a problem because
the right right moment was just the time
frame from about few hundred
milliseconds yeah and doing this by hand
is hard okay in this picture okay what
we didn't want was to golden image
allowed to fail I wanted to fail but not
this way so this validation failed and
the system went into holes or try to
reboot sometimes
yeah when I was successful I was very
good in train after some tries it failed
and the console came up so I got a
caffee and this had a lot of options you
could read flash reflash it angel and
manipulate g environment variables and
also get key sath key so Eric cool
problem was okay if I use that key my
prick my device so it's not useful
anymore therefore are here right set key
had value in hex which was an ASCII MFG
one sounds like manufacturing blah so I
end up again get key so I get lock what
was what i was already expecting sucky
had a problem yeah you couldn't enter
any value so it doesn't accept any
parameters so it's a one-time thing you
said it but you can't set any other
values here as i entered set key you
remember it was manufacturing 12 value
actually it started to engineering there
was another key not a key set then it
told me so I didn't know what to do
should I reboot it that's what only the
only option i could do see if it break
tour what else but it turned out this
was good so open so some it has no more
key state locked just testing its memory
and running up also here
he stayed in it and it came up with in
basic books so this was after your
system as i pooted i had access to the
pc box yeah so i crawled to the folders
how to look on everything what's running
on it and yeah came up some things so
the in Aspen where different programs
available also binary of a bootloader
and yeah also kept up and which is the
access point um using to connect this is
a what is it called it's a control
protocol for lightweight access point so
you have a wireless LAN controller at
your company's side and the lightweight
access point roll out anywhere in the
field on-site or like this one at a home
of the company's worker yep finally a
reason why we are here not for this
search these are flats interest but for
this one's so there's the route sword
and the manufacturer installed sword and
the corresponding private key I check
this by openssl got an md5 hash above
pop keys so they matched and we got what
we wanted
fortunately with katermukke and the
party about the access point isn't
working anymore so if you rebooted and
it tries to connect to the wireless LAN
controller you will have no success it's
an engineering mode and yeah always when
they try to relegate their certificates
and build up DTLA Adichie last tunnel it
fails there's only one encrypted package
and after this it fails so problem was
and how do I get it again back to the
tube working state to the key state lock
because this was not possible why are
you are as it yeah as the reset key
program doesn't accept any values okay
church actually rescue this was very
nice to use but first it didn't work I
hooked up to check you later which
outputs nothing and also measure the
voltage with multimeters there was also
nothing except of ground on the second
pin row yep so I put off the RF shields
of the broadcom sock where the whole
system was running on and follow three
headers from the jtech had assumed
chetak header which was down here so
it's not on the pic yeah and here I got
some empty footprints for resistors
there are no resistors on them but the
traces which I followed I'm with an
continually tester let here so
I thought okay what could happen two dy
system isn't working anymore so let's
play some solo joints here and it's not
looking very nice because you usually
could reach them because they're so tiny
just with some sodium wire but this
didn't work for me so i used some tiny
wires to Seoul urea and yeah it worked
so doesn't matter jaytech works okay we
have this not so cheap try shakti Packer
from segar which is called an trailing
which is cool when it works cuz it's
fast and yeah and it works so nothing
like the bass blaster which was when I
used it always pretty slow but the
problem was the second tools don't have
built-in support forum its architecture
and yeah i'm not a big friend of open
Oct is it's very awesome but if you try
to get it working the first time yeah
it's not that easy you have to read a
lot and yeah googling a bit i found a
simple script which has made my life
easier this way it provides a femur
recovery script and only needs a
modified port file in the board file
there is some info about the CPU or the
sock which is used and also the flash
banks and partitions the system uses so
remember this one and this is what the
AP spits out when it's booting so this
operations we need and yep
here's a GF here this is the certificate
store in here is the sort of cisco sign
third and also the private key in here
is are some parts of the system which it
needs to boot in veeram in rear em in
here are the settings for the whole
cisco things and yeah again ki a dumped
this one I dumped everything because I
want to be on the safe side but as I had
a look on the key and partition I got
this one so it's just right backward md
engineering one here the hex and what
could happen if we place this by just
again lock yup did so flash it which
chip some time and again he aquí stayed
locked and the whole thing was working
nice again in the memory times I said
you could find everything else I think
there are much more wolves inside cuz
and the software they use is Freddie
hold there they tell you it's USU air
doesn't matter nobody uses this access
point anymore I don't know if there are
customers out who use this and yeah you
could just use pin walk to extract the
files this works well for the
certificates and the private key there's
in squash FS used so yeah pretty
standard things some words about the
disclosure process at your w we usually
do the responsible disclosure way so we
did here disclosure timeline was pretty
long for this one on the second of May I
met at cisco cert which is the product
security incident response team first
reaction from
Cisco we're just few hours after i wrote
a letter and mail because i dropped in
the mail at our time beginning of
business day and on their beginning of
business day he answered first answer
calm I came and it took really long
until there is received the report we
had a lot of trouble regarding PGP cuz
my cisco contact has no damn kid GP key
on the service so I wasn't aware of his
new key and she couldn't open my files
so it's true I think about eight nine or
ten tries until he got it yeah on 29th
of tune they told me that we will block
you art on boot but it can't disable
cheytac without physical changes as I
don't have a data sheet from broadcom I
don't know if this is true because
they're usually some fuses which you can
disable so it doesn't work anymore also
there would be no Krypto possible so or
yeah so you can easily read it all the
time the keys and suds and they
announced the bootloader update which I
haven't got so far yep yesterday the
case waiting was made public by Cisco
they told I asked him for some document
page or anything like that and my
contact told me but the sea we as we to
rating was too low for in security
advisory because the product seems to be
eos and AOL and so yeah cisco doesn't
matter this yep
um yeah as a half still some time left I
think we could do try to do the live
demo cause it yeah the sir you are thing
and it's so time sensitive I hope I have
a still hand to do this okay that's the
way it's running that's my last you had
left so the other access point blew up
on Monday there were some problems while
flashing it don't know never had this
before but jaytech isn't working anymore
so yeah I'm lost at the moment I I cause
can also enter the bootloader mode
because it's stopping to work before so
okay I try to restart it and need to
have a look under the projector okay
it's just a small thing I hope my wire
up to ground and as you have seen under
the slides before there's I the first
time i used some insulation tape so now
i don't so i hope to hit the right pins
yeah and I also had to fix this pc p
while i was while I was so during the
the purchase on the empty footprints
yeah some accident happened and I
damaged a trace and fixing a trace of
this size
this AC so yeah I scratched some more
from the PCP to get access on the trace
solar some tiny wire on that solar it's
directly to the pin header and fix it
with blue tack if anyone knows this so
it's working but yeah okay let's try the
uart bootloader thing up and hope this
works nope I said it's the time frame
from about 100 300 milliseconds
yeah it failed so system hold okay this
one's too early when I did this a lot of
times I yeah every try worked but now I
did didn't do this a long time look ok
one last try
nope okay but we are lucky so i didn't
use this access point a long time so I
didn't know about the key state and as I
tried it before an hour ago I saw this
access point was already unlocked and
locked also it's just possible by
hitting ctrl C to get into the CFE call
the help call get key oh I usually don't
use put here way too sick to do so
invert colors sorry no problem yeah
that's a bad thing and presentation when
you use a tool that you don't usually
use and which is not in your yeah okay
sorry I'm hope this works somehow yeah
as we can see here the gate key oh this
works
invitation for win so khaki is now in
the eng one state and yeah that's the
whole thing is if you set key set key
again so it's keep watching it done and
if we restart it is still the same
so here's our busy box so I have direct
access to the shadow could unload
something while tftp you and yeah
manipulate the IP settings what problem
is a sad it will not work within within
wireless LAN controller cause the crypto
won't work don't know why exactly it's a
thing of the program so if you do LS of
the most temp search so here I'll see
our sign search and also the brief key
and that's the whole thing we wanted to
have so ok nope wrong slide sorry ok
that was my talk thank you for your
attention if there's questions i said i
will also be a white paper for those who
are interested in it how i I've exactly
done this and I think I really relieves
it on Monday Tuesday and think rounded
beginning beginning of next week yep are
there any questions around here hi thank
you for your talk um you mentioned yet
several of those a piece did they have
the same keys and certificates on every
AP or did they have an individual ones
individual ones thank you you're welcome
the front when I say thanks