it's great to be here thank you for
having me at this early in the morning I
when I saw the time when I was supposed
to speak and realize this is the time I
only vaguely heard of but yet here we
are so I'm going to talk to you about
rights principle which I want to be more
of a thing and we'll get to what what it
is and why it should indeed be a guiding
light for the hardware security but
before we do today is actually the
hobbit day if you didn't know this is
the day of Frodo and Bilbo Baggins had
their birthday and of course you know my
best impression of a hobbit right what
do we want for our birthday my precious
and of course it's the ring of raw
injection right or and you know maybe
the Ring of Power is not the best
metaphor here but perhaps the three
elven rings are so we want the ring to
control the state we want the ring to
control the Phi and the ring to control
the frames and of course as it turned
out there was another layer that was
overlooked by the original designers as
it often happens in hardware security
and that happened to be the Ring of
Power but here is what a Joshua right
said during his presentation when he
introduced the killer bee the zigbee
security suite editing tool security
does not improve until practical tools
for exploration of the attack surface
are made available and when I heard that
I said this has to be a thing it even
made Wikipedia until somebody of the
Wikipedian deliciousness crowd
to clear eraser to it and but this is
literally true and we're going to go
through my favorite examples of how this
is literally true I propose an extension
of this principle and this extension is
a bus or component or a Phi that does
not come with two so practical injection
of both crafted inputs and states should
be considered insecure the longer it
mrs. such tools the more its build up
the more insecure it should be
considered so when you're given if I or
a bus as a part of your bailiwick of
security responsibilities these are the
three cya questions right can you spell
she why s can you sniff gyi can you
inject cyc can you craft the packets and
the payloads and if you're not a native
speaker on the bus then somebody else
somebody else will be and if you don't
have that capability on the bus you're
seeding it you're receiving that control
to the attacker so tools do make a
difference we're going to go through
these examples one by one but remember
the internet of the ping of death in
1990s remember the time when you
couldn't open your machine at a at the
hacker convention without having it blue
screen because of a wireless driver bug
ah well Pakatan packet is something that
Travis good speed and my students did
and I wasn't it interesting that you
could actually emit raw zigbee packets
without ever owning a radio USB has
become a thing and again we had
something to contribute to that the
revelations that your disks were likely
to run a unix that could be back
word on the firmware level and so it
just ask yourself why weren't these
things obvious until they became obvious
and until they exploded and the answer
is the tools were not there the tools
with a practical exploration of the
attack surface were not there and people
have built up trust schemes that turned
out to be based on sand so the first and
the most important of one of those
things was of course tcp/ip the idea
that the internet was this friendly
environment where you had to be liberal
about what you accepted and everyone
could be dependent to be conservative
about what they sent and of course there
would be no bad packets right and then
suddenly a ping of death just an
overlong ping or a packet with the same
destination and source IP or one of
those things and if you think this time
is dunno is over and done with look up
Darwin nuke an IP options packet that oh
look at that crashed Mac OS Darwin of
not so recent versions so but what made
the difference why is it the Darwin nuke
is a big deal and not just one of those
pings of deaths from before well raw
sockets raw sockets and the Berkeley
packet filter were really the savior of
the internets because now you could
hammer on those stacks and then people
wrote libraries that allow them to craft
packets with yeast labor live net liebe
dich net net filter made it possible to
filter them so nicely steal them into
userland mingle it there this is still
the foundation of every testing tool for
your new internet protocols and of
course you had to write this in Python
because who wants to write see if you
can write in a scripting language uh and
we beat down on the internets until the
Internet's the tcp/ip sticks were
reasonably secured and the only thing
that was crash Apple that remain
crushable was SCADA now this is good
news right SCADA systems are still in
the 1990s state they still are likely to
have their respective pings of death and
how did that come about well you can't
you couldn't beat up on them until
recently as you beat up on the regular
tcp/ip stacks and unless people are
given the means to beat up on those
scalar stacks things will not be nice
because people out there are not
necessarily nice to your SCADA system of
course you know we're talking about
million-dollar pieces of equipment
rather than a thousand dollar ones but
this has to happen but raw sockets are
basically brought the internet the
tcp/ip sticks with compliance to the
rights principle on the lever layer 2
and up and that's why we have a
reasonable set of state with our tcp/ip
sticks so is that the case with most
operating systems with most other parts
of the operating systems tcp/ip stacks
have been improved did anything else not
really and I am going to throw out this
intuition because one of the
prerogatives of the keynote is that you
can you get to say things and then maybe
people will prove them true
it's not just that all layers of parsers
it's not just that parsers are crashing
we know that what will no less of is
that parsers have dialects parsers that
do not necessarily need to crash to do
bad things to your system they just need
to understand things differently between
two different components of the system
this starts at the phy layer and this
has been an unexplored land and it
should not remain unexplored if we are
to depend on those wireless
communications for or those other fight
communications or those other bus
communications for things such as skate
that's a one thing that dialects are
underappreciated we only look for
crashes we don't look for
misinterpretations or non-equivalent
interpretations our fathers are machines
for finding crashes not double readings
not double meanings not ambiguities
that's one thing and then the other
thing is that we built our operating
systems in such a way that the upper
layers trust the lower layers state to
be valid and they trust it to not to not
change from under them if you think
about how your unix is built if you
think about how your any major operating
system is built this is pretty much it
you build layers of abstractions then
each layer abstraction trusts the lower
layers that the state is what it was
that the abstraction is is wrapping and
that need not a poll be the case so
let's talk through these two things and
I predict that these two things are
going to be where interesting
vulnerability action will occur in the
next few years so let's talk about
dialects you have this problem that you
want to design a protocol a
and you've got a couple of fields and
then you need you add a couple more and
they're just not enough feels right
think of our Wi-Fi think of 802 11 right
how many fields in a beacon can you
count oh you know 2050 did you count the
proprietary information elements in the
vegan oh well okay not enough fields and
parsing is magic and of course parsers
can crash but we know this ah something
really interesting else really
interesting is going on when you have in
fields with M values each that's an
exponential growth that you've got there
it's M to the N combinations of fields
that you're looking at now do all of
them make sense does the firmware check
all of them does the firmware check all
of those M R to the power n our parts if
not then your hardware then your
firmware has dialects in which it will
interpret some things as true when they
are not and perhaps some things as valid
when they are not and perhaps some
things and invalid when they might be
valid and so the attitude 11 was a prime
example of that we only started seeing
that of course you know behold the glory
of the 802 11 beacon right it can be as
long as 200 bites it has a multiple
variable length F fields it has sub
languages for those fields we each with
its own parser and all of this used to
happen in your driver or in your
firmware in your firmware with the
original cards because only firmware was
fast enough to deal with the
microseconds timings and yeah prison too
orinoco was the first card to allow
Wi-Fi injection and it was not even as
far as I'm aware of and it wasn't even
that easy because it was heavily
dependent on the firmware the firmware
would even if you give your card a raw
buffer it would corrupt it well it is it
would rewrite it it would correct it but
of course what you wanted to send was
the crafted frame and you had to
actually erase it in the debug mode with
a writing back the changes that you
wanted to take place in the frame and
then half the time you won the race and
that's how you inject a row Wi-Fi frames
and then of course a thurs came along
and showing raw buffers out of your
Wi-Fi interface got easier and the way
we knew this was this little talk called
hijacking a macbook in 60 seconds you
opened up that's black hat 2006 you open
up your macbook it starts pulling in
that your 8211 beacons and probe
responses and boom you have ring 0a a
parser bug turned out that all those
parsers were buggy but the reason we
found this out was that raw injection
finally became available as a commodity
you could do that with your
hundred-dollar card you didn't need to
have a special equipment and security
just took a plunge and then got a lot
better because tools for the practical
exploration of that attack surface
became available and then if you want
more history of this the uninformed 62
has this wonderful article about setting
up for the exploration of this attack
surface and I could not resist
pasting the bugs of the month of Colonel
bugs november two thousand six that were
discovered in Wi-Fi within one month so
that that those are parser bucks but
what about dialects well let's look so
here is a bite full of flags so you've
got two hundred fifty sixty to the
eighth combinations are all those
combinations valid surely not i am not
going to dwell too much on 8211 but you
know you've got three types and subtypes
that you use and flags such as oh this
comes from the wired side which can know
what happen for a management frame or a
control frame so most of that space of
the values of these flags is invalid so
here is an old exploration of hours
which lobbed random values or exhaustive
256 values of those flags at various
chipsets and drivers and so how many of
those they responded to how many of
those they saw as valid even though the
combinations of legs were nonsensical
and you can sort of see the binary tree
linksys are would respond to just about
any combination of flags yeah we don't
care it looks like a valid probe to me
here is your answer various other
vendors were a bit more selective about
what they responded but they still
responded to a whole bunch of uh
nonsensical frames and the same for our
other tests when this were
authentication requests and responses so
you see if you imagine this firmware
as this collection of basic blocks and
your packet picking a path through them
it turns out that however you connect
those little checks and you will not
have all of them that makes your dialect
so what that what that what that means
is that you can talk to a particular
device a particular make of a device
with everyone else not hearing even
though they're listening even though
your way loud even though there is no
noise it's just because this device
believes that this nonsensical
combination is actually valid cannot
possibly test all of them and others
just discard them so zigbee so zigbee
was supposed to be a simplified and then
developed and then it developed some
more and then it ended up being no
simplify at all and so our next
exploration of this thing was well let's
see if we can do to that what we could
do to a 2 to 11 but with 8211 if you
know just we were at layer 2 with this
one thanks to the miracle chip the chip
con 2420 we could be at layer 1 and of
course the layer 1 is not just a
monolithic layer it contains of many it
consists of many sub layers this chip
allowed us to control the single symbols
that we sent on the air and Travis and
my students built this device which is
kind of like a good fit those of you are
probably familiar with that who have
done this are probably familiar with
this architecture there is an msp430
processor in the middle it plays
the middleman between your ftdi chip
that gives you a serial over USB this is
how you get your Python made packets
into this thing and then the chip
connected over SPI just sends them out
the antenna part was actually the most
tricky part and this is where most of
the time was spent but look at this as a
raw sockets for zigbee as a card as an
interface that would send any frame that
you care to Sam and we were looking for
dialects but of course we found the
packet in packet first for those of you
who have somehow missed it it turns out
that since the modulation of the
preamble and the start to frame
delimiter is exactly the same as that of
the payload you can send a packet that
contains the payload in the application
layer that is a valid frame and
occasionally you will hear that valid
frame as if it were transmitted in the
raw so just being able to control the
application layer on an unencrypted
network encryption would throw a monkey
wrench into this you could have the
transmission of a row frame without an
actual radio that's interesting and why
could you do this well because the
actual start the frame delimiter would
be lost to noise and for all the card
knew this was the preamble and this was
the start of frame delimiter and it
happily received that frame and if
you're interested in that we have a site
called demystify Phi spelled as Phi and
there were a lot more tricks that came
from that but what about the dialects it
turned out that zigbee has dialects on
the a fine layer
you vary the linker that preamble half
of your chips would not hear the packet
others will hear them just fine you are
so we tested three dominant vendors you
throw garbage between the preamble and
the start of frame delimiter same thing
so you can shout past your ideas if you
pick your malformation of the preamble
just right and it will not here now can
this be the case on other buses and
other files sure Andrea Barry signing
found this in Ethernet of course they
had to build a quite a device to inject
our packets there were no ready-made
parts as for our mode that we built for
zigbee but are we seeing that sort of
thing built for other bosses we're not
are we seeing tools for finding
divergences rather than crashes and you
think of it everyone has habituated
themselves to fuzzy but fuzzing is
something that generally finds you a
crash a corruption this is how it's
evidenced does it find you divergencies
and of course your system Macon's
consists of several components not one
if they disagree about what is being
sent what does it mean for the security
of your system I feel that this is
seriously under explored so so let's
this is the kind of a birthday present
that we security hobbits are missing
from our hardware people let's talk
about stage in the US so the u.s. is
this layer cake and who knows this layer
cake best route get authors
because they instrumented in the most
reliable ways and reliability is their
game a rootkit that crashes is a very
crappy rootkit but if you start looking
at this one thing strikes you is that
the upper layer thinks it's the boss the
upper layer depends on the lower layers
to stand still and if you control the
bus over which your USB hard drive sets
or your normal hard drive seats that is
an entirely falsified assumption right
there so what if you're cool back that
is supposed to notified you of the
change is not cold you know what then
what good is your abstraction um we're
seeing those kinds of oh let's pull the
rug from the higher level of
abstractions and the security schemes
based on that in octo so here is a fun
paper by Colin mulliner and others at
wood 2012 it's called read it twice it's
a hack of a smart TV and the idea of
that hack is okay here's a security
scheme that doesn't allow you to load
libraries but it does allow you to load
assigned flash files so if you actually
stick a gum stick in there instead of
the hard drive and control what that
thing gives the file system drivers the
file system driver will happily verify
the file and then you switch the file
system on it and then it happily loads
the verified file now you slipped into a
lower layer and you made that lower
layer run away from the higher layer
this is how we asses are designed the
they are not designed to do anything
else they're not designed
um question what comes from lower layers
or you might say this is just a taco I
mean and you know we note octos so let's
try to unpin whole what the taco is
right ah this a very name of the taco I
say is highly misleading unless your CPU
is somehow a magic atomic CPU you always
check before you use right you always
separate the times of check and the time
of use you can't freeze the state I mean
it can freeze your entire system before
that so at octo is really the state can
change without you knowing and of course
you have all kinds of schemes to combat
that trusted computing introduced a
bunch and it's just one of those but how
much OS code is written to explicitly
distrust the lower layer very very few
and so we find ourselves in a situation
when a lying device can do absolutely
anything to the rest of the system so I
psgroove was on PlayStation 3 the
jailbreak but was one example of that
you set up this system to expect one
thing you give it another you create a
vulnerable configuration and then you
exploit the most interesting part is
that you create this vulnerable
configuration yourself and then of
course this is the problem that people
have encountered as early as 1960s 1970s
james morris jr when he wrote his
fundamental paper on types wrote that oh
the programmer could begin every
operation with evolved form
this check but then you know there would
be no program no useful programming left
how many os's are built around types
types are the solution for this types
were the thing that allowed you to be
reasonably clear about what kind of a
data structure you trusted how many OSS
are typesafe it is a hard problem it is
going to be a harder problem if we keep
the buses unexplored my favorite thing
are weird machines all the data is byte
code if you can manipulate a complex
enough data structure then you can
probably get the parser for that data
structure to do just about anything for
you and we've done it with elf we've
done it with dwarf we've done it with
x86 descriptor tables can we do that
with device metadata if you switch the
device metadata from under the driver
and change that metadata what will
happen so we explored it for USB we
built this little rowing injection
device called the phase dancer and again
it's very much like any other row
injection device you depend on a magic
chip in this particular case the magic
chip was the max 5420 controller and
that thing basically can speak USB out
to this USB Jack called victim and once
you can do that electrically then you
just need to build up the payloads and
you do that in Python and you show them
from the host through the FTDI chip on
the on the right on the left my other
right and that's easy enough because of
course a USB
is nothing but a network and it's got
nothing but tackles and if you can write
a web server then you can write the USB
disk but the most interesting part about
this is not triggering buffer overflows
even though there are plenty of buffer
overflows the most interesting thing is
setting up the transaction to be to
expect one thing and then feeding it
another does it need to be a memory
corruption not necessarily it could be a
weird machine instead so people had fun
with this and you map to will be
released at this workshop I understand
and I'm very much looking forward to
this and people have started looking at
working at USB firewalls and at stealing
USB packets from the colonel and
rewriting them we had one project like
that ourselves and then there there was
another academic paper at usenix which
interestingly did not quote hours or the
phase dancer you know maybe they do see
they use some other magic but again
things are improving because tools for
the practical exploration of the attack
surface became available now you might
think that devices are simple I went to
a hardware security workshop where
people thought that well hardware is
simple enough you can check it through
like oh gosh no no no no you don't
understand what your disk is doing
unless you actually see what your disk
is asking what your disk driver is
asking over your disk in the blocks I'll
bet you anything that you will be
surprised when you actually see that ah
how do you know that Windows is booting
off of your drive it reads the boot
sector nine times it's just what it does
for some reason how do you know a
forensic pieces a piece of forensic
software is imaging your drive well it's
not reading your up
sector nine times instead it reads every
sector in every block in order if you
want to give it something other than
what it is it's expecting just look for
this pattern Travis wrote this a piece
of software for rick rolling forensics
of an ipod which just notices this
pattern and returns a bunch of blocks
with never give you up never lets you
down ah but this is a toy it has to
develop into something bigger because
the fallacy that you understand what
your disk is receiving in the way of
commands from your driver just imagine
this tight coupling between your
controller your driver in your disk ah
just how easy it is to topple it if you
actually start injecting into this bus
this should be done and of course our
hard driver hard drives can be back
doored and in fact that begged or can be
woken up by a pattern of accesses by a
remote attacker you know through your
web server through your web application
through all the other defenses because
causing a particular pattern of reads of
blocks is not that hard and not that
noisy and it's a reasonable channel so
we want to be PF and skype if I all the
buses and we want to be PF and skype if
I all the pieces of the OS if you see a
coupling there you have to be in on it
you have to be a native speaker on that
bus otherwise someone else will be an
otherwise you will miss an explosion of
vons when that happens and then you will
come to black head to
learn that your infrastructure is ah
well not yours anymore maybe so one
project that we're looking at and that
we hope to inspire others to join is a
raw sockets for sake no you could call
the device we would call the tool Satan
accept such a tool already exist if you
remember it was one of the first n map
like scanners for the internets and of
course you could rename it Santa if you
objected it came with the script for
that so disks are trusted disks are very
special in our trust a colonel logic
Colonel coupling with those is very
tight the attack models on the OS code
when data change from under that code
have not been explored and the right
place as always to be is is the Phi and
so we can follow that we can follow that
packet through the colonel we can follow
that USB packet these days we can't
follow that block this has to change and
so I pause it that if it ain't right it
ain't right security will not get better
until we redo until until we change the
way we look at the basic OS components
and finally speaking of rings of power
and evil overlords and things like that
I understand that all of this may
actually become illegal in the near
future because these are specially
created devices that could be controlled
as a part of the controls on the
so-called intrusion software and if your
organization has not yet gotten involved
in
lessen our negotiations or rather
renegotiations it should be because how
many lawyers can a security researcher
carry to work to be safe how many you
know at which point the basic tools of
our trust will not be available to us
anymore because we'll need to get an
export license and by the way you need
to get an export license to talk to a
foreigner because what you talk about is
an export in many regimes maybe you know
not yours but it certainly will be in
theirs so how much of this chilling on
the devices that inject that change the
standard execution path of a device you
know in order to introduce new
instructions external instructions did I
just described a debugger a hypervisor
any kind of a virtual machine well yes I
did yes there is a carve-out in the
regulation for those now you will have
to prove that your security device such
as a phased answer were aceite men in
the middle is a debugger good luck with
that so with that and on that sort of a
the darkness is coming note I will leave
you thank
Thank You professor when I decided to
introduce the hobbit day my introduction
I had no clue it's going to be part of
your talk well I mean more put out of my
research yeah you will notice there were
no cat pictures The Hobbit t theme is
more powerful at least for today thank
you for that diva does anyone have any
questions it will not solve everything
you were posing here but I know that
there are at least research is going on
on actually doing a full separation of
data and instruction sets even on the
hardware layer do we have anything to
say about that oh yes in fact I do quite
a bit so I mean having a Harvard
architecture is nice isolation has been
the most useful primitive that we've had
to date however what is data and what is
code right even the code that we think
of as such for say x86 it's just
basically data for the microcode
interpreter yeah now the example with
elf that i glossed over right you're a
typical binary of loading path right in
those relocation you are your data your
allocation tables guides the relocator
so what you think of as a table is
actually code for a limited execution
model except it turns out it's not so
limited same deal with any complex
format what you believe is tables descry
iving some data structures they actually
described behavior because they drive
some code now Candace code be turned
into a generic automaton to carry out
more than its intended function most
likely yes so it's not just separating
data from code it's making sure that
this data conforms to the types that can
induce only this much computation and
provably so say if you have a finite
automaton then you can prove that as it
consumes inputs it switches only between
the states that it is meant to be in and
not in any other approving this for
something that's an equivalent of a
Turing machine or even a
non-deterministic pushdown it is quite
hard or impossible under the
circumstances so it's not just contain
it's not just isolation it has to be
containing computing power it has to be
I mean an type theory could be one
method I know of one yes that is fully
typed unfortunately what it doesn't do
is seek on streams because that's that's
a tough operation to type it's called
ethos well I can I can share the links
of line but this I mean this is a really
good question at which point does data
become byte code and we need to build
systems so that every layer could not be
hijacked could not be could not have its
computation run away with that byte code
becoming an emergent and unexpected
virtual machine so probably a longer
answer then
any more questions well then thank you
so much