good morning my name is Philip Arden I'm
gonna be talking about the name of the
talk which I'm going to apologize for in
a second is docker it's the response
that container has an eatable continue
deployed environment I thought this was
funny
but I've been I've been informed my
number of people this is the worst dad
joke they have ever heard in their
entire lives and I should feel bad for
having put it on the screen so I'm sorry
I'm not actually sorry good cool so
quickly about me I'm a security I coin
basis coin base is a digital currency
company we store about five billion
dollars worth of Bitcoin litecoin
aetherium so these are digital assets
move moved online up just quick show of
hands digital currency familiar with it
okay like 10% maybe 20% cool the the
important thing to remember I'll talk
about this a little bit later is that
the both the good thing the bad thing
about digital currency is if you lose it
it's gone there's no there's no getting
it back there's no second chance there's
no call up the other guy and say hey
just kidding about that wire transfer
like send that back doesn't happen I've
been messing around with with with sort
of like I don't like the term dev SEK
ops because it's don't like DevOps begin
to it's but I've been messing on with a
space book for quite a while
occasionally I write them up with RO
software it's on github so let's talk
about first what we're not covering
because this this like could literally
probably be a several-day
presentation if we covered every aspect
of all the things if the US securities
you sure securedoc configuration else
dlc impact of containers blah blah blah
blah so we're not going to cover any of
this stuff we're going to focus
specifically on the incident response
impact of existing in this kind of
environment right we're going to talk
about first of all a little bit context
on the environment that we've that we've
built because sort of that that context
drives the solutions we come up with and
is overall useful we're going to talk
about things that in existing in this
sort of containerized immutable
continues to deploy an environment like
either make easier or make much much
harder
next preparation of detection and of
response so first one more one more
quick little poll who's who's messed
with containers in prod before
like five hands cool how about immutable
deployments yeah five hands and how many
of you have had the pleasure or pain of
working in a continuously deployed
environment from a security perspective
maybe one or two hands cool so let's
talk about those concepts for one second
before we dive into into sort of the the
rest of the meat of this talk first of
all talk about containers right I'm
using the terms Dockers and containers
here interchangeably they're not docker
is that it is a implementation of a
container if you're an old Salinas guy
BSD jails Solaris zones very very
similar concept all this is is a way to
segment a few processes in a larger
environment into their own little piece
of a running of a running OS the
important thing the important difference
between containerization and
virtualization is in a containerized
environment you share the kernel with
the host OS right so kernel bones still
work but the user land can be entirely
different so for example you may be
running a bun two hosts and an alpine
linux base or a CentOS or CentOS
container base or a Gen 2 container base
it doesn't it doesn't actually matter
from the usual and perspective immutable
deployments this one's this one's a fun
one so the concept here is when you
deploy a thing it should never change
again after that deployment all right so
so an example here would be if you if
you deploy a service to prop at service
has a bug in it a lot of times what
you're going to do is you know go hop in
maybe monkey pack something in the
running instance or potentially you just
deploy some more code to that same
instance right in a mutable environment
neither of those things happen what you
do is you hopefully you know you find
the bug in in dev not in prod and then
you redeploy the entire stack from the
ground
so we'll talk about how we do this at
point-a specifically but in general like
new vert new containers new security
groups enable us new ASG hold on yards
from the ground up this has some really
cool sort of security impacts from me
making an attackers life really annoying
and some really painful security pact
surrounds batching and software updates
and things like that that will talk
about the lasts continuously deployed in
concept here this is the thing that I
think I saw the fewest hands for the
concept here is the gap between merging
code de master and that mat and that
code being in production is as small as
is technically possible in most cases
it's the gap is the length of the test
suite basically so as an example of this
when we deploy services in corner basis
we'll talk about this way more in depth
but the the gap between merged a master
and running in prod is about 30 minutes
which is what it takes for the test
Suites and Security's checks and all
that stuff to run and we do that
something like 12 times a day you
combine that with the immutable
deployment concept what this means is we
are rebuilding from scratch internal
services 12 to 20 times a day
again pluses and minuses there we'll
dive into in depth so real quick there
wasn't a lot of a lot of folks who have
dealt with this live in a person yet so
let's talk about like why why we should
care I just buy cherry fix two terms
docker see ICD its acronym continuous
integration can use two canoes
deployment if I'd picked I did this for
a bunch of other things that just didn't
all fit on the slide they all look like
these graphs right up and to the right
interest is only increasing these are
Google search trends by the way interest
is only increasing these are only
becoming more popular developers are
only moving more quickly toward these
things because things like docker they
enable much cheaper cost so here if
you're sharing a host OS with
lightweight containers you can stack
Morvan on a host than you can
the same the virtualized same service
see ICD makes iteration times much much
much faster these are things developers
along these are things that we're going
to have to deal with as they show up in
our in our workplaces cool so let me
first before we dive into like the the
various problems opportunities and
things that we've built here let me let
me give you some context overall about
about home base and and the environment
which we operate I'm actually not going
to reference this network map at all
it's just pretty so so first of all and
and if you're interested in this stuff
our infrastructure team does a ton of
blogging and talking about this you can
you can google a bunch of this stuff and
find more details than you'd ever want
to know about about sort of how we run
our infrastructure first we're entirely
native US hundred percent of our of our
hosts in production dev test all that
stuff that's all any of us
so everything in our environments either
on an ec2 container or as a service
provided by Amazon every piece of code
in our environment is deployed in a
docker container then built sort of via
our build pipeline we followed immutable
deployment concepts
every time we deploy each one of those
pretty little squares on the on the
diagram there that is a full rebuild and
teardown with nothing in common between
deployments right so so an example there
we deployed the service that hosts
Clarence comm it's one of those boxes
somewhere what actually literally
happens is we spin up 22 instances in
ec2 we pull new containers into those
from the new codebase we do what's
called a blue-green deployment which is
we roll traffic using the load balancer
from the old store for the new stuff and
we tear down the old stuff never to be
seen again
we do this like I said before it depends
on the service for running and how
popular how much how much def time it's
gotten but between I'd say 15 and 22
times a day for the more popular
services for the less popular we do it
maybe once every couple days
um now like I said before we're not
going to talk about a bunch of stuff one
of the things we're going to talk about
is the whole software security stack
that follows along with this the the
stack analysis and iMac analysis all
that fun stuff it's actually really
really interesting and it's a whole
separate talk maybe like if it next year
but it's a little bit outside the scope
of the of the of these sort of the I our
focus here next thing we do is is we
segment most of the docker details from
the engineers the engineers just want to
write code they don't want to deal with
like 50,000 other things about docker
and security groups and firewalls and I
watch it
so we segment all that out from them
they have to do like two or three basic
things in a docker file in their project
that's it and that also means they don't
have control of anything below that
stack we'll talk more about this later
too
let's see yeah so we've done a bunch of
work around this stuff to make our
environment friendly this stuff a lot of
environments and we'll talk about this
are not like coinbase when containers
and these concepts first rolled into
organizations frequently it's the wild
wild west right for example if you're an
organization where a dev team decides
hey look I want to use containers you
have this beautiful managed host OS
right it's patched updated security
scanned it's gorgeous best thing in the
world and then suddenly you have Randall
like gin two containers and some
sentence containers and maybe an alpine
container and stuff you didn't even know
was there
right and none of the scanning tools you
use are going to pick up with implied a
docker container and and then it's just
it's just pain because as soon as one of
those is popped you hop on the Box
thinking yep I got my plan I got my IR
we're ready to go and you're like what's
this jindo thing where did this come
from I'm not set up to use gin too but
there's a logging right it's doing none
of the good things so we're going to
talk about how to how to solve that
problem I see a couple people blasting
in the audience a lot said that I think
I think you're sharing my pain cool we
are more or less on time awesome
let's see uh so the first step to great
degrades in response this preparation
right like anything else you want to
make sure that the that before you ever
roll into an incident you have the right
knowledge the right tools the right
processes it's practice like you're good
to go so let's talk about preparation in
the context of containers like one of
the if you look at any security
standards anywhere right the CSC 20 the
the Australian government one is pretty
cool any of them somewhere on that list
probably near the top is going to be hey
you should know what systems and
software you're running that's going to
inform like how you do into the response
the tools you use all that fun stuff in
situation ID you talked about right
where some a couple of dev team
somewhere suddenly installed like randos
software it's not scan it's not pass not
updated how do we how do we take that
situation and walk that back to a place
where you're walking into a situation
that you understand and where you have
you know the tools and processes ready
here so first of all and most important
for us has been to establish managed
base containers so the containers
especially docker have this have this
concept of layering right so container a
is layered on B is layered on C is
layered on D what this means is you can
have call it like a base CentOS 7
container raid where you install you
know nodes support go support Ruby
support that's three separate base
containers very thinly layered on top of
this one base container and you can
continue layering on top of previous
existing containers essentially
infinitely alright this is pretty cool
because this means I can control the
base OS container and I can let my
developers just sort of layer on a cadet
I get to control sort of the core OS of
what's going on I get to control it a
very fine-grained layer the second piece
there is sort of related we don't allow
people to deploy random containers in
our environment and I would encourage
you not to as well
the docker hub if you go look at it is
really cool there's a lot of prepackaged
software there in fact and this is
actually the genesis of this talk if you
go google doc or incident response what
you're going to find are about five
pages of google about containers that
you can use during it's in response as
opposed to any information about
incident response involving docker all
those containers are super awesome
really cool you have no idea who built
them you have no idea who set them up
you have no idea what based containers
they were built they were built upon or
what software is installed in them I
would encourage you not to let them run
in your environment because of that so
these two things are actually have alpha
supports in several of the of the
orchestra orchestration layers right so
these are things that say hey this
container runs in that place and it runs
this software version one of the most
popular ones is called kubernetes it's
from google it's what they say it's what
you see gcp their google cloud platform
is based on it's based on I think much
more developed version than is of the
cue bays that is open source so there's
elfin support there we've actually had
to build our own thing which is all the
way to being open source they're their
obstacles but those two controls if you
end up in this environment I would
encourage you are the most important to
making sure the environments you run in
is the environment you think you're
running it after that so Claire is a
really fun project I should talk about
talking about briefly Claire is a
vulnerability scanner for containers
it's specifically built to work with
docker and you could point it at a
docker container and it will go down
layer by layer and tell you hey this
this container is running this software
which has this this you know CV
associated with it you should you should
fix that
it'll also tell you whether that that
layer is actually exposed right so this
layering concept has one interesting
side effect that is what if you have a
base layer that has a version of open
SSL installed right and you get another
layer on top of that that has a
different version of open SSL installed
well the in container has that second
version of open SSL expose but that
first one is still there and at some
point in the future the developer
decides I'd actually
OpenSSL anymore then suddenly magically
the version below that is exposed to the
world right really annoying so Claire
does a really great job of flagging
those sort of probe owner abilities as
well so that you can patch all the way
up your container stack the next one is
also really important don't let don't
let developers do whatever they want in
a docker file there's a lot of of stuff
they can do for instance we talked about
you know that that that vulnerable
library right so you're running clear
you're scanning your docker file you
make sure all your packages are good to
go everything's beautiful and then in a
docker file somewhere an engineer just
curls down some Rando bridge going to
library from the internet and says hey
many use this now right not not what I
want to see in my environment because
when I roll into the response my
expectation is of you running this
version of the package it's it has these
known vulnerabilities or doesn't come to
find that I'm totally wrong because
we've curled down half a dozen libraries
and everything is all is all weird there
are a couple of really great I've
referenced from there they're like two
of the other docker file injures that
are really outstanding at letting you
pick apart this stuff and say hey don't
don't run curl to bash in a docker file
just don't just stop that so all this
the point of all this is in a perfect
world you will be able to go from a
version of a package to a list of
running containers that have that
package installed in a single step right
and I think that it really gets you on
part least part of a solid foundation to
making sure that when you roll in an
instant response you roll into an
environment that you expect to be in not
an environment that's completely foreign
to you another preparation and this is
actually a good thing
it's not a bad thing container should be
single purpose right running running in
a container generally means you have one
maybe two processes running within a
container it's generally doing one
specific
within that container which means you
can dramatically restrict the privileges
and the access of that container has and
there's a ton of cool tools to do this
so first of all you can make that that
managed based on us we talked about can
be extremely small alpine Linux I think
the the default base there is about 10
Meg's of user land it actually uses lib
muscle not G Lib C so you just drop that
whole class of vulnerabilities which is
super cool in some cases we actually can
you can deploy a service if it's a
compiled service and using what's called
a scratch container which is no use your
land at all so like go is great for this
some of our more critical services that
we write and go
we deploying scratched containers we
deployed the service itself and whatever
libraries are linked against which is
really cool both from a response
perspective and and from a sort of
attack mitigation perspective being an
attacker in an environment with zero
user land that's continuously deployed
so it rolls once an hour or so I imagine
could be quite frustrating hopefully
that's the goal at least right so two of
the things capabilities in set comp are
are really really awesome capabilities
these are both sort of Linux kernel
features that allow you to restrict what
a given binary or set of binary scan do
so capabilities lets you either drop or
add add the ability for a binary to do
specific things without giving it
overall elevated privileges so the the
quintessential example here is the so
say you wanna let you have a service
that's running it's running on a port
below 1,024 so you have to be roots to
bind to that port except now you don't
maybe you can just grant that service a
capability called net bian service and
it could suddenly bind to load numbered
porch without any of the other stuff
that being running as root requires or
opens you up to which is super cool
you can do the reverse tube you can take
a running running process and drop all
capabilities except the few you need for
that for that process to actually
succeed really really cool thing
underutilized my opinion set comp is the
same thing but for Siskel's so set comp
allows you to specify a policy that
specifically prevents you from calling
specific sis calls in specific ways with
specific arguments it's a really
complicated syntax very complicated
policy but it's really really powerful
so an example here so the the docker
ships with same defaults for both for
both of them
it's that comp policies may be a little
bit more open that I'd like it to be but
compatibility reasons but so docker
ships with the second policy that blocks
about forty four six goals one of them
being peat race so if you guys remember
the the dirty cow Linux exploit that
came out about a year ago I guess about
half the implementations of that
depended on peat race to function the
rest used dev name or something like
that
all of those pcap versions if run with
and document ater fail because docker by
default drops peat race in its set comp
policy along with about forty three
other syscalls right if you once you
really get get involved in this thing
you can do but we're starting to do now
which is per per service profiling of
Cisco lease and extending that set comp
drop list a little bit farther drop
forty-four by default they're about
three hundred Linux iskills more or less
so if you if you start to actually build
these profiles effectively you can drop
privileges much more extensively and you
can do it simi automatically without
having to necessarily deeply involve
your engineering staff right so you sort
of this this this layer of security they
don't have to worry about that is
incredibly effective if you've not
messed with the capability to set up
before I highly highly encourage you go
read up these are this is stuff built
into the kernel you almost certainly
have it it's built into docker very
clean ways of interfacing with it to the
best
native controls you have with with with
containers and lastly because we're in a
musical to limit concepts one of the
really cool things we can do is actually
deploy containers fully read-only so
even if we have you know a you use land
there that were interested in things
like that because the our deployment
concept says hey we're never going to
change this after its deployed we can
just deploy it read-only prevents a lot
of bad things from happening both
malicious and unintentional and it also
means that we can again have confidence
the environment rolling into in a
response is the environment we expect to
see or the deviations are bad South
preparation let's talk a little bit
about about detection this sort of you
know what I'm actually just with the
order of these two because this one this
one flow is better from from the last
slide here so that that that thing down
there the bottom is if someone says
oddity I'll buy you a beer later because
I'm sorry
so because we just talked about
containers or single purpose containers
do one thing right the first thing I
think about when I hear that is oh my
god doesn't I could do whitelisting like
really I think we insecurities of have
looked at whitelisting for a very long
time as sort of the gold standard it's
really hard to do an operating
system-level
as a number of organizations have have
discovered over the years it's sort of a
white whale of InfoSec Moby Dick fans
maybe now fair enough
in in so does this mean doesn't mean we
can really do white listing inside of a
container the answers is mostly
certainly more effectively than in a
general purpose operating system so what
we do or what we we've been able to
build is whitelisting specific syscalls
right so so today in our environment we
whitelist exec so wireless connects know
exactly connection can happen
environment in in the karmis environment
without us having profiled the app in
question and previously whitelisted
those specific calls how do we do this
we do this with much pain and and crying
and drinking using oddity all of these
is the the best worst thing I think to
happen to Linux auditing ever it's it's
the best thing because it's a it's an
incredible source of data that you
cannot get anywhere else from the system
as your live play should get from oddity
it's the worst thing because that's the
actual log format it's a multi line
format as you can see there that that
uses a that number in parentheses is the
is the common key that you can be used
to associate these things together and
it's just it's just this is actually a
fairly simple wine it's just really
painful to work with let's see so there
are a couple problems with this
specifically one is that audit d is not
container or specifically is not is not
C group aware C groups C gerson the
unnamed spaces are the fundamental
things that allow containers to work in
Linux so already using tigre where so
you don't see anywhere in that in that
big list of gobbledygook anything about
the container name or a C Group path or
any of that stuff so so how do you map
that back there's two ways one way is
you can play games with the SELinux tag
all right so you do see you see the
selinux context in that log line right
there if you if you're talking your
containers effectively even if you're
not confining them if you're just
tagging them that will show up in SC
Linux you can use that to walk back a
blob line to a container the other way
is via the the PID in the log line you
see it there on second line to there to
the right at the end of the day
containers containerized things are just
processes running on your box right if
you do a PS you'll see the process there
on your box but just have special
constraints associated with them
you can if you maintain a mapping and
this is this is probably the best way to
do it if you don't want to dive into
selinux
you can track a host level PID back to a
container name fairly trivially we'll
talk a little bit later in this
presentation I have a set of bash
functions I used to make a lot of this
stuff easier the information is all
there but sometimes it's a it's a
complicated path to get to it let's go
back one real quick so the Gipper so so
again Singapore technical purpose
environment right and this is the
problem with that there's there's no
real space here for traditional security
solutions you're not going to you know
install a tripwire in a container right
that there's just that's just not going
to work well so how do you get your
telemetry out right I mentioned before
we use oddity there probably a dozen
different vendors that will tell you
they have a solution to this problem
I have varying opinions of them we're
not gonna talk about any of them today a
few things that are that are that are
coming I'm actually super excited about
EBP F if you guys have not started to
research that yet I highly encourage
your do so it's an awesome project it
will hopefully be their ability
replacement for audit D for Colonel log
current level logging in Linux in the
future really really cool project
the other thing things we do is we use a
concept called sidecar containers it's
the word relationship fairly
self-explanatory but basically when we
deploy a host from containers that that
perform a service we also will deploy
one or two other containers
transparently to the users along with
them so that those containers can do
specific security things like blocking
DNS like doing all post rolling pcap
that we can use during into the response
things of that nature right this is
again this is transparent to the
engineers they don't see it they don't
care about it then they don't they don't
deal with it but it magically sort of
helps protect them and it helps get us
in a place where again during response
we have some of the stuff that we might
rely on traditionally like you know
potentially we have we have
recent pcap we have you know good DNS
logs we have all that fun stuff that we
want to have cool let's talk a little
about about mouth detection
intentionally I'm skipping like the hole
detection pipeline about you know
shoving these things in a pipeline so
the logs go to some service that does
magic and then alerts that come out of
the other end it's not again it's not
really relevant to this to the focus of
this talk I have a chat about it
afterwards and people are curious this
is an interesting one and and and this
is in my opinion one of the one of the
core problems with continuous deployment
if if we believe you know all the
reports and whatever one says just you
know at a critical time
easily weeks probably months if you're
an environment where your host lifetime
is hours or days how do you do a real
incident response if you detect it a
month later right it's it's actually
quite challenging I think so we have a
few things that that we do to to make
this a little bit easier one we log
everything our our log pipeline is
probably one of the most expensive
pieces of our infrastructure because we
log everything we log every single
application log log learn that happens
we keep we log all 2d every single exec
every single connect a bunch of other
specific targeted things as well we pull
down all the system logs from every
single host across the entire
environment and really the reason we do
this is because if you think about it in
an environment where hosts rotate that
rapidly you can't you can't really do a
hunt
host anymore right because they're
they're so ephemeral they're there
they're gone
when we hunt we hunt specifically on
logs right so that our logs have to be
very high fidelity and they have to be
good enough to the weekend both form a
picture and walk back a potential a
potential incident even if it occurred
three months after we terminated that
instance okay
we also enrich and I think this is this
is quite critical even if you're not in
this environment I think I think log
time enrichment is incredibly is
incredibly critical critical this is
this environment just makes it just
makes it more of a problem or more
critical right enriched log lines when
you log them that means if you log a
line IP address a talk on IP I just be
for this long as many packets as invites
blah blah blah I should also add on what
those IP addresses are at that point
because three months later I guarantee
you they are there won't exist or
there'll be something else entirely and
they'll just screw me up if I try to
walk it back right and if you try to
maintain separate repositories of like
IP information going back three months
and logs I'm back three months and you
try to like fit them together at some
point you're just going to have a huge
headache as opposed to doing a few
simple API calls when you log to resolve
that stuff I resolved I Pease resolve
PIDs there's all of you IDs resolve
everything that you can reasonably
resolve in a log line so you don't have
to try to do it later
we keep logs for years our standard
actually is a ten year retention
companies and having been around for ten
years a lot of the stuff falls into
glacier right after after it's it's live
in this period but we have it so if we
discover god forbid
a breach a year later we can go into
glacier and do restore or pull back you
know that months worth of logs and and
when we have the data there to actually
be the investigation our locking
standards are rapidly evolving so this
is actually one thing we don't do that
that I encourage you guys to do when
you're when you're going in this
direction is establish a consistent log
schema even if you format changes the
data you collect changes make it all
look the same
JSON or whatever so you have an easier
time parsing it right one of the one of
the worst intern responses I ever had to
deal with not a coin base was where the
the company question had changed their
logging format in the middle of the
incident so I'm trying to like correlate
these law
walks back it's just it was it was a
nightmare of manual magic to get even
even a broad picture put together so
pick standard state of the standard
otherwise you will have pain later the
last thing we do is a little more
controversial both because it has data
costs and there are data exposure risks
but for really critical services in our
environment we can treat service spin
down events like when we do deploy we
can treat it just like an instant
response event in terms of like the
automated things we do right we can pull
a memory dump we can pull system
artifacts we can pull all the same
things we might pull when there if
there's an see response encrypt it toss
it in a bucket somewhere put it in
glacier so that again if we have to go
back and deal with it we have at least
some data there we have a reasonable way
of walking that back now again that's a
lot of data right if you're pulling a
memory dump from every single host if
you're if you're pulling you know the
full set of live response system
artifacts off a host every time its
deployed its deployed once an hour
that's a ton of data so I would only
encourage you to do this in systems that
are incredibly critical that are sort of
like their you know the no fail style
systems
otherwise you're it's going to cost more
than than it's worth it to do
okay so so it's a little bit from from
that to you patterns in your all you're
sitting on a box and you're staying at
the stock container you've done all this
other stuff what do you what do you do
you don't know it's a nice prep work how
do you deal with it so basic question
right there's an active breach you're
staring at the container there's an
attacker there how do you isolate it
every bunch of ways I'm going to skip
the AWS bit because they're like you can
google this and find a half a dozen
great talks on abs instant response so
the most level there are few options you
can deal with docker does have a pause
command you can even pause the container
this uses a thing called the C group
freezer so it's not it's it's not what
you're thinking about you're thinking
about like a like a VMware snapshot or
checkpoints
it doesn't like take an image of memory
it's literally pausing the processes
right so you don't you don't get a clean
like file you can take away and analyze
somewhere else but the nice thing about
the C group freezer is the the pot the
process pause is not visible to the
processes being paused which is pretty
cool it's not the standard sort of
signal stuff that you would expect if
you're interested read up there's if
it's just google c group freezer I think
the first result is the curl does the
kernel box because that's I imagine an
uncommon set of words let's see so
that's an option that's more of an
option if like a if you want if you need
to say like hey this is an active thing
going on right now but I want to make
sure this doesn't get out of hand
without doing other stuff just pause the
container and move on with the
investigation you can come back to it
later and it won't have changed network
isolation right so so running running
docker
you don't want to pause it for whatever
reason you want to isolate it from the
network so that you can deal with it
later there there are several things you
can do here the two basic things you can
actually using docker you can isolate it
using active tables until very recently
docker 17 and later docker iptables
weren't really friends or at least they
weren't friends of each are also tried
to modify IP tables there was a lot of
like
stop on your changes there be a lot of
pain after 17 you can you can just drop
a rule in this docker user chain they're
good to go
using the you can also isolate it using
docker right so doctor has concept of
networks and under the hood what you'll
find is for every network there's a
bridge interface that it creates on the
linux box it when you add a host
container to a network it just drops it
on that bridge interface all the other
things and then it can do depending on
how you can pick the network it can talk
to the internet it can't it's not at it
isn't it just connects that bridge to
the gateway devices pretty simple
alright so you can you can tell docker
hey just disconnect this this container
from all the networks it'll drop all of
the interfaces internally and it's
totally isolated except if you're using
that little funding net work equals host
so that work equals host attaches the
containers directly to the interfaces on
the host itself you can't change that
once you've done it
that is own that is only the smallest
reason network vehicles hosts can be a
painful and bad so I heard you guys not
not to not to use it and encourage any
sort of product to deal with also not to
use it
it's it's easy which is what people do
it but it's it's a bad idea sort of
later in life the last thing is docker
checkpoint so dr. checkpoint is really
interesting it's an experimental feature
it's not it's not shipped yet you can
enable in docker and that's exactly what
you'd expect that's essentially just a
full snapshot of the hosting question
this is what would actually allow a
docker container to be live migrated
between hosts because it is a full
portable snapshot of a docker container
that's it
nothing supports it it's not like you
configured this docker checkpoint in two
and volatility yet there any volatility
gurus listening please build that'd be
awesome
but if you do use it it can be a very
very effective way of isolating this
thing for further investigation and you
can you know take it take the the check
pointed container from a server
somewhere where it got popped bring it
back to your system restart it there
it's nice it's a very clean way of
dealing with it once it hits once in its
production mmm get me close on time my
response so their muster standard doctor
commands I'm going to grip this a little
bit faster so I make sure I have some
time for questions
standard doctor commands like there's
some really cool stuff inside that
provides we'll talk about that next
slide but basically if we get right down
to it that docker container is just a
process on your box all the same tools
that you would use to investigate any
other process in general mostly work
because of the way docker docker exists
some things like like the PID the
process thinks it is is not the PID is
on the hosts file path so that the
process thinks is opening or not the
file path the two weeks that you want to
see in the host things like that are
confused and broken you can pull most
that information from docker itself the
great thing is anything else like you
can attach as trace to a process that is
the container and it works like you'd
expect it to work more or less you can
you can use G core to force a force a
memory dump or you know whatever other
your normal process specific memory dump
is on a container and it'll work
you can even TCP dump a specific
container using we talked about before
right that whole bridge gateway scenario
it's fairly easy to attach to the right
right bridge and filter on the IP
address to actually do a do a specific
pcap on a container let's talk about
these docker commands for just one
second there are a bunch of them and I'm
going to highlight just like to and you
can you can you can read the rest later
one is docker gif which will show you a
the file diff for running container like
how great is that but if there was like
a host OS diff that you just run when
you're doing response let's see docker
exec will let you run from the host run
a command inside the container this is
how you can spin up a bash shell
inside the container doing response and
do actual live response there on the
container itself we mentioned checkpoint
that link on the bottom there just goes
goes to a gist of a some bash functions
I use I wrote I use during inter
responses the develop docker that just
automate a lot of the some of the more
complicated things to pull like for
instance one of the functions in there
lets you pull a map of host PID 2 in
container PID for a given container that
just makes forensics after the fact much
much easier if you know that mapping
right things like that just in general
helps make your life a little bit better
last one of the questions and this is
interested I should have put this
earlier so I had more time to talk about
it so in this immutable deployment
concept right
there's a box running somewhere and I
don't have access to it I have known as
H access I can't get on it and it gets
popped because reasons right but then I
thought there are a lot of answers this
question you could you could have a
immutable deployment concept through
this there's a break glass involved that
has sort of pluses and minuses there
right but for us we don't want to do
that we wanted to actually make
immutable immutable so so so what can we
do this is what we can do we essentially
have automated instant response to
scripts that are sitting there the
monitoring and SQS cube they're looking
for assigned command we just borrowed
what gur does right you sign your
commands directly with GPG key so the
host knows that you waiting to kick off
an automated augment entire run on the
host itself to say like hey yep signed
requests let's do the memory dump let's
do the the running indicators do all the
stuff let's encrypt it back to the key
that's in this command and let's toss in
an s3 somewhere so you can pull it down
and do your forensics later without ever
having access to the host itself the
reason we do this we do this this kind
of thing on very very very sensitive
hosts or access to the host could
those things like private keys that we
don't want any one human being to ever
be able to see right let's see with that
I think we have about three or four
minutes yeah for questions questions are
you awake
okay the laughter says yes good well
awesome thank you all very much
I guess I will leave you stupid for the
break a little bit early
[Applause]