all right all right good afternoon
everybody thanks for coming to my talk
honey
I stole your c2 server so my name is
Andy rector consultant with mandiant
based out of San Francisco office I've
been with Mangan for over two years my
primary focus is digital forensics and
Incident Response during that time we've
conducted several enterprise
investigations for fortune 500 companies
involving all sorts of different
industries high tech health care
financial you name it all over the place
so what I'm going to talk to you guys
today about is an investigation that
mandiant did in 2016 late 2016
I'm going to give you a high-level
overview of how that investigation went
what kinds of stuff we found and just
overall what what that investigation
looked like and then I'm going to go
into the analysis of a c2 server so we
were able to obtain a c2 server I'm
going to tell you about how that whole
process worked and how rare and kind of
exciting the analysis was and some
interesting findings that came from
Postgres a Postgres database on the c2
server and then lastly I'm going to talk
about post-rock a Python program that I
paid to carve Postgres rose from a flat
binary file ok so before we get into
what made this investigation so rare and
exciting you should understand what a
typical investigation looks like so what
normally happens is a client calls us
they've identified some malicious
activity in their environment either by
themselves or through some external
notification like law enforcement or or
something else so we have a scoping call
we decide to deploy technology so we
deploy some network based technology
it's an endpoint based technology this
gives us full coverage of their
environment or as close to full coverage
as we can possibly get and then we begin
the investigation itself so this is
where we our tagline find evil solve
oh this is kind of a cyclic cycle where
basically we search the environment for
indicators of malicious activity up once
we find something we perform analysis on
the system or whatever the source of
evidence is that once we find activity
there we continue searching the
environment and identify additional
evidence of activity we keep pulling
those strings until there's nothing left
to find once we were able to completely
scope the environment and get
comfortable at a comfortable level that
we've identified as much of the activity
as we can we perform in eradication
event or remediation event where we kick
out those pesky attackers and also try
to improve the security posture of our
client so this is where we do things
like blocking see to rebuilding systems
and all the other things that go along
with I like passwords enterprise
password resets once that's done we
perform some post remediation monitoring
just to make sure those pesky attackers
don't come back into your environment
that usually last anywhere from two to
four weeks just to make sure that that
everything's good everything's a tip-top
shape once that process is done that's
kind of the end of our involvement with
our client and it passes on to a
different business unit and so on so
this investigation actually kind of
started out pretty pretty similar to
everything else so this is a fortune 500
financial based client and they were
aggregating windows event logs into a
syn interface and they identified some
suspicious service installations and
this was existed in September of 2016 so
what did that look like something like
this this big huge ugly blob just a show
of hands has anybody ever seen something
like this yeah a couple of people if
anybody knows maybe what made this or
what this is artifact based off of just
yell it anybody
so yet our suede empire are very related
so this is actually an artifact of
Metasploit so those of you guys that
don't know if Metasploit is medical aid
is just a freely available exploitation
framework
it's used by pen testers but we also see
it used by a number of different threat
actors including financial base threat
actors and even some apt threat actors
so some of the things that kind of stand
out about this so it's a service
installation and the service
installation is a 16 character really
random name now maybe you named your
services super long 16 character random
names but I don't and I don't think most
programmers I'll name their services
that either some of the other things
like comm spec which is just an
environment variable for cmd.exe
PowerShell being executed and then a
base64 string honestly whenever you see
PowerShell being executed
with a basic 4 encoded string it's
always something kind of interesting and
something that should be looked at so
basically what this resultant is a
memory resident backdoor so if anybody
is familiar with mature printer this is
what this looks like this will result in
mature procession so we understand that
this came from Metasploit so we can use
what we know about medically and the
artifacts that it creates to do some
intelligent flood scoping it will also
scope this environment very quickly so
some of the things that we look at are
these really random workstation names so
Metasploit actually implements their own
version of SMB the protocol to connect
to other systems in environment and so
when they do that it is cool random
workstation names and these works they
throw that field in without actually
just pulling into legitimate workstation
so we can do as investigators they
search security event logs for these
network logons involving 16 character
workstation names so that's one way we
can track lateral movement in
environment we also search for service
and slate
so these 70 45 event log messages that
contain comm spec basically for encoding
PowerShell very much the type of stuff
that you just saw the previous slide so
72 long hours anybody want to take a
guess as to what 72 hours that was if
you're thinking the weekend you probably
work an instant response because that's
exactly what it was so it's the weekend
we have to work it and we are able to
quickly scope this environment we
identified 129 systems that were
compromised by the attacker with
evidence such as the stuff that we just
talked about the server's installations
lateral movement activity 116
compromised accounts just kind of
cycling through different credentials
single works and also the initial attack
vector was able to be identified this
turned out to be a very simple poorly
configured public web server in areas
the client's environment they just
weren't paying attention to so this was
a sequel ejection that could have been
easily avoided but it just weren't
really aware of the system and how it
was configured so now that we have that
side of the investigation done we can
talk about the c2 server so in my mine
when we we do investigations we have a
two-sided perspective so the perspective
from the instant response investigation
or the offender's the enterprise
defenders we have that perspective and
that perspective is really framed by the
the artifacts and the technology we have
available so we can never be a hundred
percent sure that we've identified every
single system for a number of different
reasons whether it's our technologies
and deployed everywhere or so every it's
not every system has the artifact that
contains you know that gold piece of
information that's going to solve the
investigation we can do the best we can
with the artifacts and technology we
have available now if you've ever
thought for this investigation would be
a lot easier if we had a c2 server I
think that all the time it'd be really
nice but it's not very easy to get you
to server right there not in our
possession so if there a way to do that
well maybe for not in America but the
attackers perspective is something that
is would be really nice to have and
highly sought after so let's go back to
that service installation so this
service installation can actually be
used to extract the c2 server the c2
server IP address so how this works is
you identify that basically for encoded
data and the compression screen scheme
so this information this we have the
basic form credit scheme and then the
compression so in this case it's gzip
and some other cases it could be a
different compression scheme depending
on whatever the platform is being used
coal strike uses a slightly different
implementation of this but it basically
results from the same sort of memory
resident backdoor so once you do that
you get a second basically an encoded
layer to script right and this script
has a number of different functions it's
got some more basically four included
data so it need to be more basically
four encoded data why not just keep
decoding so we decode this second layer
function in this result and shell code
and I won't pretend to be a shell code
expert but the way this works is
basically adjusting this assemble the
shell code identify the appropriate
Network calls I want to identify that
you can basically reverse these are
going to be stored in a little endian
format so you reverse the byte order and
you're able to in convert that to ascii
and then you'll have the IP address that
is configured for this this backdoor so
at this point we've identified the IP
address that the attacker is
communicating with we know the IP
address of their c2 sir so as part of a
a very routine status update we provide
this decoded IP address
to our client now this is a pretty
normal thing we we always like to be
very transparent with our clients and
give them as much information as we're
finding as we're finding it as we
understand it we provide that
information to them so they can do
whatever they want whether it's make a
business decision or whether they want
to block right away and risk playing
like a whack-a-mole type game or whether
they just want to use it so they can do
their own monitoring as well so we
provided the IP address and what we
discovered is that the client actually
recognized the owner of the IP this is
going to be a bit of a wild ride here so
the client actually just did a simple
who is on this IP address identified
that this was a small-time competitor so
they actually had a relationship with
the owner of this IP address and it had
actually just ended it the week before
this attack began so let's all put our
tinfoil hats on and see where this goes
so they had to they had just basically
described this as a small-time
competitor they recognized this IP
address so what would you do well how
about you just ask just ask this third
party for their c2 server so the client
called them up and said hey you have a
server that is interacting in a
malicious way with our environment we're
going to need to just take that please
give us that server I'm not sure they
said please to be honest they well they
did they just gave it to it they gave
them the entire server which is really
really strange and weird and if any of
you guys interact with lawyers lawyers
probably get really screaming about this
I know our lawyers did like is there any
legal ramifications to doing something
like this well if you just freely give
things away it turns out no not really
so during the next status update the
client basically contacted us and said
hey proceeded to address you gave us
well we have the server now so I'm not
the drunk Mike but that would be you
know how their conversation which was
pretty interesting so we're like okay
okay what would we do here so they said
well how would you like to just image it
and do analysis on it of course we're
all going to be fighting to do that so
yes we did we went over and imaged the
system which is pretty awesome and these
are real pictures by the way of the c2
servers that are our analysts actually
took while imaging it we were going to
document the hell out of this so this is
real pictures they just boot it they
just you know this is an entire rack
mountable server that was provided by
this third party to our client so what
we did is just basically plug in a
keyboard a mouse a monitor and conduct a
live forensic image of the server cool
so now we have a 3-2 server we have an
image of it let's put this into our
forensic lab and start performing
analysis because this is really crazy
weird and we don't get to do this very
often so one of the forensic analysis of
this looked like well this server was a
Windows Server 2008 what we identified
is that the attacker had created their
own account on the system they had done
some privilege escalation and a
credential harvesting techniques so
basically a executed me me cats and got
creds awesome it gets even better these
are some ballsy attackers so what they
did is they downloaded VMware
Workstation on the server which is a
pretty big program and then they
downloaded a Kali Linux ISO which is
also pretty big by the way so nobody is
looking at that network apparently they
then installed a Kali VM in July of 2016
this is keep in mind two months before
the attack on our client began so this
is obviously where the really
interesting things are going to be we
need to go deeper this is a little bit
of an investigation inception
and we're also switching gears we're
going from Windows forensic analysis to
Linux forensic analysis so this is going
to be the interesting stuff so we export
that VM and begin the analysis again so
switching gears Linux forensics let's
look at some of the interesting
artifacts that we have available to us
so we have some valuable secure logs
that basically showed that the attacker
was connecting from a row reputa low
reputation IP address something from
digitalocean we also identified that it
was being scanned like crazy because
it's a public-facing Cali server so okay
that was kind of fun we also identified
a mature per configuration file
basically just the configuration file
for there of the TTP listener for when
they'd the fact or made a connection
back to the c2 server we identified some
access to some of the up tools that are
already installed on Callie by default
so the sequel map which like we said
before they had used a sequel injection
technique to gain access to the
environment in the first place so sequel
map might have helped identify that we
always perform keyword searches when we
have a forensic image so some of these
were really revealing first we ran
searches for some of the accounts that
we saw the attacker used some VIP
address some of the systems and
basically allowed us to verify that yes
this was certainly the system that they
were using we're seeing our clients data
on this system this is pretty bad news
so some of the stuff that was really
exciting actually was located in not
only an allocated space but also in
Postgres basically in Postgres files
so these postgrads hits kind of led me
to look at the Postgres history so this
tells us a bit of a story so Postgres
history basically showed us that they
had created a database several
iterations of database actually they had
connected using a couple usernames and
passwords
the thing is is that Postgres is pretty
messy it's not something that you can
just just export a file and load it up
into you know Postgres GXE and
everything's perfect just read it like a
sequel like database it's actually a
collection of files they're all just
flat binary files or you know depending
on the size of the database there could
be hundreds of them
so each one of these files kind of
represents a table in the Postgres
database itself so wasn't very easy to
look at it wasn't a publicly available
parser but knowing that one of the
things that you can do with Metasploit
is backup your information or save all
your information to a Postgres DB
something that you can do and that's
actually kind of encouraged by
Metasploit by the mostly developers as
well attackers are - are people -
they're probably not going to remember
every single credential they've sold and
you'd have a way to track all this
information so and so it wasn't an easy
way to just kind of export the database
why not just boot up the VM itself so I
just said well I have VMware Workstation
to work well for the attacker I can do
that so it turns out but as I glued this
thing up it was password protected also
not a big deal with Kali workstation so
boot this thing up into single user mode
and then basically configure the grub
interface to execute a bash shell so as
soon as a booted up it booted it loaded
a bash shell and I can change the
password so I just changed the users
password and now I had access to the
attacker system so I felt really cool at
this point because I don't know about
you guys who do instant response I spend
way too much time in Microsoft Excel
doing filters and tagging things red so
this was really exciting I felt like I
had just like executed got system
impersonate attacker on this entire
thing so this is really fun
really cool and nice change of pace on
how you know how instant response
typically runs so you know Metasploit is
used to attack things I bet you didn't
know you could also use a fur and it
responds so in this case basically I
could you I could leverage the Postgres
equal history to obtain critical
database information so what does that
mean well I know that they created a
user MSF or they created a database also
called MSF also these things contain the
user empath username password so MSF MSF
not a crazy password here so actually
just use the MSF console or a med
exploit console to connect to the
database directly so I can are not
connect to the database directly but to
actually interact with the post source
database lots of really cool things so
what I could do using Metasploit is
execute commands like creds ho lubed
notes loop being particular interesting
as a kind of a sexy name but it also
shows us the kind of post post
exploitation modules the attacker had
executed notes and services basically
just showing us kind of the
reconnaissance that the attacker has
done across the environment bones
whether they've identified any
vulnerabilities and systems and then
whether or not they actually exploited
those vulnerabilities or status on it
this is really cool this is a lot of
really good information but it wasn't
perfect not everything had timestamps
and for an instant responder timestamps
are kind of everything timestamps framed
the information that we are gathering
and the artifacts that we found into a
perspective that we can basically show
the client and they can understand what
has happened without those timestamps
the value of the artefact is this
lessened really it's good for obtaining
indicators but less valuable for framing
where they occurred and be
HAC so I wanted more detail so I figured
okay well I use Metasploit to interact
with the database why not just interact
with the database directly so using T
sequel I just connected to the database
directly this is awesome
so lots and lots of tables as you can
see some of the cool things that I
really like is like the Metasploit
credential public so you can see a
couple of things like it's got created
timestamps it's got updated timestamps
it's got the actual user names these are
like these are the actual tables from
the c2 server itself so I can see the
different accounts that the attacker had
had actually identified and harvest
credentials for this is just a couple of
them so credential realms so this is
going to be the domains that the
attacker has enumerated also timestamps
everywhere sessions is going to be a
little bit hard to see but sessions
being the most cool thing you could
possibly see in a Postgres database that
is for Metasploit and the reason it's so
cool is because these like big old
basics before blobs actually decode to
session information so this is going to
show us how how the attacker actually
configured their payloads so it shows us
username password different the the
network that they enumerated what they
were scanning a lot of highly highly
detailed information the Postgres
database stores entire meterpreter
sessions and the configuration that the
attacker used including every command
they executed within mature pa'dar so if
they uploaded a file it's there they
downloaded a file it's there if they
dropped into a shell and executed
commands using a command shell it's
there and what else is there is output
so they execute net use you'll see the
output the shell output stored in this
Postgres database entire
recessions there is nothing left to the
imagination as to what the attacker did
in our environment our needs clients
environment this is really really
powerful great information and really
just paints a pretty amazing picture
about what's happening here
so at this point case is solved right
the timeline right itself I mean we have
the perspective from the incident
response investigation that we can
compare with the perspective that we get
from the attackers situ investigation
it's all there and it all overlaps and
it just meshes together perfectly every
blank was filled in from the attackers
from the c2 investigation itself so this
is awesome client loved it this makes
for you know happy client happy
consultant everybody's happy this is a
big win for us really so post got post
crack is a tool that I developed based
on this investigation so some of the
inspiration was identifying additional
victims so like I said the attacker had
access to the system since the c2 server
itself since 2016 so July of 2016 two
months before we even were contacted by
our client in the Postgres history
contained evidence of prior deleted
databases so I wondered if there was any
way to recover those databases what kind
of information kind of led me to even
believe but there was something to
recover so besides the Postgres history
itself this could be verified via
keyword searches so in the same way that
we read keyword searches for our client
and client information those keyword
searches you could also just search for
some generic commands that the attacker
were executing so if they were executing
net use a lot like a keyword search for
every net use and see in an allocated
space that there were hits that contain
domain passwords that weren't identified
in the resident ProQuest database so
knew that there is additional
information about other victims on the
c2 server they had
just to it for at least three months but
we only saw evidence of attack for our
client so I wondered if anybody had
tried to do this before
there wasn't anything obvious there was
a tool that wasn't publicly publicly
available that was capable of recovering
different artifacts and different
database management systems but the
focus wasn't Postgres so I needed
something that was going to specifically
cater to the needs of Postgres and what
I had in mind
so I'm not a programming genius I don't
do a whole lot of development developing
but when I have a chance I do like to
kind of like dabble in it a little bit
so a Postgres sequel is a open source
which is really nice but it's all
written see I don't have a strong
background see so I didn't you know
immediately know how to read all this
information so it was kind of a fun
exercise in in research about a Postgres
work but also on the development work
cycle and how to even read you know code
from another language luckily these guys
have a strong development team behind
them and a lot of their code is
documented pretty well but still reading
see structures was a fun a fun ride to
say the least so I created the tool
called post rock to carve all Postgres
equal rows from a flat binary file so
this is something like a raw image so it
doesn't have to be just the raw image it
could be just the specific files located
in the Postgres installation directory
or it could be an entire forensic image
that's collected so I'm going to take a
little bit of a deep dive into Postgres
and what that whole you know just what
that whole structure really even looks
like so
hopefully this doesn't get overly boring
so the anatomy of a Postgres database so
a couple of the terms and definitions to
understand so tables so these are going
to be the actual physical files located
in the post guys installation directory
so each one should be considered a table
now these tables are going to be made up
of pages and so a table can have you
know fifty to sixty or one or two tables
it really just depends on the size of
the table itself the within each page is
going to be a real pointer free space
and a row entry that contains the row
data itself so this is kind of a
visualization of what this looks like
you know the red being the table header
itself the blue being the row pointers
that are going to tell us where our road
data is located and then the yellow
stuff is null space which we'll talk a
little bit about and then purple being
the road data itself so you can kind of
see at the bottom it's got some
information like command well that's a
command that was executed through the
trip retur so the page header itself so
the page header itself is a 24 bytes
structure it's got some version info
located in it from this header what we
can gain is information about the number
of rows we're going to find in this page
head in this Postgres page itself so
this is helpful for understanding how
many rows to expect in a page and how
many rows we're going to need to parse
this is part of also what my tool does
is is actually look for these types of
headers it's not an obvious header like
NZ header that's going to give you you
know obviously this is a PE file so what
I had to do with this is kind of look
for this this header that looks like
this using some certain entropy checks
about you know what what can't happen in
this sequence of bytes and so far it's
been really successful with identifying
the start of a Postgres page so the row
pointers itself therefore by structures
very important for Tongass a couple of
things where the data is located the
offset within the page itself as well
the size of the row so the size of the
rows and obediently the entire row from
the
a header all the way to the end of it
itself the end of the row the road data
the free space so free space is going to
be the section that follows those row
pointer those row pointers and what
basically can happen is that as
additional data is added to the page so
the row pointers will be added from the
top and then row data we added from the
bottom so in a Postgres page that has a
lot of rows in it there may not be any
free space so that's something that also
had to be account accounted for in this
tool post crock so the row entry the row
entry is split between two things so you
have a 24 by Tedder that contains
information about the row and then it
also has the road data itself this is
the type of data that you would see
displayed if you ran something like a
select star from table name that would
be the data this will be where this is
being pulled from so the row header a
couple of things that stick out just
like the row insertion ID and the
deletion ID so when a row is inserted
into a Postgres page it gets assigned an
ID for when that occurred and then a
deletion I do if the row is deleted so
when the row is deleted doesn't actually
mean that it's deleted from the disk
it's just deleted from Postgres file it
gets an ID you can say that well I'm not
going to display this because it was
deleted but it can still be recovered so
you can also get the number of
attributes so think of attributes as the
things that you would see as columns so
these would be the column headers so
each one of those is an attribute of the
table itself the offset to the road data
is going to show where the data actually
starts and the reason this is important
is because table and are rows that have
lots of attributes or column headers
this information will basically track
which one of those are in use or not in
use so you have to be able to understand
where this data is going to start so you
can track whether or not these columns
are going to have data in it or not so
the road data itself is going to be kind
of the different data types that you
would expect to see
so integers dates and times variable
length strings this is where a lot of
the the meat of the program live this is
kind of challenging because there's not
an obvious way to understand where
different attributes begin and end and
so you just have to you have to
basically look for certain signifiers of
say well this is going to be a string
data and the string data is going to be
this length and so there's a bit of
guesswork saz why this is a really a
carving utility so post-rock and its
capabilities so you said this is a
Python tool that is going to thoroughly
understand Postgres sequel like main
capabilities being medic and it's going
to carve rows from a flat binary file so
this would be the files located in the
Postgres installation directory or it
can also be a forensic image you can
also do keyword searching with it so if
I know that I'm specifically looking for
entries relating to a certain username
or I'm looking for entries relating to
medical a public credentials I can
search for that and just get only that
type of data you can export to CSV or
Excel access Excel and officially just
supporting version 9.5 of Postgres right
now
I suspected it actually supports more
than that I just can get continue to do
more testing on this tool so it is on
github so here if you to have a c2
server that an attacker used to back up
their entire thing to a post-race
database run this tool it'll probably
give you a lot of data so it'd be pretty
exciting
post cock findings so some of the cool
things that we were able to find with it
is that there was full interpreter
sessions occurring all three months that
this attack that the attacker had access
to the system so in july august
september everything over fourteen
hundred compromised credentials over
forty eight enumerated domains a lot of
activity and some of the things that
this look like basically we could do
some heuristics on the type of data so
as I said before this this postcard
database is going to store all the
modules we attack or executed so I
thought it was kind of interesting to
see if well let's see what their most
popular post exploitation modules were
so probably unsurprisingly this
credentials episode looking for single
sign-on credentials from a system as
well as ad computer is just a new brunet
DS smart hash thump credential collector
a number of different post exploitation
modules that they basically were running
almost every time they would be on a
system some of the ones that were less
common
our application specific ones like
tortoise SVN or Outlook so those systems
I would consider investigatively maybe
even more interesting because it seemed
like they were searching for something
and targeting an application
specifically maybe because it had
something interesting on it that they
were looking for so some of the things
that we found based on post-rock and in
the mature processions that were
extracted is that the attacker actually
added their user account to victim
systems so we talked about how they did
it on the c2 server well this is
actually what it looks like and this is
what post-rock would carve out basically
they add their user maava to and that
really really sophisticated password
that'll never delay it's not too bad
so then basically there's the output to
it as
while you can see that it was successful
they were successfully able to add their
user a new user to a system some of the
other things they did they were
uploading web shells a lot so a lot of
victims got web shells everybody got a
shell which is pretty fun so they
uploaded something publicly available
this NT Daddy PHP also other shells
called command dot PHP then you can see
they run you know they always run like a
dir LS command to basically see and
verify that their uploads worked so on
the server you can see that they also
that it actually worked it's on the
remote system and it's called ode r0 ASP
or 0.2 HP attacker data theft so some of
the things that they were specifically
targeting outside of just XLS documents
were web config files looking for
different configuration files for web
servers said there seemed to be an
obvious interest in web servers and
uploading web shell C system so some of
the things that they downloaded though
outside of that on users workstations
where things like Wi-Fi pass xlsx and we
saw this a lot even in our clients
environment the attacker actually just
downloading passwords dot txt passwords
that Excel xxxx wherever they were
sewing passwords these users were suing
passwords on desktops or user
directories all over the place which is
kind of like looking for kind of just
lazy users storing passwords on their
desktop common attacker things so we
also see that they view FileZilla
content downloaded another excel file
some of the fun tradecraft that we saw
so they used PS exec it which is just a
common Microsoft utility you can use her
lateral movement so they started a
basically a net cat shell to their come
their command-and-control server using
PS exec and then we also see
they have other files so one of these
files that are pretty interesting file
dot zip they'll see NCW c PS exec that
you can be basically a stage a directory
for this attacker so keep in mind file
dot zip we see is that the attacker then
tried to unzip their their archive write
file dot zip and they had a strong
password password of b well actually no
not a password of d they actually forgot
their password and so the very next
command we see is it actually use
PowerShell and grab it from another
victim another victim system and just
download this other DLL right so file
new one DLL so I thought that was kind
of fun that they had a zip archive had a
poor password for it actually forgot
their poor password for it and then just
use power shuttle download it from some
other victim self kind of fun so fun
tradecraft nothing you know a lot of
their commands weren't of groundbreaking
but it was fun to see the way they
interact with systems and how they were
very successful
so in summary so Mandy basically did an
investigation last year for an unknown
attacker
and a fortune 500 financial environment
and then we were able to obtain a situ
server thanks to our client and we did
forensic analysis and a lot of forensic
value came from a Postgres database
itself so Postgres was really just a
gold mine for solving this case and also
looking for additional information and
finally based on this investigation
develop a tool called post rock to carve
Postgres equal rows from a image file so
just a couple of takeaways one of the
things I like is that Metasploit gets
the job done a lot of times I've heard
you know medical aid isn't a tool that
you know real attackers use well
actually see real attackers use
Metasploit very frequently and they're
very successful with it you know just
because you're not making your custom
these custom malware custom utilities or
custom platforms that you're not
successful
environments are still getting pwned
from Metasploit and people who can
really use Metasploit very well are very
successful operational security I'm kind
I thought it was kind of funny that it
really had the attacker just practice
some operational security this would
have made this investigation kind of
obtaining a c2 server kind of
uninteresting what if they had used full
disk encryption and just encrypted their
entire VM that would have kind of
hindered my investigation what if they
had deleted Postgres history post a
sequel command history or use a
different database name or change their
password for the database to be
something other than MSF MSF just a
number of different things that I think
we've kind of interesting from an
operational security standpoint they did
delete a lot of stuff that they used on
the Kali VM itself but they just kind of
the Postgres database that they're mine
and that turned out to be a huge
forensic way and then lastly if you want
a c2 server just ask what questions oh
jeez
yeah yeah so the question was whether or
not it affected the chain of custody
when they sent us a c2 server and the
answer was no so the chain of custody
for us started at our client because our
client had the c2 server so for us it
was client gives us C to server actually
not even necessarily gives us we went to
their site and imaged it so we never
actually took the c2 server the physical
rack-mountable server itself we just
took an image on their site location so
chain of custody was really just
starting at that location took image
took image to our forensic lab good
question yeah
a good question
so that was a bit anti-climatic I'll be
honest it turned out to not have any it
was really more opportunistic I think if
I had to take a guess the attacker maybe
understand do that there was already a
relationship between this third party
and the client so they probably
leveraged that a little bit but overall
no they were not attacking them for any
espionage gain or anything or they
weren't angry they ended the contract
you know yeah anti-climactic unfortunate
good question any other questions whoo
thank you guys