so thanks for coming and seeing my talk
I always find the spark of the talk the
hardest part so I wanted to start this
one with just a little story so I I went
through this conference about a year ago
maybe a year and a half it was good
DevOps tastes like a really awesome
event
it wasn't an info set conference it was
a DevOps conference so I went to go to
gets very different perspective of
things and that was a guy given a talk
and he said who here is in security so I
put my hand up so a few other hands go
up around her around the audience and
then I heard some from the back just go
boo and to me that kind of that told me
what some of these other teams think
about inverse act right InfoSec is often
blockers we're there to say you know you
can't go live or your application is
broken or you can't do this and you
can't do your job and actually I found
this this image online I don't know who
made it but it kind of it says something
right even security these security as
the bad guy so I want to try and think
about ways where we could stop security
from getting in the way stop security
from being a blocker and tell me instead
turn security into an enabler I think
this is at least someone else's
automation because once we can start to
automate security we can start to
integrate security and when it's
integrated it actually becomes a part of
a company's ethos and their culture so
just quickly I Who am I I'm Jamel Harris
some people might know me as J I'm a pen
tester for digital interruption so this
is the company I started where but was
saskia right here um we do penetration
testing but also one thing we're going
to focus on is is more of this on like
deficit hawks type of approach to
security so we're developing new tooling
and methodologies developers can use
firstly I'm interested in things like
mobile application security I really
like reverse engineering
software-defined radio as well I've
given a couple of talks in SDR some
Twitter accounts that I think are worth
following
obviously me but also mentis the gray
hats so this is a group I run in
Manchester where we put on you know kind
of workshops are free workshops on all
kinds of topics I'm gonna get a lot of
help from Thunder Manchester InfoSec
scene there which is pretty awesome we
compete in cts we run CTF as well and
then the ice security is that company
Twitter account where we published our
research and things so if you want to
keep an eye on you know what kind of
things we're releasing as a company I
check that out I'm not a developer as
you can see here I'm mostly looking at
things from a security point of view and
thinking how can I use my skills to help
development before moving into security
I was a software engineer so I think
that's maybe why I have a site down
perspective compared to a lot of other
other pen testers I speak to so why did
I want to do this talk after speaking to
some other pen testers and a lot of my
friends they always tell me man I hate
pen testing pen testing sucks I want to
go work in Sainsbury's instead and I got
totally get it because I felt this the
same way after afternoon pen testing for
a little while all right
it's actually really boring right anyone
here there's an experienced pen decimos
that we spent a lot of time looking at
the same types of things there's only so
many times
finding cross-site scripting is going to
be interesting and I really hate being
bored and pen testing yeah it can be
simply kind of boring um writing
low-risk issues as well
so when I'm on the test and I find all
these kind of low risk you know head is
not HTTP headers not set or things like
that I've got to put those in the report
and that means if the report takes a
long time to write because there's loads
of those issues which take them to the
next point with no one's gonna fix those
right if you are the bad guy report
these low risk issues um then they're
not worth fixing as the pen tester I
need to report those because there's
still a risk involved with them so I
need the brothers in the report need
spend the time right in the report
knowing that no one's gonna read it so
that's like really the motivating ah so
from the pen testers side of point of
view we think that is kind of limited
value to some organisations and the fact
that we still have horrible software
it proves that right companies are still
getting breached even though they are
fantastic so pentesting yeah kind of
coma sites from the develop their
developers point of view again the
reports get padded with these low risk
issues so they're paying a small fortune
to have someone come in and do a pen
test and what they get back is you know
a 50 page document that says we found
that the cookie flag wasn't set or some
very convoluted but I've an ability
that's not actually exploitable because
we don't understand the context of the
vulnerabilities so when I'm on the test
I might be there for a week maybe two
weeks or something I don't really
understand much about what the
application actually does so I can only
rate things based on my kind of
experience at the time and that doesn't
necessarily fit in with the reality of
what the organization needs so I might
risk something as as a high-risk but
actually the organisation might have
controls in place it turns it into a low
and I'm not gonna know that all the
developers are going to see is a pen
test report with a high risk high risk
issue that is actually a low risk issue
or it could be the other way around I
might raise something as a medium and
actually it's you know business critical
to them as an example I was doing a test
on a mobile application where I may have
to disable this the security control
that to me it didn't raise him that
important but this was a big part of how
the company made money so once they saw
that you know this thought that I kind
of freaked out and I would have only
raised it probably as a loan because it
was very simple control that I didn't
really see was doing much anyway there's
a lot of ego insecurity and an info set
um I was on site with a colleague of
mine this was a few years back so he's
honestly one of the most skilled hackers
and pen testers in the UK but we were on
flight together and blue balloons a code
of view and he just starts kind of
mocking the developer like artists
developer you can't believe you had this
one ability look what I found blah blah
blah and the devil sitting right behind
us so again imagine you are the other
developer you've gotta work good InfoSec
and you're working with people like that
you know we have a lot of video and
we're hard to speak to and also I think
a lot developers understand that
I can't stop development right they need
to release on time that is the priority
when security comes in and says you
can't go live while the developer says
well you know what this is this is
what's making the company money so
there's always gonna be this friction
between between pen testing so we don't
like it as pen testers developers don't
like it I couldn't provide them too much
value there's also this problem where
people don't even really know what a pen
test is and I'm sure a lot of people
have seen maybe in an email or something
ten test report with a capital P and as
if it stands for something cuz I see a
lot from them for my clients we've just
kind of points out to me that then
people don't actually know what pen test
is right they just know they they need
one I was speaking to speaking to this
client recently and we were going
through the Skorpion process and he said
so how long will this take
and I said oh you know he about five
days this is quite basic web app oh five
days it's a long time so you just you
say you press go and then you get the
results back five days later I'm like no
there's no there's no hack button it's
like five days of doing things but he
honestly had no idea what a pen test
entailed I just he knew at least he had
been told they needed to get one and
also we can't even in the industry we
can't always agree with what a pen test
is in a red team boils down for an
assessment you know these things if you
speak to any pen tester they can have a
slightly different way of thinking about
it or describing likely what that kind
of test is so we're confused
our clients are confused we say that pen
tests don't really provide value they
don't really want pen test anyway
because of all the things I've spoken
before so we're gonna just look at this
fictitious company and a bit of a case
study and they're called talk squared so
they have a number of occasions I'm glad
somebody got the joke so number of
applications are web applications and
one of them was breached
okay well yeah they had a pen test so
how could something like this happen if
they have a kind actually they're secure
then again I'm gonna point out that this
is it's more of a fictitious bad thing I
mean
[Music]
sorry I mean I'm not reading too much
about smoke here yeah but yeah I mean
scope was actually a big thing
pentesting is I'm actually a decided by
the next time I do this um so fictitious
company they have web applications one
of them work was breached so they have a
traditional development star right so
they go through this waterfall
methodology which I'm sure everyone or
most people here will be familiar with
basically we start by gathering
requirements design the application
implement it and then this is when
testing so once the application is
implemented and finished then they get
tested now this isn't just security
testing this is going to be Quality
Assurance testing as well and actually
at this point sometimes this is come to
the end because the company realizes
they have enough budget for security so
they can't even think but in this case
that's kind of assumed that they do get
a pen test and then only after that will
they deploy like as I said sometimes in
the real world there really isn't enough
budget to complete the security testing
which is a real shame so we looked at
traditional methodologies and so let's
look at what I would do in a more
traditional type of pen test I would go
on site like which I quite enjoy don't I
get to wear a suit for like a grown up
which is pretty cool um so I got insight
I then have to usually go to a reception
and you know go through security get a
badge then I wait my contact will come
meet me and he will show me the toilet
slop and where the coffee is I finally
get to sit down I get I get my IP
address but I need the test or the
application or whatever and then I gotta
wait for credentials and the worst I've
seen this is I was on site with three
other consultants we were there for five
days which is a 20 day engagement and we
spent the first three days waiting for
credentials so the 15 days of the test
on so we let credentials we do some
testing when we can wait for some more
credentials test a bit more venti we
leave and then we send a repeat the PDF
report in the end
you know with there's been a lot of time
with distracting people writing reports
et cetera developers tend to feel like
this every time you find a vulnerability
right
because they just think they don't want
us to find things so we're there every
time we find something they know that
they've got to address it or fix it or
it's gonna affect their deadlines I'm
just gonna make them look bad the
companies are kind of throwing money at
the problem and testers have large day
rates um anytime we find issues the
deadlines get pushed organisation have
to decide whether they accept the
vulnerability or whether they know they
have to need to manage it and etc
they're just throwing money away but as
a consultant if I'm fine from my point
of view so let's take this company and
say that we did with some pen tests and
we found some vulnerabilities we have
some critical vulnerabilities such as
remote code execution or sequel
injection
you know the client-side prices are
trusted so in this petition application
let's say that is some kind of
e-commerce site you know if this
trusting prices from the client that
that's a big deal and then you know a
load of issues I would say a high risk
such as you know coupons might be
guessable or likely sent occasionally
some pages you know there's always a ton
of medium risk issues
not everyone him with Nessa agree that
all these are medium but that's kind of
on the problems right the way that I
rate the run abilities is fairly
subjective but I think about what I
think it should be as a risk so but
there are some techniques like the more
objective so there's like cbss schools
and things but then these have their
weaknesses were they don't always
capture the right details so sometimes
yeah I might write something as medium
when and other pen testers wouldn't or
maybe I would even rate it as a
different thing on a different day you
know sometimes it's just like poor you
medium and then loads of low risk issues
so we're gonna try and do is let's see
if we can take these issues and see how
many of those we can automate away okay
or we can we can automate so that
you no longer will find them during a
pen test but before we do that hands up
if you would have gone live with with
this pen test report so if you had a
application with all these
vulnerabilities would anyone go live
with it what hmm why not yeah and you
know what there are tears I see that
most companies they will go live when
they know that there are vulnerabilities
because again you know they have to make
money and making money is that priority
which it should be it kind of makes
sense so I've definitely been there
situations where we've delivered similar
reports to this and there's no choice
but to our life there's always the idea
that they will fix the run derbys fun
business later but that rarely happens
in fact I remember this one time I was
doing a test went back six months later
and did did another test for them I
guess I'm application to have the same
issues so um did you address anything in
northern loss pen test you know what
happened oh there was a pen test before
that so I think what happened is the
teams have changed the PDF report that
we send through which is why we do n
tests normally must just got lost in
someone's inbox so they had no
visibility of that at all so they have
no idea the offenders that even happened
six months prior so the solution I think
is we can't ignore security right that
would be a problem so we need to pull it
hand into the hands of the developers
and the test is already in the team so
we will left-shift it all right we're
fine put your questions for the
beginning of the development process so
that's been mostly to testing earlier um
so it's cheaper which is fantastic but
also there are different ways to test
when when it's earlier so our for
example unit testing and we look at that
in a bit later but unit test is not
something that I'm mentally gonna do as
part of a pen test but it is totally one
of the ways that developers test their
applications so let's look at
requirements and design part of the the
design the methodology I'm kind of team
putting these two things together but I
think they're related so we're gonna see
if we can integrate security in the
requirements and the design part
of the application development so
firstly um I'll say is for some
applications you might decide actually
you don't you don't really care about
security and that's fine if it's an
internal application maybe that has no
user data or maybe only trusted users
can use it it's probably I probably
don't need that much security involved
with it so don't worry about it focus
your efforts on other things if it's a
FinTech application something that's
public something that handles payments
something that's likely to be attacked
these are the applications where we need
to add more more budget to do security
tests and do them earlier and you pro
you the pen test as well in these cases
but the the thing is it should be an
informed decision to understand your
application understand whether it should
be tested or not and so I kind of like
how I try to put this in there a bit of
a graph right so if there's something
that's down here when the greenside
forget about it um if this don't often
what's more the red side you want to add
more security budget more budget should
be used for security only it's kind of
relevant to each company's risk appetite
as to where they want a place or
application so firstly let's think about
kind of the ways that we can discover
threats you want to be able to think
like an attacker so in the design stage
we want to say say ok so how might an
attacker abuse our applications and
there are a few different techniques we
can use so we have threat modeling um
this is where we start to decompose and
understand the application where we want
to try and determine the threats and
determine the countermeasures that we
want to do and this would be more like a
brainstorming activity right so we'll
sit down and try and and model the
threats of the application think about
one attacker might have to do where the
attackers were coming from what assets
are they gonna be after I really like
abuse stories don't we like the name is
weird after Google a few stories but so
this is more like a in fact we'll talk
about this on the next line so I'll come
back to it one thing that I'd also
recommend is looking at previous pen
test reports
often times there may be some common
vulnerabilities to an organization so if
you're developing an application and
you've had previous pen test on take a
look at those try and understand those
maybe there's maybe there's a library
that has been used a lot that's
introducing fun abilities or maybe
there's too certain the coding practices
that is kind of inherent within that
company so if you can identify those by
reading previous pen test reports you
have another way of thinking like an
attacker to try and improve the next
design training of course if you don't
want security training send your team on
security so many developers and your
testers then they have that they would
have an understanding of how how pen
testing works and how security testers
will go out looking for vulnerabilities
and I will say what this might be a good
place to to bring in external help but
you do need to use external consultants
these security firms do it right at the
beginning rather than right at the end
which is more traditional way you know
have them come in and help you to to
brainstorm threats to applications so
with a few stories they kind of like
user stories in scrum but more from the
attackers point of view so we can say is
as an attacker
I want to login to the application
without knowing the password and you can
document these and you can just get a
list of as many as possible know as a
type I want to to get free stuff or as
intact there I want to change the
ranking of specific products all right
so we have a way of documenting the
things that an attacker might want to do
within the application and of course
with each of these they can be broken
down further so as an attacker I want to
log into the application without knowing
the password well we can prove force it
right might be after you sequel
injection to bypass the authentication
mechanism maybe it as part of Reese
reset for another user so these things
we've broken it down and again this
should be something this was done with
the team it should be done with a
brainstorming session try to understand
as many ways that an attacker might be
able to abuse the system so in theory if
we did this properly and then design
your application based on this on
abuse stories there would be no
vulnerabilities but of course there will
be implementation issues that we need to
address later so one thing that I like
is security requirements right I when
applications of the birth they need to
be this requirements document where they
slay out what the application should do
very rarely do I see security
requirements added to that list
so if if we start at things such as web
progressively over HTTPS
this becomes a requirement the
application so now pay a good
application and application the meets
the requirements a finished application
is a secure application but we've added
that the security requirements into what
complete looks like and we can use some
of the previous techniques we saw to do
IP security requirements
so with security requirements we're
gonna what we try to do is we define
design problems early on okay so we've
looked at their requirements the design
stage we thought about how to try and
add security for that about
implementation how we're gonna try and
add security into the actual encoding
side of things I think it's really
important to embed security knowledge
inside the team again with training
right so we if we have developers and
testers understanding what security is
they they have another kind of tool to
be able to to use to detect for security
vulnerabilities and they have the the
knowledge to write good code write
secure code herring is a really like
this technique so with pairing you might
have two developers sitting in front of
the same keyboard I'm actually coding
together and if one of those guys or
girls people if one of those I got
thought of last time for using these
guys so if those coders has security
understanding then they will actually be
able to must train the other one because
you know so one person goes to write
some code room for example this they are
seeking judging the other person sitting
there and
sighs they were Beyonce RIT that's a fun
ability there you need to change it this
way then it's the knowledge kind of
being spread within the team
the advantage is once the parents are
the pair's change now you've got two
people on Social Security and so that
pairs will understand it as well so it
kind of makes it the security noise
mixes within the team the very very sort
of non-threatening way security SME
started matter experts actually I would
like to see more companies hiring people
to be the subject matter expert in the
team so this will be someone that they
can actually developers can actually go
to the last question hey you know like
what happens if I do this or what is
what's the best way to do this or what's
the risk of you know handing something
this way so this is like it should be a
dedicated role I think it's really
really important rather than just either
happy to google it or guess it or bring
in expensive external contractors
security champions so this is slightly
different from SME this will be
someone's actually part of the team
someone that's maybe a developer as well
and and they're the person you're
highlighting as the person that want to
be more involved to security I think is
actually really important because when I
was a software engineer I was really
interested in security and the only way
I could really do security stuff was to
comment on tester would it would have
been awesome if they would have said hey
you know what you interested in security
how about your the security champion
will send you to security conferences
would you know add training around
security then they would have had my
security knowledge inside the dev team
which would have been great
and I've seen not like I saw my friends
as well have similar backgrounds where
they were developers they wanted to do
security stuff and the only solution
they had was the content tester because
where they work did not didn't give them
the flexibility to do more security
things security code review is a good
way to embed security into the team so
lots of places they will have some code
review process before Cole gets checked
in or used and if we're looking at that
from a security point of view as well
then that's a really good way to pick up
security issues and also to embed this
ID
of quality security quality inside the
code base so developers were actually
quite proud of the code they write and
but one of the problems is that security
has never really become a metric of
quality for a lot of them so once that
happens with things like code review
then quite security becomes a measure of
quality and then because I won't be
proud of their code that will be a few
around a bit is now understand secure
ditches a bit more has anyone heard of
chat ops before yeah so I came across
this some reason I really liked it I
worked at a place doing internal pen
testing for quite a large company and
there was this there was a lot of
developers use slack my turn to the guys
in security and said is anyone here on
slack and they'll be beyond slack
there's just developers and you know the
whole team is here anyway so we don't
need to mic ok fair enough
and I went on slack and I hosted more
security questions in slack then I did
any other way that was the assumption in
the security team that if the developer
had a question they would call us up or
often as in that email or something but
as he is they were mostly just asked the
question on slack and hope somebody
would answer it and by having someone in
arm in the slack channel who honestly
security was he able to to really help
them in a way that made sense for them
and of course conferences I think
companies are really important both from
InfoSec so if you're working with
developers send them to InfoSec
conferences they learn a lot also I
think I say if I set people to go to
more developer conferences and try and
you know it's great if I can talk to
other security people about what I do
but it's better if I tweet the
developers about whitey and get them to
understand why security is important um
ok so developers they know they want to
add security in develop is know have to
test their own code and there's this
really useful technique unit testing
where we write code to test our code I
very rarely see security tests on a unit
testing at the testing level is a shame
if we can try and integrate secure
testing to unit testing again we have a
different way of testing for security
vulnerabilities so what might a unit
test was security one bit he looked like
well given the attacker can submit a
username and password when they try more
than five incorrect passwords then they
then the account should be locked so
this is following more of like a bdp or
behavioral drift and development
approach to unit testing but we map out
our requirements that we saw earlier we
can map those out to statements like
this and when we have a statement like
this we can turn it into some code now
this is not good code it probably won't
work really for the unit test but we can
see that we have with setting up the
application the way that we want with
with doing some kind of action I found
logged in five times and then we check
if the account is locked so now we have
a way that every time that application
is built this test will run and the
developer instantly knows whether
there's weather updating is vulnerable
to to brute forcing accounts and I think
the real part is here is that it is run
every single time that the application
is built so we've got some
implementation stuff arm and what about
moving off to the testing side of things
why I would say is we have tons of
Packer tools for hackers right I think
we need fewer of those we need are more
hacker tools for developers and testers
things like birth suite and sequel map
and and map awesome tools for a pen
tester but they don't really make too
much sense for for other people because
they don't work in a way that makes
sense for the way that they work like as
an example I remember there's this open
source tool it's really cool I used a
lot for in pen test and the company that
created it they tried to make a pro
version of it and they added they added
a GUI on top of it as I think oh now
it's a pro version for developers and no
one bought it because it just it wasn't
how developers wanted to use the kind of
software and how they wanted to test
test their code well they want isn't is
more like this so
it needs to be something to have an API
that can be integrated into the build
system so when the application is built
with Jenkins for example with Jenkins
think and then kick off scans correlate
results and then give back a pass or
fail to the developer no they don't
necessarily want them that has a
command-line tool with a cool hacker
banner in it and actually I did this a
few years ago I took a pen testing tool
I use quite a lot and I added a wrapper
around it so that it could be run from
Jenkins headed a plugin in Jenkins and
this was actually kind of cool because
what it meant is that when I built an
Android application it would run these
texts automatically and if the
application had the run abilities the
field would fail and I'd get kind of
instant feedback about that and if the
tool I found there was no run abilities
then that the potential passed in the
application would build successfully I
did write a blog post about this which
you can see on my website I think we've
actually expanded that since then and
we're actually developing this kind of
like larger tool around this we do have
a web interface make things easy but
really are the core of it is this API
that means that you know the web
interface might change maybe you can run
it from Jenkins or you know you can
write from online if you want because
it's just the Web API but this is the
way that I think security tools should
evolve do something that is it is
programmable some of that could be
controlled by an API because this is how
that developers want to test their code
in this how they can test their code so
there are a few different types of
security tooling sassed is static static
code scanning tools so what they'll do
is they will take a code base and they
will just scan the source code what
abilities uses pattern matching also my
taint analysis where it says that here's
the input here's the output and the
input is coming from a web request in
the output is going into a connector
base for example and nothing's happening
in the middle so therefore there's
probably sequel injections so it will
scan the application for
or fun abilities but I can't stand the
source code Nick Jones guy we could talk
about this at depth at Def Con a few
years back and there's tons of tools
that do this kind of thing but I'm 40
there's a lot of them are really
expensive the open source ones tend not
to be so great unfortunately then you've
got that which is more dynamic testing
so with with that this is running test
cases against a live application this
can be kind of hard to set up in a way
because you need to have the live
application there and working before you
can start running the test cases against
it but you know think about when you're
running like standing-room birth suite
for example or something where it's
actually sending off whatever requests
to the application doing some tests and
the same tape is up on a bit here these
tools exist but they need to be made
kind of aware of the application and
they need to understand what risks are
so it is and how the application works
to to be really effective but they can
be funny better for logic floors
compared disasters and then I asked is
pretty like a new way of doing it but
this is cool it's kinda like that's
where it's doing dynamic stuff but it's
using instrumentation so you have an
application maybe that's running and you
will the the if' tools will hook it and
then add security checks in on the
background the advantage is you can have
your normal test cases running or you
can just use the application and because
these two what by cooking the
application is running he is almost
doing security test tests for free which
is really awesome but there are some
downsides as well so we've automated
security all good we've got our that's
my SAS tools we can finish right I'm 40
it's not quite as easy as that scan
times can be an issue so I took a kind
of a vulnerable application and run his
app and burps we against it the scan
times were not super useful took way too
long something that's not that people
don't really want to add that to their
build times I tried running the version
2 of but again it's the same application
that found
I don't think actually finished the scan
it just didn't have a handle the app
so I could be quite naive to just say
run a scanner and you will get all the
results you do get some good things
right you say you do find a lot of stuff
but it doesn't find everything and again
you need to be able to tune the tool
properly to really get the most
advantage out there I've seen so many
development teams just take this app for
example and they just they just put a
URL in this app hit Stan and then they
assume that's going to give them full
cooperativity application in 8,000 it
needs to be solved properly so they
understand two authentication and you
know in switch pages to use and you know
all kinds of stuff they take a long time
to configure it correctly and many dev
teams might do that so our with QA
testing again we can try and add
security into this as well QA testers
can be really good at automating tests
but often they ignore security I was
speaking to the test at once and she
said to me
I asked you know DeeDee security testing
I'm as part of your mobile testing she
said security isn't my job so okay well
actually it's kind of a bonus job
interestingly I'm like a month or two
ago she messaged me said you know asked
on your own security is everyone's job
and it's awesome that that that she
thought you changed her mind and
understand the security is totally
accessible and it's something everyone
is take responsibility for and it means
that they can use the techniques that
they use the tests to do security tests
which again normally would just happen
during a pen test and if we can we can
use them to to help us with automated
automating our testing as well so if we
have the security requirements that we
look at at the beginning we can actually
turn these into test cases all right we
can we it will be easy for a QA test or
easier for a th tester take these test
cases and make a test and they don't
actually even need to understand the ins
and outs of security you know they can
they can make a test case to see that
will requests are goin over HTTP without
understanding why that's important and
what that means is these are going to be
fewer vulnerabilities that I find in a
pen test and actually I got this message
from somebody recently I was Gabe a
the torque at of the workshop our mobile
application security testing at a
conference good test bash and they ever
talk this person actually they won't
even act my workshop I was just talking
about security this for like days
because honest I won't shop about it so
I got this message from them and they
said you know I found my first phone
ability an application we were testing
an application and I realized that it
was sending the password over HTTP
well you'll a school like this is not a
super complex run ability but the fact
that they are after listening to me
thinking that ok security is not a big
scary thing I actually managed to find a
funny bit in one of the applications
they were testing proved to me that
actually this kind of approach can work
and again it's one fewer thing I need to
write in the pen test rapport I want to
try and minimize as much as possible
we've spoken about applications all that
infrastructure side well once we have
infrastructure as code which is one of
the keys to DevOps
we can start to use some of the same
tools we can use the SAS tools to scan
all sort of the scanner code
infrastructure code we can compare the
configuration files to a good baseline
and we can say you know we know this
this service this service you only have
what 80 open or 4 4 4 3 open or whatever
with the config files that's used to
generate that infrastructure we can make
sure that that never changes if it does
change it can be highlighted it can be
highlighted with an selected therefore
all the odds person understand that
there's been a change that is against
the baseline if you can't do something
like this there are other options such
as using hacking tools like nmap
vanessa's like we saw before
you're right wrappers around them and
try to integrate them into into your
process but that's gonna have some
challenges running these tools in a an
automated way that's quick and easy to
pass the results from this is harder
than more about the infrastructures code
type of thing so we instead that we've
changed our security checks into
something that's more like this alright
so the developer would commit some code
so that source code repo and this will
start bills
that bill system might check for
vulnerable dependencies right and then
it will run some source code scanning
stuff maybe the source code scan will
actually run on the developers box as
well so as they're developing in the IDE
they get instant feedback about any
security verses that introduce him
dynamic tests might get run and may be
that the volume it has only run once a
week because they take more time but
they can be run as part of the build
system and only if all these things are
successful the build gets deployed on in
the point deployed in production so we
have a way of pushing straight to
production which developers want to do
we also have security in place so now
security has become something that can
help developers get into production with
less risk it's also repeatable no these
are these checks will happen every time
that dedications gets built you know
gonna have a pen test every time that
liege in this bill so that working had
more of this traditional approach around
well as we're trying to move more into
something like this but where does hem
testing fit into something that is
continuously being deployed I tried to
do pen testing a company where they had
a very agile approach to their
development and they want us to pen test
their application that changed every
week it was it was almost impossible
testing became mostly just doing code
reviews right to try and see what's
changed you know how can we try and find
some run abilities in this area
oh wait note the codes changed again so
where does like pen testing and things
fit into actually this type of the saved
well what I would say is remember this
side where we said that some
applications do require pen testing
which is totally true I'm gonna say
something that we pushed into our
clients as well and actually there might
be something in this room the dynast
really agree with what I'm gonna say and
if you don't want me it oh yes but if we
have this more our automated way of
doing testing where security testing
where we know we have a
a known good application is going into
production we might say that maybe every
you know ex deployment I have after X
number of months or something then we
actually just have a tick box pen test
now I'm a pen tester that's saying that
in this case if all these things are set
up a tick box pen test might be okay
it's gonna be cheaper right because I
don't require as many skills it's a good
way to get new people into security so
it's gonna open up a new set of roles
where they go in and look for kind of
known issues they're gonna say it's more
like a verification to say okay we know
that these tools have been working
correctly and there's been no big
changes that the tools hasn't picked up
or you know things like that so it's not
about discovering new issues but mainly
verifying everything that you know about
is correct and again I think this is
going to be a real I realize a real way
to kind of change the way that pen
testing happens but also I think what it
would mean is that when the more
experienced pen testers come in they can
work in a way that's more like this
right they can do more like a red team
continuous type of thing where we're not
necessarily limited by to the scope of
one specific application instead we
might be monitoring an organization
looking for in a book that one weakness
that pops up at some point they can have
like an internal security team this just
content in looking at everything and
being able to feed that back into the
development process so they find you
know this issue being deal not picked up
by on the tick-box pen test will the
cheaper tick-box pen test not be if I
buy the tooling this kind of continuous
style of testing we'll pick that up and
they feed that back into the development
team where they can fix it and this is
where you look for kind of more complex
logic issues or new bones things that
take a bit more understanding of
security and kind of more experience in
security and you need to be able to tie
that all together all right so we have
now we have security coming in but not
just with pen testing at the end but we
kind of coming in from the continuity
running with the staffs and the desk to
coming from the QA testers and more this
red team approached our to continuous
security as well and you know bug
batteries might fit into that and
security test cases and that was all
coming into a central database which
Jenkins or the build system is using to
to decide whether the applications
should be deployed or not but in a way
it will happen as it currently is a PDF
that gets most in someone's mailbox and
I think this is a way better solution so
if I people say to you to me that won't
work
well some things they say is need to be
a really leet hacker to find security
probabilities and I think like that's
not true right
you can be you'd have to be very skilled
in security to file security
vulnerabilities checking that something
is going over HTTP doesn't require lots
lots of skills checking whether sequel
injection lock fittings bundle sequel
injection doesn't necessarily require
lots of skills to understand it and to
exploit it and to you know take that and
leverage and be able to do something
kind of cool
or something that's arm like shove off
the the issue might require more
experience but just don't detect it or
to find it oftentimes it's just putting
a couple of characters into a box and
seeing what happens so automated test
won't find everything that's true
but I don't find everything either
honestly if I've had a bad night's sleep
I might not find some some run abilities
if it's a new technology there will be
things I'm just I've never seen before
often I've seen juniors do testing like
testing application and that's the only
pen test that happens again that don't
have the experience to find everything
either so it's okay to not find
everything so as long as we can find
a lot of things or more things than
would happen without running it without
going into automated tests then you can
do them better either pen test to be
secure well that's not the pen tester
make sure you secure it's fixing the run
ability so anything that we can do to
increase the number of other bits we
find early
the better position we're going to be in
and the pen test as I mentioned is only
a point in time right so if we have a
pen test and they fix everything that's
cool but a year later they're gonna
introduce new probabilities unless they
have a way of I'm continually monitoring
for those new issues they can be in just
just a bad position so that's it either
not much time we got left 15 minutes
okay so arm chapters yeah yeah I want to
ask them any questions so could we still
up that time so smokey someone any
question yeah so it was that this one
yeah so that yes there is um there's a
really good one um I can't remember its
name it's called okay so so that's like
systems like that there do exist and
thirty pieces one I've used in the past
and I enjoyed it I thought it made sense
but basically yeah is it it allows you
to quite easily write tools that will
import into it and so everything is just
in one central place yeah I mean so
anyway that kind of make sense for the
company I don't think there's like one
answer it really depends on how the
organisation one so the question is
about how these these issues then get
fed into the dev team yeah it depends on
like if it is a large company is it a
small company is it you know a dev heavy
or they're doing other stuff as well I
wish there's no really one answer you
design some kind of policy that makes
sense for that team the hard part is
really to get the developers to be
involved with it
I've worked the places before where you
know they brought us in to try to help
invest security into what the developers
doing
that is they want to but also they got
stuff to do and any change is it's met
with resistance because they just know
it's going to take them time to to have
to work efficiently so yeah well we did
use threat fix it was really more about
like this is now the process that there
will be three things and then they get
exported zero zero and then it becomes
part of their normal while handling
process to one issue that one thing I
see a lot is that the PDF goes over to
the client of the phone abilities and
there's no one knows what to do with it
if we can start to treat them as normal
bugs then they just get picked up and
they get triaged and rated as they would
with other other non-security but
nothing that that's really one of the
he's you know he everything gets fixed
as other bugs
[Music]
yeah i think i think i am empathetic I
know because I've been there where I
work so when I was doing my first
internship I was doing development and I
said to my boss I have written this
application like you asked me to but
it's not cross-site scripting in and
he's like it doesn't matter I'm like
what does another like Krypton is like
yeah but to use it you've got to be on
the secure network and there's there's
like five users anyway so I just don't
worry about it
like oh okay that makes sense I think
ever since then I realized that security
is not the most important thing you know
you need to understand the other factors
there as well security is super
important but if it's on an entire
network and evil to be trusted to get
there then yeah there's there's more
that there's other things you can do
rather than certeyn a hack some brochure
where website
okay so the question was the biggest
barrier to seeing the stuff imprinted in
industry
um I think InfoSec the way that we
positioned security we always say that
you know you've got to be super elite to
find security issues I think for the
work I've done in the past where I've
told people that that's not true has
been where I've seen the largest impact
where they can actually they have the
confidence to look for vulnerabilities
our team after digging like indium
phosphate sometimes we can be very the
vehm in us and it should be more us all
right well over the end of the day if
I'm up hired by a company I'm I feel
like I'm there to help make that product
better I'm not there to tell them that
they're wrong they've they can't code or
that they suck is that I'm here to you
know you guys do the Badminton really
well and IT security really well so
we're working together to make something
good and I think once you start having a
more of like just an ass attitude to
things the knowledge starts did change
so security InfoSec understands more how
developers work and the Vipers on
security so the question was about the
layers of yeah I'm just wondering
whether or not you kind of map these
kind of layered security tests into the
profiles okay I'm so I don't really
um one thing I try to say is you know
understand who your but on sample your
threat is you probably don't want
application online does vulnerable to
script kiddies or you know anything if
you can find the front a bit about
running blog sweet other people can do
that too
and if that is what your threat is for
some organizations that's all they're
worried about you know it's maybe it's
like a 10 10 person organization where
they just that budget is tiny just make
sure that that's not gonna happen that's
not you fine have run pups we get on the
phones run a busy space and you're
probably fine if you are more worried
about that yeah I need to do more things
quick I've never really thought too much
about like yeah so might better have a
better you know the questions differs
from yeah so when you're working with
applications that yeah that you are
developing in cycles where you're moving
around lot really I think the only thing
you can do is to try and automate stuff
doing any kind of manual testing there
becomes really difficult like as I said
when I was brought in to do my new
testing a company that was costly
changing applications it was really
really hard so
said what they should have focused on is
having asked worked with the testers
that they already had that had the test
cases that and a way of testing
applications we should be working with
them to develop security test cases
instead of having us coming in to do pen
testing in it yes I think I think that's
probably the more sensible approach if
you have way of doing testing try and
add security into those Rob will happen
like a manual security test
yeah the questions yeah good question so
the question was about how clients react
to have a new way of doing security
stuff ah honestly that is one of the the
harder things when we first ID'd with
Rochon we as I said we're not gonna
defend testing we're only gonna do this
kind of stuff
and I didn't last very long because I
love our I said oh we want a pen test
fine we'll do it with the defenders um
so I think we keep more people to talk
about this and once it becomes easier to
do it this way there's gonna be adopted
the companies I've worked with where
they have tried to do the stuff the
biggest problem was not getting the
technology as place it was just
getting the developers to work in that
way so that's why I needs to become from
this like really embed it it's a way
that they're doing so again with
training with using the tools of they're
familiar with
I think what they don't want to do is
have like all these new tools they need
to run if it's stuff that already using
Jenkins Jenkins already kicking off
scans and doing things then adding
another one not the screws down is not
really a big deal saying here's like
this other you know here's this other
tool you pull around the gates there
because some pens have tried to do GUI
to some pen test tool that best becomes
an issue
so yeah there is um companies are slowly
moving for this idea but a lot of
companies it's ready lots of the smaller
companies they just they're told they
need a pen test because that customer is
asked for the pen test report and that's
their driver hand security and for those
described companies I think it's only
ever gonna be pen testing is the Cummins
that really want to have a highly
secure applications that might look like
this so yeah good question honestly it's
like when we slide like no pen testing
we're not gonna do it yeah yeah exactly
exactly what people to pay anything else
cool thank you very much guys