so hi my name is Joe not before I am
lets off my desk I work for BBC but I
did move the time one of my commuters
things is talking about mental health
I'm feeling his favorite thing to talk
about so like my Twitter handle I don't
score health I don't think I say is on
the speaker notes for the slides there
is a link on the last slide to the
speaker notes so if I talk too quickly
you miss that link or you want to look
at me afterwards look there also I'm not
going to talk about anything massively
like massively in detail value my
symptoms so there should be any trigger
warnings needed but if you do punch
stuff more please feel free to leave
similarly you need to go to the loo
pretty don't do that because everything
comes miss I think of their me saying it
in a slightly less eloquent way in the
speaker notes so what I'm going to talk
about today specifically in two sections
there is section about how I look after
my mental health how I check in with
myself
and then there is section on how to have
those conversations of how to code went
along home sewer goes I'm having trouble
because everyone wants to be helpful to
people who are having troubles with
health right but those conversations are
also quite hard to have and they're
quite hard to feel like you're having
them in a way that is helpful and
corrected not really really awkward as
the one who has had those conversations
from both sides of the table I've got
some tips that's why I can share those
with you as well so hopefully you're
come out of this talk with some ideas or
maybe how to check in with your mental
health along regardless if you're
suffering with mental illness or not and
how to have some conversations about
that
because we all have mental ill-health
you may not all have
diagnosable mental illness but we all go
through periods of feeling of mental ill
health stress losing something or
someone when you're physically ill you
can get a lot more anxious about that
kind of things and that can lead to
mental health there may be short
situational it's called situational
mental ill-health where an external or a
different situation is causing mental
health but we'll all go through that so
these tips are useful to have regardless
of your experience with mental
ill-health because we will all go so it
doesn't point in our life like
unfortunately we'll keep it in the faces
okay so can you hear me in the back I'm
not a load of hoping I'll be all good
thanks I just shout out is it this thing
okay tomorrow I won't do wandering then
I'll try and stay here I'm a bit of a
wanderer but I'll try and stay around
here then no perfect okay it works on
here but not on there anything know what
I'm just gonna just gonna
[Music]
so it's working on here but then if I
put that as it there
now it's working at me who knows
cool so my mental health status
sorry I'll stay here my mental health
status is that I suffer from generalized
anxiety disorder a very mild case of
complex PTSD i medicated on what i've
been on meds for about seven years and i
am in therapy so i am very familiar with
the mental health system and dealing
with that kind of stuff I'm very open
about this stuff because the more I talk
about it the less weird it is to talk
about it's less scary for me because the
more I say things and then people aren't
worried about it the less scary is to
talk about things which means it's less
because I suffer from anxiety everything
is scary if I can make things less scary
brilliant there are always people who
feel who appreciate me talking about it
is always someone who comes to me ghosts
thank you for talking about it there was
someone at my old work at my work I work
for BBC who came to me and said that she
because I've seen you tested her she
applied for a senior test a role after
hearing me talk about my mental health
issues because she owns herself with
some ental health issues I thought well
if she can do it maybe I can do it as
well so it doesn't make a massive
difference the reason I know so much
about self-care is that I've had to pull
myself up off the ground and figure this
stuff out myself if I can help one other
person to have this definite talk it's
so they don't have to learn it the hard
way
then it makes it kind of all worth it
there was something doesn't get out of
the struggles i went through trying to
get diagnosed so that's kind of why I'm
here talking about this stuff this is
just going to be a thing that happens
but I can't change this to the next
slide there we go so the biggest thing I
wanna talk about today is being aware of
your feelings and emotions which is a
really great thing to say because I'm
people are generally aware of what
they're feeling right but I wonder how
much we engage with those feelings in a
really like entirely rounded way I
didn't I started doing therapy I did two
cognitive behavioral therapy which is
where you look at the feelings you're
having are you trying to find evidence
for those feelings no that's against
those feelings it's a good way of
dealing with anxiety
because it's you have a front of you
that your brain is lying to you when
it's anxious about things which anxiety
is a lot of the time it's your brain
lying to you about things going wrong
I'm not saying you have to be constantly
navel-gazing because who has the time
for that right no one but I like right I
like picking out what's triggering
strong emotions good and bad I keep the
cry to journal so I'm great so I write
down one thing every day that I'm
grateful for so as a reminder of the
good things in my life leave our
particularly strong negative emotion as
well I try to figure out why why that's
gone from what's triggering it just
because there's useful information to
have knowing your own mind is quite
useful in knowing why you have feelings
is quite useful to have whether it's
something that you can avoid in the
future away something that you need to
work on
they're both it's always worth having
even if you do nothing it's still
information information by itself is not
necessarily a bad thing it is a lot of
work it can be a lot of work on the on
the slide for this there is a PDF of a
cognitive behavior worksheet where you
write down your feelings openness before
evidence against and you can rate how
strong those feelings are if you want to
give that a go you can it's not helpful
to everyone absolutely not but it is to
me because this thing that mental health
as well what's helpful to me might not
be helpful to everyone else because it's
entirely unique so I'm just giving you
what helps me and hoping that you are
they find something useful or it kind of
inspires you to think about this stuff
because it might not work for you that
you might look at this stuff and go no
that's fine it's so I think is so unique
that all we can do is talk about our own
experiences and hope that something
connect somewhere hmm there's a book
called Crucial Conversations tools for
talking when the stakes are high
dick no one's heard of that book that
book is really good for thinking about
how you how the feelings that you feel
in the moment that's actually a really
good book is they saying that things
like managers talking how hard
conversations with staff but it's
actually really good for communication
across the board the examples are a bit
heteronormative it's always Bill and his
wife Emily but other than that genuinely
quite a good book I highly recommend him
so the first thing I do is I write all
the time
I am constantly writing things unless I
really try to get my mouse over this
side
I find of mine what said that the
writing is the cheapest form the therapy
you can get because all therapies is
talking about your fitting interrogating
your feelings and the reason I
particularly like writing is because you
can write you can't write as fast as you
can think when you're stuck in a
stressful situation or actual situation
and your mind is going at like 50 miles
an hour writing things out it's a way
you get it to slow down because you can
only keep up with your hand when I take
your writing I write by hand with a pen
and paper because that's what feels good
to me you don't have to you can type it
out you can talk it you can record
yourself talking it out you can do
sketch notes and mind maps whatever you
want to do what I find helpful is
getting my thoughts out in a way that I
can review them back because reviewing
the back often leads to revelations
about that things right so that is my
that's why I say writing I mean right
get your thoughts out in a way where you
can review them at a later date and
they're concrete and it is slower than
your thoughts so for me that is writing
again you might not be able to do
anything with those feelings with all
those that information it's having that
information and being aware of things
that for me really helps no no that way
right we really mean to ourselves as a
species right but all the time we really
mean to ourselves how often have we
stayed awake thinking of things that
like interruptions is that the other
person does not remember when the waiter
said enjoy your meal in you went thanks
you two that kind of stuff that keeps
you those interactions that person is
not gonna remember but you remember and
you'll remember at 3 in the morning
we're really mean to ourselves all the
time the reason I write I write
something thankful for every day is to
remind myself that there are good things
in my life and I don't know I don't know
unique you think every day so I was
right what I'm great before even if I
mean great for it before because that
means I've got something in my life that
stays in my life a constant that makes
me happy
whether it be friends whether we someone
to work is a constant that makes me
grateful for my life and I've done that
for year and a half nerve and I found it
really powerful
again it might not work for you but my
main message here is give yourself a bit
of a break maybe and remind yourself II
could I can't my save you up to date all
the time not some constant looking for
work but because one it said it's all
for updating your CV when you are
looking for a job right it is one of the
worst things in the world and two I have
a list
Ami's I have a list of achievements that
I have done at work that I can look back
on ago maybe I can do my job maybe I'm
not the worst and it sounds so
ridiculous and so simple but for me it
is ridiculously powerful to have a black
and white record of things that make me
feel good that I can be proud of because
it's not sleeping mean to myself I have
to be kind to myself and that's really
hard by find if I'm kind to myself I
find it a lot easier to be kind to
others and being in a tech company of
being in a tech environment empathy to
our users to other people is massive it
is so important and this to me is a
really easy way of doing it cuz I've got
to be nice to myself so I'm gonna be
nice to other people so I'm going to
talk about self-care now like
traditional self-care what we think of
over here self-care so South care isn't
always meditation and or baths and
yogurt can be all of those things I am
NOT crapping on bubble bath meditation
and yoga but there is so much more to
self-care
sometimes it is that I let people take
my turn up first it's one my favorite
tweets in the lot
it's on tumblr but you know there are
levels of self-care
on the most basic stuff to the more
complex stuff and I'm gonna go talk all
of them as one how are you self-care and
what I can do what I can't do as a
barometer but how well I'm doing some no
come on your basic self-care brushing
your teeth in the morning in the evening
showering Greg Dulli feeding yourself
something that isn't just McDonald's
night after night after night or your
mum's really nice I don't know ever
making yourself presentable to yourself
and to other humans when I'm feeling
really bad brushing my teeth is the
first thing to go my teeth are awful
because I didn't brush them for a while
because I was too busy struggling with
everything else that is my warning sign
that is pound the alarm I need to do
some work on myself for me it tends to
be that or showering or wearing clean
clothes for pee for a lot of people that
I speak to it tends to be that kind of
really basic I don't deserve to be nice
and clean because you feel quite nice
after a shower don't you and putting
clean clothes on you feel good and deep
down you don't feel like you deserve
that so you don't do it I thought I said
that is my big warning sign making
myself fit for human consumption as I
call it then he bought your other stuff
which is harder also it's harder to do
and harder to notice when it's slipping
I find reaching out to people going hi
how are you why don't we just I must say
reaching out to people I don't mean I'm
having a hard time I mean literally
talking into people that you enjoy
talking to that kind of sleeping that
kind of slowly coming back into yourself
a little bit because I think's a little
bit too hard that's really important I
can be really important I think it's
really important people to do but it's
really hard when you're struggling to do
it keeping physically active doing
something cozen staying in bed or going
from the bed to the sofa and staying on
the sofa than going back to the bed
again that stuff again mmm it's really
hard to for me that's another that these
are all like warning signs when I'm not
doing these things I love going to the
gym I'm one of those people so I don't
wanna go to the gym that's the way for
warning sign being mindful
there's nothing meditation it can just
be going for a walk without music doing
not scrolling through your phone and
constantly which is the thing that I do
a lot I pickup crafts and I do a fair
amount of crafts and I pick them up just
so I'm not stalling through my phone
constantly cuz I will just sit on the
sofa I'll put my laptop down and then
pick up my phone and just pick up where
I left off on Twitter so doing something
that isn't just mindless refreshing of a
page doing something playful there is a
whole book that again there's a link to
it in the side notes beside it's about
the importance of play in adult life in
work life as well as in personal life
it's a fantastic looks like 200 pages
very quick read and it talks about how
as children we learn social rules
through play and then as adults we kind
of learn we kind of stop playing so we
stop learning and sorry I'm sorry
so play is a safe way of learning about
social wars and how to navigate
situations like playing board games like
playing Monopoly which is the worst ball
game therefore what is one that we
probably most of us have played right
that thing of like when do I buy
something when do or not buy something
losing all that money all that kind of
stuff it's a safe way of navigating the
unknown and taking risks right you learn
this stuff through playing board games
and then we don't do anymore when we're
adults well some of us don't I do but
you know what I mean like we are told to
not play anymore cuz that's not an adult
thing to do and actually is really
important reconnecting with that
actually can be really fun and really
important my life has been so much
better since I all good side organizing
a month the games night in a pub because
I played one I'm talking to my friends
and I'm playing games but also I am
playing a game and it is fun and I do
not have to think about work I can swear
with the people I love the most because
they've just screwed me over in this
game in fact one of my friends also
suffers quite badly and again it is a
safe place to work for us to swear each
other and get it all out because we both
know we're both already competitive but
we both know it doesn't mean anything
it's a safest place doesn't have to be
ball games that's just what I do but
something that's fun make your life fun
because Christ you've only got one of
them I'm sorry - makes me real
existential as well so I've got into it
now I know when you do that then that
then come over here Oh max why I have a
thought about mindfulness and my formal
occasion I like mindful meditation on
the sides there are some as Dropbox link
stew some mp3s and some PDFs about
Michael meditation if you want to give
it a go but it doesn't help everyone in
fact for some people it makes them worse
like there are some conditions and some
ways that people think we're but because
my for meditation if you've not done it
you do something called a body scan and
so you think very specifically about
different parts of your body and move up
or down your body
I find it really relaxing like I can do
it and just drop off to sleep halfway
through however for some people it makes
anxiety worse it's not gonna help in a
crisis so the reason I have a bit of
beef with a microphone affectation it's
because of the way the NHS has been
cooked and all the funding has been cut
at one point people ringing one on one
in crisis and we're being told to do
mindfulness meditation it's like no I
need something a bit more intense than
that really so it's it's seen as a
band-aid quite a bit and also there are
sites coming out now that it makes some
people actively worse so try it by all
means I love it if it doesn't work for
you please drop it because it's
mindfulness isn't for you and I know a
lot of companies to do mindfulness as a
shortcut for look how great we are and I
have me through that because you can't
mindfulness is can promote and
contribute to well-being but it's not a
one-size-fits-all kind of thing and it
certainly won't fix everything so but I
love it so take from that that is my
mindfulness disclaimer so first time
that's the first time in this talk up
done that right first time an amazing so
this is really important I find this
being really important someone that I
can go actually you know what I'm not
doing great I know just go yeah all
right okay I find lying or hiding things
really hard and I do it at work because
sometimes I walk into work on a Monday
morning paper go right how was your
weekend and what they don't hear is me
to go crying mostly no one wants that
all they want you to hear is fine thanks
how with quiet how is yours that's what
people want
alright and that's fine that is a social
contract but it's nice to have someone I
can go nah been a bit rubbish I find
that really important so there is also a
link to this to a mental health supports
lock that I run I'm admin off if you
have no one that you feel you can reach
out to but you need to reach out to
someone
come join that suck we are all people
who have are familiar with mental
ill-health we will give you support
advice if you ask for it we will give
you a friendly ear
if it's easier to type them to talk cuz
trust me when I first started talking
about this stuff it was much easier to
type things out than it was to say it to
someone's face and watch their face
change you can use whatever name email
you want no one's gonna know you can be
entirely anonymous please come and join
us if you need to because I do feel this
is really important to have this kind of
support and we can offer this support
for you even if it's not like you're not
diagnosed right you're just having a
rough day that's equally important to
get that stuff out as it is to go I'm
having some troubling thoughts there are
some apps there's also a list of apps
that I've crowd-sourced that people find
helpful this kind of stuff as well
whether it be thinking about your
feelings or finding people to talk to
all that kind of stuff I've not tried
all of them but I've tried some of them
and uh yeah they're all come recommended
by other people or by me so again
doesn't help everyone take what you will
leave they're asked all that kind of
stuff so the next part of my talk is
gonna be how to be that person that it's
all reached out to you how did he'll
handle that conversation because a lot
of us want to be open to that kind of
conversation right but I think we don't
get a lot of training on how to do
things and it's quite scary for everyone
so I figure if I can give you some tips
now about how to have those
conversations how to deal with those
conversations hopefully that will be
helpful as well so we all want to be
like the puppy that doesn't know what
it's doing right we want to hell just
like puppies want to make you happy but
sometimes it's really hard because we
have no idea what we want so like I said
I've had the conversations from both
sides I have had two so last year I went
back to therapy and I what got therapy
my first bit authority through the EAP
at work and it was doing work time so I
had to say my boss look I need to go
back to therapy and he was like yeah
fine
whatever you need then I got a new job I
cook the mice later and I was like yeah
I'm in therapy I need to work from home
one day a week because I did a lot of
work on myself actually last year I
stopped talking to my family entirely
which was a massive step I'm much better
for it but it wasn't that I was a bit of
a mess at work at times because I was
dealing with an awful lot of stuff and
work was amazingly supportive but I had
to have these conversations
people had to are these conversations
with me and so these concepts like I've
really gathered for the last 12 months
of having these conversations I'm also a
mental health miss state or don't know
if people know about the mental health
first day program so some links like I'm
on the slides so the mental focus a
program is put on by mental health first
aid England where this one has gotten
into Wales and all over the world it's
in some like 20 odd countries in
nineteen different languages and it is
of course that it's a two-day course and
it gives you resources and tips on how
to help someone in crisis in the
workplace and so I wear a different
color than yard at work that signifies
that anyone can come and talk to me and
go I'm having trouble I'm having issues
will sit well listen if someone is
struggling will point them to resources
we can do with people in crisis
everything from like depression anxiety
all the way through to people having a
psychotic break
suicide self-harm like it's a really
intense two days it's amazing though I
highly recommend it if working if you
can get your work to do it do it because
it's really good which makes like means
I need a lot these conversations it's
one thing so that way so I have four
points to this part of my talk the first
race these conversations are going to be
awkward
you are never not going to be awkward in
these conversations doesn't matter what
side the table you are because the
person living trouble is having trouble
and there's not going to be having them
like my words have gone just thinking
about how these conversations that's the
point very awkward very hard to
articulate these things especially a bit
somewhat under not spoken to you about
before sometimes you're off your game
you're thinking about something else
you've got a deadline and as someone
comes up to you you're like oh god I
want to help but I wasn't expecting this
and I've got other things to do oh
Christ what am i doing that's fine as
well just commit to being awkward but
helpful and take make awkwardness part
of your plan take the awkwardness
pressure off you okay you don't have to
be perfect you just have to be helpful
take the perfect pressure off you it's
fine no one has this connotation
perfectly because the other person is
not perfect anyway is fine we are all
fine all I want you to
focus on and they start leading to my
second point is being present in the
conversation don't even think about what
I'm saying to you now don't go aha hmm
say about its conversations No think
about the person in front of you listen
to them fully and send to them because
and this is the controversial statement
you're not gonna be able to solve their
problem I know we're problem solvers
I taught us a lot to engineers their job
is solving problems this is not a
problem you're gonna be able to solve
the only person who can solve the
problem is the person having the problem
and trust me that's a hard thing for
them to swallow as well it's really hard
for me to really it was really hard when
I realized that I would have to put the
work in to stop being so anxious I
wanted someone else just to take that
away for me
what's it can happen so if someone comes
to us I'm having issues I'm really
anxious I'm really struggling with
stress don't try and solve problems at
them have you tried whatever isn't
actually helpful the analogy I have is
like if I come in with two bags is that
the two bags are pops and a pint glass
of water on the top when I say to you
can you grab that pint glass I'm
struggling would you take the point
glass or would you say have you tried
finding a table do you see what I'm
saying
I understand that people want to offer
solutions but when you say have your
tried what you're saying is oh no you
deal with that I'm not even going to
help you at all for not even a little
bit because by listening you're taking
that burden off them you're gonna have
to give it back you're gonna have to
give it back but you're gonna have to
give me the pint glass back okay you're
taking it somewhere but taking off them
just for a minute just for five minutes
can be so helpful because you're sharing
it with them and it is uncomfortable
you're gonna have to sit and listen to
some things that move you make might
make you very uncomfortable but that is
so helpful it is untrue so focus on
listening first Center it sent to the
person and they're not the scenario
essentially I will now offer you a
script the script that I use when people
come and talk to me and have these
things I'm sorry to hear that now it
sounds rubbish how can I help change the
wording to fit however you want to speak
I am a swearer
I normally say that sounds really rough
oh that sounds I'm really sorry
what can I help what needed help and
they might not know but you can listen
you can sympathize and if asked to
advice you can maybe put misses and
resources before as fast you can put
into sim to the Samaritans one one six
one two three again program something
who can offer them advice if they need
to the fourth one I'm going to talk
about someone who if it someone comes to
you when you're worried about them so
I'm going to talk a little bit about
self-harm and suicide so if you this is
gonna make them comfortable please do
leave honestly looking after yourself is
more important than listening to this
talk I promise if you're worried ask
them you're not going to make some think
about it more if they're already
thinking about it or if they're not
thinking about it you're not gonna make
them think about it I'm really worried
about you are you thinking of hurting
yourself that's all you need to say if
they say no great if they say yes right
who can I call with you to tell them
this again if all else fails the
Samaritans they are there to do this
they are given the training because you
don't have the training to deal with
this and be aware of this that you don't
have the training you don't have to take
sitting with someone who might harm
themselves if that's not what you want
to do or if you can't do it if you're
not emotionally like ready for that
because it is terrifying so point them
to the smart ins point them if all it
smells drive them Duany
it's not going to be fun but then being
alive at the end of the day is they may
be traumatized but they'll be alive okay
ask them but do not take that burden on
point them to someone trained point them
to their own support system maybe
they've got a support system already
that's why I say who can we call can we
call someone see if they've been through
it before they know there's people there
they've got support system built-in okay
not going to talk about anything hug
pack again we're all good but honestly
it's terrifying but ask it because
people go thank you for asking
no I wasn't but thank you for checking
in with me because people do it to me
people come to me and gone I'm really
worried about you no no I'm fine thank
you for asking but it's fine I'm always
grateful people checking sit you're
thinking about me and you want me to be
safe that's amazing do not be afraid so
look after yourself this is hard it's
really hard to be someone's support
system even just for an afternoon even
just for 5-10 minutes it can really
drain you out because you're providing
your your emotional support to them
which means you're directing your own
emotional support for yourself
especially if you're dealing with your
own as well yeah so set those
boundaries so I've got five minutes but
then I need to do a thing then look
after yourself go do some of the stuff
that I've talked about today go have fun
go take the day off work early do
something like that - I mean look after
yourself because that is just important
and you don't want to kill yourself
looking after other people so whether
it's on the table having that
conversation terrifying going up to your
boss your coworker your friends and
going actually I'm having a bit of a
time sorry I hope people don't mind
swearing I'm so sorry
should have asked before hunt what does
he want anyway but you know it's
terrifying to go someone and admit that
you're struggling that you're you're
feeling it I do it I still do it often
enough and I'm just about I mean just
about got to the point where it doesn't
feel like admitting that I'm weak so I'm
not weak I've got through so much stuff
with anxiety I am resilient as heck but
admitting to someone that I'm struggling
and it's because you can't cope with day
to day life
is what you're saying right and that's
it always feels a bit weird going yeah I
don't have the energy to go shower
anymore
but there's nothing physically wrong
with me is a really hard conversation to
have so what I would what I do assume
when you're not in crisis obviously if
you're in crisis please tell people
immediately as soon as possible during
the samaritans whatever but if you just
need some more accommodations at work or
whatever and if you can feel yourself
slowly starting to go what I do is I
start writing things down because again
I'm a writer I write things down what
can work do so I didn't work contact
because I've got Toby but what can work
do to make me feel better
well ideal scenario would my work life
be is it taking some time off is it
trying to work from home walking
is it time off to go to therapy maybe
it's transition out of a role maybe
you've taken a role that isn't for you
find what it is and then you can ask for
it and even if you don't ask for it in
the end
sorry even if you have a conversation
you don't ask for it having that backing
means you're like to have that
conversation and you'll find a
conversation easier I've said a lot
about even if you don't do things
because I find a lot of time I may not
do stuff but having that grounding makes
it a lot easier to do the thing even if
I don't use the stuff that I've used for
the grounding so write it down or
whatever have that conversation
I just got someone to go look I am NOT
I'm having a hard time like so I mean I
say make one manages a okay enough that
you can go can you have a word I think
I'm having a bit of a rough time X is
happening can we do Y to help because a
lot of the time from my experience if
you can tell people what you need
they'll be quite happy to give it to you
and they'll be a lot less stressed out
by it because remember when I told my
first boss last year two bosses actually
the first one last year that I was going
back to I was troubling bring that we're
in Costas immediate City talking about
one to one and I was like right they say
anything else much yeah
I'm really struggling my anxiety was
like right no powered pen at the ready
he braced himself and I went yeah so I'm
gonna get therapy through the EAP we
have an amazing appointee assistance
program at our work you get six three
possessions for free completely
anonymously amazing so I'm gonna get
therapy through the AP I'm gonna use
that to then go to into private therapy
I might need some time off work
depending one of your point Misco it was
like yeah that's fine anything else I'm
like no no I'm pretty sure I've got a
support network I'm pretty sure very
much therapy will help with that he was
like oh you've got everything down then
I'm like yeah yeah I might get to work
from home a bit more and he was like
yeah of course whatever and that was it
that was the entire conversation he was
like he was almost disappointed that he
couldn't help me more uh-huh which you
may find people go into this all
adrenalin and then you're just like oh
just need to work from home but like oh
all right
so that's why I find going preparing
those conversations is easier because it
means it does mean a little bit I'm
taking a bit of a burden of managing
their emotions a bit but that how I feel
more comfortable these conversations go
in yeah no actually I'm fine I'm just
gonna deal with this you just give me
permission and then we'll go so I'm
getting towards into my talk so I hope
you all have questions if not that's
fine we can I'm really I already think
this is my goal right Mayans actually
will never go away I won't ever not be
anxious there is never a day in my life
I'm not going to be anxious that is just
a situation that I am in and yeah that's
just my life and I have accepted that
into my life that I am always going to
be anxious that's mine maybe I'll always
be on meds I don't know um but
oh I think I just got bit overheated no
no I'm good I'm good I find herb turns
out talking about anxiety makes me back
to sometimes it's fine yes no this is
like my last night victory my side so
I'm good I'm good I'm feeling okay now
but yes so my ideal day today is that I
can listen to my anxiety when I need to
because sometimes it's helpful sometimes
being anxious about basic piece of
software that testing means that I don't
know it right off and I can do a better
job I can do more investigating
sometimes it just gets in my way so my
goal is to listen to my anxiety but
learn to ignore it what I need to
because it's always gonna be there lying
to me going that person doesn't like you
you're not that good at your job and
it's tough it's tiring some days it
feels like my entire life I have two
full-time jobs my actual job that pays
me are there managing my mental health
sometimes it feels like that and that's
okay sometimes I'll do everything right
and still be really not okay and while
it's not nice not being okay I've
learned to accept that maybe that is
okay at the end of the day and it's fine
if all you get out of this talk is
insight it what it's like for people
then I hope that's helpful
I'm really hoping you've got some tips
out there that you can take away and use
or at least use as a springboard to
think about how you think about your
mental house because so the reason is
talk
start it is because a friend of mine and
a friend of pliers Vernon Richards asked
me I know how to keep myself healthy
physically but I've no idea how to do
that mentally and I was like I know I
know how to do that
and this is where these talks come from
is because it made me realize that not
everyone is hard to do this work and not
everyone knows how to do this work and
if I can it's so much easier to do it if
you're feeling okay then when you're
feeling rubbish trust me if you're
feeling okay now and you can take this
tool let's talk it away and do build
that toolbox for yourself you'll have it
if you ever need it hopefully you'll
never need it that would be great but
life kicks you in the face and if you
have a toolbox for dealing with when
life kicks you in the face you'll be
able to handle it
a lot better and at least you'll know
vaguely what you're doing so mental
health is kind of how our Charlie people
processes is a lot of agile is you take
what works for the team and you throw
away what does it and it's not changes
you pick up somewhat new when you throw
a zip away your mental health can be
constantly evolving so fine stuff here
that works for you fine stuff here that
it finds something isn't in there that
works for you
throw away everything else if it isn't
serving you that is fine maybe nothing
in this will help you but maybe you'll
go away think of your own stuff thank
you for coming and listening to me thank
you so much so I will be around for some
the day some we're asking questions
about feelings in a room full of people
is hard so you can come find me but if
there are any questions I'm happy to
answer them there
it's like group it's so there's our
thinking in the site in the in the last
slide which looks like that there's the
link to slide sorry thank you first no
question so that bitly link will take
you to this slide deck on Google Docs
and all the speaking notes will be there
and I will tweet it in stuff but it's
called mental health support dot rocks
is the URL that will take you to sign up
for our beautiful select group yeah it's
just you're just signing yourself in
don't sign up yourself and just get a
link it's not like approved right I
think if you do have issues ping me and
I can I do an email address to it so
it's fine yeah I personally keeping a
gratitude Journal has changed my life in
a way that I wasn't thinking it would do
I picked up think you know this will be
alright but actually it's made a massive
changing how I think because at eight
o'clock every day I get another
education on my phone going alright are
you grateful for today and so I have to
sit there and go right what am i
grateful for today
what interaction big or small has added
to my day in a positive way and having
that
like having to think about that eight if
I can do anything just gives me a little
bit of a boost and I found that really
helped I didn't want to help everyone
it's such a small thing and I would not
believe it myself if I was sitting there
and I'm not done it but genuinely that I
has changed my life in a massive really
positive way so I would try the rock
also I like to go back and look and
realize that I put like it a friend like
five times in the last month
Houck and then I could go sup friend ago
you've been in my gratitude or lower too
recently thank you so much for being
there and then you made that person's
day and your increase the amount of
kindness in the world yes I first you
know just show me your touch mean
because pushing is amazing and I
appreciate that but I wanted to just
having stuff like that as well in my
life I'm just little things that just
I've got a snowball like a fake snowball
that is I used as a stress ball and I
also got it for over Christmas party
from my old work that someone gave to me
you know I can't go stressful it's nice
what some one thing I do want to say in
in this bag of delights
I've got so many people have seen on
Twitter I've got their self-care maps so
they're little things they fold out like
this
they've got some resources on the back
they've got some bits you can fill in
and if you want wanting they've not
gonna be in the mental health room as
well but feel free to take some I've
also got some other like things I just
had lying around some things to write
out some feelings again that go in the
mental health room but if you want to
come grab some now you can all printed
is stapled by my own fair hunts or
folded by my own two hands
so please feel free to come and grab
some if not like I said they'll be in
the mental-health room next door there's
200 of these so but yeah other than that
thank you so much for giving up some of
an hour of your money to come and talk
to me come find me later and can I be a
break for next dog everyone yeah