this is a talk about hacking acorn
machines or the bad old days or my
misspent youth and is all about what I
got upped a teenager so first of all
what do I mean by hacking there are two
schools of thought on whether the versus
crack no debate which I am absolutely
not going to get into it but given that
this is a security conference there will
be supplies so does anyone remember
these guys if you did not grow up in the
UK in the edges of 90s you may not have
run into these but these would be BC
micros they were in primary schools to
help the land and a lot of people cut
their teeth from them as an introduction
to computers and ACON where they come
word that competed made the BBC micro
but they were also plan is the field of
networking and they had a thing called a
kinetic Annette I am not sure if I think
given that sir this was one of their
promotional materials that they were
probably going for the Eco part the
low-cost but in my world it has always
been a cadet so I do not know what they
were playing with this from the early
80s they were playing they were
developing this in like 1980 1981 before
even the BBC micro existed you'll note
that these little schematic machines at
the bottom were not in fact BBC might
hood micros they were acorn atoms which
was the predecessor to the BBC micro so
change we're doing networking before
people knew what networking was and
because they were big in education a lot
of schools also had networks of these
machines and I got to play with them
and doing this this is how they did
networking in the 80s these are a bunch
of what are called immediate packets
which you could send from one station to
another and it would do anything and if
you look this command list you will
think this doesn't look like the command
list for any Network protocol you know
this looks more like the command list
for a debugger you shall peek and poke
pipes on a remote machine that's jsr you
see there is jump to cebu T so you can
execute arbitrary code by poking bytes
into your machine your target and
stopping it also has pathologies for
stopping the sting of stepping and so on
which I'm sure was incredibly useful
when they were developing all of this
but arguably has no place in a classroom
full of girls but it was fun they had
things they had built-in facilities that
allowed you to take remote control of
another computer hips keyboard can be
locked out and your keyboard will send
input to it and you'd get to see the
speed that it produced and the way that
they did this is they did not have the
wrong space to implement any of this on
the Machinists themselves instead they
use this remote code execution to send
over code and have it running on the
remote machine and the only way that you
were expected to keep your classroom
chaos free is by declining to host the
utilities that did this on the shared
network wowza
he pulled networks work
that the concept that you would
introduce things from outside either
I mean machines did not have disk drives
the entire point of having a network is
that you did not need a describe her
machine of death drives were expensive
so you basically had one single shared
file store and if the utilities to do
all of the fun stuff were not available
on it then you were basically out of
luck unless you were to do things like
tell your woman all to class and uh
float things from tech but this is just
a sign now I am NOT going to talk about
a kinetically the big because it is
before my time
I did get to play with it a little bit
but this is just an indication to set
the scene this is what they were doing
in ages this is what they were doing in
the 90s they had moved on from the 8-bit
machines as you may know acorn were
different the ARM architecture and this
was the risk PC introduced in 1984 which
was a 32-bit machine wearing a comm 610
which was on the we know on before and
these things to really have to fight
megabytes of RAM and a couple hundred
makes a hard disk and when I was
boarding school I returned from summer
break in 1994 defines that we had
acquired a room full of ten of them and
I thought they were better than bread be
is sliced or otherwise and I had a whole
lot of fun with them over the years and
I am going to show you so first of all
these things were networked they a cause
the original econet Oreca net was
basically a glorified serial link
they had moved on from this by then they
had seed that direction that industry
was headed and everything was now
running over boxed under 10base2
at the link layer at this flew a layer
they were still using the ethernet
vertical tunnels over UDP I believe well
certainly they did have a plumbing over
UDP they may also have Hadley tooling or
overbought Ethernet I don't know I
actually understand that layer at the
time so instead I'm going to talk about
some of the highlights such cuz the file
server so first things first this is a
quote from the level 4 file server
managers died which was the software
that's beautiful plan to provide a file
store or users well we disapp it says to
prevent unauthorized people tampering
with information stored on the file
server keep the file server stationed in
a locked room even if you run the file
server on the station without the
keyboard in mind it it's a sensible to
take this precaution to prevent anyone
attaching a keyboard or monitor and so
gaining access to files did they do this
no they did not have these had computers
as I mentioned they were all in the same
room they all had keyboards the monitors
in fact a court did not even sell
service so the file server had more
memories and all of the others it had
more discs the others all of which were
useful it all sounded larger monitor
after meals which was entirely unused
because they just sat that because if
you used it this course was a
cooperative multitasking system so if
you decided that you wanted to use the
file server for something more mild
serving would stop while you were doing
something else so the file server was
off-limits but I should mention this is
a boarding school I was at it was
possible to get in after
yes so I got to claim that the file
server and when you load up the file
server you can get to all of people's
files but you can also get to all the
people's accounts as there is an
application or manager that lets you
manage the it capsule there is what it
looks like and you will notice there
that the password is displayed as a
whole bunch of dashes I guess they
didn't like asterisks but it turns out
they were actually storing plus they
were actually not cashier passwords they
had to be plain text passwords available
and they were lying on the GUI to rip
splice the characters in the password
with dashes so approximately two minutes
with a window editor says it'll do this
snow that is all that one good and I
promptly brought a list of people's
passwords suit two minutes for the two
minutes with a window editor to get at I
decided that I wanted to be able to get
the passwords off without actually
having access to the machine because you
know people will change the passwords
and it's possible that I will not get
the machine again so that will say
facility for sharing a drive read-only
so I went back to all of the machines in
the room and got them to share their
entire hard drives over the network
including the file servers unfortunately
this manager program would not run over
the network it needed to be run on the
file server which means that if I were
to get the passwords out I would have to
crack the password I suppose I was like
this those of you who follow me on
Twitter and there are here to be a few
more of you than there were a few weeks
ago as a result of this talk which is
good because I haven't had you posted it
on too
ages except this which I posted
yesterday I don't know I had a chance to
look at but if you did then enough you
will have a head start on what I'm about
to say this is the password file font a
level 4 file server and you will see
that it has some user names that are
backwards and it has a whole bunch of
other rubbish in what do you do with
such ethic
it's turns out they are using encryption
what encryption are they using they are
using XOR with a constant bite I should
point out this was 1995 UNIX crypt have
been around for 20 years why exactly did
they do it this way I have no freaking
idea acorn was notorious for living in
their own little world not taking notice
of where the rest of the industry was
headed but is also work worth pointing
out that acorn actually sold UNIX
workstations they had themselves portage
or quickly BSD to the ARM architecture
so it is not like they didn't know how
to do this they just didn't care clearly
they didn't care about defense-in-depth
they assume that if you're learning a
file server you will keep it laptop but
I have not looked into this but I would
bet good money the passwords are
transmitted in plaintext or some equally
for real encryption over the network
so that was before FAFSA or have we got
next
this is FS lock this is what they did to
ensure that all of the client computers
remain usable and that people did not
look up I'm on this prevented people
from writing to the hard-disk
except for a single public directory
where people would store files and
promptly have them deleted by the next
person that came along it was being
mischievous so if I actually wanted to
stop things and as a 15 year old by and
large the thing that I was interested in
his playing games and not having been
deleted by the administration so I
wanted somewhere to store stuff out of
public scrutiny but I couldn't write to
the hard-disk
also if did it prevented access to the
NVRAM or CMOS ROM in a conference so you
could not recall bigger than machine in
any way which again was annoying so it
turns out that there was a utility that
will ship with RISC OS which was a block
happy that we are not doing on that
first we are doing method is first the
acorn worth had a big presence in the UK
that had ambitions of selling overseas
which meant that all user built visible
strings needed to be translatable so
they have a messages file that you could
edit that would allow the translations
elsewhere so this is a copy of FS locks
messages file and it shows the strings
at the top you can see on the path to
there is dollar dot public
hwah scoffs used dots as have separators
and dollar means route directly so this
was the top directive the hard disk and
paste some dirt on public and it looked
at this message to find out what the
translated name of public was Haley your
particular look off now I should point
out the FS what was involved and so you
couldn't just go up short but it had
four visions to make sure that you did
not copy it to RAM and run it now but
the messages file did not
so what you could do is take the
original UK messages file viv place the
string and dollar public with dollar dot
remove the public and suddenly it thinks
the entire hard drive is the drive that
you can is that directory that you can
now write so this is how you dirt that
is a very small amount of code it finds
the first of all they're copies the
messages file to run it pulls out the
location of the messages file it changes
one single byte which that number ten is
ASCII new line so it puts a new line in
place of the heat of public so you now
have the string dollar dot and it
reinitialize a--'s the messages and that
workflow thing other than the fact that
it took approximately three you look at
that because you have to copy the entire
messages mm-hmm this was on a machine
with like five megabytes typically and I
thought that was it's a little bit so I
went looking for other approaches and
the other approach a second approach I
came up with was long patch it turns out
that there is a file shipped with
discussed that fixes of all of the there
had actual math ones at this point they
weren't flash or Yvonne's
they were actual math ones and the lead
timer must ones is large so by the time
the OS ships they had found a whole
bunch of books into ROM and they needed
to fix the lobster and this is how they
did it I have no idea how it works I had
no idea that's fine
I had no documentation to speak of I
basically was figuring this out with a
disassembler a hex editor and a copy of
basic well it's not too hard to figure
out what is going on and what is going
on is this you have to three fields you
have the location you have the before
and you have after and they fight that
the location contains the contents
before and it will change it to after
using some magic mhm
I'll help me to do the messages I'll
hack with using a lot easier most bit
also I would need to do a different hack
because now I could patch the S lock
module in its entirety I could just make
it be killable because normally if you
try to kill it it refuses because that
would defeat the entire point the
business of course except the incredibly
version specific doing this way but it
turns out that there was an even simpler
way I ended up doing which is this see
what yes there were two ways to kill her
module risk loss and my module think
kernel module there was not a big
separation between kernel and user space
that there was a separation of sorts
they had an MMU but they didn't use it
much as evidenced by the fact that I
could write a simple basic program to
poke into a module
have it work without to do anything so
what we have have is that what when
you've tried to kill a module and into
that mess lock is the module that we are
trying to kill that is a flag that the
operating system sets when it calls the
finalization code of the module and if
the flag is set it is a promise by the
operating system that this is a
temporary shutdown I am going to show
you down briefly I'm going to move you
around I'm going to defragment the heap
and I'm going to set you all right back
up again this is because there heap was
terrible and they had a command called
I'm trying which allowed you to we
initialize all the modules move things
down and reclaim the memory that you are
otherwise losing to fragmentation this
turned out to be a terrible idea in fact
it was a very terrible that they later
turned it in to ignore it later versions
but the flag remains so it was possible
to be tennis to do video s ly 2 FS lock
say I'm going to shoot you down
temporarily and never actually follow
through on that so FS lock thought it
had being killed the OS thought it was
still running albeit that it had removed
all its hooks from all of the SIS calls
and things and so you ended up with a
zombie and it was very otherwise to do
anything at all with a zombie
interacting with it in any way would
almost certainly mock up the machine but
that was ok but more to the point this
was incredibly portable they would work
on any version ever and I think I had a
version that was less not and advise
that code
but this is not it but yes now I have
solved the formula I can store them at
others mutiny but I wanted more it is
what else we got
yes I had not heard of the word rootkit
at this point but that is approximately
what I ended up writing because it turns
out that people actually go looking
through directory structures especially
if they take up lots of space so what I
did was I made a way to hide things so
the OS no longer acknowledged their
existence and I have a little demo and
see - and we'll see what is going on so
I'll explain afterwards ok so you see I
have a little dirty here which is the
multiplication sign in which I store my
super secret stuff I bet well if that
I'm going to run the yup a special
kidney utility now I hope in the
directory again and it has vanished and
the here is the fun part either to open
the character map I'm ready to create a
new directory with a division symbol and
hey presto its back but this is not the
division I created a do directly with a
division symbol but that never happened
and now we've got that thing with the
multiplication symbol back so what's
happened to the division symbol and the
way this works is I wanted to do this
the source codes in the background by
the way again there is very very little
of it this hooked the operating systems
redirect the entry Cisco which is read
in Linux powers
but it turned out the list is sorted its
directory entries alphabetically so when
you called reader or its equivalent you
would get back a sorted list so if you
pick something near the end of the route
map I initially picked a ski to 5/5
which I'll check which I later changed
for reasons I will tell you shortly then
the idea is you walk through the list to
see if the thing at the end is your
special file name and if it is you
simply subtract one from the number the
availeth so that saves you actually
having to do any modification of the
directory entries themselves you can't
just change the length field which was
really nice and made the code very small
but it turned out this acorn did actual
local aware string comparison and so I
don't know if anyone knows that 255 in
Latin one is a wire with an umlaut over
it which was sorted along with the wise
and so Zed came after that so I picked
something else that was further up that
was not an alphabetical symbol that
would not be confused and I ended up
with us not ASCII Latin 1 2 - 1 5 which
is the motivation symbol first I picked
up at random turns out there were later
ones such as the division symbol nobody
ever used any of these in file names so
it was perfectly safe but it turned out
is really useful to the debugging
because if you're trying to debug
something like this when it's working
you can't actually see the thing so that
made life easier to debug
so I now had a way of storing small of
my stuff album of scrutiny and this was
one on boot-up but I wanted more so I do
not suddenly have code for this still
but I was able to I have basically zero
documentation on any of this but I was I
had a list of API calls for a canet and
after much experimentation I figured out
a way to send a point just one bite but
that was all you needed and I ended up
implementing what was approximately a
the mote shop so you could have a test
window open on a remote machine that
would not appear in the process lift and
you could send right to his and get
rights back from it and the latency was
terrible it was about a new milliseconds
especially if you had lots of output
command this did not have any kind tcp
was just a glimmer in people's eye at
this point so if the network was
congested if there was packet we are
doing if packets were lost then your
session would behave strangely but that
was all okay
and I was basically able to run commands
on a machine room which was all well and
good because by enlarge I is not trying
to be malicious until other people got
hold of the program that lets human
commands on other people's machines and
by far the most popular thing that
people found it amusing to do to other
people's machines was to remotely reboot
them
which was
single command basic it was cysts who
thinks a and there were people who did
not know any basic other than that one
command for this precise reason and
someone I think it may have been my
friend K I do not know I don't think it
was me
ended up distributing a version of this
that looked as though it was sending
commands to a remote machine but in fact
executed the commands on your local
machine which put out to that so yeah
what else we got that is what life was
like it was very different for my
security perspective it was clear the
acorns priorities were making work and
make it robust and make it user friendly
and maybe possibly make it secure as
very much an afterthought and I would
like to offer a lifetime supply of
aspirin for all of the headaches that I
caused the administrator of the computer
who is dr. who attack and yeah how long
we got okay okay I'm gonna call it that
does anyone have anything to ask if this
was about 95 96
so between 95 to 98 I had over
okay Northcote I saw this sort come to I
showed you this off a two and a half
inch hard drive to an average IDE hard
drive that I had on my own acorn machine
that I had a get sooner half inch to
three and a half inch cable that I was
able to transfer it onto an IDE machine
in about 2001 but ironically I lost that
or that data to a disk crash later but
the original drive in 1996 was still
alive and just last week I was able to
load it up and pull the entire 720
megabytes of it and that is where the
code comes the network screenshots are
all from the this software is all
available for download stuff so I was
able to set it up and in fact I have it
running on my laptop because it is very
annoying to them this guy's on a laptop
because it needs all the function keys
and all of the math boxes so this hidden
video for example is something that I
created on this machine a couple of days
ago does that answer your question
[Music]
anywhere else
this rule over 500 yes and I was saying
before is have got to meet two minutes
with a window Maya to reveal the
passwords it was approximately half an
hour where the hex editor to decode the
password format telling the admin his
password with Judith priceless turns out
it was his wife's name I did not know
that could save me a bunch of time
lesson here don't have don't use your
nearest interests names as passwords
[Music]
there else