yeah hello thank you all for coming and
hope you're having a good besides of
these 20 90 and you're on the right
place next slide okay so who are we
and I'm sleep their best seven
independent scary consoling bit obsessed
with critical security controls
networking in monitoring and the
co-founder of DC one five one
I'm Matt Hall at this month with I'm a
consultant of clarinet I have about 18
or so years experience in the
cybersecurity vision spirit world and
professionally and due to that amount of
time I'm a bit of a cynic but at the
same time bit and it's a lot to missed
and so I'm also the co-founder DeSimone
1 DC one flag one and its social
government is Def Con group its
Alice one and not the contrary 3 yeah we
get stick for that but it's a regular
meeting of hackers majors breakers both
and blue team red team
and when we first spoke about doing it
and I said I was bit by side the carry
look is why people get up another chap
but everyone's welcome is every second
Wednesday of the month currently at the
Cross Keys pub which is where the
prescience was last night and format
anything girls mostly the moment it is
sort of talks and we'd like to get some
more workshops in this year 30 to 45
minutes or when it drugs on the right to
hours if you want to get in contact with
his followers on Twitter it is a message
if you're wanting to talk or a workshop
a little bit see it okay so in this talk
and introduce
that's a concept in the idea of wall
gaming and specifically been explore the
use of wall gaming as a means of fly
simulate and incident response and
high-level will explain what aids why
you should be doing it after planet and
basically outside deliver the plane and
the toughts structured of the very
logically now and final edits in the pub
in Bodega and it should make for a
relatively useful surprise so we're
going to measure slides available top
notes the things being filmed as well
I'm reachable so any questions I would
might help of anything please get in
touch and cool concept
what is it ball game yeah so yeah so
what would what would mean by wargaming
so there's the mandatory sort of wiki
exception there and for the purposes of
this talk this introductory top to the
concept in the use of it around spy and
I are and it's essentially a training
exercise that's high definition for this
just talk and basically that's you test
stuff people against you know a
realistic scenario and give you some
idea of how well you fare and now the
concept of wargaming isn't new if you've
ever worked in the military and they
were live rubber bullet simulated
exercises video tabletops as well if
you're old enough pyramid the warning to
film the mutton Broderick the war
operations Punk response computer and
wasn't too far from the truth of its
time various intelligence organizations
as well the big learnings of cyber ball
games quite some time
well this talk is really from both our
experiences and there seems to be
relatively little or few private
organizations to run a ball game let
alone have a comprehensive incident
response plan they have any at all so
today we're talking about these supposed
immature organizations yes I guess the
reason I really like
I want to talk about is you know it's an
incredibly powerful tool for a whole
bunch of reasons and I guess the thing
we want to get across is one of those
one of the bigger reasons is the
accessibility you know you can basically
play is probably one of those greatest
strengths you don't need a lot to do
this there's no like super comp sis for
while gaming like whatever like you know
you put in a bit a bit of planning this
out of the nod to do it you can make
this thing happen it's extremely useful
in the real world you know I think we're
all hopefully all I'm sure that all are
coming to terms with the fact that in
quite security-wise and can't stop
must've happening
cat builds walls high enough or thick
enough to start stuff the bad stuff from
happening
and yes quick show of hands who has done
any sort of incident on scenario testing
the pot one two three four five six
eight nine
[Music]
you've done it organizing one part sits
and as our participant that'll be dealer
three discussing that stats Linden
so I want to talk about why you should
login why should you care why you're
here why should we go really I'm a pen
tester at the moment I have been for
several years I previously done odd it
give us a I service in that in one I
built defensive systems ids/ips
firewalls so I've gone all the way from
blue teaming in auditing - technically
rocking up brick in a network right near
port which wash rinse repeat and you
know not all real-world threats can be
covered it depends s they're very useful
so this is about helping your company of
your customer become mob
against the tongue it applies to both
red jeans blue teams are meeting
students looking into their careers I'm
scary because your next job may depend
on it
ever saw the internal fight and battle
if if you have a Cecil and you're
choosing new Cecil which type of Cecil
wouldn't choose would you choose the
person that never experienced a sound
breach or one who had and you know was a
disease Laurel when it happened
Sagittarians gain ability we'll see you
later
so why should you care and credits here
to solve you from his twenty seventeen
hours a pumpkin stop but this slide it's
out completely and what it is is I've
been around since the early eighties out
born in 1918 so I go into computing in
the early nineties were in terms of
hacking scene in the mid mountains so
we've seen lots of rise of computers and
solutions we announced the security that
keep adding to each other from one year
to the next
veera the top is actually us joins the
NIST cybersecurity framework which is
initiative response standard suppose
originally created for SCADA networks
and us and thinking the 2017 was
accessible to every organization ble
but yet in the 90s it wasn't really home
ec markets fierce sort of group and at
that time most small businesses with
slope and paper and a few staff to
digitize and internet politicians around
slow and if you thought walked into a PC
world in the 90s or a membrane you have
shelf upon shelf of Windows NT by
or 3.1 still on right at the end you
have a football of Av products with a
Fiat something I'm not not plugging the
company but it's maybe some personal
file and software that's all tall people
got scared as a pellet bit goodbye cars
would go on three years the end point
defense stuff with air be moved into la
detective monitoring systems IDs
security is an event monitoring you'll
start building socks where we have now
and we are in that Europe of the soup
bridge and in the security solution were
looking at endpoint detection response
Irish access management we've got debit
dedicated side the business units within
organizations now I'm season it with
c-level roles and that's pretty much the
advanced persistent threat die and it's
kind of scary really high this is I've
been working in industry for a while
just the amount of Beach is now telling
us about all of our technological
solutions aren't solving the problem
probably got this wrong so recently
Singh one five one near you
Weaver stood our friend in the back son
of son zoo on Twitter and his talk
lessons from the region in which Nick
asked this question which stop with me
if we're all so smart which we are and
we all web so hard which we do why is
everything so awful getting worse so in
the last few years we've seen hand emic
propulsion
tax and hey wash turns around the world
the fall sort of sentences on the
right-hand side there the four major
cyber threats that the NCSE put together
in their twenty
it 18 signed a report and we have we've
seen live features involving attackers
who assisted upon a targets network the
years to come area or several months
Equifax and yeah but who can find
Equifax quickly where is it
yep you got it yeah now look that last
year cut slide was small to different so
it should be fairly obvious people now
that we are in the agency the breach
so we're talking here about testing
without pens and how to successfully
wargame an organization to help prepare
them for the coming age of resilience
and recovery this is the map of the
World Economic Forum's Global Risk
landscape for 2018 the risks we have
sieve breaches show what will be living
in right now we've got cyber attacks up
in the top right hand corner in the same
region in terms of impact level and
likelihood of natural disasters and
climate change
see ya so well what also right like the
tax not working the addition of
different Assyrian bridge we're all good
no one's I share in that kind of bit
pretty clear that those a thing isn't it
way to sell and the idea of wargaming
because we can't rely on that assume
breach message to be all yeah and agreed
with yeah you know you will for any
organization that probably invested
millions they like cyber stealth and
telling them that it was always designed
problems not known but I would say well
cliche time
take them whoever they are on the
journey but destination really is we
want to get them thinking about breaches
like the up to the breach the response
of breach to breach start to Brett down
the hole like I've got a perimeter I'm
okay man tower they need to get them to
think about how they're going to respond
and what they'll need to respond to
investment and bootstrap up once or yeah
the Jerry thing it's one of the
consequences are not doing texting not
doing incident madness testing that can
help us sell it but you know life's bit
complicated down as you know if any of
you turns away you find do this at work
with a client whatever there are
consequences are actually doing this are
tensions test in and so we're gonna call
those out so you don't trip yourself up
business keywords alright so this is how
we sell it this is how you sell it as a
people process the technology leadership
for people to first thing me to really
exercise we initiate want to get them
doing the critical thinking exercising
decision making in those less than
optimal bare you conditions know when
things go sideways and you get a call at
five o'clock on the morning you're on
your leisure things to be able to make
quick decisions the right decisions the
best decisions we've little without
perfect information as quickly as
possible
you want to get them working together to
make decisions the comp can you know you
your organization's probably up got one
king or queen our Emperor the top that's
you know but the general you know tied
everyone to new and is entail power
dynamics all economists often might not
have that authority and the abstract
enough like the whole we need to
exercise our leaders and being able to
make decisions about that's information
because a lot of the cyber stuff for the
let's in technology I think there's this
assumption that these challenging that
like you can send you know push back on
the tacky
getting back in server room and getting
to come back with the perfect
information so you can make the right
call
it's balance like we don't know what's
going on most of the time we
the information we've got there's no
single source of information that you
can pull on to get absolute clarity when
everything goes sideways everything hits
the wall like Mindy even though at
leadership wise if you know who needs to
be involved like you know it's not just
your managers you know you've got
general counsel detection offices you
know the leadership in your organization
is probably bigger than I've seen where
the management need staff skin all the
time have you got the right people in
the room can identify the right people
can you identify that's the wrong people
can you can you easily put together that
short list of people that usually about
representation across the business
across technology across products
however your organization's structured
you need to break it down and can you
identify all the relevant skills and
knowledge like I mean I'm large
international organization but they have
a challenge of come at it if I haven't
got the right people who can speak all
the languages in the room that's what
might apply to you supplies MSSP suck
that software vendor that might be
involved retail at the cloud whatever
yeah I mean process stuff right so
people leadership and everybody know
what they should be doing like you know
chances are your organisation might have
some just a plan for Incident Response
you know I like on the shelf some works
that have been touched and probably got
some archaic Tom's plan in there you
know I've send fax to whoever what nurse
that's you know pass the time in and
that everything looks simple when
objects of the testing might be do you
know if we've got that stuff and where
it is enough to get to it do we have the
right do we know what the processes are
to get the right people in the room or
please speak with those critical
supplies and third parties directly or
do they have that secret list of people
that the law inspector got process to
the interpol to keep people in the room
bad stuff can happen anytime like if you
things go sideways on Christmas Eve like
how are you getting overtime so I was
like how'd you get this far exercise I
guess control then people's arms get to
keep them in that room
do you have processes for capturing
evidence and document in what you do in
like you know some of this stuff you
might rely on it immediately it's all
going to be useful in the long term but
yeah is it rules you have to follow up
and shopping at regulators or anyone who
external scrutiny might have a very
strong opinion on how you should
document stuff as you deal with a
problem and technology wise do you have
the basics a hard but the analysis yeah
firewalling locks whatever are you
logging everything to work with can you
answer the NCATS incident questions you
don't want to you know just sure about
yesterday's like who doesn't test they
open up let's hear that right so they
don't come across time in certain
questions then two three okay so that's
a cyber police where you care sure they
haven't bet with is subscribed and they
put together back to logging and
monitoring like basically if you just
like landed from another planet and you
have to describe love your mother into
something why they should do it they
have a nice two-page article the details
all up and right at the bottom is a
super useful table of these are the
questions you need to be able to answer
than things go sideways will expect it
if we get called in I think there's a
fairly natural expectation that someone
like the ICO would expect to be able to
answer those questions if they've got
involved I can use you know where the
vendor what and seriously recommend
checking out gives me all the bad news
man right horrible fact of life is toxin
are all super positive very and for some
people everything boils down to money
and all security stuff whatever your
sort of view of the industry is probably
for the organisation you work for unless
you're a vendor there see also carry
stuff as an overhead right where a cost
we add complexity to the business and
that probably been asked and ever worked
blue team if you ever worked like car
InfoSec
you've probably have to play the
justification game you know I can eat
five analysts because I've got shift to
them
you can have three what does that mean
like will not do Wednesdays and Sundays
and put that into the bad guys well as
those days and so horrible change the
same sort of logic around London attack
money I get supplied to people and girls
they always need justified justification
to people in a jury at Boltzmann and one
of the extra value adds a ball game and
is generating you know the context of a
very real-world problem the value of
those people and those roles and
sometimes versus the technology is that
they've already had in place for
demonstrating alignment internally there
we've got C sores now that's a thing
some of them a seat at the big table
with the rest of the sea levels exist so
wargaming can arm those Caesars with
quite a tangible example what state is
and how it can respond to this to they
can you see results from the exercise to
support their basically investing in
technology or people although it can
demonstrate the maturity of the
organization to external parties ensure
effective was positively affected Rand
internally if you can somehow
demonstrate that online draws attention
to the competence of the leadership team
on the flip side there are some
potential negatives and it's not
pleasant when an incident happens head
Steve start to roll and usually to see
so hence the question about what do you
want to see said who has experience
speech I'll not and yeah how did the
first show hands and he went to break
first rage he would hire a receipt so he
was in roles he saw in a major breach
right and everyone else just know we're
not hiring but listen he
of a solver bridge okay well yeah so
this is us goes here gets shifted in
with someone else who's green stop start
to worry the news respect to the
business the Luke respect the management
and they walk out to and on the public
Internet history does tell us that if
you have a breach and it gets out into
the news people will talk more about how
you responded to that breach rather than
the size of it a lot Dayton is involved
they don't see that chat about whether
or not they see iron or credit card data
etc unfunctional intersect Twitter you
will likely get a free pen test all the
sudden and them so another one if you
review start to war game and discovered
about really no one's got clue
what's going on
you better you've got two options now a
Dodge or buckle up the Spartans yeah you
can either went run away I'll just like
that said of it so state wants panic
right I've given him a little bit yes
zoom alien sections at the top the
really dry kind of death by PowerPoint
bits and so yeah it's a pawn in like
these items over up and up and down
essentially into two bits about the
designing the war game and then basic
way and the right peephole in together
selecting the how and the way and the
final top by execution and so planning
guest farm major building blocks which
is a gap on the Nexus of thing but you
know we need some objectives of the test
we want to do the testing we want to try
and put together and we're going to need
to select some realistic scenario of the
side of shrine draw those out thoughts
on those objectives we never break that
scenario down into chunks or what tends
to get bounded rounding I are testing
wonders in jets and you want to put
together some guiding
optional guidance around the injects to
sort of I guess
pile the wheels and keep it running
smoothly and planning like it's a very
high level question but you know what do
you want to know like why is it you're
actually testing what do you want to
verify what do you have enough
information to answer the question that
you can use testing to sort out and you
can focus on themes like can we just do
we know what we're doing I might be one
of those themes and can't be testy
specific yeah like do we have firewall
logs father
that's strange satellite office in the
Middle East if there comes up in AWS can
we work out which one of our I guess
internal customers but there probably
belongs to you know whatever it is it's
quite generic so everyone can get used
to this but you need to work out what it
is you want to test before you start and
you're gonna get the opportunity to sort
of you know Mick is perfect narrative to
focus on these things and like I guess
make the testing happen the way you want
and hopefully the the questions you have
are impossible to answer otherwise I
guess you're just going to met people
forced read and you don't normally share
the objectives we possessed in
participants like you might not even
share that the details that you're going
to do testing with them until the very
last minute and we'll put onto that
selecting scenario yeah picking a
scenario unique to every organization
but you should have to go really far for
inspiration and ask people or to keep
them in the work where can i at night
and if you focus in on some concern your
sponsors actually have you not only
probably going to get and guarantee
they're buying probably going to fight
for it more and that's passionate way is
probably going to do the business or
organization good in the grill
scheme of things news and phone app news
and media we're ten minutes chats with
us or more probably other breach right
you might have customers clients are
regulars are very specific concerns like
they might ask the party question is
someone in our industry has had
some kind of incident and it's not
public knowledge maybe think about how
you can solve those impulse filling all
out these bad things de león's which is
basically speed of crap scenario ideas
like no I'm attacking from the real from
real life super useful staff small
especially if you've not you know first
because this Newton is new to most of
you like start simple I don't go out
full Bandersnatch of the first one we
like the multiple you know you out
Netflix I don't want them to Netflix
kind of which old isn't but yeah you
know just stop something small us a very
specific question if you can't and doing
on this ripped if to start with like
getting people around the room in your
organization and not doing a day job
might be a big ask anywhere keeping them
in the room is probably not too much an
extension of that when you if you have a
scenario a posting people off the
following lines all the data center it's
probably gonna get a bit more
complicated and the objective of start
and testing should be keeping testing
you're looking for hopefully through an
improvement over time the more
complicated these things get or the
better your responsibilities respond
will be pub secure name we share some
example scenario is like Boompa Park
Tesla's value incident scenarios what
everyone to call in and very cyber are
inside appreciate I figured that derive
for the audience like if if your
principal concern just like physical
like that's totally great as well like
you know someone finds a must require
comms cabinet well I think yeah it sort
of finds one those you can plant USB
cables and it turns out to be a farm but
like bus yeah that's a good it as well
okay into injects yeah they need to be
like the major plot points and twists
and in the scenario if you have in mind
try not to give away anything if you can
you know just provide enough information
to move the story along maybe promote
some of those kind of next step
questions that you can cover off in your
guidance but and people's about five
yeah is it one day made if I like the
idea of the ones we inject by
haha but there are no extreme formation
like Tibet in principle and real with
them in a full one day scenario I'll
have to burn through about five injects
with people going on and doing stuff and
that's you know if you tell say star in
five chance and if you somehow get sign
off for like a month long thing like
writes me up and all that works
I play it out and guidance yes each
inject will have some like natural
questions which will arise yeah so you
should really P prepare for them but it
shouldn't affect the should each other -
yeah I should lead a truck yeah I should
they trap from attach them you you know
they saw it on and do they tell us
anything
if the inject isn't specific enough I
don't know it's unique to your
organization but you can confirm the
whole like no there's no actual
information like a bit impulsive
guidance can be or if you have it
it's natural follow-on questions that
you'd want to provide the answer to like
you think it was like if y'all depends
on your organisation and I are you
internal search points work if you
always get certain information with
someone who possibly know certain where
I pump up drafted like I've had draft
service desk tickets to support things
like printed out and it looks legit and
it happens we allocate to the scenario
as well and again we're do scenario is
however your organization works and yet
the guidance is quite specific to you
ultimately they'll get your testes to do
all the work and that's what yeah don't
let the guidance be that easy way out so
start a lower level then when you've got
this thing written up you should end up
with something like this obviously not
in these weird super bright colors but
index other things you share the
guidance probably keep that in your back
pocket and provide it specifically to
each question that's asked you know
objectives
you probably don't share that with
anyone over on the sponsor if they're
not involved and in
partly right at the end and his
shriveling sort of conceptual ends kind
of probably how it will work
yeah I'm storing the index kind of
relate to that this guidance to support
and but the thing I really want in to
pull out is the response like what
people do and the decisions around what
they should be doing I decide to do and
you want to tie that up to your
objectives and the timing of your
injects can be important as well we've
got a narrative bullying people are
halfway through their farm process we've
got an inject in there and just screw
everything up basically just an asshole
for there and so following to actual
planning part sponsorships sponsorship
is he finds someone within the
organization who is going to be your key
player identify the participants and you
looking to find really everyone in the
business you want IT ops devs HR PR
legal senior management team you got
overseers and check the schedule for
major conflicts yeah this monster thing
like you do license to operate like at
the end of the day this thing's
disruptive like like anything when you
take people away from their day job is
like the business of the organizations
and carry an additional cost that you
need to get this thing signed off for
guests with enough authority to so that
one way get the okay to admit to let it
happen they're also then the support to
make it happen and without it like the
things not happening like you you know I
guess there's the opportunity for the
non committed sponsor to get you to go
away and do all the planning but if you
don't let you know basically back you up
on the day where you got twice the
people's time like it's going to be you
in the road in the room when your own
with some pacer possibly not bad thing
yeah yeah the sponsor you you might be
pushing you for something if not you get
explode into like sellout benefits
break it down into these kind of like
building block components walk and walk
it through within two or three times
but yet you really even it's a bucket
and it will be the notice the low drift
yeah cuz now if this tabletop you know
it is literally supposed to happen there
also a certain piece of let's face it
comparable I may I've seen some good
wide Road just a lot of
information-sharing just willingly
colleagues who also I didn't know that
right well we didn't have a pond for
that all we have an office in that
country yeah that's that's the kind
because yeah your participants then like
you know identify who you want in the
room I guess at least to start with and
the sponsor by whoever is kind of
bucking you on this thing and probably
have some opinions on what they might
want to I guess depending on your
scenario they might want to test their
business function capability in a
certain area or the certain move it move
it and if you don't know who needs to be
in the room and the sponsor can't give
you the player stare I boom that some
Jets had one like inject battling
happened tasks one word right find out
where we get in the room like do you
know okay in the room is still obviously
is the Judah cares referees you want to
call and and probably do but this whole
thing needs like support and someone's
who really I think I had it Tracy last
night as the White team right Roger
Roger
hundreds of people involved vested
there's a dedicated team the minimum for
these kind of feedback loops a little
team and conflict so destruction up on
these things when there's an office move
on all the world's cup like something
really sensitive like you're closing a
branch again in Moscow is it's going to
just time for the whole thing and
logistics yet you know so I've grown up
stuff I felt and preach but yeah yeah
well the room they're getting a navy and
like naughty they yeah print stuff out
air box if you need it and be conscious
about how you do put in my dirt does you
feel that reprographics department
conducts send all this kind of stuff to
them in advance because right known
turned up surprise on the day is going
to have got out yeah
Peter snacks and the last thing wet on
the planning stuff is basically sending
up limitations and obviously based on
the support respond certain type of
organization you in you're probably
going to become dead and tell people
what this is like I assess whatever blah
blah blah this ribbon is their response
to might not want you to do that had a
bitten up on an engagement where you
basically said I'm free kick and invite
a lot of people and it's like boom the
dunlop it's such a peptide that and when
you do send us invitations
people are gonna complain like not
everyone's gonna be on board with this
expect it you probably already know who
those people yeah you've probably got a
good failing and the sponsor might even
have specific concerns and want to
validate that as part of what they get
out of this you know we've got a
whatever team responses in their remit
we've got a tester response they're not
happy they're kicked off but I think
it's the best use of that time you know
expect it and start to think if you can
in advance of how you handle those
people team might not be your problem I
love your fight like find out who raised
and admitted Aires try and be
sympathetic but I have to remind myself
not to fidget yeah I'll probably oil
care like like influence over
instructure and haven't worked up from
but their best if we try and get people
involved and if you can and offer them
the reality check but this is the kind
of mantra I go everywhere as big as
people than have better self thing you
know bit reality is never 10 be a good
time for this thing now should be no
different I know you're busy you're
super important without your thing this
company will just fall over but we need
you like the boss says you've got to be
in the part of expecting yeah like
seriously
Branson Esther you get wet like you just
got to be you just think up and without
you
it's our value bear that
and when it did the game asses how try
not to be like dick yeah one bill uh
yeah one nose is my new like default
response to people that complain so much
the big thing is head Korea protects
always like if you do end up with anyone
in the room that's just there because of
some JFDI oh that has come down from on
high but they're not really in the room
like they're not there I got something
fall asleep on again but they'll
probably be disruptive for probably be a
jerk for probably mess it up for
everyone else and detracts from the
whole thing they'll get in people's
where they might try and derail the
whole thing like getting out find
someone else we can still do on Friday
would pop in yeah definitely not I was
so broke up and take everyone's names
keeps enough who's that you didn't go
and explain what is going on so reminded
why today trying to get it into the
spirit of things it can be fun it's not
all doom and gloom despite my previous
slide this but do set some ground rules
not arguing in between to that and
remind them about the sponsor will have
some expectations of them of their mini
post some ground rules can help people
get into it so it's about saying the
scenario I'm keeping within keeping and
we did begin not fight in this area if
you have one ground rule as that base
like you can't write the perfect text
maybe you can which can again message me
but looking out but however you code how
much research you put into this thing
even if your based on previous incidents
you got and say on the day someone's
going to find exception of the details
well that guide to work on Wednesdays
and we've got that thing login forever
but you know just those things the
Tractatus is apply to our environment
yeah yeah don't matter if you email
volume or on site honking the client you
know like email goes down deal if if you
can get people not
in the scenario you've pretty much
cracked it even if they know that the
thing you're up against will probably
never happen
you're getting all the benefit you
testing up thinking you're testing them
so you make and you know it's you still
get the value even if they can't
immediately go we're right open nothing
ever happens they can solve views on it
so game over and you gotta formally
concluded start sundown you take and
they'll send out answers whatever and
get any feedback to be learning polls
and note down the highs and your lows
and things like that
you yes we'll probably have to write a
true apart and best in conjunction with
your sponsor observations
recommendations like review dates with
response plan for what and gaps captured
in secular and share those with the
sponsor yet don't do this thing I mean
like get around to finishing the report
six weeks later and then tell people
it's you uncovered some horror show like
you mouth coverage here we identified
some horrible desk you found some office
that you didn't know you actually how to
fight you know if you if you spot those
big things like straight up anyone
sponsor any five minutes each time boxes
well found get it into their mindset and
let them work and if you can do some
high-level presentations and sea levels
about what happened then Prospero right
little our polls in mind and so the
start is like all about how he will
stand eco nice response plan the next
scenario and then just look at the
changes start with the end see people
change on just do again let's keep doing
it assume it wasn't a complete pilot
firing like you know you've not burn
every Bridge that you can say like that
initial logic is the best time to start
gets on the ship for keeping doing this
as a thing and if the first one sucks
and you burn all your you know political
collateral probably just to go another
one so coming to the end some
conclusions about fifteen minutes
nothing brings people together our
shared experience either real will
incident all simulated one the analogy I
met for the benefits of doing the
wargaming is sort of the fire alarm
drills or it gave me a very well
aspiring with in part it's about muscle
memory and if you were downstairs and
songs over stop this moment keynote and
the concept of war game does apply there
so getting that training mind the active
thinking when you eat it with mind
- it's just intrinsic it is responding
afterwards because as well in a line
incident goes back since it was taught
you can have people you know something
post-traumatic stress for things like
this
see you want a while so I don't buy the
people about camp on your watch and you
understand that some people can't deal
with all the issues that might arise so
technology does it not even readiness
all capabilities we have in looking at
the beaches four or five decades worth
of buying another product buying another
product sitting on the network Miller
but pops doing very much nothing is no
one's looking at it and that's gone on
far too long
and we're going into the age of recovery
and resilience we've got a beautiful
into from immutable infrastructure
containerization things like that way
reducing
attackers persistence on your network
hopefully but if your data gets out you
get out of regions as breaches will
continue to happen it will totally it
would be more breaches but I doesn't
even solve that problem in my lifetime
pass pessimist it to keep their lying
cheating line it's challenging that
primitive mindset no matter how many
files been by second 2 segmented
networks
someone's in the patrol and that
firewall
some freak'll at their agency in about
hardware in plan to get us to air gap
network so we're about preaching
resilience on promoting that Redis there
is a balance of technology be brought in
foot student and said on the TVs it's
coming to the end we wondered run so far
have been quite simple for organizations
just entering into the idea with
wargaming graph is quite materia some
organizations our approach has been very
linear very train tracks is next step
and go on the train and there's a next
step so the future sort of direction
that we want to go it is the usual
friendship understand China speaking
with a class now have a good shop in one
what method of viewing it might be how
many like a red team in one room a blue
team little room red team makeup and
inject on spot and that's been fed
through the blue team rule room and we
just go back and forth about no active
testings all on the tabletop I think
that choose your own adventure style
scenario might also work well with
c-level execs if you basically give sea
level is X a financial decision to make
do you put more compact zoom technology
and put more up heads in in people
process and then sort of oh look now you
the next sector of X we might look about
that I'm not committed thank you for
listening to us and we will take any
questions on any happen right now yeah
target a beer
[Music]
like with your time I appreciate
somebody over here half an hour airway
but I don't know any question about
something it left his company would you
think this Minds work with local beach
or councils and this smallest
organization I will be doing it for debt
management agency with proximately
hundred staff which would be call center
agents I am on an intersect team of
about one it's about testing that I like
how he responds I mean there's no rules
on whether you're a five-month company
are 2010 like probably going to get the
call at some point there's foam scan a
debate structured and really involved it
can be as much as I guess realization
they pull the phone so he a say all the
girls questions over whether she began
yeah he said I think the current state
of IR and like is I guess partly to is
to believe audience related to the
current said dr bc pay like they are in
basically pay at the moment for a lot of
organizations i'm not ringbinder
on a folder there's no hasn't been
updated many years and just off pull out
and the right wonder he'd every but i
think i asking a similar stare i think
it's i ours being kind of prepared for
in this ml and will have a very rigid
plan will have a mastery incident
process like some really sexy rhetoric
around up and underneath the hood it's
just step one two three hit the coal
plant send text messages cause the
office of their cv i think that it's
this immature and maybe it's immature is
directly related so that one base
yikes even some organizations not been
places why they should be the biggest
continent upon it and it's because we
did hunt being able to show they've got
an office in Christchurch and in an
earthquake in recent history and they
lost people on facility and being able
to recover on the story they could tell
was amazing and that one organisation
backing about that can recall who busy
feeding us so like I think I are is I
was just a branch of business common
area I think you bring up or it's a
biblical blip sibling yeah I don't know
it depends on which structure this table
gets on YouTube does he question iswhat
initiate looking thanks what industry
would yeah I think the tangible things
that one of its biggest benefits is Yuki
Kendall these conclusions and
observations that you don't there's no
other lines that Bend is invisible and
you know like the whole have an office
in that country like that's there's some
truth to that
like is handed out a little bit but you
don't stressing something you get very
different result and just saw relying on
what you've been sold and you know it's
the trust but verify things nothing oh
yes yeah definitely this is like
definitely first steps it because we all
have been interested in I mean this talk
actually originated Steve's first Orkut
do you see when I'm starting up to over
27 and you know so I'm getting into it
and my level in a pen testing something
Neptune like seeing all these beaches in
Kenai Patterson's not solving the
problem I'm just going and wrecking the
net-lib so yeah I think you can make it
cut like a scenario you can make it's
complicated and is the scope of our
organization if you want to know you
want to drop a rogue instance cc7 button
yeah you know that departments VPC in ed
of us and like see if we spy when it
starts interacting we still see if they
know what to do about yeah if that works
for you like there's no rules but that's
the point you make it was like the
purple team style exercises that will do
rights not full-on like no one knows
that something going on will pop someone
on site and drop an axe as part of the
network see if the wireless IDs and it's
not watching them do what they do
respond to that so it's not this won't
blur the line into the real test
this is testing without any pens but
yeah I think it does work yes they're
very much you saw I've introduction to
the concept I think and doing some song
some coverage and some fathers Marvin
bunts tested with yeah technical
specifics and he injects don't have to
be narrative best that could be
offensive general on the wire offices
you close people you dismiss and send
and account for as casual as are
dispersed or whatever but whatever works
for you it's going to take a lot more
planning of this can be very disruptive