good morning good afternoon good evening
i'm ian table
and i have actually previously been
asked to attend root con and bring my
pdo
car in a box however you'll see further
on in this presentation
logistically that would be impossible to
bring this to
the philippines however it is my honor
in presenting to you today my talk from
an iv in a box to a car in a box
which will show you how i built my car
in the box
hopefully sometime in the future when
the world gets back to normal
i will get out to the philippines um
if not i'm sure i'll come across um jay
at some point in the future
so where should we where should we begin
who am i well you could say i'm the
ultimate car hacker
um 15 years ago now um i built this
tiger super cat which is
a lotus 7s car you get in a kit
form it's based on the running gear of a
rear wheel drive 1990 sierra
has engine out of a 2004 ford focus
has about 170 ish horsepower
and um
weighs about 700 kilos so it goes pretty
quick
and it's fun to drive not exactly the
most practical thing in the world but
ho-hum
but it is completely different to the
car i hacked um
in that it only has three ecu's
of those three ecu's i built two of them
one of them is the mega square ecu which
controls the spark and engine
um ignit in injection on the engine
and the other is a little thing you can
see in the top right hand corner
which is a arduino mega based gps
data logger which actually does have
canvas on it
to read data from the mega square ecu
um so that is completely different to
what i hacked
there's a little disclaimer on the
bottom there if you are going to hack a
vehicle
you do it at your own risk the reason i
say this
is because previously i have actually
bricked my car
um two years ago now i've got a jet i
had a jag
um i was playing around with one of my
own built
um pieces of hardware plugged it into
the obd2 port
turned the ignition on it lit up like a
christmas tree
and then come up with the error message
can't find gearbox
which is fun okay so unplug the cable
turn it off
turn it back on still can't find gearbox
okay next step let's go and get the
diagnostic tool
um diagnostic tool said yep short on bus
couldn't reset the gearbox what do i do
next
so at that point it was get the spanner
out this got the battery
disconnected battery for about 30
seconds plugged it back in
got back in the car turned it on still
can't find gearbox
yeah at that point i was bet getting
very very worried
40 grand car not fun to ring them up say
it by the way i think i've broken the
car
um so the last thing was to disconnect
the battery for about 20 minutes
left it off for 20 minutes plugged it
back in
went back to it um got in turned it on
no error messages no lights found the
gearbox
started okay at the time it was about 11
o'clock at night so i didn't actually
want to go and drive anywhere
but next morning got in it went to pull
away
drove out the driveway where i live and
it forgotten how to change gear
because the jack that i had had the um
xc gearbox
um eight speed which learns your driving
style
it took me the vehicle three and a half
weeks to learn how to change gear again
properly to my normal driving cell
stupid thing was six weeks later i did
exactly the same thing
so um if you ever come across a car
hacker that hasn't breaked a car
they've even not been trying enough or
they're lying um
so on to my car packing history
um the car in question i will tell you
about in a second
um i wrote up how i did it how i hacked
it
and then i presented about that in
2018 at dc 4420 besides london rookie
track
and defcon 26 car hacking village
after that i was invited to
bug crowds live bug bash in 2018
which is probably where i first met jay
um from root con um because he works at
bug crowd
at that event myself and another couple
of people
found a major vulnerability in one of
the vehicles got
a payout of five figures between the
three of us
um which actually funded the car in the
box
um i then went back to the
bug bash in 2019 didn't quite find as
much there
um because they ruled my normal attack
vector out of scope
because anyone can attack the canvas
defcon 27 last year i did a bug crowd
car hacking panel with cyber gibbons and
spectres
um i also presented
hacker one at auto isaac on a car
hacking
vulnerability disclosure policy panel
um and for my sins now i run the car
hacking village in the uk
um 2019 we did quite a few events
i think i did about 14 in total
including the ones shown on screen there
2020 the plan was to do a bit of a
european tour
and then cove it happens um which just
meant i've actually done
some other global conferences which i
wouldn't have probably
done if i had been in real life but
i did miss out on going to dublin
stuttgart brussels
um london liverpool and still con
are all cancelled as well thank you very
much kovid
but better to be safe than sorry um so
i have actually done this talk at
quite a few conferences before but um
yep i've also been invited to go to
many many other conferences around the
world with my car in the box
for example ossetcon in australia a
conference over in brazil
nulcon in india i was asked to go to
egypt
to take it to b-sides
over there um but logistically it is a
bit of a nightmare
so onto the car in question in
2015 many many years ago now
i bought this um brand new
citroen ds5 1955 limited edition
it had all the bells and whistles all
the toys
absolutely everything including a seven
inch
touchscreen in the center of the
dashboard which
would allow you to surf the internet
from your vehicle
if you wanted to if you tethered over
wi-fi or bluetooth to your mobile phone
why you'd want to do it i don't know
because the ui is absolutely
useless and it's really slow browser but
the option was there while doing a bit
of traveling up and down the country
i got a bit bored one day and i decided
to run nmap
against my head unit while tethered to
it from my mobile phone
and found four ports available um
23 toenet um 111
which is nfs or rpc
um three three three three and twenty
thousand
uh i've subsequently been told that
twenty thousand is
um dmp3 which is an industrial control
system
um protocol which potentially will allow
direct access to the can bus
but trying to find someone that knows
how to actually craft the mp3 packet
to see whether it has direct access to
the can bus is getting a bit difficult
but i have
got some information but i've not
actually got around to using it yet
so it had telnet open so what did i do
tell it to the head unit what up next
full access to the file system so in the
center of console
there is a usb port um you can plug into
that usb port that will allow you to
copy files off
if you wish when you do
explore the file system and copy some
files off there are some sql like
databases
that include your gps history your phone
book
and your phone history thank you very
much
personal data yep great
so um i found out this
and sort of parked it for a bit until i
decided to sell the vehicle
at the point i decided to celebrate if
it was fair game let's see what else i
can do
uh i then later found out by looking
through vxworks
command reference that you didn't
actually have to copy it to the usb port
what you could do was map a path to an
ftp server
and then copy your files one by one
from the head unit over wi-fi onto the
ftp server
wonderful great so i wrote my findings
up
sent it to peugeot citron and then we're
like well we don't get it
it's up to the user to secure their
wi-fi it's like i'm not saying the wi-fi
is
insecure i'm saying you shouldn't really
have telnet running
just like i still don't see the problem
but whatever
so pose the situation to them your
mobile phone's dead
you want to go to the cinema you want to
find out what time the things are on
so you pull your car into mcdonald's car
park
um tether onto mcdonald's car park while
you're in there
some other scrote in mcdonald's car park
and then run an map across the um
wireless lan find port 23 open if they
know what they're doing they can then
find the files copy them off
and now know where you live um you're
away from home
and i can go rob you never like that's a
bad idea
i know what we'll do the suggestion is
disable wi-fi
uh which is wonderful however the same
hack is
available over the bluetooth personal
area network stack
um the only saving grace on the actual
device is
that every time you switch the vehicle
on you have to manually go in and say
tether either over wi-fi or bluetooth it
didn't do it automatically
i'm sure there must be a way to make it
automatically but i haven't worked out
to do it yet
um i did point out to the um persian
citroen
that the french president gets driven
around in one of these vehicles
very similar and it might be a matter of
french national security and they
laughed at me
it was like yeah great wonderful okay
so i sold the car
and i thought we can still do something
with this i
will what i'll do is i'll go and buy a
hedge unit from the scrapyard
so i went on ebay found a head unit off
a ds3
um went up to the scrap yard went to
collect it
and had to pay for it and i asked could
i have the cables
at that point they went well it's going
in the ds3 you don't need the cables
it's like no it's actually going in my
kit car
couldn't explain to them i was going to
hack it but um
so they reluctantly got me the cables
that require
that were needed to connect it all
together and connected to the outside
world one of them
wasn't actually from the same vehicle
but it fits and it would work
but at that point they then said no
warranty
you can't bring it back because you're
not putting in the original car
and you'll never get it working so
challenge accepted
as you can see on the screen here you
have quite a few parts of
what would normally be either on or
under the dashboard
um to get the hedge unit working outside
of the car you can't just put 12 volts
on it anymore and
flick a switch what you need is a can
bus message to say
wake up actually you need quite a few
canvas messages to say wake up
but um so i had to then purchase
the under dash wiring loom the ignition
key
the body control module and the engine
ecu
um together because they are coded um
because i was planning potentially to
build a car in the box
in the future um those are the only bits
that actually need to be coded together
um you then need these steering column
switches
the instrument cluster some other
switches and a nice 12-volt power supply
plug it all together and you get the
head unit working
wonderful at that point i probably spent
about 500 pound
um so the challenge was
could i get the head unit working
without the rest of the
bits that are shown there so i did
uh got this got my old arduino with the
can shield out
did some sniffing did some replay
managed to find out that um
there are five messages that are
required to tell the head unit to come
on
so at that point i then got myself a
nice little case
put the head unit in the case and
then i can then take that to conferences
and show people
this is how i hack my head unit this is
how you do it
you can do it too if you really want to
and you can see if you can go any
further
you probably can't see it but on top of
the head unit here
there is the wi-fi symbol that says it
is
it contains wi-fi yes it did when i
first bought it
problem was someone had disabled it
somewhere
so it wasn't actually working so you
could only do the hack over bluetooth
hack over the bluetooth is slightly more
involved because you have to do
personality network
and it's a pain however i did find a
strange russian website that actually
tells you how to play with the sql like
files and modify the settings inside the
head unit to allow the wi-fi to work
and as you can see there um the wi-fi is
now available
as well as the bluetooth all these other
components were actually from a peugeot
not a ds3 they're made by the same
manufacturer
they are sort of the same vehicle but
not quite
the ds3 is actually based on
a peugeot 207 uh infrastructure i
believe
and not applied to eight but it's the
same head you
head unit was sold across the range in
those other vehicles as well
so after coming back from the um
bug bash with that nice share of the
five figure sum
um there i had some money spare
i was off work at the time so i decided
to build a car in a box
or a car on a bench to start with um
here is the inspiration
which is grim cyber's 3po you've
probably seen it at defcon
or on some of the videos from defcon it
is
all of the works all of the electronics
from a 2012 ford focus
however there is a cavet it doesn't
think it's a fully working car
my plan is to make it think it's a fully
working car
engine rotates the wheels rotate and all
of the dials actually will work
they do i'll come on to that so
at that point it was a case of let's get
all the other bits that make it think
it's a car
so we have on this screen here the
steering rack ecu
and steering rack um that's because it's
got electronic power steering
so it will need a canvas message to tell
it to turn the power steering on
potentially some of these vehicles would
actually do actually have
um park assist so the steering can
actually operate itself
not worked out those messages yet what i
want to do is find one with park assist
and then record what happens while it's
parking to see whether actually
i can actually get my car in the box to
do the same thing
so you've also got the throttle body the
main fuse box
which also potentially has an ecu in it
engine ecu i already had
abs ecu i had to purchase none of these
parts
extra parts act had to come from a
specific vehicle
because they're not really coded to the
vehicle
in the they won't they will still work
even though from a different vehicle
um there are some things you may have to
change in the body control module to
tell it which
version of the power steering but i
didn't have too many problems
um okay in the top right we've got the
instrument cluster and the steering
switch cluster
bottom right you've got a laptop that's
powered by steam i think
um which runs the peugeot diagnostic
software
and when i first plugged all this in
together
i think that was three and a half
thousand error messages
from missing ecu's
missing codes missing sensors and
absolutely everything
yeah it was fun um i still think i'm i
think i've still got about
50 um errors on the vehicle
but ho-hum it's never gonna go down the
road again
it's not even a vehicle it was purchased
from
parts from ebay et cetera so
um if you want to make a car
in a box you don't need the wiring
diagram
this is the warrantogram for the ecu
for my mega squirt um as you can see
it's a db37 which has 37 pins
26 in use six a ground
it's not exactly a complicated engine
because it's batch injection wasted
spark
single o2 sensor coolant sensor
um air temperature sensor fuel pump
uh crank sensor uh fuel railway etc
but it's not exactly anything um
to mickey mouse but that is nothing
compared to
if you have a look at the wiring diagram
for the persia tour eight the project
tour eight in question
is a one liter three cylinder
with sequential injection
sequential ignition dual verbal valve
timing so it's got two solenoids and two
cents
two cam sensors it's got dual o2 sensors
it's got temperature sensors got maf
sensor it's got
absolutely everything you can probably
even think about
um there are three connectors on the ecu
two fifty three-way connectors and a
32-in way connector
so there's 138 possible pins
not all of them used but it does get a
bit busy
um one of the one of the looms i
actually had to build myself
um the other two one came from the
inside of the car one came from
under the bonnet um
but you can get the connectors and
they're not cheap and you have to buy
the connector the shielding that goes on
top
the pins the correct tool to crimp the
pins
because they're a pain um but yeah
so first things first when making a car
think it's the engine's working
is you gotta make think the engine is
working so
to actually fall the engine ecu you need
crank and cam signals
um if you know anything about the
peugeot engine it
has a 60-2 sensor on the back of the
crankshaft
somewhere i think it's on the back of
the flow um
in which there's 60 holes in the
flywheel equally spaced and there are
two missing holes
so 58 holes but yeah um in a certain
space so it knows where it is in the
cycle
because it has dual variable valve
timing there is also two
cam sensors one of which
is pointing here and one of which is
pointing here
as you can see there is a profile on the
end of that cam and that cam
that are very similar but slightly out
of phase
um so what i had to do
was work out what that would look like
in a graph
and then i had to find a bit of software
that could actually simulate these
signals
um so i found a bit of software called
argustim
which you can program an arduino nano
uno or anything like that
and it will generate the signal um
d0 here is the crank sensor
d1 is the inlet sensor d2 is the exhaust
cam sensor the board in the bottom round
corner there
is the populated board i have
subsequently made
to allow you to um spoof those signals
on an ecu if you would like one
message be somehow and i will send you
them
i've got loads at the moment um
if you want to try and do that it will
work there are both surface mount
and through hole for the small trans
transistors
and resistors but there's also a massive
um
transistor in there for the other other
abs
simulator that i have built um
so that
is that um the next sensor you would
like
hello like to fall is the lambda sensor
um the lambda sensor detects how much
burnt or unburnt fuel
is in the exhaust
this vehicle has two of them what
happens is
there is a ac wave on a dc offset
that basically floats between going lean
going rich
and this 555 timer circuit on the screen
here
is the one i used and it doesn't work
and it clears the
um errors on the dashboard so the landed
sensor is not working
however there's two parts to a lambda
sensor
the other part of a lambda sensor is the
heater circuit
which would normally draw about an amp
so
what you have to do is wire up a
massive 50 ish resistor
across the heater circuit both heater
circuits and
i have done that and they're on the back
of my car in the box and every time i
have this
um do this presentation in real life i
always say oh people stay away from them
they get pretty hot and someone
at the end of the day will come over to
me and go yes they do get pretty hot
but yeah great whoops shouldn't really
be touching it
um some of the other sensors i had to
fall were the
fuel gauge that was done by using a
potentiometer
the coolant temperature sensor was also
done by using a temp
um potentiometer um
the final one of the things that was
simulated within the car in the box is
the abs and wheel speed simulator
um this was actually quite hard i tried
originally to do it
with just logic and not actually have to
have
a spinning motor but um when i probe the
signal
on my oscilloscope for the wheel speed
sensor
it's varying amplitude and varying
frequency depending on how fast this
wheels going around and it's not that
easy to
do so i cheated and i've
in the middle of this box here there is
a large motor
which is probably a bit too large but
that is attached to a shaft
on that shaft is a plastic disc around
that plastic disc is the reluctant wheel
that would normally be on your
axle on one of the four corners of your
vehicle
around that reluctor wheel um
you can see there are four sensors you
only actually need two of them
but i put i put all four in because why
not
um it gives me a bit of redundancy when
i only had two
if one of them went wrong you then have
to get the steam powered laptop out
which i didn't always take with me to
conferences
and that would mean you couldn't
actually use it
um as you can see there is another
potentiometer on here
that variable that varies the speed
off the motor by using pulse width
modulation
which then spins the product wheel
faster in front of the sensors
but then um
there is a can bus adapter on here which
then reads from the can bus
the speedo speed and then tries to match
what you want the speed to be
to what the actual speed is on the
speedo
um it's very very very very interesting
because what happens is when you have it
trying to match the speed it will go
flying past it because of inertia
and then it will realize oh no i've got
to slow down then it will go flying past
it in the other direction
and then realize it has to speed up and
then it will eventually settle down
and get vaguely near the speed you
actually want it however
it makes a very very strange winding
noise but you'll
see that in a minute with one of the
videos
um so
on to the can bus networks within the
car in the box
there are actually four can bus networks
um this is the same as if it was in pdo
the reason why it's called pdo is p for
peugeot and
d o is 208 in hex
um so your normal obd2 port is in the
bottom
left hand corner here um there is a
can bus high speed can bus that goes
from there to the body control module
the main fuse box abs esp
um ecu power steering
uh and engine ecu so that's all 500k
and um that you should be able to use
through the obd2 port the body control
module does actually work as a sort of
gateway so you've not got direct access
to those
other ecu's and because it's not sold
into the american market it doesn't
conform to any of the uds standards
so you can send the request for
uds of any variable you like and it will
completely ignore it
which is great when someone's doing
virtual hacking
and they try to do it and then don't
realize and you try and tell them
they won't work and they say go away um
there is a second can bus here in yellow
and green
that's a low speed 125k canvas that one
is for the it goes from body control
module
again gateway um to steering control ecu
and the airbag ecu i have not included
the airbag ecu
in the car in a box because i don't
really want someone playing around
and setting an airbag off in in
a conference and then having to fill a
form in
um potentially i could put the airbag
ecu in
and you could actually then play around
with that
at the end here there is an additional
obd2 port
um that is so that you can interact with
that bus
without actually having to
just makes it easier to show people
hacks and things
the third bus in blue and other blue
goes from body control module the
instrument cluster the matrix within the
instrument cluster
which is actually a completely separate
ecu that's the ones that shows
you your gps arrows and things and
speeds and things when you're using gps
um
it also goes to the ivi i have
subsequently installed
into the car in the box but not quite
got it working
a um rear parking sensor
i'm still working on that one so that's
not actually on the picture just yet
um again this second low speed bus has
an extra obd2 port at the end so you can
um interact with that bus and make it do
silly things like disco mode
and the final fourth can bus it's
actually between the ivi screen
and the ivi itself um i believe that's
for the touch screen
um why invent something different why
not just use can
not really have to play with those
messages because the cable only goes
between those two points and doesn't go
anywhere else
so i really played with that
but yes so here is my car in the box
in stay at home mode which is pretty
much how it's been
all year this year apart from some of
the online cons where i've had it
available remotely
and yes that is bigger in you on the
left
um here is my car in the box in the boot
of my girl
this is the slightly bigger rav4 that i
have the actual corner box was designed
to go
in the tail gate of my
jaguar xp that i had in that it was the
only thing that would fit in the boot
and that's about it when purchasing this
car i
actually had to actually take a tape
measure
with me just to make sure this would
actually fit in the boot without having
to have the seat down
fun yes so um next two pictures
are the abs simulator on the left and
the hedging in the box on the right
again you can see the little wi-fi logo
just here that says
it's got wi-fi at this point in time the
wi-fi wasn't actually working
but i've now subsequently got it working
um here is the car in the box itself um
most of the main controls are on the
right most of the big ecu's
on the left so you have your steering
controls your ignition
key which actually does work so you have
to crank it to get the engine ecu
to start and the simulators start
working
there is a little fuel pump
potentiometer there there's the
rear windscreen washer original plan for
that was to have a whiskey bottle
attached to it and if you could get it
to spit out whiskey on the front or the
windscreen
you got to drink what came out of it
minor problem with that alcohol cars is
frowned upon
and the other minor problem is every
time you press that button it does about
half a liter
so it would get very expensive very
quickly to actually put some decent
whisk in there
and someone will get very drunk um the
plan was
if you could get the whiskey out
without pressing the button you got to
drink it
um there's the two additional obd2 ports
on the left hand side we've got the body
control module at the bottom with lots
of cables coming out of it
um steering rack which does actually get
slightly lighter when you actually turn
the thing on
you can actually rotate it and move this
back left to right
left hand side there's the abs ecu in
the middle is the main fuse box and a
loaded cable underneath it because i
didn't want to shorten it
um this little blue box on the left is
the rg stim device
there is some switches on the top that
can actually disable the crank and cam
sensors
and don't normally use them that often
but the little dial there will actually
allow you to vary the
revs on the engine ecu above that is a
piece of trunking that has some leds in
the bottom leds show the
indication of the injectors firing the
top leds show the indication of the
coils firing for the spark plugs
at the top of that said piece of
trunking there is the variable resistor
that actually controls
the coolant temperature gauge on the
dashboard
so if you play with it it does actually
go up and down
very very slowly um top left hand corner
there is the
throttle body when you plug the thing in
it will actually work so when you push
on the accelerator the throttle body
will open
um accordingly it is drive by wire so
there are situations where if the revs
are really high and you try and floor it
it will not open the um throttle body
basically because there's no sensor
coming off the map sensor
um so that little blue box next to that
is the o2 simulator
i'm using the two five five five
circuits behind the back of the board
there
is the two heater circuits there's the
engine ecu with a couple of
um oil pressure and water temperature
sensors
you've then got the clutch and brake
switches because they are used for
the clutch which is used to disable the
cruise control and
detect gear change etc and the brake
switch is used
for the flashing brakes etc
but here you can see it's actually cable
tied down because i've put a switch in
parallel with it next to it here
there is a white better board here that
is actually yes
a cutting board with some holes drilled
in the back
and some suitably colored leds behind to
actually show
the indicators front and rear of the
vehicle
i'll show you that in a second
underneath there is some
very large resistors they are there for
the purposes of
folding the ecu in thinking
the bulbs are incandescent not leds
um because if you don't they'll flash
fast because it thinks one of the bulbs
are dead
so on to a little video
here is a little video of the
ref counter going up and down which is
the argus in being tweaked
um now
you can hear the winding of the abs
simulator motor
it's getting slightly faster it's doing
70 mile an hour but don't know where
it's doing 90 miler it's now doing 143
mile an hour
um if you've ever been a perjury toy i
don't think you'd ever get it 143 mile
an hour it would have routed itself to
bits first
but um that shows you how you can play
with the
um ecu simulators and affect what's
happening
um on to the next slide
um this here is the nano camera adapter
um
i made this in 2018 as my business card
um just to get people in
to remembering who i am really
um but it's actually a pcb that will
allow you to build a
cheap probably sub five dollar
can adapter um so you can get into some
basic car hacking
um on one side is the arduino nano um
this one here is a chinese clone the
serial electronics rubbish
so it doesn't always work but it
does enough to actually make it work
on the other side there is an mcp2515
module
um once you solder it all together
um you get yourself a little can adapter
you can then plug that into your car
and listen to what's going on the
default sketch i would suggest you
install is the one that says listen all
this basically
is a dump of what the car is producing
out with that basic sketch here is it
shown in the
arduino serial monitor
here is shown in putty
using again the serial monitor in potty
um details of github is there
there is a second slightly smaller
adapter i have made
called the tiny can adapter that is a uk
pound one pound coin um for scale
and that little adapter there uses the
new 80 tiny 1614
which is actually the chip on the left
not the chip in the middle
um with a mcp2515 module
and a sn65 hvd-230
can transceiver so it's a slightly
smaller version of the nanocan
um there are two flavors of this there
are actually three favors of this now
um this is the one that can be used for
surreptitious
funny stuff you program it with um
certain messages that if it's
a certain sequence so if it sees a
certain message it will set off a
certain sequence
um and you can play with people's cars
without them knowing
it's actually there um all a bit of fun
but you could scare someone with it
and this is the alternative version and
if you notice there's a slightly
different board
um color board in the back which is
green
not blue this one allows you to plug in
um the usb to serial adapter
which then means you can run a serial
line can
and socket can on an xbox these are
actually powered from the obd2 port as
well
um i haven't got around to putting these
on and putting the
soft software and or hardware on
github yet but it's one of the things
i've got to do
probably over the christmas break this
year i'll do it at some point
um but i have actually built another
version of the tiny can adapter which
will actually go inside the shell
of a obd2 plug um
but i've not got any pictures of that in
this presentation
so next um
here is a video of what i call disco
mode this is using the tiny can
to squirt in messages on the same bus as
the steering controller
um the steering switch controller to
make it go into disco mode um that would
actually affect both the inside and the
outside of the car
i have another nano can configured on
the other
can bus which just does disco dash
doesn't affect any of the outside of the
car but makes the dashboard light up
like a christmas tree
and have an epileptic fit so
um yeah they can be used to play so
um that's me done um i'd like to say
thanks to
the grim cyber team because they were
the inspiration and they did actually
help me quite a bit in getting some of
the
things ironed out like recommendations
for power supplies
um etc they'll name their i'm not going
to name them
the kayak village team in the us
um i'd also like to thank the root con
team for allowing me to
actually talk today i will be in
discord or
whichever platform we are using to do
questions
after this talk if you have any issue
of issues and you want to get in contact
with me my contact details are down the
bottom there
um as long as as long as you're not
asking me to help you with something
illegal i will assist
it's amazing how many people are dumb
and try to actually
get you to help them with something
dodgy um
it's not worth it but i will if anyone
gets in contact and wants a nano can pcb
just ask i will put them in a post it
will cost you the postage
i don't make any money out of it but
it's just me helping
others get into car hacking um
if you want some of the other obscure
pcbs i've had
if you see them online etc again ask
because i i've got loads i always order
um
panelized so i get too many so i will
send them out
to help others but that is me done for
today
i hope you have a great com and probably
see
you all in the future thank you
very much