thank you very much
so welcome as i said everyone today my
topic is on
motivated intruders so
started
hello everyone first of all my name's
luke but
before i get started on my topic of
motivated intruders
i just want to have a quick shout out to
the organizers
and everyone else for turning up thank
you and of course
to everyone else who has spoken before
me you have all delivered some great
talks
absolutely brilliant and i've learned so
much from those
thank you very much so as i said
today my topic is on motivated intruders
so in short why have i chosen to discuss
motivated intruders with you today it's
simply because
whether you may be aware of it or not it
is not a
traditionally hot topic er of discussion
around security
plus they are also not given the same
amount of scrutiny
examination and observation as insider
and outsider threats are and i'd also
just want to bring
some awareness to the subject matter and
see what we can do about it
going forward just some brief points
first before i get into the meat of the
topic
first off insider threats motivated
intruders and outsider threats
their motivations as they are people
traditionally speaking i mean a trojan
horse doesn't have a motivation
their motivations do intersect they are
not too dissimilar
the results of their actions are also
quite similar in the sense of they
compromise data they cause damage among
other things
they while they still have all of this
in common
they still differ in very significant
ways which i'm going to take you through
as the talk progresses
so anonymization is our first one
what is an anonymization you may ask
in short it is the process of rendering
data
into a form which does not identify
individuals
and where identification is not likely
to take
place we've also got
pseudo-normalization the first tongue
twister of the day so
please excuse me if i lose my train of
thought and get tongue-tied
pronouncing these words as we go but
back to the subject what is it
pseudo-nominization
is the processing of or personal of
personal data
in such a manner that the data can no
longer be attributed
to specific data subjects without the
use of additional information
provided of course that additional
information is kept
separately and isolated and is subject
to technical and organizational measures
to ensure that the personal data is not
attributed to an
individual or identifiable natural
person next definition we've got
and denomination these two terms
are used interchangeably so what is it
in short it is described as the process
of analyzing data or combining it with
other data
with the result that individuals become
identifiable
and that course leads us to the
definition
of a motivated intruder a motivated
intruder
in short is someone who is well
resourced
and competent and is able to employ
investigative techniques
my personal opinion on this of that
particular definition is that
well-resourced is a highly open-ended
term
to me it can just be someone with a
simple innate curiosity
and of course has access to the internet
or adverse sources of
information such as libraries etc
so as i touched upon previously about
the motivations of
these types of attackers or intruders
why the motivation
in short in the case of journalists
they're motivated to get their story
scoop of the century
or something along those lines and it is
their job to you know
bring data to the forefront
we also have of course financial
attainment
or other male efficient reasons
we've got political activism and or
hacktivism
this is usually operations against a
organization person or other entity some
grand examples include a hacker group
anonymous
as i'm sure who you're perfectly well
aware of for
hacking and denominating data even
groups
such as greenpeace do partake in such
activities
there is also curiosity what i mean by
this is
just ordinary people like you and me who
just want to see
what's going on around the neighborhood
for instance
so we look around for
crime statistics about what's going on
in our neighborhood
and the closer it is to home the more
likely we're
going to be able to demonize that
particular subject because we may know
someone family friend or anyone else who
was involved
in that particular incident there are
also personal motivations
as i've already noted trajan horses
don't have
a motivation it's always pushed by a
person
a living being behind that and personal
motivations
vary from person to person naturally
so how does this actually work
or what does denomination look like well
let me give you an example here as you
can see
we've got here a news article from
washington dc
which is accompanied by a
washington dc hospit based hospital
their hospital reports or records
as you can see in the um as you can see
in the article it's got here a 60 year
old soap lake man
crashed on his motorcycle on saturday
afternoon
and he was allocated to sacred heart
hospital now look on the left hand side
as you can see
you've got the hospital record look at
the sheer amount of data that's been
shared you've got the address
and name of the hospital the code length
of stay
the discharge date and of course you've
got his address and age
in america whether you're aware aware of
this or not
in 33 states hospitals or that
particular institution
type are obligated to share data with
governments
and other entities that is alone
is a very terrifying thought about how
easy it is
to access data because as you can see
from this example it's not just
you and your doctor it is you your
doctor
and now everyone else so that brings
me on to my next point of how
do we prevent our data from becoming so
publicly available in such a
data rich sharing society
so the first thing i want to discuss is
data anonymization techniques or masking
and its variants
data masking insured just involves
removing personal identifiers
such as names from a piece of
information to create a data set
in which no personal identifiers are
present
its variants include partial data
removal
this results in data where some personal
identifiers
such as names addresses postcodes
and so on have been removed but other
tidbits of information
such as date of birth remain
we've got data quarantining this is the
technique
of only supplying data to a recipient
who is unlikely or unable to have access
to the other pieces of data that will be
needed to facilitate re-identification
these are all relatively high risk
denomination methods let me give you an
example the electoral roll data
this of course can be used to
reintroduce names
that have been removed to the data set
fairly easily
so due to its richness it's very
easy to re-identify sub-data subjects
that now brings us to another technique
known as aggregation and its varying so
what is that data aggregation is
displayed as a total
so no data relating to or identifying
any individual is shown small numbers in
totals
are often suppressed through a process
called blurring
or by being omitted entirely
that also takes us to cell suppression
so what is cell suppression if data
from a sample survey then it may be
inappropriate to release tabular outputs
with cells which contain
small numbers of individuals let's say
below 30.
this is because the sampling error on
such cell estimates would typically be
too large to make the estimates useful
for statistical purposes
in this case of course suppression of
cells with small numbers though
for quality purposes they act in tandem
with suspicion for disclosure purposes
let's say for an example data
can be linked to wider geographical
areas where age bands could be expanded
and widened we now move on to inference
control
which is when some cell values let's say
one to five
and statistical data can present a
greater risk of re-identification
this is dependent on the circumstances
so
small numbers can either be suppressed
or
values manipulated which is often
referred to as bernardization
if a large number of cells are affected
then the level of aggregation
can be changed this also
brings us to perturbation which is
a message sorry a method of disclosure
control
for tables or counts it involves
randomly adding or subtracting
one from certain cells in the table
rounding which is a figure up and down
to disguise precise statistics
let's let me give you an example of that
round in let's say if one table has a
cell with a value of ten thousand
for all people doing some activity up to
the present date
however let's say the following month
that figure in the cell
rises to one now if an intruder compares
the tables
it would be easy to deduce a cell of one
rounding
prevents this we got
we also have now sampling
in some cases when very large numbers of
records are available
it can be adequate for statistical
purposes
to release a sample of records selected
through
some stated randomized procedure
by not releasing specific details of
this sample
data holders can minimize the risk of
re-identification
synthetic data as well mixing up which
involves mixing up the elements of the
data set
or creating new values entirely which
are based on the original data
so that all all of the overall totals
and values of the set
are preserved but do not relate to any
particular individual
we also have tabular reporting which is
just in short a means of producing
tabula or aggregated data this protects
against re-identification
now these methods in particular are
relatively low risk
because it's generally difficult to find
anything out
about a particular individual by using
aggregated data
this data does not support individual
level research
but this can be sufficient to analyze
social trends
on a regional basis we also come to
derived data items abandoned what are
these
derived data is a set of values that
reflect the character of
the source data but hide the exact
original values
this is usually done by banding which
produces
coarser grain descriptions of values
than in the source data set
an example of replacing birth dates
birth dates or years addresses by areas
of residence awards
using partial postcodes or rounded exact
figures
so they appear in a normalized form
this resulting data can be relatively
rich because it can facilitate
individual level research but it
prevents
really low level re-identification risk
now let's see some examples of these
techniques in action
an example being let's use the
university stephen research center or
usrc's
data study on individuals
who have been on special assistance
benefit with a certain body mass
index or bmi for short look at
it here you've got their names
addresses and date of birth
and how long they've been specifically
on special assistance benefit
and their body mass index of course
followed by
their research cohort reference
now let's say as an example a hospital
or another
research institution which is to do
conduct a study on people with a certain
bmi
and if they've received benefits or not
this is what the usrc will give them
if they conduct a proper deer
normalization
anonymization sorry process as you can
see
a name address date of birth are being
removed the period of assistance
benefits
has been widened the band so less than
two years greater than five years
but all the necessary data such as the
bmi
age range and research cohort numbers
still there
for the institution to do
a proper study
so that brings me on to my next point
now
enough on techniques how do different
branches of society deal with it
such as let's say the judiciary
the judiciary in short counts as
motivated intruders
predominantly journalists is their main
thing
we have court orders and judgments that
grant a nominisation
of those involved in a certain case by
invoking the contempt of court act 1981
in brief should a journalist or anyone
else choose to put
make the requested data subjects
publicly available or de-anonymize it
they will be facing at least two years
in prison accompanied by hefty funds
now how do the government deal with it
for this particular talk i've chosen to
stick to the office of national
statistics as a
as an example the ons because they are
very data rich and data data-heavy usage
part of the government as you know the
demand from users of government
departments has
necessitated data to be more vigorously
assessed
prior to disclosure
they ons themselves have of course
released guidance on the snap cell
and they refer to identifiable data as
micro data
so moving on with that the ons have two
types
of testing internal and external
let's go through their differences
internal tests are conducted by
volunteers
who are working in the department that
wishes to release the data set
they normally spend about half a day
attempting to do not de-anonymize
data subjects external testing
which is carried out by a separate
organization participants are provided
typically with a list of persons
businesses and are requested to identify
them
and on that note what what defines
the success of either test well success
of either test is measured with the
number
of correct identifications along with
associated confidence percentages which
in short
means how confident the supposed
motivated intruder
feels that they've been able to
re-identify the data subject
so moving on as you can see we've got
four steps for how the rns deal with it
they
basically tabulate the data and variable
combinations
and they look for low counts or
distinctive patterns such as where
non-zero accounts are distributed
among a certain small number of cells in
rows of columns
if there are unique or rare combinations
in the data they apply disclosure
control
to the problematic variable these can
include the removal of variables
or records recoded or record swapping
continuing on they tabulate the variable
combinations again
from the protected micro data
if there are no obvious disclosure
issues then they skip to step four
otherwise step two and
and apply more disclosure control
then they carry out intruder testing if
there are many successful claims and
steps dutiful
will need to be repeated and of course
finally
naturally the published data under the
required license and there are
a variety such as open and restricted
now this brings me to how do
corporations
and other aspects of society deal with
as you can see let's
go through some examples we've got yahoo
we've got adult friend friend disney
plus
clubhouse linkedin and of course
facebook the perhaps most famous so how
do all of these
businesses deal with motivated intruders
the short answer unfortunately is they
don't deal with it
very well take for instance the yahoo
example
yahoo had a data breach in 2013
where the data of three billion people
was compromised three million three
billion customers i don't know about you
but i've been affiliated with yahoo i've
used their services services and i
imagine everyone else has
as well and they only decided to tell us
this in 2017.
disney plus have denied it clem house
also denied it
so as you can imagine they only deny
these things though
to protect their reputation and business
because emitting weakness
in this respect that you're unable to
keep your customers data safe it's
probably not the greatest idea
but transparency is also called
it's easier said than done because
minus mass surveillance that the
government conducts on us
its citizens anonymization is
key hence why anonymizing data is so
straightforward for them but
in terms of a business like yahoo google
that is their revenue stream
data sharing is what they're built upon
so anonymizing data is not
in their best interest for the bottom
line
but that also brings me to the next
point how did how would they deal with
it well
testing for motivated intruders is
very similar to penetration testing in
certain respects
that a theoretical analysis needs to be
carried out
basically we look at what kind of data
is stored
how it is stored and assessed accessed
and how granular it is
that also then brings us to the
practical analysis test
where we use a mix of skilled and
unskilled testers in an ideal world to
conduct searches
and correlate data to re-identify it
if any of these results take more than
an hour i would probably
say and i'm sure you would all agree
with me it's not worth a
motivated intruder's time because time
with anything is the most precious
resource
so when do we use testing well
when there is empirical evidence of
whether
the data can be published or whether
further protections
is necessary it enables data users to
understand the overall sensitivity
of a database also this highlights
vulnerabilities
in data specifically variables of
concern
but an intruder target to make a
disclosure consider
removal or re-categorization
and finally this also emphasizes what
pieces of information
that might be combined with the data for
the identification
this is also known as a mosaic or jigsaw
effect
respectively of course there are also
ethical considerations
to account for when testing
some of these include
including ensuring that as far as
possible intruders will act
in a trustworthy way meaning well
they need security clearance to carry
the tests out and they can be counted on
um also ensuring that intruders are
aware that should they
release the data or use it in any shape
or form
there will be penalties involved whether
that be hefty fines lawsuits
among another platform of
punishments if that's the right word a
separation of process
between who is analyzing and validating
claims
and who is actually intruding
intruders are also told to not to search
for individuals who are known to the
checkup for example
employees they work with discussion and
consideration of the
geography so that the intruders
have limited chance of inadvertently
re-identifying data
concerning individuals who are known to
them
ensuring that the intruder is not told
also which claims they make are correct
so they do not learn
anything new about identities of
respondents
in the data so what can we do going
forward
well basically we can raise awareness
advise more businesses governments and
other branches of
society that may require a test
and implementing the motivated intruder
test of course and so a risk
assessment will promote best practice as
well
just basically creating the habit we can
also be smarter
about how we conduct data sharing and
i'm sure as is
quite common knowledge of all of the
policies of today do not quite align
with technology
technology changes faster than policy
naturally
so that also brings us to broader
questions for further discussion
such as is there a critical point where
data should be
but cannot be anonymized data breaches
such as with the cases of yahoo and
facebook
who is accountable for this and who
takes responsibility
this is why the governments and other
law
institutions struggle to
deal with data breaches because these
companies and their resources are simply
so
vast it's going to be difficult to pin
down where exactly they went wrong
as well data scraping as well
is also a perfect opportunity for
motivating intruders
and other types of attackers so what can
companies and governors do
about that also
there is on a final question in relation
to court orders etc
what do we do about data that is already
de-anonymized
and publicly available because this data
that is can already be linked
to other cases on that final note
here are my contact details my linkedin
and my discord
it's been a pleasure speaking with you
all today and i hope you have all learnt
something valuable
and new thank you for your time