okay
awesome um i'll just go over everything
that i said just in case people missed
it
and if you hear a dog howling in the
background i'm sorry that's my puppy
so um hi everyone my name's chloe and
i'm an ethical hacker i've been doing
ethical hacking for just over a year and
a half now
prior to that i didn't have any
technical experience i did a degree in
criminology so something completely
different
and i'm relatively new to the cyber
industry
i'm really excited to talk to you all
today about what it takes to be an
ethical hacker and a journey into a
technical role
and just want to say big thanks to
everyone for attending today
so giving a nod to my degree i wanted to
start things off in a very social
scientist way by looking at the
statistics about
who are the people in cyber what are the
demographics that make up our industry
in the uk specifically
and i found this to be quite tricky i
didn't
find loads of statistics out there that
looked at the demographics of the people
that make up the cyber industry in the
uk
there's quite a lot on women in stem
but not so much about breaking down
further
granular than that i did find the
decrypting diversity report
which was produced in 2020 by the ncsc
in partnership with kpmg and it's the
first report of its kind to look at
diversity within the cyber industry and
it focused on
four areas of diversity so that was
ethnicity sexual orientation
gender identity and socio-economic
background and for this talk i just
wanted to
hone in on the socio-economic background
just because i thought
um it related the best to the content
today
and this report highlighted target areas
that i believe in cyber security that we
should all be aware of
and also hopefully it should provide you
with some food for thought on what types
of people are potentially missing out on
some awesome cyber security careers
so i'm not going to go into loads of
details so if you wanted to um
go in to the report a little bit more
you can find it on the ncsc website but
the five institute the finder suggests
that those working
in um cyber security tend not to come
from
lower socioeconomic backgrounds with a
greater proportion having attended fee
paying scores within the uk so i thought
this was really interesting
especially from my own experience within
school but also um
when i became an hacker i started to
do a lot of insight events at schools
just trying to raise awareness about
what i do amongst children but
especially
amongst teachers because i found that
the children didn't know but maybe even
worse the teachers didn't know
what i did or quite about a lot of
different
um careers that exist within cyber
so i think it's really important that
teachers
children and parents recognize um
the skills that are needed in order to
enter the cyber industry
and it also gives them more
opportunities regardless of whether they
want to enter the cyber industry on
leaving university or
when they progress into their
professional careers
so i think that came up quite a lot in
my research was a cyber skills gap
within the uk so is there a cyber skills
gap
um so the decrypting diversity report
says that the uk
faces a widely documented cyber skills
gap which i think
um you might have seen quite a lot of
the because there's numerous of uh news
outlets that report about cyber skills
gap within the uk currently
and um digital resilience is becoming
increasingly central to our economic and
social future which i couldn't agree
more with
um yet this year alone
the department of digital culture media
and sport found that 653
300 uk businesses have a basic cyber
skills gap
which i thought to be quite astounding
really
so then um exploring this a bit more
further getting a bit more in depth i
found this report called disconnected
which was produced by the linen work
institute in partnership with ingenuity
and this explores the digital skills gap
so it's worth noting that this
is talking about a digital skills gap
not specifically cyber but i
think this overlaps um very much so
um and it confirms the importance of
digital skills within the uk
uh economy but also helps us to
understand those supply and demand
issues
between um the points of view of young
people
and employers so um young people are
digital
natives that have grown up surrounded by
digital technology which i couldn't
agree more with
um and the majority that's 62 are
confident that they have the basic
digital skills that employers need
however
fewer than one in five that's 18 of
young people
um are very confident that they advance
advanced digital skills that employers
need
so i thought this was really interesting
before i found
found out about ethical hacking i
definitely would have put myself in
there not having confidence with
advanced digital skills category
i didn't for example i didn't know what
coding was i didn't know how to code
that wasn't something that was taught
to me in high school and it was
something that i kind of just
picked up when i started doing ethical
hacking
um and i think it's even more important
now that kids are being
immersed more in tech and
increasingly use more and more advanced
tech day-to-day but they're not really
being taught
what's under the hood of that technology
and schools especially within the uk
not tapping into that potential early on
which brings me on to raising awareness
and harnessing potential so it would be
really great if we could
try and step out of this mentality
and i believe it starts with schooling
and parental awareness as i said before
so when i joined um ethical hacking this
is when
all of these ideas about raising
awareness and harnessing potential kind
of
um came to me um because
i'm surrounded daily by some amazing
creative minds that
want to understand the why of what
they're doing all the time and it wasn't
a way of thinking that i was privy
to when i was growing up um and that's
no one's fault um it just wasn't
encouraged within me when i was a kid
um and it wasn't something that i just
did like um
quite a lot of people who are in um
technical industries have
and um i think instead of just
encouraging the thinking about the why
within
chemistry biology and physics the
science behind what you're doing we
should start encouraging it
within tech as well and computer science
shouldn't just be an option
i think um whether that be making it
compulsory i'm not sure but
definitely um giving kids
more technical skills that are um
necessary to join the cyber industry
early on
even early as primary school so i'll
give you an example of what i'm talking
about this is a very
magnified example but illustrates my
point nevertheless so this is thomas
suarez i think i'm pronouncing his last
name correctly
but this is him giving a ted talk at 12
years of age
and um he is very into act development
so
and prior to that he was very interested
in playing games on his
ipad but he wanted to understand how
these games are working
and how he could create them himself so
he set out developing apps
um and he developed an app called
bestinjiba which is a justin bieber
whack-a-mole game in response to a lot
of the kids in his school not
particularly liking justin bieber
and he released this just before the
holidays um
and it did really really well so if you
want to check out his ted talk i would
highly recommend it's not that long as
well
and one of the key points that he
touched upon within his ted talk
was that if kids know um if kids want to
play football they go to football club i
think he
referred to it as soccer though um and
um
if um kids wanna do arts and crafts or
go to arts and crafts club and there's
um lots of different options out there
but when it came to
tech or app development that he was
talking about in his case
uh there wasn't anywhere for kids to go
to start learning these skills which
i just thought is such an easy win and
it was definitely something that i found
true in my school there wasn't anywhere
that you could go to start developing
these types of skills and it wasn't
easily accessible it was just something
that you kind of
have to research within your own time at
home
so i think we need to be more with
forward thinking
um thomas set up his own art club within
his schools and has also done a lot of
campaigns to set up various app
development clubs across
um schools and from uh where he's from
so it would be great if we could do
something similar so that brings me on
to
my journey and why do i really care
about all this stuff
so like i said i'm uh non-technical uh
well
non-tech was before um and i studied
criminology at cardiff university i've
always had a fascination with human
behavior
which carries through um to this day and
i do various bits of research into cyber
criminology criminality alongside my day
job
um but when i left university i really
didn't know what to do as much as i
enjoyed my degree
it left me feeling confused about what
the next steps were and i think quite a
lot of people feel like that when they
leave university um and because
i am didn't know what i wanted to do and
there was lots of people around me that
didn't know what they wanted to do and
they were going full force to their
careers it made me feel
quite unsuccessful um and that i was
missing
missing the boat quite a lot and um
questioned
myself and a lot of things when i left
university so i set out to research all
of the different options out there of
the type of person that i wanted to be
and i came across my employer who were
offering a ethical hacking graduate
scheme to people that had had no
technical experience now i knew stuff
about the cyber threat landscape because
of my degree
touched upon it in a couple of modules
but didn't have any of the technical
knowledge
um so i decided to go for it and after
a five-stage interview process i got the
job which was amazing
um but um those opportunities don't come
around so often
and i know that the opportunity that i
was giving it given was very
few and far between for those that have
no technical um experience
and also i think i've got
really lucky in as well in some cases
for being in the right place in the
right time they happen to be expanding
that team
in my hometown um and prior to that
i'd never heard of ethical hacking
before and so i'd wish i'd known about
it sooner so that
i could develop those skills um
and this is why i set about raising
awareness and doing what i'm doing and
giving my talk today
but it hasn't always been a completely
easy ride and
this brings me on to imposter syndrome
and confidence within my job
and um i've definitely suffered from
imposter syndrome and confidence
um when coming into the industry and
still sometimes suffer with it from
today but i've learned a lot so i wanted
to share
it with you so because i'm not your
usual techie
and because i um haven't really grown up
with a huge fascination about computers
um i kind of
struggled when it came to am i in i am
am i in the right place and am i the
right person to be doing this job
um and from talking from my colleagues
who have had similar journeys to me
that aren't directly technical i'm i
they have shared that they have had
similar experiences to me
which i thought was really
worth noting and i think
what i've come to learn is that no i'm
not your usual techie
but i bring a lot of other skills to
bear within my job
and if i'm part of diversifying the
industry
so that um it's not just people that
have been
and don't develop their technical skills
their whole life but they've gone out
and done other things outside of that
and they can bring those to the cyber
industry then so be it and um
[Music]
i i'm slowly learning that
i am very much a valued member of my
team
because of my varied skill set not just
being
um a completely technical person which
is great
so what if somebody wanted to enter
the industry particularly i'm going to
talk about ethical hacking because
obviously that is what i would do
and what should you be focusing on if
you want to upskill within this area so
what i wanted to do
is just talk about the training program
that i was on
um which i believe was around
eight months um and it covered four
modules now this learning curve was
steep
if you can imagine i had never coded
before and then i had to go on to
building enumeration scripts for linux
operating systems and doing the same in
powershell and all of this stuff so
um it was it was very steep it was
challenging rewarding um and
i'm so glad that i stuck it out and got
and got through it
so first thing networking fundamentals
then went on to web and databases
linux operating system and windows
operating systems
so networking was just getting those
basics down
understanding the osi model anyone who's
anyone that's in cyber would know what
the osi model is
but then ip protocols and all of the
different protocols and how they fit
into the osi model so that was
um the first thing that we did then
looking at network
architecture so we had a chance to build
our own
networks um and do various attacks over
the network
for example art poisoning or dhcp
starvation
that sort of stuff which was really fun
then getting a bit more granular
and um me at the time thinking oh my
goodness what is going on doing a bit of
escapee
crafting various um packets for example
we crafted some icmp
packets and then did some ping scans
over the network
and then um analyzing different
network packets using wireshark which
becomes
really handy uh later on
so that was networking very much just
just getting the basic down
um but all in that wrapper of ethical
hacking so
how can these um protocols be exploited
um they're not built with security in
mind so what can we do with them
moving on to web and databases which i
think was one of the funnest but also
one of the hardest
um so just starting off with back end
servers so
when you are doing a web application
test for example
when you see that um a site is hosted on
an apache server
understanding that how can you exploit
that nginx
and same for microsoft i is as well so
understanding those
and we had a chance to do some web
development here
so building websites very basic and
purposefully
um poorly and designed insecure websites
hosting them on our networks that we had
previously built and then attacking them
so it was all an incremental
um process where the skills were getting
building on
um more and more and more and
so yeah getting the chance to build our
own websites was awesome
and then um having a look at various
exploitation techniques and i could go
on forever when it comes to that
um and then once understanding how those
exploits work
making sure that we've got that nailed
we were then allowed to use tools we
weren't allowed to use tools unless we
knew how the exploits work
and that we knew um how the tools
themselves were working
and that was really key so um for
example sql map we needed to
prove that we could craft an sql query
um
understand the back-end database behind
it and then we'd have to
prove that we could understand how sql
map was working so that we don't just go
out on a client and start hammering
their
applications or networks the tools that
we have no idea
how they're working so that was web and
databases i'm just going to check in on
the time guys cool
we've got we're on the schedule so
moving on to linux
um just in a nutshell basically
we needed to know once we got on a linux
box how do you enumerate it
so that came down to looking at um file
ownership
file missions cron jobs um how to
um edit cron cron jobs um
and then looking at the password and
shadow files
and um password cracking and then
getting to grips with a different path
so we're cracking tools like hashcat
and then brute forcing using tools like
hydra
which were really fun um and we used
nmap before because that's kind of your
ethical hacker's bread and butter is
nmap
and we used that when we were doing
different things for for web
but really getting into nmap really and
understanding all of the
different scripts that are on there and
stuff like that um
and like i said earlier at the end we
built our own enumeration scripts that
would um
that we could run on a linux box and
pull out those different information
that we wanted
and the last module was windows the one
that i found the hardest the one i still
find hard today and
i'm still working on um is windows
so we started off um just having a
history of windows where it was where
it's become and then the major exploits
so i've got a two double blue on there
of course
um and then understanding microsoft
active directory
what fun um and um
looking at uh different group policies
and spending a whole lot of time
applying group policies to things
in active directory and then thought i
was gonna cry
that day um but we got through it and
then moving on
to powershell which oddly enough i
really enjoyed scripting in powershell
built our own enumeration scripts um in
powershell and then running them on
different
windows boxes and so that was a really
quick um race through of what
the ethical hacking training program
covered but i wanted to give you
um just that overarching um
view so that you could get what i
believe
were the um main points out of that if
you wanted to to go and start developing
those
those skills so closing up
now um the future i've talked about a
lot of things today
i've talked about um the
industry um my my journey and then
ethical hacking
um and the journey that i went on there
but i just wanted to take this chance
now
to deliver my message as clearly as i
can
so i believe the cyber industry would
benefit massively from diversifying
and in order to do this we need to raise
awareness of what we do we need to get
out there
and tell people about what we do um
and we need to do this amongst children
but also
just as important teachers and parents
there needs to be a bigger person within
schools
to inspire children to think about tech
in a way that attempts to understand the
why not just basic usage
we should be moving on from that now and
the way
um and that way we can bring more people
into the industry and tackle this
so-called cyber skills gap early on well
i'm talking primary school getting them
on raspberry pi's and that just being
a standard thing that we do in primary
schools
and then finally um it would be great to
see more businesses
employ people into technical roles from
non-technical backgrounds very much like
myself and be willing to invest in
people to develop these skills
um because i honestly don't know where i
would have been
today if i hadn't had that opportunity
to become an ethical hacker
so thank you everyone for listening and
sorry about the technical difficulties
um if anyone's got any questions that
would be great those are my social media
handles and thank you so much for
listening
thank you chloe that was fantastic um we
do have a couple questions for you
uh atomic is muted so i'll go ahead and
get started with the first one
and the first question is what should
schools do to harness
young people's potential um
so i touched upon a few but i think we
need to start off
earlier um so that's in primary school i
believe
that kids have the understanding and
they have the potential to start
learning this stuff
really early on um so
and making it fun so for example i said
about raspberry pi's
and i think that maybe even
teachers when they're in teacher
training or something like that
they need to be aware of how important
these skills are as well
so i think that's what we um should be
doing but
i think what we can do in the industry
is is get out there and tell people
about what we do
and if um you know instead of just
saying because i get it so many times i
want people like
well what do you do and i'm like well
i do this and this is really important
and um you know
tell kids about it
so mike would you like to introduce the
second question sure um
so you've gone a lot about the various
tools you know you've had to learn uh
during your eight month adventure
um i guess we can't call it that way uh
so now that you've gone through those
tools that are a bit of a ground work
uh that are a little bit more
interactive etc uh
what are the most common tools you would
use now as an ethical hacker
yeah great question um depends on the
engagement
but let's just take um web application
testing
but is very much a tool that we use all
the time
um if we're doing an inf test
is nmap so heavily rely on nmap for that
and just makes life so much easier
and yeah um red teaming things like um
nessus or cobalt strike and which are
the ones i didn't mention before so it
very much depends on the um
the engagement that you're on but i
would say burp
is the number one closely followed by
nman
awesome we might have another one
coming in clutch yeah
well you can ask it
okay so i'm just going to ask it i won't
type it out um so do you have any
advice for spying ethical hackers or
women specifically looking to get
started in technology or ethical hacking
yes um i will take this question as what
advice i would give myself
um starting out so
when i was doing the interview process i
remember being like okay
what's coding what is this all about
so start there start getting that
understanding
of um coding and getting comfortable
with that way of thinking because it's
very different
um so that's where i would start if you
haven't had exposure to that already
if you have and then start um
researching um
different types of resources that can
help you
when it comes to understanding how to
think like an ethical hacker now
i think if you're a beginner things like
hack the box might be a bit too hard but
it wouldn't
hurt just um looking at different
youtube videos of how to complete
different um exercises that are out
there there's
so many different resources that you can
that you can find
and and i wish that i had um known about
them before
um i'd applied or
if i wanted to get into it um
what else would i say oh and then just
like basic
how do you build a computer that would
really help what are ports
like that basic stuff um so yeah
awesome yes thank you so much for your
time and your talk it was fantastic
uh lots of good feedback there we'll
accept
thank you so much guys thank you again