so i would like to go ahead and welcome
our next speaker to the stage
paul coggin
from he is a cyber sme at new systems
inc
his expertise includes space systems
service provider and ics scada network
infrastructure attacks and defenses as
well as large complex network design and
implementation
paul is experienced in leading network
architecture reviews
vulnera vulnerability
and analysis and penetration testing
engagements for service provider
enterprise space systems and tactical
networks
paul is a regular instructor at
international conferences teaching
networking hacking
and forensic courses
he has a bs in math computer science ms
in systems management msn information
assurance and security and ms in
computer information systems
paul is currently pursuing his msn space
systems
in addition he holds numerous industry
network and security certifications
so please welcome paul to the stage with
pwned in space
thank you jane
it's great to be
back here in the cayman this is my
second time to visit the cayman islands
it's a it's beautiful it's one of my
favorite places to visit in the world
the island is so beautiful food the
people
the scenery as you well know the beaches
it's uh the reefs are just amazing here
being able to see all the stingrays and
starfish it's just uh it's an amazing
place you have here
so this talk we're going to talk about
space systems and cyber security
and we're not i'm going to not do a
focus on the ground system we're going
to focus on events that have actually
happened in space primarily
around cyber because there's so much in
the news these days when you have with
uh ukraine
spacex biosat there's a lot of
conversation about that in the news
and then all the satellites that are
going up in space providing
internet services from space
all the new launch capabilities i
wanted to go and put some coverage on
what
what's been happening in the past up to
this point
with uh space
and cyber but but focused on the
satellite portion of it and
and i'm going to talk about the space
station as well
but
so when we talk about space
if you come from an enterprise
background or telco service provider
background you're familiar with a
network operations center your security
operations center where you're
monitoring the health and status of your
network infrastructure maybe you have it
in the cloud where you you're collecting
all your telemetry data and you know the
health and status of the network
infrastructure your apps your servers
etc well similarly for uh
for systems that are in orbit in space
organizations similar similarly to say
nasa here in this example they have
ground stations
around the world located so that they
can can continuously monitor no matter
where the spacecraft is in orbit they
can always go in uh send commands to
pull health and status maybe send
commands to change orbit pull
information imaging from a payload
that's on a spacecraft
satellite so
that's called the ground station ground
system
for the spacecraft
now what's really interesting now is
everybody's talking about the cloud i
mean everyone is moving to the cloud
well similarly
space systems are as well
and it's called and what that's commonly
referred to in the marketing is ground
station as a service but i've read the
other day where they're talking about
space as a service as well
is a new acronym that you're going to
probably hear more about
but ground station as a service
is where instead of having these private
ground stations
similar to having you know your own
private network operations center or a
private security operations center
the all these new space 2.0 these new
space
commercial organizations that are coming
online many of them are pushing those
services to the cloud where amazon aws
google i was reading that google is
going to provide the services to spacex
for the startling satellites
and so they may eventually offer
additional commercial services but and
then microsoft azure they have their
orbit solution that they're offering
cloud-based
space services and there's a company
called kubos
they have a application that they run in
aws called major time
and uh and then there's a leaf space out
of italy and there's another one i can't
recall the name of that i've read about
recently out of portugal that is going
to offer a cloud-based service so space
is going to the cloud so it's really
interesting
what's happening there but also call out
image to you might find of interest
is that the cloud is also moving up into
orbit there's a company called leo cloud
where they're going to put cloud-based
services
in space so that they can do processing
and analysis in space before they send
data to the ground and other similar
services and
i was reading where hp has designed a
new server for space
and they have to be special servers and
computers have to be specially designed
for space because it's
there's actually weather in space
due to
the atmosphere and the sun because it's
sending all kinds of radiation and
particles
into space that can affect the computer
systems and we'll talk about that and
mess it up so those the hp server is
specially designed
to provide a server in space and then i
was reading there's another company
called aim ramos out of israel and they
provide they've designed a two terabyte
hard drive
uh storage system for space here just
recently so that's going so now we're
going to have cloud in space eventually
which is going to open up a lot of ideas
of how you do forensics incident
response things that we would do on the
ground get that that's hard enough on
the cloud on the ground but now we're
going to do it in space so it's going to
be a lot of interesting activities in
the future with cyber it's going to be
really exciting a lot of opportunities
so when we talk about orbits
spacex and uh
what uh
some of the other
companies are doing
that you read about most frequently with
the small satellites the cubesats is in
leo the low earth orbit
and and that's up to like 2 000
kilometers
that's good that's what you're
predominantly reading about uh
all the frequent launches that uh the
spacex is sending up with their rockets
most of those satellites are going up
into the leo orbit and that's where
like space station is located in leo
it's closer to the earth and it spins
roughly those satellites are rotating
around the earth about about every four
hours roughly
they're rotating spinning around the
earth but when you go to geo
that is the satellites that you're
probably familiar with when you get
cable tv services some of your voice
services
those type of services are those
satellites are pointing directly at the
same spot same region of the earth and
in italy orbits
as the earth orbits up in geo and then
you have mio and
keo the high earth orbit the medium
earth orbit but primarily what you're
reading about in the news is the low
earth orbit
and then the geo orbit
so from a threat standpoint again
everything in the news here lately if
you've been following with the
activities in
ukraine
there was the recent attack they expect
they said that the that the russians
attacked via side and took out
the user terminals for
for uh
for the viasat internet terminals like
5000 plus or 5 million
might have been the number of user
terminals and they got in through a
through the network management network
for the user terminals
and so they were able to degrade and
deny service for those end users
and they weren't able to use the
spacecraft but that happened on the user
part of the network but there's other
attacks like a deception where somebody
might be spoofing information
uh and uh say you know messing with gps
messing with timing and location where
where you uh
lose
track of where you are and say like if
you're a ship floating around you might
be getting
your information spoofed so you don't
you're not showing up where you're
supposed to be
uh and then this there could be
temporary disruptions
like lasers microwave some kind of
directed energy attack in like a
electronic warfare where it's it's
jamming the signal and the signal it
will be jammed and unusable but then it
comes back as soon as the power is
removed
and so it'll be a temporary disruption
there's been a lot a lot of talk here
lately about the asad attacks where
that's been tested where's actually a
missile shot at the at the satellite and
taking out the uh the spacecraft which
ends up causing a great deal of debris
and that just totally destroys the
spacecraft but also create adds to the
debris field
that is a lot of people scientists are
worried about that eventually could
cause what they call a kessler syndrome
that if the debris field in space keeps
developing like it is that eventually
there could be a chain reaction where a
piece of debris hits a spacecraft or
another large piece of of debris and it
just starts
a chain reaction of debris creating
crashing into debris creating
additional debris until the whole low
earth orbit is unusable and that's
called kessler syndrome
and there's because of the complete
destruction of spacecraft there's a
concern about there and plus there's
junk that's just been left up there like
rockets and satellites that have not
fallen from space yet
and then and then there's other attacks
like i think i mentioned you know lasers
and
in the microwave but primarily what
we're going to talk about with this talk
though is like i mentioned jamming
electronic warfare
the the field of electronic warfare and
cyber are converging together where
where somebody might be trying to jam
your uh
your radio frequency channel with with
high power jammers
uh
malware i've got some examples of
malware in space you might be surprised
with their
malware is in space
and the spoofing and going after the
the control system payload
because the satellite is going to have
two components typically there's going
to be the computer
portion of the satellite that controls
how the satellite is flown and the
overall health and status of that
satellite and keeping it in orbit
and then there's the payload
that is the computer system that
controls what the mission is of that
satellite you know if it's taking
imagery
if it's communications what have you
that would be in the payload
and then we're going to talk about
attacks like replay and being able to do
hijacking and eavesdropping which is uh
a lot easier than you may realize
because there's a there's a lot of
misconception that everything is
encrypted it is not all encrypted
and i will talk about some real-world
examples of that so
again what we're showing in this slide
is
when we start talking about attacks
against space systems if it's like
electronic warfare
things like that it might be easily to
recover from those attacks because the
the rf the radio frequency energy is
applied it jams the signal and when it
go in it goes away
once that signal is removed and we've
been reading a lot about it then in the
news here lately but when as you move to
the right you start getting into kinetic
attacks maybe a microwave attack
a microwave attack a high energy
directed energy microwave attack could
possibly damage permanently damage the
spacecraft or
lasers could have a really strong laser
that gets pointed to the spacecraft and
totally disable some of its capabilities
or
maybe do and do irreparable damage to it
or of course shooting a missile at it
there's like four countries right now
that have proven that they can hit a mis
hit a satellite in space india china the
u.s and russia are the four
that have actually been been able to
destroy a satellite in space so
hopefully we'll get some treaties in
place that we'll quit doing that in
adding debris to the
to the leo space
some of the threat actors
the threat actors span the gamut similar
similar to other critical infrastructure
industries whether it's you know a
foreign military
some kid sitting at home on their
parents internet connection with you
know this time and i'm
in the high iq and a lot of curiosity
all the way up to terrorist
uh there's a there's a great deal of
talk that i've been reading here
recently where russia and china are
watching and seeing what's happened you
know where they were able to affect
viasat
but then
spacex and starling stepped in
and overcame the attacks that were used
against viasat and have been able to
bring the internet back up in ukraine
that's got a lot of people's attention
that that now hey what are we going to
do
when we want to go and you know exert
influence over a battlefield that how
we're going to deal with these thousands
of satellites that elon is putting up in
space so there's that's
and that's going to get into all those
different uh different attacks like the
lasers the microwave etc but then
there's but one of the top attacks of a
concern is cyber because if they can
find a way through the supply chain if
they get into the supply center chain
you know from your chips and software
all the way
through the process that's a broad
attack surface that somebody might be
good to but
but there's also
all the way down to the in to some kid
sitting at home on internet connection
because a lot of legacy satellite
communications are unencrypted
like a like everything
here on the ground it's best practices
to use use your own encryption and
verify but uh
it's not always encrypted
and the reason being is uh
because of space weather and we'll dive
more into that so you so you can set up
you can actually go and get a
software-defined radio if you're a
hobbyist and passively look at network
traffic we'll go into some
examples of that so that space threat
actors it's a pretty broad capability
there to just passively or actively
engage now i spent many years working on
red teams doing penetration testing i
got involved penetration testing in like
99 the early 2000s i got interested in
doing attack trees as a way to
develop a strategy
for the team
and for
for reporting so i like to i like to use
a whole attack tree mind mapping to
layout strategy so a real real simple
example if you're going to go after
somebody's satellite
you know you're maybe you want to go
after the ground station look at uh you
know you want to now analyze your
threats you know what is the insiders
you know some you know what is the
likelihood of one of your
insiders your engineers i t people
janitor someone getting turned
decided to work for the bad guys
you know what what is those trust
relationships out to the internet
that's kind of like what happened with
my understanding with viasat the net the
firewall vpn had a mis-configuration so
some they were able to come in over the
internet get a whole get through the
firewall vpn
and then upload some bad code that got
distributed to all the user terminals
so going through the ground station it's
theoretical
that they could might be possible at
some point to do a satellite to
satellite in space attack that's purely
theoretical i've not been able to read
anywhere where that's actually happened
but i've i have seen where a couple
papers where people are speculating on
satellite to satellite type attacks in
the future or
someone that's more sophisticated has
more resources might be able to go and
bring up their own unauthorized ground
station but typically what you're going
to see is someone is going to try to
find a way into the existing ground
station whether it's a private ground
station or
which i think is going to make it a lot
easier somebody's cloud ground station
because you know if they put it to the
cloud most most likely they're going to
have
remote internet access into it and
that's going to open up a whole big
broader attack services as this group
would know and understand
to export that trust relationship and
gain access to the spacecraft
i found this really interesting i
started doing this research about known
spacecraft attacks but apparently
there's a it's heavily speculated that
when stuxnet
attacked the iranian
nuclear program many years ago that when
stuxlet was spreading that it actually
somehow
got got into the ground station of a
cable tv
company satellite company in india and
took out the inside 4b satellite and
what what what is stated is that the
inside 4b
system was actually using the same
siemens plc controller
for uh
for uh the solar panels to rotate and
turn the solar panels that was using the
same poc and it had the wind cc system
on the ground so it was able to
turn the satellite so that
that uh it could destroy that spacecraft
and disabled it and so they lost service
now on the encrypted satellite
communications the reason the reason
that they're it's all not encrypted
is because
there's this space weather like there's
solar storms in space the sun is
constantly spewing out
particles ions electrons protons
all this stuff that you probably just
studied in modern physics
it's shooting that out across space
and
it goes back to einstein uh equation the
equivalency square it's got enough
energy that those little tiny
particles have enough energy
to fly when it was it is headed toward
uh out into the solar system toward
earth etcetera it hits those spacecraft
that not only can it degrade
economic and cause uh it can degrade the
material properties of a spacecraft
depending on how what the materials are
used on that spacecraft but if it can
get in there it could also inject itself
into the electronics
and it can do what what they call a
a single upset event where it can make
the ones and zeroes in an electronic
board
change and flip so it might have been
should have been a one but it flips to
zero and you know in this room everybody
understand encryption you start changing
ones and zeroes and flipping things well
what have we done we broke encryption
we've killed our encrypted connection
now we've got to reset it we gotta do we
gotta reboot you don't want to have to
be rebooting your computer in space
because you know you ain't like you can
walk down the hall to the data center
and and hard boot it when they don't
boot up clean right
a little bit more complicated when it's
you know
in leo or geo
so that's the reason not everybody does
encryption now you can use encryption
and it is heavily used by some
organizations but it drives up the cost
of hardening that equipment against the
radiation the hostile space weather you
got to go and put a special shielding
around that equipment
and manufacture it so that it can
survive at space
at that level
so and there's a lot of things out in
the open source where it's talked about
its best practices it's recommended but
they don't do it specifically because of
that because they don't want to lose
that
the
people who control the satellites do not
want to lose access to their satellites
due to a loss of encryption which makes
sense so so some do it sometimes the
lesson learned out of this where we're
going with this is if you're dependent
if your business
or you know your home network is using
uh satellite internet
if it's sensitive traffic if you're
under some kind of regulatory regulation
like you know health care privacy
information financial privacy
information you're using satellite
internet i'd be making sure it's
encrypted don't don't believe the sales
guys
i'd be encrypting my own traffic
an example of uh
some real world examples of unencrypted
traffic is in this case the navy had a
satellite was using uhf and some
creative
uh radio
people down in brazil discovered it and
they used the open unencrypted
satellite
that the navy was using for their radio
communications they turned it into a cb
radio network for themselves
and by the and eventually at some point
they found 39 people across
six states in brazil that were utilizing
it apparently after they rested that
bunch
more people came online and started
using it because everybody knew about it
and it was real easy to hack because it
was out there open you know if you
didn't want people to use it should had
it encrypted
now here's an example for malware with
this again showing that despite what all
the you know your isp might be telling
you that it's encrypted here's a real
world example where
it's not encrypted
some of it may be but not all of it in
this case
we have a piece of malware where you
know the malware's got its uh command
control got that two-way handshake of
signaling
between the uh the bot that's been
infected and the command control server
well these guys are pretty smart this is
a sophisticated attack i wish i was
smart enough to think about this
to come up with this idea
they would they would
the bot operators had their command
control server
they would go put their server out on
somewhat some satellite internet network
and just uh steal somebody's ip space
put it out there on somebody's ip space
just out there and squat out there
in like southern europe north africa
region middle east they would put that
put their server out there using
whatever arbitrary ip addresses that the
satellite internet company was using
and it would just wait
for uh they bought
whoever got infected to phone home and
then whenever they got a signal
that from a uh from somebody's computer
that had been infected it would get
sprayed down broadcast from the
satellite to everyone in that region of
the world and then the
the c2 server the malware server would
would send a connection back to that
infected user over a wire line so it was
an async communication so
you've got you know you're out there
trying to do threat hunting you're out
there trying to monitor and catch the
bad guys you're only going to see one
wave signal one signal is going to go
over a wire line and one signal is going
to go over the they coming in over the
satellite really really hard to detect
so
and that would not work if they were
using encryption
so it just that's a good example of
proving it ain't it's not all encrypted
and if it ain't encrypted
and you're using satellite internet
you know
better be using some encryption or
somebody's gonna be sitting out there
and looking at it i can tell you
it's a it's a lot easier there's a
there's a couple papers out on black hat
as well and on that on slideshare where
it broke down many years ago a gentleman
first published it i forget his name and
then it was published again a couple
years ago by another gentleman from they
graduated oxford university recently i
forget their names they published
there's a lot of information out there
about how to use salt like software fire
radio
really really cost effectively
as a hobbyist
bring up a capability to
to monitor
passively just passively just sit there
and listen like wire sharp
on a you know set up there on your
switch
uh sit there and passively monitor the
satellite traffic it's floating around
in space so you need to make sure your
stuff is encrypted because i've got a
project where
we're throwing something up like that
and just seeing what's out there and
what's all the noise
and it's really it's really amazing to
see
here's another example
during the iraq war there was insurgents
they were able to intercept
communications and decode satellite
communications they were unencrypted
and i mentioned earlier about that this
is this is something i believe is going
to be that we'll read about in the
future i haven't there's nothing out
there to say it's happened yet it's
purely theoretical but i'm thinking that
eventually we're going to be reading
about a
satellite to satellite attack in space
it's probably going to be it's going to
be easier to do with rf with the radio
frequency because that's more broader in
nature the signaling
but more and more
which is a good thing more and more the
communications are going to move to
optical where it's where they're using
free space optics where the lasers are
going to you're going to point lasers in
space at the spacecraft spacecraft the
spacecraft so it's going to be inner
side it's going to be optical and then
the spacecraft to the ground will be
optical and that's going to be a huge
improvement for security when it goes
optical because you won't be able to jam
it like as he's messed with it like you
can with a radio frequency because it's
a laser
it's a braiding so free space optics is
going to make it really really hard but
i'm just interested to see
if if that ever gets reported is
actually occurring
here's a
a real world example of a satellite this
this rosat satellite
was created to look into deep space
it was you know the scientists were
trying to go and study deep space see
what's going on out in out in the solar
system
and someone was able to find a way into
a ground system
and get from that ground system that
they they exploited trust relationships
and found their way into
were able to get go from the ground
system up to that satellite and turn
that satellite
toward the sun
and
damage the satellite's capability which
this kind of talk always drives me crazy
because it's like scada
industrial control systems scada you
know ot
why is this stuff
accessible from the internet to begin
with i mean who designs this stuff i
mean
that should never have been able for
someone to get remote access into that
sensitive network but
that's another that's just another rant
for later
another example is a landsat 7 satellite
in 2007 2008
it was hacked for uh
like 12 minutes
whoever the attackers were when they got
it when they got into the satellite
apparently they had full control
they had access
they had access to do whatever they want
to do basically like root level access
equivalent but it's that's about like me
getting root level access on a vms vax
box
you could you could give me
give me you could log me into that vms
box but i don't know dcl
i don't know what i'm doing with vms vax
some of y'all might be too young to
remember vms
uh
or uh
or something you know or some other
obscure operating system so the actors
when they got into the satellite they
they did not know what they were doing
so the good guys were able to take
control of their satellite back but the
hack happened twice
so my and one
one another presentation i'm working on
is to go into the details of how these
systems are built in the components and
there is a very large number of
operating systems
there's a large number of operating
systems and protocols and command
languages for these satellites so my
speculation is
is someone got got access probably
through the ground system and they got
in there they were able to export that
initial trust relationship and got into
the system
but once they got in there they were not
familiar with the command language and
the operating systems and they didn't
know what they had and how to operate in
that environment because it was just
something they were not familiar with
because there is a lot of different
command languages and os's
another one's this uh terra satellite it
got hit in uh 2000
in june 2008 and then again in october
they believed it was the same actors
they they were able to get able to get
in somehow
but they were not able
to maintain access and really do any
damage because they didn't it did my
speculation
based on all the research i've done my
speculation is is they probably didn't
know the command language the syntax and
the os environment that they had gotten
into they got the access through
whatever trust relationship they were on
the ground system but they didn't know
what they were doing
now here's one
this is noah noah in the us is a
government agency that does weather in
the u.s and apparently in 2014 the
chinese it's attributed to the chinese
with this one
that they were
able to get control of that satellite we
were able to take back control of the
satellite but there for a while the
chinese apparently had taken control of
this
weather satellite
this was a really interesting one i
found
apparently
in the uk there's a there was a
satellite constellation called skynet
and sky network is composed of four
satellites
and uh and someone was able to gain
access back in 99 and took control of
one of the satellites and it speculated
that they helped they took control
and they held it for ransom
so that's pretty interesting there
wasn't ransomware but they held it for
ransom
i'm really it's going to be really
interesting
to see how long with all the thousands
and thousands of satellites that are
being put into orbit about how at what
point may we eventually see a ransomware
attack in space because i read i read
some statistics
here recently
that whenever spacex launches a rocket
that has 28 satellites
that there's roughly 4 000 linux
computers on that rocket when with 28
satellites that's a lot of linux now
they have really good really good
security
they know what they're doing and they're
very strict in their engineering
processes very disciplined but
but you know but uh
with all the cube sites that everyone's
throwing up and uh that are may not have
a real strict devops
def psych ops program it's going to be
interesting to see how long we might be
before we start hep c and
say ransomware of a satellite
the international space station it's
been infected a few times with
ransomware it's been it's
not not ransomware but malware
hasn't been no ransomware but just
malware
there was malware introduced through usb
thumb drive at one point and also
malware introduced to space station via
infected laptops that were brought on to
space station now the
the
the flight control system for space
station was not under threat
this was a different network
where they were plugged in and
the malware was
infected on the system
but
but it made it to space on the space
station
it was pretty interesting
uh
there's an organization called the
consultative committee for space data
systems
they come up with all the standards for
space systems satellite systems and the
best practices of how satellite systems
should be built and designed
and
it's just
including encryption but like i said not
you know you can write the documents but
you can't make somebody use it
this is you don't want to read this if
you want these slides i'll give them to
you with all these references but
there's a lot of there's a lot of work
going on
to document best practices for securing
the spacecraft securing the ground
systems
securing the end user terminals
nist
nist is doing a great deal of work they
just they recently published a draft
document nist 8270 for commercial space
they just released another document
for ground system security
aerospace corporation is publishing a
great deal of work minor mit lincoln
labs
there was a as a result of the biosite
hack the cisa in the u.s they just
published some best practices
recommendations for securing
satellite networks and
including the user terminal stuff
and then the there's the federal comm
communications commission and
noaa
who monitors the weather they they have
their best practices they basically
point you to the cyber security then
this cyber security framework and
recommend using encryption and then
there's some others like the orbital
security alliance
they have some best practices for
commercial space systems to consider
using
there's a lot out there it's just it's
like everything somebody's got to read
it and actually put a program together
and implement it throughout the whole
design process
the whole life cycle
which leads into
as these new commercial space space
systems come online really need to get
defsat ops type processes involved and
start with the whole supply chain with
all the coding
and from the very beginning designing
these systems uh to be secure is like
you know like a lot of it is moving to
the cloud
and then the cloud is moving into space
itself to get this they get these uh
systems locked down from the very
beginning
uh and use crypt encryption look at
hardening the uh the systems
for whatever is required at the uh the
orbit that they're going to be and get
them
hardened for uh the radiation and the
hostile space weather all the solar
flares etc that are going on in space
the plasma et cetera
now something that's new
is what
is
i've been reading a lot is satellites
now are going to a software-defined
model software-defined radio is going to
be used which is going to help with
jamming
and electronic warfare because somebody
starts hitting you on a frequency you
can
through software-defined radio you can
change your frequencies change your
radio frequency uh configuration quickly
since it's in the software-defined radio
but also which y'all might find
interesting i found very interesting is
it it's also moving to using virtual
machines and containers in space
and that makes it really interesting
and which which uh which enables the new
idea of what we're familiar with for
many years in our enterprise and other
organizations is being able to put an
intrusion prevention system and put
logging
and maybe put some machine learning in
ai so that we have we can able to we're
able to baseline what is normal how do
our engineers our technicians when they
communicate with satellites what are the
commands we expect them to send
what order the command's coming in
you know the timing et cetera it's
probably going to be automated we're
probably going to have pre-engineered
and pre-scripted and what is going to be
that timing that those commands are
going to be set and what's expected and
be able to apply uh machine learning
ai to that and so we can quickly detect
hey somebody somebody's figured out how
to get access and they're sending
commands out of order
and maybe we need to maybe we need to go
and boot up a different payload os or
payload container to take over that's
more hard and more trusted and more
secure until we figure out what's
happening because we obviously we got we
may have somebody trying to help us
manage our sites
so so that is being tested i was reading
aerospace corporation is about to launch
a satellite to test some of these
capabilities so that so that's good that
they were headed there
and like i said you know you've got to
do the really strict
configuration management of the system
and know what version of the container
or vm you're on and be able to restore
back to a known good
uh
you know in case you have an issue then
you need to get back to a point of a
trusted trusted system so now we're
going to containers and vms this is
going to be a whole lot easier to do
maybe we don't have to reboot the whole
satellite computer system maybe we just
we can just go and pull back go back to
a trusted vm or contrusted container
in the configuration management
but
that's
what i had to share uh today
uh
i appreciate the b-sides uh cayman's
team uh inviting me to come come back
and uh
to besides and and share with y'all i
really enjoyed uh visiting the island
again hope to come back again soon
but y'all have any uh questions or
anything
yes sir
he's gonna give you a microphone
hi
um you mentioned that they don't do any
um
encryption between ground
stations and the satellites
because of the interference from sun
particles
um
but
so so is that really because um
of the limited bandwidth because of the
interference and re-transmissions and i
would assume they would use some type of
um
frequency hop-in
to to do the transmissions so is that
sufficient to keep the bandwidth up
uh to allow encryption and aside from
that
is there any kind of um
hashing that is done
between the ground station and the
satellite to ensure the integrity of
data
well
the the encryption is not that's used on
the satellites everything i've read it
is uh i've been reading here very
recently
it's on the fcc
website yeah
they uh they've decided
that they're not going to force an
encryption standard on the commercial
satellite industry so
however they choose to do the key
exchange the hashing etc that's all up
to the individual satellite companies
it's not a fourth standard like
everybody's going to use aes 512 what
have you so
i have no need to know i don't work for
the organizations and if i did i would
be under ndas where i couldn't disclose
it right so
i just all i can do is just like
yourself go out and do a lot of googling
and read what's been published in the
open source right and uh
do my own
reductive reasoning well this is seems
to be what happened but on the uh
i like i like your idea about the uh
changing the spectrum and i think that
you can do some really creative things
with software-defined radio and i think
uh i don't know for i don't know
personally but like in the case of what
we're seeing in ukraine where the
russians started interfering with
starlink
and then spacex sent a code update
and fixed it and now they don't have a
problem so i think you can with
software-defined radios
you can start changing frequencies and
you can work around issues but
encryption
it's just you know it's just that it
depends on what the vendors want to
whoever you know owns the sas what they
implement and
okay you know cool
it's interesting it's a interesting
domain to study yeah
yeah
um
but
that was that was the idea the idea is
that is it that they don't do the
encryption or they stay away from it
because of the bandwidth limitations
i don't know if it's a bandwidth
i've read i've read where one individual
talked about about it being a bandwidth
concern but everything that i've read
it's more to do with the space weather
because it's from the space weather
the solar flares
all the the protons neutrons the ions
ionization it's going flowing through
space like solar flare right and
that is the biggest issue of disrupting
uh doing the single event upsets and
flipping bits right and because of that
because of that they would have a lot of
retransmissions because of the
interference right so that would then
affect the overall bandwidth yeah that
could yeah yeah so that's what yeah
they'd have to be
re-exchanging keys getting things reset
and the connection would be up and down
they would lose control of the satellite
uh being able to manage it because of
all the key constant key exchanges
maybe you get one command
but you didn't get the second or third
command were you at in your command
sequence right because of all the
exchanges yeah
it could be disruptive but that's where
you had to start using uh hardened
hardened communications gear that's
that's uh designed to survive space
okay but but that drives up the cost
yeah and if you're you know if you're a
university and a researcher on a real
cheap uh budget
you don't have a lot of budget for
you know you're using raspberry pies and
bagel bones you got to do the best you
can do
right you just want to accept the risk
that somebody's going to be able to
listen to your traffic
right
okay thanks
which is really interesting uh if you're
not aware a lot of the computers uh
raspberry pi's and beaglebones are uh
used
for like a lot of these cubesats
any more questions
good purposes yeah it is yeah it's all
good i mean uh it's great it's just you
know everybody's wanting to get into
commercial space and i want and i'm
interested it's like okay where does the
baseline what has actually happened with
space
over the years and is everyone starts
all these new startups it's like silicon
valley you know the whole internet
crazed back
in the late 90s early 2000s everybody's
running into space now
we need to go and secure these systems
like we needed to go and secure the
internet
and harden web servers and databases
back
you know we need to do it with space too
what what would be the
the commercial value
to the small guy
here i mean it's one thing to have
infrastructure in space
that's probably communicating quickly
with satellites and doing storage
compute type things
but what's
what's the guy in the cayman islands
going to use it for let's say
well your uh your
the the weather
they uh say if there's computing in
space one of the reasons they're going
one of the primary applications for
putting computing resources in space
is a there's weather weather satellites
that could be collecting imagery in
space or be looking at certain parts of
the island watching for erosion
et cetera and
be able to pre-process the imagery
and instead of sending everything that
is collected down
and using all the bandwidth to send just
everything
and overworking analysts that are
already very busy
the
if you if you have the storage in space
if you have the computing power
then the computer in space can
pre-process apply analytics but you know
play the ai do all the image analysis
get all that automated
so that the imagery is pre-processed and
only what you need is sent down
uh so you know so you're uh
so your military your uh
whoever your environmental whoever is
watching the environment and protecting
the environment the national parks
et cetera
can be getting only the imaging that
they really need the best imaging where
they can focus instead of having to look
at you know terabytes of data and
keeping their bandwidth and running up
their cost they can just use what they
need
and so there's a lot of applications
though that are going to come about
as a result of that storage being in
space and only going to be limited by
the creativity
but the image analysis is what comes to
my mind first uh that's the easy one
any more questions
uh i'll i will tell you i don't i don't
have a slide for it but if you hit if
you hit me on linkedin if you want the
slides i'll send you the slides uh or
twitter i'll send you the slides if you
like them share i'll give them to the
conference
but if you're interested in playing with
uh satellite software
you can mock up especially like you know
if you have children that are interested
in space and and learning about the
systems there is a lot of capabilities
available in the open source community
and all you need is the power of a
raspberry pi or a beagle bone you don't
have to have a high-end computer run
this there's a
open sat kit
open s-a-t kit
from nasa freaking nasa
it's going to work
it works good in the inside of nasa
instead of the open in the openstack kit
they have cfs
core flight software which is cubesat
software that actually flies
and then it includes ball aerospaces
cosmos which is a ground system software
and then they have another tool that
they give you this is all free called 42
that is an orbit simulator it's very
nice
there's sat nogs there's one called
that's a
s-a-t-n-o-g-s check that out there's uh
also nasa has called nos 3 nos3
that's another free resource
another one is artemis
check out artemis uh and this is all
open source and you can go and uh you
can boot up like i said you can boot up
you can build satellites on your table
on your you know kitchen table with
raspberry pi's and beaglebone running
core flight software and maybe this
stuff will run in containers runs in vms
so if you want to if you're interested
in learning it you know more
it's good it's just a great stuff to
take back to you know local schools and
help the kids start playing with see if
they can touch it
and also for security research
but anyway if you if you're curious
about anything that i can send you send
you lots of links and all this like i
said it's all out there on the net
any more questions but if nothing i
appreciate you all letting me come and
speak and uh
i appreciate all the hospitality of the
island everything's been great the food
oh my god i've eaten so much good food
met so many nice people it's been
awesome
thank you