Thanks well good afternoon test tests
immunise of just a second here hang on
sorry for everybody that I'm scratching
on the wife sir
good all right thank you all for coming
to this afternoon to hear me talk about
the five things that matter this talk
for me is an important one because it's
the five things that I typically see in
most security programs where we have a
lot of problems with and with my talks I
like to keep them fairly high level and
also super technical as well and balance
both of those so I'll give you some nice
bypass techniques for Windows Defender
some other things throughout the talk
and everything else but really this talk
kind of hits home to me because it's one
of the things where when we go into a
lot of companies we see a lot of
different things
appreciate the background it's been fun
being in the cybersecurity space it's
interesting I my dad just recently
twittered I says my dad got to it it's
been a literally interesting actually so
I know a lot more about him that I
thought I would ever know about my dad
and and so one thing he did recently is
a few years ago he spoke at derbycon and
he let the whole world know that I was
scared of clowns and it has not stopped
since I get people sending me clowns all
day every day there's people threatening
to hire clowns to come to the office
like it's it's been a whole bunch thing
but recently he just he just released my
my report card from when I was a senior
in high school which I had all apps
except had 1b and was in typing and
other then I filled out a high school
and I graduated in summer school to go
there and ice shortly join the Marines
after that but it's been a great ride we
never thought being able to talk in
front of people was a thing or being
able to do computers for a living was a
thing so it's been a really awesome
experience and I've gotten a lot of
great things to do for it so with that
I'm gonna show you a quick video and
this is one of my favorite things in
life that I got I got actually got to be
a part of kind of kind of I'm part of
this segment but this is from mr. robot
and in season 3 Elliott is basically
getting fired from evil Corp and he's
trying to evade the security guy folks
so that he can stop the dark army from
actually taking down evil Corp and so
Elliott is basically trying to evade
security and get around him you know
here I'm throw a little little thing in
here that I thought was really cool it's
kind of cool when that they dropped her
name on a TV show that even worked with
and helped
and it's because I throughout this
series and he look at the screens and in
season 1 episode 5 when Elliott is
hacking into steel mountain they use a
social engineer toolkit to spoof a text
message that allows them in the steel
mountain and then season 3 episode 1 I
think it was when Darlene lit the fire
up and all the money that ran somewhere
that they deployed they deployed through
the social engineer toolkit so a lot of
really neat things you get the
experience and it really cool
interesting up to have also been in a
rap video never thought that would
happen I was in a Chris Brown rap video
and it was really interesting I flew out
to LA and it's a really interesting
piece where he he basically reached out
to our website the producer did and he's
like hey can you can you can Dave advise
us on this this rep you didn't know who
was at the time and I'm like the only
restriction is that Dave needs to be in
the hacking video and needs actually be
in the video so there are I'm in the
back like hacking away and the old
premise is that Chris Brown broke up
with his girlfriend and he wants to
delete all the pictures off of her phone
so he hires his best friend Dave to come
in and delete all the photos off of
there so I don't know this is really
cheesy don't look it up at work by the
way it's definitely not safe for work in
any way shape or form but that was kind
of a fun one too so so while we're here
is that when we look at security we talk
a lot about things that we that are our
challenges right and we all have
challenges I always like to make the the
joke that we could fix security today
and actually I can you can walk out here
with the million dollar secret of fixing
security today right now I'm gonna give
it to you for free okay and that's if
you have one dedicated person to
security for every single one employee
that you have of your organization cuz
you can just sit behind them and be like
not don't click that link you just
clicked it okay hang on grab the
computer pass over the person next to
you they reimagine you're all set right
security would be fixed it solves all
the issues that we deal with today soft
furtive on the lifecycle you have a
security person behind there like that's
sequel injection you can't code it that
way code it the other way okay got it
got okay cool you know it literally
fixed things as we see it think we don't
have that luxury so a lot of us fit deal
with a lot of different things whether
it's politics whether it's not enough
funding or staff whether it's not having
the the people to be able to support it
there's a lot of things that that create
challenges in our environment and so
that's we're gonna be talking about
today and still to this day I haven't
found a piece of technologists replace
me yet personally artificial
intelligence has
not replaced us as attackers or defense
there's a lot of things coming kind of
coming up from a marketing perspective
that are kind of interesting so what are
the top five things that matter to at
least to me when it comes to scare might
not be everybody but these are things
that I commonly see pretty much across
the board before we start in that the
basics here it's easy to say that
everything's broken and and I don't
think everything is broken in fact what
I would say is that over the past ten
years I've seen security go through a
complete transformation where we've
gotten better we're at a place now where
you actually see defenders winning
against the red team yeah we're at a
time now where people are actually
detecting attacks earlier on now it's
not perfect in any way shape or form and
I see something like Starwood and
Marriott right where they had breaches
for three or four years without
detection again not perfect in any way
but we're getting better in a lot of
cases that we're doing and I cannot say
say being a red teamer
and I'll talk about what that actual
concept means because that's changed a
lot over the past ten years but actually
being a red teamer I can say it's
substantially harder for me to break
into companies substantially harder one
little thing can totally set off an
analyst and go into triage mode to
figure out what was actually happening
one of our testers recently was doing a
was doing a red team engagement and we
use so we use we have our own research
and development team over a trusted SEC
and they develop all those cool
weaponize tools that we use we don't
disclose when you just use them for our
customers for them to get better than
anything else and it might be a debate
about that or whatever I understand but
we use this awesome amazing thing on
this customer for Red Team got into
environment bypassed all their EDR
products got command and control
infrastructure completely undetected
it's perfect use a bunch of undocumented
ways of getting a remote code execution
on to the system things that haven't
been discovered yet flew completely
under the radar right and he might be
like well why are you doing that first
place all explained in just a second
what was interesting is is about four
minutes later we got detected four
minutes using some really amazing
tradecraft
that we had spent years of developing
and we got detected in four minutes how
did we get detected well what they had
done in their environment which I
thought was really unique is that they
baseline people on two categories
technical and non-technical and what
they look for is anybody that would run
command line arguments in this specific
case we you looked at IP config to see
what the network we were on harmless
obvious
it's not code execution in which shape
or form but this person fell in a non
technical category and typed in ipconfig
boom nail right it's stuff like that
that makes it really challenging for us
as attackers to start to go into
environments we don't know where all the
landmines are at and that was never the
way five years ago by the way five years
ago we can go in with Metasploit or on
otto pone destroy a bunch of systems the
only way they would know is if the
system crashed right
things have changed substantially over
the past five to ten years to where we
are a better industry and it's amazing
to see all of the work that's gone into
making that possible that's all to
people that's all those other people in
this room sitting here today making and
making your organization's better every
time of what you're doing and that's a
huge testament to what we're starting to
see so what are some of the things that
we see out there number one the basics
the basics still kick our butts today
you know we want to stop adversaries
from breaking in using zero day exploits
and we still have password one as our
main password for all of our users right
and that's a people problem right and in
many cases there's a lot of things that
we have to incorporate it to that but
weak passwords pasture management
two-factor authentication segmentation
my god right
segmentation is one of those things
where we should have been doing a long
time ago but we have to re our Kotak how
we do business try doing that in a large
organization small organizations might
might be a little bit easier but large
organizations rer connecting and
redesigning your entire infrastructure
is a major thing probably one of the
most effective ways that we get stopped
as attackers is through application
whitelisting by far today application
whitelisting again by far the most
effective control you can put into your
environment today to stop most the stuff
you see out there now don't get me wrong
there's we've called living off the land
binders and scripts and there's ways of
circumventing those controls but guess
what guess what 84% of the noise is
today binaries and applications that are
untrusted in your environment 84% what
happens when you take that away you
don't have 84% anymore right so you know
you have 16% to do the math right yeah
okay thank God I always freak out about
that with that one statistic I get the
numbers wrong then you have 16% now you
can focus on in your environment say hey
these are the things that we can do
differently to identify the noise in May
and and monitor for deviations of
patterns to be
in your environment so again one of the
most effective ways out there not easy
is anybody ement application control and
cross your entire environment in high
integrity mode without any exceptions
not happening right not happening but
there are ways for us to at least get it
in there to do a bit better of a job
some basics that I see blocking on-site
executables and user profile directories
as a start like basic right hey it's not
a code signed application
you know just block it in your user app
data's and your downloads and everything
else and don't allow it to execute in
the first place guess what that does
prob about 75% of that 84% you see out
there today constrain language moon
being able to implement so let me just
get this out of the way do regular users
the PowerShell hell as kids in your heck
no heck no regular users do not need
PowerShell right so why do why does
every user need access the PowerShell
you could do that within Group Policy
right if you have soft restriction
policies you have app blocker and device
guard right you can do that directly
with the group policy to say hey if
they're not part of these groups don't
allow them to execute power shell and
there's two locations by the way in
PowerShell people almost for always
always forget this you have C colon
backslash Windows backslash this with
their due back sash windows powershell
backs s version 100 backslash powershell
died exe and PowerShell underscore is
seated exe okay those are your two main
locations but you also have on sis while
64 which is amir windows directory
windows backs last as well 64 back to us
windows powershell back to the first
window back to the power saw the DX e
and then powershell and square zdz those
two locations are your two main culprits
for what you want to lock down with
those specifically so this thing long
users for access powershell version 6
and above heavy logging everybody from
the script lock logging there's anybody
ever enable script lock logging did
anybody crash servers when they did that
they just Splunk licensing go up 10
million dollars yes right so script
block logging is amazing it's also the
most noisiest log that you're gonna have
in your entire environment and i wish we
lived in a world where money wasn't a
problem like again one security person
to one employee when you enable
constraint language mode there is stuff
of microsoft's internals that you never
want to see deployed in your environment
from those powershell scripts man they
do stuff wrong especially if your office
365 user or
customers the amount of unsigned
PowerShell code that is flying through
your network is absolutely astonishing
it's incredible
and by the way if you ever want to fool
a sock out by the way just take one of
those scripts it's like they're like 700
pages long put your shell code injection
in the middle of it cuz no one's ever
gonna see it and just upload and you're
all set
cuz they're not code sign in the first
place it's still gonna create as
Microsoft function and do all this stuff
and it's also gonna get you remote code
execution at the same time without being
seen so apply on that one specifically
also PowerShell version 6 and getting
more four boats into logging what's
interesting the PowerShell is it
integrates into what's called the
anti-malware scan interface which I'm
going to show you an example here in a
few a messiah is is is a great
abstraction layer getting a little more
clear of what actually is about to be
executing on your system right before it
hits the actual interpreter itself and
so with a MSI there's what's called a
messiah scan string and a MSS can buffer
and what you can do with PowerShell
scripts specifically is scan those prior
to it actually executing in your system
which gives you a lot more verbosity now
the issue with a MSI is it runs in user
land mode so as a user you can disable
it so there's a number of ways of
defeating a Masai complete setting it
down completely but what you'll see in a
demonstration here is that even with a
MSI detection you only have to modify
things in just this tiny tiny tiny way
to circumvent their complete detection
criteria so it's still a really
rudimentary way of detection but still
good visibility if you're pulling that
data back to look at that I'm a huge fan
of system on system on leverages what's
called kernel level event log tracing
for Windows etw it's a great way of
getting more visibility into things that
are happening in your environment
without having to deal with crazy kernel
drivers so system on is a great way to
deploy your environment to see a lot of
good stuff and Olaf has probably the
most comprehensive system on
configuration files what's great about
system on is you can actually configure
them to be alerts and alarms it does
it's only central correlation
essentially you can say and if this does
that and ok that's good and then send
this alarm back that specifically does
something this is great for living off
land binaries and scripts and everything
else please please please enable the
Windows Firewall internally just that
that's easy isn't it for users users not
easy easy no easy little easy kind easy
for regular users why does that matter
workstation workstation communication is
typically how we move for ladder
movement so you enable the Windows
Firewall basic concept and all of a
sudden I can't pivot from Bob and IT to
Bob and sales to Mary nighties computer
you eliminated an attack surface that we
we previously had that we wouldn't have
necessarily if you had those just
controls out there detections I will
repeat this throughout this presentation
this is one of the most important pieces
out there but in order to do endpoint
detection and in order to do a detection
at all you need to have endpoint locks
I'll repeat that you need to have
endpoint locks I know you're Splunk
licensing goes up to ten million dollars
but you need and I'm not a rep for lunk
by the way either but you know whatever
you have for your cinema your
correlation engine if you using
something like elasticsearch all you
need a storage then right but you you
leverage something like endpoints you
have to have logs that's where most of
your attacks service comes in through
again obviously other things like east
east and west traffic not just north and
south when it comes to communications
DNS logs script block Logging's grades
command line auditing another group
policy feature right you turn that on
you can see command line auditing as
it's going on why is bob and sales
executing an IP config some decent
pieces their visibility first
understanding specific tactics and
procedures techniques and procedures
that attackers using your environment
from a detection standpoint what I see
in most companies and what I do a thing
called ions there's a thing called ask
an expert which I apparently am
pretending to be an expert and so when
you're an expert the more the biggest
calls that I get is how do I take my
turist techniques and how do I run them
in my environment how do I write the
Texans off of them that's gonna be our
RC and then they call their ad that's my
adversarial simulation programming I'm
like okay we got a lot of discussion to
talk about here okay so what happens
with a lot of these techniques out there
is that you're not focusing on the
tactics or the procedures that the
attackers wrappered by or even
understanding your threat models around
which groups are specifically focused on
you as an organization and what ends up
happening is you get a bunch of command
line parsing tools do your writing
specifically Texans for and to
circumvent them is usually very trivial
a good example is a tool that I wrote
called magic unicorn which is a
PowerShell exploitation framework and
one of the customers that we were
working with will look for encoded
command which if you're not familiar
powershell coda command is the way to
essentially get around what are called
execution restriction policies and so
within code of command you can cast
something in Unicode and base64 encode
it and your entire application would
then run by running a code of command so
a lot of people look for in coda command
being run in their environment look for
- e - en - en c - e C by the way which a
lot of people don't know about so I
wrote unicorn to basically convert
encode a command back at the very end
but you never actually call encode of
command the first place which
circumvents all the detection criteria
that's out there so again looking more
at the behavior which we'll talk about
here in a little bit becomes really
important than the actual technique that
was being leveraged in your environment
I'd want to know every single time power
saw communicating out to the Internet is
that gonna generate a lot of false
positives yep can I based on my
environment yep
but I get a lot less as time goes on yep
do any people to do that yes so you know
behavior becomes really really important
in environments but you need the people
to be able to really establish that and
use it and so my personal belief is that
we purchase tools to try to fix poor
security programs and let me let me talk
about that for a second okay in this
concept because if you are if you have a
group that is already overworked right
would you is anybody here not overworked
does anybody just chill at their office
they don't do anything they just chill
got one that's pretty awesome I'm not
not look one person just chill at the
office and don't do anything you're not
not dealing with meetings or fires would
be great as if we could just focus our
entire day on security but that never
happens right we're dealing with a lot
of other things you got ITIL and change
control we got to go to the cab meeting
for something else and do this and that
and then we have audits going on we're
at the provide context and data to it oh
hey there's a fire over here where the
system's burning down was it our
endpoint agent that did it you know
there's all these different things that
impact us on a day-in day-out and so
when you take a piece of technology that
you already have embedded in your
environment you say this product is crap
and you rip it out and you put a brand
new piece of technology and what happens
that next product and we just this crap
because it's how you're leveraging the
tools and technology you don't have the
resources to be able to leverage it in
the same way you can anything else and
like I hear all the time like our voters
you know we're using Qualis raising
nessus or using rapid7 or whatever you
want to use it sucks I'm like well
what's your process well we don't have a
process okay let's let's talk about it's
not the scanner that's your fault
it's your program that you built
surround it that is not working as
anticipating to focus on that so usually
when we purchase new tools we already
have everything we need today in our
environment typically you may be a
supplement a couple of things but we
usually already have the technology
today to do what we need to do yet we go
we buy the latest and greatest because
it's next-gen it's awesome so most
organizations we see are still at the
basic concept level they don't have a
lot of the enhanced detection they're
not focusing on simulations and a
mediation to talk a little bit about
here in a few minutes some are much
further ahead than others there's a
there's a company that we do work for it
probably has one of the best security
programs that I've ever seen and and I
love to tell the story because it's
where we just got annihilated to where
we look like a bunch of kids and and we
don't like that feeling right when we're
gonna and a red team engagement and you
get in and they detecting you shut you
out in every single way shape or form
you possible you could have gotten into
their environment and then the entire
blue team is clapping and cheering on
the phone Wow like can't we be trusted
sack yeah you know it's like shooting
you're like oh so we're like playing
like playing like careless whispers in
our slack channel and like like like
eating popcorn and ice cream so to get
over it and you know one thing we
decided is hey that we don't never want
to have that happen again and so next
time in round we destroyed them and we
were clapping on the phone and then the
next time around they destroyed us it's
that back and forth that works really
well right but the way that they do it
is is they have an entire team that
focuses on understanding their threats
in their environment and building their
program around that and then simulating
that in these types of tests and
simulations that we see out there so
again some of these are great use
examples of things that actually work in
environments that we've seen and
collaboration is one of the biggest
pieces that I can't hit home enough
about I'm gonna break down a the
concepts here and then insert this is in
education or not a repeat of something
that you've already already know but we
talked about Blue Team and Red Team we
talked about purple team purple teaming
isn't a new concept purple team has been
around since 2007 Lee says this as far
back as I could find it a term usage of
purple teaming and purple teaming isn't
a new thing that we're trying to build
on top of the security industry what
purple teaming is is just collaboration
between the red team and the blue team
and what we used to do and I'll talk
about this here in a little bit we used
to go in we should just break everything
and you'd break everything you'd hand
awesome report to your customer and
you'd walk out like man I just destroyed
this company they're totally screwed
good luck and then next year to come
back same thing just join him again they
fixed all the technical findings they
didn't fix the reason why those
technical findings were there in the
first place
and so year after year after year after
year it was read winning winning winning
winning winning and it was read doing
their mystique and their their amazing
feats and they're a cool hacker stuff
from their screens flying with you know
green green green text everywhere with
cool ASCII art have to have ask yarn or
to be considered a hacker my opinion
it's also a prerequisite for any tools
that we release a trusted second test
it's actually in the tool release guide
ASCII art and so any get judged on the
ASCII art - so anyways but that wasn't
the right way of doing things we weren't
helping anybody by going in and
destroying companies every time where
companies really start to shine is when
you have that collaboration between red
and blue where instead of doing covert
all the time to test the effectiveness
of your instant response program you're
doing over testing you're working with
them as you're going through your
simulations and you say listen here's
the things that we're doing here's the
things you can get better on here's the
things that you're just missing as far
as detection you walk out of there
completely different then hey here's a
list of 10 findings at the pit patch you
know specific systems for so that
collaboration really becomes really
really important I'm a huge believer on
simulations and emulation
I think tool releases are great there's
a lot of debate right now and whether or
not to release is do more harm than good
whether researchers disclosing
techniques do more harm than good I'm a
huge advocate of giving tools to people
that may not be able to develop those
tools so they can test their own
environment attackers are gonna do it
why can't we have the same types of
tools out there yes they're gonna be
used by adversaries colbalt strike by
the way is used all the time by Russia
all the time would you say that coal
boat strikes a bad tool no we use it as
testers all the time to test the
effectiveness because we don't have a
Mudge to be able to build that tool
internally to our own capabilities and
so we have to have the tools necessary
to do our jobs as does any carpenter it
has to do their jobs could a carpenter
take one of his his devices and stab
somebody with it absolutely when it
comes to research we have to have that a
conduit of getting better and working
better to to one goal of making things
more secure
without simulations red-and-blue don't
understand each other so when I go
through and I do a simulation of
somebody my goal isn't to destroy them
and it wasn't anymore I used to really
like destroy people but but it used to
be that way my goal is to make them
better and what they're actually
accomplishing and so simulations and
working through these types of things
make a big deal usually companies don't
even have a foundation by the way we
hear all the time hey we want a red team
and we're like okay
what does that mean to you like oh we
want you this is just like completely
annihilate us and break into us so that
we you know we know exactly where all of
our weaknesses and our exposures are in
our environment so that then we can
patch them all and be secure I'm like
that's not how any of this works by the
way this is not a red team for you
Brett's most most organizations that we
deal with are not at a maturity level to
deal with red team engagements almost
99% of them are not at a level that they
even need red team's in their
environment they don't even have basic
forms of monitoring detection or even
having endpoint logs in their
environments what is a red team gonna do
for them other than destroy them and
show them where they have faulty
programs in there and that can be used
as a wedge - so one thing I'll say is
red and blue are better together and I'm
a huge advocate of that I have become
more blue and I still say I'm Red Team
but my whole operation of thinking is
all blue like if I'm gonna write
something a tool a new technique or a
tack vector how am I gonna stop that you
know when I do something new or unique I
make sure that it doesn't impact blue
like by releasing a specific exploit you
know to the wild to impact other
organizations and companies I you seen
everything about that I used to write
exploits all the time publish them up a
mill arm like yeah I just got this
awesome zero day here you go good luck
you know vendor go go go patch it a
little bit more refined now and times
are a lot different by the way that was
a badge of credibility you know earlier
in you know and earlier in times of what
exploits you can write and get around
data execution prevention and stuff like
that but again we talk about like we
talked about the red team today like it
was ten years ago we always say all the
red team is not special I hear that all
the time like the red team's not a
special group well yeah they are a
special group there there they
understand offensive capabilities within
an organization you're not applying the
red team the right way then you're right
they're just sitting there destroying
your environment and so the
terminologies that we use around
penetration testers by the way ten years
ago
right pentesters just come in they just
destroy the organization and they walk
out yeah I guess that still happens in
environments but that's not exactly what
we're designed to be doing in
organizations that's room hacker by the
way applies to both red and blue it's
not just the red team that has hackers
the blue team are hackers why aren't you
hacking our stuff up to figure out how
to defend it aren't you writing awesome
code to figure out ways to respond to us
more effectively we're all hacking
together and in this specific way and so
the industry changed and this happened
while ago it just takes a it takes a lot
of terminologies fixes to do this people
think that red team's repente ask people
think that pentester vulnerability
assessment people think I want to be
assassins or red team's people think
that physical assessments are you know
social engineering which it can be a
component of that so there's a lot of
terminology issues that we face in this
industry right now and a lot of it
really is hey red team's more designed
to understand your threat models towards
your organization and build your
capabilities off of what the
capabilities are of that organization
and to be a little bit better that's it
not not exponentially better but going
to the level of what that organization
is willing to actually accomplish you
might see a theme here around sharing
and collaboration but when we work
together and understand things we get
better research by the way sharing
things and getting better tools doing
different things that you're I thought
some of these were great some this one
was how to call PowerShell without ever
calling PowerShell that came from Daniel
Bohannon
both of these came from Danny Bohannon
over fire I and this was a specific one
is it just run for files and basically
will eventually execute power shell with
no exit on there and you could just
launch PowerShell thought that a good
ETR bypass by the way for all you folks
this one down here I thought was really
brilliant so it's very familiar with
what we call living off the lamp miners
and scripts is it me not familiar feel
free raise your hand I okay got a couple
explain it real quick so if you look at
exploitation right our whole goal is to
get code execution onto a system right
we want to get code execution it's now
granted we might have other objectives
password stealing or things like that
bypassing multi-factor authentication
etc etc but with exploitation our whole
goal is to get code onto that system
that we can then run to compromised that
asset and then from there if do
ransomware or move laterally across
environments other systems
primarily I gave a talk I think it was
DEFCON 13 it was the very first ever
PowerShell security talk and as you've
talked to the folks at Microsoft they'll
say that I was the first person ever to
give a partial secure job which is
really cool to say like you're kind of
like the father of PowerShell security
you know kind of kicking that thing was
kind of neat it's called PowerShell oMFG
and it was when PowerShell had first
come out and it was it was in every
operating system yet it was Windows
Vista at the time and they were looking
at making an optional requirement in
Windows Vista but they had come out and
announced him that any further operating
systems would have PowerShell embedded
into it so I just had to take a look at
it was one of my good friends Josh Kelly
and we're like wow this is really
powerful you can do a lot of great stuff
with and I said listen you know giving a
full-fledged programming language onto a
Windows environment
aside from vbscript and others is gonna
be pretty damaging I think to security
especially with no logging anything else
it's gonna be a big deal and it's can be
one of the main fronts of attack and lo
and behold Power Cells become a major
front of it now one thing I'll say about
Microsoft is that Lee homes literally
the catalyst for security in PowerShell
that he deserves everything that he gets
in more in raids I'm sure he literally
got everything that is currently in
PowerShell with a constraint language
mode with logging and verbosity in there
you have in their script lock logging
all the security features that we now
know instead of PowerShell you all just
have to kind of update your stuff from
PowerShell version 2 up to PowerShell
version 6 or above anyways so that's
that's PowerShell well with the way we
used to hack about ten years ago is we
would look for things like Java right
which had a lot of major issues in it or
Adobe which had a lot of major issues in
it or office products which would have a
lot of still have a lot of major issues
in and so you'd have these products and
we say well we know that a user probably
has these products in their system so we
know that it's there it's the same thing
with living off the land binders and
scripts and this is why it's so kind of
damaging this is it circumvents
application whitelisting your
application control is that microsoft
ships with binaries across the operating
system that allow it to work right you
have Calcutta XE for example right it's
code signed by Microsoft you know it has
a specific function that it produces
well all their binaries in the Windows
operating system have additional
functionality built in as well I'm like
for my my favorite ones and I'll show
you a demonstration of this is reg SBR
32 it's under the system 32 directory
and registry or 32 has a /i parameter
that allows you to go in down those
put tags directly from the internet and
run it without any type of detection
whatsoever so you can go and download
code roughly from internet execute
automatically without any type of
detection so using a code sign Microsoft
Windows binary to then go and download
code directly off the Internet and
execute it in an authorized State
there's about 77 of these binaries in
Windows I do it MSH GA CBD THC CSC THC
Matt have been checked there's a whole
bunch of these right even BG info the
background info that you use to show the
IP address this has remote code
execution functionality into it so you
know there's a lot of different things
that are codes I'm at Microsoft that
give you full capabilities now let me
show you a little little demonstration
here really quick power this back up
again sorry about that so this is a
fully updated version of if it comes
back up I hope they got it does it'll
come up take a second here it goes oh my
god or not there it goes all right so I
got a fully up-to-date version of
Windows 10 and and this is an example of
what registry are 32 would look like as
an attacker okay you give it a slash
eyes / and in the slash is the most
important and we're gonna go to trust
tech comm as an example okay and so here
we're just gonna go and download a
script object it could be whatever
extension type you want - doesn't have
to be XML or txt or SCP or anything like
that can be whatever you want to cuz you
imagine hosting something like github
and it's just a github project and it
says readme dot txt does your defenders
gonna see that and so this is this will
basically create a script logic and
execute this code for us now interesting
enough Microsoft knows that this is bad
right so I'm running the latest version
of Windows Defender if you notice here
it was less updated for the 24 so four
days ago okay so it's about four days
all wish you know hey I didn't hook up
to the Internet today I apologize but if
I run this what happens ooh got snagged
by antivirus right it must be a really
good detection I'm sure let's take a
look at this what if I throw carrot into
here wait hang on hang on Oh too good
okay
what if I throw another carrot here Oh
still denied what if I throw three
carrots this the screen to go away oh we
get through Thank You Rance my demo I'm
Dave Kennedy this is what we're dealing
with today when it comes to detection
and prevention and this is a clear-cut
case of what we seen edr products to by
the way edr products looking for that /i
throw one care in there
let's get seen throw two carrots three
carrots are good sounds good another
couple funny ones on throwing legitimate
words into your your code take a
dictionary and just have variable
substitutions in there of dictionary
words because it makes it look more
predictable from an analysis perspective
that it's legitimate because you're
using legitimate dictionary words not
coding language stuff there's so many
different tricks that we have out there
but it's super trivial is this make me
an elite hacker by the way Yeah right
I just bypassed Windows Defender I
gotten rated number one in the antivirus
category and this year and whatever the
heck magazine that was right number one
got around it right three carrots so you
know with with living off land binaries
and scripts that's a whole nother attack
surface that we have available to us and
you know when I was gonna get to this
one is that this one was found in the
wild which I would ask does anybody here
actually would anybody here actually
detect this and I'd like to see a honest
answer don't be like my miner detection
program is the best I would all right
listen to what it's doing first okay
it's going out and it's using cert you
till okay every from a cert util
import-export certificates
there's a - ping option where you can
download code directly from the internet
with Suri tool why that was ever a
feature right don't know but hey it's
cool right you can download code record
an Internet in any context and you
certain till for it fine
sounds good now here's a crazy detection
they download the power show code
directly through circuit still and then
execute it with PowerShell
never calling out with PowerShell at all
in the first place pretty awesome
where'd you detect that no one looking
for sir utility key not to the internet
we looking for you have to do that from
command prompt well that one's command C
but you don't need to you don't need to
run from command prompt oh by the way as
an attacker
I can't member last time I'm actually
dropped into a command prompt by the way
we know you all look for us drug-running
cmd.exe but that's a good one eye or
leverage a completely in PowerShell so
that's that's the good way of doing it
right more than that behavior of
understanding applications that haven't
beacon down the first place and then
from there going there totally agree yep
a couple II agree baselining your
environment sounds like a marvelous
counter so without what by way without
talking about this most the folks in
here defenders probably would have known
that you could do that right there are
ways with three carrots they get around
Windows Defender right or there are ways
with cert util to go and do this or you
know one of my favorites is MSHDA tied
exe most folks know about HDI files so
HCA files are high content HTML files
and what's what's damaging about them is
you can run them in a browser and they
have any browser execute them so they
basically you can hit open and do
anything you want to there and so with
with HT a files most people block HTA's
at the firewall right so they don't
allow those to actually actually execute
but MSHDA that exe is a phenomenal
resource you can point m sh TI DXE to
any website you want to again download
the code and execute it directly for you
they have me me cats running off of em
SCH ta ta whatever you want to running
off of MSHDA without an issue so again a
lot of issues that that with microsoft
code signing applications that give us
code execution functionality but it
comes into sharing you wouldn't know
about that if you weren't here today
your blue team probably would know about
unless you tested it out on their red
team your thread hunters wouldn't have
known about unless they've seen in the
wild before all of those pieces of
knowledge coming together to work
together collaborate work really really
well
number four behavior
focus on and Jeff Moss nailed this on
the head was last year at black head
before he introduced the keynote and
Jeff Moss said as an industry we are
focusing solely on a techniques and we
have no idea what the tactics and
procedures of attackers are any spot on
100% right mitre attack is a great
example minor attack is a great
phenomenal resource this is don't get me
wrong it's great a walk through a lot of
techniques allows you to do some
simulations in your environment but it
is not a cheat sheet for detection not
what it was designed for if you're
trying to do whack-a-mole detections off
of the technique section of miter your
programs probably missing a substantial
amount of gaps when it comes to
attacking and I would say it's probably
pretty easy to circumvent your detection
criteria so we are focused on the
techniques not tactics or procedures so
once we realize that we can start to
look at what that means to switch more
to the tactics and procedures behaviors
and behavior is a loosely level term
across this entire industry but again a
behavior why is Mary in sales using
PowerShell in the first place that's a
good baseline that's a good behavior
right
why is red Jessica r32 bikini on to the
internet when it has it before in our
while in the wild ever before in the
past
those are great behaviors in your
environment things that you can count on
to look for things again
is it gonna generate false positive
absolutely can't we minimize those false
positives in baseline environment sure
you know do we need people to do that
yes I already said that earlier today so
those are some of the things that we'd
be focused on a good example of a
behavior as I was going into a company
doing a threat hunting exercise and it
was one of those engagements where the
first minute you sit down like I got it
I got him I got a good one and it was an
exchange server running as a system
account on exchange sure which also
happen to be a DC it wasn't exposed to
Internet thank God that was one
interesting piece about there but it's
also DC and the best part about it was
they had a PowerShell script that was
going every every night at 2:00 o'clock
in the morning going to China and
downloading a binary directly into
memory through PowerShell right non code
sign all other good stuff right and I'm
like I sit then I see this attack and
I'm like I just made my money for this
one I'm good I got a PT in here you know
I got some I got some hackers you know
we're gonna dive into this everything's
fine not like you know go to the
customer I'm like hey I hate to be the
bearer bad
but you're breech like really bad like
domain controllers and command and
control and also their stuff
and it's like oh my gosh and it starts
bringing up this instant response team
we start looking at it and it turns out
they have a third-party marketing
company does metrics offer the exchanged
performance it's out of China that
downloads unquote signed binaries at two
o'clock in the morning apparently and
it's perfectly legitimate that's fine
IDC hey HCP as well which is even better
you know it's like it's like literally
every step of the way right and it's
like they're using attacker techniques
or code is IP skated you're leveraging
and voc expression to go and download
code record from Internet all great
stuff right so these are things that we
typically see an environment where like
hey I found something that's a behavior
I'd want to know that that behaviors
there but I can baseline and look for
other things in our environment right so
visibility becomes critical I'm going to
show you an example here in just a
second of getting around visibility or a
lot of the traditional protection
mechanisms that we have but protection
takes time and and the biggest piece
that you can walk away out here with is
that while protection takes time we can
augment things with detection to get
better and faster what we're doing a
good example is when that DD OTO came
out a couple years ago right I mean
remember that DD OTO came out as a way
to get remote code execution if Excel
files about macros right and so with
that Microsoft said at the time they
work in a patch they eventually end up
doing it based on the damage and crits
here it had with DD auto it was being
used in the wild within seven hours
seven hours we saw ransomware campaigns
hitting it could you implement changes
in your environment within seven hours
across your entire organization probably
not right but can we detect certain
things in our environment than seven
hours probably we're getting the right
sources of information right so again
detection becomes much faster much more
nimble we still focus on protection
because we're not giving up on that we
still need to focus on those detection
pieces and being faster some quick brief
statistics this is over binary defense
we analyzed a bunch of code code
execution samples and what we found is
that 82 percent I said 84 I apologize I
got this that wrong I did get the
numbers wrong being it 82% are
executables so still to this day a
choose executables 13% is PowerShell 4%
is living off the land by owners and
scripts so living off the lands very
small number the one that most companies
are probably trying to focus the most on
when they're not even getting PowerShell
logs not focusing on
allowing executables in their user
directories and again our priorities
become completely skewed and different
lets customer data aggregated our EDR
pieces for it and then we and our sim
pieces for correct things that actually
made it ten points yep some breakout
time frames on average it took about an
hour and a half almost two hours to
break out of a specific system so when a
machine becomes compromised what happens
from there you know how do they move out
and spray laterally across the
environments about an hour and a half so
us as defenders we have about an hour
and a half time frame to respond to that
specific incident and then go from there
right here's the thing if an attacker
customizes anything anything at all they
typically go undetected and what I mean
by by that is our reliance on tools and
technology those tools themselves
typically go on notice now where I get
busted it's not from a tool I get bust
it is from people and so every time I go
into an organization we already know how
to get past the CDR product and this
antivirus product and this specific
protection mechanism you know exactly
what we're doing
when we get tripped up it's by people
doing creative things we're looking at
unusual behavior customized stuff works
take a technique modify it anyway again
to the three carrots versus two carrots
throwing seven carats thrown done
carrots you can highly a piece key
attend carrots I'm telling you I am
you'll read the code at that boy oh you
know what to do with time carrots that's
some G stuff right there build your own
bait detection for sure right a good
example of this is I wrote a tool in
2011 note started 2013 and it was a
simple command and control
infrastructure that uses HTTP and an
advanced encryption standard to
communicate over and was a bike compiled
Python program okay and it was
downloaded over a million times the
trusted second what it would do is it
wash a shell over HTTP or https over AES
and allow you to communicate back and
forth I uploaded the virus soldiers to
kind of take a look at how it get
attacked because you know unquote signed
binary malicious is all hack been
downloaded a million times in the wild
and three out of the 67 or so actually
detected as malicious which I thought
was pretty amazing
um so again you have to customize
anything just use what was already a
available out there to me today just
kind of obscure let's do a demonstration
real quick now I'm gonna show you a
video and I'm gonna do it live so here's
an example of let me get the play button
if I can find my mouse again no I'm uh
supposed to have sound on that hang on
there we go okay so we're gonna run
unicorn and now I'm gonna do is I'm you
something out of the box meterpreter
Metasploit okay and Metasploit is very
commoditized would you see a lot of
folks use it so you know if you just
take it out the box it'll get detected
by antivirus or something else we're
gonna have a call back to 172 16 2 2 1
at 171 up 43 we're gonna go ahead and
just decode it really quick you'll see
the code here in a second I'm just gonna
decode the values here ly fast and I'm
gonna get the raw code that's gonna be
executing the system and what's gonna be
seen by a Messire the anti-malware scan
interface run it here's the code
it's obfuscated and of course now we're
gonna go and paste this over to the
powershell interpreter over here on the
right hand side we're also gonna start a
listener for Metasploit as well at the
same time so that we have something to
catch our shell in the event that were
successful so over here you can see we
have our partial interpreter and we're
gonna run MSF console and over here
gonna hit play
oh no it's kind of blurry buddy but we
got stopped by a Maasai the anti-malware
scan interface blocked us and it's it's
a virus what we're gonna do here it's
really quick is we're gonna take a look
and say whoa I wonder what part of the
code is actually getting detected by
antivirus okay let's go and run that so
I just cut that out and I hit play well
ok it doesn't get picked up and apart so
the last line of my code is getting
picked up by in averse so man must be a
really good detection I'm sure what if I
create a variable let's copy that line
and paste it it can't be that easy
yep it is so so funny story Bob does you
get your shot anything else is great
right funny story about this one
specifically is that unicorn went for
years undetected years and years and
years and make something to get more
popular and they started writing
antivirus signatures for okay and it
became a battle between Microsoft and
myself I'm sure I have horrible horrible
names being called on me over there any
great folks are there by the way I love
everything they're doing in there
getting better but when the funny parts
was is that they started writing
signatures for defender every single
week so I got upset and one week I
decided I'm like you know what I'm gonna
spend a week and write a program that
does all this for me automatically and
so what it would do is it would go and
check out the latest defender signatures
it would check to see if it got hit by
antivirus if it got hit by antivirus it
automatically rewrite the code for me I
wrote a PowerShell interpreter for
Python in it it would rewrite for me it
would do had integrated into get lab
checks so we've built and passed make
sure I got a shell back and everything I
oughta made my whole framework and it'll
automatically do a pull request for me
to see whether or not it got past it so
within about 30 seconds of a new
signature being released I already had a
bypass already up on github I'm gonna
need it so that went out for like two
months and they finally gave up this is
pretty good feel bad for the folks out
writing that by the way I mean that is
suck so here's a version I'll show you a
funny thing here some quirks sometimes
it works sometimes it doesn't but let me
show you an example here you got me
running the latest and greatest
I got a listener up here right now I'm
sure my IP didn't change over the course
of talking here which has happened
before
go ahead play we're gonna run our code
out of unicorn I notice here I got a
virus threat protection found right got
busted whatever is if I hit play again
it works no dia just to prove that I'm
not not crazy here we're on that box so
so just run your coat twice and you're
fine I don't understand what's going on
here anymore
you could also circumvent this by if you
do something like couple examples so I
run this code here this is the decoded
code you just take these this dis Bob
here which is all your shellcode and
just replace it with instead of using
like symbols you just replace it with
numeric values like like five five five
five five it also circumvents all the
detection rights here up there as well
again really hard stuff okay to do makes
me lose sleep at night Oh another funny
quirk about that I was testing unicorn
one time and I'd run a command and then
run another command and then it was for
some reason who'd be like this is being
blocked by Hannover stone would work
well my second one my third one fourth
one wouldn't work and then I realized
there was a bug in defender where if you
submitted something in PowerShell from
the command line if for some reason
their their logic layer started marking
every single command as malicious so if
you did like a equals one it like you're
being blocked by antivirus equals to
being Wi-Fi antivirus you have to
restart your computer to get rid of that
that's a big bug that they actually
ended up fixing which is good so that's
kind of all over the place I'm not sure
exactly what's going on over there
Oh still in the
there we go so number five leadership
people leadership and communication is
extremely important where I see most
programs fail as not having the right
leadership in place and what I mean by
that is when I was I was the chief
security officer for Diebold for a
number of years and when I got the
Diebold there's actually a great talk
over at Derby Con this year that I gave
him and my CIO came and one of the two
of the folks that I work with on a
security team came we all talked about
how we were successful at our company
and what was interesting is that the CIO
and me were best friends and we worked
together to do what was right for that
company and no matter what it was and
whether it was hey you're being too
crazy on security well Duke it out and
figure it out in the parking lot you
know we're just friends trying to figure
things out in the right way of doing
things and we got more accomplished in
three years than I've seen any other
program moving in five or ten and a lot
of that had to do with my first became
the chief security officer over a
Diebold what did i do that i repel
technology no did I go and I hire a
whole bunch of people no I wouldn't I
bought a whole bunch of beer and pizza
for the IT folks like like a whole bunch
of times and because I became friends
with them like hey I have your back you
have mine one of the funny stories that
I had with Diebold is that at the time
we were looking at implementing scan
safe which was it got acquired by Cisco
and scan see was a phenomenal product
the way that they did at the time is
they had these things called beacon
servers and you could basically proxy
chain your beacon servers so that you
didn't go out 18 four four three across
your environment anymore okay so my goal
was to disallow all egress ports period
and only allow 18 for for three four
specific exceptions and 21 for specific
exceptions across our entire global
enterprise ok it's pretty awesome peak
right no egress ports whatsoever and 84
for 3 completely gone across the entire
network you can't egress out 84 for 3
unless you go out through the proxy and
then hit with scan safe which is SSL
termination and everything else we had
good visibility into and so I had this
project where it should take a normal
company probably what a year to
implement something like that right
across your globe maybe six months did
in three weeks and the way that I did it
is as I tried to find a a we were a big
ITIL shop okay and I found a change
control request that had to do something
with like tweaking this can save server
and I'm like hey mark and Marcos in
and networking he's like I'm like hey
man I'm like can you uh can you just
make this one rule I think I got
everything done but quemic this one rule
we are blocking 84 for three across the
entire company and he's like man I think
that's a good idea you're gonna break
some stuff I'm like it's okay there's
this there's this change control thing
here that that you know is kind of like
that it kind of sounds like it so he can
just tuck underneath there and see if it
works and he's like nah man I'm not
gonna do it so I went to when it's a
Scott there's a guy next to him like hey
man can you get Haiti for four three two
cross the network and it's kind of like
he's like you say I think it's a good
idea and I'm like listen you're getting
trouble I'll take all the blame for it
okay and so we ended up doing this
sweeping change across our entire
company within three weeks and broke our
entire production instances of where
they produced a TMZ because they used
these signing to sign the actual boards
for each ATM and stop production of all
our manufacturing facilities for both of
those like I was like poor horse wasn't
a big deal but but good enough we didn't
get in any trouble whatsoever because it
was a specific change we're trying to
accomplish across our entire environment
and so you know funny stories like that
a story after story to store we had a
customer application where I
accidentally found on blind sequel
injection and and I overrode everybody's
password the same one on accident and
completely crash the application yeah so
you learn you're right Oz and I was
younger and younger Dave younger Dave
but the piece I wanted to hit with this
and then the leadership piece was like
the folks that I worked with knew that I
had their back no matter what if they
messed up or if I messed up we had each
other's backs no matter what I would go
to bat for them I would make sure that
they had the right resources to be able
to accomplish what they needed to do
leadership is really really important
people is really really important to
have people to go and do things to help
you out communication is really really
important I didn't just go and do things
and just like hey I'm gonna shut this
down and that's that I worked with
people and communicating this those
specific things with why we're doing
things to an organization well then I'll
say is that if you can't make a change
in a company move on i time and time
again i go to a person or organization
like man we really want to come in
because i want you to smash our entire
company because our IT folks are just
won't do anything we're doing and I'm
the only person in security and they
don't want to do anything we have
100,000 people and there's one person
that a key to the security you know this
is this is you know my struggle every
single day
I'm just fighting fires every day and I
can't do it anymore if you can't make a
change in a company that you're working
with it's time to move on move to a
place that will make a change move to a
company that wants to change in the way
to get better for information security
and I'm a huge advocate of that you if
you're at a place where you're no longer
feeling effective or you've already done
your job you've already left your legacy
on to that's--that's is that into that
organization go somewhere else and do it
again it's awesome it's exciting it's
fun it's exhilarating you do new things
you get to figure things out in a
different way
all those things become really really
important so I'm closing the five things
right I talked about what I talked about
I remember sharing a collaboration right
leadership and communication behavior
right what was the other one I press the
other one the basics there we go the
basics that I was looking for the basics
all of those things make up what we are
today insecurity and and it's really
easy to get sucked into hey I need to
start going off these living off the
land by owners and scripts and blocking
all this stuff when we still have half
or one out there focusing on the basics
becomes really really important in your
environment collaborating with people
becomes really really important what are
you doing I thought I was getting
smirnoff ice here for a second so I say
you know what's really awesome is is
events like this like b-sides is amazing
when he's like hey can you come out here
and speak at b-sides I make sure what's
the date let me make sure it works not
fly on a plane come on here in two
seconds you know it's amazing that we
have a community of people that want to
share their experiences that want to
work together to collectively make the
world a better place and that's exactly
what we're doing so you know we're
working together figuring things out
we're making things better and I could
say again I've been in this industry for
a long time it's like 18 years which is
really friggin weird that I have been in
this industry for 18 years 19 years
2000-2001 got into the security space 19
years almost 20 years which is horrible
I mean I'm not getting old you know 20
years in one individual industry and I
can say over the span of 20 years we've
gotten so much better as an industry
working in case you need to do that
again and see your point earlier in your
presentation you know paving the way for
our next generation of kids getting out
of the way and stop being that that
person's like hey you need to you know
build your own cat5 cables in order to
get a job here
you know things
changed quite a bit in 20 years it's no
longer on mudding days anymore it's no
longer you know modems and BBS is you
know we're doing things in a different
way that we had before and it's better
it's not it's just better I love all
these showstoppers when the cloud came
like we were gonna stop in the first
place really or even even waterfall like
we're not gonna eventually go to agile
to get stuff out faster like hey what
you're saying is that I can get all my
stuff out way faster and I'd have to
hire anymore resources yeah but it's
gonna be a whole bunch of bugs in it but
Han you said I can get it out faster and
get some across yeah but it's gonna be
security holes no what you said is it's
gonna be out faster like that was gonna
stop a business right or a cloud hey we
don't have to hire all IT folks which by
the way best thing ever right hey you
get to move to the cloud you have to
worry about IT folks you'll have to
worry about you know scalability of
everything is that true no cetera in
fact I would say are the past nine
engagements that I've done going after
our cloud environment I've broken into
every single nine one of those cloud
environments based on configuration
issues so again doesn't mean necessarily
better anyways we're all working
together to come together to get better
what we're doing and so let's continue
to make the world a safer place in
security I think we're all doing that
right now
share your experiences figure out what
makes you unique and and share those
experiences here great on stage and
start talking about this so that's what
makes us an amazing collaborative
industry and it's just going to continue
to grow as it is and just want to give a
special shout out to Jack Daniel over
there for all the stuff he does for
b-sides let's give a round of applause
that is an incredible man right there
one that I've gotten to known or the
many years and Jack probably didn't even
know the story about when I first got
introduced to Jack Daniel if he goes at
shmoocon two or three Jack was out
ranting and raving about something
cybersecurity at the UH Nepal security
weekly podcast on the outside area there
and I was like man this guy's really
really smart and I just sat down and
listened to him and since then I've been
a follower of Jack for was we've gone
through what do we got now I don't even
know it's been lots
I guess that we're getting old so you
know 15 years or whatnot so you know
it's incredible person over there so
again makes things again Jack for all
you do so thank you all very much for
coming out to my talk I hope you learned
something new
you know remember three carats
completely bypass anything else out
there you're all set but I think you all
very much besides appreciate
[Applause]