I know and I'm Sophia today
this is coronal Panthers - war Dolan in
2019 and since is years besides phim it
is quite the journeys into in Passaic
before I try and incorporate a little
bit of my journey pip into the
presentations so that we could hear
about that story Tamar said I have to
use my phone because my computer's not
cooperating for slightly - excuse me if
I'm not looking down all the time yeah
if you rip my body minor from Brampton
but not originally from here though
Brittany from England I went to high
school of the equivalent of high school
primary school over there
and finished there and there was this
all the time whereas finishing up with
my Jam's you get kind of two weeks of
school or a couple months to do your
exams where my parents allegedly moved
so I was living there on my own with my
sister and my uncle and it was a really
awkward time because everybody was kind
of growing up getting ready to go to
college so I decided that I'm going to
mess around on the Internet all right so
that's that's really did I eventually
time came and moved over
and there was a number over time because
being an out-of-state College is very
expensive and we didn't have a whole lot
of money
we have been nine years gonna go to
community college so it's originally
actually gonna go and be a carpenter I
found out real quick that I didn't want
to do that once to get here and it's
very hot and carpet draining you know
there's a little bit different than it
is here here it's back in there wasn't
two-by-fours of making houses over there
it's more of a skilled like cabinetry
and stuff so for what am I going to do
maybe it can be an electrician quickly
found out that I could not be an
electrician because I'm not very good at
math same as a realtor and it's a very
electrical engineering just didn't do it
you know I spend a lot of time in
computers maybe I can get a job I've
done some AOL stuff like changing the
colors of my profile that kind of thing
makes misplacing webpages I'm gonna see
if maybe a good job doing computer
programming so I'll go for computer
program it wasn't really the same
programs at Community College back then
around the 2000s as there is now now you
can you can do some type of security
right out community colleges is pretty
awesome so I chose even computer science
programming or I forget the oval but I
chose programming to the full you know
that's really cool
they came around the road this man and
the aroma room pretty much enroll me in
all of his classes he was a Vietnam
veteran still friends of him to this day
dearly
they helped me out and got me a job in
the college and everything so that was
that was pretty cool on my appearance
the first week was said I was surrounded
by record of locals at the table because
I couldn't leave I couldn't technically
drive because I wasn't 18 yeah and I
didn't have my GED so I couldn't leave
college I get dropped off in the morning
we picked up whenever just like school I
was hearing by locals and they're all
kind of harassing me like you look from
around here where are you from and this
guy came and rescued me pulled me out of
the room or the room was outside but he
pulled me out off to the side and said
hey what's up what he did and we became
really good friends he'd drive me around
with party as much as he could and yeah
he he was an English major and he
introduced me to the library didn't
write him he introduced me to 2600 I
didn't understand any of this maybe you
do business super cool let's go to a
meeting so we went to I went to my first
2600 meeting right before the first
carolina club and they
what's the word they were very
enthusiastic about me presenting and
they pretty much talked me into a know
if it was me or them all those talked me
into presenting us and that was a
mistake for ya so that's pretty much
what happened with that and I did intend
to supply it but my first presentation
was pretty old voice on water and since
then I've been trying to improve my
presentation skills and kind of share
the knowledge whose people's there
that's the presentations I've done first
was in 2005 2010 I did done a lot of
Carolina content presented at Derby and
most recently difficult and the OS
charts on there because we're trying to
stop back up so if any of you are
interested web stuff huh next month so
that's just coming out so who here has a
telephone right I think I guess we don't
need to do raised hands everybody has a
telephone or who has telephony connected
devices zero know what Waldo Nia's I
mean it's pretty pretty straightforward
right
you can't really talk about it without
doing the classic clip let's see if it
plays this mouse is backwards where are
you
don't left help right go down there we
go so we're gonna have to try to play
this
you got there like that
well basically he's asking for the
prefixes per divisionist from the
marriages and I guess that's all about
social engineer right there he's doing
strike in the numbers
this is all old stuff raised you know
floppies and everything so you really
can't talk about watering without
sharing a clip from this movie connected
it's going on
this is protégés not happy now are these
thoughts darling now I'm going to get
back to the slides
so this is you know just be dealing with
we go up Commodore 64 software a haze
modem scanner and it basically
sequentially dial through a number
prefix in and it would go down one by
one very manual you have to babysit
those very basic so you get into and I
think this was 1984 copyright I'm sure
here it went through the trouble get a
copyright our gym where these war those
there's Commodore 64 and they can tell
the graphics again way better in these
let's see the next one I think is I mean
look at those graphics written by
riffraff in the Borgata this is the
description right of the web so as far
as hackers and orders go this one's a
pretty nice one so let's see well that
we have links now we get into more
modern more darling with that THC scan
the hackers choice das based you can
probably still download this and run
this today if you really wanted to I
don't see why you would there there's
commercial dollars this one still sold
to this day arm is very expensive I
think that
if you wanna die or 16 lines is about
$20,000 plus you need 16 items to go
with it plus phone lines that's owned by
Nixon they actually bought sandstorm
which helped the patent owners so they
still there I have not used this
software is very expensive but you can
tell from the algorithm system
requirements is pretty old a minute or
until entropy and the latest of
operating systems - any time I walk room
by the Beave front of had no telephone
believe it was to be able J Falcon
worked a lot miss to this one we get
more into modern war darling with white
blinds so this uses I accept all kind of
tactile things this one's you know we're
getting up there with this was released
about the same time that's war vote
which is probably the one everybody's
most familiar if you talk war dining now
HD more release this believe ten years
ago someone that uses is to which is
very similar to sit
there's reasons towards doing that and
it's written in Ruby says is the most
potent system now why do people watering
water in the past a lot of people did it
for discovery of devices I trying to
find BBS or names of people to talk to
and they may have done it for malicious
intent of pranks on their friends you
know others with malicious them may have
done it to find carrier networks things
in the background or voicemails for
there's been a lot of voicemail hacking
or others like dialing insane a so are
are are places so on the security side
people will also be more dying to make
sure their devices are secure great you
don't want to have a modem sitting out
there that just has a password or no
passwords so
why would you want to ward out now from
an asset management standpoint knowing
what you have connected to your network
is pretty important you can't secure you
don't know is there free organic growth
people may be adding devices to your
network you don't even know of or their
devices rates in varies by industry but
the number of employees that have
telephony connected devices pretty much
everybody but it's kind of far away with
mobile devices and things they're not
actually connected to the telephony
network but things like building
controls alarm systems and often
connected to telephone clients for
backup now the last one is the recent
fax machines of a multifunctional
printers and if anybody saw it was 2018
presentation done at DEFCON where they
were actually bridging into a network
and exploiting and I guess an internal
network externally through a fax machine
using the tunnel blue I can only imagine
that that kind of thing is going to
become more popular as more people
research these fantasies but see how I'm
doing on time
and the priority realities we my company
no longer work for has a huge inventory
side numbers we have think close to a
million phone numbers and asset in the
Tor asset management system that is less
than perfect was that I mean that's
pretty daunting thinking we got dial
every single number at least one so
potentially multiple times a quarter
right we have legal issues to deal with
drafters we're not bad guys very we have
to comply with the law both domestic law
and international or if we're dialing
overseas they're going to be careful
with that in the time restrictions we
come dialed down voice lines of people
will pick up or do business on during
the day time and then there's also the
time restrictions if we've got to get it
done right he can't just be darling at
number a minute for the rest register my
career my hands
we have some requirements wanted to be
pretty automated distributed
cost-effective to run all basically
cheap to run because nobody wants to pay
a ton of money to see what's going to do
the other side of the phone line and
given the current tool set early the
only choice was warlocks so if you want
to Ward out what do you need and how do
you start your first again right so
pretty much you're going to need an
inventory of targets you can't just dial
every number because there's laws
against there in your let's say 704
prefix so you can be hard work to run
asterisk unlikely and that's everyone's
on just about anything but if you doing
it up volume like you're trying to call
a million numbers you're going to want
to run it on some pretty beefy hardware
something a bit better than a Raspberry
Pi a toaster oven it could be internal
it could be external it doesn't matter
as long as it cannot talk to each other
it should be good a station pretty much
Romany things so I've had a lot of fun
running it on Debian with a Debian
stable just because it's all packaged
nicely in the context of goods then you
can need some service I thought well we
can just use plain out telephone wire to
do this from my home phone
yes you could possibly do that but you
probably shouldn't just compliance and
legal reasons and it's going to be slow
if your business is willing to pay for
playing on telephone service you could
do it I know what the cost amount all
about cellular for a wildly well let's
get ten I'm limited to tell vampires and
run it through they're probably going
against the Terms of Service and then
there's these other services that come
to mind when you think about making
cheaper phone calls they describe Twilio
et cetera this is I believe that
describes pricing and we're looking at
$2.99 a month for two thousand minutes
notice may work for some people if you
only need to make a mm cause 15
sentiment free box yes but when you're
talking about a million phone numbers so
on scoggs gonna be about 150 thousand
dollars after that if she's trying to do
in a month
Tullio home I think it's about 1,300
bucks for the first hundred thousand
which isn't too terrible and then about
the next nine hundred thousand tons
about twelve thousand dollars so kind of
hard to swallow if you've got the budget
to work so really I would go with a void
provider you can get some really good
deals on the transit fare and it's
pretty inexpensive you don't really pay
per minute but it's built to fractions
of a minute
that's what we use and we ended up
spending way less then I probably should
have said current state Warhawks starts
release mm what's that being is good at
so unsupported there is no scheduling it
has very limited reporting in it you
there's analysis there I tell you what
it is
voice voice mail fax modem dial tone but
it is limited you it's very you'd have
to use it to kind of see see what I mean
with that we've been working to
modernize it a little bit with jobs
being able to submit a job scheduled
jobs so that you can set the numbers you
want leave for work and it will start
whenever you specify that's pretty
important for me that I want to be
starting scans everything we've been
working on making an inventory of
targets II know what you want to dial
you put it in database and it picks out
from those every night so you can scan
them working on improving rewarding
that's a big one for us because I mean
there's no point in the scanning if you
can't have a good report and have
something to show for it so that's
probably the biggest thing
and update we could do is show some
value from from this other than the
automation because nobody wants to
babysit we're adding they'll be doing a
bunch of research into you adding device
fingerprinting so that's mostly for fax
machines I've modified a very old fact
sender to connect to a fax machine
graphic configuration parameters from it
and then hang up the line and then the
modem dialing in screenshots we're
turning into a modem taking a screenshot
once you're connected so we can quickly
go through and say okay these are all
password-protected and these are good
together so let's see we're about 20
minutes the results we have we went from
about 120 calls per hour so it's two
channels to everything over 500 and
we're able to scan it 20,000 numbers in
about 16 30 days so what we found
there's a bunch of stuff that does not
match the inventory modems whether not
supposed to be fax machines when they're
not supposed to be we have voicemails
where other fax machines are supposed to
be and some really odd find these where
there be a dial tone like your darlings
a number
it would just be a dog attack they might
be false positives
I can't reproduce it on all of them but
that's kind of alarming is there any
questions well what we presented today
if you want to get started into those
two resources the operative stuff is
probably your best bet I'm going to be
publishing all my changes I made to
github so everybody else can enjoy the
pleasures of all that that is about air
of thing no questions all right go on
so you
yeah we've the question was when you
wore them Sinn féin modems what was
hanging off of it there are a ton of
modems out there still connected
I don't know exactly what was behind
them but a lot of times it's building
controls IOT backup for alarm systems
what else was there environmental
control surgeries I mean there's also
like backup service lines in to take the
centers in case fiber good spot for up
maintenance there's some of the things
I'm aware of
I don't know why I was hanging on the
other end of of my my fighting days
anymore it's I guess I think everybody
should be if you're working in an
enterprise doing more dialing and seeing
what is on on the other side of your
telephone lines because they have we had
a huge effort as a while back before us
to go through a major with modems was
Hewlett with passwords but as we know
through IT work oftentimes stuff gets
rolled back from I guess changed up
dates get rolled back and we can't be
sure that there are moments hanging out
there don't have passwords or how do we
know the perimeter was the question I
like the telephony sorry so we have an
internal database right of all every
device connected to that in theory so
that's one way we know but there are
certain reports from your carriers so
say if you use the ATT Verizon on etc in
whatever every couple of years they're
required to do an audit on that and tell
you which phone numbers you have inserts
another way you can you can get
you have us because if you were about
time zoo Gemma
I thank you for a mere them give me
opportunity speak sir