stornes Bauer Staters and Enterprise
Services all right this is a very
interesting topic at least for me and
possibly for you which is why you're
here it's kind of the agenda would talk
about really kind of games with history
give some examples of actually put this
into use will kind of wrap up with some
other training free training in this
environment in which you can practice
some skills what happening but as we
started this is me I think what the DoD
for about 18 years really enjoy what I
do in that space technically director
for cyber operations center very much in
love with PowerShell you'll kind of see
that right throughout but so much so
that I'd like to develop tools in that
space weather is Blue Team Red Team what
have you and then also like to kind of
give that right because you're a Dave
talk about kind of how everybody gets to
start and I got my start because I'm I
took some time and kind of helped so as
we started talking about this we first
kind of have to define about right we're
talking about stages let's define
malware first right this may be a two TL
DR type thing so we'll kind of sum it up
and essentially we're talking about
malicious software that's designed to
infiltrate and do things to a machine
without actual consent right and that
the cordis would malware looks to do so
where did it really all begin well it
began roughly about 1971 with a
the Thomas who actually created the
creeper Fowler it really it wasn't
thought to be malicious at the time it
was really can I make this execute on
another machine through some type of
connection so at the time it was our
phonetic right so before there was
actual internet itself and then it
wasn't meant to be malicious in nature
and as such the replication or how would
propagate was really provide based upon
human interaction and then there was a
time in which somebody looked to make it
in a more brutal fashion and when she
could replicate on this home that's
where in my new to when we look at where
we're at today it warm red today
definitely more sophisticated than
anything else all right we have not word
is polymorphic we have this whole
cat-and-mouse game right you heard Dave
talk about adding the care of stores so
as a somebody of malicious intent is
developing malware and as a defender is
coming about and actually having that
malware and or criminal detectives to
defend against it the defender I'm sorry
to on this person is constantly looking
for new ways to really go and get around
them so it's a mouse game system and as
always going on but at the core now your
words burn to space in which this is
almost like a business where people are
backing individuals that develop say
about whether it's through financial
gain or whether it is through ingest the
equipment itself but you know while we
still have people who are lone Ranger's
if you will will get to the point of it
being an organized crime estate sponsor
who really started to change the game we
see that we're very rapid in his base
today
we look at the different types that are
out there now this isn't all-inclusive
but just kind of someone was that a
prevalence till the day I think viruses
it weren't those kind of go without
saying with ransomware in this space
right really really huge it's good to
the point where people are in portrayal
machine
encrypting to set files of folders or
just data period and then you're holding
them for ransom until somebody pays some
fee to never give those files back the
less that fee is being paid rootkits
have been the bank continued to be a
thing very very stealthy in danger all
right actually how I never really
difficult for what to do trojans
keyloggers adware really great weird but
cool others definitely make an a a ramp
up in this space as well and then when
we talk about really hiding our malware
or somebody trying to hide their malware
whether they have Packers so now they're
trying to compress the actual true
binary let's say it's some standalone
you know BG info or what have you
you're trying to compress that so they
can allow their malware to be wrapped
with it it will be self contained so
upon execution it starts to do its own
self extraction we have people using
critters so that way if the binary is
found whether it's an actual exe or DLL
it's some type of a form of encryption
or ex-ored applied to it so it's not as
easily pick table the whole polymorphic
aspect very stealthy in nature makes it
much more difficult for a defender to
actually find it why because it is
consistently changing this form of the
fashion from system or platform
and we get to the point we talk start
talking about stages and really this is
the basis for the sexual talk so stages
themselves right at the core of that
that's gonna allow us to learn a little
bit about the machine before we bring in
an actual real payload that we care
about and when we take the second to
really define stagers alright we're
talking about something known as a
dropper some people call them
downloaders right or effective as if you
will but at the core these are tiny and
major pieces of code that did shift or
package which are initial payload so
maybe we have some an exploit that's
going to be our initial access best our
moment vector on a machine rather didn't
bring the actual real payload in which
we care about not really understanding
the state of the machine whether a bee
is going to pick it up or maybe it's
some you know good defender that's going
to be able to highlight our stuff will
first put something lightweight on there
that's going to allow us to protect our
equities the very thing that we maybe
spend time money resources in developing
and if we essentially an allow our state
there to look around and figure out that
the coast is clear
that's really really great for us but
that state is going to allow the system
to initiate some connection back to our
c2 server or servers alright because we
will get a bound traffic typically that
goes a little bit more on notice did
somebody actually try to be get into
your regime but at the core lessons are
below if our toolset is found because
again this danger is going to be very
very small we'll look at a couple of
examples here and regardless of what
malware we're using it's going to be
expensive
we feed they're spent the time and money
on buying it or we spent the time and
resources and actually developing it so
our delivering that that kind of looks
something like so
have actual machine it gets exploitive
the stager may be attached with it
this is just an example it would always
be this case we have that stager on the
machine that stator didn't initiate some
communication or some type of traffic
back to our c2 server or a subset of
servers all right we may have it to
where it reaches out to a number of
servers so it's not static in nature
each time and it once it reaches out to
that machine that c2 server would have a
second set of instructions maybe go we
go surveyed the machine or give me this
type of data or execute this next
payload or just go to sleep for a period
of time and then reach back out to me
later on but at any rate typically that
next stage if not that first stage is
going to be encrypted
I want to be able to protect that data
and a communication most as possible but
that second part is really where we look
to see damn our whether it is a virus
whether it is a worm rootkit key logger
or what have you that's really where we
start to see that being done the common
test not only inclusive but generally
speaking before somebody maybe myself
invests a lot of time and effort into a
machine I want to know if that machine
is clear I want to know with what the
state of the machine is is some other
active there maybe the exploit that I
have the follow-on payload maybe it's
not susceptible on that machine so we
would look to probably surveyed a little
bit some babies are better than others
right what is the state of the machine
what does the environment like put it on
what that comes back is then our next
follow-on steps will be done quarterly
and in some cases we may look to start
terminating services in order to ensure
our equities are taken care of we want
to validate afford a virtual machine now
if the environment runs on nothing but a
virtualized infrastructure that this is
a goal point but in some cases us
writing the virtual machine could not
like that somebody's trying to conduct
some type of analysis on us and at the
core we can get execution of our payload
of our stager either through somebody
opening XQ or not it's people file could
be some web link could be just based
upon a number of conditions ie this
timeframe has hacked it now execute or
when a particular user logs on not
execute but we have the ability to
really hard code that it and have some
granularity into how a lie-in may
execute and not ever environment is
going to be the same some people will
look to follow some type of methodology
as far as trying to terminate this who's
heard of cyber kill chain okay cool
there's this is a framework much like a
few other ones but when we look at this
is broken down into reconnaissance
weaponization delivery instrumentation
you kind of see it there why people are
developed this back in 2011 and it's not
a bad framework I'm not going to say
which one is better than the next but as
long as you're following some framework
with some type of methodology that's
great it's linear so we're going to go
one stage after the other it really the
idea is to if you're defending is to get
ahead in which this may take place so we
know someone is going to do
reconnaissance and they're going to work
their way down if you start to see
something like reconnaissance or maybe
what organization that we're in a place
at which you can see it happening then
you may want to jump down one or two and
figure out how you can stop their
listing come on you don't want to follow
somebody down that same path
go because inevitably you're not going
to be able to catch up with it
but when we break this down a little bit
we look at reconnaissance front
perspective of somebody just trying to
gain an understanding of our
organization that could be as simple as
to what's published about this from a
open source perspective online things
that you know could be found out it
against this and some respect if you're
in this space the spouse significant
other parents cousins typically those
are most weakest links because you could
do everything your power to lock down
some of your social media and everything
else but some of your friends and family
may not believe in that same thought
process so people can leverage those
type of people to kind of gain some
information about you as well
and if we're totally from an
organization perspective not visible
online it kind of makes it a little bit
difficult for people to understand a
product or an e-commerce in which we're
trying to sell or use so from a
weaponization perspective after we've
gained enough knowledge from the
reconnaissance perspective and we're
going to look to craft or even some
cases the vulnerabilities against that
organization whether it be a zero-day
again maybe that's not the space you run
in but I'll tell you zero days are
almost equivalent to eight days in my
opinion all right because how often are
people that are run out the next day and
update their machines some organizations
maybe yes but there's still some
organizations running XP Tech I went to
an organization head server 2000 still
running all that infrastructure and let
them tell it it was a vital piece and
still as a vital piece from that
perspective we go down into the delivery
aspect and now we're trying to figure
out how we can actually get it on the
machine so we we've done some
reconnaissance
we've done some weaponization as far as
our payload or initial payload now we
just gotta get it actually to the
machine itself and
ease into the exploitation itself and
then from there we're trying to install
something now for the perspective of our
stager this is where we start to come in
we're trying to get our stager on a
machine we're trying to put it in a
subject place and which is not really
installed but it's definitely there so
it can be called upon once we have that
executing that we actually are
communicating with our situ server or
servers from there we get to the point
of going after whatever our objectives
are but really the key piece that we're
going to focus on is really these two
things the installation of command and
control that is really the basis for
this talk right we've already assumed
you've done some reconnaissance
weaponization you've got it on the
system and now you're at a point where
you're actually just trying to get it
installed so you can reach back out to
your C to serve in way in which one
could do that is kind of like so it
would take the data it would convert it
to bytes then base64 and then store it
that's one way you could do this in
reverse order you could do one of them
all of them none of them it doesn't
matter right like there is no wrong way
to eat a Reese's there's really no wrong
way to do this unless the defender has
some type of device that's going to
highlight it but this is not a
one-size-fits-all thought process but
this is definitely a way and we've
already highlighted we're talking about
this from a post exploitation
perspective you're already on the
machine cool we need to figure out the
state of it or maybe the coast isn't
clear for us to lay down some type of
binary so from that perspective we are
going to take a file this approach again
our state there's going to be nothing
but some actual code that's going to run
out against something else for us the
good thing about it is is there when we
need so we don't have to keep going in
there and then
so for this presentation I'm gonna use
the what shovel out before us so I'm
going to utilize the power shell here
I'm going to reach out to a c2 server
that I'm gonna say is one or two one six
eight zero at one hundred right now I
have an on run over HTTP we can do HTTP
we're gonna do some manual it as well
but for a simplistic perspective that's
what we're doing now the next line
eventually converted into bytes and in
the third line I'm gonna switch it to
base64 and I'm gonna spit there base64
out to the screen my c2 server I'm gonna
call back on quad fours and in my
payload was going to be a stage or dat
ps1 I could just name it s or a right
this is the good thing about this
because ultimately this base64 encoded
string is what's going to be on the
system
somebody decodes that what do I lose I
lose that URL being an IP address domain
I lose that port and I lose whatever
that file name is now States at that ps1
couldn't say any way to a person that
this is a power show script goodness any
way that it is a stager so if we name is
something like a when a defender I'm
looking at it I don't know what it is or
what is this a I don't know it's
whatever is hosted there at the time so
at nine o'clock in the morning it could
be some text that changes your screen
blue at ten o'clock in the morning that
same file could change your text for it
so the good thing about it is is very
agile in the sense of what we can do
with it all right
we're just posting whatever we need at
the time and the place
all right so the first one we're going
to actually use is active directory
directory is a great enterprise service
it's going to provide some
authentication and authorization across
an enterprise if you're in the Windows
environment especially the domain
environment you're definitely going to
have at the directory the objects in
there are usually a rate in the sense of
users computers there's some rooms but
largely they're separated into
organizational units for simplicity the
database itself what we see word stored
system 32 in TDs and it's going to be
locked by default but no harm no foul
for us we're not trying to take it when
we look at the direct that week we see
something like so now every apartment is
going to be a little bit different in
this perspective on the left hand side
we have an East Coast
oh you followed by Boston oh you and
then we have some oh use under it with
into Boston oh you we see a number of
users some groups we see some
descriptions all this good stuff so this
is great this is typically how an admin
would actually administer at the
directory and we utilize this GUI some
people look to utilize it through
command line whether it be power show or
some other of their party tool from the
power show perspective we can see how
we're using an AV user and we're able to
get the same information from that to
directly now this is good because you
probably are in an organization been to
an organization in which there's people
who haven't worked there in some time
and they're kind of still there or
there's some service account who's
trying to log into a computer and
they're felling that authentication on a
day to day basis right maybe they have a
service account set up to perform some
service and the Machine no longer exists
or the password change or what have you
here is that this is a goldmine for us
so when we look at one individual object
we'll see something like the above here
and if I'm a power show perspective
we're seeing some of that same data the
interesting thing about Active Directory
is that there's roughly 50 properties
for us to actually use some of them have
science limitations that were cognizant
of that but the good thing about it is
by default domain users can read Active
Directory that's good seems like that
just need to get some code in there and
in no matter what machine and I'm trying
to have a point out my second part of my
code they'll be able to read their
property and then go out and execute
okay also now from the perspective of
what that really looks like we can
utilize so now up front when I was
talking about my stager my base64 code
will always be an encoded text for the
context of this this brief so I'm going
to utilize one of the three properties
that isn't shown by default is it shown
by default so if I were to go into the
gooey aspect of Active Directory I
wouldn't be able to see employee ID
employee number or division except for
with an attribute editor there's no
other place that is shown right there by
default wouldn't that have been cut that
on maybe right but again this is all
about being on my environment I say nine
times out of ten they would so I have
the ability where I'm going to call upon
the user in this case I'm gonna do big
shake and then I'm gonna set that 80
users division property with whatever
that base64 encode is again if they
wouldn't the natural be a deterrent be
able to see it now I could get a little
more stealthy in this and I can add an
actual property that big looks looks
like it makes sense with division and
push that down but for me simplistic
perspective
there now when I call upon it from the
command line we see it as below yeah
again I need somebody to go in an
attribute editor it's actually look at
that the fact is I would rather take my
chances with this because I don't
believe in end it's going to go on air
and do it nor what it is sent out to a
point in which they did would it be
something that causes concern for the
next one was the registry now that's my
favorite actually because I was up that
Microsoft and Charlotte actually like
two weeks ago and I was having this
conversation about the registry and
there's so many keys there's so many
values in the registry that I was
willing to make a bet a 50-cent bet that
there's no admin in a world who can tell
you about every key every value and
Windows machine all right there's just
so much stuff and with that plethora of
data that's there that seems like a good
place for somebody to stage your code in
my example I'm going to do one layer
deep but largely speaking we want to go
several layers deep so the registry is
really formed like so we have our
registry files on disk and then as we go
through a process either the Windows
system is self booting up or user log in
those highs on disk it loaded into
memory and then they become our actual
hklm or HKC you the things that were
customers seeing in the registry while
we're logged on while the person is long
gone those things are actually locked
and they're not editable by a user the
things that get loaded and where they
sit on disk are as follows so we have
Sam security software system default
those all get loaded into H tell them or
HK users and then we have the NT users
our data and in actual user class like
that those two sit in the users profile
and they get voted into current user if
I was logged on and we just did switch
user rather than my NT user that getting
unloaded I would then have my user hai
moved over to HK users
further perspective of the registry
though again I'm one layer deep so on
hklm software and I created a key I'm
sorry value called updater 32 because
frankly speaking if we had 32 or 64 onto
majority of everything in Windows most
people look at it but okay that looks
legit and then we've added our code here
again from a PowerShell perspective I'm
just adding a new item and I see it
there now if I get to the point where
maybe this is too loud then again I
would put in some patent to push it off
the screen make it into where it is it
would actually had the double-click and
open it and with my padding I would have
some other verbage up front one layer of
deep right now we'd go like four or five
layers it would be tough for admin to be
able to see it there it will talk about
some mitigation techniques though all
right we have event logs now the bit
bones are very interested from a good
perspective we have Event Viewer these
essentially provide some form of
notification detailed notification of
things happening on a system while the
event mode provides a lot of information
out the box a number of good injuries
need to be in able to use an oddity and
that's not really what we're here to
talk about what we're looking to do is
take advantage of the fact is good
places for our code will be really
anywhere that's cumbersome with a lot of
data that an admin can overlook and a
good thing here is this is a good place
so the bad thing about it is typically
these things are circular so as events
howl up the code that we have in there
could be overweight so really come back
this will look at make it our own but
when we talk about there's a lot of logs
in here we're talking to the tune of 386
ish just off of the server 2016 machine
alright so
that's a good place for us to be
particularly speaking if we could name
it in such a way at 32 or 64 or
something on it which could be bypassed
by an admin so I talked about making our
own event logs and the reason for that
is because if we look to put our stuff
in application or the firewall or one of
these other logs again our stuff may be
overwritten and essentially put off the
system when we put our stuff in our own
custom log and it wraps some other stuff
around it to make it look legit we stand
a chance to live in any event bugs a lot
so what we'll do is we'll create a new
event log I'm going to call it Windows
updater and I'm gonna create a source
the source is nothing more then you'll
see the top of the event log here where
it says updater 64 it's da identifier
for that actual log itself so we'll
write out to the event log R a coded
message so now I have my base 64 sitting
there I can go back at another time and
just make sure it's there and from there
I have the ability to read that file
call upon the message field and then
type into something that's going to
execute it again this contains my stager
that sticker was nothing more than a URL
wrapped in system that met that web
client no harm no foul of this gets
found I lose an IP address maybe a
domain I lose essentially bad right in
this case they see stated up on ps1 but
they don't have access to that file they
just see what I wouldn't be going out to
get now they could get a little you know
bicurious and go out there and try to
have any gate to my server we're not
really talking about how we're gonna
stop that which we would be able to
we're just more or less identify where
we can store this stuff so we can go
back and get stuff
later on we also have group policy from
policy is a little iffy but we looked at
group policy to self that's going to be
the hierarchical infrastructure that's
going to be used to implement specific
things whether it's probably miss
elation settings or just really any
other configuration that we could think
of from an enterprise perspective we
have policy management from a local
system perspective we have the actual
loop room policy itself does it really
matter which one we're going to use we
have the ability to store a code there
from a management perspective we're
going to utilize the description field
well there's a number of editable things
with a group policy that we can use the
last thing we want to do is put our code
in something that has some adverse
action on the box so we'll look to put
it in the actual comment field able to
do that we'll call upon our default
domain policy because I thought it's
going to be implemented everywhere and
then we're going to store our encoded
text and description now when we do that
I see it just at the bottom there and I
could comment normally I wouldn't care
as much but this is one of those things
that I feel like an admin would be in
group policy clicking around and it
would stand out so I'm not too keen
about leaving out there what I look to
do following this was to add in seven
new lines so what powers oh we're just
adding in new lines and then I want to
put my encoded text so I'll look to see
what that does for me and lo and behold
that actually pushes that code down okay
I'm on to something
seven new lines pushed it down so now I
look to do that a little bit more and in
this case ended up doing 20 when I do
that based upon the screen there's no
size that the user can make it in which
there they be able to see that however I
don't look
from a PowerShell perspective they call
upon it and in this case I have a
variable called retrieve I see that
blank space essentially those 20 new
lines and then I see my code this is a
good chance that I'm willing to take at
the moment not knowing who the admin is
nor do I know how they actually do their
job but I know one thing most admins are
not going to be using a command line to
to administer policy they're going to be
in group policy management or the local
group policy window itself and they
won't be able to see that to the screen
and then us will actually execute that
there's nothing more than calling upon
it and pass it into some type of
execution engine and on actually demo of
doing one of these at the end then we
have alternate data streams now what's
interesting about that is if you've been
in this space for a while you may be
saying well alternate data streams isn't
new I recognize that but it still works
all right so as long as it works we're
still going to use it now what maybe do
is that we're gonna put some malicious
code in here people hiding data in there
yeah it's been anything but when we look
at alternate data streams definitely
something as part of NTFS file system
was made as a cross compatibility for
Mac OS by default has a stream of dollar
sign data
also the dentist rooms also used by
Internet Explorer depending on if you
have your internet itself set up have
you ever downloaded something trying to
execute it it tells you hey this came
from the internet you shouldn't trust it
or what have you it's like well happy
you know that well there's an alternate
data stream associated with the causes
of the identifier and it has a tag Adir
telling you that the file came from the
Internet we can easily remove it we can
easily add some stuff to it that's
interesting so in this case we'll look
to make our own so we can actually get
around it now as we look at this I'm
going to get the metadata associated
with this item and it's called my file
all I did was make a blank file or empty
file and I see the link is 0 I'm gonna
write some green eggs and ham type stuff
to a alternate data stream that I called
my stream when I look at it it's going
to be $35.99 bytes but again the size of
the original file the host file itself
isn't altered so that's cool now I need
to figure out the place to put it and
wish this thing doesn't get overwritten
or messed with what on a local machine
then this is a good place right
it's hijos definitely not to be there
you're not going to touch it feel pretty
confident about this know the
environment won't dictate where is a
good place but as he host seems good for
me so I'm going to take that file that's
already there I'm gonna add content to
it and the content that I'm going to add
is a alternate data stream called secret
stream the thing I'm going to fill with
it is encoded text so for me to actually
see this I'm going to need either power
show or some other tool could be able to
see that all to the data stream in this
case at the bottom I'm going to go and
read that and I see my color
again this is nothing more than a stager
all right then we have the environment
variables all right these things are
dynamic in our environment and they're
really based upon the system itself so
when we had up here a while ago when
dirt we that was essentially a
environment variable and say you waited
we're out when those directory was on
that machine there is a number of them
there but it makes it to where you don't
have to hard code stuff in some people
would do the baseline installation when
it comes to windows other people install
windows on that say their D Drive so
Alton I'm sorry if our new variables
help us with that there's two types
there's going to be user specific and
then there's going to be system once
system one's a global nature going to
persist past reboots so this seems like
an awesome place for us to put things in
so we can go back and grab them later on
the way we would do that is like so
we'll create a new environment variable
I'm going to call it program common
program W 64y because there's already a
common program W there okay so I put 64
next to it most people will say this
legit and keep going about their
business
so we'll store it in our deucer run
space first and then the second line is
us doing it from a system-wide
perspective the reason why we're going
to put in our user space first is
because what we add the system-wide one
it doesn't kick in or take effect until
we reboot the box so I don't want to
affect
whatever system I'm on but I do want to
be able to get after the task I'm using
right now so when we do this we had
something like so we have it being
written to the registry we have to be
written to the actual environment drive
within PowerShell and what we wouldn't
looked at our system variables like
right clicking computer properties we
see in there now I'm not concerned what
people looking at it for PowerShell
that's a one-off skill or one-off thing
that people would actually use that
necessarily looked worried about people
looking at it from the registry I don't
see evidence doing that too often if
anything and it may look there if
anything so we'll look to push that off
so and the way we will look to do that
is kind of like what we did before with
some padding instead of doing new lines
we'll just add some padding to up front
in this case that it was like seven or
eight spaces that we had in there we're
doing a little bit more and now we've
totally pushed it off the screen again
if I was concerned about somebody
double-clicking it they would be able to
see it but if I'm concerned about that I
can add some text in there maybe I could
see one of those something right and in
a number of padded characters just a
push to rest up it off the screen and
then when we call upon this key we can
get rid of the fake text and the padding
and then executed but from this
perspective we have the ability to
actually store this on our system
and the full code looks like so so that
very first line we have a space and then
we're going to Pat it with 116 of them
and then we're going to add in our
encoded text and it would just continue
at all like we've created it before
all right and then we have WMI and sim
so when those management instrumentation
and then common information model WMI
was Microsoft's response to w bill all
right so it's gonna be the whole web
based enterprise management aspect which
was really a initiative to get after how
do we share information amongst the
system and a number of the system so
Microsoft's implementation event is w
online W Maya has been around for a long
time we're talking about roughly 1990s
and it was made available within
PowerShell up until version 2 with
version 3 Arkansas has done away with
that and they've come out with the
common information model I also work
when we start talking about modern
version of Windows modern version of
power shelves that's the method in which
they're going forth with WM I assume it
utilizes a number of classes and
namespaces largely these things are way
too large for an end to be able to
understand but nonetheless we'll dive a
little bit deeper to these namespaces of
organizations of classes themselves so
let's say we had 130 to process for
example that allows us to get running
processes off of a machine and then that
itself as a class would fall under some
type of namespace
maybe that namespace would have
processes services the ability to read
environment variables or a number of
other things so namespaces are
essentially buckets and in the classes
themselves actually allow us to get the
information the class
so they have properties and methods so
when we look at properties those are
going to be essentially attributes about
something and when we look at methods
those are going to be actions that we
can take so this is all kind of
interesting because we can utilize that
your lie and really sim to get after our
task of finding a place to store our
code and we're going to do that outside
of what they already have we're going to
make our own because if we make our own
there's no signature for it but
depending on our machine the number of
these classes kind of they swing in a
sense of number on the machine that I
was on to think this wasn't Windows 10 I
did this on
I had roughly 10,000 classes roughly
10,000 right
that's huge these classes are made
available based upon what type of
software we have we'll install it on the
machine but let's be real 10000 like
that that's going to be difficult for a
admin to transfer they don't want to get
after it another way and we're going to
do that is when I walk through so I got
a machine here
okay cool so I have a website that is
being hosted by PowerShell it's nothing
more than a a simple web server so if
you're used to Python if you've heard of
simple HTTP server the same thing in
PowerShell and it's literally roughly 18
lines so oh you know seeing in this
okay now you see cool so we're talking
roughly eighteen lines makes up this web
show
interesting about this I will shut up
this website is it serves up everything
that's on my actual desktop so we can
come in here and from a command line
perspective
we'll just see if we can interact with
the website and we can so the very thing
that we call it upon stated ps1 if you
look at the third line under was being
returned it has a comm object which it's
going to spit out a by the text form if
you will right by the pop up box in this
case is just a pop up box but you could
really host whatever you want all right
it could be another piece of code that
is called upon another site to download
something the good thing about how we're
doing is is that that script that we're
downloading at stay for that ps1 never
touches this system the contents of it
are downloaded and stored in memory all
right for the context of wishes
processes write it in so the Pentagon
would type of ap we may have this spent
a high chance of not being caught all
right because I would expect my Navy to
catch anything that I put on my disk
malicious with anything not maybe not so
much so I'm going to create a new class
called 132 defend 64 it does not exist
and the way we do that is we're going to
create a new object and then we're going
to actually save it cool so I have a new
class that I'm gonna call when 32 61 230
to defend 64 from there I'm going to
create a new property and as you will
call the properties were nothing more
than attributes so I'm going to call
this property my property I'll store
there just a string and it's going to be
you know just a simple test to see if I
can actually write that to it I'll go
back and verify that it's there and we
can see down below the second line there
it says value this is just a test to see
if data could be stored
okay awesome so David can't be stored
I'm going to go back through and take my
stagers drink and now I'm going to start
the process of converting it to base64
so I can save it but as such I just have
my strengths cool
so then we'll convert it to bytes will
convert it to base64 and then we'll
verify that it's there and this is what
I'm stored on disk so very mental if we
see that this amount of characters is
what's rendered would just add strength
imagine if we were trying to put a
binary imagine if that binary cost us
some money right maybe it was through
man-hours of development maybe we pushed
purchased it from some other type of
organization but nonetheless let's think
about the cost associated with it
so I'm going to create another property
I'll call it pad and then I'll store it
near my actual base64 code and then when
I go back to actually look at it I see
my base64 code I also see that strength
up top that we call it boner earlier so
now it's sitting here I can restart the
box I can go about my very married
business I can come back to one flater
and I can utilize this code as here so
long as this box doesn't get we start
that we started we formatted or gone
offline I have it there for as long as I
need you
when it's time for me to actually run it
I can call upon it like so verifying
that's there and then we can actually
execute it in this case is just a pop-up
box again maybe it's a next stage
downloader where it goes out to my site
and instead of pulling back this little
pop-up box it pulls down a binary maybe
I tell it to survey the system telling
me you know what users log on was to
architecture was to help the status as
far as how often they updated maybe I
tell it to execute a key logger for a
period of time and it bring that
information back really the
opportunities D the things that we could
be worth endless and I don't even have
to change the name of this so right now
it's danger got ps1 but on my c2 server
I can just open that up put some other
stuff in there and then the next time it
comes to reach back and grab it it
executes stat so it's very dynamic and
modular in that perspective
now about the first person that dick
about stagers all right so as we look at
1971 with the creeper bow where to where
we're at now there's a lot of people in
between more so in the last 10 years
that really have jumped on this where we
see a number of threat sets that are
starting to use multi stage or a stage
malware and from my perspective I think
it's more common than what we believe
right but we see people using proxies
I'm in order to retrieve additional
payloads why because the malware which
they want to lay on that system too
costly for them to go out there and just
do it from the beginning we have them
utilizing that payload or really Dennis
danger to understand the Machine we see
that's where backspace does again why
would I take time to to install or lay
down something that we've spent a lot of
time and money on just to have it set up
by some type of heavy burners and then
we see stuff like muddy water all right
muddy water at the bottom it utilizes it
so they can download the numeration
scripts to better understand the machine
before it goes on now nothing in life
comes without you know some good and bad
in this case we have some pros very
lightweight you see that that was
essentially a one-liner of sorts I can
wrap that whole on delivery perspective
a bolide machine good tactical machine
and it really all I'm putting on target
is actual base64 itself very low equity
what do I lose if that gets caught
nothing
it's modular so I can change that code
at any time then we could host it
wherever we want now some of the cons in
this is depending on the visibility of
that effort
it could be very visible that we're
going out and downloading stuff also it
may spike or really present to somebody
that we're doing something nefarious if
they're unfamiliar with the sites at
which we're gonna downloaded from and
then if our stager becomes blocked or
really an RC 2 server becomes blocked at
any time then we kind of lose visibility
and the ability to affect anything on
there so some mitigation techniques well
least privileged you heard Dave talk
about segmentation and isolation
absolutely application whitelisting
definitely difficult to actually do time
intensive but man I tell you probably
provides the most bang for a buck as far
as reward and in detection you can't
detect what you don't have so if you're
not logging you're already losing and
then from a proactive perspective
they're inducing thread honey and some
analysis well we're not infiltrated I
don't see anything well that's because
you're not looking hard enough for the
people who's in your network are very
quired
but at the end of the day there's a
couple ways to get around it now as I
started to wrap up here all right you
see we use PowerShell very heavily well
I run two PowerShell training sites one
is called under the water under the wire
I've seen a lot of 70,000 people since
roughly players from 78 ofthe 193 issue
countries and essentially under no wire
allows you to SSH into a Windows
environment will present you what they
task and then whatever the answer is to
that task becomes the password to the
next user and you're essentially going
about the game of that matter
this design to give people access to a
power show interact the PowerShell
environment and to provide training it's
all free all right it is linear in
nature and we're talking about roughly
75 challenges now if that's not
difficult enough for you as we talk
about the whole purple team Blue Team
Red Team well then we have Tosh hunter
Tosh unders roughly 90 challenges that
allows you to from a situation scenario
based perspective go through and utilize
PowerShell to answer particular
questions
one minute you're some blue team guy and
the sock the next minute you're some red
team guy on some engagement but
nonetheless all you have is PowerShell
don't get to see how people were using
it from a day-to-day perspective you'll
get to gain more familiarity with it and
take it back to your environment which
is what I think anybody and everybody
would like to have so with that that
brings us to the end I'll pause for any
questions there's some information about
me if you want to keep in touch or any
that type of stuff this presentation is
that that site if you're interested all
right awesome