alright alright thanks for having me
today
my name is Jeremy Durand and I was going
to talk a little bit today about
password analysis and how we can use
that information to help us when we're
trying to crack passwords and so my day
job is penetration testing I worked for
a large company in Kentucky and also
owned ellipsis information security
where I try to provide pen testing
services for small businesses that can't
normally hire some of the bigger
companies to do that sort of thing and
teach a little bit for sans and also
work on a project called Mattila day -
it's actually started by Adrian number
of years ago and I try to keep that
going so today a 1 to first define what
password patterns are and how to do the
analysis on them and then talk about
some of the things I learned when I was
looking into those and then using those
to try to do automated password cracking
so start out with wrote some software to
help out and there's two modules the
project overall is bypass and then
there's the past time module in the
actual bypass module and past time does
the analysis and it figures out what the
password masks are and their popularity
and as we'll see the popularity is very
important because where you call like
the Pareto rule or 90/10 rule 8020 rule
what you'll find is that the applying
the right mask is critical to getting
the fastest results back bypass actually
uses information from past time and it
tries to figure out what the password
masks are and then automatically apply
those to password cracking so to start
off with when we talk about password
patterns where we're talking about
whether it's all letters or it starts
with an uppercase followed by a few
lowercase than a number those are the
patterns and we use these symbols to
represent the pattern so Lu for lower
and uppercase respectively D for digit
is one of the symbols and then a is any
character at all if you look in popular
password cracking programs like John the
Ripper and hash cat they have other
symbols as well that are important
things like W means a word out of a
dictionary and things like that but this
is the basic idea so in the example here
capital P pass one exclamation is ull D
s so to measure the patterns you use
pastime and it just has a few commands
fairly straightforward to run and
there's a couple examples down here at
the bottom the main thing is either you
want to list the masks or you want to
analyze the password so the list mass
feature is typically used by bypass it
wants to know what the masks are that it
needs to use to try to crack the analyze
password is more for people who are
trying to understand the passwords that
they have in front of them so these are
passwords that have already been cracked
and you're analyzing them to try to
understand what patterns did people use
when they were choosing these passwords
so the some of the test files I took was
mainly from ronbo site and then I got a
couple of others as well like rocky and
so I picked these ones here because they
had a really wide distribution between
the number of passwords
I think the Facebook fish may had like
55 passwords all the way up to the PHP
BB had you know hundred thousand two
hundred thousand in it so it was a
pretty good set
all right so to do the analysis after
you get the project off github basically
what you end up doing is is just run the
commands like they were specified so a
is for analyze and L is going to show us
a list of the patterns the dash p is
percent that one can be a little bit
confusing but it's a decimal
representing the percent of passwords
that the mass represent so in this
example here for ph-phoebe up put in
twenty five percent and so if I do the
analysis on it
there's a hundred eighty four thousand
passwords in the set oh sorry about that
alright let's see
alright alright any ideas Adrian yeah
okay just mirror it got it
alright sorry about that delay
cool thanks Bill all right it's gonna
say just build me awesome all right
thank you
so Randy analysis on the PHP BB in this
case and so first let's compare what
happens if you don't put in the percent
so I'll just basically just kind of let
it rip and on all of them so there's all
the password mass that's actually
scrolls up a few screens that represent
the passwords in this set and they're
just there's tons and tons of them not
even sure how many thousands there are
probably in the hundreds of thousands
actually but if we go back and we say
well what if we only want to know the
number of mass it takes to represent 25%
of that password set that 184,000
passwords so what you'll find is it
turns out there's only three masses
needed to represent 185,000 passwords
and even if you increase it to 50%
there's probably somewhere around a
dozen or something like that so at 50%
it takes 11 mass and you'll see this
pattern happen over and over where
you'll have these really high spikes
starting out with the first mask
representing tons and tons of the
passwords and then a very rapidly drops
off and ultimately when you try to match
up the this slope this pattern it ends
up looking a lot like an exponential
distribution with the Alpha being you
know pretty intense to where you get a
big drop-off right away and this pattern
ends up holding true for all kinds of
different sets so it doesn't really
matter which password set you pick they
all have this general tendency so if I
pick a set of PHP BB I'll pick like say
the singles org list that was leaked out
and in this case to get 50% we only need
for mass and out of that's 12,000
passwords that before representing half
of all the passwords that are inside of
there
so these these patterns show up in both
the marginal percentage and also the
cumulative percentage the marginal
percentage just being how many passwords
did any given mass represent and then if
you start if you order those and add up
the marginal percentages you just keep a
running total and that's the cumulative
percentage so I checked about things
about 15 or 20 different sets that were
cracked and also grabbed the rocky one
Rocky is like a combination of a bunch
of different passwords it's actually
kind of gotten bigger over time as
people have added more passwords to the
file and it still held the pattern even
though it wasn't really from one
definitive source and so what I ended up
seeing was is that if you need to crack
just any password at all out of a set
and you're not really concerned about
cracking a hundred percent of them or
you're not picking on one particular
individual in that set that you know say
like the super admin and there's only
one of those then really just focusing
on the most likely candidates the most
likely mass is a good technique you can
get a bunch of passwords back really
quick maybe even like one one and a half
percent of the entire set and you can
get them in under an hour really easily
then the the problem was is well how do
you kind of automate this because
there's a bit of a chicken and the egg
problem even if you learn this statistic
about passwords you still have to have
passwords to analyze to crack the
passwords right
so if you're starting off with a hash
file and you don't have any passwords
cracked at all you need some sort of
techniques to be able to at least chip
away at some of them in order to get
enough password to run the statistics on
so that you can figure out what the
pattern is as you go back and apply the
pattern and so I started running this
again on lots of different sets and the
bigger the set the more distinct this
pattern was where these first few
patterns made the biggest difference so
the small set was Facebook paste Bay
you'd only
and like 55 passwords or something in it
and so the line is kind of choppy but as
you got bigger and bigger sets you'll
notice the lines start to get really
clean and that drop-off is really
distinct so what what I learned from
this was you need a large sample of
passwords to start with that's very
important the more the merrier and again
this the the context is important so if
your goal is is to crack Fred's password
or Bill's password this may not help you
much because they're individuals and who
know who knows what they did right these
this is working on average so if you
just have a big set of hashes and you
just need some passwords then this
technique worked pretty well also we
notice that it follows an exponential
distribution so we can actually predict
what patterns are going to emerge if you
start to see that some mask is becoming
popular you can predict that that mask
is going to be in the top five top three
whatever because it's an exponential
distribution and recon on the target
still was extremely important because
obviously some systems have some kind of
password requirements right and so it
doesn't really matter if the most
popular masks in the entire world is
seven lowercase digits if the system
that you're working on requires an upper
and a lower and a gang sign and a higher
glyph and everything else right so you
really have to know about the the target
and understand what the possibilities
are so that you don't go you know
fishing in the wrong place and the final
thought was is that the more passwords
are cracked the more I realized my
techniques are biased right so for
example let's say that I make a word
list out of people's names and I crack a
bunch of passwords well statistics are
going to be biased towards passwords
made from people's names so they're
gonna be biased towards having all these
letters kind of in like a chunk right
and then maybe some numbers and on the
end or the beginning or some symbols
somewhere on the end or the beginning
but in general
name is a sequence of letters and so it
produces a bias in the output so using a
whole lot of different techniques to try
to initially get a foothold on the
hashes it kind of spreads that bias out
a little bit but you still always want
to be aware that especially like in my
case I'm the only one working on the
project right now and when you have one
person working on something you know you
get maximum bias right so all right so
putting these things to work so what I
wanted to do was create a program that
could automate a lot of this work but I
had some restraints that I also wanted
to put on it so the context I'm using it
in is you're in the middle of a pen test
and you get some hashes and you just
want some passwords right this second
like that's that's the the use case for
the tool if you want to crack all the
password hashes in the file it's
probably not the right tool for you and
again if you're going after a particular
person you're probably better off using
phishing or something like that instead
of you know necessarily trying to crack
like a really hard password certainly
give it a shot because if it works
that's a that's a good day but cracking
a single hash sometimes can be
frustrating so if you're not lucky
I wanted it to run in a virtual machine
this is a requirement mainly for where I
work virtual machines are used a lot and
so I wanted it to basically work on CPUs
and that's tough because that kind of
eliminates hash ket and so now for
better or worse you really end up
needing to use John the Ripper if that's
going to be a major requirement then
also I wanted it to run in the default
version of Kali and without any kind of
modifications because I was hoping to
try to make it as easy as possible for
people who are just starting out and
just learning as long as they understand
you know they're sacrificing performance
for how ease of use right I just wanted
people to be able to get started quickly
and start to understand what was
happening fast in hopes of teaching
people more about password analysis
so with those goals in mind a created
bypass and it's essentially a wrapper
around John the Ripper it's a Python
program that interacts with John and
gives it commands and work to do looks
at the results that are returned and
then that goes back and forth through
several iterations until a certain
number of passwords are cracked and then
it can do the analysis here's a couple
of examples how to run it but I'm gonna
go ahead and get it started over in the
other window
oops sorry let me make sure y'all can
see this
so what I picked is I picked the
LinkedIn hash set and I think I got it
offer on both site but it's it's
actually on a couple of sites and then
divided it in half just to make the demo
work better because it's a really really
big hash set so I just picked the first
half for no particular reason other than
to make it smaller and I'll go ahead and
get it started run and we can come back
in a minute and check on it so John
actually handles salts for you as long
as the salt is in the right format so
you can tell John like let's say say
like your format was a salt and a colon
and a and a hash as just making that up
by specifying the format you tell John
like what the format looks like and then
it knows how to tear it apart and then
apply it from there yep and you do have
to specify the format no free lunch on
that unfortunately so you get the mighty
error of death no passwords loaded if
you pick the wrong format so nobody
likes that so the three basic techniques
are base words prayer mode and stat
crack so stack crack is was our goal
right we were going to use the password
analysis statistics to figure out what
the mass were and so stat crack is kind
of self-explanatory the base word mode
is just letting you tell the system what
you know about the target so for example
we're talking about LinkedIn here so you
might want to pick base words like
linked and linked and linked in and in
and Li and things like that right and
you would feed those words into the
system because your intuition would tell
you those are probably good base words
to form passwords off of the system will
then take those base words and it will
run mangling rules on those phrases or
words you give it tens of thousands of
rules I believe it basically uses all
the core logic rules all the genre
one rule to rule them all rules all of
them and it just tries to use variations
now because it's using so many rules you
do have to kind of be careful about how
many bass words you give it if you feed
it 50 bass words it's gonna be a while
because you're talking about every every
one word you pass in I think it creates
something like a couple hundred thousand
guesses or something like that it was a
huge multiplicative factor so it doesn't
take much at all to get to a million
you know mangling variations but I found
this works really well this is really
good for a few passwords in every set
and in these gigantic sets like the
LinkedIn set just the five words that I
mentioned was good for like a thousand
passwords right off the top so that's
where this is optional and you pass it
in with the dash B option the the
default mode in other words if you don't
say anything at all if you just say
here's the hashtag go for it
it'll it's gonna run the prayer mode
which is the core here is the Hail Mary
so it basically what it does is it takes
a lot of really popular words base words
words that people like to form passwords
from and it runs rules on those I run as
many rules as I can on the set without
taking too much time because again
remember the original goals you want
this thing to give you some passwords
right now you know very very quickly
certainly wouldn't want to run more than
30 minutes or an hour you know that
would be kind of like a really long time
in this context it does and then it
tries what's called the Hail Mary which
is just this gigantic list of already
known passwords so you're talking about
things like the rock you dictionary very
popular already known passwords list and
other popular lists where I got the
passwords from and just threw them all
into one file maîtrise English and
Spanish
I found Spanish is obviously very
popular because second most popular
language behind English and I just
picked the top 10,000 words out of those
languages
obviously thinks I think Spanish has
well and excessive 100,000 words in
English has something like 450,000 or
it's an insane number of words so that's
too many so what I did is I paired it
down to the top 10,000 as it turns out
languages also follow the same
exponential distribution that the
passwords do so if you pick the top
10,000 you're really getting like you
know 90 something percent of the usage
of the language sports team team names
people's names places and cities and
states and countries you get the idea so
it goes through all these different
iterations throws these at it and tries
to see how many passwords can you get if
if you happen to have a special format
where you have the username and the
password together it actually runs the
John single mode at the very end as well
so which is a good one in that special
case so finally it has now a set of
passwords and it runs the statistical
analysis that we did earlier generates
the mass you tell it what percent you
want it to use 25 percent was the one we
were using in the examples and then
it'll create the mass one by one and
then it'll let John work on those mass
one at a time so it's not actually mask
mode though so if you're already
familiar with password cracking there's
a brute-force technique that you can
feed hash cat and John the Ripper and
you can basically say try everything
that has say for example for lowercase
letters followed by a number so that
pattern it would try every possible
combination of the four letters and then
it would try adding the one number onto
the end so you end up with something
like 26 to the fourth power times 10
numbers right and it's just gigantic
amount of computation to do what bypass
does is it actually takes the the
popular base words that we talked about
earlier and it uses those to form the
the rules so for example in that we said
four letters in a number was our
rule we were going to brute force what
do we do instead is it would take all
the the four-letter words that it knows
about and then just add the numbers on
to the end of it so this isn't by any
means gonna find all the passwords and
it's not meant for a complete list and
again it's it's all about speed it's all
about finding passwords as quickly as
possible so and that's what it means
about targeted whitelist so again the
the things I got out of it the most was
learn about the target can't really
overemphasize that at all knowing what
passwords are even acceptable in the
system the hash form at the base words
to use using programs like cool to
screen scrape websites in order to get a
good collection of base words was super
important that was it seems like you can
never get away with anything and pin
testing without doing recon
it's like seems like that's always the
key component to all the pin test no
matter what direction you're coming from
use the base words for sure compile John
the Ripper on Kali Linux which actually
violates one of the rules I had that it
had to be able to use the default
version of Kali links and it can it has
no problem with the built-in version of
John it's just going to run about half
as fast as if you compile the latest I
think it's might be 1.8 or whatever the
latest one is out on the website if you
do take the time to compile natively
especially if you're running on real
hardware and not in a virtual machine
then you'll get a vast performance
increase at least I never had it not be
at least twice as fast even on a VM
if you compiled it locally there's
another program Pipal that does a great
job with the password stats so if you
really want to see a lot of different
stats from a lot of different angles on
the passwords then pitbull is a great
tool to check out Robin
Wood wrote it and it's on his site which
is a digi ninja can't remember if it's
order or what but it's did you ninja
site and then finally we said this one
was wrapping around John the Ripper so
if you want to use hash cat which can
offer better
performance in some situations then
trusted SEC put out hate crack I think
it was like three weeks ago or so and it
it uses the same general concepts and it
has hash cat under the hood so awesome
program there alright so while we were
chatting the program was grinding away
on that LinkedIn set and basically what
it ended up doing was is it started off
using just some super popular words that
I'm not sure if this guy's name is Hobbs
zero hobo I'm not sure how to pronounce
it don't uh don't mean to be insulting
there but I read his his blog and his
website and looked at a lot of the work
he had done and it was pretty
interesting so I used his rules and his
words to start off because they work
pretty well and then what the program
does is it'll basically tell you how
it's doing as it goes along so it'll say
like well that you know that really
really short list with those really
short number rules didn't really find
anything and it tells you okay there's
you know there's zero but as it goes
down and gets more and more aggressive
meaning it takes longer and longer to do
the different techniques and so as it
gets down to about mode 4 which was the
Hail Mary it's cracked 15,000 907 and
just using that one technique so that
one happened in this particular case
just happened to be a good hit of course
I should have used base words like I
said earlier and that would have helped
out to the so then it goes down to like
to like rule 5 where it got you know
another five passwords or so and it ends
up having about 20 different rules and
it'll tell you how it's doing as it goes
along so here I cracked one password
using English words well I should say
one additional password but when it got
down to English words and it used the
one rule to rule them all rules which is
not easy to say it ended up cracking
3733 additional passwords in addition to
seventy thousand that we've already got
up to this point so you can see what
it's doing is is it's grinding through
in these techniques one by one trying to
essentially just automate it for you so
that if if it's your first shot at
password cracking this is going to kind
of use what it knows about the best ways
to get started and it's going to run
like the top twenty best ways to take a
shot at at a given password set alright
so if you're interested in in trying
this out it's on github and so if you
scroll down a little bit once you get
over there there's actually some setup
documents that will explain assuming
you're using a default version of Kali
Linux again how to use the git clone
command to pull down the project get it
set up and then there's a config file
where you point it to the version of
John that you want it to use if you're
using the default version you can just
use the default settings but I have
custom compiled online so I had to point
it over to the version that I had put in
the optic directory and it walks you
through how to get it all set up and
then at the bottom it shows you how to
run the commands and then there's
examples for each there's at least three
different examples of how to run each
command so say any question up to this
point
so where's the opportunities for
improvement well one of the things that
I didn't realize at first is that how
important the Spanish words were and so
I'm going back in now and I'm
retrofitting a lot of it with more
Spanish words and more Spanish words in
more context in other words using those
for the mass another thing that I found
is that adding in more statistical
patterns helps there's some corner cases
and some edge cases where there's some
weird patterns that turn out to be kind
of popular and they don't they don't
come up very often but again each
individual site you know is unique so
there are some hash sets that some more
patterns won't help I'd need to practice
with it more and just keep tuning it and
then getting better word list always
helps I'm always amazed at how when I
find like a few more sports you know or
a few more people's names that doesn't
even seem significant you know you found
like another thousand names somewhere on
some list and you throw them in there
and add it to the hundred thousand
they're already there and suddenly
you're you're getting like 600 more
passwords you know it's real it's it's
real important to have really good solid
word lists and to collect a lot of lists
from a lot of different places and
combine them together instead of just
relying on the tried-and-true list
nothing wrong with those they're the
most effective of course you know the
ones that are very popular but if you
can go out and just pull down and add to
your list that makes a big difference
so improvements for ourselves the
biggest thing I think helps regular
folks is two-factor multi-factor
authentication so I know LinkedIn and
Google and including Gmail Apple
Facebook Twitter you know on and on all
offer free multi-factor or two-factor
authentication in those cases also
Amazon has offered it for a long time on
their AWS if he had one there aw servers
but not terribly long ago they actually
started offering free to factor for just
regular amazon shopping accounts you
know just what everybody uses to buy
stuff and they didn't even really make a
big deal out of it
which I thought was a little odd because
I was so happy when they did that I was
like yay
sorry had an Amazon or AWS account
anyway and it was that automatically
just started protecting my my regular
shopping account so that was good the
other thing is using the appropriate
factor for the context so I work with a
lot of application groups application
teams although I do a lot of network
pentest I still do a lot of web stuff as
well and I see a consistent pattern
where because people are very good at
using passwords right remembering things
and you know knowing what they're
supposed to type in your computers are
lousy at that kind of stuff right they
can't remember anything they have to
write everything down on hard drives or
storage and you know they're just
terrible at remembering stuff so I'm
always amazed when like applications try
to make their machines use passwords to
log into other machines you know there's
no human in the mix and so one of the
things I would encourage is if you're
working with application teams is try to
teach them about other factors they can
use like maybe the applications can use
certificates to talk to one another or
the web services can use you know mutual
authentication with each other or you
know some other technique where you know
the machine to machine communication can
be more about something you have as as
opposed to something you know and so I
think that's probably the two biggest
improvements I've seen just from just
being more aware about this sort of
thing so as far as people and Pipal I
think it's pipl Pipal this is the link
to his project and then also trusted sex
hey crack that I mentioned has hash ket
a link to theirs as well but a quick
google on either one and will get you
right to them they're both index very
high on the PageRank so alright so now
I'd like to just open it up to any
questions at all on password cracking or
how bad pass works or having I'm sorry
oh yeah absolutely yeah md5 for the wind
yeah actually that's a good question so
I mean the the the implied question is
is you know what what kind of hash
should I use for my site how should I be
a better developer yeah I think Blowfish
bcrypt
either one is is good
so now Blowfish I think is the symmetric
algorithm and bcrypt is the always get
mixed up be crypt is the hashing
algorithm so for password storage we
would use hashes we would not use
encryption not reversible encryption so
yeah I always getting mixed up too so
yes but but that's excellent point
because with bcrypt it's it requires a
lot of rounds to generate the hash it's
it's a lot at work so a ton of work for
the computer to generate the hash but
let's say like pretend you're a website
for a second so the user comes along and
they type in their username their
password and your the website so you
have to take the password that they
offered and you have to hash it and then
you have to compare it to the hash you
have on file and if the to match the
presumption is is the person must have
known the password so even if a website
takes say two seconds to make that
decision because the hashing algorithm
is is so owners that's okay it's an
acceptable user interface you know
decision but if you're a password
cracker and you're trying to crack the
passwords and you've got say five
million words in your dictionary that
you're gonna throw up against these
hashes and it's taken like two seconds
every every one of them right it makes
the password cracking and feasible at
least brute-force or even guessing
really right because it just takes too
long so a good hash choice is is really
important and can make all the
difference in the world unfortunately a
lot of those better algorithms you won't
really find them in
the standard libraries of the languages
like so if you go to I think like I
don't know asp.net I don't think bcrypt
is in the crypto provider in there right
and so you're kind of asking developers
to you know drive out their lane just a
little bit and go import a third-party
library and that can take some
convincing to do so that's the end of
the downside of the really good hashes
all right other questions yes no I know
there's a prince and a Markov in there
too and there's incremental of course I
have not looked at either one of those
but what I did do is when when the
program gets done and it goes through
all the different techniques like right
now it's on number of technique eleven
and eighty seven thousand password
sprouts tuned it's having a really good
day it's a lot of passwords what it does
is at the very end it'll it'll spit out
a message and say I did the best I could
with what I had you know here's how many
passwords I cracked right and then it'll
go ahead and it'll tell you what the
command is to switch to incremental mode
so all you have to do is copy and paste
that line and just paste it in and it'll
go ahead and switch to incremental mode
now of course the reason I don't have
the tool automatically go to incremental
mode is that's brute force and it won't
stop until it's done and obviously the
program will run for however many years
it takes right so that's why I didn't
just automatically switch it over but
that's a good idea I could I could look
at those other modes and see if they
have a fit somewhere in here as well
those those Mo's he's speaking of they
are modes that do some other kinds of
statistical analysis and they use that
information and it's built into John the
Ripper automatically so you don't need
any other wrapper around it to do that
kind of analysis with prints mm-hmm yeah
the incremental is pretty good too if
you got a big hash set and especially if
it's a fast hash set like a md5 zur
Shaw's or whatever yeah
so that's a good idea - to do that now
the the prince mode you know how long it
takes to run relatively speaking yeah I
don't either that's why I was asking so
I was just curious if it would fit the
original goals of the project or I
thought we blow out my timeline cool yep
and there's also some interesting rules
that there's one that hate crack does
that's interesting where it takes word
lists and it combines it with password
masks and puts the two together and as
it turns out that's one thing the two
programs have in common is they both
they both do that where they where
they'll take like a word from a
dictionary and then a pattern and run
through all the patterns on that word
and that works out really well if again
like if your base word is like for
example a person's name those kinds of
rules work really well if you have folks
that are say like all their passwords
are named after their cat and you use
cool on their Facebook page or something
right and so you got their cat in there
then those kind of rules work out really
well no all right other questions
all right cool well thanks appreciate
you having me today