[Music]
privacy is a complex and challenging
risk in today's world one of the
greatest sources of privacy risk are
your employees because every time they
touch data or make a decision about data
they can create privacy exposure for you
in this video we're going to hear from
global privacy experts on how to create
a culture of privacy to help address
those risks and help improve privacy for
your company the way to get people to
lead and believe in privacy is to make
it everybody's business to bring it to
their own why does it matter to you why
does it matter to what you do and then
to make it really a business issue why
is privacy critical for our business if
you don't create a culture of privacy
within an organization though what your
risk is the fact that you have a strong
legal department that really understands
the issue you may even have a really
strong engineering department that
understands the issue but there are
going to be gaps throughout your
organization where that awareness will
not exist you need smart people in the
right places making good decisions now
that doesn't mean that every person in
your organization has to be a PhD in
privacy it's not going to happen
what you need is role based
understanding so that someone has the
ability to understand that a privacy
issue is in front of them and either
resolve it or elevate it appropriately
that everybody understands that even
somebody who doesn't handle personal
information or data at all in their day
to day activities when they do stumble
upon it even by mistake they need to
understand how it imported it is to the
organization you have to make sure that
the workforce understands privacy is a
team sport everybody plays anytime they
touch a piece of personal information
they know they have to follow the
correct processes and procedures a
comprehensive privacy training program
can alter your corporate culture and
turn something that may have been a
weakness into a strength at the same
time if something bad does happen
a good privacy training program will
help shorten response times and improve
your overall results we all know that
there are going to be data breaches it's
the understanding of what a data breach
is it's how to try to prevent it it's
how to manage it when it occurs those
are the issues that are part of the
training and education and awareness
that needs to occur the front page of
the New York Times no institution wants
their name there aligned with the mishap
you need to have those people trained to
understand how your company's thinking
about the issue of privacy what the
guidelines are internally your company
for how data will be handled as well as
making it personal to every single
person at the company we all have
responsibility for treating each other's
data the way we'd want our own data
treated your customers have a lot of
expectations of your company when they
engage with you they expect that you're
going to manage their data in fact they
expect that you're gonna manage their
data well in today's world it is without
question that your customers expect you
are going to do right with their data I
think you just have to train over and
over again and you want to train to the
point where the workforce considers
privacy not to be something that they
have to do that they have to check the
box but you want to train to the point
where privacy becomes just this innate
value to the individual person in the
workforce
that they think of it almost like muscle
memory still a recent study showed that
less than half of organizations are
requiring privacy training in the end if
your employees can't make good decisions
about data if when they are presented
with a choice about privacy they don't
know how to make a good decision your
efforts aren't going to fail and so you
have to invest in employee training
without privacy we may not have trust we
may not be able to sell our products we
may not be able to engage with our
business partners because there's going
to be competitor who's going to be
better if we don't do this right it's
also understanding the lifeblood of your
organization in this digital economy is
data and that means getting privacy
right
[Music]
you