welcome to the demo for the US federal
agency privacy threshold analysis and
privacy impact assessment in this demo
these two templates will be linked
together to demonstrate how they can be
used to first gather preliminary
information about a project or system
and determine whether a full privacy
impact assessment is required and second
to conduct the full privacy impact
assessment if necessary these templates
are based on the Department of Homeland
Security's privacy threshold analysis
and privacy impact assessment templates
which are publicly available at DHS gov
to begin the workflow the project
approver would assign the privacy
threshold analysis to a respondent who
typically would be someone at a
component office of the agency the
respondent would then fill out the PTA
and submit it back to the approver the
PTA includes a variety of question types
including freeform text multi-select
questions as well as yes/no responses
the threshold also includes a section
where the respondent can provide their
own recommendation as to whether or not
the PIAA or other steps are required
after the respondent has completed the
threshold and submitted it back to the
approver the approver can then review
the answers that were provided by the
respondent here they can flag risks add
recommendations for how to mitigate the
risk as well as request more information
is needed the approver can then add
their determination of whether or not a
P ia or other next steps are required
if the approver determines that a PIAA
is needed it can then be sent to the
respondent who will be greeted with
welcome text explaining what a PIAA is
what it should accomplish and its
purposes the respondent can then begin
to move through the various sections and
answer the PIAA questions the questions
are a combination of freeform text
multi-select and yes/no questions
each question also includes a text box
where the respondent can provide
additional information or context where
necessary this allows the federal agency
to provide the narrative based PIAA in
order to tell the story to the executive
branch or to the public at large in
accordance with the Privacy Act any
Government Act
when the respondent is finished they can
then submit the PIAA back to the
approver so that they can review the
answers once again the approver will
have the opportunity to review the
answers that were provided by the
respondent flag risks provide any
recommendations on how to mitigate the
risk and request additional information
if needed
once the approver is satisfied with the
PIAA
they can continue to risk tracking
here the approver can review all of the
risk that was flagged by the PIAA add
additional descriptions or
recommendations on how to mitigate the
risk as well as provide additional
internal notes once the approver is
satisfied they can complete risk
tracking and complete the project this
concludes the demo for the US federal
agency privacy threshold analysis and
privacy impact assessment templates