good morning good morning everyone my
name is trevor hughes and i'm delighted
to welcome you all to a special call
we've pulled together today to make an
important announcement for anyone who is
a lawyer or works in a law related field
in this broad profession of privacy my
name is trevor hughes i'm the president
and CEO of the ia pp and i'm delighted
to have you all here today i am joined
today by Chris wolf partner and head of
the privacy practice at the law firm of
Hogan Lovells and Chris and I are going
to share some exciting news about the
launch of the privacy bar section of the
ia PP let me tell you a little bit about
the privacy bar section and what we're
hoping to do first of all today's call
is just Chris and I sharing with you
this announcement and so there is not an
open chat or question process we do have
an email address for you if you have
questions or comments after the fact and
we'll share a lot of news about what's
happening so you'll get a sense of how
to engage going forward one of the
things that is clearly the case is that
the field of privacy is exploding around
the world today the ia PP has 25,000
members in 80 countries across our
membership we know from surveying our
members that over 40 percent of our
members are lawyers a bigger number than
that forty percent actually come from
law related professions more broadly and
those lawyers need services they need to
meet to engage to learn about privacy as
a legal topic and after some leadership
and prompting from Chris wolf in the
future of privacy forum which Chris
serves as the president of the of the
board we came together with a set of
tools and services that we are happy to
be launching today I'm happy to announce
that Chris will be serving as the
founding board chair advisory board
chair of the privacy bar section of
the ia pp and with that I'd like to hand
things off to Chris to talk a little bit
about why this is important and why the
moment is important for us to be
launching this new initiative Chris
Trevor Trevor thank you very much and
this truly is an exciting announcement I
think I thank the IPP for embracing the
idea and really running with it you know
36 years ago when I became a lawyer
privacy law meant basically the mall the
Fourth Amendment the underused processer
privacy towards the Privacy Act of 1974
and and not much else and you fast
forward to today and there are hundreds
of privacy and data security laws we
have the common law of FTC consent
decrees we have thousands of lawyers
across America who are practicing
privacy law as a distinct area of
practice as well as privacy academics
who are teaching privacy law in our law
schools with the advent of the Internet
as a principal means of communication
and commerce with electronic health
records with online banking with
educational privacy with the Internet of
Things with big data and I could go on
privacy law has become a specialty with
burgeoning subspecialties businesses
today are embracing privacy by design
and as they do that they know that
privacy law compliance is an integral
part of their planning and of doing
business and they realize that privacy
lawyers are indispensable and that
turning to generalist lawyers for
privacy law just doesn't cut it anymore
so at the same time individuals are
realizing that privacy law provides many
remedies and tools to vindicate their
rights and governments know that privacy
laws give citizens rights and that
privacy lawyers are needed in government
organizations to guarantee those rights
so in short or in some privacy law is
vitally important to society and its
importance is growing and so privacy law
as a separate discipline is here to stay
just as when antitrust law and
communications law emerged the separate
disciplines and developed their own
separate professional forums the time
has come as PP is recognized for privacy
lawyers to have their own separate
professional forum and I'm delighted
that IPP with the support and
cooperation of the future of privacy
forum is creating such a professional
privacy lawyers including practitioners
and law professors at judges now will
have their own place to contaminant
estas legal issues and legal
developments when the Supreme Court
issues a decision on privacy law when a
court of appeals issues a decision on
the scope and jurisdiction federal
enforcement when Congress considers
amendments to update existing privacy
laws contemplates new privacy law
remedies this new ia PP professional
forum for privacy lawyers will be the
place where the details of those
developments are discussed in depth
it'll be a place for providing
opportunities for legal scholarship
it'll be a place where privacy lawyers
can consider professional issues unique
to our discipline and I think the
potential for this new division is just
terrific you look at the Federal
Communications Bar Association as an
example of a robust organization
dedicated to specific to a specific
legal discipline and I think this new ia
PP lawyers division as the similar
similar potential to be a wonderful
professional home for those of us who
are lucky enough to practice privacy
laws so I encourage my fellow privacy
lawyers and privacy law professors and
those in the judiciary to engage in this
terrific new initiative you know just as
the ITP has provided amazing
opportunities for professional growth
for privacy professionals generally
lawyers and non-lawyers alike I think
this new focused division promises great
opportunities and it can only truly
succeed with critical mass so I
encourage everyone on this call to
engage and with that I will turn it back
to Trevor to explain how that will work
excellent well thank you Chris and what
a great what a great introduction to why
this moment is so important for the
creation of the privacy bar section at
the IACP and Chris on behalf of our
profession on prat on behalf of this new
section within the IPP we want to
express our gratitude for your
leadership let me talk to you a little
bit about next steps for the privacy bar
section of the IEP P we are going to be
launching an event at the IEP P global
privacy summit there will be a privacy
bar section workshop we're not quite
sure of the name yet an event
immediately following the global privacy
summit on Thursday April 7th it will be
in DC our plan is for an event that runs
in the morning through lunch to allow
people to get back home on Thursday
afternoon after the summit so stay tuned
for that announcement watch for that
program and that event which will be the
inaugural event for the privacy bar
section we expect that program as Chris
mentioned to be heavily focused on the
needs of lawyers practicing in the field
of privacy and it will be an opportunity
for us to dive deeper to explore more
thoroughly many of the issues that
privacy lawyers are are encountering
today we are also launching an advisory
board this is an advisory board that
will advise is the IEP P on the needs of
the privacy bar sections will help us to
program content in the months and years
ahead and will also help to oversee the
development of the section with many
future services and and deliverables to
the to the privacy bar so I am today we
are today announcing that we are seeking
nominations for that Advisory Board the
ITP has many advisory boards that help
us
with many of the functions within the I
ATP this advisory board will serve in a
similar posture as I mentioned
previously Chris as really the the
person who led this effort and brought
it to the IEP P will be the inaugural
chair of this advisory board but we are
seeking 10 to 12 additional leaders to
help us guide the privacy bar session
you should see on the screen in front of
you a link to the nomination process and
just one note about that link
well that page is up right now we don't
have the field capture mechanism totally
locked down so if you are interested in
nominating I'd ask you to defer till the
end of the day today or first thing
tomorrow morning to nominate yourself
but that link is the place that you can
nominate understand that we will likely
get more interest than we probably have
capacity to support right now we think
that it's important for us to start
small and grow we will select people to
serve on this advisory board IEP staff
will select people to serve on this
advisory board based on a diversity of
representation we certainly want to have
outside counsel in-house counsel privacy
academics we want to have a broad range
of practitioners in the field of privacy
law represented on this advisory board
in the future though we expect that many
leadership opportunities will emerge for
many many people in the privacy bar
section so bear with us as we let this
this idea grow from from this this
rather humble beginning we expect lots
of great things to happen but we want
them to build on success after success
and it will take us some time to get all
of those things up to speed I do have
some other exciting news to share and I
want everyone to understand that this is
not completely locked down yet however
last week the IEP is submitted and
location to the American Bar Association
for recognition of our credentials for
the purpose of recognizing
specialization in the field of privacy
law this is important for lawyers across
the country because ABA recognition
carries reciprocity with a number of
states around the country and for
purposes of distinguishing or
demonstrating that you have a specialty
in a particular field you can think of
patent law or family law or other areas
of specialty in in in the privacy world
the ABA recognizes well-established and
credible certification programs for the
purposes of demonstrating that specialty
in the marketplace we submitted our
application last week as all of you
should know last year the IEP was
successful in receiving ISO
accreditation through ANSI for many of
our certification programs and that is
significantly influential in this ABA
process and we are hoping that at some
point this year we will be able to share
the great news with all of you that IEP
certifications are a path to
demonstrating to the marketplace
recognized by the ABA and therefore
recognized by many of the licensing
states that you are licensed in that it
is a mechanism to demonstrate to the
marketplace that you are specialized in
the field of privacy law we'll have more
news on that as developments occur as we
hear back from the ABA I can also share
with you that South Carolina
independently recognized our CI PP
designation for exactly this purpose
that lawyers in South Carolina who
carried a CI PP designation have the
ability to reference that designation as
an indicator of their specialization in
the field of information privacy all of
this is to suggest that Chris is
leadership and really provocation to the
IPP that we move forward with this idea
was very
very timely the American Bar Association
was very receptive to our application
because the moment is right to recognize
that those forty percent of our members
those many thousands of privacy lawyers
across the United States are doing
something unique doing something
different and doing something incredibly
important to today it's digital economy
and so we're very very happy about
today's announcement and we certainly
look forward to great things in the
future I do want to talk about the
future just a little bit in the future
we expect that the privacy bar section
will do many of the things that you
would expect a section of the ITP
focused on the privacy bar would do you
can expect unique content you can expect
unique events web conferences and other
things again we ask that you bear with
us as we allow this to grow organically
if you will we want this to grow slowly
based on success after success but we
are investing resources in supporting
this new section and and developing it
we will have lots more announcements in
the days and weeks ahead certainly stay
tuned for and watch for the announcement
of the event running immediately after
the global privacy summit and I think
for many of you how great would it be to
be able to say that you were there for
the very first event that created the
privacy bar section within the ia PP
that is a foundational moment for the
privacy bar and I think many decades
from now will look back at that moment
and say that's when it really started so
I hope that you'll be there with us but
watch also for other announcements from
the privacy bar section we certainly
have many great plans and you know that
many of you will have great ideas that
will help us guide this idea in the
future so there it is a big announcement
from the ia PP today an important new
section within the ia PP the privacy bar
section of the ia PP and kicked off by
and and really helped to this moment by
the great leadership of Chris wolf so
Chris
thank you thank you thank you and Trevor
is my great pleasure and I just want to
mention the support of Jules problem
etske in the future of privacy for
bringing bringing this idea forward as
well and I know they're gonna stay
involved as well absolutely they are all
right everyone and that is what we had
today please you'll see on the screen
right now you should see a link to the
nomination process for the advisory
board again we ask that you hang off
just a little bit and let us get those
fields populated in the right way so
that they feed into our systems so if
you want to nominate maybe think about
doing that first thing tomorrow morning
write a note to yourself so that you
jump back on to the system and do that
if you have any questions or comments
Tara meter here at the IEP is the right
place to channel those through they will
get addressed appropriately here in the
organization but we're happy to take any
questions and comments you have through
that email address and with that I will
express again my gratitude to Chris and
Jules in the future of privacy forum
when I express my gratitude to all of
you for joining the call today and I
really do hope that we see you on April
7th Thursday April 7th in Washington DC
for the inaugural kickoff event for the
privacy bar section thanks folks have a
great day