i'll just jump straight into it uh
trusting you can see my screen my
current role is the technical director
of cyber security for the next gen group
and we are with our friends at
microfocus proud platinum sponsors to
this amazing event now this position
allows me the privilege to be here today
and uh on my day-to-day talking to
forward forward-thinking creative and
amazing people like yourselves as i
assist in the transformational change to
which we look at implement and assess
our cybersecurity postures
in organizations uh looking to secure
their digital ecosystem from the vast
ever changing and critically unique
threat landscape now i say unique
because while some of the tool sets in
organizations might be household names
the definition and the application of
them is never the same
now you've heard some great speakers
today on a range of topics but i wanted
to take you on a bit of a different
journey i don't have much time with you
today but i want to leave you with a
brief background on why my history in
the special forces and the mindset that
i had to adopt played such a defining
role in how i approach cyber security
as you can see the beard is a little bit
grayer and the piercing stair has been
replaced with a smile uh this is me in
afghanistan in 2013 at the tail end of
an action-packed tour i spent a decade
serving in the australian army and the
lion's share of that within the special
forces community that are supported
across the globe uh in in wartime
peacetime enabling and training roles
uh within different special forces units
across the globe again
over those years i took particular
interest in the electronic counter
measures and the systems that were
defining the electronic counter measures
uh to define cyber practices from both
sides of the of the war zone i was
fortunate enough to work alongside some
of the most amazing humans in all facets
and cultures in life
experiences that have changed me and my
outlook on life for the better now the
role of a modern day special forces
soldier much like the role of the
predicating special forces soldiers is
to be critically minded it is to be
adaptable and cell phone and a
self-aware soldier that understands
their role as a member of the team as
much as it does of itself as an
individual
the mindset that is required needs to
have certain metrics that will allow the
trainability to an ever-evolving threat
landscape extending multiple domains of
warfare with the best interest of the
mission at hand
without this and some core metrics those
seeking to be an enabling force to the
special forces community do not progress
through the forces journey
now some of those metrics i wanted to
leave you with today uh in the last few
minutes i have and if you miss out on on
the rest of this please join me at uh at
my longer speech at sing kong later in
the week where i'll be talking about the
mindset and some of these in a bit more
detail
now i'll talk you through uh what it
takes to be a special forces soldier in
the mindset i just mentioned and some of
those key learnings that take us from
that initial start state to the future
state which is constant pursuit of
excellence
now i'll talk about cyber security with
the vehicle analogy and i use the
vehicle analogy because it is ever
changing now let's i want to picture
yourself inside a vehicle you're looking
through the rear vision mirror and the
reason you're looking through the rear
vision mirror is to learn from history
in order to provide the best
state in forward looking
you need to have a true historical
knowledge of what cyber security is
and this goes back to the dates of the
early implementation of special forces
in warfare
currently in modern in modern warfare we
learn from those mistakes and it is just
as pertinent to learn from those
mistakes so we don't make the same
mistakes in the future
i mentioned trainability earlier if you
can't learn from history your
trainability isn't isn't quite up to
standard trainability is a key in any
cyber security realm whether it's you're
an analyst whether you're a leader or
whether you're joining in an internship
level trainability is critical at all
levels of cyber security to learn from
history to then bring us into the
vehicle where we're sitting inside in
the present
when we're inside the vehicle and we're
present we can see all that around us we
need to have critical awareness we need
to understand what our threat landscape
looks like and we need to see as the
threat landscape is changing as we're
driving through the vast differences
within the terrains of what the threats
are as they're coming towards
so special forces mindset needs to be
adaptive it needs to have
self-criticality self-criticality
it needs to have self-development
and these three things awareness
self-criticality and self-development
play a pivotal role in who you are as a
cyber security expert or a cybersecurity
leader
next is understanding the team this is
also inside the vehicle analogy what is
around you what does that self-awareness
look like we have a steering wheel we
have passengers we have people in the
back but it's not just the physical team
it's not just the people that are with
you day to day it's not just the people
that are third party assisting you in
your cybersecurity risk
posture
it is also the tools
it's also the vehicle in this instance
it's the engine that drives us there
it's a gearbox that allows us to change
speeds
it's the windows that allow us to take
down and see and allow us to get that
awareness piece
we need to understand our team not just
from
the people and the people around us we
need to understand that our team is also
our vendor technologies that we build
together in a cyber security fabric that
really provide us the capability and the
metrics to be able to defend our
organization's digital ecosystem
once we understand that and we can truly
adopt to what our
technologies are aware we can then
become truly aware of what our team is
and what our team is capable of
we need to understand team criticality
we need to understand if one thing falls
over do we have vendor in depth or
defense in depth and the strategies that
will take us from that criticality to
the point of changeover
do we have role crossover
do we understand each person in that
team's role and if that person isn't
there for that day if that person
something happens
who can take over that role we need to
have role crossover and again that
doesn't extend from the people in the
room that extends to your vendor
technologies we need to understand the
team in a holistic sense in order to
provide security and so resiliency
and lastly is the windscreen we need to
be forward thinking
in forward thinking we can achieve the
constant pursuit of excellence and that
is really the end state of a special
forces mindset
is to be on the constant pursuit of
excellence
how do we do that in this
forward-looking piece
we adopt a rehearsal of concepts
something in special forces we did every
single day
we provided and performed rehearsals of
concepts whether that was tabletop
exercises or whether that was physical
exercises on the ground
understanding every remit and every
length of our role and our vendor
technologies role to maximize that
technical in depth now the tech in depth
as i mentioned in the uh inside the
vehicle piece we need to really maximize
what our vendor technologies are capable
of in our instance i talk to
organizations all the time and i
guarantee you that every you know once
in three conversations the vendor
technologies they've got in their
systems
are there to provide a certain outcome
but by proxy they can allow us to do a
lot more so we need to understand the
breadth of capability within our vendor
technologies within our stack
these four creek key things are not just
the basis of a special forces mindset
but they are the pieces that cross over
into cybersecurity dramatically and
allow us to learn
allow us to grow and allow us to
understand where our left and rights of
arc are in terms of a cyber security
posture uplift
there's a great quote down the bottom
there we are makers of history we are
made by history we need to learn from
history so that we can grow in the
future
join me for my longer speech on friday
as we go through and dive further into
this special forces mindset and how it
adopts into a cyber security model