now
let us all welcome our next income 2021
keynote blind spots of platform security
hardware and firmware challenges please
welcome alex microsoft founder and ceo
of finally inc
good morning singapore and
it is a big pleasure for me to be here
on the virtual stage of simcon 2021
and
i'm happy to deliver my knot which is
focusing on blind spots of platform
security and we will talk today about
the hardware and firmware challenges but
my name is alex machrossov and i'm
well-known a forensic security
researcher spring in almost two decades
uh focused on reverse engineering and
detection of low-level threats and
basically breaking the hardware and
firmwares i've been working for the
companies like intel and nvidia and some
others and actually
currently i founded my own company
called binary focus it exactly on these
blind spots and try to fix the industry
and get it watched
so let's
talk about what the challenges are
and if you think about we spend the
decades on targeting detections on
operating system level and that doesn't
mean we don't have the threats which is
evolving on um
firmware and hardware space it is
actually a big mistake from the industry
it's been constantly overlooking and
ignoring such of the spaces but now it
is actually right timing to focus on
that problems and in my knot i will be
discussed today why
so if you think about like in the open
boring security industry we just
scratching the surface on what we try to
detect on the hardware and firmware
level and of course like modern
persistent techniques it's always
evolving and try to invent new
techniques to bypass endpoint solutions
or stay
not detected for a long time
and if you look on evolution of the
persistent technique it's been always
some sort of like a
challenge between mitigations and
modern persistence complexity because if
you
look on this figure you can see so we
have a root kit which has been pretty
actively before
attacking and hooking an operating
system above the code but when the code
signing policy for external models being
involved like this uh mainstream threats
move to the lower lower stack and try to
in fact
moisture good volume records and some
other stuff which is actually bootstrap
uh
some code before the operating system
get control and basically it's allows
the attacker to be in the place where
at the time not been much solution
looking effectively to detect such of
the threats right and then um
actually secure boot came onto the
others where
it is create uh
some integrity of the good process and
boot kids became
less effective right so and it it's been
a time where
attackers need to look and find the new
spots and it is exactly it's a firmware
right so buyers and plants it's actually
less rare than we think about and even
nowadays uh
attacking the sign a driver and
bootstrap your code to the kernel mode
also a potential scenario for the
attacker to bypass code sign-in policy
because you can
execute the code uh over-exporting the
vulnerability in a legitimate driver
right or use legitimate driver if it is
providing some functions for abuse this
driver and deliver malicious code
operating system level
and
that's
a good topic with a picture where we can
see how moving down from the operating
system to the hardware we actually have
less mitigations less detection
techniques and actually persistence and
the quality of the persistent techniques
is growing
exponentially
also
that's a very good statistics about how
many
etr bypasses we have in the wild if you
think about modern edr endpoint
detection and response solutions uh
all of them based on apis which is
microsoft provide with atw interfaces
right and if you have an ability to
bypass such of the interfaces or like uh
stay
under the rudders of this cemetery
system you can be undetected by
many of endpoint solutions nowadays and
on this
chart we can see how
how many vulnerabilities actually
vulnerabilities grows by the last two
years right so in 2021
just actually overloading us with
multiple vectors which is can bypass by
design two telemetry collection and
endpoint solutions uh actually about
that my colleagues
from binary will be talked about on the
next week at black hat europe
and to be honest uh it's very big
problem for the industry where we have
unified interface which is cool right so
we have unified interface and from
development perspective it's very
effective way but
also unified interface means
bypass once work for whole industry
right and such of the problems also
exist in the firmware space and we will
talk about that a bit later
but let's uh focus on
how actually mitra attack providing us
some guidance about the firmware
corruption threats and the mitigations
is actually exist right so in
in
it's actually doesn't provide much
guidance we have a boot integrity we
have a privilege account management and
update software right so you need to use
the recent bios you need to basically
reduce the privileges of the user and
check the integrity of
your bias but
to be honest integrity doesn't provide
much visibility even the integrity
failed so you don't understand what is
cause this failure right and os
privileges doesn't equal to firmware
privileges basically yes you can reduce
a bit attack surface but you will be not
eliminated
also updated
firmware doesn't mean it is secure
firmware because uh based on our
statistics from binary actually one day
vulnerabilities can survive up to two
years in many actually enterprise
vendors and that's kind of scary right
so broken integrity really doesn't tell
us much about an impact too and we need
really to
call the industry and reinvent how we
think about such of the detection and
mitigations for for these problems
because the similar approaches we
currently apply in our operating system
available doesn't work effectively on
the firmware and hardware space
uh but let's talk about the threats
actually we're detecting right now in um
in the wild and
this screenshot made from the mosaic
regressor from ida pro and to be honest
massage aggressor has been one of the
threats detected by in the last year by
kaspersky lab and interestingly
such of the thread
being based on the even older
implant uh firmware implant developed by
hakken team and uh called rk loader
to be honest uh mosaic aggressor
developers didn't remove indicator which
is called the infection indicator for
hiking team and it is um
it is ufi variable with the constant
name fta
and
this five years old indicator why mosaic
regressor takes a while to detect and
actually
provide guidance from the industry for
such of the threats it is ridiculously
long time and to be honest it's
contains both indicators and it's stay
undetected which is exactly prove the
statement which i told before we don't
have effective tools for detecting such
of the threats right
another example it is abusing the
bootloaders of operating system and
basically provides some
sort of
some sort of
in another example it is actually some
of the pocs get developed on top of
modern e5 boot loaders when it's try to
show some random screen screen
with like a pretty simple output of the
strings on
in uefi
console output so basically this is
being detected by eset but to be honest
it's being found on github with source
code and i hope the ransomware will be
not showing up in the firmware space
because it is much more scary than
operating system level because it can
cause uh actually critical failures for
the systems
and
uh to be honest
i demonstrated some uh
uh poc about how from operating system
level to the firmware that title can
persist in black at asia 2017
and it's been in marina bay sands in
singapore hopefully i will be come back
there soon it is awesome venue and
where it's been showing how actually the
attacker can persist survive and
potentially it's quite scary vector for
ransomware right
but let's come back on some uh nowadays
news and uh
what is happening in the wild last month
right so it is a two threats which is
actually being detected in the wild one
of them it is
finn fisher uh state sponsor government
sponsored attack detected by kaspersky
which is being used in the module
where
it is a bootloader with some
[Music]
very
minimal modifications to basically
bootstrap uh
the code for uh providing towards the
operating system malicious payload and
this is a classical boot kit because it
is abused the bootloader not exactly the
firmware and another one it is being
inspector which is uh being detected by
anti-virus company called eset and uh
it's pretty similar techniques get used
by both of these um
uh attackers and uh basically inspector
also uh
interesting because it stayed under the
rudders almost nine years
and
it shows exactly the problem uh industry
not ready to detect um the threads which
is uh under or below the operating
system level right so
where it became very complicated to
detect such of the threats
so
and
if you think about uh which we're being
attacked by inspector and finfisher it
is exactly bootloaders
which is responsible for actually
loading
windows kernel and initialized rest of
the code during the boot
so
of course secure good will save us all
right so but uh on the practice even
secure boot it's not that hard to bypass
and we'll talk uh a bit later how we can
do it with modern attack factors in the
firmware
so but to be honest these techniques
which has been used in the fin fischer
and inspector it's not new and it is
even even been discussed in my book uh
which is being released a few years ago
and
uh
the techniques originally actually been
presented in 2012 by researchers and
only now we get actual detection for
that which is quite scary because
industry looks like not ready for more
complicated threats which is inside the
firmware
and this is actually a snapshot of the
code from the entry point of
of uh one of the bootloaders from the
inspector and we can see clearly here is
a position independent code uh where
the attacker tried to actually
modify the bootloader but stay stable on
execution flow and will be
independent on relocations on whatever
changes in runtime can happens so
basically
this code
obviously looks like not a standard code
produced by the compiler but still why
for detection such of the threads takes
a while
and
it's no easy answer to be honest the
industry have a lot of other problems
but back to the firmware and hardware it
is
some disconnection between
operating system and actual hardware and
firmware threads because it's completely
different worlds and need very specific
expertise to develop effective solution
for that and of course like endpoint
vendors
don't really focus on firmware specifics
because they try to cover the whole
stack and it is uh creates some
complications
because firmware it is
actual uh real-time operating system
nowadays to be honest uh
firmware it is uh six million swines of
the code in your modern laptop actually
more than six million one of the code
and nowadays in in toscarino even
smaller than that
and such of the operating system
executed before
main uh
operating system which is getting
control later and of course
uh this code need to be verified and
monitored otherwise it's hard to
trust everything which is executed
afterwards
and
also the threat modeling for the
hardware firmware and operating system
is completely separated
if you think about we have a three
different ecosystem where the hardware
vendors developing the hardware security
features and then the firmware
developers try to
implement the support some of these
hardware security features in their code
and operating system developers which is
completely separate teams separate
groups or separate companies try to
build something on top of that and this
creates a lot of complications because
we don't have unified software stack
which is protect protect where the
protection is unite right
and of course uh as we go
down to the stack we have a lack of
threat intel signals because we don't
have much visibility there we don't have
much data we don't have a much uh
interfaces to actually produce such of
the data for uh investigations for nsx
and actually protecting the users in our
modern infrastructures and of course
platform boot process is also very
complicated and
it is just
get more and more complicated
uh getting upper to the stack
so and complexity is growing
another good example of this broken
disconnection it is
this
driver which is uh developed by one of
the vendors and actually correctly sign
it this driver introduced some of the
vulnerabilities which is easy to explore
easy to exploit it's been classical
stack overflow and it can be abused for
actually delivering malicious payload
and bypass the secure wood and this
caused all uh movement of
boot hall attack vectors right so i
think
one of the main lessons learned sign it
it doesn't mean trusted and to be honest
it is a
completely different problem where we
have a lot of cyanide drivers which is
contain vulnerabilities which is can
actually be abused to bootstrap and
deliver malicious code to some
privileged mods like a system system
management mode or even others and
another example vulnerability on
hp proliant server which is actually uh
has
also
some memory corruption vulnerability and
allows attacker to uh bypass
secure boot integrity
so um also that's remind me very old uh
problem with mass 16100 which has been
called golden key and presented uh in
2016 at defcon basically vulnerability
allows attacker to bypass the security
feature by using actually sign that good
manager which has been uh vulnerable for
some of
uh some of the uh
problems and actually those are tiger to
bypass windows security features and
this uh
bootloader version can be reused on this
other operating system because it's
signed by microsoft right and before of
that it's been actually a huge problem
so we blindly trust any code which is
come from the trusted source right so if
the code sign it and come from the
trusted source we just
blindly trust any uh any code like that
and it's create a lot of complications
from the industry because we don't have
an ability to understand what is inside
this cyanide coat right so basically uh
what happening right now uh
industry overloaded with integrity
solutions for the firmware but
this integrity solutions provide zero
visibility about their alerts right
uh but let's talk about ecosystem of
modern x86 hardware and
actually
complexity of supply chain
uh we have the hardware vendors
which is actually developing the
hardware and
on top of that we have independent bios
vendors is which is developing some sort
of
frameworks on top of it device
manufacturers developing their code so
basically we have the hardware vendors
delivering the reference code to
independent bias vendors and then they
on top of that developing their code
right so and device manufacturers
actually uh providing less than 10
percent of
initial code base and original equipment
manufacturers uh
shipping this uh
firmwares and hardwares i can't say
blindly but it's a lot of blind spots in
terms of this complexity of supply chain
because like
we trust what is inside reference code
we trust what provided by ibvs and
in the end we have a device
manufacturers which can introduce also
other problems
so this complexity of the supply chain
create a lot of
blind spots for
introducing known vulnerabilities or
complicate patching uh
introducing new vulnerabilities and
complicate watching known
vulnerabilities
and this huge problem for the industry
and to be honest complexity of modern
firmer supply chain is only growing and
get more complicated and
not controlled by any single vendor
completely
so but let's talk about more
how
firmware developers and hardware
companies looks on the identification
such of the threats and what they are
doing and of course here is a big
disconnection between development teams
architects who design and security
features and actual implementation and
as we can see
basically creating the threat model just
based on the stride and other
frameworks for
threat modeling it is not enough
actually we need to understand uh what
the attack surface uh not
uh only today's state we need to
understand what it will be tomorrow uh
on the hands of the attacker just to
predict and mitigate such of the threats
correctly and of course
this framework doesn't provide that
ability and need to be
modified for um to be more connected for
uh
current industry needs
and another problem i think for the
industry we also try to make a lot of
security by obscurity i think actually
open source security firmware foundation
uh making a lot of movement to
make more popular
between the vendors
development processes for open firmware
right so we have a
a lot of activities on open bmc we have
a lot of activities on the core booth
and i hope it will be more transparency
on the firmware level in general because
it's very important and security by
obscurity never works right so and if we
have a
firmware binaries where we have stupid
function names it doesn't remove a lot
of other symbolic information which is
can be analyzed by the analyst and
understands the behavior of the function
and of course it's not removing the
vulnerabilities which is inside the
binaries right so and it's just create
much more problems and actually
complexity of debugging of the problems
than actual profit for protecting the
users
and
also another statement basically
security researchers are you can pilot
the binaries and of course yes
but
if you think about
current
reverse engineering frameworks it's very
effective and if you look it is actually
a
screenshot from one of the functions
from u5 firmware dixie driver and it is
normal
decompilation flow right
i would say it's
it's okay but it's not really readable
right so but after
the plugin which binary team supported
called efi explorer it's completely open
sourced on github so if i explorer
provides some semantic annotations and
makes this code much readable and
provide you some additional symbols
based on
constant and a lot of code context which
is can be extracted automatically so and
this functions and actually look pretty
close to the original logic of
the function in the source code and
analyzing these functions is pretty easy
that's mean like security by security
doesn't work because we have a lot of
already know that will have a lot of
novel techniques to code similarity for
symbols
reconstruction a lot of other stuff
which is
of course providing modern reverse
engineers a lot of new tooling and make
their work more effective it's why we
need to think how we can protect and
mitigate thermal threats more
effectively with current reality and
don't try to come back in early 2000s
and think about security by obscurity as
a security feature
also another story it is about few
vulnerabilities which we presented
earlier this year
visa my colleagues
from nvidia so basically uh they found
few vulnerabilities in a
dell power h server and one of them in
crystal ridge dixie driver another in a
platform initialization driver one it's
actually classical stack overflow and
another the hip overflow
but it's already actually well
documented in our slides from blackhead
vegas this year and those you can find
binary blog post explaining these
problems but interestingly why
this problem on these slides i want to
show you how current state of uh modern
exploitation for the firmware it looks
like
so uh first vulnerability actually it's
just
get some ufi variable which is can be
controlled by the attacker attacker can
uh write to this q5 variable and it can
cause
some hip overflow and corrupt the memory
and in that attacker can lead the code
execution so this crystal rich dixie
driver is quite interesting because it
is tied to the new type of the memory
developed by intel
and of course
this new type of memory
can be used
by
an attacker to
actually abuse
this vulnerability and it's been stay
and pass quite a while
to be honest and
exploitation it's
not very complicated but also which is
more scary this vulnerability by pass
any sort of integrity checking and the
attacker can in run time get execution
which will be not detected by any sort
of health station based on the tpm
because
tpm pcrs can be extended in runtime
and of course
both of these vulnerabilities is
actually
providing some sort of
context
about how it is easy to bypass modern uh
boot integrity process and boot
verification process and secondly
actually cross the security boundaries
where we execute the code and can
transplant to the operating system and
attack
from the lower stack the upper stack
effectively but they don't even need to
exploit this
vulnerabilities because it's been
another bug we found
together with nvidia team and
intel uh bssidft it's been a feature was
designed to run some arbitrary and same
cloud code uh stored in efi variable but
of course it's intel reference code and
this feature being actually totally
developed for
debugging reasons
but
uh in the end not all the vendors been
effectively disabling this feature which
is of course tied to the supply chain
problem and can cause a lot of
security failures in modern data centers
it's not infrastructure
so
uh
all the details about this vulnerability
you can find in our blackhead slides and
also binary block called attacking
pre-fire ecosystem but in short
this
vulnerability allows the attacker to
ride up to 100 kilobyte
binary blob which is can be
executed during the platform
initialization phase and it's pretty
early phase where the hardware gets
initialized and uh system management
mode and dixie it's not initialized yet
so attacker have an ability to influence
a lot on later phases of the boot
process and
this uh because this
actual design feature
it's very stable way of get the code
execution right and it's quite scary
such of the epoch
and
design problems it's actually create
very complicated problems in in
in detection and response for the modern
hardware ecosystems in the data centers
and of course the same problem it will
not uh detected by a health attack
station or tpm uh because uh pcrs will
be not extended and these registers
usually stored the hashes right so and
basically these hashes are
pre-calculated and any runtime
exploitation bypass such of the
technology easily because it just not
been designed to detect any sort of
exploitations like that
and
of course as we discussed before
a lot of vendors don't disable this
feature because it is being
introduced for
debugging purposes but interestingly
it's been another logical bug uh caused
an intel reference code where
the function which need to be emulate
physical presence of the jumper and
returning someone's information about if
activity of this feature of
this ssadft it's been always returning
true and cause some
problems because it's been hard to
detected it's been failure logic
and
as you can see it's not been this
vulnerability not been attacking the
single vendor it's actually caused the
whole industry problem with a lot of
different vendors get
vulnerable for um
this vulnerability and actually of
course different vendors have a
different patch cycles and
all of this reflecting on uh
ecosystem and basically uh even
single vulnerability in the intel
reference code can cause outage of many
many many other platforms and we see
here it's not only
vendors which is
just the usual
mainstream enterprise vendors for the
laptops it is actually servers it is
critical infrastructure and network
appliances
so we blindly trust
everything which is brake it and silicon
and not only to the firmware because we
don't have a tooling we don't have an
ability to vidify our hardware and we
have some sort of
hangover from the past
where
uh actually we really hear the story
about the bloomberg and supermicro also
counter fire device that is not rare and
f-secure laps actually provide been
providing very interesting story about
fake cisco appliances with uh actual uh
backdoors on it so i think uh it's a lot
of uh new challenges for the industry to
fix such of the problems but i think
we need to find the complex way how we
can stop the modern attacker and don't
let them hack modern infrastructures
because it's make
a lot of
it's gives them too much power to
influence in uh
in our companies and actually our lives
and this is my thoughts and thank you
very much
for uh spending some time at today's
morning and i wish you the
happy thing on 2021 i see a lot of
interesting topics in the agenda and
it's been big pleasure for me to be on
the stage again thank you very much
bye-bye
thank you very much alex for the
insightful keynote
all q and a with our speakers will be
done by this chord so make sure you get
on it
and that's it for singcon 2021 keynote
segment starting at 11 30 we will be
starting our three tracks our main stage
workshops and open biz contract
see you all then