if you've been a member of our community
of for any length of time you've seen
this next speaker here in Augusta that
besides our here security icons been a
longtime fan of security at Mindy's
recent we've been added to the team at
security lighting solutions which are
all super excited about as well so I
need power all right how's everyone
doing doing all right don't panic right
so I'm already connected up at the other
thought the other one and might go great
I know something always happens right
but this is great you guys did great as
Phil mentioned I was also gonna say
there's no way that I can be the next
speaker afterlife or larger-than-life
Doug is wheeled in and so we'll see how
this goes we have lunch coming up so
it'll be a good it'll be good time next
30 45 minutes as Phil mentioned my name
is Josh Brauer been in IT 15 plus years
and InfoSec 10 plus years recently Joey
a security onion about six weeks ago
it's been a good six weeks thank you
Doug and the rest of the team and Thank
You Devin rest of the team for this
conference this is definitely conference
this and besides Augusta I make sure I
tend every single year so today real
quick you can catch me on twitter at
defensive depth today we're going to be
talking about constructing your PlayBook
with insecurity onion and Chris you gave
me a great segue thank you so much
wherever you kind of ended up talking
about playbook so it's almost like we
had that planned thank you very much in
the beginning
Doug created the onion right and I've
run that security onion for many years
in production in my previous when my
previous organizations and last few
years I've really spent a lot of time
and effort on integrating more endpoint
data into the security onion ecosystem
last year I spoke about OS query and
integrating Oh square data into security
onion previous to that we talked about
sis Mon and all the runs and so we
really have just spent a lot of time to
last three to five years on integrating
host data into secure Union
I've also integrated and used the hive
and cortex
which Wes talked about this morning
we'll get into that much right now we'll
see it in just a second here but what I
would do is I would push my alerts over
to them um yeah now don't start that
okay so I would push my alerts over to
the hive in cortex and to have some of
that some of that some of that
integration that even Wes was talking
about this morning
and as I started working on more alerts
around host data I started working on
detections like this this is um you know
title news sensitive shared resource
network shares with loose access
controls are common places that leak
sensitive information this detection
proactively looks for newly shared
resources that likely contain sensitive
data follow-up will be needed to confirm
that appropriate access control is and
I'm in this particular detection it's
based on OS query because I'm hitting
that I'm gonna try not to step on this
this is OS query based and so we have
the O's query query we also have the
elastic search query what happens is you
have most query deployed to your
endpoints you schedule a query it says
looks for new shared resources like map
drives you know shared drives things
like that and then sends it back to
elastic search with security onion and
then we have an elastomer rule based off
of this query and we're looking for
keywords like HR finance backup dub dub
dub or scan to alert on what happened is
as I started writing more of these
detections and trying to scale it up it
became a very manual process right so I
would first I would write the elastol ER
config file I'd even using a template
and then manually copy and paste that a
last alert config then that would create
a case template with the hive manually
and then I'd have a wiki down here that
I would I would excuse me put all of
this information out on
and every time I wanted to update that
detection I had to go through all of
those different places and manually
update them and that's where I decided
there's got to be a better way to do
this can we figure out some way that
maybe automate a lot of this and that's
where the idea of the PlayBook was
formed I really took inspiration from a
book published back in 2015 called
crafting the InfoSec playbook anybody
read this yes a few okay so in this
excuse me in this context I know one in
our industry we use the word playbook
and play and a few different for it to
mean a few different things in this
context we're specifically talking about
a playbook made up of plays plays are
simply custom reports okay and these
custom reports our self-contained fully
documented prescriptive procedures for
finding and responding to undesired
activity and this is to me really key by
building the documentation and
instructions into the play we have
directly coupled the motivation for the
play how to analyze it and the specific
machine query for it all right those
three aspects I think are really
important so drawing from this I started
working on the concept that I simply
call play book sits in the middle here
and it allows me to easily document my
detection strategies number one
motivation number two next steps so when
we get results from running this report
or these this custom query what am I
supposed to do to validate that and
finally the specific elasticsearch query
that we need for security onion also it
needs to be able to easily manage the
last alert rules and easily manage the
hive case templates which we use for
next steps no more this manual
processing right should do all that
based on based on the detection right up
here in number one and so I'm going to
demo for you what I simply call playbook
it is something that you can download
and use in hybrid hunter security and
hybrid hunter it definitely is still
alpha and would be considered not
something you necessarily want to put
into production but it is live and ready
to use
for testing at this point so we're gonna
see how the demo turns out it's making
sense so far yes somewhat
I'm good with awkward silences as well
yes great thank you so much all right
so first off I am logged into hybrid
hunter a local install of hybrid hunter
let me make that a little bit bigger
here and it's just the IP address slash
playbook
I go to sign-in I sign in with the
analyst user with changed me a very
super-secret password make that a little
cleaner here so we already have a couple
plays imported it to playbook let's
let's go ahead and drill down into this
one right here you can see that the name
of this one is maybe ksdc sync we have
some metadata about it the author's
including references excuse me we have
the attack technique tagged and the
objective result analysis and the actual
elasticsearch a query that we need to
use for security onion we also have this
view Sigma down here so west's already
gave us a great introduction to Sigma is
anybody here I didn't actually see the
hands and how many here are using or
have used Sigma in the past a few maybe
a quarter of the room okay so Sigma
think of snort rules for network data
think of Y are rules for file data Sigma
is for logs okay loud it's a
specification that we can write out our
detections in alright and I did I chose
to really develop playbook around Sigma
number one it's a standard I didn't have
to develop myself and secondly allows us
to easily share the place and import
import detections from other people so
first off we're going to go ahead and
create a new play come over here and
click on new play we're going to import
the Sigma put it into the external
playbook and then we have a place right
here to paste the Sigma now if I scroll
over to
right here I have this is Sigma that I
wrote specifically for that detection
strategy that I just mentioned so we
have a title up here description which
I've already told you status author tags
log source this is coming from most
query and then the actual query itself
that we need the detection I won't get
into that right now
but down here there is a section called
tasks this is not in the course Sigma
spec this is something that I've added
and this allows us to have specific
tasks for this detection for how you
validate or what are the next steps so
for this particular detection strategy
we say check share permissions our share
permissions sent to an appropriate level
they should be tied to the relevant ATS
security group and then contact system
service owner again this active we're
trying to proactively find of
information and we want to proactively
find that so what we're going to do is
copy and paste this Sigma right here hit
create what this does is create a new
play based on that Sigma we drill down
into that new play that was just created
you can see that we have the new type
the title new sensitive shared resources
it pulled out all the metadata from the
Sigma it also gave us our objective
result analysis the elastic search query
so if you saw from the Sigma that right
here we have the elastic search query is
not in here right so what's actually
happening is that when playbook is
importing the Sigma it's using a tool
put out by these Sigma authors that
configures or that that converts the
Yambol that you just saw into the
machine query that you need for your
back-end so it could be Splunk in our
case it's elastic search so it's
converting that detection into elastic
search and it's also there's some config
files that we need for OS query or
excuse me for OS query and some other
event logs that we ship and so Wes and
I've written a couple configuration
files for security onion
compatibility with Sigma so all that's
happening in the back end you don't have
to worry about that so the end of the
day you're gonna get a query that is
specific to this play and that will give
us results once we once we see this
alert in just a second we want to edit
this
we just hit edit we edit the actual
Sigma itself so let's say it's a little
bigger you see that we're looking for
some some specific share names so HR
finance backup let's say the HR is to
false positive prone so we delete that
we make a note that we have deleted the
HR string too many false positives write
it submit this on the fly regenerates
that elastic search query and it also
gives us a very nice diff as well as
that comment and so this is really key
because once you put a play into
production and as you tweak it over time
you're gonna want to be able to see the
history that why did I change that so
why did I tweak that six months ago or
as a new analyst you get hits on the
play you want to go back and find out
the history of why you know what is
history of this play what if other
people talked about why did we remove HR
from it does that making sense okay
so excuse me once you're ready and
you're feeling comfortable with this we
can go to edit we can change the status
from draft to active it submits and
there's a couple things happening in the
background number one playbook is
creating in the last alert rule file
based on the play so it's using
templates if it's an OS query rule it'll
use the query template otherwise it'll
use some other generic templates we have
so right now we have this play in
production using a last alert all behind
the scenes and then it's also creating a
hive take our case template come over
here to the hive under admin case
templates you can see that we have some
case templates that we've automatically
did this the template name is that play
ID from over here in the play you can
see we have the description already the
play objective the link to the play book
as well as these specific tasks that was
in that Sigma okay so you can tie the
Sigma and the detection strategy
directly to the case template and we'll
see what that looks like from an alert
perspective in just a minute
alright so we've created that the last
alert config we've created the hive case
template this is all active let's go
ahead and generate a new alert based off
of this and if you recall we're looking
for new shared drives so and this is
based on OS query so we'll flip over to
Clyde fleets Clyde flee now ships with
hybrid hunter we've integrated it very
closely so you run one command
it sets up a fleet and O's query
generates packages Osprey packages so
you can download them very easily you
install them and deploy them in your to
your different endpoints you can see we
currently have a Windows 10 system and
we have the hybrid hunter system online
I've already scheduled I'm not going to
go into depth about how fleet works
right now but you can see we've already
scheduled this query so query 601 is
that query that we're using so we've
already scheduled that so every 30
seconds we'll go back to packs every 30
seconds oh is query is checking to see
if there's any new shared resources on
the Windows 10 system if it finds
anything new it will send that log back
to security onion and then from there
put it into elasticsearch and then the
last alert will find it and alert on it
okay that's kind of the pipeline so
let's flip over to the Windows 10 system
and that looks great all right so I've
got I'm on the root of the C Drive I got
backup folder I've got my financials and
QuickBooks backups in here I just need
to get this backed up by our enterprise
backup systems so I'm just gonna do a
real quick share
because we've never had people do this
right I'm just gonna share with
everybody I just need to get it working
don't worry I'll come back I'll fix this
share permissions later once the backup
is working right we've done this before
all right just a minute I'll come back
to that later
okay so once we're going to let that run
and query we'll see the difference I'll
send that lag that bug over while we're
waiting for that log let me show you one
other piece to to playbook so you have
seen that we have a lot of these plays
tagged with mitre attack framework tags
I just break something it's possible so
we see that there are some of these like
we have this attack technique right here
tagged and so we also ship a app called
my attack navigator this is a web app
put out by mitre that allows you to
visualize the different techniques that
are part of the framework we have this
right here you just go to IP address
slash so navigator ships with playbook
and what happens is every time you
change the status of a play we
regenerate the JSON file so that's all
the blue in here if i refresh this we
should see we should see our detection
coverage so the network share discovery
that is based on the tagged plays over
here in PlayBook ok
and so if we right click we can say view
technique and that brings us to
we'll even slicker when it works right
and so then you also right-click and
save you related plays that will bring
up the playbook with all of the tagged
plays that you currently have in
production okay and that's that is based
off of all the plays that you have tat
or that you have a change of status from
to active does that making sense so far
okay allows you to visualize your allows
you to visualize the coverage that you
have from a technique perspective
specifically in the playbook all right
so I have talked enough we should have
an alert we'll see we do have an alert
to alerts so again what's happened is OS
query found that new super drive sent
that log back over to secure the onion
and elasticsearch a last alert has that
configured rule from playbook and it
generated an alert based on that and it
sent that alert to the hive and that's
what we're seeing right here so we have
one right here from last learn and
security on a new sense of shared
resource so if we preview that the
hostname is the the Windows 10 hostname
the pivot link this allows us to pivot
directly to fleets and if the system is
online we can say select star from
shared resources and it already pre
selects the system there so hit run and
that will allow us to see that we do
actually have a new shared resource on
there called backup so let's go ahead
and import that and we see there's some
other indicators here import that and
you see that it's already going to show
us right here we're importing it with a
case templates so once we import that we
have our play objective we have the play
book link so we can go directly to that
see more information about it we also
have our tasks
we need to complete so I'm going to
first check the share permissions on the
Windows 10 system or this system that's
involved and so that gives us that task
so I'm making sense so far so from the
very beginning we have created a play
detection play edited it we have made it
change to status active that created the
last alerts and a rule file excuse me as
well as the hive case templates we
generated some log data that trip that
alert and then we imported that alert in
the hive as a case now suffice to say if
I went back to play book and edited that
that detection strategy that play it
would go out and update all of the other
pieces it would update the hive case
template as well as the alas lair config
if I went back and say disable that play
or move that to an inactive state and
we'll go ahead and remove that alas lurk
config will keep the hive case template
there but it will go ahead and remove
that alert out of last alerts ok now you
may be saying this is great Josh but I'm
not really comfortable writing Sigma at
this point that look like a lot of stuff
I'm not really comfortable the great
thing is is that there is a lot of
people that put out Sigma signatures on
a regular basis Wes already mentioned it
Florian Roth one of the authors of Sigma
on a regular basis tweets out tweets out
signatures one of them from earlier this
week
Sigma rule to detect form bug process
injection with specific sub processes so
the rule is right here we're going to
open that we're just going to hit raw
copy that come over to playbook new play
paste it and create and that brings it
in it's still filtering clear that out
that brought it in as a new play ok
and it also generated the elastic alas
excuse me the elastic search query that
we need for security onion all right so
you don't have to necessarily write your
own Sigma you can go out and find stuff
that's already written out there now a
couple caveats right now Sigma
we have compatibility for logs that are
shipped to OA square widows query win
beat log are the windows event logs
shipped with wind beat log and then
network data shipped found with bro
I believe that's all we have currently
at this point so if you want to generate
any of that signal with those log
sources that should work in security
onion all right so I think that's it for
my demo and it did work so any questions
comments or snide remarks I don't even
know how much time I have left yes thank
you so much Mike for pointing that out
yes exactly so if you don't if this is
really the crux of it is I was sitting
there manually trying to figure out the
different elastol Ertz op rule options
the file options okay if I want to if I
want to alert this way here's how I have
to do it oh I ran into that issue okay
let me copy and paste this over here
that was one of the key issues of why I
did this with playbook is that that's
all abstracted for you you write the
detection in Sigma you paste it into
PlayBook and it writes those last alert
configs for you thanks Mike I also have
there's a bunch of other Sigma
signatures out there that you can that
you can use I have written a bulk import
script command line script I haven't
quite got it ready yet but we can bulk
import a bunch of Sigma signatures as
well into playbook that should be
something forthcoming at some point
thing else something that you guys think
you might use might be useful yes okay
certainly any feedback is useful both of
these run in docker containers attack
navigator and then PlayBook is simply
read mine open source project management
solution that we've tweaked a bit that
runs in docker as well and then on the
back end it's sending a web hook every
time you you change this or anytime you
change the
status of one of those plays sends a web
hook to soft puss which is that Python
app that Wes was talking about and then
based on the web hook we do all the
automation from there so that's all open
source and available for you to look at
tweak and and send pr's to us all right
anything else feel like I just want to
get some lunch right okay thank you all
so much
[Applause]