stop it stop it stop it stop it
good morning everybody and welcome to
security onion conference 2019 I'm very
excited to be here today hope you are as
well I was amazed to see the number of
hands that were lifted when the
gentleman asked for folks from out of
town that's just amazing so let me echo
those comments of welcoming you to the
great city of Augusta and the great
state of Georgia we are very happy to
have you here today and it's going to be
a great day are you excited excellent
we're excited too I want to make sure
that I say thank you to a whole bunch of
folks starting with our sponsors of
course Talos MIT bit duel con technology
applied Network defense these are great
sponsors they've done a great job of
helping us out with this conference so
make sure that you get on social media
and say thank you to these sponsors for
being a part of this very special event
I want to say thanks to some other folks
of course my my family at Sakura onion
solutions mr. Phillips I know Mira who
you've met Wes Lambert Mike grieves
definitely William work Josh Brower
Karen long we are a growing family now
here at secure dining solutions and I
really appreciate all the work that
these folks have done to get us to this
point this is not about me this is a
whole lot more work than I could do by
myself so I really appreciate all the
work the blood sweat and tears that you
guys put into it so around applause for
them
let's say thanks to our speakers we got
an awesome speaker line-up if you're
here today there's probably a good
reason that you're here today and that's
probably because you want to hear some
of these great speakers folks like Wes
Lambert Chris Sanders Steph Rand Josh
Brower Wylie Bates Brian trickle and
Sean and this is just we're so excited
about these topics and what they're
talking about these folks are passionate
they've got some great content so we're
excited to hear from them today some
other things other folks that we want to
thank of course the Georgia cyber center
we really appreciate you hosting us in
this beautiful facility today
lish Mike Stokes who is out of the
registration desk Mike McDonald are
running our photography and AV crew so
thank you gentlemen for doing that and
of course as with every year I want to
make sure that I recognize some very
important folks my parents are here
hearing cinder Burks if you all would
stand up please come on mom stand up
stand up mom there you go there here you
go so my parents bought me my first
computer when I was six years old and if
they hadn't done that if that had not
happened this would not have happened
right so I'm very appreciative for that
and of course my lovely wife Trish Burks
who I don't believe is here yet but if
you see her sometime today make sure to
give her a high five or a fist bump for
putting up with me especially during
busy weeks like this week which is the
busiest week of the entire year so thank
you all to all of these many folks for
helping us do what we do and really make
it a community effort so I think that's
all the things that I have if I
forgotten anything all right so it
occurs to me that well number one I have
a confession to make
don't tell anybody and I would imagine
that one or two of you may self-identify
as an introvert as well and with the
number of folks who raised their hands
as out-of-town visitors I would imagine
that you don't know everybody in this
room so what I thought we would do is
take just a minute I want everybody to
stand up and I want you to find somebody
that you've never met in your entire
life before and I want you to introduce
yourself so we're building community
here today starting right first thing in
the morning so welcome everybody
[Applause]