distinguished colleagues ladies and
gentlemen I am very sorry not to be able
to be in durban with you personally for
this I con 47 meeting as you may recall
I had the privilege to address your
meeting in Cairo back in november two
thousand eight it is a tremendous
pleasure to be able to join you again
this time remotely using the power of
technology to bring us closer together I
would like to thank you for your
invitation to address you this morning
and in particular let me thank my good
friend fadi chehade and dr. Steve
Crocker as well as the icon board
members for inviting ITU to this meeting
ladies and gentlemen in terms of global
communications we are living through the
most exciting period in human history we
are on the brink of seeing as many
mobile cellular phones as they are
people on the planet and by the end of
this year some 2.7 billion people will
be using the internet with 2.1 billion
active mobile broadband subscriptions at
the same time as we come into 2014
almost seventy percent of people in the
developing world will still be offline
with no access to the world's greatest
library the world's most active
marketplace and the world's greatest
social gatherings this is something we
must all work hard to change because it
is clearly a matter of social and
economic justice and fairness we should
also remember that increasing access to
the online world benefits everyone
including those who already have access
by expanding markets opening up new
opportunities for communication and
richer dialogue and content and as we
all know in the 21st century the
internet is now a global resource a
basic commerce
any valuable international platform for
exchange and learning distinguished
colleagues last November four years
after my first attendance of your
meeting in Cairo I had the privilege to
meet fadi chehade who had just been
confirmed as CEO of icon at the IGF in
Baku this was just one month before the
world conference on international
telecommunications wicked 12 and I was
impressed by fatties desire to reach out
and build bridges we shared and continue
to share the goal of working together by
cultivating a relationship based on
collaboration and cooperation were very
pleased that fatty Shehadeh and Steve
Crocker came two wickets in Dubai and
were able to contribute to the important
debate they're both fatty and Steve also
came to the world telecommunication and
ICT policy forum in Geneva in May this
year where the main theme was
internet-related public policy issues
icon as the leading institution managing
critical internet resources was a key
stakeholder in this global debate and I
was very pleased that icon staff
including my good friend Nigel Hickson
participated actively throughout the
multi-stakeholder preparatory process
and at the policy forum itself at the
WTF fatty again reiterated something I
always believed in myself personal
courage grace and reciprocity is what we
all need to show in working together
ladies and gentlemen I am very pleased
that I 2 and I can are growing in our
understanding of one another and I think
it is clear that our two organizations
have complementary roles could I
therefore suggest that the time may be
right to move our relationship into a
stronger footing perhaps through a more
formal partner
between our two organizations focused on
greater collaboration and cooperation
while clearly respecting our distinct
roles and mandates indeed I believe the
timing could not be better for such a
move I tues plenipotentiary conference
will be taking place in little over a
year and our membership has already
kicked off the process to define our
strategy for the years to come icon has
also embarked on a new five-year
strategic planning process which
includes areas of considerations such as
role clarity and internationalization
and regional development I've been
keenly following your open and inclusive
public consultation process and we'll be
bringing relevant points back to I tues
membership to keep them better informed
in their deliberations I believe that a
key component of ITU strategic planning
process will be a clear understanding of
the roles and responsibilities of our
respective organizations and also the
areas in which we can collaborate on and
complement one another distinguished
colleagues we all share the same
long-term vision the vision of the world
where everyone is able to fully
participate in the interconnected
knowledge driven economy and society
from Geneva to Durban from Delhi to
South Georgia in the Antarctic from Los
Angeles to the remotest islands in the
Great Pacific Ocean the vision of the
world where everyone can exchange ideas
access health care and education
innovate and sell products and services
and stay in touch with family and
friends the vision of a world connected
by high-speed communication networks and
supported by the appropriate underlying
infrastructure and services enabling
governments businesses civil society
academia and every citizen to connect
build partnerships collaborate and trade
I
were asked to address global challenges
such as climate change and disaster
mitigation the vision of the world in
which the risk and downsides of
participating in the global community
are properly addressed so that they do
not overshadow the benefits to users and
especially the most vulnerable including
children and the vision of the world
which is fully inclusive regardless of
physical ability gender income levels or
language spoken Nazarite EU nor icon nor
any other single entity can achieve this
vision alone it can only be brought
about by a broad yet close collaboration
between a multitude of global regional
national and local stakeholders it can
only be brought about through the
efforts of all players using our best
skills expertise and people there are
clearly disagreements and differences of
opinion on how various challenges on the
way toward achieving this vision should
be addressed this is normal given the
nature of the rapidly changing and
increasingly complex world we live in
open multi-stakeholder discussion remain
a very healthy way for the international
community to seek solutions to
contemporary challenges and this is a
very important point that I would like
to make in conclusion in a fast moving
rapidly evolving environment there are
no permanent or even long-term solutions
what works today will not necessarily
work tomorrow so this needs to be a
continuous process bringing all
stakeholders to the table in an
inclusive dialogue this is the road we
are travelling along together not a
destination we are trying to reach I
look forward to continuing to benefit
from our shared journey together along
that road it is clear that I tu and icon
will be taking this journey together
and that is something I look forward to
very much thank you very much for your
attention