gentlemen I can 47 has just concluded
the focus all week very much on the
Internet in Africa a lot of discussion
about its positive possibilities but
also a need to build infrastructure and
to educate in that context what are your
takeaways from this meeting well I will
relate a story this morning a number of
us had the distinct opportunity to go to
a Township here in Durban to paint to
school and as we arrived and we sang
happy birthday hits Mandela Day here
today I was asked I was whisked into a
classroom of the 30 or so 14 year olds
to talk to them and of course my opening
question was how many of you have heard
about the internet only one child raised
his hand I could not believe it I
thought maybe I couldn't communicate so
I I probed further only one child said
yeah my mom uses it they're 14 year olds
in a township in Durban eager to learn
wonderful faces great spirit but no
connectivity so I'm glad to say that
through the great work of zegna our
partners and our host here a commitment
was immediately made to the school to
the principal the a computer lab will be
connected to the internet and it will
all be paid for for the next two years
frankly more of this should happen more
of us at ICANN meetings need to engage
with the local community this was a
great first and I hope we keep doing
this moving forward Steve picking up on
what font just said at the opening
ceremony you stressed the desire for I
can to remain empathetic even as it
expands globally talk to me about that
yeah actually let me expand in two ways
as an organization one of the
opportunities that we have because we're
not a government organization or
embedded in a beaker bureaucracy is to
not only do our job well and we've I've
stressed in the past effectiveness and
efficiency but I realized that it's it's
possible that you can be effective and
efficient and be cold and distant and
difficult to deal with and that's not
what we want we want exactly the
opposite we want to be a positive
experience in dealing with us the other
aspect of which I think relates very
strongly to what body has just said is
that a very important part of us is that
we are not a single actor we're part of
an internet ecosystem we have we
interact with other organizations and we
cannot be successful unless the entire
ecosystem is successful so it's exactly
this kind of engagement with the
community and in this case a school in
Durban but in general with the with the
broader community and to work in
partnership both with our near partners
like the supporting organization CC NSO
which is got a special place in my heart
or or more broadly throughout the entire
in
I mean Brad the facts are clear only one
in six people in Africa are connected to
the Internet there's a lot of work to do
we I can and our community as Steve said
must increase our commitment to serving
and growing the use of the DNS and the
internet and the servicing of the new
businesses and the new growth that is
being seen in Africa but on the good
side Africa is now the fastest growing
continent in GDP terms it is also a
competent that is seeing a huge growth
in schooling both secondary schooling
enrollment has grown by nearly
forty-eight percent in the last eight
years so this is the trends are all
there the engines of economic growth are
there we need to be here and supportive
of the areas that have the most
difficulties and need our help not stay
away from this now we must still do this
within the remit of I can this is not
about I can expanding its mission it's
about doing it within our mission but
doing it with with our resources doing
it with our great spirit the spirit of
an organization that has empathy so what
you're saying funny is it would be
unfair to simply look at those low
penetration rates internet penetration
rates one also has to look at those
growth numbers yes absolutely Africa is
now frankly leading the world in growth
and all of the eyes of the world are on
the African engine right now and frankly
unlike past spurts in African growth all
the experts agree now that Africa's
growth seems quite sustainable and quite
real and as many factors support why the
growth is happening
so I'm very pleased and I think Africa
will remain on icons strategy focus we
are efforts here have to grow our team
here has to grow but always in
partnership with our local most capable
community whether it's ice hawk who's
very present in Africa or the ccTLDs
with their aft LD leadership
organization or it's the w3c afrinic who
has done superb work across the
continent all of them are here we want
to join them and put our efforts and our
hands with them thoughti also at
Monday's opening events we had a
ceremonial signing for the registrar and
registry agreements tell me how
important is this in terms of a
milestone for the gtld program when you
have very senior executives from from
one registry shed tears as they were
signing it you can tell this was an
emotional milestone as well as a
practical mind stone that shows that i
can has moved into execution mode
getting contracts signed releases all
the energies of the applicants into the
right direction now not just to make the
program get off the ground now their
energies are to make the TL these
meaningful to the market and to build
industries to build communities exactly
the purpose why the new gTLDs were
introduced so indeed I believe this is a
huge milestone and one that puts the
program frankly in positive territory
moving towards that last mile which as
we discussed and committed to we are
confident will happen towards the end of
this year Steve also this week it's the
10th anniversary of the CC NSO the
country code names supporting
organization which you mentioned earlier
significant is that we have contractual
relationships and hence very
frequent and extensive interactions with
the gtld space with generic games but
the country code top-level domains are
there's a couple hundred of them they
are an enormous wealth of a diversity of
richness of the depth in in every
dimension in culture and experience and
operational capability and I I think
that they are the real backbone of the
internet DNS infrastructure and and
they're they're both interdependent with
each other and independent and as I say
I think that they provide a great source
of insight and expertise so I've always
looked to them as strong partners as
strong colleagues and so this this is
there as you said their tenth
anniversary and I thought that that's
quite noteworthy and worth celebrating
they've had very good leadership and
this time also marks a change from
leslie cali stepping down she's the
managing director of nominate and Byron
hallett Holland who is her counterpart
for the Canadian registry sarah is
stepping in i've had the pleasure of
working closely with both of them as
well as other leaders and it really is a
remarkable and Samba of talent there
fani tell me a little bit about the
panels that you announced on Wednesday
and what that means for I can strategy
as i said the ICANN strategy panels are
here to inform and provide feedback to
the strategy planning process as well as
the subsequent operating planning
process so the strategy planning process
should take us through the end of this
year immediately on the heels of it will
start an operating plan process the
strategy panels are here to frankly
inform
both of these and inform them on these
five areas that we felt listening to the
community receiving feedback from the
community through the website we said
that these five areas are areas that
frankly require more in-depth analysis
and more in-depth information these I
want to emphasize that these five
strategy panels are not going to in any
way shape or form circumvent any I can
processes such as our PDP process to
develop policy they're not designed to
do that and they're not in a place to do
that there are simply places where
dialogue will happen in fact with input
from the community during this week I
have instructed my team that each of
these panels must start its mission by
having a town hall meeting by listening
to the community and that halfway
through their progress they must do
another town hall to chat and discuss
with the community what they have
learned and then towards the end before
they publish their recommendation again
another town hall so they are embedded
in the community they will be made up of
people in the community and all they
will do at the end is inform the
community not me not the board inform
the community to aid us in the process
of creating for I can solid strategies
and solid operating plans for the year's
end we're recording this interview on
Mandela Day the 95th birthday of Nelson
Mandela what is it like in that context
to be in this country on this continent
on this day it is said
this is extremely special for me I've
followed as many of us have his life and
what he's done he's clearly an
inspiration to the world not just to
South Africans he's bigger than any man
in my memory this time we live I landed
in Joburg and the first thing I did with
my wife is to go to sweat Oh to visit
his home where he struggled his home
that was burned and he suffered in it
with his family and had to build walls
within the house to dodge bullets for
his girls what is amazing about his
spirit as we call him here and people
call Madiba Madiba is the word that
means really the conciliator the one who
brings people together and that's a very
very powerful word and he did that he
brought a lot of people together this
country is one because of him and many
parts of the world learned from the
spirit of oneness that comes from Madiba
and frankly we at I can have just
enjoyed what I believe is a very United
week it was remarkable in its unity and
its tranquility it doesn't mean we stop
making our points and we stop being very
proactive and vigilant and ensuring that
the multi-stakeholder model and the
policies that produces are the right
places I think this is a mark of a
community that is alive having said that
this was permeated by spirit of common
purpose a spirit of working together
that in my heart I believe comes from
the great spirit of madiba Steve you're
an internet pioneer you've seen this
amazing growth of the internet which is
oftentimes called the great equalizer
that has brought the world together
globally
what is it like for you in that context
to be here in this place on this day
well it touches my heart without any
question this is growing up in school
and reading about South Africa during
the times that were part ID and then
being able to come here to a modern
society which feels open feels free and
to not only and experience the warmth
which Africa South Africa are famous for
but the level of sophistication and
erudition and real experience and
building institutions at getting along
with each other making things work and
it's really it's really quite
pleasurable as it marks you a gentleman
thank you very much thank