it's an extraordinary pleasure to be
here it's a pleasure to be back in
Africa it's a pleasure to be back in
South Africa so much energy so much good
feeling and in fact it's caused a
crystallization of some ideas that have
been floating around in my mind which I
will come back to in just a second we
have as we often do at ICANN meetings
many many things that are going on it's
a very busy time and a lot of
intersections I want to start by
recognizing some guests who are not on
stage with me but who are very critical
members of what we call the iced our
community the internet ecosystem we have
I can see re i can see Lynn and oh and i
can see Paul good okay Lynn st. amour
let me ask you just to stand briefly I
know how much you like grabbing the
limelight here she doesn't president and
CEO of the Internet Society Paul Wilson
who's the CEO of the asia-pacific
network information center that is the
regional internet registry for numbers
and Paul is also chair of the entire
numbered resource organization this year
yari are co-chair of the internet
Engineering Task Force we are we have a
singular moment in time yari is wearing
a newcomers badge he's not only first
time here but I believe he's the first
time that a sitting ietf chair has
visited us we're going to return the
favor shortly with fadi going to an ITF
meeting in a couple of weeks and so
welcome yari
we have some very distinguished people
on stage here with me i will give fuller
introductions in a moment but dr. house
cosmic dodge are my halfway close the
chairman of the zonda who is the ccTLD
for South Africa and host of our meeting
dr. mhmm abraham commissioner from the
African Union hamadoun touré is not
here but we will be seeing a video from
him and last but definitely not least
what I expect will be the first of many
things that we will hear from locanda
Ladon de Loup dinda right that's better
I need to practice anything and I will
come back and introduce them a little
more fully shortly we only could take a
minute or two because there's there's
more important things to to be said but
the coming to Durban I'm struck by how
pleasant the weather is in what is been
reputed I'm familiar considerably
harsher than this and one of the one of
the things when always thinks about in
winter is how soon spring is going to
come and for those of us in the northern
hemisphere we've just left spring and
it's a long way away but coming here
spring is coming sooner which is a sort
of hokey way of getting to the point I
want to make about the vibrancy that I
sense throughout our entire community
and particularly in the supporting
organizations and the advisory
committees each one it seems to be going
through a kind of a rebirth a
reauthorization and
and I can see them not only intensively
focused internally but also looking
sideways at the at each other's
organizations and even a little small
sense of competition for for attention
there's much to say about each of them
but I'll only take a moment to mention
that this time is the 10th anniversary
of the country code name supporting
organizations ECNs oh and i think that
the very as i said being here in Africa
has caused me to put together an idea
that it's been gelling in my mind for a
while there's been a lot of rhetoric
around the requirements for
accountability and transparency and we
have formal processes to review and I'm
in fact on the the current incarnation
of the accountability and transparency
review team all of that is
extraordinarily important but it caused
me to think some time ago that
accountability transparency although
there are absolutely essential are not
sufficient we could be accountable we
could be transparent we could be
ineffective we could be getting nothing
done and so for some time I've been
talking about effectiveness and
efficiency as essential as well and the
we have to we have to get the job done
we have to we have to be effective at
what we're doing we have to do it with a
reasonable amount of efficiency one can
always equivalent of resources and so
forth or how long things take but we
have to be professional we have to be
businesslike but even with all of that
it does not quite get to another quality
which I want to introduce and have not
talked about the formerly in the past
one of the opportunities one of the
advantages that we have
of in the way I can is structured as not
being a government Bureau even though we
sometimes try very hard to look like we
are is the opportunity to do things in a
in a better way better can mean smarter
but it can also mean warmer more
engaging more accessible and I've been
paying attention you mean I've been
paying attention to a number of specific
interactions that I've had the privilege
to watch from the inside and and asking
hard questions did we do this in a way
that leaves all of the people that were
interacting with a feeling good about
the interaction even if we have to say
something that is a negative message are
we operating in a fashion that causes
people to say yeah that's really I'm
glad to have had this interaction I'm
glad to and the organization works the
way I'd like it to work as I say even
even in cases where the outcome might
not be objectively where this is this is
the human element here and I know that
sounds odd coming from somebody who is a
techie or maybe as some of my friends or
want to say who used to be a techie
until I was moved into this position so
the slogan that I'm going to share with
you this morning so I called the third e
for empathy and so my my stump speech
now is that we need to be efficient we
need to be effective and we need to have
empathy and that needs to be marbled and
imbued all the way through the
organization in every element that we
deal with and so that's and as I say
it's it's coming to Africa where
feelings are evident everywhere the
warmth and the engagement is just
something that you feel even before you
you get off the plane effect
flying south African Airways you feel
when you get on the plane which I can
tell you is different when you get on an
american airline and and so to the
extent that that i can and the extent
that my colleagues and i can can know
how that plays we will be moving as as
much as possible in that general
direction and one can go overboard on
these things but let me invite people
who see ways in which we can be more
empathetic to speak up and speaking
again personally my door is open on that
subject