a
[Music]
thanks for your time for being here and
thanks for all the knowledge you are
shared with us
of course
hi are you fine
doing great
great to be here
well
thanks for your time again
awesome so
good morning good afternoon and or good
evening everyone depending where you are
today um so welcome to our talk on web
isolation
so my name is pedro furtona i'm founder
and cto at j scrambler and i've
basically been working in security for
as long as i can remember
um
hi uh my name is jasper nagar most
people call me jazz you should too you
should definitely call me uh
as
i should probably say i've been working
in security for as long as uh pedro can
remember
yeah
and uh we want to start this talk with
um with a little story
already this is like very early in the
morning for some people better you want
to tell a story
yeah i guess we have to risk it um so
this is a story about a ship
that most of you may have heard about uh
it's the titanic
that's right you guessed it
and the reason why i'm telling you this
story is because of the way it was built
it was built in belfast in their famous
shipyard
i was actually lucky enough to visit
during the oasp upsec eu in 2017.
and it was inaugurated on april 10th of
1912 in the southampton port in the uk
so i guess most people do not know this
but when the titanic was built it was
bleeding edge in many ways
so the bottom of the ship was split into
16 major watertight compartments
a technique
to ensure the stability of the ship
despite the presence of damage
it was called a two compartment ship
because it could remain afloat with at
least two adjacent water tight
compartments completely flooded
that's like the worst situation they
could imagine back then so it was deemed
to be unthinkable
but depending on the exact location of
the hit at best it could withstand the
flooding of up to four compartments
without thinking
unfortunately on april 15
days after the inauguration it sank
because it collided with a huge iceberg
that resulted in the flooding of the
forward six compartments and two and a
half years hours later the titanic sank
so no one saw that coming
that something in this case an iceberg
could do this type of damage
they were overconfident that because of
that
um they only had 20 lifeboats clearly
not enough for everyone so the ship
carried
2224 people including the crew
and only 710 were actually rescued so
roughly 31.9
so even though it did not end well
compartmentalization
was a great idea and it is still used in
ship design to this day
so the basic idea is that damage on a
single section of the ship
does not compromise the whole ship
but the problem with the titanic is that
its implementation was flawed but we'll
tell you more about that later
wait
are we
are you leaving that as a cliffhanger
there
yeah uh
we are naughty i guess
so back to you jazz
oh um
no this is actually my part
[Laughter]
so i'll i'll tell you about a bit about
the history of web isolation
so um
the first really attempts at isolation
inside the browser
was introduced by the same origin policy
where interactions between two different
origins are restricted
but restricted how if we can embed
third-party code directly from
third-party servers into our our
executing context
so this code here
has the same level of privilege as any
other
code from the same origin
so it turns out that embedding of
third-party code is possible what is
restricted is some writing and reading
raw data from cross-origin domains
so the reality is that the same origin
policy is complex
has lots of lots of exceptions and to
this day most developers do not fully
understand it which is a frequent source
of security issues
two years later we were given the
iframes with which we can isolate two
cross-origin documents uh all scripts
running on the same web app
but soon enough people felt the need to
poke a hole through it coming without
coming up with different ways to have
communication between two cross-origin
documents
and only 13 years later we threw the
towel and finally made it official with
the introduction of the web messaging
api with which you can do post message
between two cross-origin iframes
but not every problem went away frame
iframes had
still too much power they could for
instance
navigate away the top window
among other things
so it took a while but 13 years later
iframe sandboxing was introduced which
greatly restricts what an iframe
document can do
so you can see a bunch of configuration
attributes that you can use to relax
some of the iframe default restrictions
so almost at the same time
we got content security policy version
one uh with which one could set a
domain-based allow listing
which was later found to be broken so
you can see that
you can see to the right a reference to
a well-known paper
from weixelbaum spagnuolo like is and
young
that
detail everything
around this topic
but
also
csp is pretty hard to maintain so
especially version one so later versions
of csp fix that but
but are not as straightforward to set up
so the main limitation that we see with
csp
is that it does not cover all the
behavioral angles that you want to
restrict
so if you allow scripts
you allow the scripts entirely
so it can do everything it wants so you
want a more granular type of thing where
you allow some
things that the script may be able to do
but not everything
so the problem with this isolation and
defense mechanisms is that is that
people will fight them uh will push for
ways to relax them in what they need in
order to make the application work
so things like jsonp and cores are good
examples
but if the isolation mechanisms were
more granular and configurable perhaps
we wouldn't feel the need to open holes
in these protection mechanisms
so here's the timeline of these features
so you can see a huge gap between 97 and
where you really have to wonder what the
browser people were doing during these
years
uh pedro at some point i should tell you
what we were doing at those during those
years we were sitting back relaxing a
little
so
uh back to you jaz this time for real
sounds great like so
a lot of what pedro has talked about is
uh
what's built into the browser browsers
provide us with
you know a large number of great uh
basic primitives all of the things uh
that that give you that make your units
of isolation uh smaller and stronger and
yes they have problems uh but we can
maybe do something to build uh on top of
that right and i think that the answer
here is yes and you shouldn't just
believe me uh the community
as a whole has built all kinds of
interesting mechanisms on top of what
isolation
primitives that the browsers provide
that
you know reduce the number of holes you
need to poke in your cheese basically
uh pedro do you mind just driving the
slides for me
thanks
uh so roughly speaking uh it's hard to
characterize what all of the different
uh approaches for web isolation are uh
the way that i like to think about it is
you know you you can think about them on
two axes
uh where you uh change the source code
or virtualization where you change
uh the code itself
or you are changing the environment in
which the code runs i plotted three
projects here
just as a representative example there's
many more projects um uh there's there's
google caja which you know i'm
deeply uh familiar with and was involved
with uh which uses a combination of
virtualization and transformation to
build a sandbox
so code is both changed and the
environment in which this code runs is
also modified so that uh
so that the access that this application
has is limited there's uh there is or
was a js reg which tried to do the same
there was a more lightweight
transformation uh there's j scrambler
which uh which pedro is intimately
involved with um you know which which
uses mostly virtualization
which is a lightweight transformation
but essentially all of these approaches
for building on top of the primitives
that the web
that the web browser provides faults
somewhere in the spectrum
um
let's uh switch to the next slide
so what does this look like
let's take a simple javascript
application it consists of functions
like you see here is an alert which
comes from somewhere else uh if you're a
if you're a systems kind of a person you
can think of this as system calls they
come you know they're provided by the
browser you have strings you have arrays
these are native types and then you have
functions which you
which you've written yourself i'm i'm
not going to dwell on this too long but
this transformation this slide
which captures a transformation is my
is my most favorite transformation uh
everybody has their own favorite
transformation this one is mine right
it's the basis for all the language
transformation based sandboxes that you
see
now let's say you transform these
functions so that whenever you reference
a system call or a native object you
don't get the you know the native
powerful object
what you get is uh you only get those
objects or
those types of those functions that the
color controls now i'm i'm
oversimplifying here some of you in the
audience must already be saying hey jaz
you forgot about the val hey daz you
forgot about walking the prototype
changes like these constructs and you're
right absolutely you are right but at
heart
this is the transformation that lets you
call some arbitrary third-party code in
a controlled kind of way
um
let's do the yeah perfect
uh and not only that
you can do the same thing not just for
javascript you can actually do this for
html and for css
too in fact in some ways it's even
easier
to do it for html and css because
they're less expressive than javascript
is for example
here if you have some css rule that was
you know changing every div or every
bowl tag to be the color blue because
you find the color blue beautiful uh you
can prepend like a dot
gadget one two three
uh and and now
and now
your your colors are only restricted to
the descendants of a div that has you
know gadget one two three uh
uh
as a class right so
this is this is one tool in our uh
toolbox transformation what's the other
tool that we have
so the other tool is virtualization now
i call it virtualization but really all
it is is polyfills you all know it as
polyfills
they present a feature what is a
polyfill it presents a feature that is
not present in a particular browser
version
virtualization is exactly like polyfills
uh but we need them even if the feature
exists uh in the browser but it's not
redundant because we want to override
the default behavior uh or have a chance
to trigger some additional
uh let's let's call them re reactions
okay so here you have an example of a
date all browsers do you can provide
this just to a third party directly no
polyfill polyfill needed or the polyfill
is just you know the just a wrap around
the date maybe because you don't worry
about
cash timing attacks or from a particular
third party now you have xhr and you can
provide a police version that always
proxies that request or doesn't let you
go to arbitrary places so you you can
prevent a third party from connecting to
an arbitrary location it always goes
through your proxy in fact
you know today every browser has an xhr
but you know if you remember the bad
days uh not every browser would provide
you with uh xml http requests and you
might need to polyfill that uh
the nice thing is that you can
take something that is much more
powerful like like an active x
controller would let you do
crazy things but
because you are proxying them because
you sit between the third party and the
browser you can use a powerful object to
provide an attenuated like a like a a
weaker safer version of xhr built on top
of activex to third parties
and then similarly you can do this with
like document location
uh with uh um
with access to the camera all kinds of
things the trick the hard part is
strong parts of security needs to be
that you create polyfills in a way that
can't be bypassed when you have a
polyfill
of course everybody wants to use your
polyfill because it's providing power
that you don't ordinarily have when you
use polyfold polyfills for security um
you need to make sure that no one can
bypass your political and all of the
projects that use virtualization come up
with uh with different ways
of of achieving that
now
um
next slide
so there are three principles i want you
to take away from how native browser
isolation features work boil down they
do things like you know same origin
policy iframes et cetera what do they
bring now the three and it's an
interesting set of three and you might
already be starting to get hits to that
little cliffhanger that we left behind
the most obvious design principle is
compartment size like you can have an
entire domain or origin you can have
whole pages you can have iframes you can
have individual scripts you can have
individual functions you can have
individual actions that these functions
are taking like specific api con
calls
the smaller the compartment the more
resilient a web application
that you
ship
will be
the the trade-off you're making here is
there's a lot more decisions that you
need to make the longer is the setup
time and the configuration effort next
one
the second thing is uh
the the isolation material the stronger
the material is the more resilient uh
your web application would be now
drilling holes even into strong
materials weakens them uh iframe csp the
mechanisms that we use to do isolation
are weakened because in order to get our
job done we need to poke holes into them
now these holes aren't there because you
know web browser implementations are
broken but because the isolation
mechanism doesn't necessarily align with
the with the way in which we use
developers will find clever ways you all
are very clever at finding ways to poke
holes into them in order to get you know
your job done
which brings us to the third thing uh we
which is visibility and user
friendliness now developers are people
too
they need apis that work well for their
particular use case and for their
strength model now some materials like
same origin policy and iframes works for
the threat models that existed way back
when but they haven't kept up with how
you know web developers develop today
and they do not provide you with any
visibility at least not out of the box
and this brings us back to the
cliffhanger pedal
yeah so
like we said the titanic implementation
was flawed
so by now you should be able to guess it
but the compartments were still too big
and the materials were definitely not
iceberg ready so they needed stronger
materials
the damage model
was incomplete or incorrect
which translating to our context it
means that the threat model was wrong
and finally the lack of visibility so
for obvious reasons no one spotted the
the iceberg in time
so visibility and analytics which is an
interpretation of what what's happening
are definitely essential
for our
web isolation
so now we have some time for for doing
some demos
in these demos we'll be using the same
scenario throughout
we'll be using a login page for a
mock-up
banking website
and this website uses a third-party
chatbot service
so in some of the runs
we'll replace the regular chatbot
scripts
for a compromise version that it's
attempting to leak the login credentials
of the user so you'll see a few options
in the bottom
that allow me to reload the website with
different demo settings
okay
so let's start uh with the baseline so
we'll show you an example of what
happens when isolation is lacking
so let me
start this
full screen
so this is the the dummy virtual bank
websites
and
and as you can see it has first party
codes but it also has the chatbots
script that it's been loaded directly
from the third party server
chatbot.js
so it's not really doing anything
because this is a mock-up chatbot
so that is the icon of the chat bots
it's not really doing anything
but this is a mock-up demo so it doesn't
matter
so obviously being embedded it can hurt
security so let us do another run with
uh with a compromised version of the
same script
this is the the compromised version of
the script it has
additional code
that is hooking into the unsubmit
function of the form so it will run a
malicious function when the user clicks
submit which will
capture the user and password and xhr it
to malicious dash api.jsrama.com
and will resume the form submission
so the user will not notice that
something
odd is happening so let me
login
and uh i'll show you in the in the
attacker dashboards the captured uh
credentials
okay so as you can see
uh that malicious code was able to
capture the credentials
okay so
um
so next uh well we'll be doing
is showing you uh the first thing that
most application owners would do in this
situation
so they want to remove
the
full access that this third party script
has to your web app
by isolating the scripts into a
cross-origin iframe
okay
so let me move to the second demo
so we'll be loading the compromise
version inside the time frame
and the first sorry let me
full screen this so you can see
okay
so the first thing that you'll notice
once we reload the page is that you're
getting a console error okay
so um so this is basically the
consequence of loading the
chatbot script inside the iframe
and we are using a subdomain for that so
it's not running in virtobank.com it's
actually running in
chatbots.fertilebank.com
okay so it's a it's a subdomain
subdomain by default is considered to be
cross origin
and the scripts is unchanged so it tries
to access the form directly but it
cannot find it in the html
okay
so
however
we even though we have mitigated the
problem uh this can potentially require
re-engineering uh of the web app
or even requesting the service provided
to change how the service works
and re-engineering the web app is quite
complex
and um and and it may require a protocol
to to define how we post message things
back and forth between the main window
and the third party service running in
the isolated iframe
for instance
an analytics service expects direct
access to the full dom of the web app um
so it's no wonder that many websites end
up just
adding the scripts directly
to the main window despite the risk
so
and this brings us to demo number three
which i'll ask just to do
uh sure do you want to fulfill it before
you
play uh so the part of the problem was
uh
was the asynchronous uh running of the
code like that's what is causing it to
be so difficult um here kaha tries to
avoid that let's start by enabling kaha
and rerunning this compromise script now
remember the script that we are about to
compromise here isn't supposed to have
access to the network to do its job
normally
um
we enable taha i'm actually using
something called secure ecmascript
instead of kaha actually but it's
derived from kaha
uh what are we doing here we create a
compartment we white list
just the apis
that are needed for
for the legitimate script to do its job
in this case the only things that are
needed are create element and append
child
we rerun the script the thing that
you're noticing is that there's no
network request made
and if we go to the
to the attacker server we find no
additional content was exfiltrated why
because the third party script was
granted access to just what it needed it
needed a pen child it needed create
element it did not need network access
and so it wasn't that we took that away
we basically started by taking
everything away and then only giving
back the power that the script needed
for it to do its job and it could do it
synchronously as opposed to in the
iframe case asynchronously
uh pedro do you want to do the next one
actually
of course
so
let me
oh sorry
okay so um
so to avoid these caveats uh we
developed a sandboxing solution that can
be seamlessly be integrated into any web
app uh you just have to add a scripts
and agents and you get immediately
visible
immediately you get visibility on what
third parties are doing and we can use
rules to either allow or disallow
such behaviors so let me start
the demo
so
in this dashboard you'll be able to see
what's going on so right now it's
completely empty
um so we'll reload the virtual bank app
with both the compromised script and our
agents and to see what's going on
so after a few seconds we see things
landing
in the dashboard
so in this case we see that the on
submit event handler was replaced
we can see the ip address the user
agents and we can see in full detail
what form was targeted
and the malicious function that was set
by the attacker so we can see in full
detail right now we are not blocking it
and we have confirmation that it was
chatbots compromise.js that was doing
this
okay
so let us
move forward nevertheless so we're not
blocking this but we already have
visibility
and see what happens
so the next thing that we get is
an alert
about the excitation of the data so we
can see the endpoints and what data is
being passed
and again we can see what was the script
that
triggered this action
so obviously visibility is nice
and here we can see confirmation that
the credentials were captured visibility
is nice but we need to mitigate it so
the first thing that we are doing is
creating a rule
to prevent the exfiltration so in this
rule you can see
in with which pages the rule is running
which scripts
this this particular rule will be
applied to
and which events we are controlling so
in this case we are
restricting
any network requests whose destination
dot domain equals malicious dash api dot
jskrama.com
okay
so the action we set to alert and block
so we're doing
two things and i don't need to save the
rule because it's already there so i'm
enabling the rule and applying the
configuration
so at this point we'll need to wait a
few seconds for the deployment
to be complete
and next
we'll do another run to see what changed
okay so let's wait a couple
more seconds
all right
and let's reload the page
and see what happens
so
a few seconds later
we'll get
the same on submit event handler being
replaced so we we did nothing
regard that uh
apathel this moment but we
are preventing the excellation so that
malicious function is running and when
it tries to accelerate it will be
blocked by the isolation layer
so as you can see there's no additional
entries in the attacker's dashboard
so obviously we can do better
we can also prevent that
event handler function to
for replacing the original one
um
and we already have a rule for that as
well so sorry let me
okay so what we are doing here is
let me
so we have
a rule for that so what we are doing
here is we are creating a rule that will
be applied to every page in the websites
regardless of what scripts
and we are blocking any behavioral
change that targets a form
if that happens we will alert but also
block the event okay so again
um
again we need to
enable this rule and apply the
configuration
i'll just
fast forward this bits for your benefits
and
the next thing i'll do is
i'll do a final run
to see what changed
okay so i need to reload the page
and
right about now
the unsubmit events handler replacing
was already attempted but was blocked by
the rule
okay
and this is it so uh two comments so
this demo may lead you to think that um
that you need to find about things and
only then block it
but the rules engine actually allows you
to set allow lists
for all sorts of things for example you
can
name one script that needs
access to
a given form
and every other access will be blocked
by default
and thus reducing the attack surface so
we can do the same for cookies for local
storage and for a number of other things
other behaviors under other resources
so you can you can set the terrain
um to be secure by default
uh without the actual need to be waiting
for something to happen
also the rules are quite flexible and
granular which means that our isolation
boxes
can be as small as we want without
having to re-engineer the whole web app
okay so
so this talk is is coming to the end uh
but we still need to address the
challenges ahead
to understand the challenges it helps
understanding what we have been doing
wrong
in terms of browser-based security
the security features that provide
isolation
things have moved
slow and erratically
and the reason is because it was never
one feature whose purpose was to provide
full isolation for browser-based apps so
isolation has been more about stitching
together a bunch of different mechanisms
and tried to cover as much surface as
possible
this is both complex and error-prone and
inevitably leave some holes or blind
spots
so
behind the browser there are other few
initiatives
some of which we already mentioned
that try to come up with a holistic
approach for client-side web isolation
so we mentioned kaha
but sadly kaha was eventually
discontinued and more recently we have
been working on web page integrity um
and there are maybe a couple there
there are also valuable out there
so just
what do we need for the next 20 years
pedro's covered you know what we did
uh
you know the web is evolving it's
evolving in a very fast pace we're
moving
more and more things onto the web and
it's highly decentralized where in order
to build your applications to today you
glued together
large numbers of third-party services so
what does the next 30
next 20 years look like what what i
assert we need what we're our
perspective is what we need is a single
holistic client-side
um
web solution that covers all of these
angles right we need a broad and
coherent plan and there's three
principles that we've talked about today
which is reducing the size of the
compartments
uh making each one of the compartments
each one of the units stronger
and uh developer friendly
you know aligned with how the web is
used today not how we were using it back
in the day as we were making this
presentation uh pedro and i joked i make
terrible puns i'm sorry but we we
we joked that the way to make a ship
unthinkable is to sort of give it wings
and i think that that's what we need to
do is to give
you know
is to give the titanic wings
let's talk about how far along we are
um
parts of the solution we have the ones
that we've been talking about today that
go fairly far into this vision but
ambitious plans take time there are lots
of pieces on the way here
in a couple of years the maturity of
these solutions will help make not just
each part work well but work better with
each other
and drive adoption we were ironing out
bugs pedro mentioned csp uh that was an
attempt and we found some rough corner
cases and we over time polished them
uh
we over time polished them now in spite
of the analogy that we've been making
here the plan is not actually to build
an unthinkable ship it's to
lift web application security
a little bit out of the water so we're
not constantly
so we're not constantly drowning
so we called the security community you
and i like all of us
uh to join us and and help continue to
push
um
web isolation in particular as a
mechanism that we use to mitigate
uh the extent to which we are vulnerable
to third-party scripts
uh and hopefully we'll all meet you in
the future
um take care
um
and that's all we have for today so
thank you very much it was wonderful to
be here today
uh we would also like to pay our
respects to the late sir clive sinclair
he was an inventor and a genius
personally he's responsible for me
pursuing a career in computer science
it was a huge loss
for a generation that fell in love with
computers because of his inventions
so thank you again
and we are happy to take your questions
now
to you for the knowledge
i have a few questions what is your
opinion about the firewall from the
apps and web
can you hear me
can now yes
okay what is your opinion on the
firewall from the apps web
sorry
can you
can you rephrase that again
from the
what is your opinion of the firewall
from the app
the application of web
i i'm not sure i got the question jazz
do you have do you did you get the
question
i i i not entirely but i can guess a
so maybe i want to answer differently
people ask me about your opinion about
the firewall from the natural
web
applications
right so i i'll
i'll be brief about this right so
uh i think that in general uh web
applications have moved away
from uh you know we call them perimeter
security because you know web firewalls
firewalls in general are
you know a a hard crusty exterior and a
soft gooey center right and so
once upon a time when web applications
were mostly documents that worked really
well because you know you'd have uh you
you'd you know build this boundary you
know like the the great firewall china
or you know you'd build a boundary and
as long as the attacker was not able to
get through this boundary you were good
if you think about it web applications
uh are active applications this means
that the the the attacker
could be inside your perimeter and so
firewalls tend not to work so well in
those set of circumstances a lot of the
tooling that i was describing today
around virtualization is you know if you
squint right it's moving the firewall
from way out you know out in the
boundaries all the way inside your
application so that each one of your
each one of your apis is surrounded by
um
by a
sort of virtualized firewall and the
reason why that is powerful is because
uh you know that means that you have
context on what needs to be what needs
to be running um so overall i think
firewalls worked once upon a time i
think that the way in which the web
works now means that you know we need to
pull these firewalls all the way uh
inside our application i think that
those
and only those are going to end up
giving you the kind of you know sort of
zero trust security that we need
charles if i'm allowed to add something
there
uh
the question could be uh
related with web application firewalls
and and
from a technical standpoint there's some
interesting differences that we want to
to communicate here
so basically a waff a web application
firewall is usually placed between the
back end
and the front end uh but
the way it's
deployed it will only actually
screen communications between
that backhand
and the browser which means that
in our demo for instance the
acceleration was done to a third-party
domain
and that communication
was not covered by the waft the waf
wouldn't be able to look at that
communication or any other communication
that it's not being directed to
the application backend
uh on top of this
waffs they look at code statically they
look at code that it's not running at
that moment they look at responses
so they have to deal with uh trying to
figure out what that code
will be doing once it reaches the
browser and and once it starts running
and that's very hard to to to do
uh unless you're considering like very
low hanging fruit stuff it's very hard
to do because there are plenty of ways
to hide
um to really hide because javascript is
really easy to to modify how it looks
it's very easy to statically hide what
it will be doing
so we argue that
doing that kind of screening
on the browser and doing dynamic
analysis rather than static analysis
is the right approach because it doesn't
matter how the code looks like what
matters it's what behaviors that code is
trying to engage
and using virtualization you are uh you
are in the middle of that so you can
control uh and you have actual
confirmation of the behavior that it's
about to happen
okay
the last one
how this solution help developers to fix
their code apart from mitigating the
risk
so
so this is not meant to fix the codes
this is meant to to provide visibility
to help security
practitioners to understand
the the type of threats
that are usually
targeting
these websites
it does nothing in order to make
developers
produce better code
there are of course some some
some
some good practices
that you should
follow whenever you can
but this is not the purpose of of this
type of approach
web isolation
what it can help is that
even
when
the developer
does a poor job
isolating things like using iframes or
or separating concerns separating
scripts um it still
it gets the protection from the
isolation and the costs of adding that
isolation is almost for free
because the at least from the
developer's point of view
um
he or she uh does not need to do
anything differently in order to benefit
from that protection
jazz i don't know if you want to add
something here i i definitely do uh just
to keep things spicy i'm going to
disagree with you
so this is always fun so no i i mean you
of course are right this is not the
purpose
but actually virtualization does two
things that make developers experience
much better one is
it does give you the
you know the visibility that you need
and now of course you know security
people want visibility because we want
to know what the bad guys are up to bad
guys are like sneaking around and we
want that visibility but if you think
about it when you are debugging you're
essentially an attacker on your own code
and like essentially giving that
visibility makes the life of a developer
that much easier because suddenly you
get all of this visibility that you did
not previously have didn't prevent you
from putting the bugs in in the first
place but now that you've put the bugs
in
really helpful i i personally have used
you know this virtualization tricks that
we've talked about
to debug code you know that idiot that
jazz was six months ago wrote right so
visibility is i think
really provided by tools like it i would
love to see more of them the other is
the thing that you allude to which is
isolation now isolation means that you
know the bad guy can't hurt you but it
also means that you can't hurt you by
accident right so you know of course it
is the case that you know the attacker
is trying to maliciously do bad things
to you but if things are isolated think
about it not in terms of security but as
modularity right the more isolated your
code is that means that this piece here
can't hurt this piece here because it's
been isolated if everything was sitting
in the same sandbox then you know you'd
be hurting each other even if you were
writing the code because you know you
just could not keep it separated in your
head and so i do think that yes it pro
was not built to make the life of
developers easier but i think that in
both of these cases both visibility and
isolation help make uh developers lives
easier it certainly has made my life
easier
we disagree or not you are amazing guys
thanks very much for your time for being
here to make this possible uh
and
i don't know nothing thank you thank you
very much for your time you for being
here thank you thank you
thank you bye-bye
mediatory
[Music]
a
foreign
[Music]
um
foreign
uh
[Music]
you