yes [Music]
Now how are they doing? My name is Francisco Cantero and today we are going to be doing the
Héctor activity workshop and post exploitation attacks where we are
We are going to be seeing post-exploitation attacks that we can review at
displaying stories so that with a standard user with low privileges
we can get to get a dog and privileges of tomara min said this
let's go to the presentation
well well well first of all welcome to
everyone to this workshop thank you very much everyone for attending and thank you very much
It will be done for giving this space and welcome to everyone to what this is
summer work series re show share my name is francisco camps
I am currently a metrix engineer greetings to the team I am lazy antiphon
stamina and hunter in my spare time I like to look for balsillie and break things
I am part of the hospital staff in my free time I also like
Participating in sete efe is like boxing records and I am a founder and
community organizer and 404 we are and now let us introduce my
partner that rodrigo good morning i am rodrigo that laporta today
I'm going to be like enough from France for the question part
I am software the ginger in the main hall of nou technologies and also
accompanied him with the 404 community are the idea of ​​this do what good if
Someone has doubts or a question they want to ask, they can ask it through
of the question channel within the center of discord and pop art and so if
you have them there I am going to take them and when frank can we are going to ask
see what responses we get so celebrate
perfect good let's go over first with the agenda that we are going to be looking at
In this workshop, the first thing we are going to see is that the directory is activated.
see the important concepts that one has to take into account of you director
and we go to the authentication protocols with which active works
directory once seen this let's see how we can configure our first
in our own laboratory we will see what are post attacks
active directory exploits which is where we will see all these attacks
We will see separately kerberos which is an authentication protocol of also of
microsoft but we will see it separately because we will see very in detail and
we will see how to attack kerberos all the resources that are used this
workshop are in the following link as you can see they are in englishtown with
qr scan so don't worry yourself these
slides are found right away so nothing has so much resources
available for you to carry out the laboratory
well first of all what is active directory an active director and
basically it is a microsoft tool that provides services of
directory a directory service is an application that stores and organizes
information about users and other resources a network basically a service
directory what it does is that it allows administrators to manage access
of users to the resources of said network an interesting fact is that nowadays
more than 90 of the companies worldwide and 95 of the one south training
sound use direct acting and to manage their identity that is, it is very
interesting to have Héctor activity and as a target since 90 is 90 per
hundred of companies around the world use active
directory
alright lets go quick with the important active directory concepts
domain an active directory domain is basically a logical container that is
used to administer and manage users or that for user groups
computers among other objects ok now we are going to give this well in detail
definition of objects then we have what is a domain controller which is
basically a server that contains installed the active directory role does not
main services and has been promoted as a domain controller
This domain control is in charge of providing authentication and
use replicate changes with other domains and store a copy of
directory content objects an object with which
I just mentioned that the users were the groups, basically an object is the
generic name that we use to refer to any component
within a directory although there are within the objects we can find
as recently mentioned users that for example allow a user to access
a network resource we will find groups that are used to simplify
the administration of the permissions we can find the computers good
We can find and win these shares that we are going to be
speaking in more detail about them a little later
we also have organizational units an organizational unit is basically
a container that allows grouping the objects allows us to organize the
objects like printer printers users groups etc.
For example, we can draw a u called the sales team and put
there all our all our sales computers then have one u
that are sales user and group all users we create
inside sales saúde et cetera later we have what is called a tree
that a tree is basically a set of domains which depend on a
common root and are organized in a certain age hierarchy
basically they share the main domain name they can have their
domains and by default a transitive trust is created that now we will
to be watching later
Give me a second and I'm going to give you a touch again, I don't know if the
github link I want region to enter is the crux hub
dotcom frank 205 a from workshop to suddenly
a workshop and there they will be able to find
all the resources of this workshop well
then as I mentioned a tree is basically a set of domains
notice that it is formed by several domains one can have the domain for example
with all dot com and then we have one call and use dot driver dot like
china dot 4 about dot com and this transitive trust that I mentioned to you
He just mentioned to you, now we will be explaining it in a little bit more to the side
and then we have the forests which basically the forests is the collection
of one or more trees and what is interesting is that they share the groups
of enterprise admin system bits well as you just mentioned this of the
trust relationships over transitive trust good what's this a
trust relationship basically means that a domain control
trust the other this basically allows them to react and have
Users who can log in to both dressage in controls There are two types of
trust the transitive trust and the directional trust with function to this
we are going to explain it in a very simple concept
and that has nothing to do with activities but suppose I have a friend
for example in this case to rodrigo his bonus I have rodrigo and I trust
in him then I give him the key to my house and rodrigo also trusts me and
gives the key to his house then what happens we trust each other and
we give each other access to housing
ok that would be the transitive trust what would the directional trust be
Suppose the example that I
for example i trust rodrigo ok
and rodrigo will give me keys to his house then what happens I trust him but
He gives me the keys, I don't know if that definition is understood.
see it in an example in activity that happens in haiti director and us
we have two domains one is called victor play test and one is called si corp
seidou what happens the user seidou can as there is mutual trust and
mutual access user seidou can log in to this domain and the
test user can login to this domain in directional trust
domain and hacked trust this domain but this user can access
In this domain, that is, the users of the local point corp will be able to access the
to the domain of liquor flow but those of igor lah or not to the local liquor because
because the black editor did not give him access to his and corp well I do not know if there is here
any doubt to a short break for consultations
until now they only asked the unpublished nachito thickness step the link but nothing
perfect go ahead well in short this would be the
active directory hierarchy we can access users who are among the
users by the objects that are inside a unit
organizational we can see the domains we can see about the union the units
organizational are within the domain they belong to a tree
the tree is inside a forest as you can see in this diagram
another cool thing is the tory active directory activity datastore
basically uses a data store to store all the information of the
directory and this directory contains information about objects such as
users groups computers etc. contain the nt file of that point the
which is a database that stores data of the director and this even
information about user objects groups and chair groups something
interesting is that this file also includes the password aces for
all the users in the domain well let's go here with the protocols of
authentication the first of them is the motto or the
manager basically is a protocol that is an authentication protocol that
uses a particularly weak medical hash is a protocol too
adoptive are easy to encrypt and is disabled by default to
from windows vista windows server 2008
we have the skin protocol in which good is known cnt the sister since
It is known as on the ground that obviously this is seen because it was the
first to be used in windows nt and is an improvement over the protocol of
It's basically the way it is
passwords are released on modern windows systems and are obtainable
dumping the data to me using minimí cats which is a tool that we will now see
below good and also stored in domain controllers at
file in this ds the gases cnt lm can be also
used to attack peace let it be an attack we will be seeing
now shortly after version n trm version came out
in a version 2 that are challenge response protocols that are used
for authentication in windows environments
we use analytics in the algorithm which means it can be used to
recover password via brute force or dictionary attacks
well we have kerberos which is basically the default protocol
authentication on windows computers at 2000, 3, 2000 and xp that are members of
an active directory domain older windows systems are no longer
compatible with parker but if you are going to use one of the above
authentication ok any doubt no no
we are still going ahead with the laboratory assembly the requirements
minimums are basically a virtual machine with windows server 2019 a
virtual machine with windows 10 enterprise and a virtual machine with
karim and nux disk space approximately 50 gigabytes and a
8 gb ram memory is fine it is necessary that they have suárez you must
pass the recommended requirements are good is used more rami and
basically I will be a bm of windows 10 but it is not necessary that they have the
recommended requirements because all of this can be done with a
Serbian windows and a windows 10 machine in this case I am doing it with
two machines so that you can see how each of the attacks works and
you can see well how each flow of attacks is but it is not necessary
yes or yes they are two machines with windows 10 the same anyway what
can do is use cloud services cloud services
For example, in my case we are many asur what they can do is use the
slaps that allow them to manage the actor machines and for laboratories
punctual if they do not have a lot of experience, now I can do it is
create a resource pool throw three machines four virtual machines there
turn them off and when they are using us and that will decrease them a lot
cost was a good way to optimize costs and be able to test in the
laboratory without having to dispose of those of those
resources
well the lab diagram basically we have an attacker
ok which in this case this is raised all in a mister scenario
ministries series robot
After we have the ticket, the attacker will be elected later in
A pc that is called a pc which is the Álamos pc which would be a user's pc
standard of a person for example of sales etc. later we would have the pc
of tyler wall and that would be for example the company site ok and then we have
the domain controller that would be this editor and wherever
fine until there is any doubt for now no but I want to remind you
the people who are tweets that if they have any questions there
It would be one to go through the album and ask around why the ones we take
to put they are from that channel so nothing
give it perfect perfect yes or no more
well let's start like this to see the post exploitation attacks in writing
hector and good in the initial stage basically we managed to get
the password of the icor barra user we crave that he has the password is that that
password 1 which is a basically unprivileged domain user the one time
in which it can be achieved is in the fish that is yours and remember well
again this this diagram the first thing we are going to see is this
enumeration of user attributes basically the goal of this is to be able to
we list the attributes of users of a proxy list us
the attributes of the users of this director and we know how to list the
user attributes we can find the following attributes
real and relevant that are those of admin in says if the user in a moment
The password count was administrator, now let's see what they are for
these specific attributes are not the number of times the user and / or
you wrongly entered the member of in the key to find out which group it belongs to
and the description that is a free field that today we are going to go with this first demo
let's go this way well I'm here in the fishbowl we call
to show also the first thing I am going to do is try to rule on the pc
What is the one of the lic? Look how we are going keys
one day
notice that he tells me that he could not achieve this because he is totally
restricted to your user if we do not go here obviously we
we will be able to forget
Well the first thing I want to show you is a tool called the
explorer you are using the graphical interface but now let's see how to do it
this same by console
something that I will have already put something wrong
it got bad clarifies well notice that here we can list all the
directory structure and we can see we remove them for example that there is
one that is called and use si core where we can see the different users
created and that they have interesting this that we can see, look at all
the attributes if we want using the search tool
we can search for example
e what interesting values ​​that we are going to
find in the description because we talk about your tents
Well, as you can see, here is a user who has service calls and that
It has as a key my password one of which the description says that if it can be used
password is my password 1 well this is very common that they occur
multiple times found in in description fields that leave keys
and it is something that can happen in this case this is not the key
but it is something very interesting to show now well let's see how to do this
via console, that is, for example, if we had a
open metasploit session and let's move one tap to the presentation
we are here fine
well, we are going to use them, it is a tool called power exploit
this tool will allow us to do a lot of things not just the attack
this numbering of user attributes well let's go
we are going to open it directly from the folder
powers lloyd
hold the letter so that it is via let's increase the band
let's point to one thing a second and arango yes
it doesn't come out perfect
i'm half asleep porcel john key
what am i doing with this i am opening a powers window in the
what the bypass s what I am doing is emptying a restriction that has
dread shell so that it does not run in scripts is something typical of powers no longer
it's nothing at all weird
it matters to me
now for
well it may fail
of the sunken
well, what I'm doing is important
as the power exploit tool
and what we are going to do is use this tool to start listing
ok he is definitely not loving me today
help the demo and let's test
it is not importing well in the module
let's try again
it's okay
word
because it doesn't matter
they have passed that
speaker
no good leave me
follow the point ps1 very well but it is not
I am not taking it open
it was
this was
extra that the cdu no
well you can find
Amen
It is entering me now with pc of 1 number take
with p de m 1 name take good I failed the demo that could die
adhered said we see a milestone let's talk
let's see what's happening
I am an importan
and no number takes
well
Let's see
well let's do one thing since what number is taking
Let's do one thing, it's the first time we fail, let's give it this way, so how will they be?
idea do not go out perspiring what we are going to do is we go back to do a brief
pause i'll check this before i know
learn photos and we'll be back in less than 5 minutes if you feel like it
well here we came back possibly I do not know if it appeared but it would have to appear the
image that of technical difficult and the simpsons clearly the question of
million that we are all doing what was failing and the most
funny is that a human error of mine was obviously not the point ps1 as
Some said it was not the thing about the thing but what exactly is going to be
making a comment that hit him right in the chat what he was
failing that I realized the module is just importing more
what happened in import the power view module and is importing the 'power
cloud as a conclusion that we can learn from
This is that you do not have to drink beer before the talk
when you are watching yes but when we are going to give them not so much so well nothing
a data is very important to say they have told me this we are going to continue with
with the talk and let's see how we import the good module with
needs point point bar let's put power view
And see if please don't fail me now
and at this point one is persecuted I imagine that you will understand is
as you already warm a ls sink and it does not happen we can never get out 100%
you are and the demo does not fail this is nothing
the control data nothing like it showed them to lie to
the data did not find me I put the version of the server etc. we can
get the option of domain policy or more in policy
As you can see, we can have it, for example, the domain policies at
freighter policies etc. we can obtain for example
net
and look here we are seeing all the user attributes which
we just saw with the explore tool we
from here look for example we are with the sql
service
even the description of that can be encore
others I will play is for example the one of get net
net group and the ion name troupe
admin
This is what is showing us all the groups that have admin is in their name
etcetera well let's go back to the presentation
the question to see if charlie is on top, the same where is he with a domain friend and
blocked with a domain case user user domain trace reason
reason the user is more we will show it again just in case the
user look at the user who is read we get look at the user every
good time we crave is masters
good if we try to achieve in the tyler well machine and that would be
as the site of the company amos
you notice that tells us that we can not
achieve us because we do not have permission for these times so it is recontra
standard and also restricted for us they would do it other times
well
let's continue no more than against measures we can take with this we can review
user descriptions manually extract all
user descriptions and review them to see that there are no
rare value and set a user as with the key and set a user
promptly have the key in the description and keep the events of
this user so that we see that some user is
trying to achieve with this key we are not going to detect that they are
trying to attack well other things we could do is
see the shared resources of networks and this is very interesting for the 90% who
this basically this consists of listing the shared directories that
can be found in the patient network when listing the
resources found in comparative directories about us
we can find the following as the most relevant files good
point ps1 that can have for example a day can contain string like
convert string is created is circular connection the connection also the
sql point files that this is continuous is 30 kilometers of connection or connect
a txt that contains a text of that day wv of password and so on
well, is there any question this time
if you excuse me here you ask a question if the tool they are
using in the Angela profile you need administrator permission to be able to
run to I'm watching has no sexual reason no
you do not need permission just to be a user of me exactly with just being a user
domain we are literally with just that now and dance
from scratch good because I say there is this issue of resources
shared network is something very interesting I do not know if they remember a
In a short time, this document is also being given in the lay workshop that occurred from
migrations and the most logical thing is that it happened because they left things in folders
shared that everyone could access
and well, nothing happened, what happened, but well, let's see more in detail
how we can grab and search these shared folders then these
these commands
not
today trying to put
this command usually takes time so while executing another
command
6 - - mike is the one who takes his time if he wouldn't be sweating
It is a fairly important data of salt or poverty if not looking for the srs throughout the
network then take your time
we are going to do it here
stop workshop well headquarters the power
pretty delicious
for rafa
and accept to take out
we are going to do is with this command check promptly
the user geas in this case make the lakers that is to say the
the dogma in controlling there is a question has been if the letter can be enlarged
If we give it a second, yes, there is achieving
let's go there it will look good I don't know if a little more
a little more
hawaii payton
save and here we have and cut
and wherever
I have accessed 6
for how to put here while we wait for another command found several hearts
notice what it found and see what they say type been means do not require
authentication and end found for example announce calling scripts in the
domaine controller and found a being called and used in google and pc that
It can be anyone so what we are going to do is try to access
the scripts folder and we are going to execute a command that allows us to search between
all files that have a pattern in this case to the secure string pattern
because now as the bellowing there is only one file then for theoretical purposes
demonstrative fight is to show how we would search among a lot of
files a specific file we would search among lots of files a
string basically now let's see it well in detail
well let's do and chorus
what is we close the quotes
and there we connected yesterday as you can see it is as I told you
there is only one file, although here we could be a type and see
directly what you have suppose we have many files that we can
make known we are going to use the commands provided by power shell
in this case it is get chile and tam jump records
This is done by grabbing the files one by one and with select string
the selected files the beings rotate flat tings select
and string ah
stringer
and notice that the punctual string lists this inclusion in what
line this to sony to 1 that there is a serious string which contains this key ok yes
Well, this password is quite trivial, we know, we imagine which user
can belong we do not know the user belongs specifically then let's continue
next with the aic
well one of the countermeasures that can be done with this is basically
monitor traffic and identify the number of s & m connections in a short time
time to identify newly created files and the amount of
be that they were sent and well basically do not create is for everyone all
sides well before moving on so that there is some
doubt by chat for now but right from there they are
living some so there one says to monitor that with the employees the
channel events in windows stadium
we can identify different events that tell us when a
user is try to guide us through this then in this case it would be when
access a shared directory etc.
almost everything I put humanitarian from him selling windows
there too
German says good from his own foot to the two points between says the net bird
and they detect tulle or attack so well what a good question if they detect it
but how is the subject is more in fact this is not clarified by the principle pro
profit from the work above all the environment that we are using
Windows is disabled differently because because it detects it but something very
important to note is disabled for the simple fact that for
make the talk easier does not mean that you can not see patience no
because what happens we have the tools like good power light power view
mimic h etcetera that we have directly the source code we
if we wanted what we could do is start playing a few things is
look for the code and a few more things if we can evade it antivirus can
evade but already there we would have to start
modify it manually by basically doing a couple of functions
a couple of things to try to avoid being detected by antivirus and
obviously the same depending on the action that resists is the bird can detect it
by heuristics but for example in some cases because
it with mimicry does not detect it
then basically that if to make houses as well as to be to tools and
It detects it if one modifies the blue it does not detect it
in essence that is here our friend charly the question
Also if you will have the list of key events to take into account if not
I have here in the presentation or so I have a list of 10 I could upload it to the
I don't have a resource group uploaded but I do have a list
from there it is shared by the resource group there are some more doubts but layers we can
to advance a little more in the presentation and when
give it give it give it perfect well then the next the next
technique that we are going to see is that of power time which is basically a technique
which consists of trying to guess a password of an account basically what
It happens if we get the key directive and we have a
reduced number of keys to test we can try to perform a
kind of brute force attack with the key preventing the
users for example if we know that we can test three keys before
that it crashed and if we don't have to wait half an hour, what do we do?
we check the three keys we wait half an hour we try again
this keys we wait half an hour and thus we avoid that the good user is blocked
and another very interesting thing is that what we are going to think is that a
user has a password but a password can be had by many users how many
users in the world have the password one another and 450
and possibly a lot good let's see then we
we got a key what we are going to do is see what
users belong
add
let's go here the exceptional tool kléber spain
[Music]
now
what we are going to do is the following we are going to grab and we are going to get a
list of all domain users and what we are going to do is we are going to
the users that we are going to obtain will all be already sabritas, look at how
we make below that it does not mine and use list
we inhabit and then more
and fort rhythm
He says
out
in one with everything
So
what I let me program
okay
it's a season again to be
portion
I do not hate workshop to read I am
the bar teambox the spray
[Music]
take and use 7
being something wrong
everything that is import modules oim been days no I don't know why I wait
clearly and go
we'll see
1 we are going to review why they will not be
wanting good as they normally see when one
does these things it is like a lag, do not worry if it is false because it is
common is more tolerant when it makes us carry
safety
it can happen it never comes out so direct
I have
and I want to check something
great good how can I tell you what I have of these problems?
failures that you are seeing is called excess beer because because I come
confusing again which tool to import so back to guys who
They saw it to the green it is said if you take I do not drive if you are going to give a talk
I also did not take basically it is a very important data and
-6 looking with your eyes is a very interesting fact
now well let's go with the correct tool main à porter now yes now
what we are going to do is we are going to go with the command
that there will work what this command is doing like
I was commenting on them is that it grabs us users that it is going to grab us
all users of the domain to be deleted users who are
uninhabited and this is not going to enlist them and is going to address them in a
file that shelley uses point of txt notice that if we see the file
to use nothing contain the following naval users john feeley price
tehuel and unequal fields 0 and 7-5 well what we are going to do now is
try to grab and with these users we will try to test the key that
We find that is, the one of thai airways is if we to use the inbox domain
for word trade we are going to use list
users let's pass it like this
This is the password that is the key that we find not necessarily
that you have to do this with a password that we find but
well in this case it is to follow him
the path of attack that we are carrying out
2020 the key that we find [Music]
if everything goes well 10 notice that we found two users who
they have the key is one that is tyler ua lic
and another one that is the sql service ok
notice that it is very interesting because one can find further one
think that the user had the password, this could also be that being the
site configure sql development or sql service and assign the truth
it's good as an example let's go back to the presentation
[Music]
well obviously as a countermeasure to this monitor authentication
enable and configure multi-factor authentication correctly and do
comply with the use of strong passwords well I don't know if there are any questions in
chat and there we have a stack of questions we will continue to answer
some notes that have been left from the past payment question that brought them from
tweets from ncr tells you can be set up and direct somehow
to avoid that damage that we have to hide and that is to say that any
user who is in domain can not extract all the information all that
information no
e if after setting that dose to
expand the information that of active directory that I know no no no that's no
there is way to configure the best one can do is avoid what
leave for example relevant data fields in fields like description
etc. but no, it can't be joseba, at least no, it can't be deleted, I don't know
You can after that box and ask there is a document about the
good practices in we monitor
if there is real, all the documentation is on the official sites of
microsoft in microsoft in all the official sites greater find everything
more now later same to use a recommendation to countermeasures for a few
we will also use in everything that is from the official sites of greater other
country can find a lot of official information that you give later
help with the issue of monitoring today before we are using our own
tools provided by microsoft
later it is said that layer 8 total layer 8 that I have no doubt totally
years and here brings us more chicha will endure
Switch people bring us a little bomb that makes us Natalie de Natalia 16.080
of question when the attribute and use with control has the sac password that a
low it does not affect you there's active this being maybe with the policy that you have
configured when the garment attribute
totally
what a good question when the attribute y will use with control has frac
previous e
the truth is that i'm not sure and you killed me i'm not sure
for the jaguars and for the next one I will tell you that is how you killed me then later
about that and to be able to talk, you ask me, but hey, we will be both remember and
Any doubt they have questions they have to ask France they can come to the
Questions channel inside the disk to take care of you write them and answer well
Another important thing to clarify is at the end of this presentation
there will be my contact information so anyone send a message by
twitter facebook email and if they will continue from the question there is no drama I
I always answer no there is no problem well continuing with the presentation this is
one of my favorite attacks of my favorite attacks is the peace of hasi
password pass basically this attack uses a technique in which it consists
in which an attacker obtains the login credentials from the
system and use these captured credentials to syndicate
on other computers on the network ok fine
What happens is that what we are going to do paralyzes this attack as much
important one to use is that we already have to have local permissions
admin on the machine in this case good to the user to have the
lic is not member ways and has permission from miami on both machines is
say in the isolate and in the d the own of tyler ua lic
and what we are going to do is go testing throughout the network
and try to get into these machines for now on
which one have we done that, no
let's go for the attacker's machine
well here we are from the attacker's machine to everything we saw until
receive one, bring an attacker, remember that he could easily have done it
having a poke session but open an open ice could
quietly execute power code senate the other machine and it could operate
both so I made it simple from these local machines to make it more
easy to see but not good what we are going to do now
that we are going to try to grab and review this with the user and the user
de Teruel and that we already know its password, we are going to try rosell guide in several
machines for which we have track map access
xx this is
let me see the ip
[Music] 8.15 14 good
well that there and where and local court point
p
and point 2020
and what will start to do if not false is to start looking at the
red ok if i fail now i will r
although from r
and you are going to die the quotes in the key
let's check that
not
okay
well today we see you tank m you hear me totally
the other bar is not the other bar is not
Let's see, let's take a second to hunt they are
praising your bottom to the bottom about you if I did the bottom to the harp I said
well if the monkey clap in the background is going to give for one of the two things it had
what to give - for that we are going to increase the letter a
we are if the failure of the workshop is not necessary
have them have faith hands to avargues pheasant bio
to see with this that I am eating and that action asking him the size of the
letter there yes there is increase more had increased
just but you know it appears that he was using another
version of crack not for that reason it did not fail
ok since I had another version to create and for
that
effectively for the bar
no this
Now, well, as you can see, it can fail and this is something that I also want
say the back the slow bar just as good as what was failing me
whole prison something else is something I love you I love you
share that it is always interesting whenever something fails them
go back to the documentation if I am surely going to carry the beams but
always go back and try to see what's up
can always save us in this case what happens to me is that again
you are using is the command that I had prepared was for another version of that
gay crack matic set in which you did not have one did not have to anticipate the
cmb parameter ok and that's why it was failing
[Music] what yes
I am not sure if I take the password correctly because it is not
showing how it should display the results
let's check one thing in the user
again the key that I had seems works are like for 85 user
there are 85 different keys as they are no longer mixed
we wave to drink something
what do I want to verify
it is not right and here what I am verifying if it is
network discovery active but not the case
this plan is forgetting happens to me I am giving something very fundamental no
what is to specify the user that is why it is failing me after the same failure
one thing begins to fail you everything and you begin to forget everything so nothing
I was missing users the amount of layer 8 errors that
I have been having today is is an animal well
look how now
we can start testing and we can see how the ipc could be achieved
we can see how it could be achieved and corp both pc and we know that already these hosts
this user has access to basically that
you will say the command is quite simple but hey when one is
misplaced it usually happens but in essence it was that to be able to show
how one can grab with a user can
It will arrive when you get access to several machines, we are here testing
with all the machines the domain and we managed to verify some have
access to three machines let's go back one touch for the presentation
to
over here
well let's go now with what is that is peace
of password with us we pass a key but of something called a
technique called peace leave ok in which it gets consists of theft and
reuse of basic credentials before this is divided into two stages:
first is that an attacker has to gain access as local admin at al
minus one from the computer and the seconds that the attacker does is
try to increase access to other computers on the network by using good
steal one or more authentication beliefs and use the
stolen passwords people stolen credentials how this works
in short basically we surely have three of said that we
we have different hashes with the imm etcetera
what we are going to be here is if we get one of those hashes that
It can be obtained in several ways now let's see one of them how
you use eyebrows to get into other machines ok basically it works like this
attack we are going to review normally the attacker wants to access a resource
ok the server then sent towards authentication the attacker provides
the proportional attacker hilux news ears and sends them from our tree and is
so the value of the hash against the expected value that in case of being
correct is grant him access to the atlante
well let's see how to do this, the first thing we are going to do is
next we are going to grab and we are going to clean the
gases found in tyler's machine smells like we're gonna do this
we are going to a tool but now we are going to clarify something surely it is
a lot of you already have experience with project goals you have used previously
metasploit and what one knows there are a couple of metasploit tools that
when one gets it is the one that allows one foot to garages but as it is, it fails
several options better for me this tool was used that I have shared
with you what is an impact & christmas secret stamp tool
although I'm only using is if you want
although now it is
and now if it's there
eri corp bar
lic
2 points tyrell
point 2020
8.1 15.5 this ip is the relic machine what we are going to do with this
tool is to magnify the gases found in the tyler week machine
and here I surely ate the quotes
there you go, look at how one starts to get
change the streets of who is in that machine
we here for example look we have zero streets of the account
administrator administrator and notice that I saw an account called admin and corp
okay
we have this hard it turns out that this account is an admin account that is
created by company policies on all company computers with
the same password then what happens to us to see the hash
what we will be able to do is enter all the real computers of the
business
let's go lit and this is very common to happen I have had
very fun experiences and not so
very on the edge of the legal, let's say there, well, much more in the destination but
can you say that
but it can be said that it is a very nice experience with this type of
things where when they realize they have the key all over the place it's like
which is basically an ace that fulfilled this knowledge is already there basically then
in access two sides even if you do not have access to the dogma
to control because many times it is not the
The same password, since the machines of a company have access to all this and it is
very interesting nobody sees how I commented but they argue
that is very important is not only to get dressage jamming permits but
base what is important is the impact it can generate because there are cases where
it generates more impact to leave a being shared with critical data than
get a friday morning and essentially what we gonna do now
search let's go to a diamond exploits module
but
to 10
good options
perfect
thirst what we are going to do is we are going to try
access the pc we are going to inter access the pc of tyrell huelin
with the hash of the user the new one that we get that of admin with ok
I would have also achieved this if I had done here
instead of com container ue lic if I had done this on the machine
de àngel amos would also have worked but with web users, for this
you need local services min you are wanted
let me ripert this is we are going to enter it and
60 cc 192 122 points
168 point 15 points 5 I will also be reports from essen
[Music]
lee corp
s peace and there what we are going to do is
we're going to nail the hash as it comes straight all the way and we're going to
put on that baby and wear
wei lin de
let's look at options to see if nothing will die
I think we weren't going to give it the exploit and that's where we crossed our fingers ok
let's give again
let's try
with the one we long for
sorry yes yes thanks to this injury the chat criticize more guys
the user misuses the user the user s
admin and court to domingo and korn
exactly
but let's go back to change this here
and the dream I do not know if the trick is discussed well
if the user is ok to check it admin and corp too
so [Music]
ok let's talk
Jones we are going to give because we lack mass of
cicop and well the progressive hash
and if then well it is that it is fine to me neither
court is fine be a payroll is fine
he doesn't love us
I do not know
well
that's if i'm pretty sure ah no
here not ok what happened good first I put in the
second user today I come has an amount of
third tremendous basket errors that we are using a domain user is a
local user
the ip not the base which is fine because in my hair squid s & p has to be to go with
he
wide jail lovers request some appear
if that's how it was harry well rodrigo knows go
having a very crazy week for cell phone a difficult week a week
hard
for we are approaching this with games the name of the pc
wellink and a pc close the lic
the same with the point I should take it, hug for example
point 5
come on come on let's open let's take in the little hand and chat and opened that his
art let's go to this edition to a beer that had
something else totally totally great passion of the brand brand
to share totally well as it has to be
Well we could have mind session squeeze
then notice how net system net authorizes in
you and authority system have to send the energy as totally if with the
little hands today in the chat with everything they saw that you can you can you have to be
five hours when one is half distracted who is 5 waiting for you but
It can
but well, well, as you saw with obtaining the user, we can
grab and we can enter the machine of others this is very very interesting in
especially because even in comparative environments and there are 28 other machines that
They all have the same admin user with the same password and if you can't
decipher the keys they grab the with the peace attack you leave in Pampan and start
To hit everywhere is great when you are not half burned great
totally
well let's go back here let's go back to the
presentation
well well countermeasures we can use against this attack and install and
configure lapse what administration password solution to restrict and protect
domain accounts that have local administrator privilege and
restrict and protect local administrator accounts, although these
250 of local administrators do not help us to function
well then we have the impersonation of
tokens that basically this is a technique to be used as an administrator
local to impersonate another user logged into a system
this is very useful in scenarios where you have permission
local administrator on a machine and you want to impersonate another user
connected for example a domain administrator that we
Bastian maybe we have a crazy administrator on the machine because with these
admin and corp and I find that there is a domain admin that has been praised and I
I want to pretend is another user basically that are these tokens
tokens are a temporary key that allow you to access the system and the network
without having to provide credentials each time a
file there are two types of tokens delegated tokens are created for startups
interactive sessions such as logging into or connecting to the machine
via remote desktop and spoofing touches are for sessions
of non-interactive e.g. attach a network drive
that is, for example an interactive touch when a user is
unlocks if, for example, in a jamming shot it is seen and this token is achieved
it was that interactive because delegate 11 what happens is plantation when not
whenever and well let's see how this works
well we are going to do it is a module called 5 minutes
let's come by the loft
5 nito ok something I'm going to do is us now
we are in the machine of teide llewellyn ok
let's guide us now with philip wright's account phillips price is the seal
of the company because he is the executive director of bar the key of philip
wright why no i'm not going to remember it to stick
notice it is a very secure password 2020 key with exclamation mark
obviously always with very secure and robust keys
then what happens what is what we are going to see here
I am not succeeding with these users and I am going to do is close the session.
been one I do not guide you because let's pretend that the been had to see something
On the site's computer it will be one day and he saw it, he came here, he decided
grab come here make a single and that's just that
happens there is a token is more hopefully it ends from home
as for them to remain calm that it is totally obvious, notice that already
It is the guided that has an open session outside the war, what we are going to do is
we are going to grab and we are going to list the tokens that are in this machine
list digesting in another list
under tokens I
and notice that we can the delegated touches that is the one of
and corp philip klais then what are we going to do
we are going to impress that one is ok ok how to do that we are going to use
impersonal person
and under top gun and corp
good and now what are we going to see
is the following, once we have done this, what we can take is answer
and we are going to see what we have we are like the user of feel price that is to say that
We successfully represent the user of feel price
and obviously we once we did this we could already execute
commands like philip price which is the biggest
and notice something very common in all these totals that many things can be
to mitigate
doing simple things like not leaving a lot of Miami everywhere
they can be thrown by the side not to be left arsenal hard easy keys are things
simple which cannot be solved but hey many times it does not happen to you
good as countermeasures to this attack limit the accesses of the accounts
only at their corresponding levels, for example the accounts
of domain greens and enterprise admin that only access something else in controls
that is to say that yes or yes he has permission from Miami and that he does not access the computer
of sites for example and restrict and control local administrators
that exist on the machines as well without local administrator permission
again this attack could not be carried out
well let's see another one that is told
zinc this attack consists of using the command of 10 and zinc inside mini cats
and allows to simulate the behavior of a 2 domain controller and well this
What it does is that it asks two more controls to pass them the data of
the user password attackers must compromise a
You have the rights to perform domain replication and once it is
get these proper privileges take advantage of the command a mini command
cats were interests had commented before that they used a lot of
things this tool is used to clean streets of local machines
even to extract passwords from the ram memory depending on the version of
windows in this case what it will do is
recovering the streets was when it shows the activity account
well let's see how to do this attack
let's go back to the machine but in this case we get a bit of what is
the root view panorama for this point task
We are going to use it, it is a user called that is 35
I put this attack on time because it is very common in companies that use
sharepoint for example that a sharepoint user ups them or profiles in
green section requires this specific permit and many companies if they are aware
Final have no idea and from my own experience I have seen that they leave this the key
in plain text like this
in one arrive and you don't even have the idea of ​​how important this user is because
Well obviously as I say and you have nothing to
let's see now you can do this attack let's go with him the attack
the key of the mind always very complex so step 1
Well, what we are going to do is a workshop, let's go to me and cats, so 64 let's go
to here
[Music] let's go from here to a consultation
daniel hundred english yes user if you changed the password the same will
being able to enter that is asking me with the investment touch axxion is a
good question the truth is that I was looking at the
official documentation and not the clear cause in the documentation is of the module
it does not succeed and personally I never tried it, it would have to be tried
I'm not sure I'm sure but I can't do it with honor
and in the documentation the documentation will be associated clarifies this that one is
can praise and stay and the doukas does not clarify the issue of whether a change of
key code
well if we say
with this
you can also try the first one it seems that not all 8 would not be one
good idea in this animal if they give us time if I know area with everything they have
The fact of the boys is that something else fails since it fails the least that makes it one
it stains the tiger more, no
and now we do it if we do it live
because those things are interesting it is interesting to try friends
you may be wondering since I am bad, good because in this virtual machine
I have the keyboard in the clear horizon year I have mine is in English
then and they do not know what it costs me to type well
How can we see here what we managed to do?
is to directly clean the hub in this case from the administrator account
domain notice
great second good here we have the jasen they have money
to each sun of their opinion they are allowed to have the administrator account of the
domain
as because it is not as we say we remember we emulate being a take on
against we ask the original found dogma to explain to us the
credentials won't replicate and we got the
administrator user credentials basically that
that against measures we can take against this good attack the best protection
against an attack of that zinc is to control domain permissions
responsible for controlling the permissions of domains responsible for allowing
accounts replicate changes inevitably today versus inevitably
some users will have this right and must be well protected and we will
let's do that test that was posing in the public we
what we were doing was let's use
your being and what I just did for those who don't
you know is to return to my previous privilege that I returned from phil and price to the privilege
previous
we are going to give the touches that we have although toukan of philip is still
price and what we are going to do is we are going to grab and we are going to change the password
we are going to change it will be from the domaine controller
because clearly this
we are going to reid seth password we are going to put
to know
word 30 21 exclamation mark
well there it was changed
well let's come back here and let's try
and let's say that in person
I there and apparently yes in people with which other tuna can be
Doing the impersonation of all looks of riding can also be done with
power plate tools yes yes not only with that it is easier but
it is ok from power point in fact it can be done
if not for this it is also good to clarify that for all that I am
doing now although I am using some tours it is not that they are the only ones
for example all impact suites & has a lot of tours that are
They recontra roses and they can follow them a lot, it kind of depends on the situation
one chooses the best tool there are not a lot of your to do the same it depends
of what you need an hour that is more comfortable for you
but hey there are several tools and regarding sewing
what I'm going to try to do is xx jude
john f cmd dot exe dash and dash
ok he didn't leave me if I can be
and now to see if I can do
slash and cor dash slash
rosso already with this we see what happens
I don't take it in a second if I'm not sure
say the results that appear there is why it was
if I put powers he
No means no
ok I am about to die the session of interpreting it
only me
well i'm not working because i threw it up and it takes it to get this
more I would have to see how it will happen to the grass is not taking me but beginning
answering the question that was out there on the chat I would say yes that
it works for me the problem I am having here is for now the goal
Something like this has happened to me other times with project goals, I would say yes
In short, I do not know if any other questions until now
I did not see that they were writing but it still follows us as soon as they fire
all ok well now what we are going to do is
let's make a short pause and then it's a pause of five
minutes to drink something stretches your legs relaxes your head a little
I imagine that they will all be burned, I also already realized
that some if thank you in 5 minutes we are
coming back here in ekoparty tweets
well here we are again we are going with the last part of this
workshop
and we will be looking at everything that is the kerberos protocol
and let's see how to attack this protocol
anything there is a question from daniel that exists to erase those
token with nowhere
let's give a second I'm checking something
because they always want to pass the others but that's where we are
securing the big one directly before re-assuring that
we do the same they will fail because that is how the demos work
well repeating the question told me if the
questions could be deleted those touch with some gp or
with any GP that I know of, not even though I don't know, there is no GP or that one
you can use to erase those touches
well one after another more not only very good that you have to light a candle for him
God of the demos and a lot of reason not just a candle to all has to
learn a candle so wait yes yes yes we agree we totally
Okay well let's go with this last segment of the workshop which is
kerberos kerberos basically in director activity and we the
authentication that root through iker see what this protocol is
basically this is a protocol that your dreams are based on what
they call tickets and this is presented to the different resources of the network to
check your permissions kerberos is an authentication player but not
authorization that we distinguish authentication from authorization auto is
basically say kerberos is a protocol that said in a very crude way
and direct and authentic to a person himself to say proof that such an identity is
Who claims to be this means that the protocol is good
It is not in charge, I am going to say that the protocol is in charge of identifying
each user through an unknown password just for aesthetics but not
determines what resources or services said user may or may not access even if
let's take into account that authentication details not authorization well said
this let's see the third party elements is the client machine where
find the user you want who wants to access the service
we have the machine that offers the service, that is, the system to which the
user wants to access and we have the key distribution center which is a server
central which is in charge of authenticating users and distributing among them
tickets so they can be identified against other machines
services in the case of a tories activity the one you want is installed in the
same dressage in control
and then there are these tickets that I was commenting on, of which there are two the
service tickets or the tickets that are used to identify identify yourself
against the services and two large ticket in tickets that are used to
authenticate against the candy server and get them pgs to access
to the different services well how does this work we are
a users x can be any domain user
we are going to go we are going to make a user of we isolate and we make a rich
exterior to request a trinquet a granite ticket return us worthy is
free ticket with this one we are going to make them dgt to make more enabled with this
ticket we look again at the one who says that van baldom returns us in
against returns the ts which contains the hash of the account
services ok we send here with the hash
ours and here it returns us with the hashtag of the service account that
now we are going to see it well we are attacking and then well this we
We send them to the service server which we want to access
now that we are centering the kerberos part over our part
more complicated workshop and more difficult to follow so with this already
this
or if they more or less hook those hands, we have just two tickets
one that is the big ticket and ticket and then we have the landín ticket
service which is with which we can access the service with the
landi ticket ticket we access the big ticket and service and with the ticket
during in service we access the service well before continuing
I am going to explain something, it is called service principal names or the esp / n the esp not
Service principal names are basically used to identify
exclusively for each instance a service in windows
to enable authentication kerberos requires that the cpn be associated
with at least one account login service an account specifically
in charge of executing an essential service sbn are used very commonly
to secure services to manage applications such as make sure
Álvaro óscar tells us well, let's see now how to attack
kerberos and we are going to see if attacking that it is good can be understood more in
depth how does it work we are going to give a specific attack which is the laker
austin that is a task that what he does is try to use these services and kits
to create user passwords offline
this attack wanting browsing uses the passwords of services use the
service accounts that leverage warrior serial authentications with
the main names of services say the bronze team what it does is
use service accounts that leverage camero authentication
with the sps the service tickets as I mentioned come with the ntm hash of the
domain account to the quality of the service that is, we are reviewing again
when he returns here the ts returns with the hearts of the account that this society in
in this case the account that is associated goes to a service in this case
service to do the sql server ok wants to connect the account with sp esp
n so if a user requests a tps
of a service that is linked to a user once the tgss is obtained.
can lead to work and find on your own machine trying to create the
user password let's look at some important data to
take into account how any user authenticated to you director and we can
request a gs that is to say how am I going to use standard
we scan active directory for user accounts with esp / n values
established that is what we are going to use a tgc is requested to
access a service by specifying its esp / n
to you director and flight a ts containing the hash of the accounts
associated with this service or that social service accounts with sst cpn
we grab the cash what is left until we get the password of the account in
plain text ok
let's review the new one but in another way because I know you are half
far-fetched and that it is 36 redundant but I prefer as means to explain it in
different ways, it even came out a little, let's go again, what we do is scan
active directory looking for user accounts with set cpn values
ok we go we have to look for the
user account have these values ​​that are those are have that are like aliases of
cpn be well established we have to request the ticket of
service in the d using cpn values ​​if we request with
our grand ticket a service ticket we have to get the
service tickets and save them to a file and good to create that ticket
we will use brute force well and let's see how this is
let's go so we can come back here fine
what we are going to do
it's gay ius art
they fire and cut
a local point
a brown in this case so they see that we are using a
user with few privileges we make this tool that we are using
it is also part of the impact suite & ok this get and use the spy
nothing like the one told them in packages like a huge monster that
has beautiful tools no no we cannot see all of them because we
It would take later to say that it must be another course for six there are things that if
one gets to see in details are they are workshops apart for example what of
antivirus evasion that these guys told you before about a total issue that
you can do but it is totally apart I what I want to verify this ip ok is the
ip of the domaine controller ok the 192 points hundreds of 8.4 and look at us
Now what we are going to do is this and notice that we here have the
ticket ok and now I'm good right here they have the
piece of tickets we are going to delete the ticket that had already been created from
from the previous bs workshop
and what we are going to do and there where the controversial comes the controversial of the night
and let's open a text editor that a lot of people look weird to open this
text editor and that's where in the base tweet chat
but as you can be using nothing, this should not be illegal as you can not
to be using that well nothing I love to see these things is radio beat but yes
not susana
yes yes yes yes I know what we are going to do if we fail also call Susana I don't know anything
of what exists, I already know, I know that entering here and streaming serna is not hey
hey they already told me previous months
is like saying that he wears white like that
and well so those monies in those transfers of choosing you are opening
debates that I think will be there in the chat pressure if long
It does not matter the basis of the debate if the fight is the fight of the year
and well nothing there what you are hash cut as you could see basically the
Grab him, pass him the ticket he had obtained and notice that he kept the password
that good in this case they were from the unit personally to dictionary the rope
until 2020 it remembers that we had already obtained real through the method of
hours time but hey the idea was to show how through this attack of
bankrupt Austin we could get the key is staying in the
good ticket as a countermeasure basically the
best protection against a roasting goat attack is to ensure that the
service accounts using kerberos with cpn values ​​have passwords
long and complex and obviously if also if it is possible that these
passwords are rotated regularly to detect an attack in progress
What you have to do is control the normal use of the account.
services must traditionally be used from the same systems of the same
way so it is possible to detect authentication anomalies besides good
you can monitor service ticket requests in the active
directory to look for spikes in these requests
Well now let's go with some final conclusions and some things I want to reject
there are also other attacks of warriors as then authentic
distinguish difficult vertical that we will not be mentioning in this talk
I have dictated it in the previous workshop that was in the echo for good in this one
for a matter of time, it will not be there and we will go directly to the
final conclusions where I am going to be commenting a little about a
tool called hawn blog and I'll be showing you a little bit and now
with this we close which blog although it is an open source tool that
basically allows us to automate the discovery of routes to be able to
compromising an environment to you director and using several of these those attacks
we saw this tool also graphical everything so it is beautiful when
see them more to say it is excellent good and we will go to the last one
of model of the night where what we are going to do is
came why
with sun what am I doing here if the database is working ok
and a sharia cause exc
and here we are going to blog
and there he goes wanting
What I'm going to show here is basically data that was imported
we can execute a point line of ground power using a
program we can create a kind of files and if I am not confused what
now we verify that we then import it into this tool and we
gives all these data that we previously listed and allows us
graph everything and in case we have a web infrastructure it is
all very nice with this demo that I'm doing with two machines but our
Real structure we have 500 machines and it's crazy I'm going to do it here
come good young people and a yep let's go to the radio ok
[Music]
we are going to go to
dalí take note
it did not matter well building the graph
Now let's see how, look at me, it brings me both
mindfulness that notice that for example goodbye to find all the tomatoes to me
It does not tell me good 3 is the same service transfer and price you have the administrator
and this is part of the group of this miami fixed today before all these colista
back they are already presses made one could grab and could
and doing your own ways now is obviously going to what you need
each one grabs
No return
So
Well let's look here here I managed to ask is that you tell me the main purpose sweet sixteen
write notice that it appears from that zinc that belongs to the dot liquor domain
local and notice how the root of all the connections with everything is as you can see is
basically excellent automatically allows them to graph and
obviously here look at the graph that is and we are talking about three machines
used we have a server and two clients and fixed of all the buoyant
there are only the machine there are the groups there are the users
to everything
to see if I do not know if it will seem that we do not depend on having
if you find something like mai no
look good that carver not this bag counts I think the second services
well this is the account that erviti city is good we came to give for
the own account that uses kerberos and the one of good the one of sql services that is
an account that is not ready when I put it I put what list this account is
and well nothing as you could see this was a to show you a little what it is about
this tool can obviously be exploited much, much more but
well it was like at least they know her and see what they think
and well nothing with this we are already reaching the end of this workshop
Thank you very much everyone for attending the truth, thank you also very much to
the guys from the echo who recovered are always always supportive
Thank you very much to the info community I know that the truth is that I do not know if you such
time you are the first is that in a stream and the community was never at your
message the community one does not realize me five years ago personally people
Of course I do not remember how long ago nor did it occur to me that I could be here contributing my
grain of sand to the community and tomorrow can obviously be you
who are here contributing their grain of sand also to the community and
sweating a lot because we fail them we give it like that, I don't know about you
Rodríguez if you also want to add something I do not want to thank you
all the boys of the eco send a greeting also to good
from my team send a greeting to the layman boy and I am not walking in voice
rodri
adding everything that exists before nothing that I as a developer is
communicating this avenue is very good for all those who have just been - all
they fear and know the echo, I recommend that they join when they can
do the lectures again go are incredible the people behind
it is a mass so not wide angle sad and very
proud also several years ago I go and there is always a new train and I
They surprise every year so a hug from the team that is behind everything
this and will give pride so he also imparts a greeting to all
streaming studios hello guys have the chat guys that
They study helping topics that I am with a couple of things and others so that it is not
so nothing completed with that well I already bought the country closing again I leave you
The resources are there the same, he left me there but if it falls, it could be the
There are also resources, I think they have a form for you to give me your feedback
what they liked in the ones that would improve or not
Well, nothing said, I say goodbye and one more thing is that nothing is added to
the conferences as Rodríguez said even if it is the first time if you don't
be sure or think that it is not enough do not hesitate always go to
conferences take that first step which is the most beautiful thing that can happen to you
Well it happened to me today well here we are with demos that break but pass
from the pump so good nothing people a big hug
a huge greeting to all of you and see you in the next one and shared in the
next workshop a big hug see you
[Music]
or or not
[Music] how
[Music]
[Music] or not
[Music] or
[Music]
well
not
[Music]