you
next up we have a minister our
Cloudy with a Chance of breach
forecasting cyber security incidents
thanks thanks very much so this is going
to be a little bit of a meta talk it's
not going to be about moving moving
routes around it's not going to be about
moving packets around or not moving
blocking them it's going to be a little
bit about some thoughtful strategic
thinking it's going to be a little bit
about policy it's going to be a little
bit about measurements and it's going to
be a lot about data so let's get started
so I'll be talking about forecasting
cyber security incidents I'm a nice
career and the CDO a quad metrics but
the work i'm presenting here really was
led by some fine folks at both the
university of michigan and illinois
young armand jing para nós michael and
minion so what's the background what is
this what was the problem and where did
the problem come from the the underlying
premise of this work was that reputation
matters your reputation on the internet
does matter and security posture of your
organization or somebody else's is or
should be an important part of a
business relationship ask this to just
t-mobile and Experian last week when
they reported the the data breach
perhaps t-mobile could have made a
different choice with a vendor if they
had known the risk probability of
experience they had a choice of vendors
and they chose one and we had the data
to show that they could have made a
different choice of Mike which might
have had a better better result for them
finally the issue with with doing this
though is that security posture is is a
sum total of many many factors it
includes people training it includes
technology deploy how will you deploy as
well as processes what mechanisms do you
have in place to to manage and monitor
and fix things and the problem is
measuring these things is really hard
and you need metrics to be able to do it
so you can be structured and thoughtful
about how you're doing it so it's not
apples to to oranges comparisons it's
apples to apples repetitive over time so
that you have consistency so finally you
need and you need
to be able to do this at scale because
you need this information not just about
yourself needed about all organizations
that you might potentially deal with and
finally who has who has these kinds of
problems well for example the Department
of Homeland Security which was the
initial funding behind this research
effort has this problem of being able to
assess critical infrastructure they
can't go on site they can't deploy
packet taps everywhere they have to have
some reports some independent way of
generating risk aggregation information
companies have need for this as well
we're talking about measuring
third-party risk managing their vendor
relationships and they have a need for
this information to understand their own
their own security posture not just
their current status but how are they
making changes that are making this
better or worse over time and finally
the the important one we see the cyber
cyber security insurance marketplace
stepping into this this area as well
they're starting to write policies and
they need to be able to base those
policies on actuarial information and
sound sound statistics and we all know
that 2014 breaches that were there were
top headlines including target home
depot JP Morgan on and on and on and in
some of the work that I'm going to talk
about those were actually case studies
so the one slight summary of what this
talk is really about is is this we use
internet scale data measurements and
machine learning to do predictive cyber
security risk analysis of organizations
and the information is useful for
underwriters to set premiums for cyber
insurance there are several other things
you can do there as well several
innovations you can think about when it
comes to doing cyber security insurance
because it really is a little bit of a
bit different beast than normal
insurance policies that they're used to
and finally network managers or
administrators can use this information
to measure the security posture of their
own enterprise and as well as the risk
of their partners so let's let's get
into the nitty-gritty detail of how we
do this so largely it's all about the
data it starts and ends with the data we
do large-scale and ended measurements
what do we measure
everything we're talking about measuring
active risks we're talking about
measuring late and risks as well as
mismanagement indicators we do modeling
and feature extraction based on the data
data that we do collect we have to do
aggregation of all this data up to an
organization level that is it just by
itself a challenging task we have to
develop features what are we going to
model what are the characteristics that
are potentially interesting that should
be fed into the models and finally
cleaning the data for the labels is an
extremely challenging task remember data
we have to collect historical
information as well and most of that is
reported by organization not IP
addresses so you sort of have to do this
manual process of matching breach
information into aggregation but more
about that in a little bit finally once
you have clean your aggregate data
you've cleaned this data you can
actually apply standard machine learning
techniques we can use a random forest
machine learning algorithm and at the
end of that you end up with prediction
scores based on on your models and you
can and then you go through an exercise
of doing a validation what is your test
set what is your training set and so on
and so forth so mismanagement symptoms
water what are some examples of things
that you can look for in terms of data
sets about the internet you can look at
for example open recursive resolvers
Thank You Jarrett identity for the find
data set that's one of the data sets
that we used another example might be
you can conduct tests on DNS source port
randomization who's implementing it
who's not you can look at BGB
misconfigurations the frequency at which
these events are occurring from an
organization whether it's typos
intentional anything slip ups or you can
just look at something at the
application layer talk about untrusted
https certificates what is the ratio of
expired certificate locally signed
certificates versus legitimate external
certificates and even open smtp relays
that that may exist at an organization
all of those may or may not be directly
related to the breach but the key idea
is there indicative of patterns and an
organized
and remember when we're talking about
modeling at such large scales you're
looking for subtle hints that when all
aggregated put together will give you a
comprehensive view of what's going on at
an organization what are examples of
malicious activities data this is
relatively simpler to understand so
malicious activities are usually of the
kind of spamming scanning hosting
malware phishing sites and these can be
aggregated from a wide variety of
sources things like Spamhaus spam cop a
lot of fish fishing lists are available
out there as well as dark net scanning
sensors can give you a hint of botnet
activity and all of this the information
is stuff we gather and aggregate and
model and finally this is the hard part
in machine learning getting ground truth
data to label your models we use three
different sources to build our
collections of incidents the most
commonly cited database is of course the
verizon data breach report data set this
has well about four to five thousand
reported incidents publicly reported in
some incidents that are that have been
gathered together there are a couple of
other reports like the hack McGinn or
the web hacking incidents database those
these are maintained on a voluntary
basis with by individuals and so we
aggregate all of these three different
sources together they each have that
their different biases in terms of kinds
of incidents that are reported so all
together it gives us a very good
distribution of the kinds of incidents
that are being collected in this in this
data set now once we've collected and
cleaned all of this data comes a hard
part of actually different developing
features that we're going to build our
models on we develop about 250 different
features and we're aggregating a lot of
this information up weird some examples
of features might be simple features
like mismanagement symptom ratios number
of invalid certs to valid certs ratios
open relays 22 well configured mail
servers
an organization other things might be
simple time series of rbl activity at an
aggregated scale or of fact fractions of
address block that are that are part of
an rbl all giving you subtle hints along
different axes of the security posture
for an organization and finally some of
the more interesting features that we
also look at are not just first order
statistics not just the raw counts or
ratios but also how these are changing
over time so we look at two to
three-month trending of this data and we
can develop derived features like
frequency or duration of different
malicious activities those those are
also fed into our models finally and
this actually turns out to be the easier
part because there are lots of libraries
that you can standard machine learning
techniques that you can apply once you
clean the data we use a simple random
forced machine learning classifier it
uses a sampling approach to build a
forest of decision trees and doesn't
averaging across all of those so you get
some robustness and resilience against
imperfections in the data and very
interestingly we use a fifty-fifty
training and testing test but what does
that mean so what we do is we take the
sum total of activities breaches that
are reported in the 2013-2014 time frame
we divide that into two parts the first
part is the data set that we use for
actually training our models so we use
that to to feed into the algorithms they
generate a model and finally the models
right we use that the other half of our
training set as incidents we pretend we
know nothing about and use that to
evaluate the accuracy of her models so
this is the test we pretend this is
going to be a blind test let's pretend
we know nothing about these how well
could we have done in predicting all of
these incidents that show up in the
second half and that's the second half
of the incident and I'll talk about the
results and the second half of the talk
finally the testing is used to evaluate
and demonstrate the accuracy of our
models and of course being the
scientific paper that this was there's a
there's a lot of time and effort spent
on training on multiple windows
multiple data combinations multiple
parameters for the machine learning
algorithms I'll skipper the over the
details of those because those are in
the paper so the results here's the
overall false positive true positive
from the evaluation exercises we run on
our data breach prediction overall if
you look at the the black line with the
triangles on it that is when you're
looking at the prediction of events
across all of our data breach sources
remember the fifty percent set that I
mentioned that we were going to use for
our testing what we're looking at on the
y-axis is a true positive percentage and
on the on the x-axis the false positive
so if you look at where those two
horizontal dashed lines cross you will
see that's about the ninety percent mark
for true positive and the ten percent
mark for false positive what this means
is for the fifty percent of our data set
that we pretended we knew nothing about
our models were able to predict with a
ninety percent accuracy that those
incidents were for organizations that
had a high risk in other words their
data indicated that those organizations
were doing things that were more likely
to lead to breaches than not in terms of
the different features that we test for
there was a clear differentiation
between the kinds of features that were
more important relatively more important
than others remember we were measuring
for a wide variety of characteristics
but as it turned out our hunch that
mismanagement features would be the most
predictive was actually correct with
what you're looking at in this chart is
the contribution to the overall
importance of the different features if
you look at the top row there the
mismanagement features were contributing
about thirty percent to the overall
score for different organizations and
the other the other features are listed
there as well and this concurrent sort
of was was very interesting because it
confirmed our intuitive understanding
that the human element is the most
important factor in cyber security
however and this is the twist in it can
you just
use the mismanagement features to train
your models why do you even need the the
malicious activity data set so we so we
did the exercise where we split out our
data and just use the mismanagement
features to build our models and tests
and as it turns out if you look at the
blue line there on this chart miss
management features by themselves have
an extremely low true positive false
positive ratio what works well is the
combination or the red line where you
look once again at the ninety percent
accuracy mark the red line on the chart
is once again displaying a true positive
of about ninety percent in the false
positive of ten percent so as it turns
out the most interesting result of the
study is that it's not just one or two
things that you need to measure about an
organization in order to develop a
cybersecurity prediction model you need
to look at all of them and and the
intuition behind this is actually very
interesting so remember cybersecurity at
an organization is not just a matter of
securing the routing path it's not a
matter of securing just the DNS servers
it spans the whole organization so
you're looking at securing everything
from the web applications to the DNS
servers to the workstations to the
servers to the switches in the closet
that people forgot oh and also there's a
polycom units in the in the conference
room that need to be secured as well and
that is sort of the intuition intuitive
understanding behind why you need to be
able to collect as diverse a set of data
as you can about an organization to be
able to capture all of these different
elements across many different sub
organizations within Europe within an
organization and finally this was a
chart that summarizes or attempted to
place on our prediction models where
some of the more high-profile incidents
during the 2013-2014 time span fell in
terms of her prediction ratios what
you're looking at is the CDF chart of
and on which is on the y-axis and on the
exit access you're looking at our
predictor output scores remember the
numbers are really percentages so point
8 actually means eighty percent and
we've placed for example so many
pictures with a risk probability of
ninety percent chance of reach
she did have an incident you're looking
at the vendor for the target is listed
there as well as an eighty-four percent
and the vendor for JPMorgan Chase is
listed on there as well online tech
which is a ninety-two percent
probability of reach sure so you're
looking at fairly accurate predictions
in terms of incidents that did occur the
organizations that were there were high
risk in that time frame and since the
paper has been published remember our
models were trained in about 2013-2014
and the flow of data breaches has not
stopped so this is sort of an update on
where we are in terms of our prediction
accuracy there's been anthem health care
we had them at about a ninety percent
probability breach they reported a
breach in March of 2015 same with the
Penn State Rutgers Office of Personnel
Management and even Experian so the
accuracy of the models has actually held
up remarkably well over time so in
conclusion it is possible to
statistically predict cyber security
incidents on the basis of historical
incidents which is really what we're
doing and remember what we're using is
pre incident data about these
organizations they have not currently
reported a breach we're looking at
characteristics that are pre incident
and we're using those to build models
and compare those models to historical
models of organizations that did report
a breach that and this is and the
difference between detection and
prediction is key detection relies
heavily on signatures and you have to
have a signature or zero-day all right
in play for you to have a have a
signature prediction is about looking at
patterns that may not be the reason for
data breach it's the equivalent of
asking people how often do you work out
or half and you go to the gym and then
trying to develop their life insurance
policy for them security posture an
organization is a many dimensional
problem and it requires data from many
parts of that organization and finally
protecting against data breaches
requires finding a battle on many fronts
you need to have a pro policy that is
that applies to the whole organization
and that spans across all different sub
organizations I didn't accompany lots of
time for questions
said Sandy Murphy Parsons so your graph
that said here's all the measurements
against the people who have had
break-ins so I could invent a measure
that just said everybody has a ninety
percent chance of being broken into
absolutely and then everybody who had an
incident I could say look see it's a
wonderful predictor have you looked at
yes benign examples people who are
really strong and say oh look our
measure shows they were there really
yeah so both is a population and and for
specifics the blue line on this chart
talks about the distribution for the
general population which did not have
security breaches and you can clearly
tended the distribution of scores is
different for those but I think what
you're asking specifically for is is
there a distribution is there mean in
terms of what does an average
organization on the internet look like
and for the data reported in the paper
there was a very nice 22 ha bell curve
which focused on a fifty percent of
probability so sorry the score of point
five was actually where most of the
organization's existed and only about
ten percent of the organizations had
scores greater than eighty-five percent
so only ten percent of the organizations
on that on the Internet has scores
greater than eighty-five percent okay
and another question is I wondered in
your case of mismanagement if you
considered things like the release level
for the various pieces of software that
people are using and their ability to
accept out-of-date crypto algorithms and
how fast they're doing patches and stuff
yes that so that's that's one of our
ongoing efforts right now we're looking
at many many different aspects of
aggregating mismanagement information
both version levels patch levels so we
are continuing to expand that but not
for that for the results in that paper
okay thank you thank you
Matt PTAC yahoo so here you have a nice
chart that shows data that reinforces
your hypothesis it's the good chart that
the stuff that says look my model was
right do you have cases of companies
where breaches were reported but your
model predicted them as having a low
probability of breach would be the first
question and if you did have cases of
company breaches where your model did
not predict that they were likely to
have a breach does that indicate that
there are additional dimensions of data
that we perhaps should be factoring in
that aren't is obvious that maybe we
need to take out even more comprehensive
view of this that's an excellent
question so yes one of the the
high-profile I talked about high-profile
hits I didn't talk about the
high-profile mrs. right now one of the
most important high-profile mrs. was
Ashley Madison for example huge breach
and according to our models they were in
extremely low probability of reach they
were they were well below the fifty
percent mark and we don't quite
understand why that is I mean if you
look at their their the underlying data
from the models it also is extremely
clean yet they had a breach and we can't
really know for sure but the hypothesis
there is perhaps we are unable to detect
the insider threat where there is some
activity on the inside that is not a
true representation of cyber security
policy but it is purely human element
malicious lead gained so if you could
just find a way of measuring human
dishonesty ahead of time with this out
thank you hi this is Yannick in a strike
from comcast excellent talk I have a
question does it make sense to have
among predictors or maybe you already
didn't I just didn't catch it also in
some sense how um I don't know how
sensitive a target something is because
I'm thinking that all else being equal
one type of companies may be more of a
target as opposed you know like sort of
sighs I think maybe you did have size of
company but maybe some sort of measure
of prominence number of mentions you
know in the press or something like that
like some entities may be more prone to
being attacked than others absolutely so
you're right the the output of the model
is only going to be as accurate or as
useful as the input data that went into
training it so we're hoping that a lot
of the factors that you're talking about
things like target ability or target
preference is also going to show up in
the historical data that we're using to
build our labels so if circumspect are
is off of if a certain sector like the
financial sector or the energy sector is
more likely to be targeted our
expectation is that that will it show up
in the historical reports data breach
reports as well and that bias will then
drive the Train models as well good
this one I was just asking but you don't
have it explicitly as a feature you
think that just that financial companies
will be in some sense described by
whatever features you using rather than
having a categorical you know future
financial vs that's right so we did try
to include sector level information this
is something we're working on right now
but as it turns out mapping
organizations to the sectors is by is in
itself a challenging task and in a lot
of cases it has to be done manually by
scrubbing through the data so I hear you
if you know if a good data source please
let's talk hi Jay Galle infinera I was
going to ask questions very similar to
some of these about how you could be
confident that you had enough data
sources to cover the range of different
risk factors and things like being on
outdated software loads and stuff like
that you we could probably do a poll two
people in the room and come up with a
hundred other security risk factors that
you won't be able to get data on so I'm
I'm of the same mind that I think those
commenters were that this model is going
to be very incomplete for a very long
time precisely because people don't know
where the risks are and they don't
reveal what their own internal risk
profile is in a way that is obvious to
the outside world but I'm going to
follow up with a different question
which is as anybody from Wall Street ask
you for your data sets so they can short
companies that have the highest risk
scores I yes let's talk about that
offline and in terms of the expanding or
improving the actual data that we're
using to to model or to build these data
models we're continuing to expand the
range of activities that we collect
we've been since included a much broader
set of policy indicators for examples
things like whether you have a policy
for managing development web servers
people in a lot of organizations people
are have development systems which are
open to the public unless explicitly
lock down some organizations are much
more careful about it and those are the
sort of subtle hints that we're now
expanding into detecting so yes we are
expanding the scope of what we're
collecting