so next up we have three lightning talks
talk will be a Chris Moreau are
ki operations
Hey hi I'm Chris I work with Google this
isn't really google talk but there's
some Google stuff in it so great read
the fine print I'm not going to talk
about any legal crap who decide what to
sign I don't care about that right now
some point in time hopefully people will
see value in the RPG I system in we can
operate one as opposed to discussing all
the politics if you don't know what the
rpi system is the the quick and dirty is
it's basically a pki system to manage
authorization for access authorization
for use of number resources ASNs IP
addresses or net box whatever you like
to call it at the end of the day you
sign some stuff this is I should step
back there's two kind of prevailing
versions for this process there's talk
to your rir Aaron or ripe or whoever and
have them be you the CA you talk to them
and they publish stuff for you and they
manage all the publication for you
that's actually pretty easy so if you're
a small place so you don't really care a
lot about running this infrastructure
that's a great option for you if you're
larger like you're an AT&T or Google is
going to probably do it to you want to
have a little more control of your
destiny you'll run your own see a
service the rer will sign stuff down
toward you you'll publish stuff out you
have to maintain all this stuff been
right you have to be able to maintain
servers and not some other stuff that's
what this talk is about so at the end of
the day after you do all some signing
with certificates in this and that and
keys you're running an arcing server
it's really not magic so how do you run
an arcing server and you make it
available across more than just your
local enterprise network hopefully this
is what this is about there's a couple
other presentations that talk about RPG
I and a lot more detail if you don't
know what it is i would suggest you look
at those two links hopefully the PDF
shows up someplace and the links are
usable if not mail me and i'll send you
links or you could search on patch com
which is what I did so you need to run
arcing server you need to manage them
keys and stuff and keep those private if
coming to get your keys they can assign
resources if so they were used so you
probably don't want that so you want to
keep those relatively secure
and then you figure out which data you
want to publish to the world probably
you don't want to do this all in one
server out on the public internet that's
not the best idea maybe and maybe not
all of it is accessible to everybody in
the world just the stuff you actually
want to publish not your keys so in
looking at this for Google I said well I
can't do this on all of our production
stuff which would make it easy and not
my problem we have to do build it
somewhere else we can't really run an
arsenic service for some reason it's a
it's a web company so complicated so in
any case I decided to use our cloud
infrastructure to deploy a bunch of
stuff and at the end of the day I you
know followed the process that is
outlined in the one page install that
rpi not publishers that's Randy's not
site but it's Randy's work and we're not
currently not publishing public stuff
for publishing stuff through Randy's
things so we're not the greatest example
here but at the end of the day we just
have area and sign all my stuff in
follow the same process I'm doing here
so follow the if you're going to do this
you take one of the reference platforms
there's only really two available sorry
there's only one available if you're
gonna if you're going to be your own CI
and that's the art Poquette annette
reference platform you I chose to make
one server private and keep all of my
keys and whatnot on there I'm probably
going to do that for the long term as
well and then whatever it gets created
for my publication point I just rsync
out to the world up to my set of servers
that are available to everybody to talk
to I put together some puppet stuff
which is not completely done and not
published here because our open source
process is longer than I thought but
eventually it'll you'll see the
management framework that I put together
here it's puppet but we could build
ansible or something else if people are
interested in something that's not
puppet I just happen to learn puppet so
I got stuck the key point with all of
the publication stuff is if you're a
large organization and you change your
data on a regular basis there some fear
that as you change your manifest which
tells everybody what's in your
repository you change parts of the
repository that as people come through
and gather you don't really know when
the
going to do this they may get half the
data part the data missing things I
think what I realized is if I just
publish a brand new copy of all the data
in a new place in point our sink at the
new place every time I finish publishing
everyone always gets the current when
they start form of data and I don't
change it underneath them so the the
management framework does that for you I
think that's it for that slide there's
any questions people should speak up but
so after you get all this stuff
published then what would I do with it
right I would if I was an ISP I would be
filtering my customers because I wasn't
my last job if you're not like really
seriously people it's not hard we should
do this but presuming that you you know
you find it complicated for some reason
you can take the data out of the irr
there's lots of documentation how to do
that there's two presentations about I
are our tools and another one somebody
can jump on them i can tell me who it
was earlier this week which is a good
presentation you can use those things
you can look at the data and say wow
this is really cruddy data missed and
write both kind of agree that it's not
the best in the world but with the rpi
data if the if the customer of yours
signs there prefixes or you sign
prefixes for them you could at least
take that data and bounce it against the
irr data and say okay well instead of 10
prefixes con Edison is no longer a
customer of NTT so will you know not let
them send that route to us so some
examples on how to do that you can use
the who is that are poquette at net
service to kind of ask it for for Rohit
data so you could get the RR data and
ask rpi dotnet for the right thing you
could build and who is a version of that
I'm going to probably bug Randy about
how to get that code up and running
somewhere else and put it into the same
management package and at the very least
you could stand up a server or sorry a
router off path you can do it with
quagga bird you do with a real router
junipers and Cisco's both support the
validation code you can take all the
road in EU gather from the rest of the
world you can shovel it into this box
you can look at the prefixes that you
see mark them good bad or whatever and
then take some metrics on what the world
looks like for you and then if you have
customer
or your own data that's a problem you
can go fix that hopefully and know
what's going to happen if you have to
end up using the data later in the
production Network sorry that was that
it was really quick because any
questions three two one great okay
thanks a lot Chris next up we have jose
santos he'll be doing a talk on training
the next generation of network engineers
or plumbers
thank you
sorry I'm going to no need to get my
glasses um the message on I'm bringing
today salut be less traditional I'm
going to talk about protocols but rather
about the people who is very likely to
replace you in the near future my
perspective is from the academic
environment and trying to address the
challenges of the industry as they show
up today and that's it going to show up
over the next few years if I ask some of
you what's the definition of the perfect
never engineers I mean having a
never-ending list you know not only you
meet you know protocols you need to know
the limitations of protocols we need to
be able to touch equipment but also be
able to automate some of the processes
be able to develop code custom I mean
the list is endless and but keeps going
out I see a lot of white hair or no hair
on this room well guess what we are
aging pretty fast and we have to replace
talent as quickly as we can so not only
that you have to be an engineer but also
you have to be able to communicate
socialize be professional I'll be honest
with you that person doesn't exist today
they're very few very handful of them so
if we were to even just expand any one
of these dimensions well you know basic
networking tool kids we have like 20
different protocols but also
intersection between these protocols you
know Bishop is no longer the purest
protocol now it's integrative mpls with
layer two tunneling layer 3 tunneling
and so on so how can we offer this set
of knowledge or these knowledge base
into our students today I think based on
my personal experience and perhaps some
share experience with some of the
members I discussing the past education
is not the only dimension education is
not the only way we can solve the demand
of our industry it's a combinational
skills but also combination of training
and that training has to be offering
very particular environments experience
over time making mistakes is a necessity
of our industry to be able to correct
them and try to prevent them in the
future but also the work environment has
to be
were changing or continuous training
environment so you know you foster the
growth of the person over time our
challenge is well is now going in a
master's program a two-year degree plan
that can be achievable with the
prevailing random professional from any
background we try to build him into a
basics obsessed subset of industries
industry standards so far some of the
formulas have been working for us is is
we have students who have a CS of your
science underground background they are
obviously more open to coding
familiarize with the ability to create
their own environments and they usually
live over into the Sen tracks and making
their own rules but they need to
understand networking in order to do
that if there are doubly graduates they
are more how r en tête and those are
the type of students are actually more
maturing quickly in the Internet of
Things types of architecture you know
trying to make their own components and
link them to the network but also we
have a generation of professionals who
are coming back after 30 years of
commitment into one particular leg of
the industry and they have to reinvent
ourselves so in that case we see a lot
of them being more comfortable in CLI
configuration management environments
two years is not enough to fulfill the
needs of the previews dimension the
previous slides so we took a look into
the five-year program now the challenges
that we face on five-year programs is we
need to convince younger generations to
commit to networking early enough the
man of knowledge we have to accumulate
again is linear there's no shortcut to
get that done but along those tracks
we're losing a lot of people a lot a lot
we lose a lot of interest over as they
pass through their degree plan because
their other short-term high reward
markets you know everybody wants to move
to the ladies up and make a quick buck
and retire do something fun with it so
how can you help I see at least 200 300
people here today they have a unique
Pat we are never engineers by evolution
mostly not by design so it will be great
if any one of you or some of you
remember if all of you could share your
personal experience tell me what sort of
building blocks you have to go in order
to reach the point that you are today in
your career why are the skill says you
have to combine to become the expert of
today you know what's the best way to
combine those what's the right time to
learn each one of them now you have to
be fair we're talking about two years I
mean you have to be human you have to
balance life you might be a working
professional who's taking classes
afterwards if you go for the five-year
solution a row or map you have to be
fair for the junk stirs they're in
college they're having fun they're not
going to be doing these 24 7 so any one
of your personal easter is at you know
that they will provide us with some of
the common trends okay I to programming
at this age and that gave me the
visibility to understand the logic
necessary to make changes in an
allocated fashion you know to solve
network consolidation blah blah blah I
mean if you can share that experience
with us that will be great other ways
you can help obviously nanog I started a
college admission program and I see I
mean we were able to bring a lot more
students this particular year and
assumed is going to be a constant over
subsequent events I think the limitation
of that model is that only works with
member engineers we can only invite
people who is a very committed to this
industry and necessarily people who are
don't if still don't have a clue if they
want to take this career as their future
I think we need to influence academia an
earlier time the new generation of not
only engineers but computer science and
anything that is going to be IT related
needs to understand the complexity of
networking I have discussions with all
the apartments in everybody's films the
networking is just as services
somebody's going to provide for them
we've been taking for granted we're not
one particular experiment our generation
is going to do is trying to introduce
concept of networking at the base as a
core class you know as low as
mathematics because we want to we want
to place a seat for any particular
graduating track that there's a lot of
challenges in order to do a snapchat
from 14 to another I mean issue the
complexity of the infrastructure the
lies behind is not something that is
done automatically and that actually
requires a great level of responsibility
and technical expertise other ways you
can help both grad and undergrad
programs in not necessarily in our
institution but this is going to be
common in all the institutions or your
Emma matters some of them involve a to a
junior project either at the graph
undergrad level of the grad level where
students actually have to write a
technical paper make an experiment and
believe me our institution in more than
one we are right now open to any ideas
any problems that you want to solve I
need for guys to work together on this
particular coding problem we are trying
to attract as many ideas and problems
for students to work on and all it takes
is perhaps a couple hours amount of
supervision for a period of eight months
and you can potentially have a technical
report where the students actually were
able to work together model solid
solutions and build a proposal for your
department so take advantage of that is
no cause for your institution it's not
cause for you and you can always explore
you know some special topics for which
you don't have the manpower or perhaps
the time to address and let the students
do that work for you again we put that
on the table also we would like some of
you to take advantage of your roaming
capabilities you're going to technical
visits to some customer bases try to
visit a school try to tell them how
exciting is your career your field how
perhaps your company's envisioning the
future
and how can they invest in it education
the selection of courses so they can
actually address some of the industry
demands as they follow their educational
process internships obviously is
valuable some of the companies hire
after students graduate but it's too
late to an influencer education you have
to do a lot of the work in-house and
have them internal training for a year
year and a half before they become
productive some companies are actually
being patient enough or investing early
enough that during the first year they
just show them how to integrate into the
workplace but also they commit to them
by providing a I'll hire you next year
for the next internship and perhaps you
should build on data center
architectures to have you should be able
to amend your scripting skills and they
actually get a much better results by
following the particular two-step
internship program please send me or set
us as much feedback as you can I mean it
will take probably five to ten minutes
of your time to just give us up the
desired level of skills that you want
from the next generation of never
engineers but also to share your
perspective about what are the actual
key components that the next generation
of never engineers should have on their
belt so I think that's ten minutes on
the spot thank you are there any
questions over here yes I might suggest
that the perfect network engineer this
Louie Louie connects this we Google
hardware next week the perfect network
engineer can tell the difference between
cloud and not cloud
fair enough um have you seen any of
these internship programs having
guidance on how to interview how to
write a resume because I wouldn't want
any of these valuable skills to get lost
because they can't find a good job at a
good company that can make a difference
we do have a parenting role in our
department we have to take them up to
speed professionally be able to present
their ideas concisely we do help them
with resume presentations but remember a
lot of hours we've not did not get that
help you know we are engineers we're
isolated we just care about the computer
and we don't socialize I think this I
mean it's something has to be built on
top we do have a particular effort will
do that particular effort on the side we
have a different department different
lady actually trying to build the
professional skills needed to address it
marketplace but yes that's part of the
soft skills that also are desirable by
the market and it boils down to
communication writing skills and be able
to integrate in a work environment where
you know collaboration sometimes is more
important than the technical skill that
you have wonderful thank you thank you
thanks a lot we could have fit in maybe
one quick question there sorry Panther
to others so we'll just take one you
know just a minor common matt peterson
cumulus networks you might want to look
into the University of New Hampshire
they have a program called
interoperability lab iol and my
organization has been there a number of
times and they actually get high school
students involved fairly early on I
think that's a very successful way to
get people influence quickly early in
their career another point to make also
about internships is that we actually
have college students work in very
critical parts of the product so I think
you need to make the internships
attractive not just you know you're
getting busy work with very attractive
work so thank you very much for its
presentation thank you thank you very
much all right thanks a lot it's very
quick very quick and very important
Caleb Ryan Akamai Technologies I'd like
to know if you have any special focus on
women and minorities in engineering
future our program is about rock right
now about forty percent female and
and obviously the rest male and there
are actually organizations who've
incentivize our recruitment or
recruitment not only for students with
female not background i'm sorry i love
the term there in case of amazon for
example they're looking for a hundred
fifty female network engineers and we
try to build them as far as far as we
can as far as we can but believe me i
think that working is also very neutral
environment for both genders in this
event so i'll meet with unison thank you
very much thank you very much our final
talk will be by unread sri on the not
resolver
oh hello everyone my name is Jerry and I
work for that seasoning the desert
registry and i would like to present the
well the warrior have been doing in the
last year we are building a new dns
resolver from from the scratch and well
what is its open source well obviously
its dealers resolver you can get the
sources at do URL there it comes with
the extensive documentation so well for
the start and it's not only a dns
resolver it's a platform for building
records dns services because it's it's
very module as i'll show you it also
comes with dns a politician with trust
anchor management and negative trust
anchors which is important if somebody
shows themselves in the foot with not
resigning their zones so some
technically details it's written in c
and legit so it's it's very fast and
it's scriptable and it has dynamic
configuration in lua so you can write
programs in the configuration which is
just very cool and i would show you but
we don't have enough time for that it is
very simple core just free modules
iterator cash validator but it's
extensible the modules in ceylon go and
we even ship some of them or use like
well policies views response policy
zones and more all i will talk about
them we also support ipv6 from the start
with well some tweaks to to make the
eyeballs happy and it well from Declan
perspective it doesn't do treading but
it scales by self reputation you just
fire up another instance on the same
port and it works um so who is it for
well visit for everybody for large
recursive DNS farms it's very scalable
it's very flexible because you can write
your own strips into that well we have
statistic metrics and well you can expel
are those into graphite involved with
some fancy new web stuff we have
negative trances trust anchors and it's
also cluster ever you can have a etcd
module for replicated configuration
across across the cluster it's also well
well sweetie for small recursos in
private networks it does qname
minimization which is the new stuff in
the DNS privacy well again it's the DNS
SEC and key management automatically it
has slow memory consumption you can even
Bob downscale the cash and it's also
good for your personal resolver in your
laptop in fact I am running it in for
Paul several weeks now and well we
aren't some but bugs out and but it
works very well and it's very simple you
just well give it a rich key and the
interface is to listen to and that's it
the cash is persistent across three
starts and an reboot and we also plan
for the future well do some stuff to
circumvent the horrible well hotel wifis
like the pheromone days which intercepts
all dns queries to all addresses this
this is the example of the graphite
module so it could draw all fancy graphs
if you are into that so what's the
current status of the project we are
currently entering a better phase of the
project so it's it's ready for the
external testing but as i said i'm
already running it on my laptop for
several weeks and without any any
problems and so give it a try the
sources are available we also have a
docker scraped it that can install it
for you we have linux packages currently
only for even two but we will extend
that shortly and for a strange stuff
well people can do in dms em and we
would like to hear from you about well
any failure
sore or strange behavior or even success
story so so please give it a try and
well uh that's not only thing we the
cool thing with you in season eight we
also have tourists omnia which is open
hardware with the designs available open
source home router well check it out we
have no dns alterative part of the dns
server and you probably might know birds
the routine demon this also comes from
our stable so to say ok so i was faster
than i expected so we have time for
questions if you are all interested in
asking something or throwing eggs or
tomatoes I dogma Camarena's do you have
a heuristics or built into the queue
name minimization to deal with
authoritative so yeah basically well
it's something we call best effort you
know minimization and it stops the zone
cuts too well exactly sir commandos
strange stuff that CD ends for
procedural resolvers so so it's not the
strict Hyun a minimization but it's
tries to well answer you so too it is
much whatever techniques you use well
documented somewhere either in the code
or um already after well I think right
now it's in the code basically but well
should be an email and we can talk about
it more about in the email how is on ok
hi Andre join muscles from verisign my
question was also about became kini
Amenas minimization I was just going to
ask if it's enabled by default or it has
to be it's it's own by default okay well
if I I think you can't turn it off okay
great thanks all right i'm jacques with
dodgy so for large-scale
recursive farms do you sell like
software support maintenance and all
that all night or planning to the Jack
could you said it again so for
large-scale recursive farms are you
planning to sell software maintenance to
provide to whilst the gab we build
everything open source and and we are
trying to get those projects of
sustainable so so we will well once it's
stabilized then we will offer a support
contracts for days as well thank you
very much thank you so it is finally
time for lunch which is on your own
today and we will resume at two thirty
we have our peering track in this room
and there's also going to be a talk on
strategies for packet buffering inside
of routers and I believe that's in the
McKenzie room don't forget your surveys
and thank you very much