you
good morning good morning how's
everybody I was going to do bunge or but
that's about as much French as I have so
so this is my second nanog in a row yeah
and and before that it was twenty years
so I'm going to continue to try to space
it out a little but thanks to the
leadership team for inviting me to give
the keynote I see lots of old friends
everybody looks great maybe a little bit
older but see mr. Norton over here and a
few others and so thanks for having me
it's grown a little bit since I remember
I was saying to to Randy Bush that I
think the last one I went to there were
35 people so it's it's a touch larger
than the last time I remember so with
that I'm going to give you a little bit
of my perspective and and this is sort
of the the internet at least my path in
the internet and so left to right I
started out working at a small little
lab in Frederick Maryland the National
cancerous to supercomputer center and my
good friend of 27 years Kathy Aronson
pointed out back when I had hair so that
was very nice I then moved upstream to
our internet provider Soren edge Serena
it was one of the seven regionals and
assessment regionals in the mid-90s and
and was there for a few years moved up
to MC i started the nci's internet
business with a handful of folks and
then moved on to level three where again
kathy pointed out i became a mucky muck
and I think loosely translated that
means on management so that's me and
I'll give you a little bit as i was as i
was thinking about gosh what am I going
to talk to a room of a thousand people
of which 999 are smarter than me it's
kind of daunting you know I'm in
management I don't I don't do a whole
lot of technical thing
is anymore but I was trying to think
about okay what are the challenges that
that I've seen over the last 20 or so
years and and I think that you can sum
up the challenges at least as I've seen
them into two buckets technical
challenges the ones that we see around
scale and cost and growth and all of the
things that we talked about with respect
to the internet and then the second
bucket which are really incentive
challenges and these these are the hard
ones you know incentive challenges you
can go and look in economics there's the
this notion of willing buyer willing
seller everybody heard of that well
that's that's actually an example of
when incentives align and it's been the
case at least for the last many decades
and around the internet that it's not
always that are incentives align and
whether that's because of we're just
people we have business interests that
are different there are political
environments that are different you name
it it's hard to make the technical ones
I'd actually argue are kind of easy the
incentive ones are kind of hard and I'll
talk a little bit more about that so I I
was I was not sure if I should go
through history but I'm going to try to
go through a little bit of history
because I think it's important I how
many newcomers 200 and yeah how many
raise your hand yeah so I mean a quarter
of the room is newcomers for old for the
old folks in the room this will be
boring you can go to sleep and wake up
later on but I was pointing to pointed
in Norton for that we well i'm going to
walk a little bit through a little
history and start out with in in 86 I
was in intern at the time at that little
lab and the NSFNET melted down for those
that remember it actually really did
melt down it was unusable during the day
and and this really smart guy over here
on the right Dan Jacobson a few other
folks came up with a bunch of different
techniques around TCP to fix it
tcp Tahoe TCP Reno is there a TCP uma
did I read that right is that on the
agenda I mean they're like 15 different
variants now all to really focus fix
what was a fairly decent technical
challenge on the internet at the time if
you really go back and look what's in
place today is largely what was built
many many years ago a little bit more
history bgp in the early days the MILNET
NSFNET all used the exterior gateway
protocol for those that remember do you
remember there were a few little
problems like multi-homing and loop
prevention and scale three guys i think
three guys to at least two of them went
off for a lunch at the IETF in 1989 and
came up with the spec for bgp that the
famous three napkin lunch whoo Wow
alright aye aye win the award for the
best speech it's popping breakers and
then come on are we good
evidently the right side of the room is
or the left side of the rooms having it
alright I'm gonna keep going is that
okay alright so so three guys go off yah
cough record director Tony leaker Chloe
and come up with BGP and and you know
what there's a lot of cool stuff that
happened back then all the ibgp cider
work that was done route reflection all
largely in place today a technical
problem that challenged us kind of
something that was fixed and fixed for
the long term for those that that
remember we we had a it's kind of funny
i'm going to talk about this a little
bit routers were a big problem way back
when we worried about well how many
packets could just switch switch route
through the processor in and the slow
path and the fast happened and folks
like Dennis Ferguson a few others went
off and did a lot of really cool work
around Patricia trees and trinary trees
and how to how to do fast lookup and
then the super high capacity OC 48 links
came around and we had to use things
like tkm to be able to even forward in a
box all a technical challenge great work
done but largely solved once it was
sacked so this part of my job I remember
with great kind of trepidation I
remember we were off building network
back at MCI and we literally had no idea
how we were going to continue to scale
our network for months from that point
in time no idea we did all kinds of
crazy things we put frame relay switches
in front of routers to aggregate ports
together we built ATM substrates to be
able to offer greater capacity because
couldn't buy a router that would
actually plug into an OC 12 all kinds of
crazy stuff at the time just to continue
to scale this by the way was was the
point in which many of us were breaking
internet religion by using things like
ATM and frame relay that was thought to
be you know
bad I guess at the time is the best word
I can think of it but when you look at
what we built today around mpls and mpls
te we largely due to all the same things
it's just the different technology so
many problems many technical problems
existed congestion route propagation all
those things and they were largely fixed
but but we struggled with some and and
the the first is so I've had to do a
little bit of research here few folks
dave cooper help me help me do some
research here around but when did when
did all this ipv6 start 1993 a quarter
of the Internet's of the ipv4 address
space was actually used at that time so
it wasn't a lack of foresight bradner
and mankan and all those folks they did
they did great stuff I I personally was
a big fan of tuba at the time TCP and
UDP over big addresses for those of the
number that one didn't win v6 did so
what happened well the fact is there
wasn't any real incentive and and I love
the church I guess Tony hain made this
chart up here on the right it's from
Nana 27 2002 and and the there's another
one going the chart is awesome it talks
about early adoption application porting
ISP adoption all these things and the
only thing that's right on that chart
and no offense to Tony is the plus sign
that's the only thing that we've gotten
right is that it's taken a really long
time and why is that well there's no
real incentive there wasn't a real
incentive to adopt ipv6 and there was a
lot of great work done NAT for instance
to prolong the lights lifespan and so I
would argue that that the migration the
v6 is just because it lacks an intent
security I used to work for vent surf at
MCI and he and I used to get in this
great debate about the most awesome
thing about the Internet and the most
horrible thing is that everything's
addressable and when you really get down
to some of the biggest security flaws
that there are in the system it's
because of in band signaling and the
fact that everything is addressable and
we saw lots and lots of vulnerabilities
at the time TTP Smurf attacks man the
metal all that stuff how many people
have heard of 2600 so I'd say so for
those who can't see about half half of
the people in the room so for the other
half that don't know 2600 is the
frequency that a captain crunch whistle
will blow and it just so turns out that
in the early 70s the in-band signaling
for an eighteen eighty long lines voice
which was a capable of being taken over
by that tone 2600 and there was the sing
called phone phreaking where people
would essentially take over the trunk
line and be able to make long-distance
phone calls over the phone network by
grabbing the signaling and it really is
one of the first in my opinion one of
the first examples of hacking and and
it's around the fact that in ban
signaling can be can be a vulnerability
for those that don't remember Robert
Morris very few so Robert Morris was the
author i think is he a cornell student
and the author of really the first
internet bud or internet worm or
whatever you want to say or internet
hack and it was essentially a piece of
software that he had written and it
would go and install itself across all
UNIX systems and basically melted the
internet i actually was at lice my
intern job at the time and got to see
this firsthand and got to be interviewed
the FBI and all kinds of stuff for for
for all that so that that was a pretty
interesting time now those
vulnerabilities some of them still exist
but but when I look at it I say all
right what's the incentive whose job is
it to fix security the technology has a
bit of an inherent flaw but is it the
consumer or the enterprise or providers
to fix security interconnection this is
a bit of it I I'm going to try it in
that by the way all of these are my own
opinions not those of my company so I
need to make sure I say that first
interconnection has and will be a long
problem for the internet as well as many
other industries you can go you can go
back to the railroads and there is the
interconnection fights between the
railroads if you go back in your
telephone history there's something
called the kingsbury commitment and
kingsbury was a judge and at the time
AT&T had to make a commitment to
interconnect to all of the phone
providers in the in the early 1900s we
we fixed all the inter connection
technology problems we came up things
like meds and and longest exits sure it
is things at all of those things route
servers route reflectors all those
things were out registries but at times
we ran into incentive problems and and I
was I was thinking a guy named Scott
huddle and I wrote a paper in the 90s
around content and whose job was it to
carry content and the example in the
paper was war and peace I think about
that we're talking about a book a big
voluminous book rather than today a 4k
movie or a you HD movie so the the
dynamic dynamic has changed a little bit
but the the incentive problem is still
there
so what do we worry about today we worry
about really cool things like space and
power and if you look at the top those
are copper cables on the left if you go
into one of our gateways you see that
are one of our biggest physical problems
today is the weight of the actual cables
that sit up in the trays above the racks
because equipment is getting so dense
the watts per per gig that the just
total power square foot square power per
square foot is increasing so my but
actually getting the power to the
equipment is tough so there's all kinds
of technology like 380 volt technology
looks really promising a little bit of a
health and safety issue but we'll
probably over overcome that but we're
really this is something we worry a lot
today about so fiber I don't know as
anybody ever come to nanigen talked
about fiber okay all right I thought I
mean I was hoping I was going to be one
of the first so so fiber it's a really
integral part of all of what we do right
and and in the 90s actually in the 80s
when fiber technology was first being
deployed it was direct buried into the
ground probably the greatest technology
advancement in the 90s was putting
plastic pipes in the ground so you could
actually pull more fiber not too
revolutionary but you'd be surprised how
much fiber is actually in the ground
that's not in conduit if you looked at
fiber in the in the early 90s it was
drawn from this thing called a preform
if you if you actually had that fiber he
had a little problem because the way it
was drawing it wasn't perfectly round
and it had all kinds of impairments
because of that post 94 there's lots of
new fiber and and technology like non
zero dispersion shifted cyber came into
play and when we were
start in our company we thought well
geez we've seen one generation one new
generation of fiber already in 10 years
what happens if there are more and more
fibers hence the or more more fiber
technology hence the plastic pipes so
here's what's happened in the last 15
years for from 2002 2015
state-of-the-art in two thousand was a
fiber called leaf it basically was a
large effective area fiber is better
than SMF because all sports all sorts of
things like the dispersion compensation
and what's happened is that electronics
have caught up and now we use things
like special modulation and special
detection to be able to to get rid of
the impairments in fiber what we've
really done though what we've seen is
that fiber loss has improved
dramatically the the actual size of
fiber has improved and if you look over
there on the right it's kind of small
but it 98 are our fiber was about point
25 DB per kilometer today it's about
point 17 which is about a forty percent
improvement in Los so when we use new
fiber today we will use this type of
fiber bigger core all that means is that
things like 100 Gig things like 200 gig
400 gig when you actually go in and and
and want to use that technology you're
going to need this type of fiber oops
sorry a 100 gig hey so you see the
picture that that's storing a
maintenance by the way that's not how it
really looks every day in case you're
one of our customers
I promise but we got great at ecmp and
lag and today we have you know hundred
ten gig links between cities in our in
our IT backbone it's gotten pretty
difficult and things like a hundred gig
you know we we got really lucky in this
last step in technology in telecom it
used to be you know OC 3 20 c 12 OCT 12
20 c48 OC forty eight to 10 gig all kind
of 4x jumps in in in technology and
capacity today we're experienced a 10x
jump which is awesome so when you look
at that fiber tray there that that's the
result of the hundreds of 10 gig links
hopefully in a reduction by 10 and we
think that 200 and 400 gig is pretty
much on the horizon still got some
issues around reach but but we're pretty
excited about this and so is our fiber 3
although our fiber trade vendors
probably not very happy about it so we
don't worry a lot about this anymore I
what as I mentioned we spent a lot of
time worrying about how do we grow our
network just four months from now 20
years ago today we have tons of tricks
3-stage cost matrix it's something that
we as well as many other folks have
built all because we need more fan out
and so these types of architectures are
ones that let you have more fan outs
pine leaf is another another one a
little bit other arguments for that but
frankly between the two we don't worry a
lot about how to scale the
infrastructure from this perspective
from an actual box perspective here's
what I do worry about and this is it's
hard to see on the on the left hand side
of the chart here but if you just follow
the color so blue is the route is router
capacity
and orange is transporter WDM capacity
and in 98 routers generally speaking
gross generalization were much much less
dense than WDM here so play that forward
that that's that's an 8x difference by
the way play that forward through the
years and in about two thousand thirteen
or so suddenly routers are becoming much
more dense than W DM gear and today this
is there are many and for the w Kiba and
vendors that are here in this room
they're going to tackle me when I leave
just relax I'm sure somebody's got some
guide box that's coming that is much
bigger than a terabit but generally
speaking we know the market today
routers are much much more dense than W
vm here so think now we don't worry a
lot about it we have a ton of fiber but
the industry is going to have to worry
about it because we're going to be able
to buy these incredibly dense routers
and yet we're still going to have to
slap and slap them together with much
much less dense WDM gear which i think
will become a problem for us control an
automation hey I wouldn't be doing my
job as management if I didn't have at
least one or two buzzwords sdn nfe yeah
I said it actually I don't care a lot
about sdn I care a lot about automation
of control getting less and less human
touch to our network you know we have
hundreds and hundreds of thousands of
devices and managing them is difficult
and so the more and more automation that
we can get will help us be be better we
do think that nfe has some interesting
things but frankly we're still a little
bit questioning some of the economics
interconnection so today what do we
worry about today about interconnexion
hey we've got the awesome US open
Internet order I know everyone in the
rooms a big fan what do you think
no okay well I would I give you my
opinion I think we needed some help and
I don't love I'll always love this kind
of help but I think we needed some help
so we got some help we'll see how that
plays out there is another internet
order right now being reviewed in the
EoE you will see what happens the
dynamics appearing are definitely
changing there's there's no question and
there's more and more press about it I
was talking to someone last night
talking about that that you know it's
hit mainstream when John Oliver can do
eight an awesome explanation of of the
issue around around net neutrality we
have lots of ways to measure ratios bit
miles longest eggs at all there are a
bunch of ways for us to deal with inter
connection but but frankly I'd say that
even today interconnection still suffers
maybe not as much in the US but
certainly around the world and again
back to incentives what are the
incentives for us to fix interconnection
in the long run I'm security you know
it's gone from the exuberant geek to
actually business and you know organized
crime nation-states you guys have all
read about this you can you can actually
buy a botnet a botnet using your
bitcoins or your Visa account whichever
you'd like and you can go attack whoever
you want and it's very automated it's
really nice it turns out that it's
gotten kind of mainstream and if you
take a step back and think what happens
when this sort of Internet of Things 50
billion hundred billion devices is
actually connected and that becomes the
footprint in which we need to worry
about security it's a fairly big problem
i think headed for us again though whose
job is it
sit what's the incentive v4 we all know
Aaron's out of addresses there's a
growing secondary market for ipv4 we'll
see what happens there adoption is
beginning to happen you know I i would
say hats off to to the cable folks and
and and mobile operators I think they've
done a really fabulous job with adoption
of v6 so we're starting to see it
traffic has grown a hundred percent for
us and in the last year still a barrier
still frankly I questioned what the
incentive really is I mean Frank went
when we run out of the dresses that'll
be a when you really can't get any
dresses that will be the ultimate
incentive but we still will struggle a
little bit but I do think we're making
good progress facebook said that fifty
percent of all mobile devices are
delivered over ipv6 now so our industry
continues to solve the technology
challenges and as a technology guy I I
always love it when I hear we're about
ready to hit the laws of physics or
we're going to we're going to get to
Shannon's limit or there are lots of
other engineering technical things that
people will say that we're just about
ready to run out and and the great thing
about about technology is we almost
always figure out a way and and if you
look at optics or routing or pick pick
your technology i would argued that we
almost always find a way and i'd never
bet against it but what i worry about
for the future it is and and this is so
embarrassing to say the most obvious
statement in the world is that
everything can be carried over IP every
single piece every single kind of
communications can be carried over IP
you might say well yeah no kidding just
17 years ago i sat in a conference room
arguing with
folks that were we were trying to give
get to give us money that we could carry
phone calls over IP today we're
delivering Netflix is delivering 4k over
over the Internet I would challenge you
to name one thing that we actually can't
carry over IP the issue well I left
myself one out there's no time down here
so I'm not picking a date I'm not coming
up with another chart that has pluses on
it and I'm not saying whether it's
public or private because i'm not sure i
think it could all be public the
question is whether we can fix all the
incentive challenges security
interconnection adoption with that thank
you very much
am I supposed to take questions I am
supposed to take questions or comments 0
david has questions and questions on
Jack's experiences vision his thoughts
for the future I think maybe once come
in more than one okay from the back leg
sandy Murphy Parsons I have particular
security focus and the work that I do so
I was struck by your list I agree with
all of them you got down to the bottom
and said but this is a hard problem
whose job is it to fix it help where do
you see the engineering communities role
in establishing standards when the
incentives that you have rightly noted
are not there how do the people who see
an engineering solution get wheels under
it under the financial and legal and
political and social problems yeah it's
a great question and I'm not sure I know
the answer other than I'd say it it'll
probably just take a few more home depot
target Sony's to make every board every
public board of every public company
have to deal with this what we've done
from our company's perspective is we
actually have a committee on our board
of directors that focuses and on
security and where we invest and how
we're protecting ourselves and the
privacy and services that were that
we're selling as well as you know our
compliance so I think the first answer
is awareness and if you're in a company
I'd encourage you that that awareness is
a huge gap and companies really struggle
with it so going for broke here you
mentioned prefix hijacking
and a s origin authenticity and I'm
Sandra Murphy the co-chair of the site
or working group in the IETF so I would
love to discuss with you the problem of
security in that realm and your
committees interest and awareness and
position excellent thank you there's
someone at the left hi my name is
jacques letoure I'm the CTO for da ta
and like you know CTO you need to build
a vision of the future and where we want
to be and all that and one thing that's
driving me nuts is ipv4 it's done right
we need to set a date collectively when
we shut it off I can't go on forever we
need to go to v6 and if we want to wave
it wait for it to die naturally it will
never die naturally naturally so we have
to pick a date and make it happen so
what's your thought on that I know it's
been people here want to keep by TV for
forever I don't know why but we need to
move on I mean I don't know if I
completely agree i think that that will
have will have both for izle at least as
long as I'm breathing so I think that
it's it's really hard to say that there
will be a flag day in which we turn off
the v4 address space but I do think that
that scarcity is going to become the
biggest issue will become I don't know
if I think that there's ever going to be
a day where where I believe that we shut
off before personally all right thank
you dr. Sandra Mike Dave temkin Netflix
so if you look back to when you started
you really could look at the u.s. is the
quote unquote center of the internet
right and back through all the
permutations and iterations that we've
had now we're in a world where we have
grown in globalization you've got
submarine cables that are being built
the express purpose of bypassing the US
and so how do you think that that
impacts the level 3 business and the
Internet as a whole as we get taken out
of more or less the hub if you will of
the internet and it truly becomes a
global network with China and India
actively participating yeah I mean and
this is this is frankly exactly why we
have our committee on our board of
directors and and you might say well how
the hell is that connected that the
problem is that you can't act as a US
company we operate in 100 countries
around the world and we have to we have
to abide by local law and that means
everything from information collection
22 you know all the subpoena rights and
takedown rights and all those things we
have to operate in each country as if
you know that's where we got our license
and so it's really had to change our
thinking as a management team as to how
we operate and become much much us
centric and and more more global you
know it's it's tough right because I
think that things like the inter
connection rules we have some promise
that that are some probability that that
the interconnection rules in the u.s.
might look similar to what they look to
the EU I think it probably stops there
and there are so many different
incentive challenges back to that in in
different parts of the world where
governments are protecting their PT
tease or there are different ownership
rights where I mean we don't own our own
network in in China for exactly this
reason because you know we we struggle
with ownership and putting money in the
ground and not not being able to get it
back out so we we really struggle with
some parts of the world right now but
it's a great question please by there i
call klasky comcast back to the ipv4
ipv6
discussion over over the years of the
transition ipv6 we've seen the proposals
come up if you crawl back into classful
IP v4 definition for the class range of
addresses do you ever see that opening
up or if any of the proposals get any
traction on that as you know another
patch work around on ipv4 I I don't know
I think that we're reaching the point
where where the the law of large numbers
takes over for any sort of tweak we can
do the class the address space and all
that I think that that's that's on the
margin if there really are 50 billion
100 billion connected devices eventually
that all need to be reachable I don't
think any of those proposals I mean
they're they're fine work around or find
things to add on some life but but I
think if you really believe that there
are that many devices coming and I
personally do i think it's it's horses
out of the barn then I think all those
are kind of at the margin thanks Jeff
Houston a painting you and I have both
been around this industry for out the
last 30-odd years when both of us
started the problem was the telcos and
the answer realistically was this
end-to-end architecture that pushed
control functionality and value out of
the network across into the end systems
yet you're working for a carriage
company and somehow the telcos refused
to die they continue to try and pack
complexity and what they think is value
into the network despite the end systems
and sometimes it looks like carriages
the problem still and we still haven't
quite got over it what do you think
about your future in your carriage
business are you willing to embrace
commoditization or do you still think
there's a dollar to be squeezed out of
moving bids well I hope there is for at
least ten more years 10 years I
you know and so I struggle with a little
bit of that as you probably know because
I do think at least from our perspective
we aren't a carriage company and we
didn't start with a hundred years and a
government grant of monopoly so you know
we started the old-fashioned way a
dollar at a time and and with the focus
around building something that had long
long long optionality and so from the
plastic pipes in the ground to the fiber
to to looking at technology in a very
different way I mean we we thought I
mean we were called crazy and I know
it's it's a it seems silly to say now
but we build a network and a company
completely optimized around internet
technology I mean today everybody to go
no crap yeah i mean that's that's what
you would do but back then that was
unheard of so i think at least from my
perspective we we've approached it very
differently it you're going to get me on
a bit of a rant around the cloud right
because there are like raindrops in the
crowd right there's stuff inside the
cloud and and we're the stuff and many
of us in the room are the stuff inside
the cloud so I I think that carriage is
incredibly important to get from the end
systems and and you could argue whether
the value exchange has been exactly I'm
a free market guy so the value exchange
is what the market will bear but I very
much believe that carriage is important
and will continue to be important thank
you I Paul's ignoring from LinkedIn you
mentioned security and usually in the
context of cyber attacks how about the
fire but that's been getting cut in the
u.s. in 2015 yeah I mean obviously it
for those who have been reading the
paper we as well as many others have
suffered a little bit on the vandalism
side especially in Northern California
its public there are parts that we can't
talk about but you know I think think
part of the ability of the of the
of the system is the fact that we can't
have the armed guards running around
186,000 miles of fiber and so there
there is there is some natural
vulnerability to physical infrastructure
you know we work hard at trying to
protect it eventually you can't if there
are bad people that you can't you can't
do a lot about that but I think that
it's a testament to the survivability of
the technology and and the fact that
we've you know suffered as you mentioned
some of those things we still you know
service has has if you look at the total
system has largely been resilient and so
it's a concern it's a concern there's no
question and frankly there are harder
parts to operate go down Latin America
and and not not because of vandalism but
because of just construction and
economic development it's a tough place
to operate so so we see that a lot a
more last questions okay listen thank
you very much and have a great week