all right next up we have a raffle
tee hee
optimal routing verse red
flector vnf reconcile the fire with
water good morning everybody it's nice
to be here it's my turn a knock and feel
at home yeah still good morning
especially for those from west coast
it's a time to start work so let's start
I would talk today on that session about
some implication of and of use the
virtual refractor especially in the
context of the routing optimality so we
start with as like a definition why we
are doing vnf why we are virtualized
network function which is the root
reflection function what are the
benefits we are looking after and then
we examine the challenges with the route
reflector implementation in the
traditional environment and how we
address it today typically and then try
to correct and seal these two things and
see how the hui hui achieve the current
optimality or current behavior while
benefiting from the death of virtual
function virtualization so the root
reflection is a function right we tend
to think about route reflector as a
device as a note but at the end of the
day it's a functionally needed in the
network that we can instantiate it as a
virtual instance as a software running
in visual environment and the natural
place for the virtual machine is a data
center and data center is where it is
it's not where we want to be to have a
data center from the route reflector
perspective it's where is it where it is
so we have to believe with that and
that's a very important point for my
stock because this is what we will fight
against the night at the same time for
why we visualize the
reflektor where we move it to the
virtual environment we want to ensure
that it behaves in a way from the
routing perspective in a way we expect
from with reflectors so it selects the
optimal path not worse than its today
and we don't want to have more problems
with this session scale in your path
scaling that's a second secondary order
issue but just keep in mind very very
traditional approaches to use the router
whatever the rotaries use it use them to
make to run a route reflector on top of
the on top of this platform but the
point is the Rooter by design is
optimized to do packet forwarding
otherwise it's not a Rooter not for the
data storage for processing code that
that overhead that's a cost of doing
business for the for this kind of device
however the route reflection function is
is critical is very important it takes a
lot of resources but noted forwarding
resources we have a server cell at the
other end right we have which we have
designed for compute data and it will be
good to use it because especially that
if we could consider efficiency like
cost of processing the prefix or cost of
keeping the rib it's much lower on the
x86 server platform and that's even
lower if we consider the virtual
machines located in the data center
environment we can easy eight and the vm
so brings other values as well we can
easier scale it up we can easier migrate
from one to one VM to another etc so
because route reflector by his nature
it's a cost of doing business right
nobody's paying all of your customer is
paying for better or worse route
reflector you need it to run your
network but you need
efficient powerful but at the same time
the optimization point for route
reflector is always to find the cheapest
way of doing things that's why we visual
function virtualization of the route
reflector to visual environment to the
VMS is seems to be attractive okay how
do you route reflectors works in the
sorry for that works in the traditional
network right we take to the very very
traditional approach route reflector
function is a deported or running on on
path on the kind of aggregation or
quarter or only another Rooter which is
of the path and due to optimization path
optimization the slightly bigger network
try to distribute the reflection on the
original basis in order to promote
regional local exit regional local exit
from the network some again some
traditional approach is to use the
retired router which is not able to keep
with the traffic we need to switch to
move them out of the data path and use
the master reflector platform but that's
it doesn't actually help smart because
it's all true tirso it's already dated
cpu limited memory that's that short
short time optimization so the first
optimization for the route reflector
platform would be change the platform
right move from the Rooter hardware
whatever MX juniper Cisco whatever it is
to the to the server to the egg to
compute node to appliance and that's
absolutely possible especially nowadays
when all vendors provides the software
version of the of the year of the ureter
either juniper cisco i'll capture
everybody do vai että everybody is
doing that
ah but this move this change it's not
end of the story right there is a couple
things we are not gaining from that we
still need interfaces to connect the
server to the router to the network we
still need to maintain this platform
right it's a physical block from
somewhere in the network so we have to
go there we have to upgrade it we have
to maintain it even worse this is this
requires new skills to manage the the
platform it's not a Rooter it's a server
with it has some operating system it has
to be patched etc it set up this admin
skills which not every network operator
staff person possess and of course the
last but not least the this cycle the
technology cycle in the server work is
shorter so very end of life the the
hardware replacement cycle in the server
is shorter than in return it's good
because you always has the best of the
bread and faster platform but at the
same time you have to manage upgrades
and moving the moving this software from
one platform to another the other
dimension of the possible optimization
of rotary rotary in the route reflection
infrastructure is just centralized we
need the number of route reflectors and
that's not ideal in a new idea and in
context of virtual function or
virtualization of route reflector it's a
feeling right because hey let's move all
route reflectors to the data center one
or maybe two for redundancy but then
simple centralization to onenote exposed
some challenges it's quite possible to
do for VPNs and many provider are doing
this for VPN families but it's not that
popular for internet even in the past
and there are two fundamental issues
with it very centralized it's a single
route reflector Peru or whatever size of
the
network it's a scaling challenge for
session and for path and we will examine
it in a minute and other even more
important is suboptimal routing as
effect of that so first look closer to
the sessions giving problem right we the
network are bigger and bigger they are
have bigger capacity but it also has
more and more loads so if we go extreme
and say how what hey one route reflector
will sell all my edge shooters then we
can end up with the thousands of
sessions and that's a pressure on memory
the big legal arrays but also on the cpu
and on communication path we have to
send the same information the many times
over the links which are next to the
next to the rotor factor especially the
route reflector uplink so too that's why
in today's network especially in
internet route reflection infrastructure
is kind of distributed or regionalized
because it mitigates the problem they
compile you can look all you can see on
the on the right side that the number of
session is more linear mode piece when
we distribute the distribute this is the
route reflectors this reflection system
and there is no black magic here very
similar is the path scaling right the
interesting observation is that from VPN
perspective it's not again it's not that
big deal because they forgiven VP and is
single prefix other multi-home at but if
we say multi comet is usually too
however in a internet context the big
ISP has a multiple session on across the
network in many places on the network
but end of the day there is a tenth of
peers when they get the full table
especially that's specially for the do
for that's a case for the one who
provides the transit service and this is
a pressure
the CPU we have more power there is a
high risk of the chair there are always
pop going in and out withdraw around
nails and even they are not the best
path software has to realize that this
is something going something going on
and again the regularization of route
reflectors so having the route
reflectors in the more low in the local
scope it's a kind of higher and building
the hierarchy solves the problem it's
exactly the same math behind the debt
and end the session scaling and then
finally the routing optimality problem
the route reflector as a it falls bgp so
if we keep the ad path aside we'll come
back to this in the moment in principle
BGP route reflector selects the one best
path or prefix and its best from route
reflectors point of view considering
route reflectors positioned in the
network igp view topology etc it selects
the one and advertise these to all and
every of his client so the route
reflector client is not aware about
alternative paths it just knows the one
given by route reflector and they have
to follow it and this is not necessarily
the best exit from the route reflector
from the client perspective it's just
the best exit from the reflector in a
free VPN sir l2vpn vpls this problem is
somehow somehow solved by use of the pua
of the bayous of route distinguisher
part of address which is based on based
on the lib originator loopback address
this creates the unique prefix / unique
prefix from the route reflector point of
view and of course if every prefix is
unique there is nothing to nothing to
select every prefix is the best one
however for internet doesn't happen
there is no route distinguisher is that
we have ad path but a puff is not really
good for for optimizing optimization
it's it's nice tool to provide the
alternative path for the first
restoration or faster restoration of the
traffic but in order to be able to say
eh its optimal you think we have to add
all paths if you add all paths then we
have a again the scanning problem and
it's very it this killing grows very
fast with the route reflection and add
path together we can limit the size of
the up path let's say at per second best
stuff but then nobody says the second
birth Path would be the optimal from
from route reflector perspective from
the client perspective so again the
traditional answer to this problem is go
regional route reflectors that mitigates
the problem of course route reflector
steal selects the best exit from his
point of view it's not globally the most
optimal one per every single client it's
a semi optimal but that's good enough
that's what we are doing today that's a
Carter current status quo and I'm not
trying to exceed that I just try I'm
just trying to match the current status
quo of the optimality but with the
benefits of the visual visualization of
the route reflection function so again
we are going back to the goals we want
to have your route reflector working in
the visual environment indeed in the
data center whenever data center is
located and there is an important
assumption I did during the preparation
for this talk that the data center
infrastructure may have all three
elements which doesn't participate in
the one network routing IGP bgp whatever
date mean that we
have to somehow bypass this or overcome
this problem to enable the route
reflector to choose the best exit and
what a small recap in the BGP puff
selection process we are in the middle
of selection we have very important step
and this step is that the it says that
the best path will be do one which has
the lowest IGP costs to the next hop
right and from now on this will be the
probe this would be the step against
which will do the our design and put
against which we will I will try to
explain how to play with that to achieve
up to the semi optimal original original
optimal routing we start from the we go
through the example and we start with
the traditional at all design there is a
a country whatever it is not my home
country ah and in this country we have
four regions we have to route reflector
/ / region for internet another to route
reflector per region 4-d for the VPS so
all together is 16 they are spread it
across the country located in the
network sites it this route reflector
may or may not be co-located may or not
or may be co-located with the corner or
quarters or even implemented as a
function on top of the quarter doesn't
matter the important thing is that the
data center are on the west and east
where the Royal real estate is cheap the
power is cheap space is cheap labor is
cheap but it's not necessarily the most
optimal place for the for the route
reflector so our goal is to move the
functions move the route reflection
function from the network toward into
the data center and not necessary
consolidate root or vector just have
them where the computer resources Archie
and for the gear g origin dance reason
in our group at this picture you see
that there is a SNT twist and twist the
data center saudi from each region one
of the internet route reflector goes to
the west data center another to the east
data center however we have to address
the problem of lack of layer free
connectivity or actually lack of igp
connectivity to the route reflector and
we want to keep the we want to keep the
south region or north region to select
the local exit point in the region as a
big best bgp path so the proposal or the
approach to do that is yes we we have
the visual route reflector it runs the
bgp as usual it has the same set of
clients as the route reflector in before
scenario so the let's say south south
region clients are peering with the
given route reflector instance but there
is all these this route reflector
instance has also the so-called shadow
routing context it's not in helston the
additional rip routing information base
which in some way keep the i keep the
topology and metrics information from
the south region or north region
designated regent point of view i will
use the south as example when during
this explanation because that's what the
picture is showing and so this visual
virtualized route of vector supposed to
/ from the bgp pop selection based on
the information in not in the main read
but in the other RHIB so we will go for
the three elements of that first is this
shadow instance right we have to
populate them with the
top o virgin formation with the matrix
and we would and we will do and it's
done through the using the GRE tunnel
right so we open the jury tunnel which
is which payload is terminated in these
routing king styles and we will run the
igp on top of it so this way we will be
we will build the proper rib the at the
other end of the tunnel is somewhere
deep in the network in this example it's
a one of the core router in the south
region from video from IGP perspective
there is a couple of policies with ever
we don't want the these shadow instance
to be a on the shortest path for
anything so set the overall bit or bump
the link metrics for the tunnel do not
insert the any route learn it in the
shadow instance into the forwarding
table because there is no need the only
purpose of this instance is to have a
routing information the routing
information base use it for the BGP next
up resolution and we not need anything
else than blue box right the other end
of the tunnel I call this rotor shadow
host but you can call it whatever ah we
not we I we not need anything special
here okay jiri tunnel that's one thing
but except that we'd run basic by GP on
top of it run BFD maybe if we know if we
if we need bomb d matrix and potentially
for the security reason we want to avoid
the transit traffic entering this
distant last part is global instance of
the visual so the in the global things
as we have vgp running and a global
instance has couple of the function
first of all the global instance is the
one which has the routing toward the
network and because our assumption that
we don't know what is the data center
infrastructure we cannot assume that I
GP will go there so static is good
enough it could be defaulted to be
aggregate toward loop bags we can use
your RP or if the data center provides
or use VFD and this forwarding
information this this static route are
used for two purposes first of all we
use it to forward bgp packets from the
bgp process down to the down to the
Rooter all clients in the in the
designated region for that instance and
also we use that forwarding instances to
forward to forward the encapsulated to
no packet not the payload but after
absent capsulation to forward to the to
the shuttle host that's important and I
will tell you why in the two slides
forward this was about forwarding the
BGP which runs in this context it learns
the prefixes over the session from
clients or for other route reflectors
that's a normal thing but the next hop
resolution so this defining word is the
metric toward the next hope it's
happening in the shadow context not in
the default context this allows us to
abstract the position of the ritual
ultra route reflector or which one
network function from the actual
physical location of data center and let
them behaving as it is in the south or
north or whatever region we want there
are a couple of aspects which has to be
considered residency yeah maybe it's
good idea to have to GRE tunnels and
have to
rotors and that's nothing special if we
use the traditional approach with the
root around a route reflector on the
stick you also connects them usually two
to cover altars and the selection of
these two characters are saying right
it's something which is in the region
and has equality best equality or very
similar power cost to all kinds so it
doesn't change the design a design
approach we use since last I don't know
ten years it's just we use the tuna
instead of physical interface we have to
avoid it for some of you who has
experience with the GRE or to knowing
well generally running routing protocol
over the to know it's a code for problem
that should be a like a bell because it
may result in the recursion right so we
learn the destination of the tune
alluded to know through the igp running
inside the tunnel so the tuna will flop
and I GP fresh session wolf up because
the and then our next stop resolution
will be a next hole bgp next approval
will be invited bgp read rouse and the
it's a circle of the disaster we don't
want that and using the separate
instances that's why we use the separate
instances solves the problem yes it
could happen for this or other reason
that the tunnel destination would be
land over I GP but this information will
be in the context not use it for
forwarding of the jury to know packets
so it doesn't have another security
concerning these kind of things is hey I
want to be sure that there is no traffic
passing from I dnf virtual machines and
the compute nodes are good for the bgp
but that's not the best quarter ever i
would say the request ever so
we had at the same time the shadow
instance is a part of igp they have two
objection see over to to Niles so it's a
part of the network part of igp we have
to prevent the passing traffic through
so yes we can do this on the control
line put the high metrics on them to
know set the overall bit if we can if it
is is that's good but that's not granted
that their window there would be no
traffic traffic so the warranty could be
achieved through the filters and not and
the filters applied on the shadow host
so are the ingress of the tunnel in the
network on the network side some event
or implementation may make it easier
than other but in generally that's
that's the general solution we need a
filter which allows only only IGP
traffic and maybe BFD and the concept
could be extended we may have no more
than one shadow instance right if we can
instruct bgp to use some a context trip
for our other contexts other instance
read to resolve the next up we can say
hey but we have the rip one for the
Internet ripped to for the vpls through
free for lv VPS and yet another rib for
the next up resolution for the MV GP so
you are the RPF roots for the for
multicast why not and each of these
instance may have different tune us
different point of a remote remote
points of the two now and because of
that different topology view we can even
create different regions for the
internet different for a VPN different
for the multicast it's quite flexible so
in summary
instantiate route reflector as a virtual
function could provide optimal routing
optimal to the level it's optimal today
regardless of the physical location of
the route reflector and it's like
evolutionary solution toward optimal
reflectors optimal route reflectors a
feature set which is up a little bit a
site of my talk I'm not I'm not going to
talk about this this time next up
resolution and puff selection based on
that could be different by the address
family that's possible that's doable
depending on your poll it could be
controlled by polishing and protecting
the visual natural function of route
reflector against unwanted unwanted
transit traffic has to be considered
it's very important because otherwise we
can screw up our we can overload the
software running on the vm with the
transit traffic instead of spare
dedicated these resources probably
dealing with the bgp updates that's what
i have thank you much any questions
there is a mic
hi and we got a one question and the
answer vr is ldp supported is what ldp
label distribution protocol supply okay
we have some like in tes option C
applications and which route reflectors
the YouTube like how do I see the router
reflector for into a sovereign see the
RTP is required to go to the other side
and we heard like a rdp is not obviously
answer that way I think I understand the
questions so in sake of time our first
is the support of particular protocol
the visual route reflector except bgp is
a is a vendor specific answer so i can
answer from my company but that's better
do I offline okay um but usually you
need the label that route if you want to
resolve labeled prefix bgp prefixes
again it's a vendor dependent or
software the Bandit but there is nothing
which stops you from the standard
perspective to punch to put d put the IP
prefixes you learn in the context into
the into the label a trip and tragedy
it's a fooling of the Rooter factor
right but you can do that we did you not
losing anything you still have the you
still the trace the reach ability of the
next stop exactly and for the
reachability validation and we can use
rip group and to make you to work and so
far it's a for the interior option C he
need to go to the other route reflector
and to pass the label at the coach who's
the ESP are to go to the other side is a
label switch path and which required rdp
and the physical are can do that and so
far we are and the function is there but
I heard like a rdp it's going to be
removed from support from the we are and
which I can force I think like the photo
is very vendo specific question I can
answer it but we can go about
I think it's not the place yeah that's
but I was asked to be not
vendor-specific yeah okay thank you
larry i think Randy's yeah sorry Randy
we're gonna have to close the mic so
we're running behind and we need to
continue so thank you for thank you much
thanks