and
next up will
roland oven
bitcoins and some packing just before
that couple of notes the were aware of
the Betty Burke the executive director
let me know we're aware of the power
issues and going to work on it during
lunch so thanks for your patience in
that regard and one other programming
note there was a snafu with the schedule
where it showed the it showed both lunch
ending at 130 and programming starting
in the afternoon at one that's been
fixed so it'll actually start at one
thirty in the afternoon so that's the
time to come back and one of the
speakers for the afternoon has
graciously agreed to reschedule to
Tuesday which is very appreciated too so
that super thank you and clicker here
yeah that's it sorry forward great okay
super hi everyone my name is Roland
Davin's I work for arbor networks and
I'm here to talk with you today about DD
for BC your bitcoins on your site we're
going to talk about a an ongoing dido
sextortion campaign a couple of
programming notes my slide style is very
verbose there's a lot of words on the
page the reason for that is twofold I'm
taking notes for you and secondly the
presentation is designed to be read by
those who are not fortunate enough to be
with us today so a lot of the slides I'm
going to skip over you will have the
opportunity to download the slides later
so mainly focus on me and I'll highlight
the stuff that we're going to really
talk about so DDoS attacks or attacks
against availability typically through
capacity or state exhaustion d us
extortion is not a new thing it's been
with us basically since the days of the
the early days of IRC and bitnet
non-monetary extortion called coercion
we started to see monetary extortion on
the Internet in 1997 or 1998 so it's
actually not a new thing at all so what
is Bitcoin it's basically magic internet
money it is a cryptocurrency that is
mind so you actually have to
spend computational effort to create
bitcoins either yours or someone else's
if you hijack their machines to do it
the transactions in Bitcoin are
verifiable they're posted to a public
register there's not a high transaction
fee for using Bitcoin and the
transaction fee is actually paid by the
purchaser not the vendor there's a lot
of criminal activity around Bitcoin
there's a lot of theft a bitcoins attack
against online Bitcoin wallets to steal
people's bitcoins and things of that
nature and we've also seen a lot of ddos
activity around Bitcoin for example
we've seen attempts to manipulate the
value of Bitcoin where we see threat
actors who are launching geass attacks
against Bitcoin mining farms and
exchanges and things of that nature one
of the most important things to
understand about bitcoin is that this
audience you probably know what bitcoin
is raise your hands you know what
bitcoin is ok right so if you go to the
average person in the street either they
haven't heard of Bitcoin or they vaguely
heard of it but they don't really know
what it is so it's magic internet money
as far as they're concerned um why would
an attacker want to use Bitcoin to
receive extortion payouts well it's an
international you know fiat currency
right so you can get it and move it
around anywhere on the global internet
it has the potential for at least pseudo
an out anonymity kind of like cash you
can longer Bitcoin you can run it
through several different transactions
very very rapidly to try and launder it
very similar to cash until recently
Bitcoin had a very high exchange rate
when compared to most other fiat
currencies and it's completely set apart
from governments and regulatory entities
which means that is also easy to avoid
paying tax on Bitcoin transactions and
the pool of bitcoins can be expanded to
an ultimate finite limit what is the
disadvantage to an attacker
using Bitcoin well it's not actually
untraceable cash is not untraceable cash
has serial numbers and Holograms and and
you know are fit i'm assuming these days
everything else so there are ways to
trace cache there are also ways if
you're persistent to try to trace
bitcoin payouts and see the flow of
currency through the Bitcoin system it's
actually potentially easier to trace
bitcoin then cash because you're not
dealing with physicality here you can
automate a lot of it it's easier in many
cases to steal bitcoins than stealing
cash you don't have to walk up to
someone on the street and stick a gun in
his face and say you know give me your
wallet right you can do it from the
safety of your mother's basement bitcoin
is also very highly volatile it's much
more volatile than other currencies that
we see around the world and the biggest
problem is that unlike us right this
self-selected crew of nerds and Geeks
most ordinary people have either never
heard of Bitcoin or if they've heard of
it they don't know what it is and they
don't know how to get their hands on it
so that's actually a barrier to someone
who is trying to collect an extortion
payout so DD for bc it's a moniker that
stands for d das for bitcoin very
self-explanatory this is an a moniker
that this particular threat actor
adopted so it is a self naming kind of
situation you get it angled a lot in
conversation you'll see d for BCD CBC
for and and stuff like that DD for BC is
currently the most notorious DDoS
attacker on the internet about a year
ago year and a half ago it was lizard
squad with all the gaming related Yas
attacks before that it was anonymous
right so today the DDoS attack ER du
jour on everyone's lips is DD for BC how
do they get started DD for BC first
emerged in july of last year and focused
the ddos extortion campaign on bitcoin
related sites and so--but
when exchanges Bitcoin a lot of sites
yes there's a thing that's called a
Bitcoin lotto site online gambling
houses that take payments and make
payouts in bitcoins were the main
targets of attack and just like D toss
back in the early the Bitcoin ecosystem
can be viewed by many in the mainstream
it's kind of a fringe sort of thing it's
not really viewed as being in the
mainstream of business and you know
betting shops and things like that
they're viewed differently in different
different regions and different cultures
but just like the very very earliest you
destroyed after cd4 bc was concentrating
on kind of a fringe affiliated with the
the bitcoin movement one of the things
that most d das extortionists do is
they'll say ok give us our protection
money pay out and you'll never hear from
us again and inevitably if you do pay
you do hear from them and DD for bc will
say ok I'm going to detox your site and
i'm going to take it down and if you pay
me i'll go away well from the very
beginning DD for bc followed the typical
pattern and came back to the folks that
paid and as a matter of fact the second
organization we know that was attacked
by DD for bc was an online sports
betting house and they agreed to pay now
the reason that they paid was because in
the background they were frankly
implementing all the BCPS and doing all
the things to implement a DDoS defense
that they should have done from the
get-go and so they paid to buy time and
DD for BC would come back and want some
more once or more and then they paid
again we don't recommend this but that
was a strategy that was employed last
year most of the targets that DB 4d 4b
see attacked during 2014 were Bitcoin
savvy and so they understood how to make
payments if they were so inclined and we
see extortion payout demands from DD for
BC ranging any
we're from a single bitcoin up to 100
bitcoins the current exchange rates at
something like anywhere from 227 US
dollars to twenty two thousand seven
hundred US dollars and the the
attraction of attacking fringe
businesses is that they're not very
likely to go to law enforcement and
they're viewed in many cases with
suspicion in law enforcement is not
necessarily very interested in helping
those types of victims and of course as
is the case with all DDoS attacks it's a
very very tiny percentage of attackers
who actually end up in jail and unlike
what we see in the TV shows and in the
movies most criminals aren't masterminds
most criminals are stupid and most
criminals in the criminal justice system
of any country that you care to name
talk their way into into a court they
talked their way into a conviction and
they talked their way into a jail cell
and that's how most D das attackers the
tiny fraction who are caught actually
get caught is that they run their mouths
they run their fingers on social media
so in the early in the first quarter
this year DD for BC decided that he
wanted to go where the money was right
that's why Willie Sutton robbed the
banks because that's where the money is
and so in the second quarter DD for BC
started attacking financial institutions
and has done so eminent geographies in
Europe scandic Central Europe Western
Europe Scandinavia North America Asia
India very very broad reaching
geographical attack campaign DD Form
ACCC has also has gone after banks
they've gone after online stock and
commodities traders and they've also
done a bit of research or reconnaissance
and they've gone after firms that are
embedded and are essential to the
financial industry but that aren't
typically consumer-facing
ACH check processors for example or
credit card processors and organizations
of this nature so far no financially
related organization in the world that
has been targeted by Gd 4 BC has
actually admitted to making an extortion
payout we know that at least one has but
if others have they're keeping mum about
it for obvious reasons DD for BC has
attacked a few very large financial
institutions but they mostly tend to go
after mid tier or regional financial
institutions and we believe the reason
for this is the D for VC is calculated
that these organizations are less likely
to have the technical skills and the
savvy and their resources to fight a
serious DDoS attacks and so they are
more likely in DD for bc's estimation to
be willing to pay an extortion payout
and what we saw in 2014 was that the
ratio between extortion threats that
needing for BC sent out and actual
attacks delivered was a relatively high
ratio that ratio has gotten much lower
since DD for BC has expanded its
horizons to the financial still they
send out more extortion demands and they
launch attacks but it's a much lower
ratio than before they've also attacked
ISPs the various nature transit
providers broadband wire wireline
providers ecommerce sites VPS hostess
collocation providers etc we saw what we
think was a DD for BC experiment
normally what dd for BC tends to do is
its Alexis targets and it does enough
reconnaissance to try to mine email
addresses that are likely to be answered
by a human being and then sends out the
extortion demands we saw then on the
contrary in Europe they did an
experiment we believe where they did a
lot of mining and figured out that this
particular hosting provider you
had a bunch of you know ten fifteen
thousand sites with different domain
names hosted within their their network
and sent out automated extortion spam to
you know route ad and security at and
abuse at they didn't get a payout from
that one and we think it was just just
an experiment DD for BC was seeing if
they could get a yield from span
extortion demands versus having do the
research to actually target individuals
within an organization ecommerce sites
doing online retail and trading and so
forth have been targeted as well and
eighty-four bc are still attacking
online betting shops they're still
attacking bitcoin-related organizations
as well they've mere they haven't
shifted their focus from purely
bitcoin-related organizations they
simply expanded it to include more
mainstream financial organizations and
as the S is the case with almost all
DDoS attacks a lot of collateral damage
here you know some folks believe that p
das attacks or a legitimate form of
non-violent protests because they're not
stealing anything but the reality is
that almost any video she taught is
gross overkill it's like trying to swat
a fly with a nuclear weapon and so we've
seen several VPS and infrastructure as a
service cloud providers hit and yes the
the targets did at least initially
suffer some some some downtime but tens
of thousands of other customers were
affected as well in terms of collateral
damage so how is DV for bc's mo evolved
over time well a typical DD for BCD das
extortion attack against like this
unannounced DD for bc will launch a DDoS
attack against the website of the
organization they're targeting this can
range anywhere from 15 minutes to a
couple of hours typically 1015 gigabits
per second something like that then what
they'll do is they will send an email
message with the extortion demand and
they provide enough information so that
the recipient has a pretty good idea
that whoever set this email actually
is at least affiliated with the attacker
and they'll say okay you have 24 hours
to pay us this extortion demand or you
have 48 hours to pay this extortion
demand if the victim doesn't follow up
dd4 bc will simultaneously send more
emails demanding payment and launch
bigger attacks and they will also
increase the demanded extortion pay out
over time um DD for bc attacks a
relatively low that the number of
attacks against people against
organizations who don't pay versus non
attacks is relatively low so a high
percentage of the targets that they
actually launch the initial attack
against if they don't pay d 4 BC will go
after them again and they will increase
those demanded extortion payouts over
time and if they see the targeted
organization engaging in DDoS defense
they will say ok well you're trying to
defend against our attack so we're going
to raise the price of your payout even
further when dd for BC gets into an
ongoing geass can't a deep set of DDoS
attacks against an extortion target the
attacks will persist from a couple of
hours 12 hours in some cases several
dates within the same week however one
thing that we have noticed about ed for
bc is that they will eventually cut
their losses if they are unable to gain
an extortion payout if the targeted
organization are able to effectively
defend against the attack DD for bc for
the most part will eventually go away
and target someone someone else we have
seen them come back to target the same
organizations from time to time and on a
couple occasions we've seen them go
after the same organization multiple
times we believe this is a sense of
frustration these tend to be
organizations that have little or no
availability loss
and these attacks because they are
well-prepared they've already been
through this they know what to do and so
DD for BC gets frustrated and wants to
really show them who's boss or at least
try to and so we think that's what's
going on there so here is a typical DD
for BCE extortion demand and you'll note
here that the 4 BC are actually
referencing their own press right you're
saying okay well we're DD for BC and you
may have heard of us but if you haven't
here's a couple of links and we want you
to pay us and we're running attack right
now a demonstration attack against your
server will stop in an hour and so we
want you to go and get some bitcoins and
we know that you may not have some
bitcoins on hand or may not even know
what they are and so will give will
generously give you 48 hours to get
bitcoins and you don't even have to
reply this message just send the Bitcoin
extortion payment to this particular
Bitcoin address and we'll know that you
paid and you won't hear from us again
and so here is a follow-on extortion to
me and so they initially made an initial
demand this organization did not give in
and so they attack some more and they
said you've got six hours or we're going
to start the attack again and went to up
the demanded pay up and this is one
where the attacker was frustrated
because he said well I see that you
tried to defend your site against our
DDoS attack so you know it's going to go
down again I want to take it down and
don't bother with De Aza mitigation
because you're not going to be able to
do anything and we're going to increase
the payout to three bitcoins and we will
keep doubling it every day of the attack
until you finally pass in terms of the
actual DDoS attacks the DD for BC
launches at first they will start out
with a mixture of ntp and ssdp
reflection amplifications sometimes some
dns reflection amplification and send
flooding and so after TV for pc games
them operational experience they really
they tend to lead with ssdp or ntp
sometimes we'll go
to syn floods or another methodology as
well they are very very focused on
monitoring the efficacy of their attack
and if they see that the targeted
organization is successfully defending
against the attack they will shift
vectors in order to try to defeat those
defenses and then you know the second
vector they go to is mitigated and they
will shift to a third vector they would
do them in combination so they're very
very focused on monitoring the efficacy
of the attack they always at least so
far have gone specifically after web
servers they haven't seemed to target
any other type of server service or
application that we know about and DB
for bc they're single threaded they
don't attack in parallel they go after
one target at a time and they tend to
concentrate in one geography so like
this week at Switzerland's turned or
this week it's the United States turn or
this week it's in the adjournment so
what they'll do is they will leap around
in terms of geography but they will do
they have a launch a spate of attacks
against organization space in a
particular geography and do them all
serially and then jump somewhere else
that's what we've observed so far the
the DD for BC attackers are not using as
far as we can tell any kind of exotic
new DDoS attack methodologies that are
radically new they're difficult to
mitigate in fact from what we can
observe we believe that dv4 bc are
pretty much exclusively using so-called
booter or stress or services and these
are what Jack refer to in his earlier
electrifying presentation what he was
talking about you know botnets for hire
or you can pay and Jess that you can pay
with your credit card or your a Bitcoin
typically attackers pay with somebody
else's credit card and somebody else is
that Bitcoin but you can you can go
online and pay these these folks they
have automated interfaces so it's
d-don't as a service and that's what dd
for BC
um tends to be using these booter or
stress or services 10 to masquerade they
say oh well this is a stress testing
service this is a performance testing
service for your site for your online
application what they're actually did
ask for hire we see over time that some
of the booter and stressor operators
have added additional capabilities to
their services and ask they've done this
DD for BC have adopted those
methodologies for example we saw some
booter and stressor services add the
capability to launch a wordpress XML
pingback reflection amplification attack
and shortly thereafter DD for BC added
that attack mythology methodology to
their repertoire so they are keeping up
with the publicly available tools and
adopting new attack methodologies ask
the Butera stressor service operators
add those to their services d 4 BC are
very disciplined they have a methodology
the methodology that I just described to
you with the initial attack and the
initial distortion demand the
escalations for non-communication the
installations for attempted defense
these are all standard and we don't see
a lot in the way of variation in those
behaviors so DD for BC have kind of a
cookie cutter approach and again they
will react to successful the US defense
within the repertoire that they have
they will start out with one methodology
if that doesn't work they'll switch to
another methodology they'll switch to a
third methodology then they'll try to it
once three at once for it once never any
really radical shifts and these are how
the booter stressor service is
advertised on Twitter guaranteeing power
10 to 50 gigabits per second and
updating our amplifier bliss hitting
extremely hard as always so it's very
easy to go and find these services
online we have seen one innovation it's
almost too strong a word a variation I
guess you would say of an attack
methodology in DD for bc's repertoire so
ssdp
reflection amplification attacks are
actually making use of a feature of upnp
universal plug and play that has been
implemented unfortunately on a lot of
cpe devices like small home Soho types
of cpe devices around the world in it
and in some cases on host directly as
well and so the way that a normal
run-of-the-mill ssdp reflection
amplification attack works is that the
attacker spoofs the IP address of the
victim and he sends an ssdp which is
HTTP / UDP or HD p / you in search
enumeration requests to this whole list
of ssdp with lector amplifiers and e
spoofing the IP address the target and
all of these CPE devices that have ssdp
running on their internet connected
ports then cheerfully answer the victim
and pummel them with all these
unsolicited in search responses that's
how a typical ssdp reflection
amplification attack works what we've
seen be four bc do in some circumstances
of a little bit different we've seen
them lead off with a regular vanilla
ssdp reflection amplification attack and
when that doesn't work they'll switch
over to something that we hadn't seen
before and so at least some of these
booter stress or services are actually
going a step beyond scanning for ssdp
reflector amplifiers and what they're
doing is they are actually enumerated
all of the upnp registered services that
are sitting behind those CPE devices
which have registered with ephemeral
ports on the public IP address public IP
interface of the CPE device and they're
sending HTTP / you get requests to those
ports that show up as having a upnp
registered service the reason they're
doing this is that by definition all unp
pnp compliant devices that register
themselves with a upnp control point
like a home router they have a very
brief HTML Status page that lists some
technical information about those
different services and this is stuff
that's sitting inside the home like a
game console like some embedded linux
device that's a media player things of
that nature and so this particular set
of Butera stressors are actually
enumerated no services and the way that
this attack works is that DD for bc
commands whatever system is using to
launch the attacks to send a spoof HTTP
/ you get to the ephemeral port that on
these various cpe devices millions of
them out there on the internet that
actually have new pnp services
registered and those devices receive the
HTTP / you get and they dutifully return
the the Status page for these upnp
service is sitting behind the cpe almost
always matted and they pummel the target
the attack profile looks a little bit
different because instead of as with a
normal ssdp reflection amplification
attack instead of seeing the attack
traffic emanating from a source port of
UDP 1900 on the cpe devices they're
useless reflectors amplifiers it's
coming from some pseudo random ephemeral
port the packets tend to be around
400-500 bytes in size the attacker does
yield multiple packets for a single
request we believe that the
amplification factor here is something
around eight to one ten to one something
in that nature so what is a normal ssdp
reflection amplification attack look
like we have our initiator over there on
the left hand side of the slide the
initiator decides he wants to attack 172
19 234 dot 6 so he sends
TPM search request which again is HTTP /
UDP he sources this request from the
port that he actually wants to deed us
on receiving in the most typical port we
see the attackers uses UDP 80 does
anybody know why the reason is that a
lot of non-specialists don't really know
the difference between tcp and UDP and
or if they have an instrumentation at
all all they see is poor dating so it's
kind of a form of obfuscation and so the
the attacker will source the EM search
requests from the IP address the spoofed
IP address this is why bcp 84 is so
important he will spoof the IP address
of the victim say ok I'm going to source
this M search requests from UDP 80 and
I'm going to send this request up to all
beings ssdp enabled devices which again
a lot of them are home Soho cpe devices
some of them are windows boxes that have
a upnp toolkit enabled and things like
that the request is about a hundred
nineteen bytes in size so the request
goes out and so what happens is all of
these ssdp reflectors amp and amplifiers
dutifully respond to the victim with
these unsolicited SSD p.m. search
responses sourced from UDP 1900 on the
reflectors amplifiers to the port that
the attacker chose on the first leg of
the attack in this case you dpat we see
yields of up to ninety eight hundred
bytes in these responses and they are
typically two traffic stream distinct
traffic streams that we see we see the
initial fragments which have the source
and destination port so sore sport EDP
1900 destination port 80 then we see the
non initial fragments which of course
don't have source and destination ports
and the important thing to note about
any reflection and amplification attack
is that on the reflector amplifier to
target leg of the attack the source MPs
are not spoof those the actual
reflectors amplifiers that are emitting
the traffic this variation we talked
about works a little bit differently you
see up here at the top all the different
devices that are sitting behind these
cpe devices so our attacker again spooks
the IP address of the target and he's
sourcing his request from EDP ad but
he's not sending it to UDP 1900 he's
sending it to whatever ephemeral port
the previous enumeration scan showed
that a upnp registered service was
attached to on each of these particular
reflector amplifiers and he sends this
HTTP HTTP / you get and all these
devices some of these responses are
cached by the cpe some of them actually
live they gateway the request all the
way back behind the net to the home
devices and they reply sourced from the
ephemeral port going to e dpat anywhere
from 300 to 500 bytes and of course this
impacts the victim the target of the
attack it can cause problems and
intervening networks and it also
actually has a negative impact on the
folks who are unknowingly running all
these reflectors and amplifiers as well
this is what it looks like this is a
layer 7 d code from Wireshark wireshark
will decode HTTP / you just as it will
TCP base HTTP and you see here this
location URI so this is the location of
the Status page that the attacker is
sending to get to and you'll notice that
that's an RFC 1918 address so this is
actually sourced from behind the net
behind the cpe device is acting as in a
device we see this is some kind of linux
device running a upnp sdk this user
agent red sonic so this is being relayed
back by the cpe risk from reflect your
amplifier responder attackers often
don't know a lot about tcp/ip and they
try something once and it works so they
kind of have a cargo cult mentality they
say well I did this once and it works
I don't know why so I'll do the same
thing over and over again at some point
whoever it is who wrote the actual
attack tool code that is doing this
unity this upnp invariant attack decided
for some reason to use the user agent
red sonic in those HTTP / you get
requests this maps onto a company in
California that makes some kind of
embedded Linux distribution that's used
in a lot of home appliance type of
devices and it consistently shows up in
this attack variation there's launched
by DD for BC so here's another one very
similar again we see in RFC 1918 address
and of course the port number is there
as well and the name Gate desk xml so
this is coming from the home router
itself we believe gannets running Linux
we see our red Sonic here we see that
the upnp string is a little bit
different though than in the previous
one and so this is a different type of
device from a different vendor or a
different operating system version or
build this one is different yet again
can anybody tell me what's different
about this one does circling rad its rad
amor right it's a rattle IP address so
this is not an RFC 1918 address this is
a routable IP address and also the ERI
TX meteor renderer and upnp speak this
is some kind of device that can receive
streaming video or audio transcode it
and then play it for the viewer and we
see this is a windows box so this is
actually apparently a naked windows box
sitting on the Internet of course we
still see red Sonic and here the upnp
identifier reflects that audio video
transport identity that we saw in the
URI finally we have this one this one is
different yet again can somebody tell me
what's different about this IP address
set right self assign that's right so
this is a device that try to get you a
dhcp address and failed so it's using a
self-assigned address we also see WPS
device there what does that mean well
thats related to why
this protection system right and we see
here sure enough if we look at the upnp
registration information we see that
this is apparently a Wi-Fi access point
that's sitting behind some kind of home
router so who is DD for DC what a CD for
BC based on lexical analysis of all the
extortion emails that we've seen we
believe that the DBC is relatively
fluent in English but it's not a native
English speaker DD for BC got really
exercised over the fourth of July
holiday the United States started
sending out and financial organization a
bunch of extortion demands and was very
upset we need to get a response and so
started launching you guys attack the
stuff like that and the United States
the fourth of July is the second most
widely known holiday after Christmas in
New Year's it's a four-day weekend as
banking holiday and so anyone who's
familiar with American culture such as
it is would probably know not to send an
extortion demand to a bank over the
fourth of July weekend so we don't think
DD for BC is very familiar with American
culture DD for BC is cereal in nature
not in parallel attacks a single target
at a time this plus some other factors
leads one to the conclusion that DD for
BC may well be an individual this is my
personal theory i think is probably a
single person i could be wrong um DD for
bc is reasonably tech-savvy dv4 be seen
knows what bitcoin is knows what a DDoS
attack is knows what a booter stressor
is and uses them somewhat effectively
but it's not really a big innovator we
don't see exotic attacks from BB 4 BC
that are difficult to mitigate and we
also see that 84 bc maybe a little bit
naive because one of the worst kinds of
targets you can go again up against if
you're trying to stay free and avoid law
enforcement involvement is financial
institutions and that that is right
where DD for bc has expanded so not very
smart in that regard basically VV for bc
hasn't been caught yet for number of
factors first of all because of only a
very small percentage of ddos attack
xicot do the pseudo anonymous nature of
the internet and also before because the
d 4 BC so far has utilized relatively
good operational security DD for BC
doesn't run his mouth a lot went after
fringe organizations at least initially
he's willing to cut his losses and move
on from target a to target B to target
see if you can't get a payout on and
though DD for bc and the extortion
emails will claim 400 500 gigabits per
second of capacity so far the biggest
attack we've seen from DD for bc is
about 60 gigabits per second now that's
not insignificant but it doesn't choke
all these peering links and transit
links and core links and cause a huge
amount of interference with bystander
traffic that is passing through
intervening networks it really starts to
add up it's the various reflect your
amplifier source path get start to
topologically converge towards the
target so it's not big enough to cause a
huge huge problem DD for bc's attacks
riffs are kind of sporadic he'll do a
few and it'll stop we'll do a few more
you can move from one jurisdiction to
another and only attacks one at a time
and again we think that part of the
reason BB for bc even though he's very
prolific and as notorious hasn't been
caught because it keeps its mouth shut
so what do we think is going on with ad
for bc now in the future well the first
thing is that imitators have sprung up
duty 4 BC has become so notorious that
we have seen imitators spring up in
different geographies around the world
claiming to be DD for BC and sending out
X torsion emails or posting extortion
demands on pastebin com or regionalize
pastebin types of sites in relatively
poor English not up to DD for bc
standards and that upnp variant that we
talked about that yields of 300 500 byte
packets we haven't seen that from these
either we believe that ask the booter
stressor technology and features of all
the four bc will adopt them
we think you'll be more in Asia but
language is a very significant barrier
there we believe that English is a
second language for TV for bc we don't
think he speaks any asian languages same
thing for Latin America South America to
some degree you do have Spanish you also
have Portuguese same thing for Africa if
DD 4 BCE remains active we think at some
point he'll branch out beyond financials
and Bitcoin related stuff to other
verticals as well DD Form bc is a
traffic posse the cause TT 4 BC has
gotten has gone after one has gone after
financials has attracted a lot of heavy
heavy heat from law enforcement agencies
and intelligence agencies and security
researchers around the world so the lot
of eyes looking at the e4 bc right now
and we believe that if TV for bc
continues attacking financial
institutions this dramatically raises
the profit probability that you might
actually be caught how do you defend
against GD for bc all the standard BCPs
the I ackles and GTS N and your DNS
architecture make sure you have flowed
flowmetry so you have good visibility
and your traffic you can detect and
classifying trace back and attack the
standard reaction mitigation tools like
source based remote trigger black hole
closed fat that slows back and
intelligent DDoS mitigation systems full
disclosure I work for a vendor of the
latter um apples are really really key
and those of you who are familiar with
my ramps about how apples are not a good
reaction tool may be surprised you can
we say that but apples are not normally
very they don't lend themselves to
static reactionary defense but having a
reasonable network access policies in
force in front of a server or service
make sense you dpat should never make it
to a web server you say well if DD for
bc is even launching a 60 gig attack he
can fill up the last kilometer or last
meter transit link of the target that's
true but they're still value in keeping
those packets off the actual public IP
address of the servers because they
don't have to deal with traffic and if
let's hope not but some folks still do
tend to put sir
worst behind devices that are ridden
with state like stateful firewalls or
so-called IPS devices those devices will
go down just like that and they'll take
30 or 45 minutes to reboot so apples are
a key we advise organizations if they
get an extortion email they should
immediately contact the relevant law
enforcement agencies their upstream
transits or their peers they should if
they have an MSSP that's providing
security services let them know as well
if they're involved in any industry
specific groups related to security
where information is being shared let
those folks know as well and if they're
part of any of the closed offset
communities that are vetted let them
know that you received an extortion
demand as well play for time pretend you
don't speak English pretend you don't
know what bitcoin is engage in some
dialogue here and try and string this
this person out well this group out
while you're contacting your law
enforcement and your peers and your up
streams and making sure that your do das
defenses are sound we urge you most of
all don't pay if you pay eventually it
will probably come out it's going to
make you look bad and it incentivizes
the criminal to come back hit you again
and again and again so DD for pc is
prolific long-running campaign
reasonably skill reasonably good
operational security so far he hasn't
talked his way into a jail cell he's
very very focused on the efficacy of his
attacks and will vary his methodology
depending on the efficacy of a given
attack he seems to know when to cut his
losses in most cases and move on to the
next target we don't think he's American
we think it may be an individual again
that's my personal leaves i think the d4
bc is one person all the standard bc
peace and stuff that you've read about
heard about here at nan augs past and
see me heard me ranting about my little
corner of the internet those all apply
there's nothing exotic here the max
capacity we've seen for do you for bc is
about 60 gigabits per second he will
adopt new DDoS attack methodologies that
are supported by the commercial booter
and stress
video says the service providers it's
got a real long tail posse on multiple
jurisdictions after him he will go away
if you defend successfully against him
and he can be defeated because we've
helped defeat him multiple times so
questions comments a couple of people
make anyways the microphone by the way
of this QR code you can use your QR
application on your smartphone to snap
that and download the presentation also
the short you are a yes sir microphone
number two Nick Carlin Microsoft can you
comment about efforts to track the
follow the money through the Bitcoin
blockchain probably are you acts are you
asking are there is here an effort to
track the money is that your question
yeah I mean Bitcoin transactions are
public record and there are multiple
individuals and organizations working to
track it absolutely the question
microphone number two again Matt PTAC
yahoo so you mentioned that you've got
this upnp vector where they can actually
enumerate capture the response and then
go after the sources behind it this
would imply that instead of it being a
spoofed source at some point the command
and control system is actually using a
real reachable node to do the N search
enumerate and capture those responses do
you know if people are doing honey pots
to look for non spooked sources right so
that's a very insightful question so so
the questioners point is that whoever is
launching reflector reflection
application attack has to go through an
enumeration stage to discover and
enumerate these various types of
reflectors amplifiers out here on the
internet and the question is is anyone
looking at the skins to see if they tend
to triangulate somewhere the problem
with the internet is background
radiation okay the vast majority of
packets that are out there or actually
garbage packets first of all and
everyone and his dog rate on the
internet nobody knows your dog I think
you're a security researcher everybody
on his dog on the internet is constantly
scanning
and the attackers are scanning in many
cases from there also get there's
getting from compromised systems and in
many cases they're scanning from systems
that have different IP addresses from
the botnets or the booter stress or
services that they're actually using to
launch the attacks from and so they
engage in that kind of offset another
thing that they do is they identify IP
blocks that are not masqueraded very
well that obviously are part of security
research organizations and they don't
allow those you know to scan them that
they do a lot of obfuscation and so
that's why it's a good question but
there's just so much noise that's very
difficult but thank you micro number one
Phil Rosenthal from is prime so about
the the booter and stress through
services you know you said they they
advertised it as like oh this is a
stress test and I mean real ously
speaking people here may actually choose
to buy you know a stress test from them
I'm sure that's not the primary business
but that said if they were a legitimate
business selling the service they would
be buying transit and actually launching
it from their own networks but they're
not doing that they are bouncing it off
of things on the public internet that
therefore it is trespassing it's theft
of services why doesn't law enforcement
look at it that way what you and I and
everyone else in this room knows versus
what lawmakers and regulators and law
enforcement agencies in different
jurisdictions around the world now are
sometimes very very different things
right and to your point the nature of a
reflection amplification attack tends to
militate against the excuse that this is
just a traffic generator this used for
legitimate stress testing right and
you're absolutely right unfortunately
the law hasn't caught up and there's so
many jurisdictions worldwide there are
jurisdictions where the rule of law does
not hold sway and by the way that's
where most of the SS the pot the current
floating population of ssdp reflective
amplifiers lives is in a couple of
jurisdictions where the rule of law
doesn't tend to hold sway and so that's
part of the prob
as well if you look at human history
crime has always been with us ok we have
skulls right from the police to Sierra
you know in 60 50 60 thousand years ago
of human predecessors that were
obviously murdered because we can tell
you know forensically look at the holes
and their skulls that they were attacked
with a blunt or sharp instrument crime
is part of the human condition the
internet is part of the human condition
therefore crime is part of the Internet
condition right it's always going to be
an issue the biggest thing that folks
can do of course is to implement anti
spoofing ingress policing at their edges
for anti spoofing BCT 84 we also
strongly strongly urge broadband
operators to proactively scan your
customer base your customer base the
access IP ranges to flag cpe devices
which are reflectors amplifiers and
encourage your customers to remediate
those devices or and fire those
customers if you have to great any other
questions comments okay you've been a
great crowd thank you so much going to
enjoy your lunch
thank you all