we should start i got to figure out
what's the best way to share the slides
this window
well if your browser allows you to uh
share just the window then
that usually works better yeah
all right
let me as soon as i can get those shared
i will do that and we can start
yes
select window
all right is that working now
screen share is being started i'm still
not seeing slides though it's thinking
yeah there it is okay there we go yeah
you're hot
cool thank you roman all right
now that i've mastered the tricky
technology i'll just be able to hit the
down button
okay welcome everyone to acme
we have a few presentations about an
hour
so let's um
i know we all wanted to be in bangkok
but instead we're all on video
so be it
you have all hopefully seen the note
well by far
before it describes how the iatf
operates what your rights and privileges
and responsibilities are
um by viewing this via meet echo
you have signed on and entered into
you know sign the blue sheet and
therefore a legally binding document
should we all get sued so
don't worry about it
administrative tasks uh so we need
one or two note takers uh jove's gonna
do the jabber scribe
because he'll cut in and talk
can we have someone to do the kodi md or
ether pad whichever you'd like to call
it
we can't we'll be stuck on this slide
until we get some volunteers
let us volunteer to drop some things in
cody md
thank you for that yeah oh thank you
great okay
should be pretty easy the it's populated
with the formatted version of the
minutes
of the agenda so great thank you
all right next slide the agenda
so we already did the first bullet the
administrivia
uh i'll go through the next section is
the drafts
that are out of the working group and on
to
you know various parts of their uh
publication life cycle
um the authority token authority
authority talking list those
have been ied iesg reviewed and
we're waiting for revision um we know
the author i know the authors plan to
do stuff they've just sort of been busy
with stir which is their
their main interest so those will happen
uh alexi had a whole bunch of feedback
um and he's just recently posted a
revision and he's got another one
coming soon to hopefully address the
last of the feedback
uh last meeting we moved to be
pushed star delegation through working
group last call
i have to write the shepherd do the
shepherds write up
and hit the forward to the isg but i
will do that
shortly uh
drafts in progress okay all right
yeah hey richard if i could just jump in
on the first two documents around
authority token uh they're actually not
with the isg they're still actually with
me
so i'm waiting i'm sorry you're waiting
for the revisions yeah we haven't made
it that far yet
got it yep thank you roman yes so they
are waiting for they've had
a d review and he's requested some
revisions reasonably so
um oh outlook notice yeah thank you
uh start allegations waiting shepard's
right up i will get to that
probably during the next coffee break
thereafter and
hit the button to forward that drafts in
progress
um acme client and the acme integrations
we have presentations from owen friel
about the updates on those
dtn node id was published
as a working group draft has had no
other changes
and i don't believe brian is here so i
don't think we'll have any talking
on that uh
some new documents were submitted for
working group consideration
uh one on um
subdomains within night within uh
acme uh we'll be talking about that
onion routing was submitted by roland
schumacher
who has you know left let's encrypt and
moved on to another job and i
haven't been able to track him down so i
don't think we'll be having anything on
that
um i encourage anyone who is interested
in onion stuff and i'm trying to solicit
some volunteers
um to consider picking it up otherwise
we'll just have to consider it a banded
service discovery will have a
presentation
um and related to that is i guess the
server capabilities
and that will be coming from fraser
teasdale
so any bashing of the agenda
um well kathleen is not here but she has
to to get feedback on
uh her draft i guess it means
integrations
uh yes good integrations and and
actually i think her draft was an acme
client
[Music]
anyway she wants to know if we think
that's ready for working group last call
okay so when we start speaking when owen
presents on integration to talk about
that
okay okay
all right um
oh and you're up
and what richard owen
michael yeah can you see and hear me
it thinks i'm very faintly very faintly
is that any better
any better
yes okay
okay so a quick update on what's
happening with acme integrations
and we can go on to the next slide rich
rich can you toggle to the next slide
rich can you hear me
for what it's worth i can hear you
anyone hear me
i can hear you can you hear me yes yeah
rich can you go to the next slide
well i share how would i share let me
see if i can share
um you can't as long as rich is sharing
but
have we lost here i
stopped his sharing so you can start now
okay
oh there it is okay
frasier are you available
okay now
people can see my screen hopefully
um so quick summary this is an
informational draft
it describes how acme can be integrated
with multiple
existing clients and device certain
normal mechanisms without requiring any
changes to acme
and the the three main things we're
looking at is integration with est
integration with brisket and bristly
cloud which is really just briskly with
a default cloud registrar
and integration with teep
there's been a few changes since draft
0.2 we just published draft 0.t very
very recently and we've added the
security considerations
and this is a quick summary probably
documented um
the first thing to consider is that acme
disintegrations draft makes no changes
to the
existing standards we're just primarily
referring to the security considerations
that
exist in the existing reference
standards um
but a couple of things we did explicitly
call out the acme integration service
could be configured with keys for dns
updates in order to handle acme
and challenges so so the operator of
that acme integration server should
consider
restricting the blast radius and the dns
zone that those keys can update
and similarly the actual integration
service could be authorized to write to
http servers for handling http
challenges
and again the operator should consider
restricting the blast radius of the
server accesses
um and also the acme integration service
because it's handling requests coming in
from multiple clients
and proxying those requests through to
the acme server we need to consider acme
integration dos tax
and we should consider on the acme
integration service having a certificate
caches to avoid
having to ping and the acme server
continuously when it's not when it's not
necessary
so those three three consider security
considerations are described in more
detail in the draft
and additionally the only other changes
that are made there's a minor tutorial
changes we've fixed up some broken
references
and we've made we've picked up some nits
with the calls and some knits and titles
throughout the doc
but they're only minor editorial and
there's one discussion item do you want
to talk
talk about it was brought up on some of
the mailers a while back but it didn't
really go anywhere
and it's about cmc ras that that eku
um so when you look when particularly
when you look at brisky
um and it also mentions this in est
that when est or brewski goes to um
enroll for a certificate when the easter
brewski client goes from role for
certificate against the east to your
brewski servers and the client
or the pledge should check for the cmc
ra
eku and i've what i've quoted there is
the explicit text from est
the explicit text from brewski that
outlines how the cmc ra should be
checked
now when you consider acme acme says
nothing about eku's at all
and currently if you look at say the
bold implementation for let's encrypt
acme server policy and server
implementation decides what he can use
to accept and to include in csrs
so when we're looking at him est or
brewski
integration with acme um we just need to
think about
if the registrar itself is going to be
enrolling automatically with acme to get
its own identity certificate
um should that register be requesting a
cmc ra from acme currently that's
encrypt won't give
out a cmc or a um eku
um and what does that really mean when
you're when you're getting a certificate
from a public
acme certificate authority such as let's
encrypt and should the pledge really be
checking for this anymore
so that's just a general discussion
point that we probably need to bring to
the brewski anima mailers
and the iot onboarding mailers but i
just wanted to call it out here because
we don't have a good answer for this yet
we haven't thought about it
deeply enough
and next steps is reviewers please and
feedback please
and there is an old email thread on um
brisket
on this cmc ra that we must bring to the
top emitters again
because we do want some input on this we
do need to close this before we close on
the um
um acme brewski and acme est
integrations
sections and that's it
okay thank you and see that we have
it i'm going to stop the share so that i
can take a look at the chat again
and that's it back to you rich
i am done no you're not because we have
a question for michael
oh um uh owen uh asked me
a couple days ago about this point and i
went oh
um yeah this is a real issue um and
so i have an email half written to that
about this
issue and ironically
allows the registrar to have a
self-signed certificate
and um that is actually part of the
the leverage point so you can have this
bizarre situation where you could have a
registrar that's giving out
certificates to clients that it got via
acme while itself not using one
um which really feels bizarre um
and uh so i think that you know
that's a discussion that i think we
should have and in the
uh not yet adopted uh acme subdomains
thing um it's it's possible that that
maybe
that uh the authorization process that
would
allow you to uh through one
authorization doing
quite a number of sub-domains not a wild
card but many certificates maybe that
actually should set that bit
um but then there's some other issues
about what that bit really means that
maybe
our it means actually really we
shouldn't set that bit
and we maybe we need another bit uh i
don't know
um but i think that's a conversation i'd
like i like i'm going to start on the
list
okay yeah thank you moment um
anything else okay so i guess uh the
next one is what uh subdomains
yeah supplements okay i will
share again
so rich i think you need to one of the
chairs needs to approve me i just
requested
share
oh okay i just grab it
okay
okay so subdomains three
we published a new version of this a
couple of months ago
um so the summary act made house
an acting server to issue certs for a
given identifier each a subdomain
without requiring a challenge to be
explicitly
fulfilled against that identifier for
example an acme server could issue a
search for
through one.future.example.com or the
acme client only has to fill a challenge
against one of the parent domains for
example birth or example.com or
example.com
an acme server cliche search for a
number of sub-domain certs and only
require a single challenge to be
fulfilled against the parent domain
which is a nice optimization and has a
scaled benefits
when we want to issue a large number of
identity certs
and this is related to the device
integration stuff we were talking about
in the last presentation
um acme result domains may optionally be
used with pre-authorizations but
pre-authorizations are not necessarily
required
i just quoted the relevant section the
relevant text from rfc855
uh x on order objects and leave it in
bold here that's important
the authorization is required or to
serve a policy
and there may not be a one-to-one
relationship between the order
identifiers and the authorizations
required
so what that means is that the order
output could be for sub-domain and the
authorization required could be foreign
some changes since since changes in
three since ik108
we've incorporated the meter feedback on
zero two i know ross gave quite a bit of
feedback
we've updated the terminology section
and we've added security sections and
there's
there's some open items that i do want
to talk about that were discussed on the
mirror but we didn't really reach any
concrete conclusion um i just for
terminology clarification what i added
was uh
some ca browser forum based on
requirements definitions i reference
these for
base domain domain name and domain
name space and just for clarity what i'm
finding a sub domain as is a domain that
is in a domain name specific given
parent domain
for domain name space domain name and
parent domain are the ca browser forum
definitions
um security considerations we've added
quite a bit here but um
in summary acme for some domains has
exactly the same two security goals as
acme and i've quoted these two security
goals from acme
verbatim so only an entity that controls
an identifier can get an authorization
of that identifier and once authorized
and account keys authorizations cannot
be improper use by another account so
exactly the same security goals um
we don't propose making any changes to
our counter key management
channel establishment and validation
channel establishment or the security
mechanisms or threat models there
and for acme server policy decisions we
just clarified because there was some
confusion on the mailer about this as
well
the document may be applicable to public
cas privacy is for issuance of iot
search etc
um the baseline requirements may not
necessarily
be applicable and specific server
policies are outside of the scope of the
documents we just clarified all that in
the security consideration section
and there's two main open items which
were which were discussed over and back
on demeter over the last few months
and first is does the client need a
mechanism to indicate
that they want to authorize a parent
domain and not the explicit sub-domain
identifier
or does the client need a mechanism to
indicate that they're happy to authorize
against the choice of identifiers
so for example for the food through one
the future that bar the example.com
should we enhance the acme protocols
that the client
is able to specify anywhere from one to
four identifiers that they're willing to
fulfill challenges against
and the second question is that was
raised on the mirrors is does the server
need a mechanism
to provide a choice of identifiers to
the client and let the client choose
which challenge to fulfill
so for the same example again should the
server be able to specify anywhere from
one to four identifiers that the client
can pick from to fulfill
so both one and two require json object
definition changes to the baseline acme
spec
and they're not currently covered in the
sub domains document
currently the document only defines how
a client can submit a new order or new
authorization for a sub domain
and the server can choose any of the
parent identifiers that requires a
challenge for the madam but
can use just one and so we're not giving
the client
we're not giving the client a mechanism
to offer a choice of identifiers that
you're willing to fulfill
similarly we're not giving the server um
the option to
choose or to provide a choice of
identifiers that they're willing
for the client to pick and choose from
and if we want to do that it requires
some changes to the json
and next steps is just discussion on the
open items
and based on the discussion the open
items what we actually want to do with
this document because it's still not
adopted
okay i'll just leave the open items
shared out there
and that's it that's the presentation
pretty quick
any comments because i know there were
comments in the jab room
might as well make them at the mic
unless you want me to relay them
yeah but i can see the comments in the
chat room seem to be about the previous
one where we're asking about
ra eku's right so
so that's the open question from the um
from the the integrations one that
slider popular integrated to cmcra
and and currently acme says nothing at
all about uh
about um ekus it's entirely up to the
server policy and we actually don't know
whether
i i don't know whether we need to try
and explicitly extend the acme spec to
see anything that he can use you're
requesting or explicitly extend the
specs
server can advertise what he's willing
to offer
um but we're not proposing that because
we haven't really
discussed the eku's and specifically for
the cmcra on the matters at all yet so
at the moment we're not proposing or
suggesting any changes to acme to do at
equus
and currently that policy is just acme
internal server policy
and we're not entirely sure how to
handle the cmc rx yet which is why we
need that discussion
and but in the sub domains in sub
domains we're not talking about
equals at all in the sub dimension we're
not really talking about eqs at all
the only open items are the choice of
identifiers
so is anyone any opinions or comments on
these two open items for sub domains
that were i think it was was it jerome
and ryan who raised these on demanders
possibly and trying to recall
uh
just to comment about the eku's and
whether
we want a mechanism for service to
express
things like what eku's it will put
on the cert uh i have a draft
uh which i'll speak to very briefly
later
about
a mechanism for servers to express their
capabilities in the directory meta field
and in that draft i also talk about
the possibility of servers expressing
their policy
that's out of scope for the draft
but i do suggest that it might be a
topic of
interest for future work
so i'm i'm definitely on board with
discussing
ways for service to express their
policies so clients
can make more nuanced decisions about
whether or how to interact
with the server
okay it sounds interesting i'll read
those when they come out
uh to move forward oh and maybe just
start two email threads one on each open
item
and let's see what the group says if
anything
okay
okay i'll stop sharing i'm finished
thank you
brian sipos you want to give an update
we missed
earlier that you were here sorry
uh i'm on can you hear me
okay um so the
good news is that the the primary dtn
drafts are making their way
through the iesg review now the security
uh review on the primary users of
these certificates that are being
discussed for acme
issuance uh are being worked out uh
there's a lot of detail that's that's
being hammered down
um which is good uh but what that means
is that
the uh the acme use of those
certificates is is really going to rely
on those details being
finalized and i also saw that the s mime
draft
uh having gone through for acme uh
uh progressed further is going to help
out because the the dtn use case
is very similar in flow though a
completely different
encoding than the s mime use case
so all the secondary activity is is
progressing
uh which is good for the final use
that dtn will have of acme
but that means no change to the draft in
the very near term
okay
yo if you want a solicit discussion on
the client
uh the client document kathleen stock
yeah sure just uh let me share my screen
this time
uh this one right
yes i did okay
um can you assist because i can't
um can you see the screen it's
still being started okay
so let me know when you can see it
i thought they did comment said you need
to pick the screen app you want to share
okay
okay and
that's the one i think yeah
okay yes okay
so um this is the the draft and uh what
kathleen wanted to know is uh i'm going
to do solicit comments and the other
thing to
answer the question whether we think
it's ready for working group last call
so anyone
okay
okay that's
not a lot of participation and i guess
we'll take it to the
list i'll just
stop my sharing
[Music]
okay which leaves us just with the acme
service discovery
so i need to start a screen share
oh
okay
back to the beginning
uh so just presenting my
draft for a service discovery mechanism
for acme so why do we need service
discovery
the acme ecosystem is growing and there
are now multiple
publicly trusted cas with acme endpoints
and also private enterprise pkis
are beginning to implement acme
so we have environments that may have
access to multiple acme
servers furthermore we're standardizing
new kinds of identifier types and
validation methods
so clients need to know what service can
i use
to acquire an email certificate for s
mine
or to acquire a dns certificate
explicit client configuration can be
challenging
not always some environments with
centralized
configuration management
are likely to use that to push
configuration to clients
and the disposition that says well i
don't want any
auto discovery i want to make sure that
my client is explicitly configured
is valid but in other cases
that doesn't work so well or it doesn't
scale
so you can think of devices maybe
printers
you know iot things even a light bulb
entering a network and
this thing could be quite difficult to
explicitly tell you need to use this
acme server over here
but you may still wish to be able to
have it
talk acme and opportunistically acquire
a certificate
to secure communications with that
device
uh another situation is uh an
organization with a
bring your own device kind of network
where people are coming in with
who knows what software that can't
necessarily be
managed by their configuration
management system
and yet you know their email clients
they might want their users to talk
smite
okay if you're a big enterprise network
using outlook everywhere you might be
able to push that configuration out
through
active directory well what if some of
your users have brought their own
computers and they're running
thunderbird
or mutt so these are the kinds of use
cases that
service discovery can be useful for the
goal
is that where you want service discovery
it enables automatic selection of the
best
server in the environment best being
defined by the network administrators
and how they
express the services that are available
so there are a bunch of different
service discovery protocols
some are peer-to-peer or distributed
such as
dns service discovery over multicast dns
some use a central registry some are
specifically tied to particular
communications technology such as
bluetooth
and some are general using existing
naming systems
such as the dns so
in the enterprise environments dns srv
records have been used for a long time
for auto discovery of ldap servers
with the organization's directory
the kerberos key distribution centers
mail servers and probably
other things that i don't even know
about
rfc 6763 defines dns service discovery
and it uses
pointer records for listing of
available service instances in a given
domain
and srv records and txt records with
supplementary data
to give information about where those
service instances are located
and any other data that might be of
interest to clients
for that particular service type
uh so acme service discovery uh is built
upon
dns service discovery or dns sd
so uh there are a few assumptions here
the assumptions are that the acme client
has its network configured
and that its network configuration
includes a domain name
or a kerberos realm name
or something that it can use to decide
i'm going to look for services in this
domain
the assumption is that the organization
can manage its own
dns records to advertise the services
and we also make an assumption that
successful retrieval
of a directory object by an acme client
implies that the service or the server
is
up and running and available
for the client to use
so the first step for the client is to
determine its parent domains
these could be given by explicit
configuration
or as i've alluded something that comes
via the network
configuration or the kerberos realm
basically
some way for the client to decide here
is a domain name or here is a series of
domain names that i will search
for acme services in
it then searches for pointer records
with the owner underscore acme server
dot underscore tcp dot the parent domain
and i'll just give an example here of
this domain corp.example
advertising two acme server instances
one called corp ca and the other one
called
c4a
so each of those servants our service
instance names
owns an srv record and a txt
record that describe where that service
is located
gives the path to the directory object
and gives a list of the
acme identifier types that
that acme server supports
so this will allow the client to
construct the url to reach the directory
object
and also make a decision about whether
it will even
attempt to use that server
for example if this is a
an smi email client there's no point
that it would try and contact
a server that's only offering dns
identifiers
an important thing here is that this
specification
re-scopes the meaning of the srv
priority field across
multiple owners whereas traditionally
it would only be for multiple srv
records in the same
owner scoping it across multiple owners
allows the administrator
who is setting up these advertisements
to define
priority among different service
instances
and the uh the draft goes into a bit of
detail about that and also
some security consequences
of this rescuing of the priority field
so from here the client will choose the
best server that is the highest priority
server that is advertising capabilities
that
meet its needs and constructs the
directory url attempts to get the
directory object and pass it to see if
it is a valid acme directory object
and if so all good that is the server
that the client will try to use
otherwise it will try the next server
and if it exhausts all of the service
instances
advertised in the current parent domain
and it has other parent domains to try
then it can
go across to the next parent domain and
repeat the
dns service discovery for that
parent domain and once it runs out of
parent domains then it can either give
up
or fall back to a default such as
uh let's encrypt if it's if this is for
a dns
client
so i have some working code for this i
have a fork of certbot where i hacked in
the service discovery uh i don't
know if i will submit a pull request but
if you
hack on certbot i would be interested in
your feedback
on the feature uh and and the draft in
general
and also on how i have gone about that
and i wrote this blog post uh that
gives a bit more detail and some
demonstration of that running code
and if there is time and if you really
want to see it then
i can do a demo for you today but i'd
probably rather start
just discussing some some of the
uh things that need discussion
in this draft so i'm i'm very interested
to hear what other people think about
this
uh re-scoping of
the semantics of the srb priority
field we also need to think about
multicast dns so dns sd
works for multicast dns and unicast
this specification
restricts it to unicast unless there is
explicit
configuration telling the client that it
can do it on multicast but i think we
need to
restrict service discovery to domains
not ending in dot local
and we need to restrict or filter out
service instance names that end in
local as well so that acme clients
performing service discovery don't
inadvertently accept
service instance names that have been
advertised
over multicast dns
just in a first come first serve basis
by peers on the local link
the security considerations talk about
dns security
i'm curious whether people think
it's worthwhile or important to mention
uh dns over tls and dns over
https
i see in the chat rust does dot home
have similar concerns
yes uh possibly stroke
probably uh
and yeah the whole question of parent
domain selection this draft does
not uh seek to
specify or constrain how clients would
do this but i would like to give
good examples of how a client could do
this
that aren't completely insecure and
a terrible idea because
people will sometimes mindlessly follow
the examples
so yeah we just don't want to give
people loaded foot guns
uh so the next steps is for people to
give feedback
and for the working group to consider
whether you would like to adopt this
draft
uh i have the source for this draft in a
github repository the link is there
and you can create issues there some
people requests if you wish
i'd be very happy to
collaborate with people to
improve and advance this draft
a brief note on other work
i have another draft i don't want to
elaborate it much today
that can go on the mailing list but it's
about
giving servers a way to express their
capabilities
in the directory object so this is
not related to or required for service
discovery but
it is another way for clients to make a
decision
earlier on about whether a server is
suitable to be used by that client
rather than just trying to
submit an order for a dns name to an smi
macmi server for example
i'm also curious if anyone is interested
in working to
specify srv name support for acme
this is something we've talked about a
little bit at red hat we think it would
solve some problems that we have
um obviously this would need to go hand
in hand with
proper support in popular tls
libraries for srv name verification as
well
but uh you know we have people at red
hat whose whole job it is just to work
in maintaining
open ssl and nss so
you know if if we agree it's a good idea
then
um where there's a will there's a way
uh but again that's something we could
probably discuss on the mailing list
just wanted to flag it as something that
we're interested in
and that's all thank you
gee i'm not sure well i don't yeah we'll
use i guess the show of hands tool
do a quick poll uh how many people have
read the draft
give me uh
uh raise your hand if you have do not
raise your hand if you have not
all right not i don't think enough
people have really read it yet to
discuss uh to consider adoption
frazier could you post an individual
draft
uh via the data tracker
um and then we can and then mail to the
list
asking people to read it and let's see
if we get feedback there
um or if you want to if you prefer just
post a note to the list saying you've
got the draft
but you know we have some discussion
let's see what the github
interactions are
good feelings about the idea if not the
particular draft
on the jaba room so there is interest in
doing this
uh maybe in acme
yeah that was going to be my kind and
since we have a queue here i'm
popping in um so this is richard barnes
from
cisco um i think this is a really
uh good idea i think this is a problem
that
is worth solving that is certainly
emerging in some uh enterprise use cases
i i've seen some of the same challenges
i expect of fraser has seen
um i haven't looked in detail at the
exact best
mechanism for discovery here so i agree
there's a need for some sort of
discovery here i
haven't looked exactly at the details
the dns based thing here
um the main thing i think worries me
about this is the choice
of the the the starting point the name
the name you use for lookup
and for that i wonder if for at least
some identifier types
we could leverage the identifier you're
looking to authenticate
uh as a starting point so for example
with a domain name uh
identifier you could use the domain name
itself or or some
parent domain or for email address
identifiers you could potentially use
the domain of the email address
as the starting point um you know with
with appropriate
you know underscore prefixes um just
just suggestion there
um the the identifier type stuff i
wonder if that might be better in meta
as opposed to in the discovery system
um since it's just one more http query
so
in general i think this is on the right
track and i think it's probably a
problem with solving this working group
uh mark you're next
okay any any other comments
i guess all the others in the queue
wanted to say essentially the same thing
as richard
okay
all right uh we have hit
the end of the agenda and
this is not any other business part
yeah normally we'd be like okay let's
rush to get the cookies oh mark said he
agrees with richard so
okay um but since any cookies are
either in the wrong time zone or have to
make them yourself
is there any other business it's always
the right time for cookies
yes daniel hi there
i realize i am way behind on uh keeping
up with what's going on in the acme
and i recognize that the s9
draft is very far advanced
um but recent discussion on the
lamps mailing list suggests that um
the preferred configuration for
uh email users is uh to have two
certificates
that is one for encryption and one for
signing
and i'm trying to find in the s mine
draft how it deals with
a dual certificate situation and i don't
see it
so i'm wondering if this is if i'm just
missing it or
if this is something that we need to
actually think about for s time i don't
mean to pull it back when it's this far
advanced but i'm just trying to figure
out how how i would do that
as a male user agent implementer how i
would get a dual certificate like
dual certificates like that
very interesting question i haven't
talked about this so
yes now would be a good time to
clarify this i think might need a small
extension
field
yeah i wonder if that's just an
informative note to say that
um you know once you've validated an
email identifier you can issue different
certs under it for different key types
well i was just wondering if there is a
need to signal that you want for one
purpose or for another and what is this
for reflection certificate
that's my only thought
um i will raise this on the acme mailing
list i suppose
um i'm not i i apologize for being
you know for being this late in the in
the process but i'm just
not sure how how to get that done
yeah roman
uh per dkg's feedback if we want to talk
about a little bit on the mailing list
uh and come to some agreement we can
just bring the document back i'm happy
to do it
alexis said i have him in the notes is
it's a good question
so um daniel bring it up and we'll give
a lexi first
whack at it i guess
okay will do
thanks anything else
any other business
so i guess we got two minutes of our
lives back thank you everyone for coming
no need to sign the blue sheets because
they're generated automatically
thank you and for your patience with the
chairs my
bluetooth connectivity problem okay
enjoy the rest of your week
bye bye
thank you benson
[Music]
you