okay
all right we're at the top of the hour
so let's start with a few of the
preliminaries while we see
um who drifts in welcome um
ietf 109 i guess is uh underway here
with the first of the working group
sessions for the week
my name is patrick mcmanus um got my
co-chairs here uh ben
campbell and um um
an incoming co-chair of chris dp we'll
talk about that in a
in a moment as we go um here's our
agenda
for today we can have just a look over
it but um
from the top uh we of course need
um we need a note taker for this session
braum i believe uh offered to do that on
the mailing list i'm not sure if i see
you braun in the participant list or not
let's see feel free to grab the
microphone and shout out if you're there
i'm gonna need a note taker before we
get going
so if braun isn't there yet would um
anyone else be willing to pitch
in
i know the timing is tough the system is
new
and we have a hot agenda to get to but
we do need someone to take minutes
before we can proceed
all right we'll go with this one can you
hear me i do feel a little like i'm
talking into a void today
we can hear you patrick i think what
we've got is the moment where everyone's
trying to be quiet and not be noticed
while you're asking for no tickets
i know it's easier to avoid eye contact
in this virtual format than it is uh
than it is in the room we need we need
the feature to turn on people's video
remotely
so hopefully braun will join shortly but
we could certainly use a second
notetaker one way or the other
so so please someone anyone well
kirsty said in the jabber room that she
can take notes
okay okay i just just paged away from
the jabber room
i missed that that'll work out great and
ben you're going to keep an eye on
jabber right
it sounds like uh well apparently i'm
supposed to be but
here we go all right looking at jabber
now
all right uh with those preliminaries
out of the way
you can see what we our agenda in front
of us we're going to have a short
discussion
um from our id's we have two dispatch
items to talk about
uh as a reminder the purpose of dispatch
is really to be a friendly and welcoming
place to
new work to the ietf and
to help it find the permanent homework
will really be developed
this working group itself very rarely
adopts a draft
the more likely and desirable outcomes
are to find an existing working group
for draft
to discuss whether or not perhaps a mini
working group would be in order
perhaps a buff would be in order and to
make you know a recommendation amongst
those things or even perhaps a
recommendation not to proceed at all
with the work
to the ads who of course get to make the
the actual decisions so we have a couple
things to talk about under dispatch
the haptics top-level media type and the
webrtc http ingestion protocol
this is a joint meeting with the art
area um
which means we'll also highlight some
other stuff going on in the art area of
the ietf this week
and have an fyi discussion of work that
may be even like too early for
being dispatched but is of interest and
could take
feedback from from this audience as well
that alexi will be presenting
on media types or rather content types
to distinguish between forward and
encapsulated
uh encrypted each uh encrypted
emails i believe okay
a reminder of our mailing list art at
iatf.org and dispatch at itf 4
being the mailing list and we don't have
our note well
in these slides i'm sorry that's my
oversight
but i will refer everyone especially
given that this is the
first meeting of the week to uh in your
favorite search engine look up iatf note
well
those are important terms under which
your contributions with the iatf are
governed
a contribution is almost anything you do
that interacts with
with other folks in a semi-public ietf
context so that could be a mailing list
that could be this
meeting and so those cover things rules
both related to ipr as well as your
your code of conduct during these
meetings so if you're not familiar with
that
please do take a look all right that's
the usual
getting started stuff out of the way um
and with that we can
uh move over to our first speaker which
i think is going to be
our ads i don't know barry is that going
to be you
that will be me and you should have my
video now
so hi yes everybody welcome to uh to the
online
ietf 109 for some people like uh
uh our our asian friends and um
uh the down under people it's a good
time zone for some of us it's going to
be an interesting week
but uh i'd i'd like to start by
most of you know that uh fairly recently
uh our beloved colleague and good friend
jim shad uh died
and i'd like to just take a moment of
silence to
recognize jim and his contributions
uh the the working groups he's chaired
the
documents he's edited the smiles he's
shared and the wine he's
he's made so
a bit of silence for jim
thanks and i won't do the full minute
for that but
we all remember him fondly
sorry the uh the next thing uh is a bit
of happier news we have a new chair
as many of you also know we we've been
interested in rotating chairs in this
particular working group to
give different people a shot at
having having something to do with
bringing new work into the art area and
being more exposed to
things in the art area so
ben is rotating out and kirsty payne
from the
uk national cyber security center is
rotating in
and she will be our new chair starting
at this meeting
so as we speak right now i am clicking
the button
to update the data tracker for care
state and
at the end of the meeting at the end of
the week
i will remove ben from the chair list
and there you
have some video from kirsty kirsty say
hi
yes hi everyone
yeah i'm nice to be here this morning um
it's nice to see you all thanks i'm
looking forward to
chairing dispatch okay
and that's all i had to say murray is
there anything you'd like to say before
we move on
and hearing nothing from murray let's go
ahead thanks guys
um awesome christy that's great um i
don't want to overlook
thanking ben you know i either who's
really done the uh
the yeoman's work here the past few
months which i've really really
appreciated and you've left us in a uh
you know in a great place so you know
thank you ben uh for your efforts
we can do sort of the uh the meat echo
golf club i'm sure everyone who's muted
is uh is showing a appropriate
appreciation but sincerely ben
um thank you so much um and with that we
can move on
um to our first dispatch item of the day
which is the haptics presentation um
do we have our speaker available
yes what yeah hi patrick
restaurant hello so um i'm going to show
your slides because it just disaster
always happens if um
okay if we don't have the shirts do that
but when you want a new slide just shout
out um
next slide okay okay
given that this is my first ever ietf
meeting what's a
protocol do i need to have my video on
while i'm while i'm talking
i mean i'm happy to go either way i just
want to know
that's up to you but um i think the
trend is towards more video and i
personally think it's nice
um would you like questions um during
your questions at the end
uh questions during is fine uh
if i'm not able to answer the question i
will ask until i
get through the slide and then answer
them but questions during the talk is
fine
and i am assuming i have about half an
hour according to the agenda is it
correct
including the question time that's
correct um and ben and christy will
monitor the uh the queue and they'll
just like pipe in
directly with any questions that need to
be addressed
so with that take it away thank you
great thanks patrick and
hi everyone good morning good evening
good afternoon if you are in a time zone
where it is afternoon
uh my name is yeshwanth muthusami i work
for immersion
and i'm going to be presenting our uh id
on the on on a proposal for haptics as a
top-level media type
uh next slide please patrick
okay just a quick quick introduction
haptics refers to the degeneration of
touch related sensation it's the
it's a slight vibration that you feel
when you're trying to
set the date and time on your iphone or
other smartphone
uh it's used widely in in a number of
consumer
devices for where your work
when you're using your virtual keyboard
or to get any kind of
vibrating notifications and off late in
in many of the cars the the dashboard
the buttons are usually replaced by a
large
touchscreen that provides a
bi-directional
touch interface and the thing about
haptics is there
it requires some kind of actuation to in
order to
to create that tactile sensation in a
mobile device that actuation is provided
by small vibrating motors or actuators
or in a larger or automotive touch
screen these actuators are
piezoelectric materials and haptics are
these days they seem to be everywhere
the the most recent example is a sony
ps5 dual sensor controller which has
just been released
and it's getting a lot of good press
because of its
haptics controller or pretty much all of
their
smartphones on the market have haptics
in them and they are right haptics is
considered pretty essential
for enhanced media experiences next
slide please okay
the this is uh just an uh
indication of that of the differences
between
version zero zero which has been uh on
the
dispatch mailing list since the middle
of october and version one
which i uploaded a few hours ago i i
apologize for this
late breaking uh uh update but until
late yesterday evening i didn't know i
was going to be presenting here so
uh thanks to an ee and email snafu
at our end i wasn't aware of this
presentation
so i kind of had to scramble and get the
new version out
the new version it tries to address all
of the comments
which we have received on version zero
zero on the on the dispatch mailing list
and specifically it try
it tries to i've added pros to
dispel the inadvertent inadvertent
misconception that some people has he
seemed to have
gotten from version zero zero that these
these following haptic subtypes were
already in use
that is not the case the haptic data
formats like ahap and org and ibs and
hapt are
are indeed widely in use and we expect
them to live under the
haptics top level type once it's
approved
so i made that point more clearer and
based on feedback from more than one
person i've added
the sections on the subtype
registrations for
haptic slash ibs and haptic slash hacked
to to just to illustrate how the subtype
registrations
would be handled once we have a haptics
approved at the top level i've added a
number of new
new references that show the progression
of the standardization
of haptics in mpeg and the availability
of documents for the various haptic data
formats
that we envision to live under the
haptics top level type
so that is the basic basic differences
so if people have read version zero zero
i i just want to point out that my
presentation is going to be based on
version one and this slide uh it kind of
gives you an indication of what is
different
which you may not have gone through next
slide please
okay in the in the next series of eight
slides
i basically go through various
justifications for why we believe
haptics needs to be treated as a top
level type and
that's what i'm uh that's what you're
going to be
seeing uh the first slide here is
basically more of an introduction
so to speak uh haptic signals provide
an additional layer of entertainment and
overall sensory immersion
and the and as the user experience and
enjoyment of media content
can be significantly enhanced if you add
haptics to the audio
video content in iso bmf files
media streams like atsc 3.0 broadcast
for those who may not be aware atsc to
3.0
is the next generation of the tv
standard
it's an international standard but
mainly used in the us and
south korea and also in streaming games
and
mobile advertising and i mentioned the
last part mobile advertising
because it it provides a good segue into
the last
point on the slide which is haptic
tracks
in separate files are already being
combined with audio video files
and played back in sync to provide an
overall immersive
media experience so it's not just audio
vivi
visual but now you have audio visual and
tactile
and our and the mobile advertising
business that my company used to have
actually used this exact mechanism
uh next slide please
and to date there hasn't been a
registration of for
formats for haptics and but uh
but starting in april haptics will have
was
proposed as a first order media type
which means that it's at the same level
as audio and video tracks
in the iso based media file format and
this proposal that we made was accepted
by the mpeg
systems file format group and then it
has since
progressed to dan which is a draft
amendment in
the at the uh october meeting which
ended in october 16th
after passing a worldwide
cd ballot so it is moving on to the next
stage in the standardization
and if it if it progresses at its pace
it's
expected to issue as an amendment uh
which would be which would be the
equivalent of an
international standard in october 2021
and when when that happens it will
become part of the
iso iec 14496
part 12 sixth edition and
this is a question we get asked often
how is it
what is going to be the designation for
haptics in
mp4 files given that video mp4
is already taken and audio mp4 is
already taken
and and and we do realize that and so if
a video a an mp4 file has got video
audio and haptics then
we are not going to mess with the
designation
it it's going to it's going to still be
video
mp4 the same goes for if a file has
audio and haptics and happens to be a
dot mp4
file we are not going to change the
designation uh but
we are we do envision to
mp4 files with just haptic tracks in
them
and the examples of such files would be
uh
mp4 files used for streaming games or
have haptic files for haptic
vests and and bodysuits and belts and
gloves
and for those files we envisioned that
designation haptic slash and b4
uh next slide please
okay now there are i mean for the
longest time
haptics was kind of of
to a lot of people haptics meant
either the buzzing or the rumble in the
older game controllers or
just the vibrating feedback that you had
on the older phones
uh but haptics has actually got multiple
sub modalities vibro tactile which is a
touch vibration is just one of them
the force feedback we which you will
feel in the
in the sony ps5 dual sensor controller
is called kinesthetic haptics and the
surface
is for the friction and and where you
can actually
get the different types of you can get
the feel
of different textures so you you can
actually get the
feeling that the the that you're feeling
uh that that you're actually touching
rock
or soft silk or a sharp object
or all that be because of the surface
friction that
you feel on your fingertips and then you
have the spatial
non-contact haptics which is based on
ultrasound and last but not least you
have the
thermal haptics so these are all the
different submodalities of haptics that
you need to take into account
and and designating haptics as a
top level media type would allow us the
definition
would enable the definition of these
data formats pertaining to these sub
modalities
in a more streamlined manner and you
will not be able to
do this with this level of the required
granularity
if you were to place haptics willy-nilly
under
any of the existing top level types like
audio video
or application next slide please
and this in my opinion is a pretty
compelling reason uh your mileage might
vary i mean
for for the human sense of hearing we
have the top level
media type of audio for the human sense
of seeing we have the
top level type top-level media type
video and for the equally important
human sense of touch
i think it makes for perfect sense to
have the top level
media type haptics and more to the point
placing haptics under audio or video is
not reflective
of the kinds of files or the use cases
that would need
haptics but would really have nothing to
do whatsoever with audio or video
next slide please
okay and there is a considerable amount
of
commercial uptake as i kind of mentioned
in passing
earlier it is rapidly becoming a
standard feature of many ce devices and
these
bullet points basically give you an idea
of the extent of the uptake
i iphone as you can as you see here is
over
191 million this is data from last year
the
the last year for which full year data
is available
and it does have native success support
for haptic encoded
data uh the the aaa app format as well
as the core haptics api
for those of you who are familiar with
the ios platform
in android you have a api css support of
haptic pub
buffers the w3c has got an html
vibration api which is
which provides haptic support in the
mobile web browsers
i've already mentioned the game consoles
and those
remain a very popular ce device or
close to 40 million units sold and then
xr
is in high here is an upcoming market
and
it helped in large part by the first
version of the kronos
open xr haptic api and so
haptic media is expected to be commonly
exchanged between these devices
and since these devices in in total they
represent the majority
of ce devices around the world
i think a strong case can be made for
haptics to be a top-level media type
next slide please
and haptic data formats
are already in use these are prevalent
in a large number of
devices around the world and these would
live
as subtypes under the proposed haptic
top level
media type once it's once it's
standardized or once it's
registered uh the aaa app for for format
which is the apple haptic and audio
pattern data format
which is this is the de facto standard
encoding on all ios devices and ios
connected game peripherals
and of late it has seen usage and
adoption
beyond apple devices as well uh
the very recently in android 11
google has introduced a proprietary
extension to the og for
format specifically to any enable
uh the adhd in the encoding of half
of haptic media in org files the
ibs haptic data format is a
vendor-specific format
as of now that is in use in mobile
phones from lg
electronics a number of models like the
v30 v40
and the newest v50 that are sold
worldwide
and gaming phones from asus
especially the rog one and the
rog ii and rog3 which are also available
worldwide the hacked haptic data format
is another
vendor-specific format which is used in
mobile haptic advertising as well as the
the following two game developers in
japan
you use them as part of immersions touch
sense
sdk next slide please
now these are these subtypes don't yet
uh haven't yet been standardized but the
but
they live in terms of and they live in
an informative annex
that we made uh as part of our mpeg
iso bmf proposal
and we propose the following distinct
4cc codes for them once again these
codes are not registered yet but
the standardization pertaining to these
is ongoing
in in some cases and the plan is to
is to standardize these haptic coding
formats in the near future
the first one is hmpeg or hmpg
uh this is this would be the 4cc code
for the coding format that is chosen as
the winner
for the recently issued mpeg call for
proposals
on the quoted representation of haptics
this draft call was
issued at the uh at the october meeting
at the mpeg-132
the the final call is expected to be
issued at
a mpeg-133 in january and
the rm0 technology or
which is rm0 is mpeg-speak for the
coding format which wins the which means
the competition
that is expected to be to be selected at
the
april meeting at mpeg at mpeg-134
and the h-i-e-e is the is the
four cc code for the ieee p1918.1.1
vibro tactile coding standard which is
currently
under that under development as part of
the ieee
tactile internet initiative
and then the hnem is the enumerated
effects acting coding format that's
based on midi
and hivc is a audio to vibe
haptic coding format which basically
refers to the
uh growing area of automatic a
a to b or or audio to vibration
conversion algorithms uh so one
standardized these for
these formats will live as the subtypes
under the proposed haptic
top level media type next slide please
okay we have gotten this feedback
when we first put it in the on the media
types list
and from talking to uh others as well
but in our view haptics really doesn't
belong under any other media type and we
see the
following three reasons as the main
reason why the haptics
media type uh does not fit under the
application
top level type haptics
connects to a sensory system of a touch
or motion directly and is more specific
than the abstract application type
application
historically has been used for
applications that is code
which means it's viewed and treated with
great skill for security
hack pics is not code in in much the
same way
that audio and video are not core either
and haptics is a property of a media
stream
it's not an application under any normal
definition
as such i think it should be its own
type of media type
uh next slide please
this is a somewhat involved slide but i
felt it necessary to make these points
because we were told as part of the
instructions for rfcs that we need to be
very explicit uh so i'm going to try and
get just touch on that that the
highlights here
uh signal data is typically i mean
haptics data can be
can be represented as collections of
signal data
or it could be represented as
descriptive text in
xml or json or a similar format signal
data is
typically not executed by endpoint
processors so there is not much risk
there
but descriptive text is passed and
represented in memory
using xml data structures then this data
is
then further utilized uh to to to
construct one or more signals
which are then sent to the actuation
hardware
and because of the media rendering in
nature of the
data path for haptic coded data
you can you can think of the security
profile of haptic
data would be pretty consistent with the
security profile of
visual or audio media data so
there is some security risk but it's no
more
or no less than the security risk that
you need to be aware of when you're
dealing with audio
and and visual media data uh
and then media rendering systems are
normally implemented with a mix
of user and kernel space execution since
this media must
ultimately make their way to a
hard-based system so
in theory you could have a you could
have malicious instructions that are
present in the
descriptive haptic media and those could
execute arbitrary code in
kernel space uh effectively the
high passing system permission
structures or execution sandboxes
and so you so it all is so
haptics audio video and media data
widespread use
and careful attention need to be paid by
the operating system and device driver
implementers to ensure that the
synthesis and rendering parts
do not provide attack surfaces or
malicious
payloads uh any
coded representation of media haptic
media is insufficient to implicitly
provide sufficient security and this
protection
should really be enforced by the os
implementer
next slide please
okay now we are in the iana
considerations uh so here
when you say that haptics is a pre
primary media
content type it it implies that the
content
defined by it requires a certain haptic
subsystems
such as the low level haptics apis and
those in turn require hardware
capabilities such as one or more
actuators or vibration motors to
actually render the haptic media
now the haptic media type does not
provide any specific information about
the underlying data format or how that
haptics information should be
interpreted
those those subtypes defined within a
haptics tree
those would name the specific haptic
formats and if you have any
unrecognized subtypes of haptics those
should be treated as
application slash octet stream okay
next slide please okay
uh
the timing there were 20 minutes left in
the slot please be sure and leave
room for this right i am i am
about three slides away from being done
is that okay sure just uh
go a little fast okay all right did
this is a boilerplate stuff i mean the
registration
procedure if you worked with rfcs you
know what
happens here next slide please
okay the these are the last two slides i
believe
uh these are we we just give a gig give
examples of the i ids
haptic type uh it's uh the
subtype would be would be ivs and the
file extension would be dot ibs or dot
ivt
and this is and the device independent
haptic effect
coding i think the rest of the part uh i
will
let you read on your own time i will
point out one that there is a i would
point out though there is a published
specification
uh that was recently published by mpeg
unfortunately the mpeg website seems to
be
down or they are in the process of
updating so the link is not available
next slide please
this is the haptic format
so and the file extension would be dot
hacked
and this is a device dependent haptic
coding effect that's effect that's based
on the rif standard
the research the resource interchange
file format standard
and it's and yeah and that's
pretty much all i want to say about that
and i believe that brings me to the last
slide
next slide please that's it
any questions comments
critics
people in queue i seem to have forgotten
how to let them in
hang on one might think you're up
then you don't let them in directly
anymore just tell them to go and they
unmute their own audio
ah tim go ahead when you're ready
i just uh wanted to hear a couple of
scenarios where you'd send haptics data
over the wire
all by itself
okay uh the i i i think i've
given a few examples there but if you
in the case of streaming games and if
you wanted to send
the haptic the data by itself to
to the controller uh it will not have
any
audio or video because it's mainly meant
for your
controller which most likely has deals
with kinesthetic feedback
the other time where you can expect
haptics to be sent over the wire just by
itself
if if you had a wirelessly connected
bodysuit or a vest
for example i mean the the this might
seem a bit far-fetched but uh
in reality there were at least three or
four companies
at last year ces we which actually were
showing these kinds of
haptic bodysuits with up to between
12 and 12 to 24 different
actuators and the other one is
a if you want to pre cache effects for
ads or games
is is that that's also a
haptics only a use case
does that help answer the question
magnus i think you're up
um about does this uh
top level type going to imply that we
actually update six rsc 6381 on
on the codex parameters for container
file formats
uh are you talking about six
663 6381
so the codex parameter yeah for for
example we just use swedish base
media file formats so uh and and then
before
so this is the codex parameters i mean
you have the
fork iso cc performance for haptics
which
already this allows you to tell this is
container file with
these haptics types in it but that's do
we have a direction in the other way
that we need to do something about
okay i mean i will have to admit to not
having gone through 6381 but if you are
referring to
haptic codec specific parameters we do
envision those being being standardized
once the
mpeg cfp which deals specifically with
an mpeg
coding format standard once that
standard is finalized
in the in next april or in the june
that cut time frame so i would at that
point
i would envision 6381 to be needed to be
updated
okay uh yes look at it let's consider if
it's
we're gonna need to do something in the
other direction also actually updating
that format
if if this happens okay thank you
okay thank you
so this might be a good time to jump in
and remind folks to
try and be responsive to the fundamental
dispatch questions we're dealing with
as well as the the merits of the
proposal
so if we get fairly nuanced questions
um this might not be the right venue to
work them through
and actually what we're trying to do is
find the right venue so
so please be responsive to that question
as we explore this
merry christmas
hi this is center
you think about applications that use
media types
you know the idea that you could say
haptics blah
instead of application blah or
audioblock
you have to make up some new mime types
for the individual
formats because audio doesn't carry them
it does nothing in their character
but if you think about generic form
applications
that know that if something is audio
star
audio that they can do something with it
you know it has
timing that it lasts a certain amount of
time
and you can associate metadata with
portions of it
that you can mix it together with other
audio streams
to create a new kind of audio stream
and you can't do that with video and and
they wouldn't know about haptics
and you might be better off using audio
for haptics just to work in applications
like video editing applications and
final cut pro or
adobe premiere after effects
they would automatically take this as a
different kind of soundtrack
and fit it in whether or not it was
haptics
or audio but they'd have to add more
stuff that would know
about haptics specifically is a
top-level mind type
okay i didn't hear you say
you you gave a good justification for
not using your application
or video but i didn't hear uh about
audio okay
yeah i i can respond to your your
questions and comments
the first point is haptics is not
typically encoded in the same way as as
audio
and point number two is that the the
whole point of our
mpeg iso bmf proposal which has
progressed to the dam stage which is a
draft amendment stage
is to treat haptics as a first order
media type
at the same level as or audio
and video and we actually have a working
implementation of our proposal that
works both on ios and android devices
that shows that you could have an mp4
file which now has three tracks
and and as far as your
pop pop point about the audio tools all
of those tools
use uh i mean they all
ingest mp4 files now it is true that
i mean once you have uh
once you have haptics as part of the iso
bmf
the standard uh they did they are
they are going to be a third track in an
mp4 file and there might need to be
changes
to be made in the media player engine
that now
recognizes the hacked box in in iso bmf
in the iso bmf header and make allowance
for that
but that's just the progression of the
standard it's no different than the next
version of
a any other and mpeg standard
now that being the case the the the
third point i would make is
haptics is or in many cases like if you
take the
ahap format they have for
format if you've ever looked at an ahab
file it's actually
a bunch of json so it's a very it's a
very
descriptive file format that basically
says uh
uh at what offset with respect to the
audio
timeline do you want to play out a
haptic effect
which could be a short click or a or a
buzz
or some kind of a transient and that and
at what percentage strength you want
that
transient to be played so those kinds of
things you
you can't really do with a with an
audio format and it's for those reasons
we
didn't want to shoot on a haptics into
any of the existing or audio audio
formats
we felt that you could get the most
flexibility
and benefit from the growing field of
haptics if it were its own
top level type
thank you swan um do you have
um an opinion on
how you think this could be best
dispatched or are you really
in a in a position where you really need
advice on that
uh i mean that seems like you are asking
me if i know the procedure in ietf
i mean i i would be looking to you for
that i mean what is the
what would you consider to be the next
step
i mean we we have we have we have made a
case and we have we have addressed all
of the comments we have gotten so far
i really appreciate the thorough
presentation i mean i think i asked the
question just to make sure
to refocus the conversation we're having
on that dispatch question and to make
sure
you know if you had an opinion on that
as some folks do when they're making
their
presentation so that was clear to the
group um but i want to make sure
i mean i i mean my my my question
back to you i'm i'm i'm sorry to respond
to a question with a question
is what is needed to convince this group
that this is a viable uh
uh top level type and does the group
think there is something else
missing if not obviously we would like
to
take this to the next team so sure i
mean fundamentally that will be driven
through iatf consensus and the the
purpose of this exercise here is just to
get it into
you know the room that will start making
those forms we will not reach
consensus and dispatch on the merits of
it um
so janna you're next if you can speak to
this part of the question i would
appreciate it we've only got about six
minutes left here
hi i can't hear you john jenna ingar
yes yes yes
okay um i i uh
i was going to ask and is probably a
question for the area directors or or
or the other dispatch chairs um given
that this draft has gone through one
iteration and there's been
presumably some engagement on the
mailing list is what i gathered now i'm
not paid attention to that
but does it are there other
folks besides immersion technologies
that are interested presumably they are
uh and are they willing to come here and
engage
uh at the idea the reason i ask this
question is because this depends
to me at least where this lands kind of
depends on who the other parties that
are interested are
i can read the draft and and to me it
makes sense to have haptics as a high
level thing but
it doesn't matter because i'm not the
one building this stuff so i'm curious
to hear there are others
who have expressed interest in having a
standard on this
if they've expressed an interest in
actually uh building
through the standard word to be
described because ultimately
uh what you're trying to do is generate
among people who are who are
engaged on the details of the draft and
for that you'd need people who are
not just interested on the side but are
actually implementing
and deploying this stuff are there
people like that
um
yeah i can i can respond to that
uh there is actually an iet
i mean an ieee effort which is ongoing
and that that i as i mentioned it's the
p191a which is a
haptics codex for the tactile
internet it is a and that that working
group
is actually in the process of finalizing
the
vibro tactile coding standard
for for the haptic haptic vibrotactile
coco coco coding standard
as well as a kinesthetic haptic
coding standard and so and they are a
number of
uh academic institutions as well as
companies who are active there and
they're actually
actually implementing those two
standards
that is one apple has been
is quite active in impact iso bmf
in fact the chair of the a mpeg
systems file format sub group is david
singer
he's from apple and apple has their own
haptic
format and they have actually been quite
active because they have an interest
they have a big business interest in
haptics so they've been quite active in
creating this
mpeg cfp which i mentioned the call for
proposals
now outside of that a a a little bit of
anecdotal evidence might be but we
immersion uh founded what is known as
haptics
what is known as the haptics industry
forum which has now grown to over 50
companies in the haptic space and they
are all
happy in that area okay yes one i don't
want to cut you off but i think we're
gonna have no i'm
i'm done move this along so um
stefan just jumped into the end that'll
have to be the end of the queue i'm
gonna ask people to be
real quick i think we're gonna be okay
on overall agenda time but we do need to
wrap this up
um so spencer you're next
thank you so the uh the thing i'm seeing
in the chat is basically
you know this is a top level
registration so maybe
a uh working group is appropriate for a
short-lived working group
is appropriate for that does anybody
disagree with that
then i'll get out of the queue
so i i believe barry has made and
offered a d sponsor on a couple of
occasions
i'd appreciate if maybe he would get in
the queue and and give his
his view on this as well but meanwhile
richard
you with me richard hey yeah it's just
busy granting permission prompts
um real quick comment here i think this
is a very natural 80 sponsor i think we
should not waste the bandwidth the
stabilization working group on this
uh ietf last call in the ensuing
discussion will be plenty to nail down
any
any of the questions that have been
raised here that's it
brass tacks i love it pete
no audio pete
we'll come back or we'll get your
comments reload
mo are you available
um i think the top level
uh type makes sense uh so i do support
that
on the question of where to dispatch to
is there any point in a work group
i think the relevant question is what do
you plan to do beyond the top level type
do you plan to have any of these uh
elementary stream formats
uh standardized within itf or do you
plan to have
uh payload formats um in in avt core
carrying these um or do you plan to
describe them
in sdp and then music i think that would
make it more relevant
of what level of integration this has
with other itf work
other than just the top level type
okay uh i can try to
answer that i mean at least one of the
four
uh formats we which have mentioned
is not going to be under ietf it's going
to be done by ieee and the second one
the hmpg will
probably fall out of the work that's
ongoing in
mpeg which leaves the remaining two the
he
m and the havc those are
possibilities for standardization under
ietf
but i can't speak to them just yet
because we don't know how it's going to
go
with the first two and one personal
comment
is there any format that supports
spatial haptics
uh encoded along with the video stream
so that you have spatially and
dynamically
variant haptic fields is that
standardized anywhere
not yet but but it's interesting
you should bring up spatial haptics
because that is part of phase two
of our mpeg cfp and it's so under the
overall
umbrella of mpi or mpeg in
immersive media so once phase two of the
ccfp is over we do
expect something on spatial haptics to
be standardized
but but it's probably the short answer
to your question is
it's too early to say
so i'm going to jump in real quick with
pete's comment from earlier that he was
unable to make
uh which is that he doesn't think a work
group is necessary
that a.d sponsored would be uh
reasonable
and some of the commentary we've seen in
the
chat is along the lines that a.d
sponsoring plus
calling out to the right experts as a
way to approach it
that's not my opinion that's that's just
that's relaying stuff i'm seeing in the
chat
that's great thank you ben stefan is
next um
cullen you jumped in the queue after the
queue was closed so i'm gonna
cut you but we do appreciate our
america's chairs in any event
stefan so um
two things one is i'm supportive of
getting this
top-level domain done that's my personal
comment
one comment as idf listen to
mpeg this activity
is by no means the most active but also
by no means the quietest
that mpac has there is a significant
amount of
industry interest visible that goes well
beyond
one startup company thank you
and we have barry and murray left in the
queue as our ids
yes um i i think this is
uh the the the primary discussion of
this will be
on the uh media types list i think we
don't need a working group to do this
but i think i i do want to defer to the
community for the decision on that
so uh i'm hearing mostly
people thinking ad sponsored is fine and
i'm good with that
and murray being next he'll he'll he'll
tell you whether
he's willing to be the sponsor or not
and he's a media type reviewer
anyway so i'm done
yeah i'm happy to sponsors if that's the
uh if that's the cons
but the community wants to handle this
it's fine with me
great
so the chairs are huddling in our chat i
think we're
we're hearing that that is the
most common view um and are leaning
towards
uh suggest uh suggesting that as the
rough consensus outcome of this meeting
does anyone want to stand up and say
that that's uh doesn't match what
they've heard
go ahead colin so yeah i would like to
have a chance to speak please as i was
in the queue before the tool dropped me
for the second time
is that okay yeah go ahead so
uh i think that this is draft is going
to require
i mean so first of all i think we should
do this okay no question about we should
move forward with some sort of topical
type
but the hint of magnus's question
several other peoples that have worked
in this space before
has been like there's some really
complicated tradeoffs because nothing's
perfect in this space the audio plus
video is already a disaster to explain
when you use one and when use the other
and this is going to expand that and i
think that
it's not that this drafts complicated
it's that the set of contradictory rules
we've already set up in this space
is going to be complicated and there's
going to be no way to get this draft to
meet every single one of our existing
rules simultaneously
and i think that that complexity is one
of the reasons that
i would argue that given we already have
very experienced media type people
expressed
that this shouldn't even be done at ietf
you may not want to have that whole
conversation on the itf last call list
which is where it's going to end up if
you 80 sponsor it now it's clearly the
ads call whether they want to sponsor or
not it's not even a matter of dispatch
dispatch has no input on whether it
chooses a sponsor yet
but i think the ads should think about
that conversation
and i think we need to have a way of
making sure we get consent get people
involved when the tools broken like we
need something better here this isn't
working
all right well i'm already cleared
himself out of the queue
ben christie do you have anything you
want to add to the wrap up here is this
a
case where we need to uh consult the
minutes and write a summary of where
we're at i
what i would take uh this has been i
think
with cullen's last comment there and it
it probably makes sense this is a com
the dispatch conversation needs to
continue
uh because i don't think we've
necessarily reached a resolution
uh so we probably need some discussion
but among the uh
authors chairs and area directors in the
uh
very short very in the very near future
and and see if we can resolve that but i
don't hear a resolution
right now between um 80 sponsored
and
some other higher wages presumably a new
working group
um i agree i think we should continue to
have that discussion and um
further input on the list is um i think
appropriate right
i'd like to stick one quick thing in in
response to culinary
um yeah i suppose and the ads can decide
to
ad sponsor anything they want to but one
of the reasons we have dispatches
exactly so
we will listen to what dispatch has to
say about these things
so thanks for your comments on that and
yeshwand i want to make it clear to you
that um the message i'm getting from
this is
we're going to do this it's just a
question of what do it in a new working
group
or just with ad sponsorship and that's
the only thing that we have to decide at
this point
okay and so i'm going i'm assuming that
i will
i will find out soon enough from one of
you gentlemen as to what the direction
is
yeah we'll be in touch please also you
know read the to specialists but we'll
certainly be different
yes absolutely with you as as awesome
okay just for the sake of agenda time we
need to move on
uh sergio are you with us yes hello
there you are hi hello is your
shout out next slide
yeah that's a slide please
okay so webrtc is still the the best
media transfer
used for streaming real time and audio
and video
but while it is possible to use other
transport for ingesting webrtc content
into a media server
when using webrtc both for ingesting and
delivering the
the media allows stream to have several
good properties but mainly you can work
on browsers for both
the publishing side and the viewer side
you
avoid to have protocol translation
between
something that it is not webrtc into
webrtc
this you have to do that you will most
probably
cause delay and have to
increase the complexity of the
implementation because you already are
supporting webrtc for
for streaming out so implementing
something different for assuming
and doing the protocol translation is is
going to cause
more more will will
be more difficult to implement i just
have webrtc foreign
and in most
you will most probably have a protocol
then
problems do with the codes for example
rtmp does not support opus at all so you
will have to do
transcoding between other codecs and and
the codex that
a webrtc supports and also
some feature that they are webrtc only
are
you will not be able to support it
end-to-end for example some servers may
decide to just do
a rtxor or flag or or effect
end-to-end just from whatever the the
the the sender supports that the
producer support to the viewer so
if you are doing other different
you are using other protocols for
ingesting media that that november
decision
some of these features are lost
so however if there is no current
uh standard signaling protocol that it
is say available to do this i mean the
most laws could be
simple like mpp
but they are not used for broadcasting
or streaming services and there is no
sign at all of any kind of um of
industrial option also they are complex
implement
so it is they will not likely be in use
at all
and in rtsp that this
could be the closest that we can have
for the broadcasting industry
and is not compatible with rtc sdp of an
asset model and also
a for for publishing the rtcp
record and doing a push from our rtcp
server is not very widely supported so
the consequence is that now it's
its service has its own implementation
of the of
uh custom adult protocols so you want to
have
an encoder that supports several several
webrtc instrument services each way you
will have to implement
a one protocol for one let's see a
streaming service so this is not
probably that it is going so something
that is going to happen
so at least in our opinion do we
the the consequences that we need a new
reference signaling protocol for this
use case
so let's slice this
so what would be the requirements from
this new streaming protocol
i mean it needs to be simple and simple
to implement
and also simply to to use i mean and to
be able to set the table
or to provision an encoder with this new
protocol
it will have to be as easy as you have
now with an rtp
a rtmp uh uri so
you will not have to do i you
should only be need to to point your
um your encoder with an uri
and have the the streaming and the
streaming up
uh the and for ingesting the uk
is quite specific so um
it is only required to you only require
to
to implement a set of webrtc
functionality
mainly that you only need to support
only the directional flows from
from the from the encoder to the to them
into the media server
typically the server is assumed is is
not
like in the typical webrtc use case that
you have peer-to-peers ball behind that
i mean in
in in if you are broadcasting to a
server the server is assumed either to
have
a public ip or is deployed in the same
private a
private network as the publisher so the
network the the
the not restriction is is is
less um difficult in in normal web
participate to appear
and also you don't need to to support a
negotiation that you are not going to
for example in rtmp or other protocols
that i
use for ingesting today you just send
the media from the start and if you want
to change
things yes stop and restart again you
don't need to support renegotiation
so um in
the requirements really has to be a full
compliance with rtc
and rtc web specs and must support
authentication of the
for the for the stream has to be
both subletting web browsers and knight
different colors
and if possible lower the requirement
readings on
[Music]
to be able to be supported easily by our
encoders
by reducing some kind of functionalities
that we have in webrtc's are reducing
the the number of
or the the possibilities that some
options that we have from webrtc
and to just narrow down the use case
and also to be able to to easily support
load balancing and restoration
to to be able to handle massive loads of
of a stream into a into an streaming
service
so next slide please
so that the profit the proposition
solution is something that it is
really really simple it is just a
doing an http with an sdp offer
to from from the encoder to to the media
server
and receiving the sap answer from the
from the
from the from the media server with this
sdp offer asset you set up a webrtc
and a session so then you so manage you
yes
establish the ice and get the less
connectivity and from then on you will
you
control the the state of the publication
with
the isan dtls
states so
you use you will use ice content
freshness for the testing if the
if the if the connection or the encoder
has
abruptly disconnected from the encoder
or the
media server and you also
use the dtls teardown in order to know
when the session has been uh normally
terminated normally by any other of
those both sides a authentication bay
will be a an authorization will be
supported
natively by http a
header under the adopted doctorization
header with a
video token so it is just exactly what
um i mean a standard http
stuff and also you will use you will
it will support http radiations for load
balancing
so next slides please
this is an example implementation of
javascript in javascript i mean it is
you can see you can get more simple than
that
and you just need to to set up the the
the track yes you create apple
connection and you
get the the offer just to do
a fetch with it then for sending the
post to the media server receive the
the answer and and pass it that they
said
remote description and once it is set
and you can control the
the state of the of the feed with just
by the
the on connecting state changes events
received so you have the connected
disconnected failed and closed
so let's like this
we have tried to
reduce the complexity mainly because if
it is going to be
implemented by the by
native encoders and hardware-based say
solutions i mean trying to reduce the
the requirements for implementing it was
important so
we have restricted that that um in a way
that
well first the stp bundle is always
required and rtcp maxine so we don't
support
nonviolent num bonding and also
no rtcp in different boards
and the server may implement
a slide and the codeman implements
must implement full full eyes
and the the other minor
change that we haven't done is that we
allow the
the encoder to just set up then
implement the
the active setup so not to have to
implement active and paste it
and the server must support both at a
thin
um as a
only as a spaces fan in case that
for example if they connect they are
interconnecting with something that is
supporting also at
past because it can has to support
atheist
or basic i mean we
if there is any other and
other um optionality that we're going to
remove from current web artists in order
to
to to make it easier to implement i mean
it will be welcome but this is only the
the ones that we have
a phone for now and i think that
it may be my last slide yeah
so the the conclusion is this that
it is i think this is the the lowest
thing that we can have for having webrtc
uh a easy protocol with
the the with a
standard that already available so it is
just use them
and in order to create something that it
is really simple and really
uh easy to implement
there has been some discussion if this
should be
a make a bit more complex to have and to
be able to control the state of this
this the of the stream by http rest or
something like that but
this is the the bare minimum that it is
that it is required to in order to to
have this same
working and with um
yeah now as a thank you for all that
before we open the queue
do you would you like to address the uh
the core dispatch question
um are you familiar with the possible
locations for this work
um or should we open the queue
suggestions on that from the floor
i'm i'm not aware what is the best scene
i mean
i think that this is really simple i
mean the draft is available and
it is really small so i think that the
the
at least my my opinion should be that
you should be the the whatever is
best for for having a fast solution
and i don't expect to have much
discussion i mean
i would not like to have to get this to
grow much more than
what it is so obviously address concerns
and things like that but not
make this much more complex that it is
today
okay great is there any commentary from
the group
bernard please
uh sergio i mean as you said you showed
this is a very simple
web page you know it's probably not a
lot more complicated on the server
either
so i guess my question would be why you
need to standardize the protocol given
that this
you know you just showed us the
javascript for it and you could
implement this pretty easily
mainly because if i going to to speak to
a hardware encoder
a band to implement it i need to to say
please
implement it so it is possible to use it
with
a more than one service i mean i already
have implemented it but
if it is not a standard it would be just
another thing that
and that my server implements but
no other server implements so if we can
agree that having this
as a specification within the encoder
well
they're going to can be say that i just
need to
i just super whip and
i mean it's a just
to try to be able to to
to have this more how to broaden the
adoption of it yeah so basically you
don't have control necessarily over the
server so it's not like you could write
your own
you know python or node.js server you
you're trying to get somebody else
who has kind of a okay i think i
understand it now
harold
uh thank you hello elvis john
google i think this
makes perfect sense the point of having
a document
is really to have an online
stable reference for it
there are a number of cases where people
tend to
not want to incorporate
someone's bright idea or someone's
unmaintained
npm or something so having a stable
reference for a really simple protocol
is probably a good idea
i mean karen and i were trying to do
something like this
way back when that uh failed
or it failed to get gain traction at the
time probably because we were trying to
incorporate it into the spec
instead of just having it that's a minor
item
so i think we should
just let this be published i think
informational publication as city
sponsored would be fine
so let's go
yeah so i think that i may not have
answered probably or
very carefully to today completely to
the bernard
question before i mean that the
situation in in
web in streaming is different with that
in common
webrtc cases that you have one vertical
that you control the clients and the
and the streaming services typically in
streaming
you will have a hardware encoders that
are
nor are even that works
is for example with a with you support
rtmp
you just implement rtmp and you are able
to talk to facebook to twitch
to to a broad range of
of service so the idea is here is the
same to be able to
to have it in for example in in obs or
in in the vendor for the for the encoder
is different that the one that is
deploying in the
the streaming service so if it is it is
as hara has said having a common spec
it allows to to people to be more
comfortable
when implementing something that they
know that they will be able to use
and connect to uh to any webrtc services
and instead of now that that
if i have to toggle with a vendor to
implement my
a protocol they say well why i have to
implement it
for you if it is only going to work with
your
streaming service
victor oh and bernard you're still
in the queue if you want to be in the
queue stay there if um it's just
leftover
oh can you hear me yes uh i guess
my main question is what the
implementation experience status for
this especially
for clients that are not web
it is yeah it is already implemented in
both in in
in janus and and in medusa i mean in in
in our in the melica's
streaming platform and we have
implemented in
in an obs fork that we are trying to to
get into
to the main one but the complexity is
having to is compiling the delivery of
rtc
but a part of the web browser we have
already been in in obs
and trying to get traction with the
people that it is implemented in
in however encoders
uh and the second more of a clarifying
question the understands that the urls
for this are https
[Music]
yeah the url is just an https url
um i just wanted to say i i think this
is a good
uh good thing we should be doing i think
there's some
still discussion to be had on how much
simpler it could be
i think there's still some optionalities
that could be taken out so
i kind of think that publishing it as is
might it needs another round of
discussion in terms of the detail from
my point of view but
i i think it's eminently implementable
even as it is
jonathan
intended this is intended to be a um
i know you wrote a a replacement
you know flash standardization
replacement for
our rpmp is this feature equivalent to
rtmp has used um
because one thing i did notice is it
didn't seem other than
you know the stp proper it didn't seem
as you wrote it terribly extensible
so i'm a little concerned about that but
i'm also going to ask you know is
is there anything that rtmp you know
does as used that
this doesn't do and if so where would
you think the extension points
would properly be
i have not understood the question could
you please repeat so is is this
feature is this protocol as you've
described that does it do everything
that rtmp
does we know your goal is to replace
rdmp
yeah well the goal is not to replace and
rtmp
i mean rtmp or the other broadcasting
protocol
can that will be and use for different
things i mean i don't expect this to
replace
and the current broadcasting solution
for ngs
but um the problem is that if for
example if you use rtmp for
webrtc first you are adding delay
because
you will have to to wake in in the best
case
when you don't have a buffet on the on
the encoder side
you will have to to have professor frame
before you start doing the packetization
and the for example rtmp does not
support opus so you will have to do
and transcoding from from aac to opus
so this is something that and i want to
avoid first yeah
rtmp does not support iframe requests so
i mean there is so i guess that makes
sense to me i guess my question is
are going the other direction if
somebody did want to say okay that
sounds great
i'm going to take my exis thing that's
using
you know um rtmp for this and replace it
with
whip would there be things that would
run into that you'd say oh well
i do need to i can't do this in web this
thing that i'm doing today
i don't know i mean the the main goal is
to have webrtc and from end to end
so i i i don't know if
this makes sense for example to ingest
from in webrtc
and and do hls out
i mean probably it can make sense i
don't know how that's compared to other
solutions that they all ended
but if you are done trying to do webrtc
uh for webrtc in jason webrtc out
there is no other solution that that
really works i mean for example if you
want to
to use uh
for example let's say if you want to
stream out again
a dc conference from our browsers and
then
you the scream in one of the
participants and trying to ingest it
into
a cdn to deliver it as a as um
as webrtc i don't think that there is
any any other way to do it
that they said ingesting webrtc
okay uh we'll have to cut the
queue after mo um and ted before you
start sergio can just get some clarity
on
um how much development work uh ietf
contribution do you think
needs to be done here as opposed to is
this say um
a static or informational document
you're really looking
you're putting forward for the purpose
of uh publishing in a static
reference to i mean i think i don't
think that there is any
i mean there are some open points that
for example
i know that for example lorenzon i would
like to have some
more control of how to disconnect the
session that not just
to rely on on the delays and ice because
it could be
on the worst case it will just you will
have to wait for the ice disconnection
for the and if in case of hybrid
disconnection only if the dhls terminal
is down is lost uh this is one
point still to be discussed and also i
know that team
want to to discuss some other analysis
to be removed
but a part of that i don't expect to to
to have much more work
and than what it is already in the
current spec
i appreciate that ted you're next
ted hardy speaking after he hits the
allow button again
um uh thanks uh i just wanted to to go
back to the requirements slide for a
moment uh when i look at the requirement
side
you have two things on here which may
make me
feel like maybe this actually does need
a working group to to think about and
that's
um when you have under the second bullet
server is assumed not to be behind
a net and also supports load balancing
and redirections
my my sense of this could actually
get a little bit more complicated than
you think if you think both of those are
always going to be true in these
situations
if if you have a subset of these
requirements where you know
it's always true then i think the right
thing to do
is to take it to the ise have it
published as a
this is how we are doing things for the
information of the community and stop
if you actually want a signaling
protocol that's going to be able to
handle
the load balancing and redirection
problem especially if you're going to
redirect across say
address families you have more stuff
going on here than i think you nest
you then you could certainly handle an
ad sponsor i think
if that's something you do want to kind
of hash out then you need
an actual working group to work through
this um and i have no objection to a
working group to work through this
but i think unless you're going to to to
take out some of that complexity
um by by removing some of these
requirements
you probably can't go the ad sponsor
group so i would
i would say from the dispatch questions
point of view
my answer is if if you really think this
is done go to the ise
if you don't and you really want to
handle this set of requirements you need
a working group
thanks yeah but first what i mean
support load balancing is
uh it is just relying on the the load
balancing
and radiation that http already supports
so i'm not talking about the load
balancing
about the media it's just about the the
load balances of the http
supporters for example you will be able
to to do an entity lcd post to
a factory and that that sends an already
relation to to that pal media server
so it is not anything more complex than
that
so sergio these might this might be
related to the heart of what i was
sort of asking for before ted
took his churn um if this is a situation
where we're really not going to give the
iatf change control over the document
and it's a
static done thing then you know the ise
is the the common recommendation in
those circumstances
um but it it sounds like we start to go
down that road and then we talk about
like a number of
fairly tricky things that actually um
probably require
a bunch of different viewpoints and you
know are more suitable really for a
for a mini working group if you will
instead of um even for ad sponsored so
those two things are actually fairly far
apart from each other on the spectrum
and so like some clarity on that might
help us get us to a a recommendation
while yeah ponder that mo you're up
yeah so on the surface uh it seems like
a good idea if i understand right
you want to have simple devices be able
to
uh have have a way to push things up
even when they can't run the full-blown
uh full-blown browser with arbitrary
javascript
and you want servers you want services
to always expose some common ingestion
point
um but the thing that i question is why
do you think this has anything
with ingestion but you know seemingly a
much much much bigger
uh demand would be for receiving webrtc
real-time streaming
and that hasn't happened people service
providers are not
letting you know arbitrary devices hit a
simple url you have to have a
you know an app based integration just
to receive
streaming from those services um so it's
i
question whether or not um you know
why haven't smart displays been able to
simply put
a uri of whatever streaming service you
want um and and run and go with that
instead of doing the full integration
with the specific service
i think the same kinds of problems may
hit this if you think that all services
just have an easy ingestion point that's
interoperable without any work on the
device or app developer
i'm skeptical that we'll specify
anything well enough to
actually make that work the uh
i completely agree that it is also that
something that i am working on
but i think that there are different
issues and then
the the target is different i mean
for for in for the ingestion and the
stream
implement that are related to two
different people i mean for example
to be to talk about ingest i have to
talk with encoder people
and to talk about the view and the debut
website i have to talk about
mainly for example web browsers to be
able to support
an sap with something url
in the video src and
to be able to set up a view only the
stream so
well the solution may be similar i
prefer to to to handle them
independently and but i i think that it
is something that it is also needed
but if yes i don't want to
the solution may be similar but the the
use cases is different so i would prefer
to have it in in different places
great thank you for that um
okay i'm reading the uh the chat and the
chair chat over on the side trying to
decide what we've heard here
um
i think there's
still a little bit of confusion here but
people are leaning towards
um trying to discuss on lists and build
what a charter for a
small mini working group might look like
to try and give clarity to the work that
would actually be done
on under iatf change control
and of course we can dispatch things
directly from the list
um should that look like you know
suitable work
that the ietf wants to take on and the
vads want to charter
um but i think that's probably the next
step this has been i think a very useful
discussion
i'm glad we've got we've had it um but i
i think that probably needs to be done
to to crystallize what we're
asking um we got probably like three
more minutes we can spend on
commentary if folks want to react to
that you know next step
plan including sergio
most importantly
mo you still queue on purpose
okay sergio would that work for you we
could try and uh
build a charter a proposed charter and
that might clarify
our our thinking uh whether that's right
or not
yep okay
we'll wrap up this and move on to the
next topic thank you everyone for your
your time thank you
think this is where i need to
do my little zip and non-linear zipping
around in the slides
we'd like to take a uh a moment in um
each art area meeting um as we're now in
the art area section of our
agenda uh to mention um
some new working groups and when they
when they next meet um we have email
core and asdf which have been chartered
since the last time we met i believe
http
api has also been chartered since last
time we met
and they meet um on friday morning
um and i'll highlight the other
interesting meetings located down here
and then if anyone would like to
step up and offer a 30 second you should
really come to this meeting
uh testimonial uh for any of these or
something else you think would be of
interest to this working group i would
encourage you to do so
we have sec dispatch gen dispatch the
iab open
the rfc editor future development
program um
and shmu which is of continued interest
to all of us i am sure
there's also one buff this week
medina's uh mac address device
identification for networks and
adapt or application services
um they are meeting on wednesday
um does anyone know isn't that awesome
sorry isn't that scream also that's
frame is also a day one good catch
karsten you're first yeah i just wanted
to
quickly point out there's another new
art working group the jsonpath
working group that is picking up this
format from 2007 for doing xpath
like things on jason do you know when
they're meeting
uh later today so it's not today
thanks pete we had a lot of people in
queue but you all left
um am i making sounds this time
yes excellent um
just uh ten seconds jen dispatch the
only
item on our agenda is an update
to uh it's 7
2 2 1 which is the rfc about how
working groups may wish to adopt
documents or
unadopt documents so not
terribly exciting stuff but you're all
welcome to come and chat about that if
you like
thanks
all right last call for other
announcements
okay hearing none alexi you have our
last presentation
of the day floor is yours
hello can you hear me yes
sounds good um yeah i this is the most
obviously the most uh interesting
presentation today so i'll try to be
quick
um so bernie and i uh are working
on um
mdkg in uh lamps on header protection
for smile and pgp and this is sort of
came out of
this um whether a signal
saying that a particular message is
being encapsulated
um is useful and we want to talk about
whether it's used for another context
next slide please
right so um yeah that's that's that's
good
um basically um
when protecting headers um
we need to make a copy of um
the header fields um
within signature or in encrypted block
um so they basically sort of need to be
duplicated
um and the way this is described in
s prime is just says to wrap it in
message rfc822
which is unfortunately ambiguous
because it's unclear whether it's
afforded message or whether it's
a mechanism for encapsulating headers
and the message next slide
so this is expanded example how this
might look like
so there is a outer unprotected header
a little wrapper
and then the copy of it in a header and
the message itself on
the signature next slide
so um the draft at the moment says
that in order to distinguish from
forwarded message
uh there is an extra parameter on the
content type
which is forwarded like yes or no um
there was some discussion on the mailing
list martin's suggestion
suggested that maybe content disposition
is actually a good fit for this
for example content disposition online
uh
maybe a new content disposition type
like encapsulated to make it specific
for this purpose um and there was also a
suggestion to maybe
uh have a new content content semantics
had a feel to to signal that
the first two um
proposals have advantage that they sort
of work
very well with imap because
all parameters to content type and
content disposition are returned
within the protocol the last one doesn't
work as well
but happy to hear opinions on this
next slide
so uh question for this group is are
there
are any other
use cases other than so basically is
this
uh very s mine pgp specific
or are are there other ways
that this can be used and
um what's the best mechanism for doing
this
i think what's the next slide
yeah questions
uh please john levine
no audio john
we can see you
still not
cannot hear you why don't we give braun
a chance and we'll come right back to
you john next
by approval of things uh content
disposition feels like the right thing
to me it feels like that's exactly what
this is is
a disposition for the message rather
than the content type of the message
but other than that it seems like
something that could be generally useful
thank you
why don't we do uh daniel next then
we'll
give john another chance john are you
ready
still no audio
all right dkg hi folks
um this is dkg i'm with aclu
um so i've been trying to figure out how
to use
this uh forwarded equals no or
kind of distribution or anything like
this in terms of header protection
and the the difficulty is that
we can't we can't tell
old clients that don't know about it to
respect it this way
um right but sort of by definition that
the already deployed clients are
behaving differently
um so i'm fine with making an indication
that
you know yes this is exactly how i meant
it and it wasn't supposed to be a
message that was an attached message or
a forwarded message
um but there's still going to be a
challenge when dealing with
the large number of legacy clients that
are out there
um so in terms of uh i mean we'll be
discussing how to protection
in lamps i think tomorrow um
i think that there are other options for
how to do
uh header protection um
including stuff that's actually been
deployed i mean enigma has been doing
and several others have been doing
header protection uh in a different way
um that has some level of backward
compatibility
uh that you makes things work with with
um
with existing clients so you know i'm
fine with any of these ways of doing it
but i think it doesn't
fundamentally solve the problem of
dealing with
uh of interacting with the legacy client
and we don't know when you're sending
the message
whether you are interacting with a
legacy client or not so i just think
this is a very challenging
space to work in and i'm not sure that
this is the right spot to do the
signaling
but any of the proposals seem fine to me
[Music]
it says i have audio now now can you
hear me yes
oh good um the other another use case is
mailing lists and dmarc everybody's
favorite mailing list thing
um back when we were trying to fix the
itf list to work around dmarc one of the
things i tried
was um wrapping single messages very
very much the same way this
this thing does it so there's an outside
header that passes dmarc and the inside
header actually describes the message
um that's basically it's basically the
same scenario
my question is why adding
it seems to me this like this is the the
message the
the mime type here would be like message
encapsulated rather than adding a flag
to message rs8
rfc a3822 and i agree with dkg that the
current
behavior of muas with any sort of
attached or wrapped messages is pretty
poor
so on the one hand i mean i
imagine partly it's like well message
encapsulated is likely to work worse
than message yeah message global but
message global already works pretty
badly
this is not a hell i'm this is not a
hill i'm planning to die on it's just
it's mostly a question
okay thank you good good question i i
tend to agree with you
that um it's tricky
harold you're up next yeah i feel like
old man yelling at cloud or something
but
multi-part signed was never ever ever
or a message signed was never ever ever
ever
ever intended for forwarding
so the fact is the muas that this
display this as a forwarded message
are begging so we can either yell at
them to fix the bug
or we can add more markers that mean
exactly the same thing
and then tell them to fix the bug so
i don't think this this is solvable by
by by adding more markers that mean the
same thing as what we intended in the
first place
can we just get the bug fixed
philip as of now you get the last word
we'll
see if anyone gets in behind you uh
i i support doing something on this i
mean
i i think everybody in the queue and
ever you know i think everybody's played
with
s mime has proposed something of the
sort
over you know the past 25 years and
there's
always been the problem of the legacy s
mime
clients don't do what they should or
what we would want them to
i think there's another piece that comes
up and that is
when we talk about headers there's
really two types of message headers
there's content headers you know there
are headers that really should have
always been part of the content
and there are routing headers and
[Music]
smtp just smushed the two together
and so maybe what we need to do is to
disentangle those two
and say which are the two things
and which are different before we try
and you know and uh fix rfc8281
before trying to layer more stuff on top
um because you know as i said
we've tried this before and it didn't
get very far
thank you
any wrap up thoughts alexi
i have lots of good comments sorry i i'm
sort of still waking up in
my time zone so um yeah i'll uh
i'll review the comments and
we'll continue you know if you're
interested in the header protection
topic specifically please come to lamps
which is tomorrow
awesome thank you thank you
um so the that completes uh our
structured agenda we do have
um 10 minutes available if there's any
other business that's available to the
art area
anyone would like to step forward with
otherwise
we can conclude
braun
didn't um didn't get ready in time for
this meeting but
the there was discussion that i emailed
the list a few weeks ago about
a time format basically updating rfc
so since we have this time and no one
else seems to want to discuss anything
does anyone want to
to talk about where they think that
might be best put
so the the concept is to add
basically sigils afterwards that include
both the time zone that a time is in
um and also the calendar format it's in
if it's not gregorian
so that there are other this people seem
to be moving towards the idea of
having a gregorian time stamp always but
then saying it transpose this into this
calendar system to process it
and keeping that sigil with the time
because that's the safest
for round tripping things and this
this work is coming out of the
javascript working groups amongst other
things
i'll jump right in here and didn't we
try to address this in calder calyx
cal something about
somewhere in the in the late 90s
we've done uh recurrence rules and r
scale
which is to say that this recurrence
rule applies
in a a different time system than
gregorian
but what hasn't been addressed is the
format so
the the iso 8601 whatever it is sorry
not that one
um yeah time time for rfc three three
three nine time format year
year dash month month day day and then
t and some minutes and seconds but what
we don't have
is the ability to say what time zone
that's in
in that string and so it's stringifying
a time
with a time zone and a calendar system
and it's working out exactly what format
we want that to be in
so they have just to bring this to itf
so all the proposals for doing that
failed the last time
yeah well it was a stupid idea to leave
out
thanks braun thanks harold uh
neil got time for one more i think here
just going to yeah clarify on this yes
the tc39 group
um developing ecmascript javascript that
are
currently looking uh for this i think we
do need a serialization format
um for uh dates with time zones
lots of people do this and if we don't
define something then we'll have lots of
different compatible versions out there
it seems an obvious extension to
3539 to me
so braun if people want to explore this
further what list do you think i mean do
you think this is dispatch or
it's probably just i think probably
calcify is is the
sensible place to discuss that given
that all the other calendaring works
there
yeah okay so if you're interested in
continuing this discussion
uh calcified sounds great yeah the other
other possible places tz data
i'm subscribed to both so i'm sure i'll
see whatever you say
thanks thanks for raising it
hey ben given that we're wrapping the
meeting up and this is your last meeting
as
chair would you turn your video on so
people can like wave goodbye to you
so i can i can wave goodbye to you i
just i want to tell people like how hard
uh ben has worked at this job i mean i
think
the most important part of the dispatch
chair job is actually
reaching out and integrating folks who
just have no idea how this
idf process works and then
it's just an exemplary
instance of of making that work as a
chair and so i've learned quite a bit
from him and i
i really appreciate it so we'll be sad
to see you go
but um you know the the istar is always
happy to have you
so thanks ben and thank you everyone for
a good meeting and we'll see on the list