hey eric did you say something
yeah you're not coming out clearly eric
maybe you're very far from the
microphone
um it shows me audio feedback in the
little
uh ui but um no i was just saying
no hello yeah
okay i think we can get started i
believe yeah
all right uh folks welcome this is the
itf
dmm working group i'm shree gandaveli
and with me is saturday shawn
is also there okay so the agenda for
today
see i think before that i think uh some
a few things we need to take care of one
is uh
the the ipr rights i hope you
are able to see the see the slides on
the
itf's position on the ipr declarations
and the general rules and this is the
noteworld statement
you're running the itf meetings are held
in certain
rules and regulations these are
documented in these
specific documents and a few other
things
you don't need to take care of blue
sheets anymore there's a virtual meeting
so that's of note takers any note takers
any anybody willing to take notes
please post a note please
write something
folks any no takers
how do they respond they'll write
somewhere in the chat window i guess
right
carlos alex anybody
uh
i just want to make sure they don't know
how to respond or is it
nobody's interested
okay pablo thank you okay pablo
is there not any other one more one more
person please
oh thanks pablo
thank you yeah
you need one more no taker please
all right we can get started
okay now thanks pablo for that and now
a few things i think
our last idf meeting was itf
106. honor 7 was cancelled 108 we did
not schedule it so
between 106 and now i think a few
updates
the key things is we i think uh
the distributed mobility anchoring draft
is published as
rfc818 contracts to the authors
i think it was in the queue for a long
time but uh it
had to go through several revisions and
even re-write
so but thanks for all the efforts
all the authors and also
you know premium v6 extensions for dmm
is also published as rfc rfc8885
thanks again to the office i think uh
so that's that's the key update and now
on the working group the documents i
think uh
we have the user plane protocol uh and
architecture analysis document
that's uh it's coming out you know
pretty good
uh that's in a great shape in general i
think uh
last time i believe the authors were not
ready for the last call or
at least you know i thought but now we
should
probably in the next you know now it
should be able to move forward
the other document is segment routing
srv6 the mobile user claim
this one there was a dependency on the
spring document i think now those
dependencies are clear
getting cleared and i think now we
should be
able to take this forward i think uh
there are two other documents related to
fpc
i think this one
there hasn't been much progress uh
charlie
and lyle two of the key authors are
not active and charlie retired so we are
having a few issues on this one we did
talk to our area director eric on this
right we promised to see show some
activity on this but uh that did not
happen
so for now you know we are not making
any decision on this yet but
uh we want some more time to reach out
to charlie and laurel and uh
finally make a decision but but it's so
sad the document is almost done it's
just that
that one last push i think that's
one in fact all we need is just a you
know
publishing the document a new revision
and
somebody willing to you know address any
comments ideas
through the iesc process uh but
i think uh tremendous amount of efforts
went into this
this document i think that's uh it will
be unfortunate if you leave it out here
but uh
but let's see what comes up now
this is where we are with respect to the
working group documents
right i think now today's
topics i think you know there are you
know
updates on the the two working documents
and
two other new topics and
also there is a
rechartering discussion we would like to
you know uh
discuss that at the end of the
presentations like to see like you know
i think
overall this working group is chartered
to do two things right
overall what are the topics that we
actually do for the distributed mobility
management that
we are somewhat you know getting closer
to completion
right the srv6 work is a major thing
that's left out
but at least the other documents were
done
and we also are chartered to support any
mobile ipv6 pm v6
v6 extensions as an ongoing process that
was the
agreement when we form the working group
so so
that is there but uh overall for the
near topics we'd like to have
you know see some interest i think you
know more last i think a
few months we have been you know the
terribly really bad actually with
respect
to working group activity i think it's
more than the
the participants even the chairs we were
not active i think uh it's inside a
perfect example as how
not to run a iet working group but i
think hopefully
you know i think if you bring some focus
back and like with some new topics and
if there's proper interest we want to
take it forward
at least that's the that's the goal and
uh
with that i think um today's topics
first topics is uh the transport network
availability
for 5g uh uma
is going to present this uma are you
there
okay i'm here so okay
let me you know share nothing once okay
i'm trying to see what's the best way to
show you i guess
um
you can see this i probably are still
seeing the
uh i think the 5g usb analysis forks
have a subscribe
okay you're able to see the sling that's
what you see
um i can see that today is pretty deep
but uh
i don't see that right
okay one once again just let me make
sure
okay i don't know just
okay let me stop
let me open the local copy and then
share once again
um you can now see
hello uh hi hi i couldn't see your
slides you want me to present myself
yeah go ahead actually
so let's do it
uh s3 i'm not sure how to you have to
give control to me or
how is it one second just
okay cool now i can see it you're
screaming did you see something i
couldn't hear
no no okay yeah yeah let's
all right okay please go ahead
uh again it's a blank screen it's a
black screen now
oh yeah yeah good good first idea okay
okay so uh i'm going to talk about hi
this is uma i'm going to talk about
transport network availability for 5g
and uh just give a recap so i'm going to
talking mostly about the updates that
have been done
uh last two months but to give a recap
for the people
who were not there earlier so uh release
15 23 5 0 1 5 0
specified 5g architecture and various
mobility procedures for ue which covers
uh
4g 4g case ssc mode 1 and move to mode 3
which are specific to 5g right so uh
make before creating ssd3
but the problems are so these uh uh
there is no transport network awareness
in the scenarios right so
uh if they care about ran uh their radio
access network and the core network
but the transport network is not
factored uh so
why this has to be factored because some
of the use cases where here we are at 5g
regular uh network cases uh the
transport network
and sla guarantees transport network
need to be factored
both on f1 new and npn interfaces uh
so it is difficult to the current
approach it's difficult to provide sl
guarantees end to end
um so this is uh this is this framework
addresses that aspect
and the second thing is there's an under
specified
mapping function from three pdu sessions
or to the uh network underlying paths uh
it could be
any underlay it's not specific to a
particular underlay like rsvp
sr or any versions of sr but there is no
underlying mapping function so this has
to be defined because
when the mobility happens from uv uh it
has to be uniformly configured across
network
so this aspect also has been addressed
in this draft
on x right please
yeah okay so
so this draft was first presented in
july 2018 ietf 102 in montreal
uh this mobility function aware
underlying transport has been defined
here
and mapping to various underlying
transfer technologies
initially like you know we laid out a
lot of stuff also we talked about lisp
and other
uh uh technologies at the time 2018
we're talking about uh
uh ila based mobility and other
scenarios but we
eventually in our number 2001 we just
focused on the
specific two aspects that is how uh how
the framework can be defined how the
underlying transport mapping can be
defined so these two aspects we boiled
on
uh in november 2018 um both in and three
online interfaces we started
n9 is the new interface in 5g uh how the
cost is being carried in both these
interfaces has been defined
missing transport network related items
like slice selection and integrated
approach
there are two approaches as defined in a
backward compatible way in 4g
deployments which addresses the 4g
deployments and eventually
which can be migrated to 5g uh both
cases have been defined in section 2.2
and eventually section 3 some updates as
for
uh comments received from uh from the
list and offline
in uh 2009 ieta 105 we further
uh we got a lot of feedback time in one
of my time
so we have contributions from although
star we are working on the rant
landslide mostly
and nokia for future wireless and
interdisciplinary so they have a lot of
discussion a lot of contributions so
uh their content have been added and as
a co-authors have been all set as
co-authors
and uh that time or there were we
because we couldn't come up with a
unified approach so there were two
solutions
set for the time in zero four version
next slide please
us even eventually these two solutions
got harmonized in zero five
uh simplified solution approach and uh
we left with the one
outstanding issue how to carry the
transport network context identified in
the packet
so we don't want to specify anything srv
specific because
uh the network some parts of the network
cannot do we may not use
sr at all or some layer 2 network so we
we have a lot of ideas from the working
group that time so finally eventually um
settled up with one option which is
neutral to the trafficking moving in the
transport
so uh we also added uh further
refinements in zero six
by john and all the updates and some of
the comments received in the list
uh some of comments received on the
november 2000 singapore
meeting has been presented in the list
next
so a recent comment summary so now sorry
unfortunately we couldn't present last
uh two sessions because there's no dmm
session and also we're also not active
um
various other things that were happening
uh so unfortunately we couldn't uh uh
progress further but when we asked two
months back uh
chase asked to uh discuss in the working
group and uh we
mentioned it and a couple of folks
responded with a couple of comments
uh one is from one comment is from pablo
uh related to simplifying section three
uh section three and appendix
uh which is the new mobility scenarios
with the tv mechanism ppr
uh second comment is additional ranges
texan this demand scenario for
enterprise 5g use cases
they're working on so they wanted to um
extend this to end-to-end scenario where
your session generation is not happening
on the edge rather than
on the cloud right so in this case n2
under service they want sdm sd1
extensions you want security
um to be added to the range of some of
the ranges defined in the draft
uh finally some a couple of comments
created inconsistent descriptions and
list items have been also asked by
kaushik and
these are the summary of the comments
okay so uh uh what we changed to zero
eight so
uh the last region uh so the main
section is
from pablo to take care of the public's
comments uh we uh
we just simplified the section three and
uh just to show the applicability of the
framework
on different underlays uh this is not
meant to be exhaustive on the list like
you know
we discussed couple of underlays how
this can be done
so this similarly uh any new underlying
transport mechanism can be used
with this framework in a mobility domain
similarly appendix
which is related to ssc modes various
mobility scenarios
uh have been described and you know that
that pablo asked to remove that into a
surprise section because that is mostly
focused on ppr
how that can be done so this all been
moved to a different
raft ppr and that is appropriately
referenced in
various parts of this draft
unfortunately both the drafts are
uploaded on the same day
i could not add the reference into this
draft so
so unfortunately i couldn't do that so
that's one thing that's the last thing
that's spinning on this
uh yes and other ranges says kaushik
asked we are
we added the text to uh define the
additional ranges for the security
uh with slicing like you know some
slices they want security as a key
parameter
so uh this is in addition to uh what
happens
from the g note b emits the packet with
ipsec in cases of it cannot be done
uh this can be done in the pin in front
of it
uh and the comments are also this next
i think uh we were ready from other
point of view undercover the common side
from zero section
zero six version itself but uh
unfortunately you can follow up
as i specified earlier so uh current
version is explained at us for the
comments received uh last month and uh
and that been all addressed so we feel
uh from other side we wanted to
ask for working reproduction and i want
to continue further continuous work
based on the amount of uh efforts this
has been already
done on this
okay thanks ma
so any questions comments
hi pablo right yeah
do you have it you're telling me to
yourself okay let me unmute yeah
okay yeah please go ahead okay so
um first many thanks to the authors
uh for all the work on this document and
improving significantly the document
is the last reason and i do have
two comments um so the first comment
is written on the scalability in section
2-3
and basically you say that an mpnc
represents a slice with a given qs
configuration and a transport path in
between two particular
predictive etfs um and so basically what
you say is that the
in section two you say that the mtnc
idea
space is actually scaling a score to the
number of sites
um identifiers so with 50 minutes is
enough
um now the question that i have for you
is that
if i do the math if you have three
traffic classes
and 200 gps for example you have already
burned
all of these 16-bit ideas
and the question that they have for you
is have you considered decoupling the
slice id from the heart id because to me
it seems like
you could really only i mean one way
that you can improve scalability is just
by encoding the
an identifier for the slides instead of
an identifier for this license
uh pablo i think you're breaking up but
what i'm understanding i just want to
let me repeat that what i'm
understanding so
so you're saying that identify space is
not enough with empty and say id defined
here
with number of ups that's what you're
saying
so i'm saying that yes i think it is not
enough
and my question is why don't you
decouple the slice from the path
id oh no no okay
so path id you don't have to uh so see
you you don't have to
it's not coupled at all right so so what
is
done is uh when the packet is emptied
from gmp or upf
uh the source ports are representative
of this la the information ssd
information
so that information you can use it uh in
the pe to
configure policy if you are using sr
srv6 or sr mpls whatever the technology
you use underlying
use a configuration policy in the
ingress node
and use those codes to map it so there's
not directly with path id no
so if you have a path id it will you can
manage it better
but it's not required you can manage it
better
uh from management plan you can manage
it better but it's not essential
okay so then just to confirm the mtnc
idea space is
independent from the number of upfs you
have then
right right that's correct but there was
in section i forgot the section there
was a calculation
john has done uh the typical scenario
how many
are required and you know how this is
justified
there was a text based on that and you
can see that if it is
if you have any questions i'm happy to
answer there but that has discussion has
been done in one of the versions
and we added specifically text for that
okay thank you yeah okay
oh i know is next oh no yeah
can you hear me yes yes right
just just checking this that
observation that in in this work group
they're working on
network slices and and they have also
the framework
this looks fitting into that but i think
later on
when you develop further this it it
would be good to
have in in line what what this working
group is doing otherwise we are just
acting
more confusing here okay so i can i can
take this
somebody uh commented on this and the
working room calls in the mailing list
so yes so this work has been started
with you for almost one half year before
this workbook is done i started i think
this working group i am following this
closely what this working group is
doing uh both the framework document the
definition document
they are not specifically targeting of
course the 3gpp use case is there but
it is a more generic framework idf slice
what is idea of slice
and what is uh required but we are
talking about two two two points that's
being addressed in this draft is
a little bit orthogonal but uh but only
thing common is eventually once the
young models are defined there uh if
if working group accepts this draft we
can
extend that whatever the framework they
come up with we can extend
whatever the mapping scenarios we
creating here we can add it there we are
not conflicting with what we are
generically proposing if you have any
particular comment if you think you are
conflicting anything you can we i i'll
definitely take your comment seriously
and take off
okay but i see you thank you
okay all right so yeah i think uh
thanks uh uh thanks for the sir so
uma did you present this in other
working groups like transport or other
any other
groups now way back we presented
i'm not remembering uh no we only
presented in dmm
we thought of presenting no i think this
working group
john has presented i believe oh no no
wait a minute yeah john has presented in
peace working up in a different format
oh yeah now i remember so john has one
contribution in last year
so he was presenting in peace but rather
than it's mostly 3gpp specific
uh so we he merged that portion that
part of the draft into this draft
so yes it's kind of kind of presented in
waste by john
yeah all right okay i think uh yeah
where we'll get the work done
probably that's you know a separate
discussion but in general i just
you know i think it's good to get some
feedback from other groups as well
right so i think so you are suggesting
authors are suggesting we you know issue
an adoption call is that what the
you know ask is yes that's that's what
we're asking based on the
effort that has been undergone and you
know the consensus we have on this
document so i think this is
not a good starting point for further
progressing the work i feel
we feel okay so maybe let's do a quick
poll on like how many people have read
the draft uh
sort of the sound can you issue a
polaroid thing please
show up hands too
okay john is saying he presented only in
dmm okay
okay so eight numbers
okay
all right people i have
all rendered okay so
we will discuss with eric and uh in the
mailer
adoption
okay thanks sri thanks
okay
okay so do you see my
screen now
um
oh yeah
hello
[Music]
all right let me let me try this during
the preparation i
think we can have a voice from yeah
in the queue oh yeah
oh okay
hello can you hear me yes
okay
so um
so who is presenting
mia i see yeah
uh yes so still i cannot share my screen
okay
let me see if i can do that that's fine
let's
just
it's not good to share so
can you try this
this is
what is the context
okay then i will i will share
how about now
do you see the screen
um
no it says permission error
are you
restriction ah perhaps
i would use
let me try
what you should
but nothing
i checked the privacy but there's no
okay yes wow thank you
thank you thank you sorry for taking
time
thank you very much so um thank you for
your time this draft discusses
the architectural implication um
to supplement the srv6 mobile user
playing draft
which is um dmm working group document
so agenda is
so we revisited the objective
of the draft and then architectural
discussion and then
we are discussing about the
exemplification
of network sizing edge computing and
urlc
so next slide please
so we have revisited the objective
of this draft and basically this
document discusses
a solution approach and its
architectural benefits
of common data playing across domains
which includes ue ip transport data
center
applications and across
overlay underlay
so this approach maybe in a sense
contrary to
proposals that the underlying
transport can be anything but it is an
approach to make the network as flat as
possible and make making it more
suitable for the distributed mobile
deployment model
next page please
so the diagram shows a typical
example of the mobile network so gtp
session
from ue to mobile anchor upf
in this diagram and mpls or segment
routing
is used in the transport network and
vxlan or geneve or whatever
for segmentation in data center
and the vlog id is used as a
correlating id and that firewall
is used for
for the address conversion and
perimeter security
next slides please
and this architecture has some
limitations
so this um tunnel based architecture
is not optimized for edge or distributed
computing
and gtp session termination uh could be
a
scaling bottleneck and it's also not
optimized for any to any communication
and
the security model is perimeter security
um next right please
for future distributed uh mobile network
uh where access is heterogeneous
and data is spread
ubiquitously by multi-cloud
or distributed edge cloud the
architecture
need to change
oops we use
this
right
sister sort of take a moment
okay
yes sorry for the trouble
thank you so for the future distributed
mobile network
um access should be more heterogeneous
next
next slide yeah so actually should be
heterogeneous
and data should be spread ubiquitously
by
multi-cloud or distributed edge cloud
so we are aiming more simple
on flat architecture by communalize data
plane
across domain and ovary underlay
next next page please
so as some example for
applicability of 5g mobile network
um so the one is network slicing
so basically flat network can
eliminate pec hierarchy
so the current issue that is that uh
certain extra id
like viral id is needed for segregating
traffic and mapping
it onto this designated slice
and the pe and pec connect connection
is a single quantum failure so some form
of the redundancy is required
but
if upf or mobile anchor can
belong to ip network it can directly
interact with networks license and or
make applications
on multi access its computing
applications
uh by the way it does not mean we must
eliminate
pce hierarchy we can still have
domain boundary or a pc hierarchy
depending on the network design
but to flatten the network
could have some advantages next
things please
and for edge computing edge
or distributed computing needs some
application framework
and data plane will be simple
and should be easily
implemented in compute stack
so that application can interact with
the
data brain using next
page please
and for you our llc
um 3gpp pr237
section 6.4 addresses the issue
on how to support redundant data
transmission
via single upf and signal
land node but but overlay
terminal cannot ensure the disjoint path
also the replication and merging point
would be
the single point of failure
in this context as well um srv6 is
simpler to support
height sla and you already received
furthermore um srv6 supports in-band
telemetry or
timestamping for latency monitoring and
control
so it could be a big advantage
in terms of monitoring and controlling
the latency
next slide please
um so this documentary discussed
our solution approach with system b6 and
it architectural benefits
of common data playing across domains
and across
across overlay underlay we
believe that this approach makes the
network as flat as possible
and enable distributed mobile deployment
which has advantage for major 5g
requirements
like network slicing edge computing and
url
erasing and
so this proposes the data frame will be
more
simple and flat and we'd like to ask
dmm working group to add this document
thank you very much thank you
thank you mia so i think
you know you don't have enough time to
have any questions on this but uh
yeah now discussions
okay
okay it's here
shhh
one
so dancing
i want to share
unfortunately
can i ask a quick question uh or no i
don't know
right so i think it's a good summary of
where services
can be used uh but i i think i didn't
understand the relation between the
overland under the case right so overlay
is the gtp
so is it referring to the asytarou's
draft where overlay can be removed
with srv6 or it's focusing on only on
the underlay part i think from the last
layer it shows that both are over and
underneath
what you you're saying about overlay or
regular
i i just want to be clear on that one
okay it could could be used for
controlling
the overlay as well
okay so that is the uh satoru's draft
right i think that's working with draft
where gtp can be replaced with srv6
yeah can be okay okay okay thanks
be displaced to the gtp
one of the candidates to provide the
choice for the operator
to use whether the mobilizer plan is gtp
or services
okay breathe
can you hear me right yeah i can
so i i'm i am the presenter q just to be
able to
share my screen can you give me access
to share my screen
because i'm next right on agenda
yes yes okay good so i'm wondering if
the
statement of common data planet was
an application interaction uh with the
application interaction is the intent to
know that the
applications are part of the routing
fabric so that that are also
involved in distribution of segment
identifiers
um fortunately this could be um
your boy is a breakup you've got to chat
for the question how is
our applications interacting with
this common database are they part of
the routing
or not
i understand the question um the
how the application can interact
with the yes um
yes so the application needs some
um framework or programming
framework or programming platform and
such
platform need to support the data frame
and if the data plane is
supported by the compute stack then it's
um it becomes easier
to to be the application platform
that's what i mean
carlos
yeah you can leave me here my screen
you can get him
can i can i have a spin myself
um
okay
okay perfect so uh i'm carlos bernardos
from uccm and i'm gonna present this
draft for the first time in dmm
i tried to be brief because my my goal
is to basically
present some some ideas general ideas
and to see whether there is interest in
working in this kind of topics
so the main motivation for this is to
work in
control solutions for mobility
management in
in distributed sfcs well in sfcs in
service fashion chains
where in sfc you know that there is a
working group in atf working on
on different mechanisms for service
function chaining and
control mechanisms for
for sfc were not there in scope
in sfc so they've even defined control
mechanisms
yet but i believe that is an interesting
topic
and mechanisms that are required and in
particular
there are some points regarding mobility
of functions migration of functions
within an sfc
that i believe could leverage from from
using
or reusing or extending mobility
protocols
as the ones define and maintaining the
mm
so in the picture i have just one
example of architecture so
even though i'm gonna use terminology
about cellular controllers and central
controls is
just an example so the idea is that we
have an sfc
so a function a service function chain
we have different nodes here
ues and a g node b and we may have an
infrastructure connected to the dnob in
the network
we have functions running on ues and
gnode bs for example we have function 1
running at node
a function 2 running at node b
and function 3 running in the g node b
in node
uh with current architectures we have a
central controller slash orchestrator
call it
whatever you want that is basically
managing responsible of
the control the lifecycle management and
under control of the sfc
and the motivation for this work was uh
some solutions that we are exploring in
which in addition to this central
controller
we may have what we call silver
controllers but basically
is other entities that are capable of
also controlling the
the sfc and one of the things that these
controllers may do
is detect the need of moving a function
to another
node for example in this scenario if
node a b
and c are moving away from node d
function 3 that is used by this sfc
may may not be in reachable anymore
and we need to migrate that function
three to another node for example node c
in the in the uec so this is the
motivation for
having a mechanism that allows two move
functions migrate functions in sfc
and our approach or our proposal is to
extend
mobile ipv6 mechanisms with new
uh messages for this specific purpose
that is moving a function
which is something similar to moving a
host but
not the same thing because here
we have that the node that is triggering
the movement is not
may not be the move the node that is
moving itself and we don't have like
central
entities like a home agent or an lma so
basically the scenario is different and
i'm going to go into the details because
again my
my idea for this presentation is to see
whether you think that this may be
of interest of dmm i i want to present
this kind of work also in ssc but it's a
cd we meet
for the last uh couple of uh itf
meetings
but the idea is that that we we extend
the mobility pv6 to support this kind of
mechanisms in the draft
we define different mobility headers so
one is service path update
and the acknowledgement so basically
this is like kind of a binding update
thing
for moving a function within sfc and we
also need some mobility new mobility
options to identify the network service
and to identify
the the functions that we are moving so
again i will not go into the details
so my my request here is
basically to ask people for feedback on
the mailing list
and regarding if you think that this
problem is
of interest and this is part of an
overall solution because for
doing this kind of distributed sfc
control we need other other
things and there are a set of companion
drafts that
are listed there for for interested
people to to check
that's it i would like just to to call
for feedback whenever you have
time if you think that this is maybe of
interest for you guys
thanks uh thanks so
much uh i look up any
questions but one comment is
typically element
yeah because i mean there is no control
mechanism no protocol for control
defining yet so my my proportion is that
if they go into this if they go into
standardizing
protocol extension for sfc control that
is not specified by
by ssc i believe that for mobility
for for life cycle management operation
related to mobility of functions
i think that we could reuse uh mobile ap
as a control protocol for that that's
the proposal so they they need to do
this if they wanna standardize this kind
of
sfc control that is uh they haven't done
yet
that sure well thanks
i think a little less i think recently
you know
we are running on
sorry about that all right uh
that's the uh service anything
or eric last one
yeah sorry nothing from me lots more
reading to do
okay uh thanks everybody
this is the end of that thank you thanks
everybody
i think yeah uh yeah i will follow up
okay thank you
you