i'll take i'll take notes and i'm sure
someone uh
will kind of step up with me to work in
cody md as well no worries
great thanks um
so yeah uh let's get uh started
um uh joe salloway
uh one of the chairs and uh my co-chair
mohit
is also on
and this is the emu meeting for uh
the virtual ietf109
um so uh there's a couple links here
i think probably by this time in the
week you're pretty experienced with
dealing with the
virtual meeting tools but
here's some info but what you're
probably really all waiting for
is the favorite notewell again you're
probably all familiar with this but
if you're not please familiar yourself
familiarize yourself with the
ietf's ipr policies
all right so
we have a pretty full agenda i think
we'll have enough time for it
uh this time uh but because we ran out
of time last time we did uh
give a priority to some of the
presentations that we were unable to get
to
in uh at the last virtual meeting
um we have uh note takers
the blue sheets are taken automatically
we have people monitoring
jabber um so
is there any uh bashing of the agenda
that we'd like to do i mean we have uh
tls proof of knowledge um
uh from either owen or dan will present
i'm not sure which
and we have tls ibs we'll go through
some of the type of rada
hopefully that will not take the whole
time but uh hopefully we can have some
good discussion on that
an update for eep noob and then
a new presentation on eve ad hoc
any other topics people want to go
through
all right
so um i don't know mohit did you want to
talk through some of the draft status or
uh morning can you hear me yes yes
uh yeah so um uh
i will be presenting a short update on
eve noob so we'll deal with that
uh during the agenda today uh
i think yari submitted an update of uh
epk
pfs i don't know if yari wants to say
something but
it looks more or less ready i i guess
if here is on the
i don't know if he is in the meeting and
wants to say something
then we had this large certificates
which was approved by the iesg but
pending uh
pending a document update and i
submitted an update
yesterday so now it's uh i guess with
you
roman to uh i guess
uh send it to the rfc editor
yeah i haven't i'll take a look uh and
then yeah assuming it's fine
we'll keep it moving sounds good
uh using epls with dls 1.3 is
scheduled for the isg telechart on 17th
of december
we got like a couple of emails from
ayanna that we need to clarify the tls
exporter labels that we are registering
if
it's okay with dtls and whether it's
recommended so
i plan to add those information to the
inner section
and submit a new version hopefully today
but i guess more importantly we are
waiting for a review from harness
he had promised that he will go over the
document
uh once more and thank you hannes
already for sending the
reviews uh thus far
uh so yeah then epls with tls 1.3
hopefully will be done
by december uh if uh
aka the 5448 best document
is spending some synchronization with
3gpp
so we'll wait for that i think uh yari
and vesa who are co-authors are also
like discussing this in 3gpp
and basically figuring out how how to
ensure that both
the document here in the ietf and the
specs in 3gpp are
are completely in sync and don't leave
something to to be misunderstood so
we wait for a document update on that
too
and yeah we had our first rfc published
between
108 and 109 which was uh rfc
8940 and thanks to alan for doing the
work
yeah i guess that's the status unless
someone has some more updates
i think harness is in the queue
yeah hi hi cho hi mohit um yeah i've
started um
doing the review already uh this week
was a little bit busy
but uh yeah thanks for the updates mohit
uh
i definitely much better the document is
much better now
um i think uh from a readability point
of view so that
only maybe knits here and there but
nothing
nothing really substantial
yeah thanks and look forward to the next
review so
uh just fi the document is on the
tele chat for 17 so if you can get
get it before that uh that would be nice
but
your reviews are welcome at any point
even when it's in the rfc editor's queue
so
no no i try to deliver them in a timely
fashion
i guess we are done with the status
update
great um so i think we'll move on to
our to either
who's going to present is it going to be
owen or
dan for
it's going to be owen all right
um joel might will it be easier if i
just share
and i can move on the slides as i'm
going uh you can if you want
um if that'd be fine i'm in the queue
for a screen share all right let me see
how i
let me stop this one
are you able to there we go
okay people see my shirt now
yeah perfect okay so this is tls proof
of knowledge
myself and dan i'll just give you some
background context first
um on the wi-fi alliance device
provisioning profile
so what wi-fi alliance tpp does it
defines how a supplicant bootstrap
keypair can be used to bootstrap the
supplicant security against the wi-fi
network
um dpp gives the supplicant to guarantee
that it's connecting to a network that
knows its booster public key
um and just some information on what
this butcher public key is it's encoded
using a
rfc 5280 subway public key info
um it's a rocky pair it doesn't
necessarily have to be part for pki
it may be static embedded in the
supplicant firmware printed on
it may be delivered via printing on a qr
label included in a bit of materials etc
or alternatively the bootstrap key may
be dynamically generated and displayed
on the gui
if your device that you're trying to
bootstrap has a suitable display
um we want to reuse the same booster
public key to enable the device to
securely bootstrap against a wired
network using etls via tls extension
and what this means from a deployment
perspective is that
if a device supports both wi-fi and
wired networks the same qr codes the
same bom et cetera may be used to
establish trust across both wi-fi and
wired networks
and just at the very bottom there i've
given an example of um
the asn-1c encoding of a public subject
public key and what that
looks like in qr and this is all defined
in the dpp spec
so the just a quick again more context
is a quick outline of what dpp looks
like and what the product
what shape the protocol has and the
public bootstrap key
step one the public booster key is
provisioned in
an entity that's called a dpp
configurator so typically this could be
mobile app
or alternatively the configurator could
be embedded into the wi-fi access point
and proof of knowledge is carried out
via divi helmet exchange
and between the configurator and the
supplicant and it uses the booster key
of the supplicant and the configurator
generates an ephemeral development key
as well
and the supplicant proves it knows the
private key of the booster key pair
and the configurator proves that it
knows the public key to boost your key
pair
and then a secure step a secure channel
is established
and step three network information is
securely exchanged
and then step four the supplement
attaches to the network
so in summary the um the configurator
and the supplicant establish a secure
handshake
where the configurator proves to the
supplicants that um it knows the
supplicants
puts their public key the supplicant
proves it knows a private key
once that secure channel is established
the configurator imprints the supplement
with network information
and network credentials and then the
subsequent will attach to the network
and so what we want to do for wired for
wired lan is the
um the public key of the booster key is
scanned into the network are known by
your
aaa or your epls server the device wants
the network to prove that it knows
the bootstrap public key before the
device will connect to the network
and this can be quite easily achieved by
making a simple extension to the
theater's handshake
and what we do with the teal's handshake
is we exchanged two sets of tiffy helm
and keys and the client loan server law
and so the first key share is just the
standard key share for
in tls 1.3 if you haven't for both sides
generated femoral keepers and exchange
them
and in step two we add a bootstrap
extension
where the client sends a hash of its
public key
to the server and the server uses that
hash the public key to look up the raw
public key and the server generates it's
a thermal key pair and then
the two sides can complete that um
second divi helmet exchange
um so both different helmet calculations
are injected into the key schedule
using the mechanisms outlined in the
draft of reference there
and there's also the alternative draft
which is which is referenced in in our
document the hybrid design
draft so there's multiple ways of um
figuring out how to inject that second
piece of information into the key
schedule but what we've implemented at
the moment
is the the highland one
so these these are extracts from the
draft
it shows you the shape of the bootstrap
key extension
and that extension can be sent to either
a client law or server law
in a client at all it's just a hashed
reference a hashed reference to the
public keys that allows the server to
look up the public key
unlike a standard key exchange you're
not selling the full raw public key
you're sending it
a hash representation which allows the
server to look up the public key
and in the server law the server is
exchanging their
um ephemeral difficult key their second
department if you haven't key alongside
the standard key exchange
um so you can see that illustrating the
call from the bottom left uh the client
sends um the bootstrap key and it's
client load the server sends back
it's a corresponding bootstrap ephemeral
key in its server law
in addition to the standard key shares
and the
the graphic on the right hand side shows
you the
mechanism taken from the holland draft
for injecting
a second input into the key schedule
and the bsk input is just the secondary
element
that takes place and we're injecting it
using the mechanism defined in that
other draft
so what this means for an operator
perspective is everyone is happy
if you have a device that you're trying
to onboard the device has a
an associated bootstrap key which could
be embedded in the firmware dynamically
generated on a label whatever and that
qr code
is um scanned into the network
and regardless of whether you're
connecting device via wired using dpp
or via sorry by wireless using dpp
rfi wired using this proposed tls
extension inside an eep
and we were able to securely
authenticate the network
um security considerations it leverages
the tls handshake and there's no we're
not defining any new esoteric
cryptography
all of the existing tls security proofs
should still be applicable
and the security proofs that will be
defined under their touchdown in the
highland draft but they're not fully
fleshed out should handle the key
schedule changes as well so we shouldn't
have any work to do there
um and in terms of bootstrap key
security
tls proof of concept has exactly the
same security stance as the wi-fi
alliance tpp
with respect to those bootstrap keys so
for dpp
if you know the bootstrap public key you
can claim the device
and exactly the same is applicable here
for tds proof of knowledge when you're
doing unwired if you know the booster
public key then the network can claim
the device
so we're not making any changes to the
overall security stance there
we do have working code um we will just
work in tls.code that's been
up on um it's up on github for quite a
while now for
since before the last itf um it's
built using it's built on top of the
standard
goal line mid stack that would that the
guys in the tls working group have done
loads of proof concepts on top of
um and this last slide discussion and
next steps
um there's three general work areas here
one is defining the tls extensions to
transport that booster
key and that's a pretty small trivial
piece of work second is
the enhancements to the key schedule to
inject that second if we have an
exchange into the key schedule
and we're hoping to piggyback on one of
the existing drafts either holland one
or the hybrid
the hybrid key exchange one um
there will be some per tip extensions
defined and required to leverage how
to define how to leverage that utilis
proof of knowledge handshake
that work is still that work still needs
to be completed
um and with some general discussion
questions here well obviously the first
one is to run a general interest in this
and and the other question is
where does this work fit and we could
cover this in one document that it
currently is or do we split it do we
need to split it into two or three
like for example we could have a short
draft to define the tls
extensions we and then we could have an
inu draft of reference to those two
extensions
and the highland key schedule changes
um and where does this work where does
this work like did we start an emu move
to tls says do we have to split some of
the work between emu and tls
and those are the kind of things we'd
like to discuss and that is it that's
the end of the presentations it's um
pretty short and but we feel it's a it's
a
pretty elegant solution um for security
bootstrapping a device onto a wired or
wi-fi network
and the the there is working code
okay that's it
i don't see anybody in the queue but i
guess i'll
you know ask a couple questions so
we uh this is using both um
a new extension and uh
the hoiland uh draft and so
those are two pieces that need to be
kind of reviewed and worked out
um i think right now i don't think
if i remember correctly hoiland isn't a
working group
item yet that's correct
that's correct it's not sure so
yeah and i think there is interest in it
um
but the word group's kind of been
working through some other items
and that hasn't come up again yet
uh so that's probably something we want
to i'll probably talk with jonathan and
other folks and see
what their plan is with that draft um
and as far as the extension i think you
know certainly
i don't know that the extension needs to
be done in tls
um uh especially since like
you're you know you're going to be using
trying we'll we'll try if if you're
using the hoiling draft and you're using
sort of a standard way to kind of mix
things in
you know that that would be reviewed by
the tls group which would probably be
the most concerning part
um
but uh yeah i don't necessarily have
a too much of an opinion do you see use
of this
outside of dpp and
um well
these cases that we're currently
targeting um
the use case that we're currently
targeting just putting on my cisco hat
at the moment we're certainly
talking to um to operators
and this is a problem that they need to
solve and they have a serious problem
with security onboarding um
sensors and devices onto wired networks
um i see elliot is in the queue waiting
to talk so i'll actually defer to
audience to see do we see use of this
outside of eep
um
hi um good good morning good afternoon
good evening
um so clearly there's a there's a pretty
clear use case for eat
but i wouldn't exclude the idea that it
might be used
um elsewhere at a higher layer
right but that doesn't mean the work
couldn't be done in emu
it just means that we shouldn't write
the code we shouldn't write any
extensions
that you know that would exclude the use
of email
there are of things other than email
excuse me
that could the influence
of the draft as well and how many drafts
we write um
and it may make sense to have
the tls extensions in a short separate
document so that is not
like bound to an emu draft if that makes
sense
uh so there's uh ben in the queue
uh go ahead ben can dan get in the queue
too
uh sure i'll join
now you're in the queue behind ben
okay i mean if you wanted to jump ahead
i don't know what you were
talking about no no go ahead
but i guess my question
or comment i had started to say in the
jabber room but
it seems like we're using a standard
private key pair for the bootstrapping
keys here
and i was wondering if there was a way
that we could be able to use like
threshold crypto instead
to fulfill the same goals without
sort of relying on this weird mechanism
where
you are not treating the public key as
or so you're you're treating the public
key as something that
is not um widely distributed
like it's supposed to be secret as well
in some sense
and i don't have a great sense for
whether threshold of crypto would
get around that in any way
so if i can answer well i i just see
daniel's in the queue as well but
one answer i have is we haven't
considered threshold crisp
crypto but we had been looking at
complete reuse of the dpp
bootstrap key so we want on the
bootstrap key
and dpp is is a currently defined and
published wi-fi line standard and we
want to reuse that exactly as is as the
bootstrap key
and now i don't know whether dpp is
uninterested moving to some kind of
threshold of crypto
i'll refer to that on that
and go ahead okay thank you
so i i'm not sure whether threshold
crypto would work
uh but that said you know
that's an interesting comment uh
what i wanted to say was that you know
there's a
a a discussion of uh using the
uh hoilo work in tls to do
the extended key schedule and
you know even if that isn't adopted
something's going to get adopted because
tls needs to deal with the
post-quantum crypto issue and so they're
going to
they're going to come up with a way to
inject
random goo into the tls key schedule and
we can just use whatever that that
technique is
if it's not the the technique that that
we're specifying now
if the tls working group decides
something else
then we'll just use that
definitely yeah i considered saying
something similar as well but
uh i think we're all on the same page in
that aspect and
and thanks to both of you for sort of
clarifying the the threshold of crypto
and then wanting to reuse the dppkey
point i had missed that part so thanks
eliot are you still in the queue
not anymore uh so there was uh just one
comment from era mcdonald that
uh i guess i should say at the mic uh
she's
uh suggests uh keeping tls extension in
the tls working group to ensure review
by
smes i feel the same i think uh
our job emu will be much simpler
once this jonathan's draft and the
extension is
adopted by tls then the emu draft would
be
very straightforward and i don't see any
issues with
progressing this
okay and just for reference paul stood
into the chat as well
the um other draft that we've referenced
as the alternative
schedule um import
and it's the the hybrid design one that
has been a draft adopted by tls
so we looked at both we implemented what
looked like the simplest and most
concrete thing at the time six months
ago which was the highland draft
okay um i think um you know it would be
good to
i think it would help your case in tls
um
i don't know how much interest there
will be in in there for this particular
thing we can certainly
check that out on its own but
if this is something that's of interest
within you know the
emu space i think that kind of helps the
case of of
working on an extension either in in tls
or
or in this uh working group
so there's a question and uh there's a
question in
jabber i don't know if dan or one you
want to answer
john frederick uh asks will the server
still authenticate itself against the
client using a certificate
or is the public key of the client the
only item that the server uses to
authenticate
as per this draft the only item that the
server will use authenticate is
knowledge of the public key so if any
rogue operator has gains knowledge of
that booster public key then
that operator can claim the device on
their network
now there is if you read the full dpp
draft that the wi-fi lines tpp spec
it does allow far mutual authentication
where you can print
credentials on both sides and but this
draft only does
this draft here the tls proof of
knowledge only does it one way
uh thanks hopefully john frederick this
answers your question
hi hi this is hannes uh i was wondering
whether you couldn't just reuse the raw
public key mechanism
out of the box in that case
uh also okay so the raw public key the
raw public key remembers the client's
key
and there's currently no tls mechanism
for a server to prove it knows the
client's public key
so if raw public key the if you use a
raw public key in tls the client is
going to send its full raw public key
and to the server so it won't work
yeah i will have to read the trap but it
sounds interesting here
okay and you should read the wi-fi lines
tpp spec as well because that's
that's part of the genesis id
okay so i think what we would want uh
folks to do is
is read the draft so maybe uh posting
it to the list and asking for some
review
would be good um so that we can see
what the interest is in the working
group
i guess this is a question to you joe
i don't know if this should be posted to
the tls list or
if like this can be presented in the tls
working group
at the next ietf that's something you
can consider
yeah i would definitely think should
post something to the list and and see
if we can get some discussion
on it um you know irregardless of
you know when we would present it in the
working group
dan yeah i i guess you you i guess you
just touched on that i i just wanted to
say that it would be nice if we could
get a feeling from the group whether
this is something that
the group wants to address you know if
can we produce it yeah we can uh
we we can do uh a show of hands right
now to see what the
interest is um so with the interest
would be
uh or the question would be do folks uh
is this
this draft or this this um
topic something emu should work on
like a the closest alternative that emu
is currently working on is
is noob noob um
that this this mechanism is currently
defined
only goes in one direction
to boost your key provisioning only goes
in one direction only but the
i think the closest analogy is noob
yeah sure um so i think that you know i
think the question though is is
we we have noob is is this um is this a
mechanism that
people think would you know would be a
good topic for emo to work on
this isn't like uh this is just to get
an idea of
what people feel at this point in the
room
or did i misunderstand your quest pure
comment
so i can answer for noob i don't see it
competing so i
i i don't see any reason why we can't
have
both because as one said this doesn't do
server authentication
you can't do like oob in the other
direction where the key is somehow
printed or shown on the server and then
sent to the peer so i don't see them
competing i think there is
interest but maybe let's let joe ask the
question to the
okay using the show of hands tool i'm
going to start the
thing here and so if you uh think this
is a topic the
group should work on so there's a a
raise your hand and there's a do not
raise your hand
and then there's you can you know not
do anything so we'll let it go for for a
little bit um
you seem to have ended it go i sent i
sorry i must have ended it i clicked the
wrong button
i started it again
all right i am going to stop it
now okay so it seems like there is
a fair amount of if is there anybody who
you know did not raise their hand who
has an objection to this
work or
who wants to come to the mic
okay so so there is some interest so i
think that that's uh
promising i mean i think it's good that
it's you know kind of
bridging the gap between what dpp does
and what can be done on wired so it
definitely seems to me like there could
be place for it so
uh we we need to have more discussion on
the list but i think we need to move on
to the next presentation
is my bling on
i can run the slides if you'd like
smiling if you're available
but i saw
hmm
i thought i saw my wing on the call
hello cheers hello
hello just okay you help me to create
a pointer from a computer
here our
yes thank you very much
okay hello everyone i'm mei lincoln
uh this is my first print presentation
on the
emu world group so my draft was
first submitted in may this year and i
have sent
emails in the email list for my uh
draft in this draft
we propose a merced of using
identity as raw fabric key in
e if yes the curry idea
is that we use identity-based signatures
for
authentication instead of just relying
on ca certificates
before we start the whole content
introduction of my draft
it's really necessary we have a look on
background
pki based 0 acts
certificates are really now used in
fps but still some problems with
traditional
certificates such as management cost
lodge
certificate chains and intermediate
certificate is not so friendly to the
constrained environment devices such as
iot devices especially for
weak computing power devices
so i think there are two solutions
one is to simplify the certificate
and intermediate validation process
another is use a new merge search for
the authentication
of course we choose the letter
what's your public key uh
in the owens presentation most of us
have no republican that means there is
no
if no information arden than the public
key for cryptography
sentient sacred kings are more
lightweight
but the disadvantage is also very
upwell such as the
dating operation so why not try to use
asmt cryptography
public and the private keys are involved
what type of data can be used as the
public key
that means we which we will be choosed
as our identity this is out of
scope of my draft
but it's another topic for my research
this drift i propose is placed on two
other rfc rc7250
and 6507
in the rfc rfc6507 specified
an identity-based signature algorithms
using elaptic curve
cryptograph the mathematical calculation
method
of signature and the verification is
provided
and we also notice that fc
sam250 specified using raw public key
with two extensions
makes the raw public key and variable in
ts
and dtls next slide things
literature yes think
so the however draft
we can complete we can divide into three
parts
part one is about the structure of the
raw power breaking
extension and part two is about ifts 1.2
extends republican in authentication
procedure
and part 3 is about if just 1.23
authentication procedure
next slide thanks
this is the horror handshake
exchange during the ftis
authentication procedure
all of us all knowing it's your best
most of
us are very familiar about their tia's
handshake
the message is started at the current
hello
these two extensions is
server certificate type and client
certificate
type
server certificate type here means the
types of server certificate the kind
is able to process
this client certificate type means the
type of certificate
the kind can provide to the server
after receiving the current loan
the server will respond with say hello
and
these two new extensions also exist
here from the
hello side the current certificate type
indicates the selected type of client
certificate type
of client certificate
and the extension of server
certificate type here indicates the
type of certificate certificate in their
following certificate load
what's more important is the extension
of
certificate we have made some
some changes to their content compared
to what we had before
the certificate contains three major
informations
the first one is raw public king we can
also described
as server identity the second one is the
selected signature such as
eccsi the third one is the hash value
after
us algorithms fabric parameters
after receiving their message from the
server
the quite well verified and
the signature message same id and the
public parameters
will be their input and then this
the peer will verify their signature
if success declined will also send their
own certificate with the same form of
the server
after several verified the client
certificate it means their virtual
authentication complete
and the whole king develop derivation is
also complete
they can transport application data
securely from now
next slide things
the part three is we desire
e if ts 1.3 with
identity based signature
the whole authentication procedure keep
the same ways
are efp if just 1.2
the current differences between them is
just
the differences between t
ls 1.2 and ts 1.3
next slide
this slide is an example for if
yep ts 1.3 uh
version identity based signature
we can see that in the current hello
there are three
extensions signature algorithm character
signature algorithms they can use under
these two new extensions several
certificate
type and kind certificate type they are
they can be listed types
and after receiving their current hello
there sam hello will respond
and with the same new
extensions the server hello site
choose republican as their
certificate type
what's more the certificate here will
carry
the i object
identity for ecsi that's the wrong
uh mass value here and the hash
value of the public parameters
and also that's their id that's their
public key
and also their certificate request will
carry
eccs i sure 205
6 they that means they want
their current site will also use their
easies as i
sure two hundred fifteen
six so
after the client received our
message from the from the same hello
they will
also do their verify and share
all certificated to their peers
after both all material authentications
complete
their hover tls
handshake finished and
send the e f six thirds
to the kite
next light
so what we will do
we want our more discussion
uh i really think now this version draft
is not a perfect one so
comments and co-authors are welcome
and the plan next to do my draft
is to apply to their iae
and a their type code for apis ibs
and divides their key direction
based on ftls ibs
things
so we can start the discussion
i don't see anyone in the queue that's
anyone have same question i have a
question so it looks like in
in your presentation that you didn't
need to do any modifications
to the way the tls flow work
and that you just used the
asm1 definition for the curves that you
wanted to use
inside the raw public key message is
that true
i don't get a key point of your question
does that mean that i just use this uh
two is new extensions
uh did do you have to create any new
extensions
or data types within tls
yes we have you can if you familiarize
the rfc
uh five
zero seven you can know the
extension you can see the extension
there
current certificate type and the
self-certificate type
is really not a new one here
we also have a draft about
ts ibs uh it have uh
we have submitted in the tl as what
group
do
hi um hi this is hannes uh i was
wondering
where you plan to use your um
document like this specific method like
what deployment environments do you have
in mind
sorry if i missed that
oh i think the uh most disturbed bros
scenario is for the lonely
passive i ot devices
you said long long lived which devices
like uh
maybe not very exactly with that but i
think the
robert machine can use this
especially in the constraint environment
for the internet so internet of things
devices okay
uh there's a question uh in jabber from
rasoozlay
uh is this leveraging draft huang tls
ibe
um can you
you uh you mean
you mean the uh drafter of
for one haikuang right
uh so i don't know if uh i'm
pronouncing the name correctly it's uh
there is a draft uh
uh that's draft huang tls
ibe uh is this is
your draft leveraging that
ibe is a very good thing but it's
much more difficult for me so i just use
uh ibs here not encryption here
just use ib ask for the uh identity
authentication but not use the uh
encryption crypt crypto here
all right uh
pki uh the traditional pki
certificates yeah
thanks uh harness asks is there some
running code for this draft
oh yes i have uh
in my program
i did the implementation of aps
ibs based on ips
1.2 we
basically implemented the whole process
but
it's not opensets in the github
is our internal
code but we can share with the
test result
okay i guess joe the next step is like
to continue the discussion on the list
for this yes thank you
more comments and discussions i
won't see in their mail list thank you
very much
all right next up i guess joe you will
be doing the deep
errata yeah so
um we had a busy time with tea paradis
since the last
meeting um i think we we had a total of
um errata published
um or or submitted against teep
um i think on the list we've resolved
um six of those
and i think four of them are really
close and i wanted to kind of go through
them today
uh with as many people as we could here
i did get some comments on the list from
oleg so i know he's looked at them
um but i want to make sure that that
people
have looked at them and if there are any
comments today then we can chat about it
um so let's see
the first one
we have is has to do with the authority
id
which is a tlv an outer tlv um
and currently the draft or sorry the
the the rfc says
that this uh should be mandatory
um and uh the the problem there
is uh there's another part of the rfc
that says outer tlbs cannot be mandatory
and so the the suggested resolution here
is to to make this
optional now realizing that
optional means that not everybody has to
understand this tlv
um and and it turns out this tlb is
important when you're processing
uh packs um
so if you're using packs you would you
would want to understand this tld
because it helps you to
to uh manage them on on the client
um but if you don't then it would be
optional
uh quick question john this one so yeah
is
is this being made optional because it's
an outer tlv and
the document says that all outer tlvs
are optional
correct so
uh and this and
so this is only needed in in the
scenario of a pack
that is my understanding at least you
know for the
usages now i mean somebody could define
something else that could
make use of of it as well but it
identifies kind of the
aaa server okay so there are scenarios
where teeth can work without this
tlb in which case this makes sense
making it optional
but i'd you know if um if uh
elliott or um anybody else has
has any comments
okay if not
so jorge said it agrees with optional
um all right so any any
additional concerns about making this
optional
no looks good move on to the next one
all right um here
this is one that's a little bit tricky
um there are a lot of places in the
document where
the term eep method is used and in a
great many
of them it really means eep
authentication method
which is really any method except for
the eep identity method which does no
authentication
so you know there's a suggestion to
um modify this in in a couple places but
really it needs to be modified in many
places
so my uh thinking here is that this is
something that we would hold for a
document update because there's
really too many places to update it
uh just doing it in an errata
and so the errata would be hold for a
document update and we can place a note
explaining uh the reasons why we want to
make that change
but the change would be made when we
update the document
so quick question what side if identity
method
um the eep identity method is uh
the it's a e type
that can be uh that the client sends uh
the server sends an identity
request i believe and then the client
sends an identity response that contains
an nai for routing typically
it's a message type right so we have
message types and it can be a request
response
identity and so
wouldn't it make sense to like i i don't
know if the current rfc
refers to identity method and maybe just
say
identity message or
i'm not sure if follow
are you saying that eep identity should
not like we if identity isn't a method
and that we shouldn't that this doesn't
matter or
are you saying that we there's a one
place where we can make a change or
so what i'm saying is that for me uh and
hopefully for
most other people i could be wrong if
method generally
means an eep authentication method which
was i guess the intended
meaning when deep was written and
i haven't now looked at the deep rfc
maybe i should
check it again but if there are some
instances of uh
identity method it might make sense to
like change those to an identity
message or
yeah i'm sure i'm sure that the teeps
back i'm pretty sure it does reference
the identity method
at least a couple of times
i think in general people know what
this means and we've clarified we're
going to clarify some of the other areas
where there was confusion between
when you send different types of
messages
um
so i i think i think you know fixing
this in in multiple
other places is is not really in scope
for an errata
does anybody
else want to comment on this one
all right so i i mean
we can take a look and and take a look
at the
at the rfc and see if you if you think
there is uh
if there's a simple change to make that
isn't like
you know in 15 different sections then
that
that might be worthwhile doing um
but this is borderline almost an
editorial change
it does have some technical meaning in
some places
yep makes sense i'll make sure to look
at this
i'm now reading the errata again so i
get some
context maybe i should have done this
before but uh
you're right this is just an editorial
change so we can see what's the best way
forward
yeah yeah okay so the next one
i think whoops is better to
look at in github
so this particular one has to do with uh
um
with when um how we handle
multiple authentication mechanisms
and whether you send an interme
and when you derive keys and when you do
uh interme
intermediate uh results and crypto
binding
and so the real question was it didn't
really specify whether you did crypto
binding after a basic password exchange
it didn't make that clear
um and so
uh we've made some modifications here to
kind of
make it clearer what you do and so that
also
we defined made sure the procedure for
when you don't have a key generated such
as in a password method
what you use in the crypto binding and
insert
into the key schedule
um so this section is is just clarifying
that
um i think this is the main
there's a couple different changes but
this is uh and
i went through and kind of what the
changes would look like
in
github and this is basically saying uh
the zero msk is used in the case that
uh
when no key is uh derived and then
if the and then the zero
msk is defined as just an msk of
32 octets and zeros
and i think there was another section to
this change
[Music]
let's see now i think that's it
that's all i await here
this is taking a little time but i think
oleg has gone through this change as
well
and it seemed like
seems like things are
for some reason i am not able to open up
the other
thing right now
um but did anybody who's looked at have
any additional comments on
the resolution to 57.75
let's just see if we can so jorge says
he has
reviewed the pull request and no
additional comments
yeah here's the other other change that
describes um
what happens with the intermediate
result tlds
that are required after basic uh
password authentication and eep
authentication
and oh like i made
uh the a was i think the change was with
the next one
basically on what you had
requested
all right so we can move on to the next
one
which is uh again having to do with the
intermediate result and password
authentication
joe sorry one comment regarding the
previous errata
yeah so was it decided
it was decided not to
introduce the new flag that denotes the
only zero msk is present right
right the
yeah that sorry go ahead go ahead go
ahead
that means that there is no technical
possibility to
to use zero msk where
at the msk or emsk are allowed
technically right in other words if
the method if the inner method
exports at the msk or emsk
it must be used and zero msk cannot be
used
so usage of zero msk is implicitly
followed by from the
specification of the inner method
yes maybe we need to mention this
explicitly so it will not
it will be clear for the protocol
implementators
um if you could look at
i don't know if that would fall in in
this errata or one of the other ones
but if if there's a sentence we could
add
um um
maybe even in this one
we should look to see where where we
could add that um
maybe even in this table which i think
maybe was edited
in another uh pull request
also the good place is is for section
5.2
yeah oh it is yeah
that's where we are um so if
if you could take a look at the i think
that that could be a fine idea if we
just
if it's just an addition in one of the
current
uh errata which i think it could fit
into um
that would would be good because i i
think the intention is that if a method
is generates uh an msk that it should be
used
so i i don't think it would be worth
time to to
uh fix this here but we can go offline
and and
work through what what the change would
be
thanks okay
okay then uh 5844
um this is another one with several uh
parts to it
this is just again i didn't want to do
that
just again uh kind of clarifying some of
the appendices uh to include places
where
um there was a missing uh
crypto binding uh tlv and intermediate
or i think the uh
crypto binding tlb seems like maybe this
isn't
correct
oh yeah no the crypto binding tlb is
right
to here that you need an intermediate
result
so i think this these were errors in the
in the specification i think it's pretty
straightforward
for this particular change
and in this case
the other changes resulting from this
errata are
almost there
i'm just going to try to get these going
github is not responding quickly to me
today
um
so looking at this change
this is again clarifying that
intermediate result pld
goes after authentication methods and
basic password authentication methods
pretty straightforward
[Music]
and
this is where i clarified the text based
on
oleg's uh comments
uh that an intermediate result
indicating success must always
be accompanied by a crypto binding tlv
this is discussed elsewhere in the
document
but just to make it crystal clear we we
included it here
as well
is that clearer oleg
yes it looks clear
thank you all right let's one more spot
um
then again instead of just talking about
individual eat methods
we talk about authentication methods and
password authentication as well
so are there any other comments on these
errata
or any of the other errata that we
didn't discuss yet i think we have still
have one open issue which
oleg brought up um which we can
i think that'll be pretty quick to
resolve uh but i'd like to
try to wrap these up and send them to
roman uh
so he can figure out how we
take this to the next hooray you are
up next go ahead yep
i apologize i sent an email to the list
just
right before this meeting so i doubt
anybody has had time to review it and
think about it
but errata 5768
the chrome code is too
um it involves the hmac and hmacs have
different
lengths depending on the algorithm used
and so it relates to
changing the length in the crypto
binding tlv
to be variable based on the type of hmac
used
which sounds good uh to me but i do have
some compatibility concerns because the
existing document says
the crypto binding tlv
the length of that field is 20 and
existing
implementations uh use that length of 20
and they truncate any output that is
longer than 20 they truncate it to 20
octets
so i agree that the direction of
making that variable is good but i am
concerned it has compatibility impact
and so perhaps
to make that change we would have to
increase the version
of the crypto binding tlv
yeah um so then if
if existing i think if we're going to
increase the
version of the crypto binding tlv that's
like a document
update and what we could do in the
errata is
is clarify what the existing behavior is
um i mean if if existing implementations
are doing
you know shot or shot 256 and then
truncating it to 20
bytes and and those are existing
implementations that might be what the
errata
should say and then in a document update
we can add a new
tlb that or uh you know create a new
a new version of the crypto binding tld
i agree with that path forward and we
can
um we can clarify what the existing
implementations are doing on the list i
suppose
i just want to to raise that concern
here thank you
yeah that it would be awesome to to get
the
make sure that this is what
implementations are doing and then if
they are doing this then
that's probably the best path forward
elliot you are next hey thanks very much
um this is just a weird ietf cause i'm
i'm trying to follow
two rooms at once i'm supposed to speak
in another
um first joe
and jorge and oleg
thank you for all of your work on this
and it was a lot of work and it took a
lot of effort to just
get all get slogged through all these
and a thanks to yoni even though he's
not here
um first i agree with the last point
that
um that one should be hold for update
but the reason i got on the microphone
was to say
and now that we're getting through these
i want to unstick the
the deep update i didn't want i couldn't
do
i didn't think we should start that
until we got until we slogged through
these i think that was the general sense
i think you you said uh a meeting or two
ago that was the general sense of the
working group that
we should we should slog through these
and then do the deep update
and so now that we've done that um i'll
unstick that trap but i think we're
probably going to rewrite it from what
was a sort of a brewski oriented draft
to more of just a deep update draft with
a cup
with a couple extra tlbs what i'd
like to do is invite um you know jorge
and yoni and others to to really um work
with me on that
so that as as we go through we can make
sure that
um all of the errata get properly
incorporated in
that we're making sure that we're
comfortable with
1.3 there are a couple of
authors on the draft already dan harkins
is on it
i think owen is on it and a couple of
others we'll probably want to
incorporate a few other things to make
sure for instance that the
the poke work is is incorporated
depending on you know or or that we can
easily update
on top of uh the update as it were
with with it with a separate drop for
poke and we can make some decisions
about that depending on timing
so um again uh thanks for all the work
it was it was a lot of work and i
personally appreciate it
great yeah it'll be it'll be good to
kind of
get our revision going i think
um especially now that we have
implementations i think
the this experience with teep really
solidifies i think the areas where we
had
most of the problems are areas uh which
were not
did not receive as much implementation
at the time
and so implementation is is key in
when we're working through these issues
absolutely
so again that you're absolutely right
there has to be code
totally agree
[Music]
all right i think there are a couple
items to take so jorge thanks for
for raising that issue and um
we will uh you know take take a look at
what's on the list make sure our
implementations are aligned
and i think there's one other kind of
more editorial change we could make to
to one of the erratas but i think
that'll help understandability so
awesome we're almost i see the light at
the end of the tunnel
roman is there any other information
like that you you will need i mean i can
work with you
on what format is best for you and how
we need to split these up or whatnot
but is there anything you think we need
from the working group at this time
uh no all i can really do is reiterate
the things that elliot said
what what's happening here is phenomenal
uh i love the process kind of with
github kind of on the clarity
for every other working group i have no
one works the errata so consistently is
this
so this is a tremendous amount of help i
i don't really need anything more other
than i may have kind of the occasional
questions when i personally drop it into
uh into the interface but it looks like
you have all the necessary things and
you everyone we've walked it through the
working group to make sure that we're
all on the same page
so this is phenomenal and when you say
you're done i mean i'll i'll start
dropping it into the errata interface
thank you really again this is awesome
okay cool all right so i think we're
done with this for the time being
and i think the next thing was uh an
update some updates on eep noob do you
wanna
are you giving those mohit uh yeah
uh if you can share the slides that
would be great eliot
by the way are you still on the queue or
just accidental
uh so yeah hi this is a short update on
uh
eat noob i think by now uh people are
familiar with what this
method does uh so next slide please
yeah generic authentication framework
and there's no methods that do ob
authentication so yeah this is a new
method for doing that
uh next slide
uh it basically does
uh user you uses a user assistant out of
band uh
authentication in either direction
whether it's from the peer to the server
or from the server to the peer
and supports basically any type of ob
channel whether it's qr codes and dev
tag audio blinking leds and so on
and the user doesn't have to perform
this step
every time because we have this fast
reauthentication where
previously registered devices
can get fresh keys without further user
interaction
next slide
so this is the rather long timeline of
uh it noob but it seems we are getting
towards the end and hopefully there is
light at the end of the tunnel
so it has been around for a while there
are several
implementations we adopted it as a
working group item in
uh earlier this year uh
and like the draft already was stable
when it was adopted and now
like we got like reviews from harness
from the iot directorate from security
directorate and
basically the working group portions
have been
updating the draft based on on these uh
reviews so now we are at uh working
group version two so
uh that's the stage we are currently at
next slide
uh at least we the authors believe that
it's
ready there's uh three implementations
two
two of them in uh wps applicant and host
apd and one in contiki
uh there's formal models in mcrl2
which is basically for checking the
state machines and dos resistance
and pro verify to verify the security
goals
so the difference between the two
implementations
in supplicant host apd the first one is
more feature rich
so it does all sorts of things like nfc
from peer to server and server to peer
whereas the the third implementation on
this bullet list is i would say more
streamlined and stable and less
feature-rich so it's
i would say like less bugs and less
features
and more stable implementation which was
completely rewritten
earlier this year after the draft was
working group adopted
so the first implementation was uh done
mostly by us the authors
whereas the second and third have been
done by other folks
next slide
so updates since the last itf we have
been receiving like
private emails basically asking
questions or
opening issues on github so we got like
a email from
miguel at analog devices and they are
working on an
internal proof of concept of efp noob
and basically
we received some questions on how to set
up the implementation
and there were some minor issues with
the reconnect exchange not in the spec
but mostly in the implementation so
what was happening that the the
reconnect exchange was
uh not triggered in the state machine at
the right time and
this caused the reconnect exchange to
fail and
uh miguel from analog devices then
actually send the pull requests
to the implementation there's several
others i'm not sure if they want to be
named here and listed here
some of course are university projects
which are obviously nice but
maybe the the uh
i some of these poc implementations in
various uh companies uh sound more
interesting and have
more like interesting use cases where
for example one of the emails that we
the authors got was
that the deployment scenario is we come
with our own access point and then
configure the devices
and then take away the access point and
transfer the devices
to to a different access point at the
customer side
which i thought was interesting and it
seems that
thanks to eep in framework in general we
don't have issues with
these kind of scenarios where the access
point
there is a temporary access point for
configuring but then the devices join
the actual access point on
on site
next slide
so the only remaining issue i think that
has
now been on the table
was uh basically doing sea bar versus
json
and this came up in dev talor's
directorate review and as well as
michael richardson who was
saying uh whether we should move to
seaboard and
we realized that seabor is going to be a
major change
uh at this stage uh and of course we
could do simple mapping of
uh json to seabor but uh that doesn't
really get you
the gains that you would get from like
doing native c bar and doing the entire
specification in cddl
and since uh we are seeing some of these
uh deployments that are creeping up at
at this stage uh maybe it's fine to
just stick with json and let this go
through and
of course uh eep new has secure version
negotiation so you can
perhaps uh think of a future version of
heap nowhere
which supports seaboard although i think
we will have a presentation after this
on epaddock which perhaps is more
suitable
for the extremely constrained devices
where you know seabor is more likely to
be
a necessity rather than
the case of eat noob so
for now given that you know we have
these deployments coming up
i'm a bit concerned that moving this to
seabor
is not worth the benefits
and i mean if there is strong requests
in the future this can be done but at
this stage it feels like
the really constrained devices may
prefer
then to go with the ad doc for example
next slide
and hopefully this is my this is my last
slide so we have had early reviews from
iot and security directorate
uh we got uh inr okay with the current
request whether it's for the
method type or the special domain name
and
i would like to thank wes hardiker from
the iab
who kind of did the hand holding and
explained the process and
it's nice that i and i can do this early
reviews to
confirm and weed out any issues in the
inr requests section
so the authors believe it's ready for
our last call
if there are any comments i'm happy to
answer
in particular i'm interested in anybody
has any strong
uh feelings about
just keeping everything in json it
sounds
to me like that's a good way forward but
i just want to make sure that we don't
have any strong objection to that
i don't see anyone at the queue so
maybe joe if you can do the last call
then
i'm sure we will have some other you
know issues to sort out when the reviews
come in from other
directorates during the last call but
unless there is something major we could
start the last working group last call
yeah i think that's a good idea
all right i think we are doing great on
our time so
next is a dock
hi eduardo hi can you hear me
yes we can go ahead wait thank you
well thank you for having me today i am
edward ingress
and i'm going to present this draft
published with dan garcia
and rafa marin the draft includes the
initial
idea of the new method for it
based on adult country authentication
protocol
exercise live please
our goal is to design an alternative
solution
for constrained devices using nedoc
edoc is a protocol that is currently
under development
at the lake working group and in this
working group
they intend to produce a lightweight
authenticate the
key exchange for oscar usage
and they use the silver protocol and
recommend the
use of co-op to transport messages they
also want to
provide entering protections you need to
more information you can check the
the drafts and the working group next
slide please
in this first version of the draft we
established that the
peer acts as an edoc initiator
and the server acts with the role of our
responder so on that basis
the message exchange for the ip method
starts with request and response
identity
then the authenticator send
a needle start message with no data
and add it at this point since the
pair is the initiator it starts the head
of the change by
sending the three corresponding messages
and
ends with an ip success or failure
message
next slide can i ask a question here
of course uh so
like now that i see this orange message
isn't it like a dock is a three message
protocol but now we have the fourth
message and you would you might be able
to get rid of this extra message
by just making the server as the
initiator is there
like i'm wondering is there any reason
not to do that
uh yeah that's a great question actually
we are
we have that in mind uh we wanted to
to plan this question here uh there are
two options of course we can uh
use the server as the initial as the
initiator
so the fourth message will be a
message with data we will have to
define it correctly but of course yes we
can we can do it
starting with the servers as the
mediator
and we have john in the queue go ahead
john
yeah there are some privacy implication
by
changing who sends message one
um so in ad hoc
and all the similar protocols like tls
103 and
so on you you get so in
in this metric flow the server will send
its identity to basically anybody asking
sending
a doc message one uh so if you
return so you get active protection of
the
erp peers identity in this message
and only passive protection
of the server's identity if you reverse
the water you get
stronger protection of the service
identity and weaker of the pier
that makes yeah that makes sense
yeah in in that case i think the
current message flow is uh fine yeah
your
i think it's better to protect the
privacy of the peer
so yeah that's actually that's why we
started
uh including this version instead of
including the other option but
i mean i don't i don't know any use case
that we really need to put the
server as the administrator but
maybe the someone else has another use
case
yep thanks i guess thank you
so next slide okay thank you
so edok allows to define which protocol
is
responsible for ensuring the correlation
of messages
so either itself or the protocol
or the transport protocol sorry in this
case the if protocol is based on the
locasted procedure
and guarantees the ordering of messages
therefore edoc doesn't need to use its
internal mechanism for correlating
messages that means that we set the
variable
core to the fixed value 3
next slide
so
my intention in this presentation is to
actually present the idea to the
community to get
your feedback and our next steps are to
add the
feedback received continue adding the
protocol details and work on making the
design compatible
with this draft based on
app for radios next slide please
and to end this presentation i will be
pleased to hear from the participants
whether they think this draft makes
sense as a working group item
or not and please be welcome for any
other comments
thank you
are you still in the queue
no
okay
uh so i i can say as an individual
participant
maybe uh some some at some point uh
why why not uh right now i think uh
it's maybe a little bit too early but uh
perhaps uh when they when a doc is
perhaps a little bit i don't know maybe
maybe one more right
cycle and maybe a dock is almost done
and then we can go start deploying a
dock in these other
protocols but uh doing that right now
maybe
i don't know at least personally i feel
it might be just slightly
early but maybe others have
differing opinions
okay okay
john go ahead uh i think
as support is draft i think it may be a
bit
too early to adopt it
ad hoc is now adopted by lake but
which means that you could work on it
in parallel but there's no hurry
it would still have to wait until lake
publishes ad hoc
okay
well i guess that's all uh thank you for
your comments
and and i think so far i will continue
working on parlor but
of course i understand your your opinion
that still there are many changes to be
done on edoc
so i will take that into account
yep i guess joe the next step is to
continue the discussion on this draft on
emu and lake whenever needed if there is
some requirements that epad dock
requires from
from a dog and the lake working group
then of course it should not wait
for a dog to finish but perhaps we can
revisit this
next next idea yeah i think that makes
sense
to to kind of you know just let let ad
hoc uh
kind of go through a cycle at least to
kind of get
get it a little more stable and then you
know
we'll you know see if any additional
issues pop
out of that and and then we can start
thinking about adoption
okay thank you
all right i think that is the end of our
agenda
yep indeed uh we seem to be
20 minutes ahead of time does anyone
have
some comments uh before we close the
meeting
any words of wisdom before we part
all right well i guess we'll see you at
uh
intf 110 or perhaps at some interim
uh meeting between then uh
yeah i would just like to thank uh roman
for taking the notes
thank you roman
yeah thanks
it was only me in the beginning others
helped for the rest of it i i only got
the first two sessions so only a little
bit of credit
thank you you broke the ice though so
all right we'll see you in gather town
or somewhere else
bye bye bye
you