well by now
i'll be very surprised
but of course we are operating under
this note well welcome to the extra
session
at ihf 109 virtually in bangkok
we have a couple of
submitted documents that i'd like to
just do a status check on
and then we have three work items to
talk about and we'll finish by reviewing
our milestones
so looking across at those couple of
documents
braun can i yes quickly interrupt you uh
who's taking notes uh i'll probably take
notes actually
i have the session open to do that
all right then
just want to make sure that nothing is
lost
yep thank you
so we want to look at the
documents
so we have fetch preview and sieve
mailbox id that are both
sitting uh submitted for publication
and in area director follow-up so barry
if you
are available to to talk to what's
happening there that would be great
i know it's civ mailbox id the the most
recent thing on that
yep go ahead which one the fetch preview
um okay i mean i guess what's
status of that is i need to go look at
it so yeah let me do
while we're having this meeting and i'll
get back to you cool
yeah i think that fetch preview is
pretty much ready to go the big
discussion point was
civ mailbox id was how to deal with the
case where you specified
a mailbox id and a
special use in the same document
um so in that case right
what i said to do in there was
to resolve mailbox id first because it
is the most explicit and exact thing
um right then to go go and follow the
special use process which includes
creating a new mailbox with that special
use if it doesn't exist
but it's it's basically binding the
mailbox i do most tightly
which i think does actually also make
most sense because it's the most
explicit
thing but it's very unlikely that
anybody would ever specify both
well and that's that's really my
question that um
it doesn't make sense to me to specify
both and it would make me happier
although i'm not going to hold out
on this one too long but i wanted to
have the discussion
it it would make more sense to me to say
that they that you can't put them
together
because in the one case you're looking
for a specific mailbox
by id and in the other case you're
looking for a function
and yeah put them both in the same
command yeah i guess the the question is
whether
the the answer there should be don't do
it and it's not allowed or don't do it
but if it does happen then then here's
how it works
i would prefer to say don't do it it's
not allowed but as i said
i'm not going to hold out on it once we
have the discussion
does anyone though i guess what i'd like
to ask is does anyone have a use case
where it actually makes sense
to specify both including a use case
where
you want to be tolerant of certain
errors and and it makes sense to do that
which i don't see it but if you
if someone wants to speak up for that
please
so what is the semantic of this going to
be do you have to
it has to be both have the id and
the special use no no it's the other way
around
the idea is that if you're using mailbox
id
it doesn't make sense to put special use
on also
and if you're using special use it
doesn't make sense to put
mailbox id on there and they're
completely different
things that won't work together now i
understand i was just trying to
uh think of if we are to leave the
combined
allow the combination of the two what
the semantic is going to be
ah the semantics would be that
if the mailbox id exists then you use it
otherwise you fall back to the special
use
yeah and the the most complex thing was
was this example here where there's
create as well
in which case if nothing existed it
would create a new mailbox with the
archive special use but it would not get
the same mailbox id
and and that specific one sounds like it
really would be an implementation
issue uh it would complicate
implementations
i mean you you have to check for the
mailbox id existing
then you have to check for the special
use existing and then you decide whether
you're going to create something
but what you create i guess would have
the
um the special use attached to it but
would be a different mailbox id
it it all seemed to have the same name
it seems much better to me to say that
it does not make sense to put them both
together and it's an error if you do
i'm happy to do that as well i think uh
i can't think of a reasonable case where
you would have to have both um i guess
it's a nice
fallback in in the case where that
mailbox gets deleted
that it would get recreated with the
special use but if
it gets deleted and then something
creates something with that special use
already then it will
file into there without having to create
a new one
and this is i'm thinking kind of on my
feet here
but the example i'm thinking of is that
you had to file into with the specific
mailbox id defined just because your
system
automatically does that but you also say
that the purpose is
as ascent folder and then
you might want to tie other things that
mailbox id in your sieve management
system as well
and then if someone went ahead and
deleted that mailbox and then
another client created a new mailbox
with that special use
you wouldn't necessarily want to go
ahead and create it yourself in your
script because
it had been created by another client in
the meantime
and and what if you cross the
international date line i mean you know
it starts i mean the answer there is to
make your sieve generation script not
use the mailbox id if it's
right for a file into my use um
let's see what ken has to say it's going
to work your way i i think i'm leaning
towards
very suggestion of making them mutually
exclusive and they cannot be used
together
especially in light of the fact that we
have a test for both
if the mailbox id exists and a special
use exists so
you can write a script that will handle
both cases just by using the tests
as opposed to having everything jammed
into one action
all right i will go ahead all right i
think
just say that okay thanks
cool done and you're going to read
through fetch preview which means we're
now on to the next item in our agenda
which is imap4 rev2
alexa you're welcome to share slides
yourself if you want or i can manage
them for you
um if you manage them for me that would
be
great thank you cool
so we do have murray here so that's
great um
right um quick update and the war
uh i think there were like three
revisions since
july um finishing
um yeah move to the next slide um
finishing comments from stefan uh as
well as
um catching few other remaining things
like list of recommended extensions and
stuff
um next slide please
that's right there you go
yeah so um on pointed out that
the text in the at the front of the
document was still talking about sort of
um changes in rfc
3501 which is previous version so needed
to be adjusted
i didn't quite go all the way with on
suggestions to list
everything that changed but um i think i
added enough pointers so hopefully this
is clear
um a few clarifications
um i've noticed that star tls
description
command description was uh saying that
it can
return bad if command is not recognized
well
how can it be not recognized if it's
here so that sort of
sounded like a silly case but um there
is a more useful one which is
if somebody issues 30 ls when tls is
already
active whether just repeated start tls
or on
telesport so this now is clear that this
returns bad
um we had several
there were several remaining issues from
um
last atf um about making sure that list
responses are mandatory for selected
and examine
so uh this is fixed and examples were
updated if people can send you check
examples that would be great um
some clarification there was some old
text about uid and x and ud validity
about
what the behavior is if they're not
there at the same time they are
mandatory
elsewhere in the text so it's it wasn't
entirely consistent so i think
yeah i basically deleted the old
text
and we also uh added some text about
how um mailbox canonicalization
whether it's due to normalization or
some other kind of mapping rules
can be done and how this is written
returning list responses
for when mailboxes get deleted when
mailboxes get renamed
like uh to specify that client
issued this name but now new name is you
know something else
um so please text about that
i think that's all changes oh actually
no i think there is another slide um
next slide please
yes um there are there are uh there were
a few more things we had discussion last
uh
itf that uh whether to clarify that
each you search with the currently
specified
options like mean man max count and all
uh whether it allowed to return multiple
research responses that have to be
amalgamated and now the document says
that
that's not allowed you can write an
extension which allows for that but
you'll need to specify this explicitly
um some editorial changes um
moving section specification into a new
subsection
of and um
referencing it elsewhere in the text
um there were several comments from
stefan about um
like for well-formed messages it's clear
what the date should be
what uh you know
in in envelope um and various other
places um
so there is now more clarity about how
this kind of football formed or draft
messages
so like when you wrote an empty strings
when you return nails and stuff like
that
next
now there is a reference to tls 1.3
um the text is worded such that
both are allowed in use um
tls 1.3 is recommended but uh
tls 1.2 is still loud um which i think
is very similar to recommendations
coming from
tls working groups anyway um
i cleaned up appendix d um they were
like
i was supposed to list all the pending
changes as well as changes made sense
i rationalized that i think i removed
everything that was done now because
we're really late in in the process and
there shouldn't be any open issues about
that
and then there is a new section about
recommended extensions
um i'll revisit this very quickly today
just to make sure that people are
comfortable
for now it it mentioned quicker sync on
store and object id but
we can discuss if people want to add
something else
next slide please
right um i was checking my notes and i
was like i thought i i did
everything and then i found out that uh
there was some changes in relationship
to supporting
64-bit message sizes
um i forgot to do this change
i think i still i or somebody or chairs
should probably still double check on
the main english that people are happy
to go with this because this
your servers don't have to support this
but the clients always have to support
this because they they have to
accommodate
bigger message sizes basically orbit bar
sizes
that shouldn't take very long um i
had a separate draft on this
which was parked few years back so uh
this is mostly just debian f
fixes to allow for bigger sizes
if you have opinions one way or the
other
please shout um i
double checked with teemo see ryan and
yesterday
he said that he served already support
64-bit
message and body part sizes so he will
be quite happy with this change
and from notes from our previous meeting
i think braun was happy
with this as well um but if somebody
really doesn't like it please let me
know
yeah the only challenge with it is what
happens if you have a message in your
store which is more than 32 bits
and a non-imap4rev2 client connects
does it get a truncated version does the
message not appear to it
um and how does that work and we haven't
solved this problem
no um particular trick is if you connect
us an imap
for rev1 do some queries decide to
upgrade to imac 4 rev 2 and suddenly
uids appear that were not present as
rev1
so it does mean that you need to treat
rev1 and rev2
as completely separate for caching
message id number
purposes if you're going to have
messages that disappear and reappear
depending which mode you're in
this is going to be very tricky to be
honest
i said i mean the the main thing is to
say either always use it for f2 or never
use i'm at 402 with the same server
don't mix them
yes which is probably a good good advice
anyway um
yeah so it might be worth putting
specific suggestion for that in the text
clients should not on pain of
confusion mix the two
because they'll be in there we'll make
sure this is in the notes please
so that we don't forget um and
i i think yeah we might need to discuss
the whole concept of hiding some
messages which are too big
to be exposed uh how this is going to
work
um however irrespective of this question
i think the document
as far as our
responsible id is concerned
i think murray can just review the
document as is
once this is implemented this will be a
very very small
small patch to the draft
so murray don't make it uh stop you from
reviewing the document
uh no problem this is reminding me is
this going through
another working your blast caller that
closed already
that should be closed okay yep the
working group last call
is finished i was just checking if
there's anything to oh i would have
submitted it
a couple of weeks ago but life got in
the way and now i thought we're going to
be talking about now anyway i'll submit
it after this just in case some last
minute thing comes up
okay yeah when it goes into publication
requested that's when i'll be able to
finish
it otherwise it doesn't get my attention
as easily as stuff on
pending telechats so yeah
which brings me to my request
can this be put into publication
requested
i think we discussed this uh maybe even
a couple months ago
yep we can do that i i wasn't sure if
this was the final version to do it but
i can certainly go ahead and do that now
it's
the last call has expired and there's
been no feedback on that
all right um
next slide just to triple check
um fairly new section
about recommended extensions
do people have any feelings about
whether we should
mention acl and multi multi mailbox
search
or anything else for that matter um
i don't have strong opinions on that
fuzzy's already in which is the main
thing in search
that that i really care about
but certainly i mean recommending is is
pretty
lightweight it's not
a requirement
yeah i suppose um
writing a client i found bits of acl
expect to be useful for example some
clients issue my rights very frequently
just to see whether they are allowed to
do various operations which
so um i
would be weakly suggesting to add
acl to the list just as a you know
obviously it might not work for
access control models for some mail
stores but if you do it you know do it
this way kind of thing
yep that makes sense and list returned
my rights as well
yeah i'd be in favor of including pcl
all right um multi-mailbox search
i think it it's a great functionality
not sure how
widespread it is so maybe
not just yet
but if you have an opinion please
come to the mic
it doesn't hurt either way as far as i'm
concerned because it's just recommended
so
you do it or you don't do it depending
how you feel as a server implementer
yeah well um i did add some weasley
words in the document saying that
uh if you don't see your favorite
extension here it doesn't mean that it's
not recommended so
just to make sure that people don't
think that these are you know
more blessed than others
but
i'm happy to edit if people are using it
we aren't we're doing other evil stuff
that's mostly gmap these days
what
okay uh is this the last slide i think
one more i think next steps
awesome all right then i will
submit it apologies if you can hear the
noisy helicopter that's just come over
my
house we cannot
excellent i have a very high quality
microphone it it
collects things at my mouth and not much
else which is fantastic because it's
super loud for me
so um just back on fetch preview
i put in an rfc editor note for the
a small edit that we had talked with rob
wilton about
and that michael hadn't put in but other
than that i
uh it's fine so i i gave it the final
approval
you should see it going to the rfc
editor queue anytime
great thank you
cool um
then we are done with i'm at four rev
two and we are well ahead of schedule at
the moment
but i guess we may as well move on to
our next topic
which is quota so alexi welcome back
yeah i was um my apologies for
i just posted the zero three yesterday
because
i haven't done much on it um
but changes are fairly simple
next slide please
next slide
yeah so um i was debating this for very
long time about
whether the document specifies status
deleted and
capability storage which is number of
deleted messages and number
uh total ties of delete messages
um i was sort of debating uh
four months with myself whether they
should be tied to specific
capabilities as in you know if your
server supports
quarter on message numbers then you
should support my
status deleted um
i didn't get much feedback on this but i
thought i'll just go ahead and
go with it and make it slightly easier
to implement
uh obviously if you do both uh already
that make no change
you know it doesn't make any difference
for you but if you are thinking about
implementing one another
then it makes it slightly easier to
implement on the server side
and then the idea is deleted and stated
deleted
storage is client can answer ask the
question
um how much space can i free to get
under quarter for example this sort of
thing
that's the point of that
next slide
oh yeah that's actually
possibly a question about
a map4f2
basically syntactic issue is that
response codes are not allowed to
have close square bracket and
tags are at the moment allowed to have
this
[Music]
do people have a strong opinion either
way i um
on one hand we can tighten definition of
tag to disallow this but
if there is any client that decides to
generate tags with this
then they will become non-compliant
with this change i'm slightly
apprehensive about it
yeah clients man
i would be pretty happy to say once
you've enabled map4rev2 you're not
allowed to use that in tags but
the problem is what do you do for i'm
for rev one
clients do they not have this over quota
supported
is it something that only gets turned on
in our map for rev2
or do you not generate them if the tag
is bogus
yeah i suppose we can say that you know
it will work most of the time as in
you know unless you have a stupid tag
it will work uh over quarter has
actually two forms one is
uh just over quarter with no tag uh it
means you know for the current
the current operation uh and over
quarters space tag
is for cases where um
you're moving message like from one
mailbox to another you sort of want to
know whether your current one is
reporter or the destination one so it
helps a little bit
um
how important is this uh
do people think as in to convey this
information that over quarter relates to
a specific
command as opposed to the current
mailbox
i don't think it's generally going to be
important
if if you're doing a move operation then
over quota is very likely to be the
destination and regardless your response
to getting an over quoted message is
going to be to tell the user hey you
can't do that
you hit a quota limit and you can then
poll the quotas at the various locations
if you want to check what happened
okay so actually uh
yeah sort of just like this but i think
you answered my question that it's
probably just drop this feature and
don't bother with
um this will avoid all sort of
complications
fine let's do that
unless i hear otherwise
i'll do this in an extra vision i think
that's it what's the next
is there are more slides to this i don't
remember now future directions
yeah my usual questions basically
anything missing anything
should be removed i think this is ready
for working group last call
um
cool should i do that with the next
document whether where the
uh over quota space tags been removed
uh fine i mean i guess you can always
upload that during yeah i can start the
working group last call now
and just note that you'll be uploading
one more version of the document that
will have this minor edit
yes that that would be my preferred
solution if you're happy with this
cool
done
awesome all right thank you alexi
uh next topic is gmap civ snooze from
ken
okay so uh the first revision zero zero
pretty much encapsulates what we have
implemented and are using
at uh fast smell at this moment
the next slide if you want to move
forward please
so what are we talking about here so
it's basically a sid action
that postpones the following of a
message to a later point in time
which essentially means that it behaves
very much like
a file into which is delayed
at some point in the future the draft
is somewhat vague on the actual
mechanics of house news works
but it does discuss that this could be
done either via
a special met mailbox or via smtp
currently we use a special mailbox at
fast mail
next slide please
so here's a current syntax um there's
one
required argument which is a list of
times
uh in hour minute second format
along with that there's a time zone id
string which is a a timezone ib
there is a list of weekdays using
strings but they're digits from 0 to 6
that borrows from
ned's date draft and finally there's a
destination mailbox
that you want the message to appear in
once it has awakened from its
snooze next slide please
so basically the uh combination of
weekdays
and times forms a chronological list
of awakened times so when a message
arrives
it gets snoozed until the next awaken
time in that list so
a couple quick examples obviously if
you've got something that's uh
monday through friday awaken times of 9
a.m and 3 p.m the message arrives at 8
a.m
it'll awaken the same day at nine it
arrives at three
um pixel if it arrives at noon it'll
it'll awaken at three the same day
and similarly if it arrives after three
pm on monday
it'll show up the following tuesday and
if it shows up
on the weekend late friday or saturday
or sunday would show up on monday
pretty straightforward i respect
next slide please
so we also support with our current
implementation of these various
extensions
so if you have imp for flags you can
specify
and add flags and remove flags option
which will set an unset flags when the
message is awakened
um you can use the
uh map4 flags with the variables if you
want to set something at snooze time
that's done via the internal variable so
that would be a set flag or add flag
actions
separately um
additionally going back to one of our
earlier conversations we actually
support
create special use a mailbox id
i will certainly update this draft to
discuss that mailbox id and special use
are mutually exclusive uh in that
respect but
in any case all three of those options
have to do with the
awaken mailbox not the
snooze mailbox
uh next slide please
so it was mentioned on the list by
stefan i believe uh he asked
why this is a separate action versus
just being additional parameters or
arguments
uh keep and file into which seems like a
logical discussion to have
two questions are what's the syntax
going to look like
and more importantly at least for our
use case how do you specify flags to be
set at snooze time
and at the awaken time
next slide please in terms of
[Music]
syntax i think there are three possible
options maybe more
if someone here has uh alternate
solutions i'm
open to hearing them so we could just
jam all the additional
arguments uh in line with the existing
file into
arguments um but if you've got something
that's gonna support
um you know the times
the weekdays the timezone id create
and special use the the list of
arguments is going to get pretty
unwieldy
kind of what we already have with uh fcc
uh i did some digging around the abn f
for civ itself
and it appears as if even though it
might be ugly
we could use the test list syntax
at the end of a command which appears to
be legal
so there's an example there of what this
may look like
um it kind of encapsulates all this new
specific stuff
uh into its own uh apprentice
uh its own um
structure at the the very tail end um
don't know how people feel about that uh
additionally on the next slide it also
looks like we could use
a block at the end of filing to or keep
which also appears to be legal for the
syntax
this seems a little bit cleaner to me
but again
it may confuse some parts just not sure
i actually haven't tried it with our
parser to see
how this would work it's also somewhat
confusing in that in this case snooze
really isn't its own
command it's just a way of
parameterizing file into
any comments or suggestions
um making this a separate
make making this part of keep a file
into and how to do the syntax
what is the advantage of making a part
of keep or fall into
other than than reusing the name i guess
i don't see any per se
but i'm open to hearing any argument
when people um list
interactions with other actions
this is less likely to be forgotten if
it's already an existing action
that i know it might not be a strong
argument but the fewer actions we have
the easier it is to list how you
interact with all of them
this is true
can uh ken can you uh
remind me why you want flags to be both
at the snooze time and then at delivery
time
i could let neil uh make that argument
if he wants to jump in
otherwise i'll i'll go ahead
sure uh is this on yes yes we can hear
you yep all right
great um yeah so basically
um at delivery time
the flags are set as pony normal stuff
so you might mark red
or pin or whatever uh but then at
awaken time um we set a particular
dollar new flag
so that we can mark out those messages
especially when they move back to your
inbox and then once when you actually
open the message we clear that flag
um we
and because conversations amalgamate
different messages some of which may
be snooze you
they also make keywords and so that that
could lead to
um
yeah so so so that that's basically so
you you could leak out even while it's
still in the snooze folder because it
might be flooded with other messages
i guess in theory you could set it when
you snooze
but i i think yeah it's safer to do it
when it you wake up because
you could again have more client logic
to exclude stuff that's currently lose
from the keywords
kind of malformation within a thread but
that's the reasoning
the other issue we have in our
implementation is because
we actually have a news mailbox that
that an imap client can see
the user could fiddle with flags and
change something that they may actually
may want to have
um set or run set when it actually does
get awakened
right yeah but this is really a you're
expecting user to sort of project how
this is working for your implementation
if they mess with flags you know they
probably know what they're doing
just well i mean yeah it depends which
flags obviously
clients make it very easy to change
things like the scene flag and
flag flag etc um
uh yeah i can have i'll bring up the
code down have a quick look but
it might be okay if you only set them
on delivery um
but i'd have to double check all the
things we do to see if that is going to
work
i just see this as an option that
users are likely to confuse themselves
with i don't object to having it but i
can't imagine
actually using it and i
can see if you don't use it very
carefully
you're going to wind up getting some
parts of a conversation
delivered right away and others snoozed
which probably isn't what you're really
meant to have so
i mean as long as the
if all the messages are actually
delivered to a mailbox it's just it's
delivered to a snooze mailbox and
the conversation view in your client
shows all of them
then you won't like miss some that were
snoozed earlier if
something else comes in like that's
actually a valid use case if like
you normally you would snooze it because
if it's from a main list you don't care
about too much but if it comes from a
particular person you do care about you
don't want that to be snooze
that conversation will now show up in
your inbox and the previous messages
from people you don't normally care so
much about that were snooze will still
be in thread
for you to get the context that depends
upon whether your client
is uh threading them that way and not
all clients
do that's true that's presumably a
thread across mailbox not just within a
member so it might be worth putting
something like that
in uh as non-normative text in in the
document
um somewhere of uh maybe implementation
considerations
just warning that this can cause some
funny things depending on how the client
displays the messages
that's all yeah i i brought this up
on the list um that there's some
security in
um you know implications here um
and they they vary pretty dramatically
depending on how you implement this if
you implement it like
using a future release sort of mechanism
uh then the messages aren't visible at
all anywhere until they're unsnoozed
um and that has some really i think
potentially
you know serious implications um
you know to users uh and if you use the
mailbox trick where you put them in one
and then switch them to another you get
different behavior
but the other thing you you know when
you use those different tricks you know
the delivery dates are going to be very
different
and the threading situation is going to
be different um you know
lots of potential confuse you know for
confusion here yeah i mean we didn't
really go with the deliver to a special
mailbox one which i think solves the
most these problems the delivery date is
the regular delivery date because it's
not delivered late um it's threaded in
with all the other messages immediately
if you want to go find you can search
with everything else
um i i think that the the reason the
spot's kind of
more open on that you know maybe maybe
the right thing to do
it that's how you have to implement it
if that's you know if that's bad
yeah i think
yeah i think it was the spec was written
this way to just try and
make it easier to accommodate for if
there's existing systems doing something
different but having said that
i don't think any i know of are doing a
delayed delivery
um but please correct me if someone
knows about one that is implementing
this in a different way
well the point is you're bothering
themselves you have no way of predicting
what people are going to do in the
future
you know if someone sees publishes in
rfc and they already have
you know they already have future
release that's just a logical way to
implement it
i mean yeah absolutely i was saying
sorry the issue that ned and i are
bringing up isn't that we shouldn't
do this but that you need to say more in
the document
to guide people who are implementing it
on what the pitfalls are
and you know you can say that if this is
implemented this way it works better
than if it's implemented that way or
something like that
um but without that you might get some
very weird implementations that could
cause problems
yeah and you you've got a security issue
either way because people
you know average users aren't going to
know to look for some special snooze
mailbox
you didn't even gonna occur in the um
queue for a while too so let's not
forget
so who's
daniel gilmore is is in queue just yep
just talk isn't it
still very soft
okay hopefully um
so uh i i want to uh second that the
other thing i think is right on that we
should
think about how this is going to
actually perform for for the user
um i think barry's concerned that like
if someone setting flags that they know
what they're doing
is maybe not um
maybe not correct what we're specifying
here is not actually something that's
like
a user-facing feature this is like a
mechanism that i would imagine
good male clients will
use to implement something that the user
is going to understand right like
they'll have a fuse button in it and
they'll choose one standard set of
behaviors
um and they'll implement and they'll
they'll encode that maybe
via active uh command on the back end
but the user is not going to be
like crafting what these specific
options are
right that just seems unlikely to me so
i think you know
i think that kind of guidance for um
male user agent implementers um is going
to depend on what the back ends actually
do and so i think that
you know this this idea that will make
it generic and you can do arbitrary back
ends
isn't actually a safe thing to specify
so i i support the idea of
um saying that this is you know you
really shouldn't do this with smtp
um you know delayed delivery or anything
like that
yeah i i'd be happy with that i also
think it makes sense because if you're
this is just for basically creating
rules that snooze if you're going to
implement snooze
like manually for a user you're going to
need a special folder for anyway the
best years have already been delivered
uh so it it's much better to use a
single mechanism and have two different
mechanisms of doing snooze depending
whether it's
on delivery time or manually afterwards
um
i also i just had another quick look at
what we're doing
um the reason we want uh to be able to
set flags on awaken time
uh the main one is uh some some users
said that they want it to be marked
unread when it's awakened
but they don't want it to be marked
unread immediately because they might
have a
view that shows all on their mail they
currently have and so you don't want it
showing up there until it's
news
we include that as an example um
right i mean as you're writing this
draft we're thinking about how
implementers are likely to use it
and just having you know a sentence
example of you know this is one way that
you can use it
uh might might be useful that
yeah that makes sense right without
example like there is quite a lot of
extra complexity
that the draft is proposing which is
like you know
i think i'm just about to be convinced
that it might be worth it but
please add an example at least yeah
yeah i i definitely would probably lean
towards i think mandating you
use a special mailbox not future release
and
let's register if you're not already the
role for the imac game roles
uh special use registry uh
like yeah
i'm fine with that appending any strong
objections to leaving it
open-ended like it is now
um as far as synthetic is concerned um
the the one on the screen i think it's
very cute but
it's sort of i'm concerned that it will
break
quite fastly it might not be a bad
thing you know if your pastor doesn't
know about it
um
yeah that comes down to whether we want
to make this its own action
or roll it into keeping file into right
so i think that's the first decision we
made and then
if we decide to go with the keeper 512
with the settle on the syntax
right do you have any strong opinions on
that alexi or no
um i have slight preference for using
file into
but then it comes with so you're saying
it comes with extra synthetic complexity
i don't know or you have a lot of extra
arguments
yeah it's it's news
yeah as neil said it's not really making
it more complex it's just making it
unwieldy with the number of options that
can be in there and they
i guess i'm just i don't like the fact
that you've got
a set of flags a set of options that
apply to one particular functionality
that could be spread all over the place
right
by definition the tags are unordered so
you know you could have these things
intermingled with any other file into um
argument like we had with with fcc which
you know
after having written that um and
implemented it it this looks kind of
ugly
yeah i think it's gonna be cleaner as a
separate command because you have
multiple arguments you need for the
snows and as ken said if they're
intermixed with
other arguments and they only make sense
if you like
a snooze add flags argument only makes
sense if you have a separate snooze
argument so it's invalid if you have one
not the other
it seems cleaner to me to have a
separate command but i don't really care
what the syntax is usually i'm just
it's just might be
actually related to that do we have a i
am registry for action
we there's a registry for the extensions
but
not specifically for actions i don't
believe
it's just it's just an extensions
registry i mean
you know an extension can define one
action zero actions 50 actions
i know but it would be nice you know uh
even if you're writing you like if
you're considering interactions
or you know look up in action and find
out
all the other seeds of the being
mentioned and all of this
yeah i get your point it's it's a valid
point that
you know we didn't really think about
you know the fact that things have to
enumerate their interactions pretty
thoroughly
ned i know you've you've implemented a
lot of the stiff stuff do you have any
strong
opinions on whether to make this its own
separate action or to roll it into
keeping file into
i don't have a strong opinion though i
really don't
um there's arguments either way i
i'm i am a little concerned about the
whole
you know using tricky syntax
um to do things i wonder if i mean
i can handle that in my implementation
but i
uh i mean i have the ability to
you know um evaluate arguments
you know it says mine's essentially call
by name is what it boils down to
and if your implementation works that
way you can probably handle this but
they're probably our implementations
don't work that way
yeah fair point we're kind of
limited by the by the fact that 5228
does not allow arguments to arguments
and these are only two ways that these
are only two ways they could find even
shoehorn stuff
all right
um i'm not
i i mean you know the way i though you
know i i
this will probably sound stupid but uh
you know basically what you do is you go
through the code and look for all the
places where you're
doing those you're looking around at
file enters and you make sure that
they're looking at snoozes where it's
appropriate
so it's not that hard to add
you know all of the interact you know to
deal with all the interactions
right again that's how my implementation
works who knows
yeah that that's how ours does too it
kind of treats 512 and snoozes
you know equivalent actions with
somewhat different semantics
what can i say
i think after listening to this i'm
leaning towards
let's do a separate uh action
just that's that's kind of what i'm
hearing too uh
and uh we can have a separate discussion
you know
uh registry for actions that might be
just a nice thing to do anyway
i i noted that as potentially a separate
draft
um anyone want to volunteer to author
that
well i seem to care so i think
yeah but if somebody wants to help me
out i mean it should be just a simple
iron registration
cool all right i don't think i have any
more slides i think the last slide was
basically discussing what we've already
discussed
yep that's the final slide
all right um so i guess the next step is
for you to go back and rewrite
uh having made it that it requires
the message to be placed into into a
folder somewhere that the user can see
somehow
and creating the snoozed registration
and i didn't quite follow is is a snooze
mailbox then
a special use mailbox a new kind of
okay it's a new special use so that will
get registered
are we going to limit this to imap
servers
oh it's just for example
i'm sorry i like say i was talking over
there i didn't hear what you said uh it
was just as well does jm app
yes that that's so that's i mean yeah my
question was
we don't want to limit this to just imap
servers it obviously it could you could
make this work with a mailed or
mailed their server as well right
yeah so we can make it that if if uh
you're using an imap or jam up server
then you should
file these messages into a mailbox with
special use snoozed
as registered here right
and then but people can still do it
other ways so
yeah it
i don't know maybe a silly argument but
if you use pop for access
with save then you this will be just not
something you can access
probably until you you get the message
just to be clear we want to remove any
hint of using smtp to implement this
from the draft correct
i think i've got even more over
suggesting
not to do that
yeah that's what i had okay but we just
want to discuss
potential security issues and pitfalls
in doing so
ideally yes okay i'll
i'll craft some text along those lines
and then hopefully i can get some help
with
wordsmithing things that aren't clear
or incomplete
right all right thanks thanks everyone
the last
thing that we have here is just a glance
at our milestones
looks like civ ai we still need to come
back to
quota is there to be sent off timings
about right there ima 402 will be
submitted now
sip mailbox id has been submitted so i
can mark that one as done
and sif's news has been adopted so i'll
update that and mark that as done
i don't think we've got anything new to
add there other than
to adopt a document creating
the civ actions registry do we have any
other work
that anyone wants this working group to
be doing
that was a a not really
um because i suspect that given that we
will finish this work off
fairly early next year and we'll be very
quiet for a little bit
which i'm fine with until being a
working group that can
take up issues as they come up in this
space because there's
there's still plenty of action
and how email core is going that being
quiet for a while is a good thing
i i agree
all right thanks everybody uh in that
case we've basically finished our time
here so
go grab yourself some popcorn and a
stiff drink and prepare for
the plenary
see you later now nice to hear your
voice
yeah looking this time thanks i
appreciate it
bye all bye