okay well
it looks to me like it's time for us to
start
first order of business uh can you hear
me somebody speak up or wave or
something
yes you're very much audible excellent
is that james
yes yes okay well uh on behalf of james
and myself welcome to everybody
uh good morning good evening good
afternoon
depending of which uh depending where
that applies wherever you are
um i'm actually uh kind of surprised and
delighted
at the number of people here um
so so let's get straight to it oh and
more coming in
all the time can we move along there
james next slide yep
right so whether or not you have been
involved
in the ietf before um
read this it it matters there are
certain rules that apply as regards
intellectual property
and conduct and so on and and they're
not optional
so um please do read this and take it
seriously
um moving on
right please we need a volunteer for
note taking who's going to put up their
hand
well there are lots of people who wrote
excellent drafts and have obvious you
know
writing skills at least one of them
ought to be able to
to to take notes for us
i will take notes for you tim i just got
to pull up the
eat the ether pad excellent uh
who is that speaking sorry
was michael richardson
michael richardson thank you very much
michael um
let me know when you've got that running
it's asking very jabber scribe uh i'll
i'll just keep an eye out on jabba if
if anybody is unable to use their might
you can just prepend
send a message in the chat with mike at
the start of it and
i'll do the talking for you
excellent thank you for that um for
those of you who haven't used the
interface before you can
detach the chat so you can see both the
user list and the chat that that's
that's quite useful
okay um thank you uh both for for
pitching in
um now uh if the agenda that's
posted as the agenda was very minimal
but then there's a larger agenda
uh maybe james we could look at that
and before we do anything else just a
couple of words
my notion was to see if there were a few
sort of big and
unsubtle issues that we might have a
good hope of uh making progress on here
in real time
but i'm not religious and i don't think
james is about this either
um anybody would like to uh object to
one of these or
um or add something they think would be
a good candidate
now would be a good time to speak up
um along with the compliance test suite
do we want to talk about
a reference implementation
um what do people think
i mean there are lots of implementations
out there
yeah i was thinking of one uh i've been
developing one
in line with one of the drafts to kind
of exercise the draft
and push out any corners along with it
just a way just to help to as
a way of developing the draft
so as a working group
i think we should work on our document
and not on a reference implementation
but
on the other hand i think we would be
better off if we had one
or two reference implementations that we
can throw examples against
and decide whether
what the people who wrote the reference
implementation understood of the
document
actually matches what we want out of the
may i suggest that what we do is when we
get to compliance test suite in the
agenda we
we cover that together with um a
reference implementation since the two
are closely linked
yeah thank you okay fair enough
anything else
okay without further ado then let's get
into this
um now the general
issue here is the writing and review
process uh there are
you know the vast majority of working
groups these days i believe are using
github
and a sort of a hybrid approach with
github issues and
on working group mailing list
conversations
there's a couple of decent rfcs that
describe the process 80
88 74 and 75
and i i just wanted to to to avoid
future surprises by
by putting this on the agenda and giving
anybody a chance who has strong opinions
about the way we should
do things to speak up now i think that
the process is working pretty well
across quite a few working groups but if
there's
somebody who has deep objections to
github or to doing anything on the
mailing list or
wants to approach this in a non-typical
way now would be a good time to speak up
and at a metal level um uh
if you're going to speak up let's let's
use the the list you push the little uh
up raise hands button and and we'll call
on you things work better that well
so i if i'm going to shut up and if i
hear silence for a little while i'm
going to assume
that means everybody's fine with the
typical
hybrid github and mailing list approach
okay so found excellent
um now uh there's one meta issue uh
james and i have been discussing a bit
about so we're going to have to
name and edit an editor or co-editors um
and uh several of you have have
expressed willingness to put cycles into
that so thank you
so much for that it's it's so great to
have people who have energy to do that
um uh speaking you know personally
my instinct and i've talked about this
to some you know really
seasoned iatf hands is to have you know
fewer rather than more editors
so so i think most most likely will
probably want to
um ask one of you to step forward um and
the idea is that if you're not netter
that on
enables uh unleashes more energy you can
put into the discussions
and and uh we would like to have lots of
people putting
energy into the discussions um so thank
you for
ever for that and and james and i will
think about it and probably have further
conversations
with with you folks
okay we have two existing input drafts
um we're going to have to get to the
point where we have a succession of
working
of working group drafts um i think
people on the call probably understand
the uh the normal process that works you
have working group drafts and we have
consensus calls and update the drafts
and eventually we're all happy and
take it and convince our ads that things
are fine and take it forward
does anybody have strong opinions on how
we should move from our existing
two drafts to a consensus working group
draft
i think you're not seeing my raised hand
um i'm not oh sorry i was
wrong
yeah so we have two drafts one was
essentially generated from the original
article and essentially just updated a
little bit but not completely
for 2020 and one is
charging ahead and and defining some
details
um and i think that's actually a very
good situation because we have
input for both the introductory part and
and the detail part
of the document so the next step i think
we should do is just merge the two
drafts uh which is probably easier when
we have had the discussions
we have to have today so we have answers
and and
can select between text where we have
different
pieces of text but that might give us a
good basis for
going ahead
uh i guess the question i would have to
the to the working group is
do we have we've got glenn here so we've
got the editor
for one of the documents uh without me
having to scroll through
would would would uh
both of the editor would both of the
editors to that
uh be willing to put in the time to help
uh
editorialize what would then become the
the starting
uh working group a doctor adopted
document
do you mean both of the editors of that
or return of both
those uh the former not the latter
i think go ahead glenn
glenn you have no audio
no you're still muted
okay i have to join the queue thank you
um
so edward shiroff and i were nominally
editors
of the the other draft marco has been
joining in the
writing process so i don't have a strong
feeling about
um you know continue i'm happy to offer
that
uh if anybody else wants to kind of
take the lead on that i'm very happy um
i think edward has
has got some time available i don't know
if he's on the call
he seems to have had less time available
more recently so i suspect he's not in a
position to offer that
but i'm guessing there
okay so i i think i'm hearing
consensus that um nobody
is really attached to the notion that it
must start from document a or document b
and nobody is objecting to the notion of
creating
you know a working draft uh taking input
from both of them so
um would i be correct in saying that's
that's the feeling that i'm hearing
okay hearing no objection that's fine i
i thought they were
oh uh uh oh glenn go ahead
yeah i'll just voice one concern which
is that
um there are a number of things in the
original gerstner article
which um were kind of uh dangling links
uh you know things that weren't
dereferencable
uh promises that weren't uh delivered
and such like
and there's a little bit concerned that
if we took that as a starting point
the camel would have got its nose under
our tent as it were
and we could soon end up with the whole
camel there uh if you
use that analogy and um so i'd be happy
to take that as input
and cut and paste sections of it to
provide introductory material
uh so i prefer to start with a blank
slate sheet
or um possibly start with the draft that
i've been working on because
the approach there was to go for a
minimal subset that should be
non-contentious
and that should satisfy the um the
consensus amongst the current
implementations so i was trying to be
conservative there
so it'd be easy to adopt but i don't
mind if we start from a blank sheet and
cut and paste from both of them
but just be a little bit nervous about
taking the whole of
the ghost document to start with because
it's very difficult to remove text
it's easier to add text incrementally
that's my personal
position
does anybody know if hans gustner is
actually interested in
participating in this work well
you know stefan told me that
[Music]
his interest in this work his uh
focus has shifted back from from
computer related stuff to mechanical
engineering
related stuff in in the last decade or
so so he's not going to
put in major cycles but he's certainly
interested
and he has already asked me about the
progress of
this activity because things take some
time
starting up in the ietf so i think he
will be around
i think he won't have strong opinions
on detail issues
but i think he's he's generally happy
with with the
approach of finally having a document
here
kristin you're at the front of the queue
is there anything else you wanted to say
i just just wanted to say to glenn that
i'm a part of the people who
find it easier to delete text than to
add text
so maybe we have different sets of
experiences
here of course not not all of the the
original 2007 article has has become
true so
we will have to to look at that and
that's maybe a welcome opportunity to to
actually
uh check uh whether there are maybe some
some nooks and crannies of the jason
parker universe where some of this has
actually happened
and that we may have to to look at but
yes so um there is an appendix that
describes the current implementation of
2007 and that that's probably not useful
anymore at this point in time and so on
excellent i mean i like what i'm hearing
it sounds like nobody is particularly
religious
about how we're going to use this and
we'll use the material from
from both of them to work towards a
an actual working group draft um
great okay so i think i think we all
understand where we stand on that one
does anybody want to say anything else
about
about the existing drafts and how we're
going to move forward
excellent okay so um moving on the
agenda there's the
compliance test suite and the related
you know reference implementation
um you know i i i'm i'm perhaps being a
little bit self-indulgent and putting on
this
having had a lot of experience in this
stuff i i think that
compliance tests are insanely valuable
um and i understand they are never the
part of the official output of a working
group but um
i i just wanted to put on the record
that i i'd like
i'd like it i'd really like it a lot if
we produced a compliance test suite that
was conformant with the actual document
we produced so glenn is that entirely
your work up till now
uh yeah the um cts as part of the um
reference implementation repos is my day
yeah
yeah one or two people may have chipped
away at it but it's mainly my day
okay and you're okay with posting that
uh and
i haven't looked i it's on a repo and
and you'll be open to taking pr's and
things like that
sure yeah
any other opinions on on
test suites and reference
implementations and anything we should
be careful to do or avoid doing
glenn go ahead yes um an approach i took
with this
test suite was to make it lag strictly
behind the draft
because it's easy to get ahead of the
draft and then you end up with
essentially uh tested behavior that's
not specified
which i think is anathema to this this
group so i
kind of recommend that approach really
to try and let you know if there's a
reference implementation
certainly if there's a compliance test
suite to have it lag behind the the
words in the text
rather get ahead of the words in the
text of course we can do branches
to experiment
cool thank you kirsten
yeah what glenn said so um
it's really easy to have a document that
that
doesn't really describe things and the
compliant test suite that that does
and then you you run into ambiguities
and so on so
it's probably a good idea to to have a
good way to reference
uh back from the test suite to the
document to make sure that things that
are in there
are either rooted in the document
or are actually proposals for something
that needs to be put in the document but
isn't there yet
so i think it's useful to have that as
part of a test suite as long as it's
clearly separated but i would like to
repeat
my my observation that it's not really
the job of the working group
to do compliance test suites and and
reference implementations um actually
some itfa groups have done that so for
instance the opus people have actually
generated a
reference implementation so we could do
that but it would be a somewhat unusual
[Music]
way of of going forward for for a group
like this
okay i understood alexander
yes uh thanks everyone um i want this
account what what carson has said i i
think we should be careful so that
not the reference implementation
actually drives the standardization
effort because what could happen is that
people actually look us sideways on the
implementation and say oh we actually
found out
that it would be not much nicer if we
tweaked here and there
so that the implementation suddenly
becomes the driving force in
standardization i think that shouldn't
happen
yeah so so um the the
the reference implementation however you
want to call compliance you
shouldn't be an official work item of
the working group in the first place
yeah yeah
good point i hadn't actually considered
the issue of the official status
but but that's a good one we should look
at i i had seen it as unofficial you
know just in
i'm reflecting the personal bias um i've
found that having a
test suite actually more than a
reference implementation to be
tremendously useful and
what you cautioned against actually
something that i found useful is if if
if a change comes in and it turns out to
be really hard to implement in the
in the test suite or really hard to test
that it's maybe a pretty good signal
that you know
maybe there's a you want to look
carefully at that uh rick taylor please
go ahead
i'll try again unmuted um actually tim
you just covered
pretty much my point which was um
test suite as a working group item seems
a bit of a stretch
but uh a a
a a set of uh
worked examples with canonical
results so rather than the test suite
implementation the
the the the body of data sorry it's
early and my brain's not running at full
speed
a body of data to use as a uh
as a sweet check for your own
implementation would be
incredibly useful and possibly a valid
working group
working group item okay
fair enough i i will take an action item
to find out you know
what is the conventional wisdom about
potentially actually adopting such a
thing as a
as a working group item i would i would
be uh
in favor of having that done i i either
way but anyhow
yeah uh uh carsten again
yeah so let me contribute myself um
we like to have good examples in
specifications
and that may be somewhat of an anathema
to to people who think that
specifications should be
overly formal documents that you need a
phd to understand
and so that's not usually the way we
look things in the itf
um so good examples are kind of a test
suite
a little bit and we actually have
built test suites out of the examples
uh in an rfc but there is
essentially never a way to be complete
in that but implementers tend to read
the examples first and then the text and
not the other way around
and julian has agreement well julian do
you want me to
say that sorry
sega julian has a comment in the chat
so julina said that's what we did for
the http
structured headers specification
except that i don't know what that is uh
yes julian any more detail on that would
be welcome
in the in the meantime oh julian's on
the queue excellent we'll get to him
glenn
yeah um i understand
that the um a piece of software
is going to rot over time and so it
can't be a deliverable
of a working group because it will just
become irrelevant
but given that the compliance test suite
is probably going to be a piece of json
text
we could even make that an appendix of
the internet draft
and that's probably a really bad idea
but i'd like to understand why
and it could then someone explain why we
shouldn't do this something like that
that's definitely an interesting idea
and something we should explore
alexander thank you um
i actually it just came to my mind i see
one opportunity and one risking that in
that
compliance test street um the risk is
any implement of any any chest path
implementation would like
run their code against that compliance
suit and consider it
100 compliant even if that compliance it
probably doesn't cover 100 percent of
the specification
that's the risk that i see so we need to
be very clear on what that compliance
you does actually cover
um and and now to the better thing to
the opportunity i think as soon as we we
have final residue in jsonpass
the idf will want to have a validation
tool that whenever jsonpass appears in
their documents in future drafts they
want to validate it
so you might want to talk to the idf
tools people
to see if they have experience with
other languages that they integrated
into the
authoring tools
interesting point julian
hello can you hear me yes
i had to grab a headset sorry um so the
http structured header spec is something
that defines a new microsyntax for
header fields in http um
so because of the whites
because of the many differences that we
have in header syntax
so this is essentially uh
a micro a language to to describe header
fields and tags
and um so that spec is currently an auth
for the edge
um so to be published and the the
working group are actually the editor of
the spec mark nottingham
came up with a set of test inputs and
um expected test output so that's not
part of the spec but but that happened
in parallel
to writing the spec and
following up to what was just asked
before um
in in the new v3
rfc format world we can tag source code
and artwork with
types and based on the type we can run
validation tools on that
that's not yet part by part of the rfc
publication pro
process but for instance it's part of
the tool chains that many working groups
or some working groups use to
build their specs from markdown
so in particular mark nottingham just
wrote a validator for http messages that
you might have in examples
so um this is relatively new but um we
should look into that and that's
clearly possible cool
glenn you might want to have a look at
that
rick again hi guys
i just had a quick look at the jason
pointer rfc
just as a sort of cross-reference and
that has
some uh examples which
you know personally i found extremely
useful to start building a test
validation suite from
so perhaps as a pragmatic approach at
least having some examples
that are fairly canonical and cover most
of the corner cases
within the actual specification goes a
long way
and then the working group can can worry
about
producing a test suite as a further
charter item
that would just be my approach
yep cool i i mean my experience is i've
you know
been engaged in the development of
various dsls of one
kind or another and i notice the ones
that when they launch have a command
line validator that anybody can
just download and run people find that
just
just insanely helpful and i recognize
the risk that you know somebody might
over rely on that and assume that if it
passes the validator everything's fine
but but still it's a useful tool okay i
think i'm hearing
um julian go ahead
you're muted julian
can clearly sorry yeah yeah um
one more thought about test cases so if
we have test cases it's extremely
helpful to have
also test cases for invalid syntax
and potentially also for example
diagnostics that you
might want to produce because that's a
good way to
avoid having implementations except
things that they shouldn't accept
so we want to that's actually a good
point do we want to be draconic and
error handling
just a question i think we should
yep that's clearly an issue for the
working group to take up we're going to
have to
have something to say about air
semantics
okay i think i could summarize our
consensus as everybody seems to be
friendly to the idea
of you know something ranging from one
extreme to having good examples
to on the other extreme having a fairly
complex to you know another option
having
you know uh test inputs and outputs to
actually having runnable code and and
you know i think we can all agree that
work done in any of these areas is
helpful we'll have to see if any of it
has official standing
um but you know i certainly think we
we're all friendly to such work and
would appreciate it
anybody who does it anything more on the
subject before i move along
okay that was useful thank you okay
an actual material technical issue and
and maybe we can we can settle this so
as everybody knows the original gessner
spec
um uh specifies syntax for how you could
how you could
jsonpath could reach out and you know
invoke functions
um but didn't actually specify anything
about what the functions would be or
what language it would be
and you know various implementations
have done various things
and um i would be very interested to
hear the sense of the working group
as to well what should we do i'm not
going to constrain it at all
what should we do about this who would
like to have an opinion about that
kirsten go ahead yeah i don't understand
the question
um so um what does specified scripting
language mean
the the original uh
article says use whatever scripting
language you have
and that's certainly not a model that
that
is very useful and specifying a
scripting language
might mean we come up with an
expression language that can be used in
jsonpath
or it might mean oh let's all do python
and and
you can do python in in these
parenthesis and
problem solved and i think the the
answer to the second
approach is no and the answer to the
first approach is
um yes so let's specify that expression
language
and find out what is actually needed in
that expression
language so the the original code from
from
stefan had essentially a regex
parser for this expression language so
it was very limited
in the level of complexity you you could
express
with it but it actually already turned
out to be useful for people
um so i think yes we should specify that
expression language
rick carsten
beat me to it um i'm i'm in full
agreement with carsten
uh so specifying the
uh syntax for the expressions
uh used for for searching
absolutely uh specifying external
function
access um is is a step too far
um and i think is out of scope um having
implemented jsonpath parsers
in non-scripting languages
the ability to have a constrained but
reasonably flexible expression language
is incredibly powerful and and
i really support that effort but
um expecting that your entire
implementation is javascript or python
or or whatever
that's that's a non-starter for me
anyway
glenn yeah i think i
agree with what's been said so far um
there is a bit of a distinction
in my mind between filters uh the
square brackets question mark round
brackets stuff
and the um the camera scripting
expression um
side of things which seems more
open-ended
and certainly when i've implemented this
in the past the filters came out fairly
cleanly and didn't seem to you know the
there's quite a lot of consensus amongst
the implementations about what filters
are
valid uh but on the other side there was
complete
lack of consensus and my concern there
is just how would we
as a group come to any kind of consensus
because i could imagine people uh
just arriving at a late stage and saying
oh what about this function what about
that function
and you know how how does that work in
the ietf
because there's no kind of defined
membership of the group you know and
it's
there's no bound to when the the
discussion is over as far as i can tell
well on the ladder yes there is when you
publish your rfc you've published your
rfc
and it's immutable now you know they can
be replaced or superseded by by
subsequent
rfcs but um you know i i
i think we probably don't want to become
like another ekma
owning a language for the foreseeable
future uh
please no um but you know what
i i hear what you're saying
rick i'm
i'm agreeing again roughly with everyone
i think the tipping point with filters
from my implementation experience is
when
language features such as the name of
the type
of the property attribute
is string then you've sort of crept into
language implementation detail
when it's you know is is the length of
the string less than 10
fine is the value of the property 1.1
that's all great but when you start to
implement what looks an
awful lot like language implementation
features i think
that's the line in the sand which we
shouldn't cross as a working group
then we invent another language
you there as the topic of
extending this thing later
like in a subsequent rfc came up we
absolutely need to be sure that
we define what is an extension point for
the future and what is not
so um
for instance in the http 2 um
work we found that things that were
supposed to be extension points
and be useful for future modifications
of the protocol
were not implemented properly so once
those things get exercised these
implementations break
so we need to have um a plan
for what is must ignore and what what is
must understand
if if you see something that you don't
expect
just a thought
kirsten again yeah i
would have thought of extension points
with julia and hadn't beat me to it
so i think that that's really important
to to understand
and i think it's also really important
as you said to exercise extension points
so
the the draft if the first specification
the first rfc
should already use its own extension
point
mechanism and in the itf we have a
pretty good way to organize
these extension points by running ayana
registries with designated experts
that serve as a gating function to uh
what
what gets into the extension point and
and what
doesn't um so one one of the interesting
questions here will be to
to decide how liberal or how
conservative uh
that that gating function needs to be um
so i don't want to
to anticipate the discussion here but
extension points are
really important and one of the nice
things of having a good extension point
mechanism is that the base mechanism
of the language can actually get uh
pretty
small because you can put lots of stuff
into extension parts we
notice that that in cddl where
all of the new stuff we have been doing
in the last one or two years
went into the one extension point we
provided and for for some reason it just
worked
and we consider ourselves very lucky
there
uh a comment back on the adjacent on on
the
on whether we can use the type uh
freely or if there's that a
implementation detail
i think we should reason whether uh
the well-known types defined in the json
standard itself
are still whether they do belong here
and i think they should
so we can freely talk about what types
of the node have
in the filter language
cool okay i put myself on the cube
because i actually wanted to say
something technical here
um so when you start talking about
extension points
i start to get a little bit nervous the
um you know the classic example of a
standard with a lot of extension points
is sql
which has an infinite number of
extension points and has zero
interoperability so
you have to be careful that an extension
point isn't an excuse
for vendors to stake out land grabs and
so on so so you know when we get to
technical discussions i'm probably going
to be quite conservative about
what we say about extension points
so i'll take myself back off how do i do
that oh yes here
so i think what i'm hearing is that
the sense of the group uh for the people
at least who are
speaking up is that uh the filtering
capability
is uh seems to have fairly broad support
nobody seems to want to either adopt an
existing language
or invent a new one
but but as i said filtering has a strong
support and we've heard a couple of
voices
talk about the importance of having uh
good clean extension points
um and uh i really admit i don't know
what that means
but we should record that concern um and
and make sure we address it
uh as we go forward
okay this is an important issue so i
don't want to move off it
let me see we're doing just fine for
time um
wow we're doing excellent for time we
have a full two hours here
um no further comments on
scripting and filters
fine okay um next one what can we say
about the result of evaluating a json
path now
the reason this came up was um
in the discussion the early discussion
we had somebody said well of course
everything that comes back is by
definition an array
and i went oh really
and uh so uh clearly
the document you reproduce has to be
very clear about the syntax
of you know what can what's legal in a
json path
and what it means but given this is
going to be embedded in many programming
languages
i'm wondering what in fact we can say
about what the result of evaluating a
json path is
um does anybody have have strong
opinions on that
rick
okay so so there's a there's a
mutability issue
which has always slightly worried me
with jason poynter
and i think might creep into jason path
as well
which is i'm not sure
how this is going to work with jason
park but i know at least with jason
poynter you can say
um sorry let me rephrase that ignore the
json pointer comment
the um if you're returning an array of
results
then that array is effectively uh you're
creating an array and returning it
so find me uh uh all the items
with a a property of red within this
large data set and that that will return
you an array of the five items
that that match your filter that is a
that is a new array that's required a
memory allocation and requires some sort
of maintenance using your
your if you've got a garbage collected
scripted in the scripting language
that's absolutely fine
compare and contrast that with a filter
which
will only return you the one result
you're looking for and can effectively
return you a pointer to an existing item
and requires no memory allocation
as a little better background i i work
for airbus i work in the aeronautical
industry
and bizarrely we actually use a lot of
these so-called scripting
style languages but we use them in very
formal environments where
we care a lot about memory allocation
and a lot about performance
and this applies to iot and embedded as
well so
having the the the standard result set
from a json path expression be something
that has to be
immutable it has to be allocated and and
returned is
is something that needs some
consideration so in
for example in my implementation i
effectively have two code parts one
which will return you
pointers to something which won't touch
the structure just reference into that
existing structure
as compared to a completely different
json path function
that will return you a new collection of
results that you then have to go and
handle and own you know you it's handing
you out the pointers you have to
and and that is the consideration that
sometimes gets missed when you're coming
from a from a garbage collected
scripting language perspective
interesting um julia
so um thinking about what could
what program could do with the result of
a json path
query isn't one obvious use case
something like find these things
in my json and once i found them i want
to delete them
so that would mean that um returning an
array
containing copies of these items will
not really be helpful right
because then you would need to go back
to the original json
and find these nodes at the point of
running the json path query
was to find these notes right
that's the thought and the takeaway from
that
is that um there are
different ways to use the result of a
json path that are wildly different in
the requirements they would impose on
the
on whatever comes back um i don't know
what i take from that but it's an
observation that sounds true to me
uh glenn yeah i'm
sympathetic to that uh issue of memory
allocation
uh and one of the implementations i
worked on um
had a uh essentially a dom of the json
file as input and a collection of
pointers as output
into the dom and the the reason for that
was so we could mutate the contents and
then produce a new document
by picking out particular points and
mutating the nodes
but i think the crucial thing for me is
that in the spec we need to be very
clear
what the difference is between a single
node
uh result and an array
of length one and think in the past
there have been some
ambiguities there and confusions so you
know we might want to
give options to return a single item but
we need to be really clear in the spec
when it is a single item when it's an
array of length one
okay um kirsten
yeah so basically i think the the
abstract model should be
that we get a json tree as as input
and this json tree has positions
in it which which are the various places
in the other branches and the leaves and
so on
and then what what a json path spec
gives you is a set of those positions
subset or essentially a mapping of these
positions to a boolean or however you
want to think about it
but it just selects part of that tree
and i think what part of the confusion
is that
the discussion then always turned into
how do we represent this in environment
x
and of course there is no natural
representation for the set of positions
for instance in json so
stefan's original document talks about
returning the values at those positions
or returning output parts that are
essentially json pointers
in into the structure
and both are representations but i think
we should not
think in terms of those representations
we should think in terms of the
concept of marking the json tree with
part of the result and not part of the
result and that's essentially what the
json path expression reach ups
i put myself on the cue so i'm going to
speak here listening to this
makes me a little bit pessimistic about
our ability to specify
uh the output because i i can think of
you know
so many different needs you know we use
this very very heavily in a couple of
products
at aws you know that we're running a
million events a second
through something and you know you if
you match an event then you would you
could apply a json path to the event
to say what would what the customer what
the what the receiver of the event would
see
and if you said something like dollar
dot a dot b
and that was just the number four then
that meant that the
customer expected to get a four and
that's all i expected to get and i think
that's also a perfectly used
reasonable use case um which would be
you know
it would be unfortunate if our spec uh
ruled out
any of these perfectly reasonable use
cases i i've just heard about
which bothers me a little bit because i
it would also be nice to
have you know a level of precision about
what you can
expect to get and to the expected people
who map it into a new programming
language wouldn't be surprised by the
mapping you get
and yeah i know i don't know what i
think about this yet anyhow marco
just to complicate things no further if
you have like an array of arrays
at the top level and you have one array
that contains only one
one such element one array when you then
select all the
all the elements of the top level array
you will get
as a result one array so is the result
like under one array or a singleton
array that contains
an array or is it the array is that the
top level array
you know it's it's confusing
glenn back to you
that was essentially a similar point
really um the
my mom went blank come back to me
okay back to rick
this is a discussion around return by
value or return by reference
and there are pros and cons to both of
course uh
i think carsten touched on the fact that
we we have the mechanisms for reference
it's
it's jsonpointer it exists it will give
us a reference back into
to the original tree um
i think this is solvable i think it just
needs to be covered and not ignored
so i'm not too worried but it's and i'm
glad we're having this discussion
okay uh karsten yeah again i think it's
really
useful to be able to separate the
abstract concept of the result of a
json path expression and the various
forms in which they
they can be returned and i said tim i
think the the example you gave
where you expect the json path
expression to return exactly one
position and they are actually
interested in the value from that
that is indeed a very common use case
and and we definitely should
make sure that gets some attention
for a json path processor it's currently
not easy to find
out whether that is what you actually
want
um so do you do you want to get a set of
nodes back or do you want to get a
single node
back so it essentially becomes an
exception if if
there is more than one node or even an
exception if there is only
only zero nodes being returned so that
that's one of the
the little problems that i have with
jsonpath
where i don't know whether we are going
to to solve that
um but i think the the
model the high level model should be
flexible enough to
actually address these different use
cases
interesting remember what i was going to
say
um the um i'm sympathetic to the idea of
an abstract model
and you know the idea of just coloring a
tree to say which nodes were selected
is great but uh looking at the consensus
of
current implementations you know that
excellent project that was done by
someone else
which covers 30 odd implementations that
uh there is often duplication in the
outputs
and um and questions about the ordering
and if we settle on an abstract model
that rules out that then we're going to
cause
pain for all the implementers migrating
to the the standard
so just concerned about about being
overly prescriptive
michael
yeah i must mostly wanted to double down
on the fact that
i i don't think it's the biggest problem
here is
the distinction between reference
between and and copies and
the the the the allocation comes from
from the the allocation problems comes
from uh
the the selection uh problem so uh
the the the arity of the results uh is
is what i think uh is
one thing matters most here is do we
want
to uh force multiple iot or do we want
to uh
to somehow automatically detect the
one versus the multipolarity or do we
want to let the user select in the
syntax
whether you expect one result or
multiple
rick it occurs to me i've posted this in
the java but the java's got such long
lag on it i decided just to step to the
mic there's
there's without affecting the the
the syntax or the uh search
mechanisms etc of json path
surely you can specify a find first
operation and
compare it to a find all operation and
therefore
specify find first will perform the
following jsonpath
evaluation as detailed in section x
and we'll return the first result
and a find all will do this but we'll
return all results found
as an array and you can also add a sort
of a second dimension to this to say
find by ref return by reference or
return by value
so as an implementer i can say i don't
care about these by values because in my
environment it's not important
i will return via ref and we can specify
by reference means return adjacent
pointer as in
rfc i can't remember the number but it's
specified
so i think that gives us the flexibility
without
having to have different expression
forms or different search
path criteria etc we can still have that
standardization of how you find
these things but depending on how you
call them
answers do i end first and return a copy
because i'm doing something deeply
asynchronous and only care about one
or do i actually am i just doing a
search over a dom tree where i want to
find
some of them but i don't want to get the
cost of the copy
but still the the syntax of doing the
search itself
is is the same that would be my
compromise
so i put myself on the queue to ask you
a question rick which is are you
proposing that we actually specify an
api
saying you know i want pointers or i
want values
sorry can you say again you broke up in
the middle of that for me sorry are you
are you suggesting that we actually
specify an apis where whereby the user
of a jsonpath can say whether they want
references back or values i i'm not sure
i go as far as an api because we we step
into
well what's the binding for my favorite
language
but i think some elegant
way of saying uh an implementation
may provide a mechanism to return
by value and here are the considerations
that need to be applied
or a mechanism that should return by
reference
and when we say reference we mean json
pointer which would be my proposal
um and the following things apply and
you could have
another section which differentiates
between find me the first and find me
all with relevant considerations but
don't say and here's how you do it in
rust
and here's how you do it in insert
favorite language here
that's that's not gonna work so really
this sounds like you're suggesting
some non-normative implementation
guidelines
as part of the document is that right
i would go for normative to say look the
working group has
has realized that there are use cases
where you want one
item and you can stop the search as soon
as you hit one item
um but there are also use cases where
you want all
and there are uh an implementation may
realize that there are
performance implications etc associated
with finding first and finding all
so this is or should it be normative i i
don't know but it should definitely be
strong guidance for implementers to say
really you should implement this twice
and if and if this
uh if the output of the working group is
picked up by ecma
or or the java standardization guys or
whatever and they say
well yeah we're going to have this in
our next version of our language
then this guidance can apply to them to
say you need to consider
this conversation go go go i've heard
that we're just about to get a reboot
of the entire infrastructure for this
and we'll be offline for about five
minutes
um there's a problem with the chat which
has broken everything and so they
are rebooting the entire medical
infrastructure so just so you know when
you disappear
okay let's keep going let's let's keep
going until we disappear
i'll give way to casting yeah i just
wanted to point out you you said fine
first
and of course another interesting
uh case is to find any
uh which is different from trying first
that you don't get to guarantee that
it's actually the first
um so um yeah
i think right in clarification when i
said find first i meant
return me the first one you find
depending on
whatever the express the expression may
say i want you to search from the back
going forwards or or depth first or
whatever
i mean the difference between fine fight
i meant to find any
as compared to find all but i can't find
first
um yeah so i think the if the mental
model is this
this model that we didn't call marking
the tree
um then we can derive
those various api variants
from that model easily yes
absolutely we get a really nice
separation of concern we have one mental
model that that governs
uh jsonpath and we we have
the ability to specify a few apis
or abstract apis that we might uh
want to see but of course that not
everybody
has to implement all of them
yes
oops
um my my
my meeting is back
same here it was a very quick reboot
that was really fast
for me as well it may bounce again
who knows whoever did that i'm super
impressed
um james is restarting his screen share
there we go that should be back
here's
i'm michael sure what happened to the
chat oh the chat
wait a second there is there seems to be
no chat anymore
they said they had chat problems which
was the cause of the reboot so
uh the chat might be running behind
well here it is it seems to have
returned
but there's nothing in it
james your screen share isn't working
it's not vital
but you might need to hard refresh your
browser or something oops
okay it sounds like we're mostly here
again
james's screen share is having trouble
but i don't think it's that essential
we had we were on the last delineated
item i think on the agenda which
produced some i thought some
really interesting discussion um let me
see if i can try
and and and and summarize where we've
got to
is that i think we agree that the
variety of uses
to which a the evaluation of a json path
expression
can be put um makes it
difficult to be very prescriptive well
and also the different number of
programming languages is going to be
embedded in
are going to make it hard to be terribly
prescriptive about exactly what form
that return takes
but uh there is certainly scope for us
to write strong guidance
into the uh document for
implementers about the kinds of
requirements they should be
uh prepared to to to solve
any other key points from this
discussion we want to capture
or does anybody want to add anything
further yeah rick go ahead
so one last thought on this subject i
think it
may be worth in the actual json path
specification
enumerating these different methods of
of of of acquiring a result
the reason being um i'm doing a fair
amount of heavy lifting with jason
schemer at the moment
and jason schemer uses jason pointer
as part of its structure so
a certain part of a schema is defined as
this is a json pointer to somewhere else
now if that was to be extended to say
or changed to say this is a json path
to somewhere else but the
the consumer of that json path is
expecting only a single result
then whoever is specifying that
mechanism needs to be able to say
this is a json path returning only a
single result as defined in rfc blah
blah blah
type section three which defines a json
path returning a single result as
compared to a json path returning
multiple results so
rather than just advice to implementers
i think it's worth having these things
normatively named so that they can be
referred to by
other other specifications
i like that point a lot of having
normative names to specify these
behaviors
um glenn and there was discussion about
whether to call
one of the apis find first or find any
uh i think that raises a really
important point which is
what's our attitude to non-determinism
in the spec
um i see non-determinism has been a a
strength
because it gives you freedom to
implement
uh in a more efficient way or a
different way some people think
uh non-determinism in a spec is a
weakness and it's something to be
avoided at all across
so i just want to raise that in case
anybody has strong feelings about that
apart from me
it's that is definitely a tricky point
um and i don't know what i think marco
i i have some strong feelings um against
uh using json path as a way
to point to things just because other
uh some some other standards of pointers
are
too weak to actually find their ways
through a document that has
a a complex schema in in particular json
pointer doesn't have the ability to
to find things through arrays um
i mean other than using using positions
and so i seen people drawn to
jason path precisely for that reason for
the the expressiveness of json path but
i don't think you can
uh you can ensure with jason pat that
you are
actually you know pointing to one thing
you know rather to than
getting you know
just you know too much things
unexpectedly so
i guess all that i can say on this is
that um
our discussion on this is going to be
aided by the introduction of lots of use
cases
um so
[Music]
fortunately jsonpath is in the field has
been there for a while it's heavily used
um i speaking only for myself i'm going
to have a much easier time understanding
these kinds of propositions saying well
suppose i have this data and this json
path in this scenario
here's what i want to happen how do we
you know how should i not want to not
happen
um i think that's going to get us to to
consensus
um faster um
marco you're still at the head of the
queue are you we want to say some more
no
well this is interesting and and we're
certainly not tight on time
i think we've increased our
understanding of the problem
if not of the solution to it and that
that's a good thing
anything further on the result of
evaluating a json path
okay at this point we have run through
our agenda
and any other business things that we
forgot to discuss
things that i foolishly uh suppressed
because i thought we'd be short on time
but we're not
um karsten
yeah i think it may be a bit early to
ask this question
uh but uh early is the the
operative word here we probably need to
develop an understanding of the
timelines we are
operating on uh here um it's
really hard to estimate the amount of
work that goes into
such a specification effort but on the
other hand
uh yeah if we don't do any planning at
all then it's going
to be even more chaotic um
so i think we should try to understand
what are our next milestones and i don't
mean formal milestones in the charter
sense but just things we want to achieve
and when are we going to to
have them um have it with them
and i think the the the next milestone
for
me is actually spending time on on
getting these merged drafts
or this merge draft um out there
uh and i probably also could write some
text on this
abstract model that we uh talked about
um so that that might be going on
independently or might go into the
smudge draft depending on on
what the timelines on of either thing um
is and the other thing of course is
to get people's favorite examples there
are lots of examples
in the that other project that has been
uh mentioned but maybe people still have
examples from their practical work
uh that they are very interested in
getting right
um in terms of dates i i just
looked at our charter and it has no
dates in it
i thought it did i'm surprised i could
have sworn i said tim tim it was my
understanding that that there was a
placeholder milestone for iesg
submission
for mid next year um
i i would i would like to propose if if
if
the the various people who are
interested in editing this have
have the time and the brainpower to do
it
if we could aim between sort of now and
the next ietf meeting in late march to
to have uh sort of a you know
the the merged document as as it were of
of the
existing uh personal drafts that are out
there
and to have an os um uh an oo draft
out there uh and so that when we come
around to the next meeting in the end of
march
you know we should be uh fully into the
into the motions of of working through
a lot of the issues that we have
discussed today i think that that would
be a fairly
fairly achievable goal i'd be interested
to know what the
uh what what the rest of the working
group thinks
yeah um i see glenn's at the top of the
roof but i also see murray our a.d
there and i think his opinion is highly
relevant to this yes
murray would you like to go ahead please
yeah i i
you just have the one milestone for june
next year which is the standards track
document defining json path but that's
that can be renegotiated so there is one
there but it's um
not set in stone so tell me what else
you're thinking of i'm listening
so let me just glenn i haven't forgotten
about you but i
i believe i heard uh if i understood
what james was proposing was he's
proposing
that we have a working group draft
um uh with consensus
with consensus backing of the working
group which nonetheless is is not
complete
um by the next ietf which is march you
said
yeah and and
my opinion is that the smart way to do
this is going to
start with a very very small draft and
build it out because i mean there are
certain aspects of jsonpath that are not
controversial at all i mean
dollar.a.b you know and dollar square
brackets three
you know kind of thing are are not
controversial and if we had something
with a really good job of capturing that
um and even in that there's a few corner
cases and so on
um if we could get to that by march
i think that would be pretty good other
opinions glenn back to you sorry for
interrupting
um well before i make my point i was
going to make i would say that
the draft i've been working on is is
that form
it's the non-controversial subset and it
tries to cover the corner cases
so um you know let's have a look at that
as a working group
what i was going to mention was the json
jsonpath comparison
project that's been done uh i mentioned
30 odd implementations that are covered
um just wondered about you know since
we're talking in real time it might be
good to discuss
people's attitudes to existing
implementations
and how we see migration to the eventual
standard
going you know how disruptive do we want
to be how
accommodating do we want to be you know
i would like
to accommodate the consensus in general
you know maybe not always maybe not when
it makes doesn't make sense but
you know rather go towards the current
consensus rather than away from it
personally i'd be interested in other
people's positions
yeah i put myself on the list um because
i i uh on this one
um so you know at aws we built a a a
couple of
large complex you know vast numbers of
users vast number amounts of data
uh services and we didn't even realize
what we were doing we just built them
with j-way
and so the semantics you know the
language we we actually
de facto supported with whatever j-way
did
and that was a little unfortunate and
realistically the chance
that um uh that we would
you know that that product will ever
adopt a
new json path syntax it's inconsistent
with something that joey does today is
effectively zero because there's
literally hundreds of thousands of
people
just using it so my take away from that
is we should you know
try to minimize that but let's let's
face
facts and
realize that what we're building is
probably for you know
uh future implementers and future
adopters of jsonpath because existing
adopters
mostly just aren't going to change um
karsten
yeah i think in in the end there are
costs
uh to to any decision and there are
in making the wrong decision as well so
when we do something that is not
supported by the majority
of the implementations then we have the
cost of
uh causing them pain or losing them and
so on
uh when we make a decision that actually
is
well bad uh we cause
cost for for future users
um of uh the specification and we have
to balance these two
costs so the the default answer
probably is make sure to work with
existing specifications
with existing implementations but if
there is some decision that we make that
makes it
really much more complicated for people
to actually
implement or use jsonpath just we want
to
drag a specific implementation along
that's also wrong so i don't think this
can be
discussed in the absolutes it will
depend on every single case
whether we go for documenting existing
practice
or maybe cleaning up things a little bit
and so far i think i've heard from most
people that there probably needs to be a
really good reason to go for cleaning up
things but i would be unhappy if we
cannot do that at all
fair enough marie
just wanted to mention that the charter
actually talked about this we
anticipated this coming up and it talks
about how you might break ties or
um try to accommodate the consensus of
the common
implementations and that sort so just
you might want to review that we can
always tweak this too if it needs
additional guidance but it seems like we
did think about this a little bit
already
yeah i'm just going to read from the
charter it says uh the working group
will discover will develop a standards
tracks jsonpath specification that is
technically sound and complete
based on the common semantics and other
aspects
of existing implementations where there
are differences
the working group will analyze those
differences and make choices that rough
consensus considers technically best
with an aim towards minimizing
disruption so yeah
and and i agree this is going to be a
pain point for this group
so to get back to where glenn launched
us
about you know target dates um
i've heard the proposal of of the next
ietf
for a working group draft uh with with
consensus backing
that will probably not be complete but
will be correct for this episode it
covers
i like the sound of that does anybody
object or disagree or think that's
unreasonable
excellent
good okay do we have any other business
um just as a just as a housekeeping
thing what we can do is
now that we have our uh github
organization uh
created thank you very much carsten uh
we can
uh create the repositories and
and and the necessary boilerplate so the
editors can just
uh get on with with the editing part um
and i can disseminate information about
that later today
excellent thank you
glenn yeah
before all this started i picked on a
github org name which is probably
unfortunate now jason path
standard just as a place in the sand
so i'll probably ditch that and
move somewhere else for the reference
implementation and cts
uh because that's you know may end up
being entirely informal
uh but there's also a slack instance
i'll probably kill that as well because
it's not going to be
archived it's not uh appropriate so
just wanted to mention that i'll be kind
of killing off those things
so that we centralize on the official uh
organization
and uh mailing list
right there's actually a procedural
thing
is it appropriate to do the compliance
test if in fact we decide it's not an
official output
in that organization i don't know i'm
gonna i'm gonna
ask around uh you know julian will have
experience what they did
on the structured headers um
so you're probably correct glenn that
that that
that's probably not the right place to
do it with the under that name but
but let's not uh there's no hurry let's
make sure we get this right
yeah i mean i would destroy the repo
just move it into a personal repo
sure yeah sure julian
julian audio
hmm we can't hear you julian
and we don't have any chat that i can
see does it work now
oh there you are okay complicated
interface
sorry um for structured headers it
actually is
a mark nottingham's private repository
so um
we i think on the working group
materials page
we have a link to that test suite or
test cases
pointing out that is not a working group
work item but
it's relevant anyway so but i wouldn't
rule out that the itf allows that even
if we
had don't have the goal of publishing it
so it's worth asking i guess the area
director
sure murray i'll talk we'll talk to
murray about this and see
you know what the what the feeling is
about this kind of thing i'm
you know i'm a cheerleader i i think
that that that specs that have
supporting software are are winners but
uh let's see what the community feel
feels about this kind of there may also
be some devil in the
some details in 8875 which we
might that might give us the answer to
this
correct correct i don't yeah i didn't i
didn't read it deeply
so perfectly possible
fair enough okay any further business
okay well i've learned something about
this working group we get through stuff
next time we do this i'll put more stuff
on the agenda
um
it was a pretty good reasonable size of
group i mean if you have
200 it's hard if you have three people
it's hard but this group
seems to have about the right size to
make progress
i sincerely hope that you're right
oh i see some names i know as we've
joined you'd like to ask a question
actually
um sorry i'm not on the queue none of
that
glenn we talked about consensus meetings
but i don't really have a feel for the
frequency of those other formats
they occur only i etf conferences or
are they more frequent well working
groups are
different there are some working groups
that have lots and lots and lots of
interim meetings and address these
things
uh others um uh firstly
you know the only time they meet at all
is at itf meetings and there
are you know chair calls consensus
periodically
and uh drafts are produced uh karsten
yeah so um i think it's a good idea to
be very adaptive
um in that so that there is no one right
answer
um in several work moves that i'm
involved in we do
have periods of quick progress where we
have about bi-weekly uh meetings and we
try to time-box them into one hour
so it's not uh it's not
becoming epic but we can actually use
face to face
uh time but your face to facetime
to to get progress and we also have
which is very important uh milestones to
which people have to have their
preparations
uh in place but uh even those groups who
have these bi-weekly
periods also have silent periods so for
instance the
call working group probably won't do
another
of these virtual interims for the rest
of the year because there's
thanksgiving and christmas and other
holidays
so it all depends on what phase we are
in
and whether we actually have something
to uh discuss but
by weekly one our format has worked very
well for us
and on the other extreme i've been a
member of one working group where
it was all done between between a couple
of iatfs and i don't think there was
ever a face-to-face everything was just
done on the mailing list and with
consensus calls
so so we'll we'll be flexible i i don't
think
any of us are religious about uh
how to do it we'll we'll talk about it
and you know i obviously i think james
and i would agree that if people
feel the need for such a thing feel free
to say so um
then of course we might have something
like design team
uh meetings or editors meetings uh
things like that so when we are trying
to make progress
on things where we already have
direction from the
working group but simply have to do
medial work to
get that reflected in in the document so
i think that that will also happen
because
in the end we will need to have a
document
that is good
glenn sorry it's me again but
taking the opportunity while we're face
to face um
what's the process for um uh kind of
drafting and and reflecting consensus
into a draft because the approach i've
taken so far
has been to for the draft to kind of
lead the process and put up a pr
and then invite people involved to
comment on the pr and then merge that
um is this some other approach that we
anticipate where we
kind of discuss an area on the mailing
list and elsewhere
and then edit it into shame well the
traditional ietf approach is
issues come up and are discussed
at an appropriate length and then
eventually the the
co-chairs make a consensus call and the
editors
have the amusing fun of taking the
consensus call
and turning it into spec language um
that's sort of the traditional approach
obviously um
you know prs are
are a really good way to to make
arguments in some cases um
kirsten yeah we
have recently had the discussion on that
if you have a really large working
replay like with
quicker or http and you want to have a
very formal model with
pull requests and working glass calls on
full request and then finally they they
go into the document
that means essentially the document is
really just recording consensus that has
been generated in
in another way and that works well
uh before you you dive into other
bureaucracies and so on
in a smaller group it's sometimes also a
good idea to
have leading documents so
you are not waiting for consensus to
form
but people are actually
writing up things that can be in a pull
request
or it can be in the main document that
depends on the style of editing
uh things it depends a bit on how many
of these things are going on
in parallel which one works better
but it's much easier to get consensus on
something that already is
in the document because you are not not
discussing it on a theoretical level you
have actually text to
to look at and you can make pull
requests to
the the changes and uh improve it before
uh there is actually a consensus
so yeah good
so i agree with what carson said you
know that's what i was saying as well
sometimes the best way to
argue for a particular change is to make
the change you know put in a pr saying
yes i want it also depends on whether
we're arguing about the best way to
express a shared understanding
or the situation which you know
regularly arises there's actually a
disagreement in principle
about what needs to be done and then
there's usually a lot more work that has
to go into discussing and then making an
official
consensus call glenn glenn go ahead
yeah just to to sharpen my question a
bit who
in particular would would we expect to
drive the work
uh do we expect the editors our editor
to
drive it do we expect the chair to drive
it do you expect random individuals on
the mailing list
to drive particular issues
well de facto the people who have more
time and resources to put in
tend to uh you know do a lot of driving
but the
uh but the mechanism uh in in
is is that the chairs um
are supposed to steer the discussions
and and make the consensus calls
passive to me uh it's like there is a
discussion going on and the chair
derives consensus and oversees it
uh just wondering you know uh
you know for those of us in the frame to
potentially be an editor
i'm just wondering how much we're taking
on by agreeing to do that
well but you know when you become the
editor um
the the change control is
belongs to the working group and the
working group
uh you know expresses it by debating and
then by eventually by consensus calls
in the happy case where you know there's
a shared vision of exactly what we're
trying to build
um uh you know then everybody pitches in
to get to the best language
um the real in my experience the real
difficulties arise when there's
genuine disagreement on what the shape
we're trying to build is
but uh uh aside from that i have not had
ex
you know had a lot of difficulty with
the experience it seems to work
reasonably well
okay and it's probably uh worth
clarifying that it
based on how we're how we've been
discussing things in this
in our first meeting i think that we'll
be able to come to consensus on a lot of
the topics quite easily
uh and where we don't have that
consensus i think that's that's the job
for tim and myself to try and work
through the subject
with the working group to try and figure
out some sort of
outcome to that
yeah what what timber said it's of
course right but it's only true
once the working draft has been adopted
so right now there are two individual
drafts and
of course we can just go ahead and
change them as much as you want
which will in turn influence the
probability that part of the text
turns up in a working group draft
so in larger working groups that have
more than one draft to look at
it's sometimes better not to do the work
adoption too early because
as long as drafts are individual draft
the owners of those drafts can charge
ahead and fix things without
waiting for for a lot of cycles through
the working
group so i'm not sure we are in this
situation here but
as a general statement i wanted to point
out that
adoption actually completely changes the
dynamics of
how a document is being processed
yes glenn just to that point i was
intending
on the draft i've been working on to
kind of halt work on that
and focus on the document being
developed by the working group
and not to run it in parallel so i'm
very nervous about getting ahead of
consensus
uh you know based on the discussion
we've had today i'm i i agree
whoever was said i'm i'm not too worried
i think we'll probably
be relatively straightforward for us to
build consensus
and that's helped by the fact that we're
not inventing anything right i mean
jason path exists
large parts of it have you know
everybody
agrees what it means and and
getting that just written down the
shared understanding
in a clean comprehensible way um
is is is is non-trivial uh
i think it's worth working on and i
wouldn't expect
a lot of disagreements along the way um
but i also agree with what carson said
you know there's there's a lot of value
in individual drafts
but once again i i i really am
optimistic that we can get
to uh shared consensus uh incomplete
uh draft by by march
is it then worth us uh just just to be
explicit and clear
is it worth us uh just saying that
what we what we could do is is adopt uh
lindstraft as it stands
uh with the full anticipation that we
would be merging in
um the uh works from other other
documents
the the other draft as well as any any
other contributions
as the starting point for the working
group document
is uh anybody have any particular
thoughts about that
a thumbs up from marker
okay i i put myself up but i'm going to
defer julian
can you hear me yes yes hey
um i i just wanted to know that's uh
typically something that you will call
for consensus on
either on the mailing list or i think
this
meet echo thing has a show of hands tool
that we could use
which would replace the hum that we are
doing in
actual itf meetings so the
the the decision to adopt an individual
draft
as working group draft would be
something you would do a formal call of
coil for consensus for okay i
i'm i'm happy to do that as uh in the
medical now if if
if that's the uh easiest way to get to a
conclusion on this
and that said the um show of hands or
the hum
in a working group meeting is taken as
input for the consensus finding but it
would still need to be confirmed on the
mailing list so for those
for those who are unable to show up at
the virtual meeting or the actual
meeting
okay we can do both
yeah i'm a little bit nervous you know
simply because of the distributed nature
of this
of this meeting and i'm really pleased
by the number of people who showed up
here which is much greater than i
expected but
um you know it is after all a an odd
time for a lot of people
and i'd be maybe a little nervous about
adopting based on on on at the basis of
a
virtual show of hands here uh without at
least taking it to the mailing list
um sure let's take it to the list
rick go ahead as a chair of a couple of
other groups
uh it's really best practice to uh
to handle adoptions on the mailing list
by all means
ask during a session that's great
but the decision should be on the
mailing list really for for
completeness sure yeah i i agree 100
glenn i guess the question is are there
any objections here because the
objections here we could discuss them
fair enough glenn's uh raised the point
does anybody have any specific
objections
kirsten
um in larger groups it's often a good
idea to do adoption with questions
in the working group meeting because we
need to find out who's actually
going to work on the document who's
going to write code who's going to
review the document and so on
so um all of that doesn't occur here we
we are all
here in this virtual room right now
because we care about
uh this effort um so that's the
part we just don't need to do um and the
other part
actually works better on the meetings
the question really is
what what document is being adopted
and i have indicated my preference
for that and that's different
from what you just said so i i would not
agree
with the procedure but of course i may
be just one
well i don't see any reason not to do a
show of hands um so the specific
proposal
if i understand it is that the working
group
adopts the current state of the uh
glenn marco and somebody else i forget
the name um
draft um
and let me see let me use the show of
hands meeting so i'm going to try and
do this so
let the working group adopt the current
state of the gwen at i'll
draft as a draft
okay so um i've started that
um and um
uh if you do people know how to do this
there's a little uh
graph bar graph thing uh just under your
your name you click on that
and while we have 22 in people here
that's really excellent
let's give people a minute we only have
seven
hands raised or not
now the tool allows you to not
make a decision so it seems true
quite a few people are sitting here who
don't know what decision they should
take and that's just fine there's a lot
of people who don't have an opinion
that's also
perfectly okay input
so just to repeat what uh in the spirit
of
what cast and said i did not raise my
hands
but that's for the only reason because i
haven't looked at the draft
so i need more time would be the answer
so ask on the name of this and give a
few days
uh to be honest i have the same
situation i did read the draft but
that was a while ago and frankly i don't
have
a strong opinion so i'm just not my hand
is not raised at the moment
uh rudiger is next in the queue
yeah clicking on do not raise your hand
does not mean objection
sorry i see please ask that again i
didn't understand
okay
clicking on do not raise your hand does
not mean
objection it just
it just means it just means you were
using the tool
asking for objections would be a
separate question
okay fair enough but um de facto there
is a real difference between clinton do
not raise your hand
and not clicking anything at all
um okay so at this point
i'm seeing three hands raised six
explicitly not raised out of 22s that's
probably less than half the people
um
uh murray
normally when we take homes you would
ask both questions
so you would say does anybody want this
hum now and then you would say does
anybody object to this
hum now sort of thing so you might ask
the question twice just to eliminate
that
but this is um that's not a major point
i don't think since you're planning to
take this to the list anyway
yeah no this is useful input
so it shows us that a lot of people
haven't made up their minds
that um there are people who are nervous
about doing it um
and let's let's take this idea to the
list and
it also may help for uh james and i to
do our jobs and and
and make decisions about editorial roles
and things like that too to help
yeah that move along
okay that's enough votes i'll end the
session it was three six
three and six
oops my m my meat echo is
well there it is it came back okay folks
this has
all been very useful any any further
input
any further business
well with that i'm going to say thank
you uh one once again good morning good
afternoon and good evening thank you for
coming out i'm
i'm i'm really pleased with the uh
it seems like we have uh broadly
speaking a shared understanding of what
it is we're trying to do here
and a good understanding of the problem
so i'm super optimistic that we are
going to get a good result so thank you
everybody james any closing remarks
um no i think you've done a good job
covering it
thank you everyone for for your time and
uh participation
cool okay thanks everybody
thanks you later
uh
yes
um
[Music]
uh
oh